oh thank you
boo % I lovely Thanks hi I'm great I
work with havens today's talk is really
going to be about Incident Response from
the perspective of crisis management and
looking at some interesting clinical
models that actually talk about the way
people handle people under medical care
and how they actually deal with crisis
and then sort of comparing that to what
actually happens during a standard cyber
Incident Response I am a lord I like to
say a reform nerd I used to be technical
but compared to guys like you know Ed
Ferrell and Kay Norton I'm a lowly noob
so I'm okay with that
what I do spend a reasonable amount of
time doing though is coordinating I are
either helping organizations plan and I
are capability and I are frameworks or
actually assisting organizations in the
throes of an incident I've worked on
cases that are relate to criminal
activities arguably nation-state stuff
depending if you believe in the internet
boogeyman and activist incidents as well
so I've seen quite a variety of
different types of incidents with
different motivations all the way
ranging from purely business based I'm
going to make money out of your business
all the way through to people who have a
an emotional or a political need to get
a message across so Luddites so one of
the reasons why I wrote this talk was it
within a conversation with a customer
who made the offhand comment that I am
just a Luddite I am you know I'm not
tech enough to understand I'm not tech
enough to be useful and the background
of Luddites is actually there were a
group of people in the about the 19th
century who started to rise up against
the increasing automation particularly
in cotton and wool milling at the time
so in some ways it's kind of similar to
what we're seeing where organizations
are becoming more and more heavily
focused on automation orchestration
heavily technical focus responses to
two incidents and those of us that are
slightly less technical start to feel
like we you know we don't have as much
to offer so for those in the room let's
just do a quick show of hands who would
say that they based on that for the
definition will be consider themselves
to be a bit of a Luddite great I've got
news for you today's day we are going to
join forces and raise up against the
oppression and tyranny of tech
oppression Luddites we are awesome for
those who didn't raise your hand you're
like oh there's like all the
managers is out of control we're going
to be documentation everywhere and
policies will be fine so why is incident
response cool basically intimate
response fills a gap for an emotional
need fray the technical guys around
being the guy that comes in and save the
day if you compare your traditional
penetration tester who comes in drops an
amazing o day totally owns the
organization puts it into a document
hands the report to the customer who
then goes great we're going to risk
except that that is an emotional
response pretty bloody awful however as
an incident responder you get to save
the day you get to play with all the
cool pics
you get sexy bad guys you've got I've
got Chinese hackers from Iran that are
like using North Korean tech and they're
owning everything and you get to sound
really really awesome and the best thing
is as an incident responder you get to
save the day you only turn up when an
organization is having their worst day
ever and you are the solution to that
problem so as an emotional need or an
emotional response that feels pretty
bloody good the reality for us mere
mortals manages Incident coordinators
into the managers is a lot different
incidents are painful they mean that
you're going to have a lot of time
dealing with people above you more
senior than you communicating with them
you're going to get all sorts of awkward
questions and frankly you're going to
spend a lot of time just herding cats
but as an incident coordinator or an
incident manager this is actually your
time to shine and is actually a critical
role in any sort of incident response
capability
so one of the things I noticed around
incident response is that it is infested
with elas to let three-letter acronyms
and four letter acronyms that's
basically because incident responders
are too busy to use for words and
sentences so you load up your your
sticks in the taxi with your io CS and
you put that into the scene and all of a
sudden you've got this whole
gobbledygook language but for the people
that are not really that technical that
starts to lose any meaning so there's
actually a barrier there of
communication between the people who are
trying to manage the incident and the
people that are actually trying to get
done the one thing to bear in mind
though is that during an incident the
fundamentals of InfoSec basically don't
change
it's a resources game whoever has the
most resources wins and generally its
weight weighted towards the bad guys
they only have to find one hole or one
weakness you get you have to plug all of
them so from a manager you need to
continue to challenge and question the
tech response and make sure that your
response is appropriate it's efficient
and it's effective
now most but not all true cyber security
incidents tend to unfold as a crisis
they don't always deserve this level of
drama but that tends to occur mostly
because people's preparation and
execution of Incident Response
frameworks is pretty crap so what that
does is drive people to a panic response
or a crisis response and then starts to
drive their behaviors from there and
we'll look through some of those in the
moment often you'll see that incidents
are really a human or an organizational
issue but these incident responders will
try and find a technical solution for it
now our Christina Kitty presented a
great talk yesterday where she was
talking about - the interaction between
the human and the Machine and having a
human controlling a machine actually
provides a weakness I've seen instances
like this where during an incident you
have a human making a decision about
systems they make the wrong decision and
all of a sudden the incident gets a lot
worse so one recently which seemed very
simple and answered as benign that
actually made life
pretty difficult was an organization
were being hit with a fairly light
denial of service attack nothing out of
the ordinary the firewall admin decided
that what he would do would be blocked
that traffic on the firewall sure that
kind of makes sense until the firewall
state table filled up and the whole
thing was bought they lost all
connectivity so they went from having
sort of a reduction in connectivity and
some some delays in the way the website
was being presented to the whole thing
dropped now that's not because the
firewall did anything wrong the firewall
did exactly what it was meant to do but
was the decision made without checking
and analysis and sanity checking around
how to use the firewall that became the
problem so despite what the tech vendors
will tell you and I our specialist the
Luddite has a crucial role to play one
of the things that an incident manager
and Incident coordinator will do is
provide focus only solve the problem you
need to solve you don't need to go and
put out every single spot fire you just
need to pick the major one and solve
that first sanity checking as I said you
end up in situations where people make
decisions and you need to be the person
that is asking the questions around but
what will happen if we if we do that but
why do you think that is the appropriate
response
have you checked that with a peer that
kind of constant questioning while
somewhat painful at times is actually
very very useful in ensuring that
decisions are made are effective and
appropriate another one that I like to
call guarding the fan is basically being
the person that prevents the
hitting the set to kind of stand like
that and make sure that nothing sprays
beyond you and the last one is executive
distraction or executive communication
executives get very nervous when you
have an incident primarily because
they've lost control and often they are
out of their depth technically so your
role as an incident manager is to make
sure that they are getting enough
information that they understand that it
is in hand or if it's not in hand if it
needs to be escalated and ensuring that
basically they stay out of the way the
last thing you want is an executive
coming to help sorry I meant to say if
anyone's got questions as I go please
just sing out I'll try and repeat it for
the crowd I know we've got lunch the
answer runs going to race off so if
you've got questions fire them in as we
go okay so incident types so most
incidents will fall into sort of one or
more of these categories sometimes
they'll be combined and sometimes
they'll exist on their own now these are
intentionally simplistic but you'll have
a denial of service that can be both
technical and now what is becoming more
prevalent is a financial denial of
service where actually you smash someone
say AWS account until their credit card
runs out of funds things like that the
Faceman takeover of public sites
including social media you know you take
over someone's Twitter account and
profess their love the Katy Perry
something like that data breach and
exfiltration and malware realistically
fit for the typical organization you
really only need to have an incident
response plan for those four categories
that will give you enough to coordinate
responses get the right resources in
play and begin to address the issue you
see if you have twenty different
playbooks you probably have too many how
do you know which one of those twenty is
the right one for a given incident so
what what I'll be looking through today
is the CDC crisis continuum and as I
said it's a it's used for clinical
purposes for nurses and medical
specialists to identify where someone is
in a in a stage of crisis and what the
appropriate responses are so it talks
about different physiological responses
and behaviors during a crisis there's a
lot of things in there where if you
picture your manager or your executive
during a crisis there's a lot of things
in there that seemed eerily familiar so
this is the continuum you know you go
from stage one everything's generally
okay to stage four which is holy
everything is on fire we'll go through
each of those so a pre pre crisis is
really around being aware that crisis is
able to happen it is a possibility and
being prepared around that
as I said before having play books that
are really detailed generally doesn't
help your PlayBook is more than a sort
of an a4 double-sided piece of paper
that's probably too big in my opinion do
you know what normal looks like for a
lot of organizations that challenge for
them in performing an incident response
capability or an incident response is
that they don't know what normal looks
like they don't know when it's over
they need some reference to say this has
stopped being bad and we can now get
back to BA you the way you do that is to
identify thresholds and Canaries
a canary is a leading indicator that
something's up it's not a definitive we
are now in crisis it's a this looks a
bit weird we need to know something
about that an example might be you're an
Australian online business you only have
Australian customers and all of a sudden
you're getting a lot of patronage from
Russia that would be a canary that would
be that's a bit odd
not sure why that's the case we should
probably look into that a bit more a
threshold would be we normally get
10,000 connections and minute we now
have 15,000 you've now breached the
threshold that means you need to get
into action
some of the other things is executive
awareness getting executives aware of
what happens during a cyber incident and
what their role to play is and how they
can be involved in decision-making is
quite critical and the other one where
organisations often fall over during an
incident is a chain of command there's
no clear way that someone knows who they
should escalate up to to get a decision
made and if that person is not available
what is the next step are they able are
they unable to make a decision on that
behalf do they need to go find someone
else all of those sorts of things are
massively inhibiting during an incident
so these are the things that before the
crisis unfolds an organisation needs to
ensure that they have in place so normal
normally sort of you know there's a
normal stress and anxiety level
background is basically minor annoyances
that sort of thing this is generally
where the Canaries will come in things
are just kind of normal but every now
and again something is a bit bit off and
we're just
look into it usually what happens is
that organizations post incident look
back and go we should have known then
that was the sign we don't sell anything
in Russia of course but that's the point
where organizations are able to better
install capabilities either technical or
procedural to ensure that they are able
to identify those issues in future kane
norton present an awesome talk yesterday
he was talking about logging and
basically log everything you can logging
is critical the more you can get into
your data data stores the better your
chances are of identifying trends and
outliers that are meaningful in the in
the sense of an incident the other thing
is that being aware that business
thresholds will typically spike or break
before business one before technological
ones will a great example this is if
you're seeing if your organization's has
seen the state of account stuffing
attacks at the moment account lockout
and account lockout from a technological
perspective perfect you tried to
password three times you didn't get it
right
locked from a business perspective you
now have hundreds and hundreds and
thousands of customers who now can't get
access to their account because their
credentials were being attempted to be
breached that as a business threshold is
something that an IT team needs to be
aware of because that is absolutely a
leading indicator that something is up
so what else can you consider during
stage one cyber insurance Nena yes
yesterday today talked about cyber
insurance cyber insurance I I do get
asked relatively frequently about you
know is it a great idea or not I don't
know it's it's a very challenging area
you've got the question of cost if no
investment so if I don't pay ten grand
in in premiums every year and nothing
happens for five years I've saved 50
grand that's a really sort of
challenging argument to try and weigh up
against the benefit that I would point
out about cyber insurance however is
that there's a lot of additional
benefits that organizations rarely take
full advantage of things like having
access to advice
having access to pre-vetted resources
and having support during an incident
from the insurance perspective it is in
their absolute best interest to make
sure that you are as capable and as
geared up as possible to cope with an
incident so they offer a lot of advice
and support and resources and tools that
you can get access to as an insured
customer that you may not otherwise get
access to so if you are considering
insurance or you have cyber insurance I
would strongly recommend talking to your
insurer about what are these additional
benefits that you can get access to and
make full use of them so stage 2
heightened condition rapidly rapid heart
rate and respiration people might appear
lost or confused you might have managers
kind of walking the halls in circles not
quite sure what's going on voice may be
pitched higher or quaver when talking
that is a sure sign of a manager who
knows that they about to get a visit
from an exec and I can see a few smiles
here I think everyone recognizes that
that sort of mental image usually what
this is is something is behaving
strangely something's up
we don't quite know why we don't quite
know what but there is a problem one of
the big things that happens here is
customer service if you have like an
outward facing customer service line and
service desk internally they are the
Canaries for you in this in this case
because they are the ones that see the
business level issues and they may also
see the system level issues having a
really good relationship with both of
those teams is very critical for an
incident responder for a you know a
cyber manager of some description
because they are the ones that will let
you know that something's up and you
need to start doing a bit of digging the
other one is communications at this
point communications is quite critical
but you need to be clear about who you
tell and what you tell them if you don't
have anything definitive how do you
communicate internally that we think
something's a bit weird
so having some really clear guidance
around what do we communicate who do we
communicate it to and when do we do that
we'll make your life easier it may be
just about agreeing with the marketing
comms team that in the event that
something looks a bit odd we just send
out a
blanket email that says hey something
looks a bit odd we're looking into it
we'll come back to if we know anything
more that is usually sufficient to keep
people at bay and allow you to get into
the nitty-gritty of the issue the harder
one is what you tell your customers if
you don't have anything definitive to
say in general the rule of thumb is that
you better not to say it until you have
something meaningful and reliable that
you can go out publicly with the other
one is a regulator if you are subject to
some sort of regulatory body be aware
that at some point you are probably
going to have to tell them that
something's up being very clear about
what that is when you told them and what
you're expecting from them is going to
be quite crucial the relationship with
most regulators these days is in these
sorts of incidents is actually pretty
friendly and quite pragmatic regulators
in my experience generally like being
given a quick heads-up hey we think
there's something up we're seeing some
abnormal activity just letting you know
but we're on to it that is far better
than contacting them six weeks after the
fact saying we got owned and it was
terrible you the proactive nature of it
will serve you well in the long run
severe stress and anxiety something bad
has definitely happened this is getting
to the old moment person's
reasoning and capacity seriously
diminished what generally happens is
people start clutching at straws
everything looks like a Russian hacker
everything is bad that server has never
done that before all sorts of things
people just start blaming whatever they
can because they're trying to make sense
of the situation communication main
shoot include shouting swearing
argumentation and threats absolutely you
will see colleagues who work together
quite well normally all of a sudden buck
heads about what is the best course of
action is that an appropriate threshold
that sort of thing you'll also get a lot
of conflicting views on origin impact
the extent of the incident this sort of
thing from the Luddites perspective this
is your time to shine this is when you
get in there and you start showing your
stuff the big thing for at this point is
what do we know for sure you need to
keep repeating that question what can we
reliably prove
we can't reliably prove it where do we
get the data that will allow us to do
that as we go that kind of data and
questioning will allow you to separate
the wheat from the chaff and be able to
focus and ensure that you're only
solving the problem that needs to be
solved the other thing to bear in mind
here is generally mistakes made at this
stage tend to compound massively later
on if you get it wrong here you will
definitely have a bad day later on so
it's quite important to make sure that
you're not burning time chasing down
something that's you know a mistake or
someone's sure that that database has
been owned and it hasn't so you need to
be very precise and continually
challenging the sources of data and the
reliability of that data so some of the
common issues we see you know as the as
the crisis starts to escalate in
sufficient quantity and quality of data
as Keynes said yesterday log everything
inability to get decisions made is a big
one you if you are unable to get an
executive to make a decision often the
the decision will be made for them which
is not what you want you want to remain
in control of the situation as much as
possible there is a lot of noise there's
a lot of people trying to come to help
there's a lot of people adding their
sort of valuable input and opinion which
is generally not what you need so at
this point it's about reducing noise and
maximizing available data you can talk
about having too many shifts spoiling
the broth too many chiefs not enough
Indians too many managers and versus
people that actually do and know useful
stuff prioritization is a big one trying
to ensure that you know what is the most
important thing to fix from a business
perspective what do we care about and
what does success look like if you don't
understand what success or victory looks
like at this stage you're going to have
a hell of a time trying to figure out
what an appropriate response is and
again if we go back a few stages and we
talked about Canaries and threshold if
you've set Canaries and thresholds
really your aim should be to get them
back down if you said that you know
10,000 requests
minute is normal then your focus should
be getting it back down to 10,000
requests or at the very least
understanding why it has spiked Stage
four this is this is crisis everything
is now bad unbearable anxiety loss my
favorite one here is loss of cognitive
emotional and behavioral control I've
actually seen managers do the closest
thing to a table flip and just
completely panic that does happen
because people are generally not in
control the situation invariably they
don't understand the technical aspects
of it and generally it panic sets in
behaviors of a person in crisis are
erratic and unpredictable you will get
people make all sorts of strange
decisions that in the cold light of day
they cannot explain why they thought
that was a good idea but they will make
those decisions the role of the Luddite
is to ensure that that does not happen
your role is to guard the fan get the
right data sources challenge the data
and ensure that the right decisions are
being made at this stage everything is
on fire everything is bad you've got
problems everywhere you need to take a
step back facts versus theories going
back to the concept of what can we
reliably prove why can why is that
reliable where did we get the data from
what does it mean business priorities
are quite quite critical and it allows
you to determine what is the best course
of action often you will see
particularly coordinated attacks where
you may see an attack led off with the
denial of service which keeps you busy
meanwhile there has been a bridge and
data exfil something like that so from
your perspective you need to understand
at a business level what is the most
important thing so I can prioritize my
time and resources accordingly the other
thing about the role of the Luddite is
it is not your job to provide asses you
let the experts do their thing your role
is to provide the structure and dare I
say the environment that they have got
the best chance of getting you through
this incident with as few bruises as
possible you are you are there to make
sure that they are not distracted
and that they are focusing on the right
things
so during an incident and the bad guys
are often you know the least of your
concerns to them this is generally a
business transaction particularly if
it's an organized crime if you've got
something like a a denial of service
attack and you're being hit for bitcoins
or something like that
realistically you just want to make life
difficult enough for them that they go
elsewhere you don't need to be the best
you just need to not be the worst so you
you know you roll something like casada
out make their life really difficult and
expensive they go away and move on to
the next person There is obviously an
edge case here where you have people
that are either politically or
emotionally charged and this is
basically a personal thing for them at
that point really it's about determining
is that going to go away anytime soon
and how do we address that both at a
technological level and potentially at a
business level so who are the real bad
guys if during an incident the guys that
are attacking you or people I'm sorry
for the ladies if that folks they are
attacking you not not the baddies who
are they the enemy is within this is
Simon Simon works on Service Desk he has
seen sneakers hackers and wargames he is
a wannabe hacker he he dying to get
involved the thing to do with Simon is
to find a useful task for him you want
him out of the way and you want to
ensure that his time is being used
usefully for your purposes so with with
a a person like Simon generally I try
and get them researching similar attacks
elsewhere in the world and trying to get
some insight into what is the motivation
of the attacker people like Simon love
that role they want to be useful they
want to help and they want to show off
their skills great maximize that skill
set give them something to do this is
Bob Bob loves to tell you that this
incident is nothing compared to the
great database outage of 2014 this is
nothing he has seen it all he's been
with the company
since probably the Luddite era he
basically doesn't give a that
you're having a bad day and he wants to
tell you about how much worse he had it
when he was a kid the great thing about
Bob is that he has been here for so long
and he knows the organization so well he
knows where all the bodies are buried
his ability to understand the linkages
between different applications all of
the stuff that never gets documented in
an organization is great Bob's role for
you is to be that maven of the
organization the person you go to and go
hey Bob what would happen if I turned
off this database I bet you that that
documentation doesn't exist that it
lives in Bob's head bob is an extremely
useful individual but Bobby's not
someone that you want to be offering
advice you want Bob to be a person that
is a sounding board for ideas and
concepts this is chip or Chuck or one of
those two the names
he's a micromanager he really really
wants to be important and to be seen by
the executives as helping showing
leadership taking initiative whoops all
those sorts of things so he is probably
the most dangerous person in it as an
incident responded because he is the guy
that will make a decision and go round
you or talk to some of your resources
and basically distract people you can
fill his need to be that person who's
taking ownership and leadership of the
role by saying great Chuck chip buzz all
those sorts of good names your role is
now to communicate with the executives
every 15 minutes I want you to send an
email to the executives with where
things are up to thank you you have now
established a layer between you and the
executives you feel his emotional need
to be involved and you've given yourself
one less job to do this guy is really
important but you need to handle him
really carefully so they're not such bad
folks you know they want to help they
want to get involved and do the right
thing for the organization but
realistically they're going to make your
life pretty difficult so you need to
ensure that you're able to keep them at
bay and you
successfully for what you want the key
thing is to ensure that you recognize
what their emotional need is like what
is it that they want to do and find a
task that addressed that really quickly
one of the things particularly with chip
is ensuring that even if there are no
new updates in terms of that we don't
know anything else is providing that
upwards communication to management
saying we're still working on it we
don't have any answers yet we'll let you
know we'll come back to in every 15
minutes set a schedule meet it every
time if you miss that if you send an
email in the sixteenth minute you can
guarantee someone will come down and ask
what's happening send it at 14 minutes
that sort of thing is really crucial
it's a responsibility of the internet
manager the Luddite to identify and
delegate upwards to an incident owner
chip or Chuck or someone like that you
want to put a layer between you and the
executives to ensure that you can be
focused on doing what you need to do and
the executives can have a feeling that
this is under control often you want to
be able to liaise with the marketing
communications people as well and ensure
that your messaging is appropriate for
the executives I guarantee if you send
the executives an email saying we've
just loaded sticks in the taxi you're
going to get a very different response
to we're looking for signatures for
malware we think we'll be fine we're
working on it it seems like that a
really crucial to an executive all right
engaging an IR expert ideally you've
already done this generally probably not
this is usually about the time where I
get a phone call be very well aware of
responders bearing gifts
of appliances and licenses and a
responder invariably shouldn't need
additional kit or licenses or need to
sell you anything other than their time
and expertise if they are trying to sell
you a box be very careful be ready to
provide lots and lots of data and be
aware and be ready for the uncomfortable
silence when the respondent asks you do
you have this logged and you say no you
will get that awkward stare it's okay
that's kind of what we're expecting but
that is the type of question
that you're going to get so as much
information as you can have ready is
going to make the responders life a lot
easier the other thing is being clear
about what do you want them to provide
when the responder arrives what is it
that you need them to do do you want
them to provide attribution who is doing
this and why are they doing it do you
want them to try and figure out how bad
this is particularly if you've got a
data breach do you want them to be able
to tell you where all your data is gone
does that matter at this stage
resolution incident do you want someone
like myself to turn up and go it's
alright we're going to get this sorted I
need this sort of information and you
basically want someone to hold their
hand and get them through the incident
or is it something else entirely if you
if you are you know calling a cane or
like Ed Ferrell or someone like that
you're probably wanting a really
technical response you want someone to
dig into the detail and tell you exactly
what's going on that's fine but you need
to be aware of what you want out of the
engagement in order to ensure that you
actually get the right skill set and you
use it effectively so so the paranoid
legal privilege I am NOT a lawyer but
you probably should consider covering
your ass if you have reason to be
concerned about litigation as a result
of the incident you may want to consider
the manner in which you engage an
incident responder so any reports they
get issued to you by the IR organization
can be subpoenaed at a later date
through civil litigation class action
that sort of thing however if your IR
firm is engaged by your group counsel or
a legal firm for the purpose of
obtaining advice and all that sort of
thing it's able to be wrapped in legal
privilege and cannot be subpoena at a
later date now that said if you are
getting chased by like a pro or a Zeke
or someone like that you're going to
have a bad day there's not a lot you can
do about it
but if civil litigation is actually a
consideration for you there are some
ways that you can minimize the damage to
your organization crisis resolution in
the aftermath of a crisis person who
acted out may be ashamed of the outburst
we've all been there where a manager has
then felt kind of awkward that they said
said some dumb things and made some bad
decisions
the key thing at this point is to
identify at what point is the incident
become BAU how do we know that we are
back to business as usual who decides it
and who communicates it organizations
have often have a real problem where
they become addicted to the crisis
certainly we saw that behavior during
wanna cry where organizations were using
it as a way to smash in additional
patching and that sort of thing
which is great but if you become
addicted to the crisis it becomes very
difficult to make a determination about
what point the crisis is over and we're
back to business as usual the reason why
that is important is that you need to do
a post incident review post incident
reviews are absolutely critical and
ensuring the next time you have an
incident its impact is lessened as much
as possible
I really recommend having external
facilitation and analysis during the
post internal review doesn't necessarily
need to be done by a particularly
technical person but it needs to be
someone who can get all of the
stakeholders in a room and talk about
what did we do
what went well what didn't go well how
do we get better next time that kind of
knowledge and data and insight is
crucial and is generally overlooked and
undervalued so now what if you're
looking at this talking like okay well
you know what is what should I get out
of this what what do I do now at a bare
minimum you should have some playbooks
or run sheets those that's a snapshot of
one that's of a long security colony but
you know some general high-level
information that will provide some
structure around your internet response
capability this one cool I get uses this
thing up here usually that is who your
key contacts what are their phone
numbers and what is their role and a
series of key questions around what am i
doing what is my part to play in the
incident response the one down the
bottom there is really just a quick swim
lane around what do we do next
often as a as a first responder you're
not quite sure about what is your next
step
do I need to call come on first do i
reboot systems do i unplug something
what should I do
this is a very quick guidebook to ensure
that you
always know what's next or what decision
needs to be made a top drawer letter is
a great thing to have
it's basically a pre-written letter that
you would issue out to the public or to
a regulator or something like that
it's your it's your typical letter that
says something's bad has happened we're
looking into it we'll take the response
seriously that sort of thing
chain of command establishing a really
clear and reliable chain of command
around who can make what decisions when
and what happens if that person's away
you can guarantee an insolent will
happen at 2:00 a.m. on a Sunday or right
in the middle of the grand final or
something like that when all the people
you need are generally not available so
when that happens what are you enabled
to what decisions are you enabled to
make and if you're not who can you get
decisions made by have a have an ir
partner formal or informal it may just
be a matter of saying hey you know
random security company if we have an
incident we're going to call you guys or
it could be all the way through to
having a proper retainer depending on
your organizational appetite but you
need to know in the event that an issue
happens who are you going to call last
thing again logging logging is critical
log everything and that's it well so as
a Luddite you should feel like the the
Good Fairy of the East West which is
basically you're able to walk into an
incident scenario and say relax I got
this thank
looks like I've got about 5 minutes of
questions or couple minutes before lunch
but yeah anyone have any questions thank
you she's not the one to get squashed by
a house full of anyone nope all right
everyone get to know oh sorry got one
so as you explained that as an incident
manager your main role is to coordinate
between the experts and the executives
but who are we should take the decisions
in an incident so let's say you have a
group of experts and you're doing the
management and the coordination between
these guys and you had conflicting
opinions or decisions what would you do
in such a case where you have like the
technical experts with conflicting
opinions there are decisions to be made
yep so that happens quite a lot so the
question is really around what happens
when you get conflicting information who
makes the call the short answer is it
depends the longer answer is that's why
you have chain of command there should
be someone who is unable to make the
decision I often think that actually
making the wrong decision is still
better than making no decision because
by making the wrong decision you are
still in control of the situation even
if you get it wrong so generally it's
about making sure that the right people
have all been heard their inputs have
been provided and then the right person
is in the place to make the decision
about this is what we do next
often it is the incident manager it is
the person who's trying to run things is
that always the best person
realistically probably not but you're
the one that's sort of in the middle of
it and sometimes it's about gut instinct
and sometimes it's about making sure
that the data supports that anyone else
cool early mark for lunch oh sorry sir
sorry my bad