so I want to grab the door for me back
there perfect thank you hi everyone I'm
melody Lai I'm a pen test manager with
the government of Ontario and I'm really
just here to introduce our next speaker
to you this is Jacob Kalu's me and he's
going to talk to us about abusing voice
biometric solutions so take it away
Jacob hi so my topic for today is
penetration testing of voice biometrics
solution has anybody actually used voice
biometric authentication for your bank
or all right one person well it's
becoming popular now so before I start
I'm going to do a quick demo of how
powerful these little ferry microphone
is so only the volunteer from the back
rows I think like it's around 1015
meters to that point
well somebody from the back row just say
I need like random number one two three
four five my voice is my password can
you do it and my voice is my password
great so yeah this microphone wouldn't
even catch from five meters but you just
told us your password and you cannot
change it because that's your voice
right alright so yeah let me introduce
myself I'm a security consultant at the
missing link security in Sydney and I
recently moved from Europe where I was
basically doing application security
payment systems mostly for the financial
industry right and sometimes I do have
interesting projects this might be
bypassing J's based malware detection
men in the browser malware reverse
engineering of proprietary network
protocols some enterprise solutions like
be data based on Hadoop or H first and
currently voice biometrics so the
research started in back in 2015 when I
was testing few solutions and some of
them were implemented in IVR Channel
some of them in the mobile application
it was extremely interesting and easily
under scoped
now I
some more data some more tools and I
want to share it with you so I'm going
to present today's and get general
challenges when testing
non-deterministic systems based on some
artificial intelligence or machine
learning and the systematic approach to
pen testing voice biometrics solution in
short time I'm not saying the voice
biometric is a bad idea I'm not saying
it's a good idea either so yeah voice
biometrics becomes becomes popular so if
you look for voice biometrics patents on
Google there are around 1,000 patents
for generally voice biometrics
technology is it is it new
not really when I looked for risky
business number 10 which was in 2007 I
patrick was already mentioning voice
biometrics right and considering
security of those solutions so it's not
new how does it work
to be honest I don't know I'm doing a
black book stack so basically the
enrollment looks like you have to say my
voice is my password or a different
phrase three times and then during the
authentication you just say you usually
enter your customer ID or your mobile
app is already paired and then you say
my voice is my password and that's all
you need you don't need a password or or
any second factor right it should work
even even if you're fake giving you've
got a sore throat it should work even if
you get old and it should not work if
you record the voice and we play it so
the current state of voice biometrics is
that you're calling your IVR channel you
are calling your bank let's say or
you're using your mobile application you
try to say my voice use my password if
the system doesn't recognize your voice
it will be there will be a fall back to
a standard password and if you don't
know if you don't remember your standard
password it will be a fallback to the
IVR and the security questions so what's
your mother's maiden name if it doesn't
work it can still go to the branch right
so somebody call that blo one factor
because you can join multiple factors
and and it doesn't guarantee that that
without knowing your
without knowing your password you won't
be able to login right the system is as
secure as it as its weakest link so
currently nobody will focus on voice
biometrics because exploiting weak
passwords or security questions in the
IVR channel it's much easier than
hacking voice biometrics but it will
become popular last week actually BBC
did let's say a prank on HSBC voice
recognition technology and they
basically took twins and one of them
tried to spoof the other all right so
the basic parameter which describes the
quality of voice biometrics
is equal error rate which which is the
number which is a value of when the
false acceptance rate and false
rejection rate is the same so false
acceptance is of course if if I'm trying
to prove somebody's voice and it would
be a false acceptance and false
rejection if I'm trying to authenticate
as myself and we will be rejected right
and currently these values are around
from 1% to 2% maybe 4% so many sources
would say that biometric strength of
around 1% of this order of magnitude is
far too low it's it's basically basic
biometric strength and we're looking for
something like medium or high biometric
strength which the technology I think
it's not mature enough right now so here
are some public is some public data on
false rejection rate and false
acceptance rate from one of the vendors
and currently they're equal error rate
is around 1.5 so it's 1% a lot or not
basically all we need to do is let's say
we call one hundred voices and try those
hundred voices of one on one person
right all the other way
horizontal brute force so I'm using my
voice and I'm trying to authenticate as
each of you right I'll show you a quick
demo how easy is to build a database for
education and up this one I think it
goes there
thousands of any siblings in the
Caribbean welcome Sidney whoops
try to plant it a long time
hi I drink it from zero then we should
be here as well
because
hi I'm Jacob home security mm as many
some links security and welcome to a
survey for science physically going
around the Sydney and asking people if
they can say my voice is my password and
surprisingly I could really get a lot of
voice trials so first I asked if I could
do a survey nobody responded but then if
I introduce myself as University student
and I'm trying to do university research
everybody was keen on telling my voice
enjoy doing this university research I
need to ask people to say just to say my
voice is my password my is my possible
great way to get here great thanks guys
:
I forgot yeah so things I'll state my
voice inside pocket my voice is my heart
great thanks mate my voice is my
hospital it little louder
my boots great thanks a lot mate thank
you my voice is my voice my voice right
right which is a vector there were also
two other but yeah so it's quite easy to
build such a database and if you've got
such a database you've got the database
of around 100 voices they were almost
able to spoof a voice of everybody let's
go back to that slide so the horizontal
brute force is really possible
how do vendors calculate their equal
error rate so in ideal world they would
like to test 3000 participants and half
of them will make an enrolment and half
of them will try to spoof it so in
practice this is from the public
information on the vendor website this
is what they do they just take 300
participants and they make 5 to 7 normal
calls and 10 to 12 importer calls and
they claim the generally generally text
with less than 100 participants are
considered anecdotal at best right so
are you saying that these vendors are
introducing innovative modern technology
and
they cannot simply take all of their
recorded voices and automatically
cross-check them all and they have to do
actually recalls mildly just can
cross-check them all in a database
they've got WAV files so the real
problem with the voice biometrics is
that there is a thing called central
limit theorem if we take a voice it of
course for voice biometrics purposes the
voice has 20 or 30 parameters right
let's take one parameter let's take a
peak pitch of the voice right if we take
the whole population a lot of people
have average peak pitch with a small
number of people will have a low peak
pitch and a small number of people who
have high big pitch right if this is how
they calculate the equal error rate
let's say Morgan Freeman will try in
their test will try to impersonate
further right this doesn't make sense
in real-world scenario Morgan Freeman
will will try to impersonate only three
months funnily so this is the problem if
if the attacker is able to choose the
voices which he's using for spoofing in
a way that he is able to not take the
whole population but just let's say 10%
of the population he's able to increase
the false acceptance rate not from 1% to
let's say 20% and this is the the key of
this research that you don't need a lot
of voices or a lot of complicated
technology rocket science to spoof voice
biometrics
it's basically math math math switches
against them so yeah of course they can
keep constant threshold which means that
a high big pitch spoofer will we be able
to impersonate only few people but an
average peak pitch will be able to spoof
a lot of people and they can keep a
constant constant force acceptance right
but in both cases it is bad so yeah this
is funny gender does matter there are
completely different voice
characteristics for males and females
and or different algorithmic metrics and
or different attacks for males and
females fine let's do a quick threat
modeling on voice on Penta
voice biometrics so we have effect on
the enrollment but it basically requires
that you can men in the middle or recall
somebody during the enrollment it's
quite complicated then we have
authentication bypass we're going to
focus on that information disclosure so
there are many so let's say in one bank
there are thousands of voices one
hundred thousands of voices what happens
if these database leaks what happens if
you can grab those voices right if there
are keeping the original voices not the
voice print sort of like that and
denial-of-service so we'll try to abuse
the availability of the system right
what about the authentication by part
there are some vendor approved scenarios
which they accept and this is basically
hiring spoof errs and sometimes
horizontal brute-force that's what
they're prepared for what else well
audio codec exploitation wouldn't it be
cool to whistle some music and you will
get a shell mobile ipi pen test so if
the solution is integrated in the mobile
application you can try to do a
man-in-the-middle there you can try to
exploit the web service or api which is
on the server side and you can abuse the
process and abusing the process is also
the key to high voice biometrics I'll
show it in a second you can just pitched
into this and I hope you didn't expected
that basically there there are heaps of
companies Adobe just did the volkl
product there is Google Wave net and
there is Lyrebird these are products
which allow us to record
somebody's voice just for a few minutes
and then synthesize this voice just like
any sentence saying any sentence this is
cool but this is basically what requires
years of research they're hiring the
best voice recognition scientist I'm
going to show you what can do a security
consultant pen tester which I am mostly
focused on application security on web
application on embedded software on
mobile applications but what can I do
with really simple knowledge about voice
synthesis and we can do the replay
recording and this will be the focus on
this presentation we'll try to record
somebody and then to replay from the
recording modifying the
a little bit so this isn't doesn't
recognize it's a replay there is also a
Snickers attack
so basically recording somebody's voice
saying different words and reordering
them so that it creates anybody who's
saying the Snickers film from 1984 right
okay so there is also one more threat
IOT so for example there were these
cloud pets are dolls connected to the
Internet
somebody hacked them it was actually I
think MongoDB database exposed on the
public server and this voice recorded
from mostly this was kids voices
recorded they leaked what happened what
would happen if in the background will
be some parents saying my voice is my
password authenticated to their online
banking one once it gets popular and
there is also all Wells telescreen
implementation by CIA and Samsung so
basically they they hacked smart Samsung
Smart TVs to recode people silently all
right so now hacking voice biometrics
what do we need to do the target is a
mobile a mobile integration mobile app
integration of voice biometrics IVR
integration of voice biometrics and they
both claim that there is a replay attack
detection so we need to first gather the
voice do some vocal isolation then we
need to fold it so that we identified
the thresholds of replay detection and
change it enough and then we need to do
impersonation so ultimate the request
you know called a thousand times to five
year nobody will do it manually so how
good is a good microphone for the
initial research I was using Nexus 5 and
the standard journalist microphone which
is Sony ECM for the research also but
few about few other microphones are the
microphone this is non directional
microphone now it's directional
it's actually quite surprisingly
well-liked good at gathering bosses this
is this is actually this one is the rode
videomic and you can actually hire rent
rode ntg-2 on for 700 which is worth
$700 you could rent it for $40 a day and
I'm trying to contact some companies
which record audio at football stadiums
and they're using this clever mic worth
3,000 is basically a parabolic 26 inches
microphone and recording with that that
would be cold right so let's do vocal
extraction
we've got voice trails record it from 5
meters with this microphone if we just
replay them to the system it will not
catch the voice because the voice was so
not so loud right so we need to amplify
the voice by using few techniques
basically really basic techniques in
other city by isolating the voice on
redacting the noise some high and
low-pass filters amplification adding
some leged nose noise and the parameters
I wouldn't present any parameters
because it basically defers firs parody
voice biometrics ocean so yeah some
vendors claim that this is cooperated
because if I can record somebody from 5
meters there is a cooperation I don't
see much cooperation there and some
solutions rely on noise so if you replay
the voice and the voice is changed but
the noise is not changed it will detect
a replay right so this is how it's not
so easy
this is the recording from two meters
and this you can see on the catch by
solution and this is with vocalization
either Y or holding this and the same we
can do with five meters
and vocal isolation and this is enough
to pass to the voice biometric system
alright so we did some voice recording
with the vocal isolation now we need to
fast the voice to intensify the
thresholds what are the thresholds
basically let's say this is the original
recording if we modify voice just a
little bit there is a replay attack
detected tarish alt there is a threshold
for a correct voice authentication
because it has to accept situations
where somebody has a sore throat or is
it just bad day right and there is some
third small threshold when the system is
unsure and of course all the rest is
incorrect so what we are trying to do is
we are trying to modify the voice so
that it fits the correct threshold but
not replayed detected all right
so for filing the voice I use socks
that's a standard UNIX package linear
functions are perfect for bypassing grid
plate detection because it should affect
the replay but it should not affect the
biometrics which is rocket science
they're working on not on wavelength or
working on a spectrum and basically they
claim that changing pitch changing speed
wouldn't affect both authentication it
is true it won't but it will affect the
reproduction so I came up with five
different modifications free levels of
noise reduction 13 levels of changing
the pitch nine levels of changing the
speed then the random pauses and from
background points when you multiply how
many cases we've got here this is 38,000
recordings it's almost two days of
conference two days of out there so what
we need to do is choose which will be
the best and we can try maybe 100 maybe
300 I'll just quickly show you oh I
forgot about this so this is true that
after a few days of it that moved after
a few days your colleagues will ask you
to work from home I'll show you in a
second why and after a week you will
answer your phone
my voice is my password why because of
death the assessment was one of them was
I think 15 days the second was 12 days
for 12 days you're doing authentication
my voice is my password authentication
yeah another one authentication my voice
is my password authentication my voice
is my password yeah so this is this is
quite uh it becomes complicating all
right so I came up with this solution of
reducing the number or the number of
calls which we have to do basically
38,000 recording comes from multiplying
all these different levels of parameters
changing the parameters right I came up
with the solution that if for example
the system will not accept changing the
voice let's say 20% of the pitch it will
not accept any other combination of 25%
and any other combination of the rest of
the parameters right so what we need to
do is invite the results maximum
thresholds for separately for each
parameter this is maximum 50 trials then
we did remind the maximum threshold for
a separate parameter change so let's say
the system will accept 15 percent of the
pitch change then we choose three levels
it would be 15% 7.5% and zero will have
three levels of change for each of five
parameters this is just 15 files right
then we do combinations of these
parameters at three levels only on the
maximum threshold for a separate
parameter and we try to join them
together now we multiply only five
parameters at three levels which is
around 250 trials this is doable and
once the system responds if it was
accepted or not we choose the most
success
trials and with replay detection on we
try to trash the selected thresholds and
select few bad values for the basically
for the vulnerability so in the end the
vulnerability should be well if you
change the speed by this value the pitch
by this value and you add this kind of
noise the system should have more or
less stable vulnerability to accept
those four trials even though we play
alright if we cannot act ask the vendor
to turn off the replaced action we can
just really time this takes time but if
it's easy enough so a recognizance how
this works so we have the enrollment
right and then I figured out that there
are many phrases which the the vendors
implement in in their solution so
sometimes it's my voice is my password
sometimes it's signed me into the XYZ
bank and my name is ABC and my voice is
my password can anyone see a problem of
of the how the choice of the phrase
affect the security anybody all right
so let's say at one bank the dead phrase
is my voice is my password and in the
second bank as well if somebody is able
to compromise the first system most
probably you'll be able to leak download
The Voice trials and try them basically
try them on a second in the second Bank
right so this is not unique per client
enter provider sign me into the XYZ Bank
is a little bit better but still you can
do a horizontal brute-force and my name
is ABC and my voice is my password it's
still a data leak risk so so it can
happen that you can steal somebody's
voice trials from one system and try it
in another one what would be the best
one the best one would be my name is ABC
and egg at XYZ Bank my voice is my
password from the functional point of
view nobody would accept it so then in
the IVR channel we need to call the info
line dial the customer ID on the utmsu
TMF owns and play the phrase the system
says that either it is a success or it's
incorrect
or replay detected and then end the call
or the system is not sure and asks to
repeat and then there is an
authentication mobile app and I have to
admit that mobile application
integrations are much more secure simply
because the apps are already paired with
accounts so the horizontal brute force
is not possible and there are the rules
for working for the phrases are the same
so it turns out that there are a lot of
challenges if if I'm testing a system
and there is an SQL injection III put a
payload I get a response and I'm 110
sure that the system is vulnerable right
the same with our see what happens here
I submit a vulnerability and the vendor
says now you made a weak enrollment and
actually one of the vendors are detects
weak enrollments and it claims that
there at the end of them so you need to
test many times and even if you find a
vulnerability you have to confirm it on
using different enrollments multiple
enrollments right there are also some
machine learning mechanisms right so the
more proper identifications are made in
in months time the system is more sure
about the voice right all right so of
course we try to repeat the attack many
times but actually the vulnerability if
the easter vulnerability is possible to
exploit only one time that's good enough
so a second challenge we create an
account we enroll our voice and it's
only me I'm testing it I'm trying to
open a second account with my voice and
the question is is it possible maybe we
need more voices third challenge I
create the account I transform the voice
with some function and it works
sorry in the first case it doesn't work
so it says that it's not your voice but
after I changed another voice of my
colleague with that transformation the
system accepts it so we need even more
voices because some some thresholds some
changes may work only for specific
voices not for all of them right
next challenge so we've got a light
modification it will be small F and
strong modification first we we send the
light modification the system detects
the replay because it doesn't differ
much from the original recording then we
part the strong modification and the
system detects the replay because it
doesn't differ much from the light
modification which was supplied a minute
before but if we supplied the strong
notification first time it would be it
would be a success so the previous
authentications affects the future ones
because there is a database of
recordings so that the system is able to
do replay detection right so if it's
possible try to ask the vendor to turn
off the replayed the learning mode so
that you are able to test the results
separately all right the next one oh
this is actually good this was actually
reported as a Boomer ability so we
created an account we transport the
voice we unroll it we transform the
voice with some function we pass the
modification and the system said I'm
unsure please repeat and in the same
call the system asks please say one more
time and you were saying one more time
the system is still unsure but during
the third fry in the same call the
system will accept it why because simply
to increase the false rejection rate the
vendors decided to make life a little
bit easier in the first try and if
somebody's trying my voice is my
passwords really then it will try it a
little bit lower than thresholds and
allow more voice trials to accept why so
different trials during one call so in
some solutions it's worth to attack in a
third time all right the last challenge
so we've got a live modification and
from clarification we pass the strong
modification then we try the live
multiplication many many many times it's
always a failure and then we try to
repeat the first scenario with the
Strongs modification but it doesn't work
and it's not the replay the system says
it's incorrect why because there may be
a different threshold not during one
call but for one user in general during
many calls and this is basically a
mechanism something like a brute-force
detection so we have to identify
thresholds on your account
and then confirm the vulnerabilities on
new users oh one more so we passed the
recording it's a success I mention it we
modify the vocal but we leave the same
noise and the system can detect the
replay based on the noise itself that's
why we also change the noise each noise
has some characteristics actually I've
heard that like some nation-states
secret services they're actually from
the videos on the internet they're able
to locate people based on some noise in
the background right so they it may
happen that the detect all right after
bypassing all these challenges and and
supplying those voice trials it turns
out that your I was able to do a more or
less stable replay attack detected by
pass in a standard environment the
environment was standard so like the
thresholds were set to normal of course
they've got they've got basically
different thresholds they can set that
the system is super tight but then the
false rejection rate will be high or
they can set the system will be loose
and the false acceptance will be high
all right the meta their environment was
medium-large
the process was hacked so like they'll
say the modifications were sent in last
step it was more or less gray box so we
were allowed to change few things and
there was no IDs so the we didn't need
we didn't need to use multiple voices
like many voices and re-enroll each time
so little bit easier task but still
definitely you're able to replay this
process and bypass I think any voice
biometric with 1% equal error rate ok so
the last step of the of hacking voice
biometrics or pen testing them is
impersonation if I was about to call IV
air 100 times or 300 times in in 10 days
time it will be impossible to win
ultimatum I use Skype for PI it was not
perfect not not really stable not really
automated scheduled PI's the library
which basically allows the right to
scripts in Python and turn on this kibe
window which basically in newer versions
of skybirds it's complicated it's good
enough it's easy to integrate but
currently
out-out suggest using gather avoid
social and there was a big end this
variable noise in in describe in the
Skype connections but is it bad or is it
good it basically works at adding a
different level of noise which we are
already doing during the voice fighting
crime
so another VoIP solution we can also
like develop some mobile app user jack
jack cable cable and reprogram the audio
input and output I realize I used Skype
for pie and I use the posh blood Python
plus public control so I turned off my
physical microphone I relate the Aldea
output to disk out audio input and the
other way so out the output from Skype
was I supplied to the microphone
and in this case I was able by supplying
a comment a play I'll basically play a
recording to the Skype and a record we
collect from Skype what is to detect
what this is what was the response
dialing the DTMF tones that's quite easy
basically you have to generate you wav
files that's that's interesting so you
have to collect the responses and you
can use of course some API if you've got
API access that perfect like mobile
application that's perfect but what if
what if not you based on the system
saying authentication rejected
authentication accepted you have to say
what happened so you can do some speech
recognition actually you can use some
free or non free voice recognition
technologies like Google Cloud or Amazon
but I did a simple response length
analyzer trick so I came up that
different responses have different
lengths so authentication rejected was
the shortest one like two seconds then
let's say three seconds and four seconds
one comment in socks allowed to cut the
noise and basically calculate how long
was the server response and based on
that I basically chose what was the
system response all right and this is
there's a set of comments to calculate
the length which is he alright so the
effect process we've got all the tools
we've got
the ideas and voiced files so we just
need to take the next file fat voice
print call the number that DTMF tones
play this voice print collect the
response if the response is let's say
unsure please repeat we need to decide
which voice print and end the call
easy mobile applications as I said
they're a little bit more secure because
the application is already paired with
the account but there's a lot of
vulnerabilities in mobile API so for
example in this case the audio was sent
in a multi-part post replay and there
was a second parameter called F and F
was 44,000 what can it be
Oh frequency so there was a - 2 megabyte
file limit but if you passed F is 1 F
equals 1 the system tried to I don't
know create WAV file or plate is
recording using 1 Hertz frequency which
basically does the system because 1
Hertz frequency on 2 megabyte file was
thousands of hours so yeah often voice
biometrics are implemented as a separate
box the box is developed by the third
party so we don't control the software
development lifecycle their security
HTTP request often have a different end
point so the security of these end
points cipher suit choice or basically a
man-in-the-middle attack is possible
because the solution may not detect
verify the certificate so I suggest that
the voice identification sessions should
be distinguished in the let's say online
banking that this session was
authenticated using voice so let's allow
this guy only make wire transfers to the
trusted beneficiaries not to all all
right the summary I always repeat that a
pen test without threat modeling is bug
bounty hunting and really if you do a
proper threat modeling on these
solutions you are able to find
vulnerabilities just during the
recognition space without touching the
cold or touching the solution yeah
analyze the business assumptions so when
the thresholds are changed try to pick
the
test scenarios ask to turn off the
learning mode ask to turn off replay
section to identify to result faster
identified results on one account and
attack the other that's basically to
bypass the learning mode do test with
noise cancellation and without because
some of the solutions as I said may
detect those replay that replay of of
the noise and yeah as I said it's not a
bad idea it's not a good idea either
but it should be tested thoroughly and
the final thought while solutions
integrated mobile apps require to be
paired aware does not that's currently
with current maturity level of science
behind voice biometrics
I'll suggest first implementing this in
mobile apps and maybe then moving this
to idea alright I am working on the Noah
cheat sheets which will define the
security requirements for voice
biometrics oceans if you know any
vendors or if you are a buyer of such
solutions I'll be happy to have a chat
the draft is not available anywhere yet
because I'm trying to cooperate with
vendors as well basically this
presentation they wouldn't like this
presentation to be publicly available
right this is basically affecting their
business right so I'm trying to work
with them to come up with security
requirements which are acceptable from
security consultant point of view and
their point of view so what is doable if
you're if you're interested in any help
just let me know all right cold will be
soon at my github you can follow me on
Twitter and if you need any materials or
this presentation just drop me an email
thank you thanks Jacob we're about out
of time so I think you said if people
have questions you're around - yeah I'll
be here opportunity yeah okay I just
want to present you with this also we're
officers 2017 nice quickly an
appreciation of you coming to speak
perfect um another round of applause
please
so we have an hour break for lunch right
now from 12 20 to 120 and then if you
come back here after Andrew Jamison
talking about biometrics as well
so please don't forget to rate those
sessions on your apps if you have them
and have a good lunch