and it needs to stop so just so you're
aware I've trusted me I have had a
million mentos over the last day and a
half this is unacceptable
and next presenter though is going to be
Kate Pierce I'm not going to do an intro
I think she's going to do a great
introduction for herself but she's going
to be talking on the balkanization of
security community please welcome Kate
[Applause]
alright so those of you who have seen me
before over here about five minutes ago
will know as I said I do not really need
amplification I've got this usual
starting slide about me Who am I
Kate dear if you wish to yell at me
complain at me tell me I'm wrong
whatever on Twitter
there you go I work for Cisco however as
to a standard mega Corp disclaimer or
using my own now this is also a
different talk to what I normally do it
because I normally do technical talks I
normally talk about specific technical
things um yes they're all technical
maybe not last one we were singing about
exploits though so yes the stuff I've
I've done in the past has been multi
pass filter evasion to go straight
through network defenses by fragmenting
across different connections are eighty
to be too and quick new network
protocols that walk straight through old
network protection my recent stuff is on
guest lighting for defense where I
present at a KERS with fake
vulnerabilities but I presume each
attacker with a different set so that
when they present them to their friend
their friends like throw that that
doesn't work and I missed with their
sense of reality and the hacker chorus
is something which I still can't believe
happens there are however witnesses in
the audience when I keynote it at unrest
Khan and Melbourne last year somehow we
got the entire 200 250 person audience
singing sober to the tune of Amazing
Grace about exploiting things it was
hilarious and I lost my place and one of
the people in the audience here who I
will not point out took over and
continued leading yeah I tend to be very
high-energy as you've already picked up
but I also feel strongly about inclusion
in our industry and doing different
things different ways rather than
reinforcing our echo chamber yellow
people in print honor people remember it
that's all you remember about me
remember the yellow then when I walk
around and this would be like that's
that loud person also lately I've been
working on b-sides Wellington same time
of year when the late Kiwi con was and
we really would like in ER any
submissions it would be great build the
community but really what am I here to
talk to them see you're here to talk
about small differences and the big
difference they make the small
differences we have between our
different communities when they're
different people and how we let them
sort of divide up so let's take take
something that's well understood let's
go with film and literature okay so
you've got fiction and nonfiction pretty
simple pretty obvious let's break that
down a bit let's dive into fiction what
do we have inside section we have a few
different things this is just a subset
that I R so from the Wikipedia page
let's dive into one of them let's dive
into science fiction
okay what about erm what we got in there
oh look we have a few more genres okay
so with multiple levels down and we keep
diving we drive into space it continues
we get more breakdown and then under
each of them we get some familiar
friends Star Wars Star Trek do not mix
them up do not mess them up on this
crowd you will suffer it'll be hilarious
now this is really as far as the rest of
the world is concerned a tiny difference
but we're not the rest of the world oh
no we're not even close
millions of people care millions of
people write articles millions of people
read articles yeah small differences big
difference and I'm not saying that they
don't matter because if I say that they
don't matter I may not make it out of
here alive and I don't know which of
those sets of fans gives me more
or maybe it doesn't matter but those
small differences in a big difference
they make least to a couple of takeaways
from from my opening here small
differences really do make a big
difference soak up to that four times so
far let's make it up small differences
make a big difference especially when
humans are involved we like dividing
ourselves we like understanding what we
are not and you know there's been many
many different memes about this this is
one that I came across and read it
recently and there are many more had
different people in different groups
within technology communities view each
other this is a common meme what my
friends think I do what my parents think
I do or professionals think I do in this
case what the NSA thinks they do what I
think I do and what I actually do
the fact is irrespective of what each
group thinks they are doing the same
thing is occurring
it's about perspective it's about
differences and why am I talking about
this what motivated this well first of
all I do a lot of international
consulting and in that I travel and do
the customers with different cultures
different verticals different everything
and every one of them is different every
one of them has its own culture its own
culture shock if you will this is not
just countries this is companies so it's
not just company this is verticals
this is teams within them and then I
came back to New Zealand I went to all
of the things because that's what I do a
good event lead up that meet up day to
be in their conference their thing and
why am I here again I don't know but I'm
here and what I keep finding is that
that fragmented that I don't see a lot
of people at more than a couple of the
things everybody is going to the thing
with I feel comfortable where they feel
they belong and yet not many and
multiple things and people are just not
mingling across communities and as a
result of that I get hilarious
conversations at one event complaining
about another group that they don't
actually talk to and Arthur gets painful
because a lot of people talk about
cooperation and working together but not
me
actually do it so we talked a Tod suit
of course about this united we stand
which you know I'm going to throw out
there for no reason who is we
what do we invite United what are we
mean by stand well I don't know I've
been served into that that seems like
way too much work but that was another
thing motivated this the theme of this
year's conference how do we work
together to achieve our common goals so
when I'm doing research into the
psychology of this stuff and how it will
work I come across a few phrases and I
hear there's quite a bit this one should
look familiar
I wish other people would recognize the
authority of my group okay what about my
group is extraordinary
where ever we heard that before you know
I won't be happy until my group gets the
recognition it deserves you know we
really deserve this and I insist that we
get that recognition but but no one
understands that we don't get that
recognition and no one else is how
important we are in all this is
collective narcissism these are quotes
from collective narcissism entry because
as groups we start to define ourselves
and complain in these consistent ways
it's just human nature collective
narcissism but I've heard every one of
those phrases at different events from
different people but as I say it's um
it's not our fault it's just the way
that communities work and that's an
earthquake jerk which Australians
weren't really geared so I'll move on
people are not really how about a phrase
let's restart people are good at
separating into groups good at defining
who we are they're really good at that
and those are good at defining how other
people are like if there's one thing
that humans can do without help it's
theft and sometimes what you define your
own group to be and what someone else
defines your group to be don't agree and
that's where it gets really messy
and that's where a concept like the
charged word that I used in the title of
this talk like vulcanization Metis
organization happened as a result of
various larger empires falling apart and
the people on at the lower levels trying
to find identity and to Scrabble for
that identity and remember every one of
these changes probably involves a lot of
conflict a lot of death and harm this is
what happens when you're high level and
you're low level like entity don't agree
when the groups you think you belong to
in the groups who actually belong to
break up and it just keeps going and
this is the wage human societies keep
doing it and this happens at large scale
but it also happens at smaller scale and
as I said that is a charged term at the
pejorative term and I'm not going to use
it for the rest of this talk however
people generally know what it means
the reason it's a pejorative term is
because it's not there's nothing
Balkan about fragmentation that's just
the modern contemporary example because
a few one other examples asked the u.s.
Society austro-hungarian Empire British
Empire Ottoman Empire things break up
there's nothing to do with the Balkans
that's just a fragmentation when
external and internal groups don't agree
and yet I can use the word fragmentation
from here on so let's do that a phrase
that many will have heard one person's
freedom fighter is another person's
rebel it's the same within our
communities one person's are idealistic
thought-leader another person's sellout
and that builds again and again and
again or as I've got here one person's
sellout is another person's thought
leader is another person's change maker
it's all about perspective the
fragmenting isn't always bad sometimes
it's good there's good and is bad and
between those so a good one you get to
decide your own destiny but at the same
time they can cost you from fighting
from lost shared opportunities so we
need to work together we need to stand
united
and we fragment for various reasons many
of them historical as I gave there with
the various empires in the various
country but there are other reasons too
and a key one is a source ative mixing
what this is in short is that like is
attracted to like or like is biased to
like we tend to associate with those
with whom it is most efficient to
communicate with and to work with and
they tend to be the most like us now
this is yes like like me is stickier
than not like me but this is not just a
human thing this is you see this in
chemistry and biology and computer
networks you see this in all sorts of
places this is just a characteristic of
adaptive systems and when you see this a
sort of mixing are and humans it has a
different name for muffle E or again
because why would I write my own
definitions when Wikipedia has them I do
have other sources but the Wikipedia
rounds are the easiest aside because
they're that long not that long
and yet it's about the common
characteristics and this is a key thing
to be aware of especially with yourself
as an example biases and there are lots
of them are background or context where
do you come from what was your path to
where you are your goals are you going
for risk or compliance what company do
you work for what's your experience your
management level your technologies your
country your culture and more we like
breaking yourself down we like
associating with those who hit the
labels we associate with ourselves but
and I'm going to get to an industry
point here eventually we have different
incentives we have different goals we
have different perspectives and dealing
with not like me is a lot harder than
dealing with like me and then we get to
the issue of trust groups trust groups I
want to be least diverse
types of organization you will ever find
particularly those with batching because
they tend to take the sort of
association the sort of mixing and they
magnify it they can become echo chambers
very quickly if they are not careful and
that might be relevant for this
community make sure that you go and you
expose yourself to different groups
because the transcripts breed there that
similarity and how many diverse trust
groups you actually know whatever metric
you want but let's start doing what I
said was bad earlier and defining
identities on others because I didn't
learn from colonialism so when I talk
about security what do I mean what is
security is about preventing detecting
responding recovering managing managing
the probability like impact on or chance
of it actually happen in the first place
or the by the impact what do we mean
when we say security or security person
it's messy but what is a security person
is that a builder or a breaker a debtor
defender or perhaps a hunter and a
sister when I got hunted twice a
repairer an operator a regulator an
enforcer they're all these different
labels you can apply yourself now the
trick is more than one of these may
apply to you yeah why not
so let's quickly go through these as I
go through each label put up your hand
if you believe it applies to you and
look around and see if the people around
you would apply that label and whether
you would apply it to them so in this
room thinks of themselves as a builder
look around people look around mm-hmm
alright who thinks of themselves as a
breaker all right what about defenders
I'd expect that in this crowd hunters
yeah pure them Assessors
yep ina scripts ii hunter repairers or
fixes fewer name as well okay operators
regulators enforces now did many people
look around and see people associating
with things that you didn't think they
thought of themselves as or did you find
yourself having to think does this apply
to me because the more we use these
labels and always fragment it gets
interesting and if we define these
communities whether it's by goal or by
activity or vertical or mechanism or
education or philosophy or experience or
whatever it is we get different things
look at this we've fun and I'm not
actually to go through all of these but
these are some of the many different
ways different dimensions that you can
start breaking down security people some
of them this is not exactly a full
taxonomy and every one of them applies
to a different person in a different
combination but all too often we like
are those hackers or are those you know
those those are those compliance box
stickers or whatever pejorative term we
want to use because twice labels matter
particularly labels for other people but
the groups that I'm going to use I'm not
going to use any that's way to me and
I'll stop tapping that I'm going to
simplify this down I'm going to use a
far smaller number of groups start with
academic public private and independent
okay and then under them you know you've
got your teachers researchers under your
academics and the public you've got your
military your intelligence
regulators law enforcement and more and
each of these you've got more and more
and more different types of people but
I'm not going to use all of these I
clamped them up again something to do
clone them let's start breaking them
down into a different text on ax me
you're going to record in it your public
your private
and you're independent and I'm going to
throw those ones from earlier it's going
to matter under each of them what does
it go public you can have in a
mission-driven or protection driven
private you can have money driven or
membership driven and under independent
you've got this sort of weird
combination of curious and ideological
and chaotic and yes I did consider
mapping against the DMV matrices it
didn't quite work or rather there were
too many of them in the one box and yet
we start placing all of these on there
but I'm not going to throw that many
groups to you I'm just simplifying so
I've got academics which I'm going to
find as those who are teach or do
disciplined research military or
intelligence those who a mission-driven
enforces those who are protection or
regulation driven business those who are
driven by profit loss and missing
brackets industry which is the
membership driven organizations you'll
be familiar with them they might be one
around here and tracted how do you group
independent people how do you herd cats
well I call them wild cards those you're
never quite sure what you get but a key
point of this talk in the end this is
fun I love teaching people concepts like
this myself it's into sectionalism every
person has a whole lot of different
things that tie into their identity and
if you clump them into too granular a
group you're actually not talking about
a person you're talking at a caricature
and you're trying to interact what the
person doesn't exist and most of the
time that's going to annoy them and yeah
like how 1990s is that but there is a
continuous point coming I would argue
that security is not a high status
position and most organizations we
pretend it is most organizations do not
gladly listen to us they do not gladly
follow up because we're difficult to
deal with we say no a lot
and yeah that status isn't that high and
in practice it's often X even lower than
it it's professed to be now this is
improving you look at something like
we're the CIS Oh reports to that is
changing over time that is moving up the
org structure but if you don't believe
security was low status at some point
what comments that ceases to be
reporting five or six levels down that's
not a high status
that's alecky and that makes it hard
because if we can't get status within
organizations often we'll try and get it
within our own communities or within our
own cake companies horizontally it's
just a fumbling but yeah and getting
that status is hard because we tell
ourselves it is high status we tell
ourselves that it's you know it's a
great job it's great to be in but often
that's really really hard often we're at
the coalface
only they've taken epic extras away and
given us like sticks and then the sex or
too expensive so they're replacing with
toothpicks okay find the toothpicks not
very good I'll give your middle to it to
have fun but it's okay because we really
respected professionals and our
organizations rely on us often not so
much because that's just the way
business and the world works so we need
to work with each other that's how you
make that change because you know at
least we were right it sounds like the
stuff at the start and it's difficult
and I as a security practitioner say
this but one of the reasons we are
highly paid is not because the best
potatoes it's because the risk of not
having us it's very expensive even if we
don't actually do anything good doesn't
matter where they measure our outcome if
the accusations will you have no
security team you're going to get hit a
lot harder than if you have a bad one or
if you have an ADD resourced one and
then that works you know if we want to
I've gone to things where they tell
people go into it make change and
sometimes we can but we're particularly
when you're in an organization you're
struggling to make the best with the
things
have available if your consultant you go
in you break and you leave that doesn't
make change either we make change over
long periods of time not because of our
status skip that one
so yeah everyone's having a different
last everybody else and just because
they don't act like you doesn't mean
they are wrong and this is a hard one
because sometimes from your perspective
they are wrong and if they were in your
job that would be the wrong choice but
they're living their different life and
those are not wrongs they don't act like
you expect and if they don't act
according to your knowledge and
priorities again it's this theory of
mind and this is one of the key things I
want to get across to you is there are
certain things each of those groups do
did it really get to the others what are
the things they complain about what are
the flow path what does the culture
shock because that's what this is and if
I'm telling you to go to these different
events what if you used to hang around
with sealable and then you walk into a
hacker con you're going to be
uncomfortable and culture shock is going
to clip in I love abusing animation
sometimes this disorientation we get
this from the Sun familiarity the
feeling of disorientation experienced by
someone when they are suddenly subjected
to unfamiliar culture unfamiliar way of
life in an unfamiliar set of attitudes
that is what we get when we try and work
with others and that culture shock is
not their problem culture shock is yours
to deal with and this is hard this is
really hard I know I went to India for
the first time for a customer a few
months ago it was so confusing and
intense but that wasn't their problem to
deal with that with mine and you're
gonna get culture shock when you
interact with different people and there
are various ways of dealing with it and
you can go and like look up the
Wikipedia on culture shock if you want
but after time you start to deal with us
we start to adapt you get excited in the
mega danger in it we go through these
processes and you do this new
consultants do this with new customers
new people do this a new jobs you did
some new organizations and when you're
interacting in different community
you will go through the same process
let's get that one so I said that I'd go
through one of these faux cars what are
the things you do that fit others so
let's start with academics and as I
defined them and we're going to find
these off-script through I did make a
grid it was unreadable I'm not giving
you a grid but if you want to look up
what do I do to not purpose of these
people you could do this or only go
through this way if you're an academic
how do you when we get to these groups
I'm sorry how do you avoid ignoring it
to these groups academics often upset
government people by publishing stuff
without fully understanding what harm
that will do regularly they also upset
the enforcement community by their
training students in letting them loose
well by experimenting with things
actually not just appear meeting with
things upsets the people who like a
rigid understanding academic subsets
business people because oh you train
them I can't use them or because you
make something and it's useless whether
it's research whether it's people and
the negatives go on up state industry by
reinventing the wheel rediscovering the
wheel and weaving a bit of wheel that
will only hold negative loads or really
bizarre things but they upset the
independent people and some of us except
me
when I was acting as a security
consultant academics will often not cite
grey literature I've had someone reuse
my black at work and say we're the first
to publish this you quoted me but
because it wasn't peer-reviewed to your
standard you're claiming it's novel
that's a way to really alienate
communities if you're an academic and
studying things that don't don't matter
yet or that don't matter anymore or
being too rigorous or there's no Sun
well yeah but you actually don't know
what you're talking about
you found a shiny bag under a rock and
then see that you've discovered
something but you don't know what it
means you don't know where that goes
into
it's just it's a very different way of
approaching the world I love this one
because they have not you everyone the
same way they don't explain and they
don't share and it's basically what
their job is that's how they work if
you're in that space not talking is like
the key job requirement so whenever you
can give the illusion of sharing do it
whether or not it's actually sharing of
course they'll see a wild card just by
representing the man but there's not
much you can do about that okay so
what's our next group how do they annoy
everyone what do I got all the enforces
those who go and stop people studying
things those who get in the way
no I just want to have fun what do you
mean I can't release my malware or they
enforce the rules consistently or they
enforce the rules inconsistently or they
make rules so they don't make rules or
the update rules so they don't update
rules or they enforce mindlessly this is
just a nature of of doing that work but
sometimes a little bit of nuance and
perspective or the appearance of it will
gain you a lot of credibility now how
you ahead of this these people have set
industry bodies constraining or
controlling you standards it's a fun one
no no about how do you think of the
lawful intercept in there it's a privacy
protocol like it doesn't work like that
and that's hard and wild cap again these
people who just like to have fun and
feel other independent you know are you
wrong my fan you're overreacting why are
you doing that well oh you're just -
you're telling me no okay so these are
simple things to say these are not
simple things to not do and if your
business this is always a fun one
business often complains about there not
being enough novel stuff they don't want
to fund the development of it they
complain there's not enough students
they never want to actually hire them
until they've got experience this is one
of my bugbears don't complain about them
not training students if you won't hire
the students they train to your standard
a vendor captures a fun one where a
vendor basically takes over and defines
an entire industry to their own benefit
or sorry flip there where an industry
body has taken over by a vendor to the
vendors benefit standards bodies can be
very vulnerable to this so can certain
industry organizations a vendor comes in
they throw their money their people and
suddenly does they're on the board and
upsetting the rules and that can really
be a problem
they make secure center they're making
secure standards met upset well you
can't win that one vendor capture again
for business or for learning slowly it
vindication might be a theme and this is
a real problem with particularly any
vendor that makes product but also
services they work in their own interest
and over time they start to shape
everything to their own interest and not
to the interest that their customers or
that or the shared goals of the industry
this is something to be very careful of
again you make secure sandwich you make
insecure stands either way you're going
to lose someone's going to complain they
can't see through it they can't play
with it it's not open or it's open in it
and so anything you can do just to at
least acknowledge that's understanding
is really key and of course the wild
cards I'm going to reading wrong slide I
should read the right one or should not
read them um yeah industry taking
without giving every vendor will do this
to a point they don't want to reach to
do that vena capture happens with these
guys as well already covered that one
the wild cards are the hardest people to
keep happy because they forgive
themselves the most highly another least
pragmatic academics think that the wild
cards aren't rigorous because they're
not in most cases they're really
dangerous things yep but they're fun or
they break rules well they really sane
Juris things again seems familiar
business is like when you're not making
any money you bit of fun
but it's interesting and you're
releasing dangerous things again well
you're not cooperating so there are
common trends you start to see with each
of these groups and each of the other
groups has conflicting goals so what I'm
encouraging you to be is a bridge
between these different communities
because even if all you do is join two
of them that makes a difference a bridge
connects multiple groups groups that are
highly thinking to themselves and you
should really try to be a bridge I'm
going to speed up a little for time
while the slide is big given time I'm
not going to go through this because I
can skip to the next slide but if you
want to take a photo or give it a few
seconds these are the different ways
that have to find each of these groups
and when you're working with them how do
you understand them how do you
understand how they think of themselves
are they trying to achieve and how do
you prove to yourself the value of what
you are doing this makes a difference
even putting in a couple of these things
will make a huge difference when
interacting with these groups
and how do you how do you deal with each
of them how do you serve them well if
you doing with academics cite their work
not citing is basically fleshing them
that's what they work for that defines
their success in their institutions it
defines their success in their own minds
people seeing and recognizing it but at
the same time don't expect immediate
results and don't come and say I'm going
to give you money to study this if you
get that outcome because that that is
seen as very offensive but it's very
easy to do and don't require proof of
value before proof of validity what I
mean by that don't require a business
case for the thing they haven't found
yet I see that all of the time we some
funding bodies these guys pass on tips
don't expect to hear anything back to
say here's some you might want to look
at by don't ask questions seriously
don't have questions that wait like bad
places for you and talk about what you
do with them if you're able to because
sometimes they can use that but you'll
never know you're throwing it into the
abyss and the abyss told you to go away
it's not answering questions I'm not
yelling back yeah it's really key to
work with these groups the enforcers you
can tell them when the rules make sense
you don't complain about all the bad
ones and only that and if you do have
someone they should go and deal with let
them know don't just whine about them
not dealing with it the one that
particularly bugs me that when people
are dealing with this group is all but
it's not perfect so it's a waste of time
compliance isn't security no but in
non-compliant is probably insecurity in
most cases that means they are still
raising that floor don't go and argue
that a stupid rule shouldn't be in force
because that's not their choice and
don't ignore a break rule because you
think that's stupid because that is
really badly for you in the same way
with business try and get numbers try
and get metrics try and yeah speak their
language but don't knock your morality
I thought I could argue all but that's
it it's irrelevant they're an amoral
entity they don't understand that and of
course this is one largely that security
people and technologists doers oh but
more security is always better no added
business is always worse be pragmatic
understand that zealotry soap boxes
don't keep you in business very long now
when dealing with these industry
organizations understand the goal of
sending members goals don't understand
your own goals because they're there to
represent someone they're a political
organization in most cases their
governance body and also don't go
preaching against their members because
it's not their fault with the members
are usually that's whose idea to
represent like going and arguing against
the politician about their face that's
irrelevant I did it representing them
not to argue with you and don't insult
their members don't go and say oh you
but all your people a bunch of hacks and
sellout because then you're never done
never going to work with you again
because all you're done is shown in
taken ISM wildcards motivations and
appreciation these are people who want
respect these are people who want to
feel loved but feel that the work is
loved and it's not personal the same way
don't bother discussing discussing
pragmatic solutions which is a direct
contradictory to one of the other groups
because it's not about pragmatism don't
insult their honor oh god don't insult
their honor don't insult their work
especially on the internet unless you
really are as good as you think you are
because they will prove if you're not
but all of these groups have
commonalities so you don't go insulting
their work we have pride in our work all
of us do we think we're doing the right
thing and we do the best we can and we
have a different life and a different
work life than you so let's start sum it
up so don't go to mistaking difference
for wrongness and don't expect other
cultures to play by your rules
don't go in convinced of your own
superiority so that's a don't what are
the dues how can you make this work
together well you regularly go to at
least one thing that's not your normal
echo chamber and actually talk to people
that makes a huge difference you just do
that every now and then and you'll start
getting different perspective and
different ideas but do expect the
culture shock that comes with that and
find your common ground and work with
that if you're comfortable you're not
reaching out far enough and we're not
actually trying to work together and yes
that's how we're going to stand united
is by actually finding our common goals
working together on the things we agree
on and ignoring the things we don't
because the enemy of your enemy is your
friend even if they are actually your
enemy that is actually a key a key thing
to think through as you might have a
common goal even if it is simply dealing
with that don't get distracted by the
stuff that you're not got in common
because all do is build antagonism work
together if it wants me go back to those
slides let me know and I can zoom but I
think we're out of time
yeah alright I'll hang around if I'm in
yellow I need you to find if I'm not I'm
hidden thanks very much for your
presentation be initiated