it works good morning everybody to day
two of all sit in these streams and I'll
just remind you of the obvious things
that I'm told to have to reminder every
time remember to put your thug mobile
phone on silent and use the also
conference app to rate the different
sessions now for this session we have
Steven duty from this guy cue talking
about interesting stuff that you can
discover on the on the web so please
welcome Steven thank you everybody we
really appreciate you coming out to
listen to the stock as we just said
we're going to talk about interesting
stuff right now
the focus of this talk is how we can use
global Internet data to improve our
cyber investigations so there's there's
a lot of information available to us as
investigators how do we make sure we use
the correct methodologies to inform our
investigations and better protect our
organizations so at worst guy Kiwi let's
talk about threat hunting
so leveraging those relationships we can
go from a malicious commanding control
domain we can find additional
infrastructure that the actor may own
and we can understand better who is
targeting our organizations I like to
talk about threat infrastructure
analysis and all this is is a research
process that allows you to bring context
to your incidents the reason it works is
the same way that we as businesses or
organizations have to Internet interact
with the web on a daily basis to provide
our services actors have to interact
with the core components of the Internet
in order to effectively conduct an
attack campaign some of those actors
make a lot of impressions and core
Internet data sets others have stronger
operational security but at the end of
the day they leave behind breadcrumbs
that we as investigators can use to
inform our Incident Response so why is
this important as organizations you are
your best you know intelligence source
so if you take something you know of an
organization your organization that's
targeting you you can take that one
piece of information and you can create
a whole bunch of threat intelligence
based off of say a single command and
control domain within a piece of malware
the reason this is effective is most of
the time attacks that target your
organization target you more than once
so if you're a target of a specific
actor group they're not they're not
going to stop after the first attack
they're going to consistently come back
and target you so if you do this process
effectively you can essentially get an
understanding of that actors
infrastructure and hopefully proactively
block that infrastructure or on the
reverse understand the scope of the
attack campaign and start to monitor for
for that infrastructure internally and
maybe find new infections within your
organization it also allows you to bring
kind of context so there's a lot of
information available historical context
and TTP's that people have published
allow you to enter to respond to an
incident a lot more effectively so by
understanding who may be targeting you
you can respond better and finally it
allows you to identify gaps within your
organization
so as you're responding to an incident
and you identify an actor's
infrastructure you may find additional
infections that you didn't previously
know about those things weren't alerted
on in your organization and therefore
it's a gap within your collection or
your intelligence and you need to
address that going forward so what they
do do we use to do this process we break
this up into two areas traditional data
sets
driving through methodologies and web
crawling data the traditional data sets
would be passive DNS so you have an
attack in your organization and you want
to understand what is related to this
commanding control domain who is
scanning my infrastructure and is there
some information in there that I can I
can glean during my analysis passive DNS
is just the the phone book and
historical record of the internet so
where did this domain previously resolve
or where what IP address did this domain
resolve to and what other domains may
have resolved to it so it's just
one-to-many approach why would we want
to use passive DNS in our in our
investigations domain overlap actors
tend to use similar infrastructure when
they're conducting their attack
campaigns and therefore if we are
looking at one piece of infrastructure
we can start with a domain or an IP and
say show me the entire historical record
of this domain our IP from there we may
identify additional domains owned by
that actor group or a part of that
attack campaign and now we have more
context where we can we can block those
those domains from there we can go to
second order domains and IP addresses so
it's kind of a neighborhood approach you
start with with a single entity and you
build up that second order of
information could provide context to
your research do we know anything in the
public realm that's previously used this
infrastructure and then finally sub
domains if an actor has registered a
domain and is using it in a targeted
attack oftentimes they'll use multiple
subdomains or fully qualified domain as
a part of their attack infrastructure by
understanding subdomains we can
understand
full implication of the attack
infrastructure and we can proactively
block that infrastructure but we can
kind of rinse wash and repeat we can go
back and say what IP addresses did this
did those subdomains associate to and is
there any new information as a part of
that second data set that we use a lot
is Whois information as actors register
domains to conduct their attack campaign
they have to provide some information to
the Whois system it doesn't actually
have to be valid all the time but as
humans we're relying on you know
laziness I'm lazy sometimes actors are
lazy people registering domains are lazy
and they throw the same email address in
or similar names or maybe they use the
same phone number as they're registering
domains each of these areas is a pivot
point to provide us other domains
register using this information on the
screen you see passive total org which
is the platform that I run for risk at
you you also see that it's registered
using domains that were scheduled on
that and our CEO is is named there we
can use each of those pivot points to
understand all the domains that lose
ever registered or all the domains that
risk IQ owns and so it provides us
context to who's registered the domain
and maybe additional domains that may be
associated it also gives us a little bit
of information on a TAC timeline so if a
domain was registered yesterday and
you're seeing it in an attack today
that's a very quick turnaround but
oftentimes I'll depending on the type of
attack an actor may register a domain
six months ago six weeks ago and that
can start to give you some insight into
how far back in my logs internally do I
have to look how long has this domain
been alive
and how is it affecting the time slice
of my investigation and then finally
history history comes in more from a
historical research perspective but
sometimes actors register domains and
then they privacy protect them
so that we don't know who they are and
if we go back in history we can
sometimes see who may own that domain
so how do we use these traditional data
sets I've talked about correlation
between them but in a very quick
scenario we have an IP address that IP
address has multiple domains those
domains associate to other IP addresses
we can take that information and and
proactively block those domains or IP
addresses or at least monitor for them
within our organization as we build out
this this infrastructure additionally
with Whois information we start with
some type of facet most of the time who
is email addresses are the most
effective we're seeing a lot of efficacy
and phone numbers at this point we can
take that unique bit of information and
go from one entity to many these
methodologies have been used for by
organizations for for you know many
years now and they've been very
effective in understanding the full
scope of an attack campaign but there's
a problem
actors understand how we as
organizations defend against them and
they've changed their tactics techniques
and procedures they've increased their
operational security so traditional data
sets like who is and P DNS are still
very useful to inform our investigations
but there are a lot of hurdles around
them as I said previously an actor may
privacy protect their Whois information
when that happens you can't use this
methodology to find additional domains
or understand the people targeting you
we see a lot of actors fully segmenting
their infrastructure so there's no
overlap in in passive DNS we need new
data to inform our investigations but
the methodology still stands so we need
to expand our visibility how do we
expand that visibility we do it through
through crawling by crawling the
internet we can get a lot of information
from actors and organizations technology
now allows us to do this in a very
effective manner to database it and to
index that information in the same way
we look at who is in P DNS and what
we're really relying on here is is
exploiting basic human weaknesses and
or operational security the fact that
someone is going to mess up at some
point and we can use that to our
advantage as defenders so how do we do
this
it starts with what's in a web page what
are we seeing when we crawl the internet
and how does that inform our
investigation web pages have a lot of
different things in them we'll start by
using passive total org this is our web
page it's fairly straightforward but
what's going on in the background when
you go to pass a total org what is
actually happening from from an Internet
perspective well a lot of different
things are happening when you go to pass
a total org we are pulling resources
from other web pages in this case we're
pulling from our parent company risk IQ
we're bringing in their blog information
and we're linking out to two different
contact information within their webpage
and so our web page is made up of
resources that are pulled from a third
party most web pages nowadays are made
up from resources pulled from third
parties dependent requests you go to
passive total org we don't have many
dependent requests but we pull a custom
type set from Typekit and you can see
that we've pulled that that's an
association between my web page and type
2 cookies what's being dropped to to
track in this case we have we use rubra
to track interactions with our web page
we also host all of our infrastructure
on AWS when you come to our web page
both of those cookies are associated
with your browsing activity headers how
do we handle the interaction between the
request that's being made from the
browser and our server this header
information comes with user agent
strings it lets me know what browser
you're using maybe what what operating
system you're using it gives me
information that I can use to to make
sure that I'm displaying the page
appropriately and then response and
document object model everything that
that is in the web page is pulled back
in the in the document object model and
we can see all different parts of the
code scripts links and basically every
interaction
this is very useful we pulled down the
full document object model because web
pages change all the time and so we take
a snapshot in time what a web page looks
like today may not be what the web page
looks like tomorrow and so each time we
crawl a web site we grab the document
object model and store it for later
indexing and then finally SSL
Certificates is as the site secured with
the certificate is there an association
here you see passive total org wild
carded this is our certificate there's a
direct association with my website and
this certificate so why did I tell you
all that there's a lot of things in a
webpage how do we use that the same way
that I previously walked through P DNS
and who is to inform an investigation
well and that's the self certificate
very similar to who is there are details
as a part of the certificate you have to
go through a certificate authority to
get it or you have to create a
self-signed certificate and we can use
that the same way we use who is to
inform our investigation so maybe an SSL
certificate associates with multiple
servers or IP addresses over its
lifetime maybe an actor uses the same
certificate to encrypt its command and
control communications there's a record
between this sha-1 and the IP address
that's a link I can use and that's
unique
if someone created a self-signed
certificate as is the case with this
maybe there's something unique in the
information that they've input into the
certificate that we can pivot off of and
say show me other certificates that are
similar to this so why are certificates
important to your analysis it can
identify potential overlap in
infrastructure as I said I'm lazy I
think we're all lazy eventually as a
part of your job you may duplicate
effort we find that malicious actors use
the same certificates across multiple
pieces of infrastructure and therefore
we can track them using that certificate
certificate maybe stolen or embedded in
malware and so during your malware
analysis there could be a correlation
between that malware and that
certificate which lets you identify new
pieces of malware it could include
information about the regice
organization and also as I said
self-signed certificates are often used
by malicious actors beyond ssl
certificates we have the idea of
trackers so I showed the document object
model that we pulled down I said we
index it one of the things we index is
for tracking IDs these are things like
Google Analytics codes clicky IDs New
Relic Twitter Facebook you name it
anything that is that is in a web page
that associates to social media or
legitimate analytics on a web page we
index you may ask why well what we find
is these are unique identifiers for a
web page an organization creates a
tracking ID with Google Analytics
because they want to understand
interaction with their end users and
their web page but also that belongs to
them at that point and so what we can do
often is say show me everywhere that
PayPal coms Google Analytics code shows
up what we find is when actors are
standing up malicious infrastructure or
trying to impersonate PayPal and do some
credential harvesting they copy
wholesale the HTML of a PayPal login
page that login page contains that
analytics code if they don't remove that
analytics code we now have a brand new
unique identifier that connects
legitimate PayPal infrastructure with
typosquatting or malicious
infrastructure so it allows us to to use
these same methodologies of one-to-many
to understand actor groups so using our
same you know visualization we start
with a document object model we index
out trackers that tracker correlates to
a unique set of domains those domains
may be legitimate they may be malicious
but either way we have a connection
point that is very interesting to us as
investigators that we can dive into with
SSL Certificates we start with a
certificate and that certificate has
facets it has a sha-1 those facets
associate with other certificates that
sha-1 associates with other
addresses and each of these is
correlation points that we can build an
investigation off of hosts pairs as we
look at links and dependent requests
that come into a webpage those are
unique relationships parent-child
relationships that give us information
about how a webpage operates but also
gives us information about maybe how an
attack campaign occurred so what we do
with host pairs is we understand the
relationship between a web page you go
to a page it has links in it those links
associate to other web pages that page
you visited is the parent those links
pages are the children vice versa if
you're pulling information from a third
party though that information in
correlation is pulled in and what we
want to understand here is where where
are things coming from what third-party
assets are being pulled in and what are
those redirections that are interesting
and this is a little small but what you
can see is the domain that we saw the
first time we saw associating with the
the parent domain the last time we saw
and the cause of the redirect so is it a
top-level redirect is it an iframe was
it was it a script was there some some
CSS at play there's all sorts of
scenarios that could that could come
into play here and the big upside to
using this type of parent-child
relationship in an investigation is you
can start to understand compromised
websites and where they're sending maybe
your employees or victims and understand
the full scope of the avenue of attack
so we see this with for cyber espionage
we see this with watering hole websites
victim goes to a legitimate government
website finite financial website that
website is compromised in some way and
redirecting the user to another web page
or a piece of infrastructure that's
actor owned that page or a domain allows
for download of malware if we're not
looking at these relationships we may
may not know where that compromise
happened what the initial infection
vector was this gives us understanding
into that process
so again taking link sequencing data and
dependent requests we lump that into
what we call host pairs and those host
pairs give us relationships two domains
and those domains give us relationships
to IPS and it's a very rinse wash repeat
scenario but what we what we find is by
combining this data with traditional
data sets like passive DNS and who is we
greatly expand our visibility into actor
infrastructure and into attacks
targeting our organisations so all well
and good I've told you that this data is
useful how does how is it useful in an
investigation we're going to walk
through two examples this first example
is a cybercrime example that the risk IQ
research team dug into we refer to it as
mage card it was targeting ecommerce
websites fairly mid-tier websites
it was injecting JavaScript code into
the sites at time of checkout in the
cart and so they were stealing credit
card information based on this inject
you can see my sequencing data from the
crawl we have a UK website here faber
comm I think it's a book company and it
could be wrong and what we see is the
sequencing data shows us that Faber is
having a top-level redirect via script
to mage online Ness / JS / / mage j/s
seems totally legitimate from there
we're also seeing a sequence to jQuery -
CDN top top domains are never malicious
if we start to look at this from our
traditional data set standpoint we have
that top level website we see that mage
online.net is the domain that it was
redirecting to we see jQuery
- CDN top on the far right is also one
of the domains we saw in our sequencing
data and if we start to pull information
we get a couple of IPs we get a who is
email address that gives us a couple
more domains Magento - CDN top and
angular Club
and that's it that's the the extent of
our visibility but we may not understand
how broad is this attack surface we add
in sequencing data and crawl data we
start to greatly expand our visibility
into the mage card actors so we still
have faber co uk and now we have 45
other domains or web pages that were
redirecting to mage online net each one
of those 45 domains is a parent of major
online net and now we understand that
this isn't just a one-off instance it's
a much larger part of attack campaign
but we can keep going from there we can
say show me all of those relationships
for this new domain we found angular
club and now we see that there are four
web sites redirecting to angular club
and the same over at jQuery CDN top we
have two additional domains redirecting
to that that infrastructure now so by
adding and layering in web crawling data
over our traditional data sets we have a
lot more visibility into the mage chart
attack campaign as an organization this
is useful because if you find a scenario
where an employee is has been a system
has been infected and maybe it was
infected from a legitimate web site you
have the ability to understand the full
extent of the attack infrastructure but
also how many sites are redirecting how
big is this how how many you know
additional investigations am I going to
have to conduct we're going to use a
different dataset this time in a
different attack we're going to use the
the DNC I didn't get a lot of press 2016
semyonov campaign targeted the US
Democratic National Committee
it was attributed to a Russian group
where we use crowd strikes fancy bear as
the name and as a part of that attack
campaign the command and control
domains or infrastructure for the
malware was encrypted and so you
couldn't see anything but that
encryption allows us to make some
correlations in the attack campaign
using traditional data doesn't give us
too much we have a couple IP addresses
that were associated with that external
Mallard you can see that they're the
tags that I'm showing here associated
with espionage activity Russia
CrowdStrike
if we run passive DNS we get a handful
of domains most of them not very useful
we get this one miss department comm
which was widely reported on as a part
of this attack campaign as well
resolving to a single IP address and
that's it it's a dead end there's no
other information we can we can gain
from this analysis we add in web
crawling data and some of our new
components we get a much larger insight
into this attack campaign as I said at
the beginning the command and control
channels were encrypted they were using
a certificate to encrypt that that
communication and so when we asked show
me all related certificates or sha-1
associations to this IP address we get a
lot of certificates so in two three four
five six different certificates that are
associated with that initial
infrastructure and then when I ask for
the historical associations for all IP
addresses associated with that
certificate I get this cluster of
additional IP addresses if you went and
looked at each of these IP addresses you
would identify that they are associated
with the external malware implant and
each of these is a different commanding
control channel and so as an
organization we could take these we can
proactively block them and now we have a
better coverage of an attack campaign so
to kind of wrap up after TTP's are
evolving we can take tried-and-true
methodologies of linking data together
to expand our knowledge of actor
infrastructure this expanded visibility
provides us a new kind of lens to view
our actor groups with and it provides us
as organizations threat researchers
incident responders the ability to have
a better understanding of whose target
our organization
but it also allows us to evolve as our
as the actors and adversaries evolve and
improve their their operational security
and so by using these methodologies and
datasets I just outlined you have the
capability to really create your own
threat intelligence within an
organization and understand who's
targeting you once you have that
baseline knowledge you can take that
information and continue to do this
process which will give you a threat
feed of information and threat
intelligence to practically defend your
organization with wouldn't be a vendor
talk without a little bit of a pitch at
the end all of this data is available
within the passive total product that's
the platform that that I created along
with Brandon Dixon you can login and
register for free
jeanna passed out some cards that allow
you 60-day access unrestricted to dig
through the data if you didn't get a
card hans is at the booth feel free to
walk over there and grab the card when
you register for an account enter the
code and you can use the same data sets
I just talked about in your own internal
investigations so that's that's my top I
really appreciate the time are there any
questions
it'll be it'll be an issue we support
some of it but that's a massive amount
of data you can still do similar pivots
it's Jay
I guess the the preponderance of data
when you pivot is going to be much less
so it's something we're trying to
address right now but if I'm being
honest we're not looking at it too
seriously because how long has ipv6 been
around and how many actors are using it
and not as many so it's something we
know on the horizon we have to address
and you'll see it in some of our
datasets where you can look at v6
addresses but it's a smaller use case
economic um hello so a compromised
website is probably in relation with
than with the militias that are a server
but it's also in relation with maybe 10
or 12 not malicious service how do you
manage to get out the false positives
sure that's with all of this analysis
that's an issue so you're looking at an
immense amount of data as you pull in
crawling data you're going to capture a
lot of legitimate infrastructure or use
cases so in all of those use cases I
showed you I've pointed out the
malicious associations but you could see
Facebook and Google and Akamai and any
CDN and really how we look at that is
frequency so the likelihood that a web
page is going out every day to a
specific domain or multiple times a day
that's legitimate is high how many times
has a connected duration how long has it
been associated with that that page or
that redirection those are kind of the
things that I key in on as an analyst so
how often has it linked to it and what's
the time frame it linked to if you see a
link that's only been active for a day
or a few days and that web page has been
up for four years then that's probably
something I want to key into as an
analyst to investigate so frequency with
all of these data sets not only crawling
data with who is with
DNS is really my biggest indicator of
what I want to go investigate hello
given you do a lot of correlation on
lots of different data types are usually
doing anything you're printing in
correlation based on what the malicious
actors are actually putting on the
servers in terms of their size the suite
selection and potentially preferred
cipher suite order so from from a high
level correlation standpoint as we do
this crawling and index this information
we have a team everybody has data
scientists now we have data scientists
what they're looking at is there each
time we pull down a page not especially
for fishing events let's let's slice the
the attributes of that page into about 7
into 10 slices let's hash those slices
and let's compare them across our data
set so if we've trained a model to know
that something is a fishing page and
malicious how close to each of those
slices correlate to our known bad
fishing page and we can do with some
certainty we can tell you that that this
page that we've just seen today we may
not know it's associated with fishing
but has a 96% you know uniqueness to
attributes in a page we do know that's
associated with fishing and so we do
that correlation and for the past total
platform we'll tag that will say this is
on our blacklist is associated with a
phishing attack and provides you that
context as you're querying the platform
wisdom slightly more Easter than whether
you're actually doing using that those
sorts of techniques to actually generate
correlation between different actor
groups just to identify whether one
actor might actually be the same actor
playing somewhere else we'd love to but
the the honest answer is were not at the
moment farm well if there are no further
questions I'm I'd like to thank Steve
for his really interesting talk
[Applause]
the next session starts at 1120 so if
you want to get all the way down the
other end you've got plenty of time