i'm with you but are we about to hear
all about red teaming
is it about to to teach us how to break
into computers
i'm excited about that he's already red
teaming us we just don't
we're going to make you a presenter
cedric looking forward to it
and wolfgang great talk a lot of good
points so i look forward to
talking about those as well thank you
sir i'm looking forward to yours i will
drop off video then and mute
all right you all see the screen okay
the floor is yours
all right sounds good
well thank you to uh the girkon team for
um sorry greg conte for having me
it's been a long morning grim con team
for having me super excited to be here
i'm
cedric owens and be talking through
building
effective red team functions as an
internal
corporate security red teams here in
so a little bit of background uh
information on myself
i'm currently the red team lead at
twilio and personally
i enjoy kind of two areas that i like to
to play with in my personal time
i enjoy mac os post exploitation and
infrastructure automation so usually if
i have free time on weekends and i have
side projects i'm
usually building something in one of
those two buckets
um i'm blessed to be a husband and
father to wonderful wife and
kids and currently reside here in austin
though i'm actually
from all of us in the family are from
the east coast we've been here for about
three and a half years
uh the photo here is actually from the
highest what i believe
is the highest point in austin mount
venell um
so pretty cool area um did a good hiking
there with kids
um but prior to red team i used to
actually be blue team and that's sort of
where in the intel community
i fell into being like a packet analyst
all the way over through
internet response in the private sector
and
for me something that wilking really
spoke on about
empathy that's sort of why i have a
heart for blue teams and
because i've actually worked the role
and i understand the challenges
associated with
uh blue teaming effectively today um but
i really
really do enjoy collaborating with blue
teams um
with purple team exercises and just
helping uplift overall overall
detection and response posture this
here this time here twilio this is
actually my second time building out a
corporate red team function in both
instances
i was able to be the first basically i
was the first person i was a one-person
red team show
sort of with the open question of hey
like what what is a red team
what does it do should we invest in it
etc
and uh in both instances i was able to
grow the team with additional head
counter resources
so i hope that some of the things i've
learned along the way will actually be
of help or benefit to those who are
looking to do similar things
um i'm also a fan of 80s and early 90s
uh the music the food the movies
all that stuff is good with us me and my
wife we just
kind of love uh looking back at
nostalgic stuff
so um it's a good chance you may see
some memes pop up
that um reflect those decades throughout
my presentation
and i am on twitter at uh stead owens so
occasionally i'll post things from time
to time there that may be of interest
so agenda i plan to talk through from my
perspective what the state of the union
is right now in terms of like a shift
towards
internal red teams uh at corporations
some ground level foundational things to
think about as like if you're going to
build out a red team program
some general guidelines and approaches
that you can use some pretty practical
approaches around
running red team exercises some things
around some considerations around your
road map how important the roadmap is
how to plan it
workflow your workflow around that
some meaningful metrics and lessons
learned
so let's jump into the state of the
union so
i remember initially when i fell into
security
uh many years back uh it was kind of
interesting for me to see the shift
between then and now because back then
it was more like you had
network admins or sysadmins that's that
basically had their normal day-to-day
job and then they would also roll in
security things like configuring
firewalls or
uh responding to intrusion attempts
things like that so
at that time the security field so to
speak was more generalized
outside of the federal sector and it's
been interesting kind of watching things
evolve over time
where like eventually you saw companies
like ge and mandy and in the forefront
sort of defining what a
security operations center and incident
response team look like and what the
workflows look like
and you know started really
standardizing those teams and
kind of fast forward to today and uh
corporate internal red teams are still
kind of like the new kid on the block
along with
things like uh insider threat just
trying to figure out like
how do these new teams fit into an
organization
what do we do there's really not many
standards since it's pretty new and
we're all sort of learning from each
other
um those of us that are doing internal
corporate red team
we're kind of building and trying things
and seeing what sticks and works in our
environment
so hopefully uh from this talk i'll
share some things that i've learned and
hopefully you'll find them useful
in your organization as well so some
foundational
ground level things uh first key
assumption
uh if you're looking to start an
internal red team would be that there is
a blue team
there as in there's a security
operations center an incident response
function there that the team has the
ability
to see at least some visibility in the
environment and the ability to roll out
detections and essentially why i believe
that's a key assumption is because
red one of keys one of uh red's key red
team's key functions
is going to be to be that sparring
partner with blue
to ensure that the detections and
procedures that are in place
operating as effectively and essentially
help blue prepare for a real adversary
so my 10 000 foot view of red teaming
and there's a lot of little nuances that
i won't really get into here i'll just
kind of keep it high level
which is that red teams essentially test
the people processes and technology
from an attacker's perspective so you're
helping drive improvements
being a sparring partner with detection
and response
you're also assessing the state of
security controls at different layers
and looking at attack paths and how
attack paths can traverse
security controls at different layers
and what that looks like in the
environment
but in my mind like effective red teams
really drive positive change so the
environment gets harder
blue team gets gets increased ability
for
detection and response based on things
that have been done and also just a
general increase
in the awareness in an organization
around security from an attacker's
mindset
um and so those are some things like my
personal philosophy around
uh internal red teams but of course like
how do we get there where do you start
if you're starting a new program
like what would you do in your first
year and so these are some things we'll
walk through here
uh but before we get there just kind of
wanted to go through some
key skills that are at play when it
comes to building out an internal
ranting function
and as a especially if you're starting
new it's a good chance you're going to
be wearing
different hats across different roles
so um an example is like your planning
or process development so thinking in
terms of how red team
what processes you need to put in place
and how to plan out for your your
year your next two years um operator
skills is another one
so the ability to navigate a corporate
environment and what does that look like
and
a lot of times from for the operator
skills these even may differ from
the skills you may use in a ctf while
you may you
utilize general pin testing skills on
both what's interesting
on the red team side is you're looking
at very different tech stacks than your
approach
in the cfp world or ctf world
um where like you have a lot of
integrated technologies
um cloud on-prem a lot of things you
deal with in the corporate environment
that you may or may not necessarily come
across
in your ctfs so um just thinking when i
when i mention operator skills just
understanding how things fit together
in modern corporate environments um tool
development is another
key skill just because like you may have
a need for a certain type of tool
to save you time or to effectively set
assess a application or an environment
maybe that tool doesn't exist on github
or you're not comfortable pulling it
down running it
so the ability to build your own
infrastructure automation
you know the ability to stand up secure
infrastructure quickly
so that uh if if it gets burned in the
course of a red team
exercise you can keep moving forward
project management like that may or may
not be
inside of the red team but the ability
to drive
things that red team is seeing over
through to completion
so a lot of different things here um
that are at play but i will say one of
the key skills i believe
that may sometimes be overlooked is the
soft skill of relationship building
and wolfgang really highlighted on the
importance of empathy in his talk
and uh that is in my opinion that's
really important because
just um being an effective red team it
takes an understanding of
knowing like the challenges that blue
team deals with or that
security engineering and architecture or
cloud security
just kind of understand understanding
the different challenges limitations
and uh being able to sort of put
yourself in our shoes and work together
as a as a cohesive unit to move things
forward
uh so another thing i wanted to do is
sort of lay
the foundation in terms of how you view
your internal red team
so while red team is not necessarily
like directly responsible for any of
these
teams there's a lot of opportunity for
red team to help
these teams and even vice versa so an
example might be let's say you have a
cloud security team in the organization
and cloud security has been seeing
things systemically
in the environment and they've been
trying to move the needle forward with
preventions getting things
fixed and they just haven't been able to
move things
forward as quickly as they like so let's
say you do a red team exercise and part
of that exercise you assess cloud
environment and you find things you find
attack paths you abuse them
and you have that as part of your attack
chain now
you can actually share that data over
with the cloud security team
and now you provided them with evidence
or muscle as some would say
in order to help drive and move things
forward that's sort of how i like to
view
renting like how can i lean into what
other teams are dealing with
and some challenges that they have like
and it takes relationship building
and then hopefully as i craft my red
team initiatives or exercises
i can make sure that i'm considering
those inputs from other teams in my mind
so that then i can help them move
forward things in the organization
and essentially what it comes down to is
just really building a cohesive
uh environment especially within the
security team uh
at large so that you're both basically
all teams are kind of helping each other
move forward
some other foundational things to think
about if you're starting a new red
team corporate internal red team is you
may
kind of deal with some preconceived
notions that differ around what does an
internal red team do
as i mentioned there's really not a lot
of standards here so
you may start in the red team and one
perspective may be hey we want you to do
a lot of
web application assessments or another
application
another perspective may be hey we want
you to do
internal corporate phishing for metrics
exercises which
looking talked about right in terms of
like how that
may not necessarily be the option you
want to go so
just understanding that there's
different perspectives because
red teams are still relatively new in
terms of dedicated functions and being
able to have those discussions
with your management chain with other
team members
to see what the expectations are and
level set so that for your environment
you know exactly how you all want to
define and scope red teaming
other things to consider for year one uh
year one in my book is critical because
if you have a successful foundation it's
more likely
that you'll have a longer runway for
success
but again like relationship building
especially
with uh assert and just understanding
where they are what strategic
initiatives they have in place
how you can help and even use some of
that for inputs into your purple team
planning which we'll talk about a little
bit later
what processes and docs do you need to
have in place how do you show what
impact you're having as an internal red
team like what types of assessments do
you run
all those different things you kind of
want to think about early as you start
your red team and you can
then begin to kind of map it out along
the way
and so now what i'll do is some
recommendations about each quarter
in the first year of your red team so uh
you'll see iq one q2 q3 q4
and these are just kind of
recommendations from my experience of
if you're starting a new red team
function things you might want to
consider across each quarter in order to
get things going in an effective manner
so
uh first quarter of course relationship
building
and i will say that a lot in this in
this talk because
um there's all like the technical aspect
is well known like the good
technical skills to do red teaming but
sometimes i think the
relationship part gets undersold in
terms of understanding
how valuable those are and the reality
is even
in most organizations today
relationships is how things move
forward sometimes there's red tape or
bureaucracy
in order to kind of get things done and
sometimes just knowing the right person
and you built rapport with them can
really help
kind of expedite and move things along a
lot quicker
other helpful documentation that you
might want to have in your first quarter
as a red team
is your charter and that's really like
who you are what you do
what your purpose and mission are like
what your key deliverables are who your
stakeholders are
you can have all that information and
like a wiki
in your organization and have it
available to everyone at the company so
that
they can see that hey we have an
internal red team this is what they do
uh here's how to contact them uh another
helpful document would be the rules of
engagement
and that's really how you do what you do
um and so essentially things like
uh what's approved what's what's kind of
like in scope and out of scope
what is um the deconfliction process
look like so if
blue team finds activity that they
suspect to be read like what does that
deconfliction process look like
um are you gonna have a person who's in
the know like a white cell and
what does that process look like or even
how do you get your red team exercises
approved
like all that stuff kind of fits into
your rules of engagement
um other helpful documents that i think
are good to have up front
are your red team exercise proposal and
your purple team exercise proposal and i
actually have
a couple slides right after this where
we'll look at examples for those
uh last but not least i highly recommend
having a road map when you first start
and plan one to two years out and just
thinking about
you can basically use a roadmap to
identify where you are in terms of
resources and capabilities head count
and where you want to go like what
additional capabilities how do you want
to
mature your exercises so how do you want
to look at things like supply chain
attacks and how that might affect your
company
or up leveling your exercises to mimic
higher level adversaries
how do you plan to work with threat
intelligence to kind of
incorporate uh emulation or simulation
and so those are some things to look at
and since i mentioned emulation
simulation tim malcolm better did a good
job of sort of
explaining the difference between the
two for where a lot of red teams are
and so uh emulation is typically where
you
uh mimic the exact tools techniques and
procedures
of an adversary that would be interested
in tar
targeting your environment and
simulation is more
like you don't have a specific threat
actor but here
if you know it's basically saying if we
were to look at an
adversary with this type of capability
with this type of interest
and they were to target our organization
these are the tools techniques and
procedures
that they would use so emulation and
simulation
uh red teams may kind of switch between
the two across their exercises
but essentially you want to identify and
lay those out in your road map so you
have a starting point and at least an
initial vision for where you plan to go
so here's an example of a red team
exercise assessment proposal that
i have used myself and thought it was
really straightforward especially if
you're just getting started
for your ranting program first few
assessments
and it's very basic like it shows the
description
of the exercise whether it's going to be
outside in or some breach
information on the scope so if you're
going to fish is part of it how many
people are you fishing
what organizations you know maybe
are you going to do a random selection
for fishing or target organizations
like all that stuff is good to put in
here uh what
is like what type of fish you're going
to use if that's that's how you're going
to run your exercise
uh your dates you can even break out um
things like attack phases by the date
and then that's helpful because there
may be other things like change freezes
or blackouts or financial reporting
and while in reality an adversary is not
limited by those things
the fact of the matter is if you're a
new red team like building trust is
important
especially in that first year and so
there may be additional restraints that
you put on yourself like
running maybe you don't want to run an
assessment around
financials or or maybe you want to
restrict the type of assessment you run
on financials or
during blackout periods things like that
but as you build trust
and you grow the program eventually that
will probably become less of a concern
but it's just something you may want to
consider for a new programming
new program looking to build uh
credibility
also you can list like your desired
outcomes and what controls or detection
response you're gonna test
even your resources so like what tools
you plan to use
and whether or not you're building
anything custom
so this just something as simple as this
you can get it up to your approvers they
can be in the know with exactly what
you're doing
when you plan to do it why you're
planning to do it etc
and essentially like have comments that
questions that you can go back and forth
on and answer
and essentially make an approval
decision so this is an example of one
that you could use
for your exercises for your purple team
exercises this is a template as well
that i've used and this one
is more collaborative between red and
blue whereas the other
template i just showed is more for like
red and it's
management chain and so here you're kind
of working with blue to figure out what
do we want to test
and why do we want to test it especially
kind of letting blue
sort of lead in that space at times to
figure out like hey we have run books
here that we really want to drill down
on
i think we might be missing some
detection gaps here
and crafting some purple team um
exercise
scenarios around that and that could be
something as simple as
like red and blue getting together for
an hour or two
in the same like a in a virtual room and
just kind of
knocking out the tests you can do it um
like
kind of collaborating over slack there's
like a lot of different ways you can
actually do a purple team exercise
uh but in this case just kind of looking
at the template you would also lay out
your specific
tests that you're going to run so you
can test by platform
indicate for each test whether it was
prevented or detected
and i think this is important on the red
team side for everything that you're
running
uh to make sure you know the things that
blue could take
and use as actionable indicators so
things like parent-child relationships
command line arguments like something
that blue can run with because it's one
thing to come to blue and say hey i just
i just ran a payload it's like well
outside of the file name
like what else do i have to look for so
i would say red can can
do some work up front there and sort of
give blue more details that they can
uh use to pivot and dig in their log
sources
but essentially for this uh template
you're you're identifying your tests
the people involved and who's going to
do what for the purple team exercise
uh so some ground level or continuing
our foundation
discussion for first quarter i
personally
this is just me but i like to run a
blind
outside in exercise before i become too
biased
um the reason being is like i know the
longer i stay at a company i'm going to
start to learn things especially working
in security
i'm going to start to learn things that
may taint like how i you know decide to
run an op and for sometimes that is
appropriate like you want to use insider
knowledge at certain points
but for this uh my first quarter i like
to do a blind outside end
keep it very short in duration like no
more than a week
very tightly scoped with objectives and
using very low level ttps like maybe
targeting the publicly facing login
portal
or a simple fish for endpoint access and
see if i can get keys or
data from the endpoint pivot somewhere
else something very basic but it helps
you get a feel for
the current state of detections and
controls
um along a very basic attack path and
it also helps build that credibility for
a new red team in the organization
because
while purple teaming is definitely going
to be integral to your first year
there's also this expectation that red
teams can also
um you know basically test and assess
the controls in our environment
as well and help uplift those so that's
just something i like to do but
you definitely want to make sure it
works in your case and it makes sense
uh for quarter two um i recommend
unit testing your detection so you can
do miter attack you can do the c2 matrix
um like those are really good starting
points like the
the cool thing with attack is there's a
lot of automated stuff like red canary
out now that can
you can just have it like run through
different phases of the attack that
for unit testing that you want to test
for your um
for your endpoints or even for cloud
even
and then c2 matrix is a good source
because a lot of the commonly used
uh command and control tools by red
teams are already available in c2 matrix
in fact a couple of the command control
tools i've written are in c2 matrix
which is which is truly
a cool thing for me but essentially you
want to gauge visibility
detection coverages and gaps and help
build and improve
high fidelity detections for your
initial purple team
you can one other thing you can do is
the
red team exercise you ran in the first
quarter you can take the things you did
that weren't detected
kind of break those into units and um
sort of replay those together with blue
where you can start working on things
that
you did that weren't detected and build
detection or validate that logs are in
place etc
but essentially for quarter two just
continuing to build relationships and
build out your internal red team
docs and processes um another thing i
thought that wolfgang pointed out
um which is which i thought was really
cool was just the mindset
and something that sort of conveys the
mindset to have as your purple team in
your environment but
just thinking about how can you
complicate things for attackers get them
really frustrated to the point where
they move on something else i know for
me and
the assessments or exercises that i've
run the more complicated
uh the environment is like it causes you
to burn time
and usually nobody has an unlimited
amount of time right there's usually an
end goal or endpoint so you want to
complicate it and have attackers burn
the clock and hopefully pivot and move
on to somewhere else
um and then on the flip side when it
comes to security controls
or even on the detection scene i think
it's also applicable but
simplifying things and um keeping
making sure you're not putting like over
overburdening
your people with unnecessary things but
empowering them while also securing it
so i thought that was really good
perspective for wolfgang to keep in mind
uh for quarter three i recommend like
continuing your unit
uh testing detection unit testing so
whether it's a miter attack
or c2 matrix like continue along that
road and get your coverage there
i also like to do another tightly scoped
red team exercise this can be outside in
or soon breach just making sure your
objectives are impactful from a data
perspective what you're going after no
more than one week in duration
so you have i guess just to recap
with this approach like the first
quarter you would run your initial
tightly scoped red team exercise the
second quarter you would have done a lot
more
purple teaming unit testing then in the
third quarter you're doing another
red team exercise that that's tightly
scoped and then you're also
uh building relationships and you're
continuing to share
what you're up to on a red team with
other teams such as
intel insider thread cloud security like
any other teams and within the security
umbrella and even outside of security
umbrella
i think one thing that's been cool that
i've have been able to do before is
being able to speak at other teams all
hands meetings that that are not even
security teams
just saying hey what a red team here's
what we do here's how to get in touch
with
us this is the kind of um workflow we
have are there any questions
and just sort of getting the name out
and the word out across
uh both security and non-security teams
and then in q4 uh you're actually
wrapping up the year now and it's time
to start demonstrating the impact that
you've had for year one
so things like like what have what has
the red team actually help drive
are there new high fidelity detections
new runbooks do security controls that
we can highlight
how has red team sort of leaned into
other strategic initiatives
in order and basically helped other
teams move things across the line
for security that they've been trying to
do um again the knowledge sharing brown
bags
etc those are things you can highlight
to demonstrate impact
and also this in quarter four would be a
good time to
basically refine your road map for year
two so you started it at the beginning
of the year now you can refine it
since you've sort of been doing it for
almost a year and think about additional
capabilities
if you need head count here's a good
chance to not just say you need head
count but
why and what won't get done if you don't
have additional head count
and even demonstrate before you get head
count approval that you already have
work slated out for each person
just makes the process a lot smoother
and it shows management that you've done
your due diligence
and planning and preparing uh for the
upcoming year of red team
so some additional guidelines and
approaches for red team exercises
themselves
i like to think in terms of like
business versus
tech even though you do need to know
tech as well
but i'd like to think more data driven
versus system driven
so like accessing a system is only
important really because of the data
that it contains and so thinking about
things
from an executive's perspective like why
would they care
and what i found is a lot of times
stories tend to resonate
um basically telling the story of what
you did why you did it how you did it
uh started here which led i gained
access here which then i was able to
pivot here
um here are my recommendations etc just
really cut
you know clean cut a direct path and
i think it's also important to identify
like what made your attack harder
so what controls worked and that's a
good way to
give credit to the teams that have
invested in security and let them know
that what you've done has been effective
or at least it slowed me down also
identify
areas for that detection and response
did well in i think that's important
because a lot of times it's a lot a lot
of times the tendency is to focus on
what was missed but
it's also good to call out what was not
missed and what was done well
and then of course you can identify
additional opportunities for betterments
around
controls or response a key thing i'd say
is really know your organization so in a
red team space it's common that our
debrief reports are very long and
detailed
uh which is great but just make sure
that that resonates in your environment
so if you're at an organization that
likes that kind of stuff by all means
but the the companies i work for tend to
like very succinct
straight to the point um like
presentations that tell a story
and so i typically tend to use
powerpoints that that basically get
right to the point and show the attack
path
like the evidence of access and then the
recommendations going forward
so just something to to think about
um next i'm going to quickly talk about
some approaches to red team exercises
themselves i did a blog post on this
based on things i've experienced and
others in the industry so four different
approaches
um that i've seen through red team
exercises uh first one
your long running exercise so a lot of
planning and preparation
up front usually involves emulating a
very high level
adversary and it's from the outside in
the goal is to
gain access and to retain access without
being detected
in order to like access data live in the
environment and route to meeting your
mission or objectives
and so usually this assessment there
will be multiple avenues
in with the assumption that at some
point one of those will get burned
but i will say this is a great north
star to have
but most organizations especially new
red teams we're probably not going to be
doing a
long running exercise for the first year
or two at least
um because this is better suited for
organizations with
very large and mature blue and red teams
where a lot of the basics have been
covered like unit testing
uh your detections etc and even on the
red team side it requires a considerable
amount of resources to emulate a very
high level
threat actor but this is a good north
star
another approach is what i call linear
exercises and
essentially what this is is some uh
approach that you see that some
adversaries will use is they'll use the
exact
same thing in terms of tools techniques
and procedures until that thing no
longer works
and then they'll level up and they'll
keep it there until that no longer works
and you kind of see that here in the
chart where the lightning bolts
represent the red team exercises and
like the first one here
you ran exercise you weren't stopped um
so you
basically the second exercise you do
almost the exact same thing
this time you're stopped so for your
third exercise you level up
and uh this is an interesting approach i
would not recommend
like having all your ops follow linear
approach because you'll be kind of
limited in your
your adversary profile and your tools
techniques and procedures but it might
be interesting to have maybe two or
three
exercises kind of look like this and
just see how that works in your
environment
one thing i do like about this approach
is it does sort of emphasize
closing out the uh detection response
and security controls because you know
the same thing is coming back again
so if you want something you know you
want to see a different technique you
kind of have to close out
what's currently being used um another
approach is non-linear so the opposite
of that where you run different
exercises that are
really have no relationship to to any of
the others and
there's different threat actor profiles
etc and what's neat about this approach
is it helps blue team see a variety of
different
tools techniques and procedures one
thing to be careful about though is you
just don't want to get the shiny object
effect where it's like ooh this new
attack pass out let's run it
oh another one let's run that and uh
while it's great to have
give blue and the organization exposure
to a lot of this stuff
just uh make sure you have time to close
out things like your
detections and responses your security
preventions your
procedures like make sure all that stuff
can be closed out before you move on to
the next
then of course you have uh unit testing
so this is um
i i won't spend too much time here
because we've already covered this but
this is where
for example using the miter attack
matrix and getting your coverage across
platforms to at least detect base um
like based ttps but one area that that
red teams can really lean in here
is sometimes we know way other ways of
accomplishing those same tactics that
may not necessarily be in
the attack matrix so we can introduce
those during our tests and we can also
provide those as feedback
to mitre to add them into future uh
iterations of the attack matrix so
opportunity there as well um so as
you're planning your road map
uh just things to think about for your
exercises i recommend a mixture of
linear and nonlinear
and ensuring that you continue your unit
testing coverage by platform and os
and make sure you stick to whatever
frequency or cadence that works for you
i personally like running quarterly red
team exercises
because i feel like that's enough time
um if it's a short scope
exercise to like find an impactful
attack path
um do the out briefs kind of close
things out
fix the remediations and then kind of
move into the next one but you have to
make sure
whatever cadence you pick works for your
environment um
and then of course for your roadmap like
making sure you're watching out for
areas that you can grow as a red team so
what skill set gaps do you have
collaborative exercises that's a big one
like letting other teams
uh jump in and help during red teams
like that's a great way to build
relationships across the organization
identifying any peanut butter effect
where maybe
some other things that are slowing you
down that are not necessarily
primary red team things like being able
to identify those
identify some solutions and how to move
forward
um so here's an example of a red team
workflow throughout the year that
that i've used before um again just an
example but
i like quarterly red team exercises
whether it's outside in or soon breach
along with a quarterly purple team
exercise
and then even running like twice a year
maybe some specific
assessment and it could be like somebody
asked or a blue team or
security engineering comes and says hey
we're rolling out a new edr product we
want red team to help
kick the tires on it or hey we need help
with segmentation testing we wrote out
controls
that should properly segregate these
environments uh while those necessarily
may not uh fall under the quote unquote
red team umbrella
those still may be opportunities
especially for a new red team
for you to lean in and help other teams
um with some of their initiatives
um i also like dedicated research and
development time so i like
to do at least one to two weeks a
quarter where i can build new
capabilities do research on techniques
do my um infrastructure automation so i
can be more nimble
and also like helping with the cert
tabletop exercise so providing an
attacker's lens
on whatever scenario that you're
crafting for the exercise so these are
just some examples of a
a workflow that you could use for a new
red team
uh next i'll jump through some metrics i
also did a blog post here on some
helpful
metrics specific to renting exercises
first one dwell time and for me i define
dwell time is the time where
from when a red team gets initial access
to when they're booted
time to initial access so the time from
when you start the exercise to when you
get initial access
that one's pretty interesting because it
may even show like some of
some of the controls and how effective
they are in terms of making it difficult
to get that initial access point
uh time to detection so your initial
access time how long
is that from when blue first sees you or
even how long like where in the kill
chain are you being detected
uh time to remediation um like from when
blue first detects you how long does it
take them to
remediate you those are just some
examples and there's other ways you can
slice the metrics but
i think these are really cool and very
specific to exercises and allows you to
track
at least with some level of consistency
across exercises how things are trending
i know truth of the matter is it may be
difficult to do that across various
exercises when
like there may be different um
visibility issues in different
environments
but it's still something i think you can
work towards and it's very collaborative
it forces blue and red to
work together because neither side has
the whole picture so just something to
keep in mind
um these metrics can also help with the
storytelling in terms of
answering things like how effective our
remediation processes how is blue team
trending across exercises are things
getting harder
for red team over time how are we
shifting detections earlier
so just something um to keep in mind if
you're looking up thinking about like
impactful metrics for an internal
renting
so some things um just wrapping it up
around lessons learned
flexibility i would say it's key when
you're starting a red team function you
may not do red team things all the time
like you may get pulled into other
things and and that's okay
uh just make sure you're able to
document uh what
you know the impact of other things
you're getting pulled into is on your
primary objectives and
map a way forward like maybe you can
automate something and give it off
to an appropriate team foster open
sharing
i'm big on like just being an open book
not only with blue team around your
tactics you're using
but just in general um to other members
of security or even to the organization
around
who the red team is and what we're doing
i think that just helps raise security
awareness
also if you do not have a vision for
ranting and someone else will
so i take time up front to think broadly
about the program
and like beyond just the technical
aspects of
like the hacking piece think of it as a
program and where you plan to take the
program
uh fell forward so like i've tried
things with purple team exercises that
didn't
didn't work very well so that was a
chance to go back and
tweak it and try again uh so just keep
trying things until something works in
your environment
uh blue team being successful is a great
thing and that's the end goal
what we're going for so blue stops an
attack path or
security prevention stop an attack path
that's awesome like that's what we want
to call
out and make sure um like we give praise
to those teams or
to those efforts that have made the
attack path harder uh clear concise
reporting
just making sure that your reporting is
telling a story and it's telling it in a
way that resonates
with upper management i think that's
that's important and helps
convey like the why of your retention
exercise
and of course relationship building and
can stress empathy enough just
understanding the challenges that other
teams are dealing with and
leaning into the best of your ability to
help them get things over the fence
or by taking your outputs and seeing
how you can help them and how they can
help you
so putting it all together uh the ground
level again
relationships your team charter your
your basic documents you want to have in
place up front
some things to think about around your
exercise your red team exercises use
both
linear and nonlinear options and keep
long running
up as your north star that you can sort
of mature and work towards
keep a cadence that you can stick to and
that makes sense for your environment
um again just make sure you can you can
track meaningful metrics that will help
tell your story and fail forward like
don't be afraid to make mistakes that's
how we all learn
and continue to openly share with other
teams
so these are some references of some of
my blog posts here that back up some of
like more information on some of the
things i talked about here i also
recommend
checking out wolfgang's design thinking
for blue teams talk which was
right before mine really good stuff in
there um
again this is just my lens from my
experience there's other blogs
out on corporate red teams as well like
to malcolm better
red team journal it's all sorts of
different things out there that you can
read on as additional resources as well
so uh thank you all for listening for
taking the time and
i'll be hanging out in the discord
channel afterwards for any questions so
feel free to
reach out
i was taking screenshots of that one
i have some questions perry might have
some questions too
bryson has no questions
dave go ahead all right so first of all
i can't help but notice
the red teamer in your jiu jitsu photo
was the one getting armbard
and i do not think that's representative
so um
i'm gonna request the next presentation
has that swapped out
uh but my real question
is one thing that that struck me in the
initial portion of the presentation when
you were talking about developing
partnerships
with other organizations within the
company
is one of the ones was obviously
incident response
now i will say that in a million years
of doing this
since i'm as old as the hills i have
very rarely
seen an organization
be willing to share like the incident
response information
which is sometimes very sensitive with
their red team
organization have you encountered
success
with linking these two parts of the uh
of the system
yeah that's a really good point um i can
say that
at least in one of the organizations
i've worked in that that has been the
case
um and mainly like cert would share
their incident response plans for
feedback or even input into like a
purple team exercise
so say hey like this is our run book
this is how we handle
i don't know i'm just gonna say now
we're like a host malware infection as
an example
and a chance to kind of look at it see
what cert does
and then in our purple team exercise we
can actually
run through it and see if that run book
makes sense or
is there any gaps things we want to do
to improve it
um so i would say yes um i have
experienced that but it kind of depends
on
on the organization because like
sometimes there is more of an
adversarial mindset between red and blue
um but i think i guess for me personally
i'm more along the lines of open sharing
even on the attacker's side
like even if something has not been
fixed
rather than trying to hide it and reuse
it again uh from a ranting perspective
i think it's built more beneficial to
just share it with blue like here's the
how the attack works underneath the hood
here's everything you know about it that
i know
i just think it's just a better better
approach to sort of uplifting the
environment
i was really struck by the emphasis on
collaboration
and empathy as someone pointed out in
the chat
there is a notable theme to all of these
talks
namely empathy um i i would ask
some questions but we're about ready for
our
next presenter uh dave would you like to
introduce him
oh yes i would like to introduce him i
actually prepared a special let's bring
him in
did i put you on the spot there no i
actually prepared
but i don't see him you need something
thank you so much cedric that was that
was really wonderful
um i i learned quite a lot actually
so thank you
um i'm attempting to speak korean to him