um so welcome everyone to my talk uh
about repo jacking and how github
usernames expose 70 000 open source
projects to remote code injection
i'm indiana maro i work for security
innovation and today i'll be talking
about repo jacking which is
essentially a novel supply chain
dependency vulnerability
that's extremely widespread in open
source projects
so we'll kind of explore how that works
you know how to exploit it
how widespread is and then we'll also
talk about some remediation strategies
um and also kind of supply chain attacks
in general
so when i start talking about supply
chain attacks i'm not talking about
hardware supply chain tax which is like
a whole different beast i'm talking
about software supply chain attacks
and i can't really talk about that
without talking about soil winds
obviously everyone's heard of
solar winds in the coming uh the past
few months
um a huge hack you know and that was a
software supply chain attack
um there's been a lot of other notable
ones like mimecast asus
ccleaner in the past past couple of
years um it's kind of a
it's a whole attack field which is kind
of on the on the rise
um specifically you know with solarwinds
um
it's a it's a type of supply chain
attack where you're hacking this company
and this company is
used by a bunch of other companies but i
want to talk about a slightly different
type of supply chain attack which is
dependency supply chain attack and more
specifically open source supply chain
attacks
so everyone uses open source right
everyone knows open source according to
the show on the type 2020 state of the
software supply chain report
uh 90 of modern application is just open
source which makes sense right could use
a web framework you use
a pre-made ssl library or whatever um so
this is obviously a very
important aspect of your application to
to secure um cyber attacks in this range
are growing
apparently up to 430 year-to-year growth
um
because you know targeting this open
source library if you can get this one
library
uh you can hack you know and break into
a lot of other things
so it's extremely important to kind of
secure these um because you know they're
a huge part of an application
um and we're talking about open source a
lot of
open source is stored on github right
github is
a website that hosts most of the world's
open source um
and and basically everything anytime
you're you're looking at open source
applications it's most likely to be
stored in github
so if it's important to like secure open
source it's even more
important to secure github because
github hosts all these right so all
these libraries that everyone
is using um github is the the source of
truth for those
so you know if you could find a
vulnerability in github you could
potentially exploit it to exploit
you know some some some other dependency
down the line
um and so when we're talking about open
source
uh kind of supply chain attacks and
vulnerabilities um they're slightly
different from attacks like solar wind
attack
um because in solar wind like the the
attackers went after kind of the biggest
target right solar wind because solar
wind is
as big and a lot of people depend on it
and such um
but with open source and dependency
supply chain tax uh
the the valuable targets might not be so
big so this is a website
uh libraries i o and they maintain a
page called unseen infrastructure
and the premise is basically they make a
list of libraries that are immensely
popular or immensely dependent upon
but aren't uh aren't very there aren't
many contributors so like if we look at
the list down here
we've got like concat map for example um
it's got 800 000
dependent repositories but it's only got
like 30 stars on github
and one contributor so essentially
there's one contributor this one
application is used by a whole bunch of
others and these are all
kind of different popular ones that uses
so you recognize a lot of these right
so so all of these are loading in code
from
this one contributor so it's kind of a
really valuable target
um if we actually look over here like
angular for example the third one down
angularjs is actually what's used in the
front end for solar winds
so if someone want to you know break
into solar ones again all they'd have to
do would be to
you know break into this one app this
concat map it'll get loaded in by
angular angular get loaded in by
solarwinds and then you're in um but you
know maybe you don't want to
break into it maybe it's too hard you
won't go the easy route and maybe you
just
ask the developer if you could have it
um this actually happened in the past
back in 2018 there's a very popular
library called event stream
same type of deal right loaded in by
lots of things um and
it was maintained by one guy um and he
was on to other projects right he just
had that kind of sitting in the
background
um so someone went came up to him and
asked hey can i have this
library like can i maintain it and he
said sure passed it over
and soon after the the person was
actually a malicious attacker
and they loaded in malware to that
library um specifically targeting crypto
wallet
um they were actually caught but um
the not the person unfortunately but
they were caught in their attempt
but only because they used the
deprecated api in the malicious code
um if they had to use that deprecate api
there'd be no warnings that came that
would come up
um and to this day they might not be
caught um so you know that's kind of an
example of someone
of one of those really core libraries
um being taken over but let's say you
don't want to find like a vulnerability
one
and you don't want to ask the developer
because you know you don't want to talk
to people
um q repo jacking so that's where repo
jacking
comes in i'm going to talk i'm going to
kind of get a little story about how i
actually
ran into repo jacking so it started with
either engagement
um working for a big client and doing
you know a standard source code review
so looking through the dependencies and
such and i run into a github url
so they're they're linking directly to a
github url um
and you know loading code from that so i
search it up
i follow the user so whatever user is
pointing to and when i try to browse to
that user i get a 404 error user not
found
from github so it's kind of interesting
because they're clearly loading code
from
from somewhere so then it browse to the
full you know repository
um and it directs me to a repository but
for a different user
so i was getting redirected to to a
different user's repository
that was really weird because i thought
hey you know this github link is
pointing towards this user
so what i did is i went onto github
registered a new user uh with the same
username
and it worked and then i create a new
repository uh with the same name
and now this this uh this code that i
was
auditing essentially was loading code
from this newly created user
um and that's kind of that's the premise
of repo jacking
um so what happens is github allows
username reviews
so when someone renames or deletes a
user their username on github
it's going to allow you to anyone to
re-register it and any kind of previous
urls pointing to that
is are going to be affected because if
you look at like a github
url you've got the github domain right
that's pretty static that's not going to
change
um then you've got the repository right
all the way at the end
um that's kind of dependent on the user
right the user gets to name that
repository but then you have the
username
um and if this username can be reused
and
taken by anyone essentially whenever
someone you know deletes their account
renames their account
um that username is going to be
available to be re-registered and so
anyone could re-register that username
and then recreate a repository and then
you know that they've got full control
over
what's being loaded into code so a
couple points about
repo jacking it's conceptually similar
to s3 bucket sniping or subdomain
takeover if you're familiar with those
we're essentially yeah you're pointing
to a location
online you know an online resource but
that resource is available for anyone to
claim or anyone to register it often
results in code injection
uh just because you know github stores
code so people are often loading code
off of github and running that
um as a dependency so it often results
in code injection which is pretty bad
um and the other kind of scary part is
that you can become vulnerable without
changing your code right
because you might have a dependency that
is pointing towards a github url
right like in this case let's say
twitter bootstrap or whatever
if twitter were to delete their account
anyone can now reclaim that
reuse make a new account with that
twitter name and then you haven't
changed anything in your code
but you're now vulnerable to repo
jacking
and obviously since github is public
anyone can exploit it and it's pretty
trivial to do so
so there's three main scenarios um when
talking about repo jacking that can
make an account essentially or a
repository or url
uh vulnerable to repo jacking scenario
number one
a user deletes their account that's the
obvious one right someone deletes their
account so obviously it's up for grabs
from anyone
and any url pointing through that are
going to uh
get get hijacked essentially and this
actually happened in the while before
so kodi is a video streaming platform
and it has
add-ons and a lot of those add-ons load
code in directly from github
there's a popular add-on that would load
code from github
but then that user deleted their account
so now that's available for anyone and
someone else did actually
create a new account with that same
username and now had control and they
pushed updates and stuff
it wasn't malicious um but it could have
been so that's that's
you know scenario number one so the
thing with scenario one number one
though
is that most likely when user deletes
their account all the repositories are
gone right
so anything that was linking to that url
is gonna break it's all you're going to
get a bunch of 404 errors
and if you and obviously people
investigate that and look into it and
say oh this user doesn't exist anymore
and they're going to change the location
of that dependency so
that's kind of a big flag that when that
goes on and you have to be like a
well-timed attacker to be able to
monitor all the usernames when one gets
deleted re-register it and
and take over that way scenario two
though it's a little more complex
uh the user renames their account so it
sounds the same right because in github
you can rename your account
that's good um but then your old account
name is now available for registering
from anyone
but there's a little something called
repository redirects which i'll talk
about in a second here
which makes this a lot more dangerous
than snare one and the scenario three um
is a little more niche for sure
where a user transfers a repository over
and then they delete their account
and this also sets up a repository
redirect which i'll kind of talk about
so repository redirects this is a
feature of github that was introduced in
2013 and they got a little blog post
about it
and essentially what it is is that
whenever you rename a repository or you
rename
a user github is going to set up some
really handy redirects
so any of your old urls are going to
point to your newer urls
this is really good for like developers
um because you know it doesn't break all
of your code
um so you know so if you're if you're
pointing towards it from somewhere else
uh it'll just redirect you seamlessly so
that's really nice um
unfortunately it can also be really
dangerous because it means that now when
someone changes their username
that usually is up for grabs so anyone
can do it so they're vulnerable to repo
jacking
but no one knows because everything
works the same any old link works the
same and that's what happened in the
case of
uh of that first that first repo jacking
basically was redirecting somewhere else
and even though it was
vulnerable no one knew because it was
getting redirected so here's an example
of this repository redirect and
at work um this is the the github
if you go to github.com twitter
bootstrap and you can do this right now
um it'll redirect you to somewhere
different it'll radioactive github.com
twbs bootstrap and this is because
twitter probably you know create a new
account
specifically for bootstrap and transfer
repository over but the old link will
still work
now when you when that repository direct
is created um
it's all it'll continue working
indefinitely unless
a user is re recreated with the same
username in the same repository right
and that's how you would hijack
it so in this case obviously they won't
do it but imagine that twitter were to
delete their account
anyone could then re-register that
twitter name and they would be able to
recreate that bootstrap repository
and any of the old redirects that would
redirect it to wbs which
is the legitimate repository would now
go to this new repository and code to be
loaded from it
so that's essentially uh repo jacking in
a nutshell
uh once we found this you know obviously
we fixed it pretty quickly
but then we went to github and we said
hey github you know this is a problem
uh because you know all these all these
people who are linking to your urls
don't realize that this is bad
um and as a quick note here this also
works for actual forget operations so i
could get clone or gate push
we'll get redirected um yeah so we went
to github
and and we told them this is bad right
and and they said yes we know about this
um and they kind of pushed us to point
us to a link um
and so this is something they had done a
while ago which they basically
retire the name space which means that
they don't allow the repository to be
recreated
for any project that had more than 100
clones in the week leading up to the
owner's account being renamed or deleted
this kind of mitigation that they
implemented uh to ensure that really big
repositories
aren't being hijacked um so like they've
got examples here for example like
microsoft typescript
or swagger api um those are really big
repositories
um and because of this you know if they
have 100 clones in the week leading up
to their deletion then
no one can can re-register it uh but
we found or i found when i was doing
kind of a more in-depth research on how
where these urls are being used is that
it's not these big repositories which
are vulnerable right all these big
repositories are are going to have
a package manager package somewhere
right so any who's going to want to
access those will just pull them in from
a package manager
but the bigger issue are people who are
doing like a fork
of a common repo and then changing just
a bit of code and then relying on
that direct github url of their fork
right so
it's always if they're basically if the
if the dependency is big enough it's
going to be in the proper package
manager
there's always the small ones that get
you and if we look at like the old
example of concat map
you know that's got that what 30 30
github stars and one contributor you
know what i mean
um so somewhere to look directly to that
you know maybe that that hasn't had more
than 100 clones in
in the past week um so you know so so we
do find i found that this
mitigation can be good for the bigger
ones but definitely doesn't fix this
issue everywhere
so once we knew about this repo jacking
um github wasn't planning on fixing it
or
you know they had their mitigation
already um i decided to kind of take a
look on just how prevalent it is
because you know i've seen that a bunch
of times in code i've probably done it
myself quite a few times
linked directly to a github url so i
want to scan through all open source
code that i could and see just how many
people are linking to github urls you
know how bad is this
so i'm going to walk through the
different steps i took so step one
in this process was the data collection
so i had a couple data sources to
actually pull the
the data from first one here being the
github activity data this is published
by github
it's a three terabyte data set that
includes three million open source
github repositories
and the full source code for each one as
well really good because i could search
through this
find any any reference to a github link
and kind of
go from there but the only issue is that
i was last up in 2019
so you know the day is not super fresh
um but it still can yield a lot of good
information
and the second one was from the same
place i mentioned before libraries.io
they they maintain like an indexed
database of dependencies and packages
that depend upon each other
so this was a really good source for for
that type of like reverse dependency
analysis
um so i kind of use that on the
secondary steps over here
so i went through all of that and i came
out with a list of about four million
unique github links in source code
so that's a lot of links and this is
basically anyone or anything that linked
to a github
url but that's not you know that's not
necessarily all the impactful links so
step two is the cleanup
because you might have a link like the
one below in a readme file for example
where you know it's not actually it's
not going to result in code injection
because it's just a readme file or like
a comment of a file for example none of
these are actually
particularly interesting because even if
you were take them over you wouldn't be
able to
get any kind of code injection right
we're more interested in like something
like this this is a docker file
that does a w get on on a github url
and then obviously you know runs the
code there so for example if this
protocol buffer slash protobuf
euro was hijackable and vulnerable to
repo tracking
then this would result in you being able
to get your code running inside this
docker container
so you have to do that cleanup um and
the other thing we had to be wary of
is that different package managers had
the ability to link from
github directly but in different formats
right they all had slightly different
formats so we need to make sure we were
catching all of those
and the one which i found was
interesting is like for example npm and
ruby gem does the same thing
where you have the shorthand format um
so instead of putting the full
url uh if you just put the username
slash repository name
npm is going to know that you mean on
github and that kind of speaks to just
how common it is to link
to code directly from github right
because they even have a shorthand
version from it so you have to make sure
you catch all of those
that was the cleanup and so we got rid
of all the uninteresting links
we're left with 2.1 million unique
impactful github links so these are
these are you know links that are going
to load code
um and if you can hijack these then
you're in
so after that you know we trim it down
to just the github view usernames
so we've got about 650 000 github
usernames you have to scan through
um the github api only allows you to do
5000 requests an hour
so it took a while but we managed to
look through all those usernames and
find all the ones that currently don't
exist
because if it doesn't exist it can be
re-registered
and therefore you know any link that is
part of that username can be hijackable
so we did that scan and it turns out
about seven percent of the usernames you
found
were unregistered um and that's a lot
bigger than i thought
i was expecting like sub one percent
maybe um but seven percent is
is a huge number right obviously people
get bored of their user usernames far
more than expected
and this was kind of the point where i
realized just how widespread this was
going to be
considering that basically this meant
that we had 92 000 github links using
source code
in a meaningful way that could be
hijacked so the next step is just a sip
book have reverse search
for any place or any source code that
used one of those links
and turns out about 18 000 open source
projects are directly vulnerable to repo
jacking
and that is a lot of projects um you
know and these kind of range from
everything from
super large organizations like you know
google or github uh to like small
personal projects and such
so here's an example of one that we
found uh i'll gorilla search helper
that's the name of the package
version 3.2.2 since this closed into it
has since been fixed
um but basically in their package file
they were linking directly to the super
wolf slash middle and smith place
um and that is a repo uh like a github
repository
so we found this so we take a look first
of all does the original user
exist search up super wolf does not so
obviously the user change their name
um or delete their account and then you
actually check uh the actual repository
mel smith in place and if you go here
it's going to redirect you using that
that repository redirects
to this repository the male smith male
smith in place
and that's why this code is still
working and that kind of highlights the
danger of
the redirects because this code has been
like this for a while
um and it just kept working even after
that super bowl fuser disappeared
um so basically this is a hijackable
this right here is vulnerable to repo
jacking
and you can inject code in there so
that's the 18 000
impacted project right those are when
they're directly vulnerable but that's
not the whole story because algolia
search helper
is one package that's dependent upon by
other packages right so you have to look
at everything
so what depends on this package so then
you know you build out that graph
and you take a look okay if you instant
search what depends on that and you just
keep going down
qcli.u keep going until eventually you
reach
a really interesting project in this
case it's the the vue.js
command line tool uh ucli and it depends
upon
you know through a series of
dependencies it depends upon the algolia
search helper
um and for those familiar with uh with
the vue ji
view view uh cli that's essentially the
command line tool for doing view
operations
um which is you know one of the largest
web frameworks in the world
so essentially because of repo jacking
what you have is you've got this super
wolf user
changed their name or deleted their
account and because of that
and through the supply chain you know in
the dependency chain
view is now vulnerable to code injection
so you know a malicious attacker would
re-register that super wolf name that
mel smith and place repository
um would kind of create code that
they'll go up through the dependencies
and eventually get into the the main cli
and from there you know the impact they
could have is tremendous
so that really highlights the importance
of doing this this dependency analysis
as well because
you know looking at a single directly
vulnerable repository doesn't get you
the whole
image of the impact okay so we got our
18 000
projects which are impacted do the
analysis
right so now we gotta see what's what's
actually vulnerable uh through the
through that graph so due for a depth
one
we're up to fourteen thousand more
thirty two thousand thirty eight
thousand
as this is as we keep going down through
the depths and then eventually
after like five a depth of five um we
have seventy thousand
impacted projects now we actually had to
stop after seventy thousand
um because part of those were actually
huge web frameworks and libraries that
are used by basically everyone
like that concat map example for example
um
and as we tried to do the next level uh
we physically couldn't process it it
just took too long to process all the
ones which would depend on them
because they're so big and so that's the
point where i said okay this
this is you know this is enough this is
clearly extremely widespread
um and that's all and so that's where we
stopped at
so the key findings from this this
research and this kind of mass analysis
was that there's about 70 000 affected
open source projects
um only up to that right there's there
could be so many more um past those
depth levels
um and if you add up all the the star
count
like the github star cam of all those
projects combined they have over 1.5
million stars
which is a huge amount right like the
biggest github repository has like 300
000 stars
um so this is this is a number of times
you know larger than any individual
project
and it affected basically everything
right because it's not language
dependent
um it goes you know any language can
pull from from github urls
so it affected you know java python go
um
it went all over the place um and then
also affected basically every major
organization
that has open source so like microsoft
we found some google some facebook
github themselves so we're vulnerable so
it
impacts basically everyone um and and
this this one is a little hard to
determine um because you know different
package managers use different
ways of calculating downloads and they
don't always make it available
um but there's at least two million at
least the bare minimum would be two
million daily downloads
of these impacted packages and projects
um
you know so that that that impact alone
is tremendous
um so we got all this data now i thought
it'd be interesting to load it up into a
graph and kind of get a visualization as
well
so here's a visualization we built
essentially this is a project this node
with a thousand downloads a month they
kind of give you the size
and these are all the directly
vulnerable projects
so everything here are projects and each
each project gets their own little node
sized up based on how many downloads
they have
and you can kind of see already based on
that thousand dollar a month just
just which some some really big projects
are directly affected by this
and then we walk down the the dependency
chain
this is the second a depth of two what's
affected at depth of three you see some
some big dependencies starting to kind
of crop
up and you kind of see how they're all
getting pulled together by the different
uh
by the different links and there's some
really interesting um analysis to get on
here just by looking at this
like for example this node over here
which seems to to really touch onto
everything um the node and kind of the
bottom
the bottom right side there and there's
also some interesting bundling if you
look all the way on the left over here
um you can kind of see all the nodes
sticking together and that's because
they're
they're interconnected you know that's
f4 and once you hit step five this is
where we had to stop right
if you just look at this it makes sense
because virtually every single one of
these
nodes are huge libraries and frameworks
used by everyone
uh you know if this is if this is view
um you can just kind of imagine what
these big frameworks are over here
so we had to stop because obviously this
would have this graph would have
completely exploded
on the depth level six um so this i
think is a really interesting way to
kind of visualize uh
visualize just the impact that this has
and you can't see that initial thousand
download a month note anymore
so we've talked about the actual
vulnerability now we have to talk about
some remediations right
um so the biggest remediation if there's
anything you're getting
gonna get out of this talk is don't link
directly to github
repositories right that's like that's
the most straightforward
way you remediate this because github
urls are not
meant to be like immutable locations
essentially
that's what package manager is for so
always use a package manager npm pipe
composer whatever you use for your
language
that'll kind of ensure their job is to
do that to make sure that you're
downloading exactly the ones you
uh you want to and github urls don't
just don't offer that safety
if you're currently the maintainer of a
of a project you know open source or
even or private or whatever
i highly recommend you go right now
after this talk look through your source
code
and you know even just a search for
github.com uh or whatever and try to see
if you're if you're linking to any
github urls
and if you are you might be vulnerable
already um to repo jacking if these if
those
usernames can be reused um so just don't
do it and that's the easiest way right
a second way that you could protect
yourself is through version pinning
so pin your dependencies to a specific
version so um
the student of you would have noticed in
that example of a goalie search
algolia search there was a little
hashtag and a git commit hash at the end
and that's version pinning where you
basically say to your package manager
only download this specific commit
so by only downloading that specific
commit it will you know it'll ensure
that
uh it'll ensure that no other commit is
downloaded um
so i did kind of take a look at this um
as part of this research
and for basically all of the major
package managers i looked at
i was we were able to bypass that
version pinning
so version painting is definitely not a
one fix
all there um so it can be bypassed and a
lot of them through a bunch of different
kind of nifty ways
i don't get too much detail because i'm
still kind of in the process of removing
these with some of the package managers
um but definitely keep an eye out for an
upcoming blog post
that goes into more detail on this um
and the other thing is don't pin to a
tag or a branch version painting can
pink to a tag or a branch of a
repository uh don't do it because tags
and branches are not immutable
anyone can change those or delete them
and then the last remediation you can
take on are lock files so log files is
basically a file that ensures that only
a specific version
of a of a dependency is downloaded and
those might have an integrity check to
make sure that
you know there's no nothing funky going
on and it's exactly the version you want
it
the thing is log files aren't always
used from security
point of view so some people use lock
files to ensure that other developers
get the same version as them so you know
there's no bugs or anything or no
untested code
so for example this is the npm log file
if the package comes from npm
it'll include integrity check which is
good right because i'll make sure that
nothing can happen
down the line but if the package comes
from github like in this case
for the express case at the bottom
you'll notice that there is no integrity
check
um and all it relies on is that commit
hash and
you know as we talked with version
pinning that can be bypassed
um so you know lock but be aware of lock
files they can definitely help
but they're not the one fix all either
the biggest is don't link directly
github repositories
so basically the tldr of the stock is
gear repositories can be hijacked
through repo jacking and you should
never link directly to them or else you
could get
to have a code injection vulnerability
so just don't do it
i have i've written an article about
repo jacking at the security innovation
blog
called rebo jacking exploring the
dependency supply chain um that i would
encourage you to read if you're
interested in this
there's some more analysis there and
some some different things i couldn't
get to talk about here and i will also
be posting another
kind of upcoming in the coming weeks
article about the version pinning bypass
and some other kind of interesting
findings that we had and kind of
how we how we went about trying to help
remediate this issue
um you can contact me at any of the
snare places and
thank you very much for listening to my
talk
that was awesome that was really cool
good talk you did have a couple of
questions come in through the discord
um somebody said uh wouldn't it be like
really easy to write a script that goes
through all the possible dependencies
that could be used to target
a given library uh which uh
you touched on in slide eight i believe
yeah or you wanted to comment there yeah
i mean it would definitely be uh
easy for for someone to go through that
um
and and do that analysis themselves and
and find all the
of everything that's vulnerable and
that's kind of the the danger here is
that it's really easy to find and it's
really easy to exploit
which is kind of a double whammy in
terms of of impact
yeah that's awesome i uh did we have
other questions in here before
uh yeah
so i don't see any questions in the chat
for go to
webinar or in the questions panel
so i i'd actually put in the discord
this is this is clearly bonkers pants
because
uh uh g dynamics put in there and the
same thought i had
simple but deadly as the best things are
or i guess worse it depends on your
perspective
yeah no that was how did you do the the
the scanning was it a script you put
together
how did you go through and find those
links was
that's that's actually a great question
um so that data set i talked about
the github activity data is actually
loaded into google bigquery
which is basically a google's kind of
cloud offering for querying large
amounts of data
um because it's you know it's a three
terabyte data set um
so downloading that and sifting through
would be hard but
google could do it in just a couple of
seconds using their engines
and they allow for regex so basically i
made a big super long complex regex
extracted all the github links um and
then from there i could just kind of go
to the individual files and
and then do my analysis yeah that's cool
yeah because that's
that was my first kind of thought there
not not necessarily the size but that
you have that
data that you were able to go through
and do that so that's a
that's really really really awesome
um you said you're working with some
repos right now or you're working with
some folks right now
um without saying who they are obviously
because uh you know you're trying to
work with them
but are you seeing when you do reach out
to people that they're
you know generally oh hold on yeah let
me go fix that or
let me go change this kind of what kind
of reaction are you getting when you
talk to people
yeah um so i've actually had some really
positive reactions um
you know this it kind of i've published
the blog post um so a lot of people read
through it and they're like okay yeah
they make sense i get
i get what's going on here um and the
fact that it's a pretty simple fix right
just point point somewhere else get a
package manager or whatever um
makes a lot easier for people be like
all right yeah you you got me and then
they fix it right there but um yeah i've
had some really positive
feedback and a lot of people especially
with the repositories or contacting
which are really
huge and large repositories really
understand the importance of security so
yeah they jump on it right away yeah no
that's great
um yeah very very very good and uh this
this talk as well will be recorded well
it is recorded and it'll be up on
the the youtube there uh youtube for
for grim and i'm i'm gonna point some
people to this because
uh excellent excellent work uh tabitha
delaney uh any other questions we have
any questions coming in or do you have
other questions
i didn't see any other questions come
through i thought it was uh
just to reiterate like just what a what
a dead simple
thing to to be able to fix and remediate
you know
once you know about it absolutely
knowing it's off the ballot right the
other half is red lasers and blue lasers
i had no specific questions myself but i
did want to comment that uh
in speaking your pacing was remarkable
uh you're you're a very excellent public
speaker
well thank you a pleasure to listen to
very good and this was your first talk
huh so yeah
yeah anymore yeah i will be presenting
this talk to a couple other places
coming up
um and also be including some kind of
further further analysis as i
continue to look into this and kind of
go from there
very good all right well feel free to to
hang out here a little bit we got about
15 minutes till the next talk but if
you've got other places to be oh are you
gonna be hanging out in the discord or
uh be uh in the virtual uh virtual happy
hours
yeah yeah i'll definitely be available
in discord for any questions or any
comments or
so yeah so i'll be there and feel free
to reach out to me