hi and thank you for coming to my talk
today
i'm really excited to be here as this is
my first ever grim con
and it's also my first ever conference
so i thought a fun way to start off this
conference since it's all virtual is to
ask you all
my virtual audience a couple questions
the first question is do you think
you're a good speaker
why do you think you're a good speaker i
would guess a lot of you fell into one
of three categories
yes i think i'm a good speaker no i
don't think i'm a good speaker
or maybe i am a good speaker i want to
ask another question
do you know you're a good speaker i want
you all
to ponder that while we're talking
through this concept
i know i wasn't a good speaker my first
year in a big four consulting firm
i was stuttering i could not stop
shaking
and if someone had asked me what my name
was before i walked into an executive's
room i probably would have said yeah and
walked the other way and gone to the
bathroom to collect myself
i was too focused on having the right
answers instead of actually looking at
the situation i was solving for
i failed a lot of speaking engagements
some well in front of executives
and i thought the best way of failing
was to do that in front of people
and do it constantly but i hated that
way of learning and i think it's the
worst
to do by failing or learn by family
so instead i decided to do some research
and i practiced that research
every chance i could whether it was on
projects with my managers or
in front of rooms of executives so what
i learned today is those tools and i
wanted to share them with you
before we do that i think it's important
for you all to know who i am
my name is alexandria esposito and like
most of you i work in information
security
i never thought i'd be working in this
industry i thought i was going to be a
lawyer but i landed here and i couldn't
be happier
to tell you some of the three important
professional facts about myself that i
like
to share with everyone is that i'm
curious about how things break
i always have been and problem solving
is
a way to continue that passion critical
thinking and solving hard problems is
essentially why i became a consultant it
allows me to do that almost on a daily
basis
and then lastly communicating security
solutions and their impact to my clients
and to our clients over at grim
i am here to talk about speaking with
impact since
the past three years that's all i've had
to do is speak to executives
because about their security impacts but
on a personal level i think it's
important that you know about me
outside of work and i have some pictures
here on the top left hand corner you see
my dog cooper he is five years old and
he has been my shadow
throughout the coved pandemic and then
on the bottom left-hand corner and that
black and white picture is my dad
he's my best friend he's been my biggest
supporter throughout my entire life and
he's the first person to show me a
computer
and the first person to actually get me
interested in cyber security
and then on the bottom right hand corner
is my boyfriend michael
he has been a harsh part of my life and
he has taught me so much about myself
and i couldn't be happier with him
um and then also i love playing apex
legends with my twin brother
john unfortunately john and i don't have
a lot of good pictures together so
that's why he's not featured on here
so why are we here i think we need to
put a framework together so we all know
where we're going
our first step is to define
communication it's very important for us
to have a baseline
my definition of communication and your
definition of communication
might be different so let's get on the
same page about it on top of that
communication has a couple things that
we need to talk about
in it what makes a bad communicator what
are the pitfalls of communication right
and what makes communication easier um
and then we'll talk about that my
favorite part of this talk is the reason
we're here
is the scqa framework and in sdqa
framework
in our a area we're going to talk about
the time and difficulty factor so how do
we
factor in time and difficulty to show
our executives that we've thought
through the problem
and then lastly i will be repeating
these questions throughout the entire
talk
but we'll wrap up with did i understand
you and did you understand me
these are questions that you'll hear
throughout but it's important to keep in
mind that they are the driving force of
the scqa framework in my opinion
so before we can get to the core of our
talk we need to define our problem
what is communication communication has
a lot of constitutes these days it could
be
texting it could be face timing it could
be tweeting
instagramming facebooking zoom calls or
zoom conferences
or you know the casual in-person
communication that we've kind of lost
over the last year
but what does it really mean well i can
assume that your definition
and my definition are the same but i'm
not going to do that i'm going to define
it for us
so for the purpose of this talk
communication is the act of
not talking itself with the act of
articulating your point
and having it received on the other side
simple
right because there's a whole fact of
i need to get my point across in the
first place i need to ensure that the
people
in the room when they're telling me
about the problem
are telling me all the facts that i need
which is where our first question comes
in of did i understand you
have i been provided enough information
to be able to talk
about the problem and then on the other
side of our screen we have our audience
members
they're asking the same thing when you
get into that room after you've
gone through the whole proposal and gone
off and you're done testing for weeks
now it's did we understand what the
solution being offered
is and so i'm asking myself as the
speaker did you understand me throughout
that entire presentation
and it's important for me to be asking
myself that question
um on the other side of the script we
also have our audience asking themselves
did we even give a crap about what this
person has to say
i know that i care about the offered
solution that i'm presenting to these
executives
and i know that these executives are
very busy and likely
don't have a lot of time to talk about
my offered solution so
did you understand me comes in a lot and
it's going to be important as you're
presenting to
your audience
i want to talk a little more about these
questions and i know it's going to seem
a little redundant but it's important
that we get these right
communication seems simple but it's not
easy
as you can see on the right over there
in our cartoon i love cartoons i think
they're great at
depicting things that we might not be
able to say perfectly
with words but this person is saying a
lot of buzz words and
his audience is saying i have no idea
what he's talking about i just want to
help
so how do we not be the person
presenting on the right so did i
understand you these are questions that
i'm going to be needing to ask myself
before during and after the presentation
so what is important to my office my
audience is it the impact of a security
finding
was it something broke and we need to
figure out why it broke
was a remediation effort that failed
what is it
so i'm asking myself these questions
too why are you listening to me and like
i said to you in the beginning of this
presentation
i feel that you all are listening to me
today because i've been speaking
to executives and working in consulting
for three years which has allowed me
to understand this art of public
speaking
so another things that you want to ask
your audience or understand what your
audience's role is
do you have to solve the problem is your
audience having to solve for this
problem most likely yes that's the basic
question right
do you have to implement the solution
okay i'm offering you a solution
is now the audience job to go off and
take this offered implementation and do
it themselves
or are they paying me to implement this
solution
all very important things to understand
to help you
understand your audience and then lastly
you're in
the executive's room talking about this
offered solution and you want to know
did you understand me like most of you
or i hope like most of you i've been in
executive rooms and thought to myself in
a moment of insecurity
please please please understand what i'm
saying to you
i wish i had learned to ask did i answer
what was important
to the audience with facts and data did
i test my hypotheses
and further learn how to silently ask
the room
by context clues if they're
understanding me
is the room paying attention are they on
their phones what's going on
and are they caring about what i'm
proposing to them if not
if they're not caring how do i get them
to
so we can all make communication hard
it's the unfortunately
the fact of life that communication can
get mixed up sometimes so i wanted to
put some of the pitfalls that we've
probably all seen
here in a list of three because i like
lists of three
there's three things you can do to make
communication hard for yourself get on
your soapbox
give your audience your non-expert
opinion and rant as much as you possibly
can
let's just say that you've solved a very
hard security problem
we're being very high level here just so
that we can all stay on the same page
you are really excited to tell these
executives about your offered solution
how you did it all the details about how
you did it so you get up and rant as
much as you possibly can
and you don't really look up at your
audience while you're doing it you're
just
sitting here talking about your security
finding while that's all good
sometimes you might lose them because as
you can see it with another cartoon over
here on the left
you can have this internal dialogue
going on in front of your executive
audience and they could lose you give
your audience an unexpected opinion
i try to avoid the words i think and i
feel as much as i possibly can
sometimes you have to throw in the i
think and i feel just to show that this
is your opinion but if you can avoid
them
i suggest you do and renting as much as
possible
and getting on your soapbox can be
similar but
you're trying to engage your audience if
you're a solo communicator
you're doing it wrong and then lastly
before we get into how to do the work
there are some traits that we can all
develop to be good communicators
you want to be a listener the more that
you practice listening the better you
are
going to get at framing the scqa
framework
you're going to be able to find your
situation and listen to what's important
from what that person is telling you
the good news is you can learn this
skill
you can stop talking and you can start
listening to people around you to learn
it
next trait that you could possibly try
to develop
to be a good communicator is solution
oriented we don't want to always jump to
past experience to be a good
solution or to find the solution to your
problems but
we want to always try to put the
solution first which is why the scqa
framework will help you do this
and then lastly careful word choice we
all know as communicators
the words that we use are important so
how do we pick those words in a way that
will
articulate the impact of our findings i
like this cartoon over here on the right
because
this person well very wrong tactic was
innovative in the way that he got his
audience to pay attention
try and do that try and be innovative
with the way that your audience is going
to be engaging with you
don't turn on the sprinkler system but
definitely try and find a way
that your audience is going to engage
throughout your talk
how to do the work is now the most
important part of our talk and
most the reason that we're here and i'm
very excited to talk about this scqa
framework
so now we finally have gotten to the
topic that i've been wanting to discuss
this entire talk the sc
qa framework i might nerd out a little
here but this idea has
changed my life and the way that i look
at problems not only
problems that i'm being paid for but
problems that are going on in my
personal life
one thing to note that i learned about
the scqa process
is that it takes a little time to start
structuring your thinking this way
it's a very very structured way to think
about
problems and situations now you don't
always have to follow this but i think
it's a good idea
so let's dive in you always want to
start with your situation
you need to ask your executive or that
executive's delegate
as much as you possibly can to validate
the provided background information
you are a dog with a bone you're getting
paid to go and fix someone else's
problems so you want to make sure
that bone is right and to repeat to
reiterate that provided background is
ensuring that you have it
the situation correctly grasped so once
you think you have a handle of what that
executive is telling you
it's your job to take away and go and
start solving a problem
right so before we get into actually
creating a hypothesis and testing our
hypothesis we always want to make sure
that we understand
the whole situation problems and
solutions are bound to have limitations
there's dependencies before you want to
get to where you want to go
it may be that the company doesn't have
proper technology or they have too much
technology configured incorrectly
so take that background at face value
and then poke some holes
in it provide a reason to yourself and
your team for solving for this situation
what i like to do when i start projects
especially with people that i haven't
worked with before
is to ask them this question what are we
solving for
what do you want to get out of this
engagement the reason that i do this is
because
it helps set an end goal for all of us
and it helps
everybody understand the situation
correctly so once you've figured out all
the complications
and you are ready to go with your next
set from the sq
scqa framework you are going to want to
check yourself
i think question is one of the most
important parts of the scqa
framework i think this because you got
to check yourself
there's everybody has their own bias and
as information security professionals
we've solved a lot of different problems
so we tend to have the knee-jerk
reaction to look at a situation
and think oh i've solved this before
but what you want to ask yourself is
have you exalved for this to be exactly
the same way with the exact same
parameters with the exact same company
well you may have very well of solved
for a very similar situation
but it's not necessarily that you've
solved this one
so you want to make sure that you're
looking at it objectively and not
going back to confirmation by bias
so once you've questioned it you think
that you have a solution that you can go
start to test
i'd call them a hypothesis obviously
because we're in scientific mode
we're going to want to test these
hypotheses so
you go and now you're trying to figure
out what your offered solution is going
to be
that which leads us to our last section
of the scqa framework which is answer
i keep repeating myself here i think
i've said it a couple times throughout
the talk
but answer is not saying you're
providing an answer and this is a
definitive and the only way this problem
can be solved
i like to say you're offering a solution
because
through this careful methodology of the
scqa framework you have been able to
test
what will work in that given moment with
these given parameters
that does not mean that the situation or
this offered solution is always going to
be the same and will always work
but you've provided a concept for your
executives to go and test
themselves even though you've done the
testing for them
and see whether or not this is the
solution will be good for their
overall environment the thing about
offering a solution is you're accounting
for the fact that things are always
changing
so i like to spend a little bit of time
on this answer portion of the scqa
framework
because it's probably one of the most
important
it's the one where you're going to sit
in front of the executive and tell them
what you have found after they've told
you what their situation
is so at this point you might have
thinking
be thinking to yourself that you've got
my whole situation and my whole
presentation figured out
maybe you've drifted off gotten a couple
emails and you know what my offered
solution is
well even if you think you do i want you
to pay attention for a second
because you might need to re-hear that
this is really important stuff
um one thing that we may fail to account
for in the scqa framework
where we assume our audience has the
same background is
that we're assuming that our audience is
on the same story as us
so when we're going in and framing our
offered solution we want to account for
something called the time
difficulty factor as we all know
executives like the answers up front
so when you're factoring in time and
difficulty you are providing that to
them
i think that with all of our solutions
we have
the ability to factor in time and
difficulty because it offers
all of the aspects of the solution
you're telling them
these are your limitations for
implementing this solution maybe it's a
resource
maybe it's a certain tool maybe the
remediation effort
depends upon another effort concluding
so while you're thinking about this
offered solution you need to account for
the level of
effort your audience has we all know
that
in information security there's not
always a level of resources
or money being thrown out to being
thrown at the solutions that are being
offered
so you need to make sure that you are
providing the value
up front to these executives by factory
again time and difficulty
because it shows that you've checked
through all the limitations of your
offered hypothesis
and you've tested your offered
hypothesis into your offered solution
you're also doing a couple things by
doing this time and difficulty factor
you're checking yourself which is very
important you're seeing that your
solution
is going to work because you've
accounted for all of the situation
and also and probably more importantly
you're checking your audience
while talking about your um time and
difficulty factor they're going to be
able to think in this moment
is the solution going to work for our
company i need to ask a follow-up
question because i don't understand how
the presenter ieu
has gotten to this point it allows your
audience to think
and engage with you and by the time
you're already at this point in your
presentation where you're offering your
solution
this is where it's very vital for them
to be paying attention
so we've gone through all of our scqa
framework
and we are at our most important
questions as i had said
earlier that these questions are going
to keep coming up throughout our talk
i think it's important to take a moment
here and to find something that i find
very useful and it's actually was
recently introduced to me through a book
called think again
so over here on the left hand side on my
left hand side
you see a chart that says conviction
with knowledge
and in the middle there's a humility
sweep so the concept
of confident humility is and as i quote
from this book is that many people
picture confidence as a seesaw
gain too much confidence and will tip
over into arrogance as you see in our
arrogant zone
or lose too much confidence and we
become meek
this is fear with humility it's where
our insecurities come out
that we will end up having a low opinion
of ourselves
and nobody wants that when they're
walking into an executive room or a
conference room
so how do we keep that seesaw balance
and how do we apply this to the act of
public speaking itself
the way i like to look at confident
humility is you can be confident because
you know the material
and that you have the ability to find
the solution but you also know that
there are certain things that you might
not have at your disposal
whether or not that's tool or you need
someone else's knowledge
you need to have faith that you have the
ability to be self-aware to look at
yourself and to
enlist other people if need be
that's why our questions of did i
understand you come in
enlisting other people is very important
it helps you
solve the problem we don't have the
answers all the time but we do have the
resources if we try hard enough
so as adam grant says in his book having
faith in our
capability will while we meet may not
have the right solution or even be
addressing the right problem we have the
tools to figure it out
it's very empowering to have this be
something that you
add to your toolkit especially while
you're trying to answer the question of
did i understand you
it does the checking of what we were
talking about within the question
and it not only helps you find the right
solution and helps you feel confident
while you're walking into that boardroom
that you looked at this situation
as much as you possibly could
now our last part of our the last part
of our
talk is something called did you
understand me
i said this again in the beginning of
our talk that this is probably one of
the more important questions that you
should be paying attention to and if you
take
anything away from this i hope it's the
scqa
framework and these two questions so
you've gone through and figured out your
answer
you've presented it to your executives
and now you need to take the temperature
check
of the room that's tough to do while
you're standing up there or virtually
looking at your camera
and trying to figure out is my audience
understanding me
do they know what i'm talking about well
while you're in the presentation
yourself you can check yourself first i
think that's the first important thing
that you should be doing
was i arrogant was i confident enough in
the answer that i was providing
now right now i'm checking my
temperature and i'm feeling pretty good
that i've explained what communication
is all the way through how you do the
work of becoming a public speaker
or at least taller royal at public
speaking which is what i was kind of
going for
here some of my favorite ways to include
temperature checks for our audience and
probably the most important
people in the room is ask questions it
keeps your confident humility intact
and it allows you to engage with the
audience in a way that you likely
wouldn't have been able to before
so if i were you right now i would
probably
ask you if i was in the same room with
you unfortunately i'm not
does this make sense does the scq a
framework make sense to you
if not how can i help that make sense
just confident humility makes sense to
you if not
how can i make or explain that so that
you understand
was there certain points that were
confusing what was it
you can let them know you can let me
know in the middle if on discord
if this made sense to you and i hope it
does but if not i would love to explain
any clarifications or if there were some
complications that maybe i didn't
account for for this framework
once you find out those answers i
normally like to wrap up my summary
with some key takeaways but first
i think the one of the most rewarding
things in a
public speaking engagement is that you
got to the end you didn't stutter you
did pass out
and you made it so you nailed it do you
think you understood what was going on
in this talk i really hope so
but before we go i will anything i want
you all to take away
these six key takeaways
one communication define it for yourself
if you don't like my method of
communication or my definition of
communication
i encourage you to set one for your own
having this definition
keeps you straight when you're using the
scqa framework
all the important parts of the framework
are there all you need to do
is utilize it you need to assess your
situation
and find any complications when the
problem is being presented to you
ask questions not only of yourself but
of your team around you
and you know go back and ask these
executives these questions if it helps
you test your hypothesis
that is the end goal having a testable
hypothesis once you find your answer
i like to say i'm offering you this
solution
based off this information and these
facts
so once you've gotten there you've
offered your solution and you've
accounted for your time and difficulty
for this particular situation you
need to make sure that the level of
effort is articulated to your executive
group
or else you're probably going to lose
them and they're going to say
why do i even care about this solution
right
last four well lastly number four
confident humility
very important i think that this is
something that we can all start you into
and listen to our daily tools right i
want to check myself i'm very confident
in the strengths that i have but also
very aware that maybe i don't have a
tool or a person
with the knowledge that i need to solve
this problem so how do i get that tool
and how do i enlist these people
since i have confident humility i know
when to enlist other people which is our
number five takeaway
and you know your weaknesses you're able
to involve not only
other people from your team but your
audience while you're in the room
it takes a very transparent approach to
telling executives about very sensitive
problems that they're trusting you to
solve
and most importantly do you do i
understand
i think that these questions if anything
are understanding your audience and
understanding yourself making sure that
you're looking at a situation in a way
that allows you to solve a problem that
maybe was unsolvable before you came
my name is alex esposito and thank you
for coming to my talk