Hey so that's who I am
Mike and hackintosh reviews name of the
presentation so that's motivated to do
this talk because I've done some things
with akatosh I thought I'd share so
that's basically my reason for putting
this together I'll go through some of
the basics and then I'll do a little
show-and-tell afterwards and anytime you
have a question feel free to speak up
so why hackintosh I mean you know you
can you can download a VM somewhere and
and run it and you got to play with the
Apple OS X system you don't need to you
know beat around on a piece of hardware
that never was intended to run it well
okay so there are people out there that
have Apple boxes and they have to buy
new ones all the time because Apple
keeps obsoleted the hardware and because
it's in their business to do that they
generate money when they do that
so the other thing is you know it's got
an Intel chip on it it may not be
exactly the same Intel chip that runs on
an Apple PC but it's an Intel chip how
hard can it be so some people have
figured this out already and I'm this is
not my original work this is something
that's been around for at least five
years and you know a lot of people have
done this kind of thing and you know why
not if you have a computer you want if
you want to work with that below if
you're a fan of Apple or whether or not
you are and you just want to try it out
go ahead so my motivation was I had some
hardware and a hat some time and
doesn't want to play with it see what's
going on I like I like learning
something too and I like working with
operating systems I've been doing
hardware things for many years and being
mostly Asafa program in the last couple
of years I figured well you know let's
find out something more a little bit
deeper dive in what the harbor is so and
learn something about it
so hackintosh I kind of a cool name
what's a good akatosh do well well
what's the difference between an Apple
PC and an irregular PC the BIOS some of
the hardware and what does that really
mean for the operating system
well the operating system reaches out to
some hardware that knows about it can't
have it all encoded in itself so there's
a sold interface that we'll talk about
but basically you have PC BIOS is and
and their their main intention is to run
Windows because that's the operating
system that you'll find on most pcs I
mean you know Microsoft has contracts
with the with the BIOS vendors put a
little bit of this in here there you go
Apple doesn't have that contract they're
going to do their own thing but they
still have to have biases because they
they talk to probably the same vendors
that do the BIOS but they say well do it
a little differently and we'll do some
things that will so what is the
hackintosh do it resets the expectations
at Apple house what does that mean well
I mean the Apple operating system wants
to look at the hardware so what does it
say hackintosh do it makes the existing
hardware look like out the hardware so
how does it do that
well what does it need from the hardware
it needs to know how to configure the
hardware it needs to know how to reset
the power when they shut the lid turn up
throw them put into the hibernate wake
it back up again when you open it up so
it's pretty simple stuff really it's not
that hard and you know well because it's
Apple they want to change some of the
names and things because they don't want
this running on any PC so that's in fact
what's happened is you look at an apple
BIOS it has some of the features we'll
talk about and they're different
the PCs in some respects they will talk
a little bit more about that too so the
constraints that you have about this
activity is for resetting the
expectations once the ACP there there
are some ECPI tables I'm a little bit
out of sequence y'all get into that a
little bit later what a CPI is a CPI
advanced configuration and power
interface so that part of the app of the
system is a bunch of tables to talk
about the configuration and interfaces
so when you were providing services the
operating system the hackintosh does the
same thing but it changed the name so
that the applet is familiar with the
name of the objects that is looking at
and there are some things that are done
in completely in Sona PC biases and what
the akatosh does is it provides the
additional methods so that maybe fixes
some of the things that are that are
problematic with the with the system so
there are some constraints though when
the ACPI tables are read in and the end
loaded to the operating system they
can't be changed so what it was a
hackintosh do is it it sits between that
loading interface and it loads another
copy of the tables in the memory you can
change that copy the tables it can
change the names it can add additional
components to that to the tables to look
in another table for this the similar
function that's needed and that's where
they can make changes to the to the
methods that are done so the original
ACPI
the original base of the other bios a
cbi table stays the same except for the
name changes and then additional
functions are added as well so that
enhanced all the function set the
athletes so there are some glute loaders
that can do this they can rename it
substitute these objects and to bridge
the gaps between what the pc bios offers
and what the apple operating system
expects now there are some additional
things as well because there are some
harbor differences that are not in the
bios that have to be dealt with through
external drivers or to not leave the
Apple operating system
Allah has a lot for criminal extensions
are thirty part third-party extensions
that it supports
always has always will and these are the
places where you add an additional
proposed for Hardware that that is
specific to the system that you have so
a lot of the work that's done a katashi
is really these kernel extensions do you
have to do the work well I mean if you
if you buy or you do some pretty
standard hardware you won't a lot of
people have already compiled these
things so I need to do is find them and
where'd you put them in together in the
soup that you're making the soup which
is called the hackintosh so um look a
little bit back a little bit deeper into
the BIOS and the AP so Elias is the
basic I input/output system what the
bias is so it's the part of the machine
that initializes the hardware that makes
it ready for an operating system to be
loaded and and to take control of it in
and use it better so so it's a program
and initializes the hardware it finds
and loads the operating system and
provide services to the operating system
to such time as every system can serve
itself it also can provide some control
to the interview interrupt structures
well the interrupts structures are
needed because when there are events how
does the operating system find out what
those events
and then what does it do next so that's
the advanced programming interrupt
controller and there's two pieces to
that these days one is the local of a
pick and the other one is at i/o a pick
so why are these things important you
find out later that the processor has it
the local a pick and then Iowa a pick is
in the chip sets both those things work
together but so what that means is that
you have when you're gonna have a
solution for this merging between what
the Apple hardware what what the PC
hardware has what the Apple software
expects is you have to find something
that supports the processor and the
chipset and the system in turn running
both those things together and then that
gets you looking further down the road
and then back to the advanced
configuration and power interface this
is the thing that is exposing to the
operating system how the system is
configured enumerates all the devices
and all the power events and all the
voltage levels and all the stuff that's
specific to that hardware it's brought
up in these tables some of these tables
are usable solve them or not most of
them are based around the differentiated
system description saver table that has
most of the things that are enumerated
there are additional tables that we'll
talk about later the SSD T is part of
that so what does a CPI is then it's it
replaces a plug-and-play if you remember
what that might have been remember some
PC things and the advanced power
management so that's kind of where that
is any questions
okay so you have a CPI you have the one
that's on PC and there's a difference
between that and what's in what's in an
Apple so there is software called the
bootloader logically speaking this is a
piece that is really the shim that sits
between the the BIOS and and and the
boot up and the operating system so the
bootloader can take care of cleanings
some cleanup stuff there's a lot of
things than pcs that aren't used or
needed by Apple there's no need to keep
those things loaded around so I can drop
those out of memory and then the
important thing that it does is it
renames the tables the objects and the
tables that are specific to a PC to make
it look like what an apple would like to
see so there are other things that have
to happen because some of these biases
are really differentiated for Windows
systems are not differentiated for
apples so there's gaps that have to be
developed sometimes here they're simple
some of the device support that you have
has to get implemented in device
specific methods that are in the a CPI
some of it is dealt with in external
drivers so you can go over the ECPI
stuff this here hardware is very similar
to an apple chip but it might be a
little bit different model number or a
different some subsystem ID so if you
wanted to get started what do you need
to do well you need to know something
about the equipment you're working with
let's assume you have found an abandoned
computer and then why I call it
abandoned because if you make a mistake
with this that this process
if you don't want to be losing anything
so considered have been you know it's
like okay I this could blow up if they
go away I'm gonna try it anyway you know
if you go slowly you probably okay but
if you're you get in a hurry or if you
make a mistake you know you can fry it
it's possible to fry computer with the
system I did once it turned out to be a
system that I really like having so this
it was really bad for me and have an
eSATA port next door other course I like
to work with life kind of Miss that one
but I fried the CPU on because I play
with the underworld do stuff so don't do
that
so the thing is you need to know
specifics about the the machine that
you're going to work on because you're
going to try to fit the the a CPI tables
and the kernel extensions to that
equipment and more importantly try to
fit that to an operating system as well
and then you know you need to know more
about what that hardware is and then you
need to find that or support for that
hardware in the community so that's why
you need to know the specifics for the
processor the chipset the audio the
graphics and the network controllers
because you know almost have a computer
it doesn't sing to you and then the
other thing to find out is that a lot of
this information is precipitously
gathered in other words people started
getting into it and they're talking
about on the forums after a while they
started developing a language
context work with the information but
it's not very well structured you're
going to be doing a lot of research
you're gonna be looking at a lot of
forms and you know some things are
conflicting in the information that
you're going to see you gotta wonder
like what does this mean so you have to
do a lot more research a little bit
understanding so you really need to have
a lot of patience this is not you know
something you could do what we're not
you could if you had exactly the same
processor and exactly the same chipset
as somebody who had already done that
work and they did a superb job
describing step by step what you needed
to do and you had the pieces that they
had and you bought the same operating
system that they did because this isn't
something that you're gonna well however
you get the operating system is between
you and you but you know you really
should buy the operating system because
well maybe you'll feel better about it
maybe more but that policy out there so
the other thing is to be inquisitive
about during this process like word it's
gonna be learning gonna learning
something new and different maybe it
won't be exciting for you and if it's
not well you know what you don't need to
do it but it was fun for me and I really
enjoyed yourself be inquisitive but also
be specific in your messaging when
you're gonna ask questions you know a
lot of times you see in the forums
people ask the question well it doesn't
work well that's great you know if
you're if you run a support organization
you know that's the worst thing you
could hear that's that's like you know
it's a brain fart you need to have if
you want to get the response for your
messages you need to tell them what
processor version you're using what the
steps you took to some degree of
correctness and they can help you with
and actually they can help pretty
quickly when you do those things and
then be humble about it right you know
a lot of this is not stuff that it's
hard to do some of it is but you know
when you when you make a make you when
you make a win celebrate it and you know
just remember that you know you weren't
the only one to do it
and you weren't the first maybe were the
first on this particular model and
that's guy too but if you're humble
about it
people will come you and appreciate you
more for it the most important thing to
do is to take good notes because you're
going to be moving things around you'd
be trying a couple things out you may
try a combination of kernel extensions
and ACPI tables and configuration
there's a lot of moving parts in the in
the whole thing and you know you want to
make one small step at a time and you
want to develop a good experiment so
that goes with the good taking the good
notes and doing the backgrounds
understanding of what the what the
process is so what do you need to have
well unfortunately you need to have
access to an Apple computer or somebody
who has one because what you have to do
is you have to create an image and
installer image and probably put it on a
USB Drive so that's best done in an
Apple box
you really can't deal with the VM this
people recommend not using a VM for that
so you need to have an existing Apple
Computer
Natacha that has a blogging system model
that you could put the media onto a USB
stick so you need the USB stick and then
the abandoned computer with an Intel CPU
and then they even want to make sure
that that Intel CPU and that chipset are
supported on a particular version of the
Apple operating system the older boxes
may or may not be supported on Mojave my
experience has been that the really
really old ones won't the ones that are
about five or six years old probably
could run Wahhabi on but Mojave may not
be your best bet to install it's more
complicated it's more restrictive
there's just problem Bobby and Catalina
the latest one a lot more problems so
you may be better off looking at a
maverick server or assembly but that
depends so once you've determined which
OS fits your hardware a number of them
will but start with maybe an older one
and then you pick up pick your operating
system so where do you start when you
have all these things that you have you
have to identify the processor that
you've said in the controller's so how
do you do that well there's a couple
tools out there if you have if it runs
Windows from that box that you download
program called cpuid it can get you the
information about the processor in the
chipset and it might get you some
information about the audio boards as
well if you have Linux that you can you
know do a live boot on that and you're
going to download and run f w TS and
dump it and basically what that does is
it gathers the information that lettuce
would have like the DMI information of
DM ID code the processor information for
proxy when you info the PCI structure
from LS PCI and other things so it does
that all in one fell swoop and that's
every TS is a pretty cool tool
anyway because it'll also check your the
compatibility of your ECPI with the a
CPI spec not with Apple at the a CPI
spec so you can do things like test us a
little work you can do sleep state
testing if you want to do with it as
well fairly complicated I don't
recommend it the only reason I'm
mentioning here at this point is so that
you can gather some of the information
about this processor and chipset and the
system that you're gonna work with so
then you want to find where the
operating system that would fit that
that combination there's several that
fit so there's some that don't
so when you find the operating system
version then you buy it you know they do
look for the installation guide and pour
through those really understand what
they are we read them a couple times
because some of the things were saying
are subtle some of the some of these
guides are written like you already have
done it because the person who wrote the
guide already did it but they didn't
understand that maybe you don't quite
understand what they're saying the
terminology they're using may be
specific to their group or to their form
whether the way they this they just do
things and it may not be something you
completely understand so you know look
at that first and then the other thing
is said for a particular processor
chipset there may be some issues with it
support may or may not be great for for
that kind of combination where you're
going to find most of the problems
really with network controllers like
these an F ports most of the time those
are pretty well supported the Wi-Fi
cards my phone cards were terrible if
you have like an Intel chip for a Wi-Fi
component you're probably not going to
be able to use it because the Apple
doesn't support it and nobody's
the kernel driver for the century knows
it's unfortunate isn't sarin a lot of
machines but that's not gonna work out
while you may have to buy a network card
never allow my children to make it work
you don't want to do that right off the
bat want to make sure you got that thing
working first and then once you have a
working that make the investment in the
car so you look through all the issues
that are there and the issues are often
with the installation guide which over
time changes because over time the
operating system changes and all these
other kernel extensions and pieces that
people had written those get operated
those get improved and you know pushes
things out for getting it done then you
get the operating system that's where
all the easiest thing how do you get it
well if you have an apple system already
that you're about to upgrade you have a
great opportunity to get the operating
system if it's the one that you want
when it comes to the upgrade part and
your rate has started stop it and then
run look at the installation guides and
they can run this thing call I think
create install media to basically take
that installation step putting it on
that machine put it on a USB stick even
if you wants you can upgrade that
machine but once you do that it takes
away the pieces that are in place
there's some image files that are there
once you do the installation on the
operating on that Apple box it takes
away that image so you can't use it
again
the name weight this you obtain the
operating system through the legal means
set of service
what Grievous might oh okay well they
don't take that out from next one no
let's good point that's a good point I
guess I didn't read the agreement sorry
[Music]
the whole thing yeah I didn't read the
whole thing I did not I did not read the
whole thing
no I didn't okay good point
so what problems can arise with this
situation well when the vendor bill said
about PC they have a little bit of time
to market so what what do they do about
the a CPI well maybe they implement
enough if that windows can run I mean
their contract with Microsoft may say
you need these things in here but there
may be some additional things that that
could be in there but Microsoft takes
care of it
Apple does so you need to provide some
of the functionality that all right that
isn't there to make it work and that
that that may be true the most important
Alvin Peters HP's are better so you know
given model given given day you know
vendors do different things with API and
then there's through all the all the
reading that I've done there are a
several places where BIOS bugs pop up
and there's somewhat subtle so you know
you may want to the reason you want to
do all the research is to make sure that
you have enough
nation to guide you with the process you
may run into a problem with a particular
choice of computer your computer may not
be may not be worth it if the issue is
severe and you know best to stop before
you do any purchasing anything else like
business of our system so the big things
are when you get to a point with the
with your hackintosh you've got it work
I feel pretty good about okay let's turn
on the CPU power management stuff you
got to be really careful about that
because that's where you can run through
situations where the specification for
the for the given Harbor that you have
are probably not robust and if you start
doing things like pushing the CPU clock
up high you might over you might burn it
up people interval just down to low and
you put a setting in there like that you
can break the out on the motherboard so
those are not and that means that if you
replace the CPU is still bricked so you
gotta be careful when you play with the
CPU our management stuff
yeah yeah that's why I need to go with
what all the components are the
patrollers the North Bridge the South
Bridge the chipset and that you know the
CPU and sometimes you'll see it in
installation guys they'll say well this
is for you know Dell models 6230 oh well
it's for an i7 chip and I got an i5 chip
do I proceed with this mmm
certainly what I don't want to do the
cpu stuff there are some things you
might stay away from like they're called
CPU friendly that's that's what you
definitely don't want to be using when
you're when you're first exploring so
there are like you say subtle
differences between the ones that were
installed so install guys we have really
good definition which chipsets are part
they make form and some of them don't
they may have a really good processor
definition sometimes we'll just go with
you know is it a pass well or is it
abroad well general a general genre of
chips you know process your type and
maybe that's good enough
most of the later versions of the kernel
extensions are probably okay and in that
case then your your issues are really do
I get the CPI tables right
and then there's other things too when
you get to the later versions of the
operating systems Apple operating
systems they turn on system integrity
protection which is their way of
basically the root privilege the the
system that you would have to touch the
portion of the system you have to touch
to install these kernel extension
service it agreed only and the only way
you could turn them off is running a
program that has to be run during the
recovery mode so you have to make sure
you have a recovery mode installed and
that's where you get into creative media
doing it the right way to do it the
right way to do is to use the Apple tool
to build media because it puts the
Installer image on a USB and it puts a
recovery partition on the USB as well
so you'd run from the recovery partition
to just like reset the password on your
box or turn off the system integrity
protection so that you would probably
would like to do that at some point or
if you're not feeling comfortable with
it loader loader older version start
with an older version of the operating
system
so that continuing down the path of
doing this you want to design controlled
experiments that's the boot and they
stop programs to the finishing your
computer it's not a big deal but if you
have a really old box you probably want
to use something like a nutburger
chameleon if you have a newer one
clovers your busier is your best bet
clovers the best support these days most
of the new kernel extensions the tools
that do the configuration changes and
they all support clover and a lot of the
several forms won't answer any questions
about the other ones so I want to
support it out there that there's older
versions and then you learn how to ask
for help
and who to ask there's there's times
that there's there's a forum called 20
man x86 and then their big thing is you
know beast multibeast method of
installing basically you install and
they're really anal about how they get
the operating system to the Box you have
to basically download it from your from
your Apple ID from the Apple Store
well alright there's other ways of
getting the Apple operating system and
that I choose not to use that method but
so I haven't really touched it but you
know beast is one way that was stalled
with the operating system to the box and
then multi pieces that is the post
installation part that does all the
kernel adjustments and all the things to
make it make it work great
so if you go over to the Sandy Mac you
have so many question about the universe
multibeast installs a no we don't talk
about that yet and here's why they have
a they have a page that we refer you to
and it goes a great length that tells
you nothing about what happened but
apparently the people that run 20 back
did some things that upset the people in
other other parts of the communities so
there's you know that's where you have
to learn new it could ask so to go with
insanely Mac you're going to be a pretty
generic otherwise
I've had good successfully or a sex life
so when you're making making it work
get the graphics in and the keyboard
mouse thing won't do first that's that's
your best bet you don't have to have the
cues and such but you get you get the
basics going and don't rush installing
and kernel extensions the those are the
things that are for the drivers for the
heart of it you don't the apple doesn't
know what you're done
Apple friendly hardware stuff like here
why fight you just get it working first
get a feel for what the configuration
stuff is and always do this in small
steps take good notes and backup the
configuration so basically install with
the USB stick and then boot from the USB
stick changing the configuration on a
stick
I'll tell you like it and then once you
do that then you can copy the portion of
the installation over to the system and
they just are booting from the system
and then you know after all that a
redress back to clover so it'll make it
look like an operating system and make
it look like a particular version of the
the system you can find that out there
are places you can go to find out what
models in Mac we're supporting the
particular processor or a lifetime
process that you use and you might want
to think or two of those different ages
it really doesn't make a lot of sense to
me I mean some of these names that they
have are
well maybe said I'm at one time over
MacBook Air pro or MacBook Air
right so well what's the difference
there isn't a whole lot except some of
it if you know that the operating system
takes advantage of of some of the
acceleration and the other models there
might be excessive to pick one of those
so it comes right down to it hits at the
USB stick there's two ways though you
use the old-style Master Boot Record
where you have portion of the actual
system BIOS interfered now it works with
the Master Boot Record you load up a
boot code it will find the sector on
them on the USB stick or already going
to do next and run up or you can use the
efi system partition the efi partition
where you have portions of bootloader on
it for different operations that you
have more flexible
nor flexibility with the efi but you may
have a problem with the bias of your
machine that it doesn't support it so if
you have a really old machine why say
Dell 6320 you probably have to use the
MBR map
because the although that particular
system has be it fine it's really not
that well supported I've had a lot of
trouble with it and we're really not
doing anything with that right now is
they got other machines to play with but
so the advice is though is that kind of
like the way to go
so these are some references for a CPI
discovery if you're if you get to the
point where you're where you feel like
you're you want to do more with this
thing you've got a system basically
running and now you're going to look at
building your own dsdt changes are you
going to do more of that work with a
dynamic DST team the more that you can
do with the configuration ahead of when
the operating system loads the more
flexibility you have with that operating
system changes it will when they go for
version say cierra
- hi Sierra there's a significant change
in how they structure things if you go
to Mojave they change the file
partitions on the disk so things that
you could do with the recovery portion
of your USB stick on I Sierra you can't
do with hobby because its uses the AP FS
houses a completely different sin
corrected and all myself
very different so these are some places
that you could look for some general
information most their linings based
this is just because I was lazy and I
have a lot of time to make this perfect
presentation there's better places to
look but once you get into it so join
the forum's look around at the install
guides look at some things that are on
github and then go back to the forums
and start from the end of the really
long threats that look interesting to
you because that's probably where the
current working progress is it's very
young structure it's the forms you're
terrible in to search in my opinion I
have not found a good way to search them
and if you find a good way to tell me so
I'm gonna try to reboot the box and
superego
so what
see the
the Dell logo in the startup of the
v-fib
that's trying to find the different
partitions I got three
you don't see what I'm looking at right
now but basically it's tough a little
window things the boot the clover allows
you to select other part of partition
sue I have this triple boot I have
Windows - two apples running on it and
yeah it took a little while to do it
because Windows isn't that easy to play
with there you go
it says Dell on the box
well you know just another operating
system
thing that's really kind of cool about
this is I don't have to write a driver
for this ESP Thunder I must be seeing a
thunderbolt it just worked I have an
inland
I don't have the Dell USB see you
network - so no but that was Sierra you
know once you look at it's like okay
it's us so one thing not on this machine
but on an uninspiring I did yeah
actually when you mean if you have like
that desktop computer you're going to
find that a desktop is going to be
easier to work with and the reason for
that is the BIOS doesn't have as much
power management stuff on it the end of
live don't worry about you really have
to worry about hibernating a desktop so
there's a lot less crap I mean kernel
extensions that you have to deal with
so now this one I'm showing the I'm
showing the will hobby on here but it's
not coming through on the USB sorry
about that well kind of cool showing the
night picture now it was showing that
yeah the daylight picture during the day
and Catalina's kind of fun too when you
when you see Catalina running into a saw
you see the Sun different light is
shining on the on the island of Catalina
South Vietnam Los Angeles but it's local
timezone it's not the times other words
actually it their work showing so
slightly yeah
are there any questions thoughts
concerns comments yeah yeah they do
oh well you just let them update oh yeah
I mean there's nothing special about it
um if you do this if you do the
hackintosh you where you keep most of
the changes in the ACPI tables and you
don't do too much with kernel extensions
anytime you do something with a kernel
extension it's gonna be reloaded because
it's going to be a new operating system
is to be new new part portions of it so
that's gonna change things but if you
can keep most of the changes in the a
CPI tables and and let clover do that it
won't be any problem at all yeah in fact
when you when you install
and install mojave it'll reboot a couple
of times and float responsibility last
boot and smarten to know that there's a
pre a preload that has to be run so that
it figures all that stuff on I really
haven't done anything with the TPM chips
you can do stuff with file crypt but you
have to be careful with the key as you
would in a any situation
I'm not work that area I haven't really
seen a lot of discussion on that but
there are some places that won't we can
find out more about that there aren't
there is some support through TPM chips
I don't know if there's anything for t2
chips on non-apple Harbor I don't think
there is something that's terrible it's
an Apple only situation right
that's that's turned off it doesn't
force it
you have full hardware compatibility on
that laptop or this one is no because it
came with me up an older version of the
Broadcom chip and this the the brought
conscience really interested with
Broadcom chip there's an extensive the
DW 1828 is the one that this one has
there are like three different serial
numbers on some system numbers on it and
there's three different ways that it's
supported I have the one that's not well
supported so I don't mental capability
so but the USB C port works great and I
have network connectivity with I have
like a rj45 cable a USB external one of
the applications interface with the
magic touch
I haven't run that to know for sure
touch bar there's been some discussion
about that that I that I've read I don't
really know but I think it's it's at
least partially supported yeah
the way to find out is to look to see
you know with anybody have any trouble
with it
some people have have trouble working
and it depends on the hardware right
some people have made it to work for
some of those applications this one it's
an XPS 9350 I wouldn't use it as a first
choice just because it's you know it's
got a got a binky's keyboard eyes the
the form factor is nice and I kind of
like it you know
but I really liked mine 6230 better I
like the full size the touch and feel of
a full-size keyboard this is kind of
chickadee this personal thing right so
but there's there's all kinds of if you
go to insanely Mac and take a look
around look at the install guys on they
have a sirs that lenovo's HP's so does
homo-sex latitude is not just dell
latitude so they support and it's not
that they support them right the
installation guys have said you know
you're on your own
they said right there in big red letters
you could fry your computer don't blame
me you know it's like it's if you give
you that's why you have to be careful
you have to know the cpu does chipset
that you're working with
if you grab somebody's bag of clover
installation with all the kernel
extensions you may be getting their
problem - so you you want to be careful
what one of the kernel extensions that
you're that you're putting on on your
clover partition that could you know
like with the CPU friendly stuff is on
there but it's for a processor that's
not your processor
but I've had a lot of fun I've I've done
maybe five or six aquatic monster
[Applause]