pretty acceptable so welcome everyone
golf gang Roberts these pirates whatever
you want to call yourselves these things
try to stay gender-neutral but otherwise
thanks for joining me thanks for coming
out and seeing this little shadow Rooney
let's talk just walk about whatever we
want to call it these days this is the
kind of introduction to my talk tomorrow
as well called not so secure software
factories that's where I'll be actually
digging into something and taking the
parts and all this other fun stuff but
today this is an introductory course
this is gonna sue no knowledge of
software development containers DevOps
like if somebody asks you to make an app
right now you'd have quandary right so
preliminary information kind of set the
tone what is DevOps what is that dev sec
ops security yes is the thought of
including security in the forefront of
DevOps we've been doing DevOps for
decades now
people don't get clerical about it but
now we've found out that these CICE
platforms and pipelines and automation
engines and all these other functions
that we've built into each other don't
have security at all and not even the
best of money so it works so we're
finding a lot of exploits and software
supply chain issues that we wouldn't
have really thought of you know a couple
of years ago and this is something that
actually other industries have had to
deal with for decades right in
distribution and large machining
practices the supply chain is absolutely
crucial right you don't want to get an
Intel chip that's not an actually an
Intel chip and they do make off-brand
fake third-party chips so
putting that in your laptop you're
trying to sell that's an important thing
to have now we're having that issue with
supply chains in software and how it's
being delivered as well not just how
it's being built that how it's being
deployed and how it's being used and
that's a little bit more in-depth
tomorrow we'll go into the onion light
layers of container security and a
couple other bits but yeah this is
precursory sort of bits here now someone
said that software is eating the world
I'm really surprised that's working on
my hot spot don't use any Wi-Fi in any
conventional don't use that anyway what
software is eating the world right
everybody interactive software mostly
right now through apps usually through
your primary device there phone nowadays
that's weird thing to think but that's
usually most people for primary devices
so we see a lot of these apps we see
lots apps for X I just got this watch I
download three apps to users watch
absolutely insane right this is smart
home I have teach as a few years ago did
a smart things stuff before they are
acquired by Samsung which is cool
because we're things have two apps and
Samsung button so they made their own
versions of those centers of course so
then I have four apps on my phone just
for that little ecosystem not to mention
the other dozen apps I had to run my
smart home enterprise right you know say
I've come gotten out of that but IOT
devices have not stopped becoming more
prevalent right you heard about the
other nuts you know smart connected now
LG's got one and it can send you a text
when it thinks that it's been on for too
long right like if you forgot it on here
away from the house but it's not smart
enough to turn itself off okay cool this
is smart stuff right now we've got you
know smart infrastructure as well okay
so anybody know where what this is
no Oak Ridge is a little bit longer than
color that's a cool little spot weird
people but this is actually knits hands
I probably butchered that name Iran Iran
this is a nuclear station and it was hit
with something that you probably have
heard of called Stuxnet right now
arguably that wasn't connected to
internet like a lot of these other smart
IOT devices but a software attack
crippled this nuclear safety okay
infrastructure right this is not even
going into the recent tax on Ukraine's
infrastructure and even locally we've
seen issues of power distribution
stations so now the smarts have started
to become sentient as well
we've got connected little smart classes
with 5g devices that can scan people's
faces very quickly identify all right
yeah you probably you're thinking I
guess we're not there that's that's
that's then it's not a problem
okay keep telling yourself you might
have heard about some of the you know
stockade jumping issues that they've had
New York MTA well now they're installing
some cameras with facial recognition
capabilities it is here we've had this
sort of technology kind of put in our
faces for years and now starting to
become more commonplace with advanced
software and we're just are we gonna
start chopping these off with hats off
to a become hey hopefully it's also
going to our defense all right
this is Nicholas shillings effort
deficit cops across the entire DoD
there's pretty impressive
not a lot of people have had some issue
with gitlab before about how they're
selling in Iceland I think is Isis
horrible and also the fun jazzy
there is some moral issue there but
surprise surprise every vendor you've
ever heard of is selling to the
government there are hundreds of vendors
in this software Factory you check that
it's actually pretty cool but what's
important about this is that it took the
DoD or ten years over a decade to get on
virtualization and they've stood up
kubernetes clusters in months that's the
kind of heat that we're feeling from
other actors okay that's on state level
so software really is starting to eat
work and my name is Ken Monty I'm here
to scare you and tell you everything's
still alright alright as everyone even
involves around security knows that our
role is kind of broken by hey it's
alright you can see my programs on
github you can see my posts on
Twitter otherwise during the day today I
work for for your software we are a
value-added reseller a lot of other bars
just move came around but we do love
extra fun stuff hands-on workshops
webinars consulting a lot of hands-on
engagement our enablement forces is what
kind of sets us apart we specialize with
public sector entities so we actually
work with Nicholas Schilling put
together that that SEC ops
we specialize in secure platforms DevOps
and des analytics which usually go
hand-in-hand pretty well my job as the
lead solution architect is put a lot of
these things together and mash them
until they work for our customers and
that's usually really fun and also
nerve-wracking at the same time but we
have got amazing capabilities in just a
couple
these softwares platforms up the years
and thinking back to whenever I did
qbasic like we've we've come a long way
right now I'm not setting irq settings
for my new sound blaster Cartman okay so
how did this happen how do we go from
such simplicity this is such a large
complex technologically evolved world
how is software eating the world in fact
well some people would say it's you know
these boots everybody's got these
software boot camps learn Django in 31
days and that's fine for its purpose if
I want to learn Django in 31 days cool
if your PHP program you want to learn
Django say one probably good there
doesn't do pretty alright but they're
missing a lot of fundamental so what
happens is that spit out people who know
Jenkins
nothing underlay nothing as far as how
to work with a source how to contribute
with the team and at work Enterprise
I've got friends who have done this
exact same thing and they've been stuck
because they can't really fit piece of
software practice but they are very
helpful they expose a lot of people and
they've actually gotten people a lot of
different good places another argument
is that the Internet is a lot more
available right there's a lot more
information out there on it too you
don't have to listen to dial tones wait
for things to load if you want to search
something I can okay google halo go by
and it gives it to me on this it's so
fast that's the Internet
that's a good argument to the I think
that you know computers now are just
kind of a little cool hopefully I keep
telling myself that I've been telling
myself that since I was a kid
but people agree
one of the other things that I think
really helps is that there's usually a
decent bit of money Mike's also cool
right lots of people like one you can
make a lot of money and that is again
cool and you can do it all from the
internet most important though that's
easy
oh my gosh it's so much easier now all
right like you want to build an app you
can build an app in a short amount of
time you can take a an idea go from
concept actual production money-making
business without writing a single line
of code now you do it all from there now
you can learn how to do it all on the
Internet and it's so easy all you got to
do is pay ten bucks a month of some
subscription service like Skillshare or
whatever they're Hawking online now and
you know max Academy and the udemy's and
all this other stuff cheap easy boom
easy it's all that means now all right
I think that's really how things have
kind of exploded one of the other things
that have kind of helped is we've kind
of gotten our ducks in a row over the
last couple of decades technology's
right not to say that there isn't lots
of innovation out there millions
millions funds projects but through
decades of learning practice which
standardized you've optimized them with
automating this is theme is gonna be
very important I operate threes and
you're gonna see a lot of a lot of car
factory references all right so one of
them is this amazing new tool all right
you can standardize on anybody done any
sort of car work a curiosity change a
tire even brakes whatever's is a simple
stuff right cool you can YouTube it and
learn right that's literally like if
there's some weird thing that goes on
with someone's brake so hold you to it
find out oh that's a pin I just got it
look like school gotta go buy that final
so if you do this enough you learn that
if you work on imports or domestic cars
you end up
different toolsets right soon enough
hopefully maybe you can standardize
themself but otherwise there's a
different form standardization right
like I have a bunch of tools at home and
they're all lime-green REO B's the
oneplus platform
I've standardized on their toolset and I
just plug in a battery in this and plug
in the battery listen then I've got
tools here and there and everywhere and
it's great all right I can do anything I
want
I've got saws I've never even used but I
can use them now if you are like me and
while all these lime-green little
components everywhere and don't work you
know you get into this little eye track
that did not scale that well but um
there are hundreds of different
open-source software libraries out there
that you can choose one as far as tools
but whenever you are thinking of tools
the only thing I will say whatever your
objective whatever your workflow
whatever your mission is check out open
source ok this should already be kind of
instilled with most of us but most arts
kind of keeps you away from locking
ask anyone who's had to deal with SAT on
Oracle Amazon had a party when they
switched off their last world full
circle that's how momentous it was that
is but whatever you do go to open source
models you do have that little gravity
being to migrate or do other things or
integrate in things that are just much
more capable than closed source
proprietary
this is a software you get this is the
only thing you ever get right so we've
standardized our tools we're
standardized on open source now we were
optimizing our processes optimizing is
pretty key because you can take a very
funky process that takes days and weeks
to mince with proper optimization ask
any C developer and they'll tell you
that much right Java as well who don't
talk to me about
but optimization is very important
because without that you can't properly
automate and we've been on mating for
decades too and we're getting a lot
better than just bash scripts which is
really nice so this is the trifecta
again without standardizing on set of
tools we can't optimize our workflows to
automate
does that make sense if you've got
eighteen different sort of platforms to
support eighteen different ways of doing
something your workflows are not gonna
be optimized your processes are not
going to be animated and even if you do
try to automate all your different
processes we're gonna spend more time
maintaining those automation workflows
then it gives you anything dying right
so now we're kind of getting into this
automation bit and I am here to kind of
the common thought that robots are gonna
take our jobs automation it's gonna
destroy the industry computers are just
gonna be bleeping and blooping and
that's humans are gone ten years twelve
years whatever you know IOC said we're
all gone it's just gonna be computers
but don't work
robots are actually our friends right so
automation is here to help you not to
replace you it if automation will be a
thing that sets us apart as far as the
actual ability to adapt human beings
supposedly have the inherent ability to
adapt right and automation is coming and
being able to use automation is
absolutely crucial think about the power
tools again right I got a screwdriver
here I told the build a deck I don't
want to build that deck you give me a
impact driver and a good drill oh I'll
build a deck
but you have to learn how to use that
tool right cuz if you don't you're gonna
poke your eye out so that's the
difference learn how to use the power
tool right so learn how to use robots
all right how to build these robots and
again we've been doing it for decades
we're doing building batch scripts and
Python scripts and Perl scripts for days
and days and days on that but that's
been usually secluded to a small subset
people right you have to know how to
program in those languages to actually
use those operational processes so we
have not really enjoyed automation as a
society it's because it's still kind of
hard in most cases if you are looking
into IOT smart home automation sort of
stuff on today I would really bother for
a little while because even if you do
try to automate all your things and tell
your Alexis to you know set your scenes
to this stack in the other it doesn't
really work out that well all the times
a lot of events miss it's really hokey
yeah I've spent a lot of time setting it
up
one thing breaks you have to start all
over again it's just okay all right it's
not simple now what is simple though I
think as far as automation and this is
one of the key takeaways if you're not
automating if you don't know an
automation platform I suggest ansible
because pretty much everybody can use it
all right there's chef and puppet and
the stack the other out there and a
couple other platforms and hey you could
just autumn you can automate with PHP if
you really want I've seen PHP shell
scripts
but blur automation
I think ansible is great because it's
extremely simple with the others you
have to learn Ruby or Python or some
other sort of subset actually really use
it now cool thing about ansible is that
you can read it from top to bottom it
just executes you could read what's
going on and pretty much anybody will
understand you I can give you a playbook
right now you'll be able to read it I
can give my CEO a playbook and you'll
generally understand what's going on
right as long as like tests are going on
you can use it for pretty much
everything not just application
deployment not just you know web servers
or whatever beacon ping endpoints it
might have heard Starbucks throughout
their entire enterprise to use ansible
who can automate their network tens of
thousands of notes that's pretty cool
you do with a lot of weird stuff I gave
a talk a couple years ago somewhere else
about automating my home network which
has dual Wang capabilities also the fun
stuff with a lambda fired function for
an Alexa skill so I could yell at my
echo and restart my network and just
whenever I felt like terrorizing my
girlfriend one other cool things about
ansible is that as agents that's really
important and secure enclaves like the
ones that I get to work around a
non-negotiable thing is putting an agent
on a box I mean I'm going to have a
piece of software running on all your
machines with root access okay like
that's not gonna happen
do you do that easily sometimes for
something but but it's agentless which
means that a can interact with API it
can interact with Windows machines
connect with your machines and all sorts
right very important a little bit more
secure that way too so what does it look
like right this is a ansible playbook
let's read this together install and
start Apache on what hosts all of them
for installing servers everywhere
variables anyone who's programmed done
automation you know that you need
variables in to modify your execution
right simple variables HTTP port max
clients no problem
remote user root talk about that tasks
we're install base you need package the
young module we're targeting the package
httpd we're ensuring that the latest
version is out there cool we write some
configuration file with a little
templating module we have a template
file it's gonna take some of these
variables and put it in there and then
we're gonna start the SERPs
it's pretty human readable that's pretty
easy understand and we can push this out
to thousands and thousands like that and
we can run it again and we run again
next week it's gonna make sure that
Apaches updated because it's gonna make
sure that the state is latest very cool
and this is Gamal I'm actually told that
it's not yet another markup language
something else it's like a recursive but
either way this should be you know
pretty simple and pretty easy overall
which again we're pushing that easy
button okay now if this looks familiar
to you then you're probably in the
DevOps
ecosystem because pretty much everything
is ya know that's right yes right if
you're doing any kubernetes you have fun
stuff that's all again I'm about to
change my fallacy animal engineer but
otherwise that's kind of where he goes
into our next a little bit with DevOps
even we're automating now we're going to
kind of keep optimizing all right and
this recursive cycle is kind of what's
kind of feed our system but before you
the box again this is cursory sort of
information what is DevOps who does
DevOps I hate that phrase but who does
DevOps in there
enterprise their team organization at
home last year I told you all to get
home labs
y'all got home labs yeah you're doing
DevOps in your home labs now right it's
good but um it's good we've got a couple
people who are doing what do you think
about them UPS if you sat through any
sort of you know presentation online a
little webinar something you you you
probably instantly think cloud uh
there's a cloud containers pipelines
pipelines and synergy synergy consider
your see interview vertical integration
customer experience huh all right
that's DevOps right yeah kind of that's
where this a chart of you know why did
that scale properly on that bar whether
this is this is where this ice chart of
tools comes back to the haunt us okay
right this is what people think when
they think them up sometimes which
there's a lot of DevOps you stuff here
but you don't need to focus on this okay
we boil the ocean and we render to the
salts what do we get everything Z animal
like I said earlier everything is code
if you don't work with get you need to
learn how to use get you don't have a
github account all I've got to say is
it's 2019 yo its 2019 if you don't have
a github account my boss has a github
account and he's he's a sale to do he
just stars all my repos I don't know why
but anyway DevOps a couple other core
tenets is at this point we've been on me
right we should I should have drilled
that into your head one of those bright
green Rio be join us we're automating
everything and with that we're trying to
automate the process automation so this
pushing to get that actually kicks off
another process that continuous
integration will help deliver an
application maybe later and then that
means that as we commit our application
should be released will if it's in a
pipeline that's continuously good-looker
right well we're pushing out
applications thousands of times
cool the push of a button that's that
must be marvelous good golly on your
Jenkins server but without monitoring
without seeing the logs where you're
failing without this rapid feedback
you're not gonna be able to figure out
what's going wrong when you move this
DevOps containers sort of life cycle bit
ah you need these logs and this feedback
to actually figure out what's going on
because you're not gonna SSH into these
containers okay you're not gonna go in
and fix boxes something's wrong in
execution you fix it and you rebuild
that's it you're not fixing hundreds of
boxes you're pushing out hundreds of new
images with your so cool stuff that is
DevOps when we've got this you know
synergy thing you know that's all the
fun stuff
and unfortunately for Moore's
organizations they can only do a couple
of these steps properly some Vulcan code
problem someone can operate properly
most of them cannot secure and test
properly gone in some large
organizations where they don't write the
tests and they're handling earth some
part of your large amount of expendable
income per month but either way that is
DevOps and before we think it's just you
know two people fighting yes the
developers and operators there's
actually a couple other folks in the
room they're trying to yell at you two
okay business is gonna business they
have tasks they've got objectives you
got to make that sprint security is
trying to make sure that you aren't
getting bleeding lis hands but somehow
you still roll out default long-ago
credentials developers well they're
doing whatever they're doing a lot of
these go programmers I don't understand
what's going on magic
and otherwise your operators are just
trying to keep the lights on make sure
that nothing breaks explosions so we've
got a couple different actors and
there's a little bit of war and
infighting usually right problem gonna
be developed or boil it down the
relationships are dumpster fire we need
to get better at working together go
well we've been relying on just throwing
things over the wall as the same goes
so it's developer I'm just gonna throw
my coat over the wall and hope it works
right operations is like I've got an
application here you go that Security's
like no that's still boiling out of the
pot what are you doing go back okay this
throwing over the wall practice doesn't
really work out that way we have these
troubles and we've had more troubles and
usually again if we boil things down
it's with software applications okay
so application delivery application
development application security is
extremely hard all right even if you're
going by best practices and this that
the other for a layman like me for
instance one time I had to set up a
Hadoop cluster ran a full analytic
pipeline great injustice sequel data
this that and the other
oops I got to go catch a flight I'm
heading to the airport I installed the
cluster with vendor instructions to the
end so I was like I guess alright I
guess it's good ready to roll
I'm saying a little TSA and I start
getting email messages from Amazon hey
we're noticing some unusual activity
from few of your nose I think okay
that's weird I just got
yeah probably when it was doing the data
stuff I get another message hey you
really need to cut that out
okay minute later I get another message
look Amazon threatening disconnected my
account lo and behold that duper cluster
I deployed was hacked within a few
minutes pretty impressive stuff right
there right now others you might have
heard default Mongo credentials Hadoop
systems in securely set up this
technique that actually has a lot of
issues in our day-to-day life now
because we are something so it's not
just oh my database is insecure can
actually affect other people's lives so
we standardized we optimized we've
automated this far we've got that going
by doing so we're a little bit more
secure so we're not doing all these
other different things
since we're optimizing our process we're
embedding DevOps that should be a
cultural thing that's again it's not
just technology and now that Rob's
automating we're we're getting better at
what we're doing we're we're not messing
up a lot of practices that go awry or
usually do the human error try to
eliminate the human error and you're
usually sitting better if I'm not
forgetting the turnoff telnet reason
because it's a base construct of all of
my pipelines then great I'm scanning
that great so we talked about containers
real quick you think that's gonna solve
our problems right there's an
application delivery with a software
development problems is DevOps thing
now it's kumbaya docker brought the
champagne developers and operators are
toasting and living the good life
who is messed with containers hands yeah
I mean containers are easing that's
actually one of the one of the key
points you just type it in a couple of
command here like oh that's cool that's
it's that cool is very important that's
very powerful that whatever you go oh
that's cool
think about what happens when the whole
room goes oh that's cool or for
organization goes well that's cool when
the whole country goes that's cool so if
you're not too familiar with containers
the core bit of containers is process
isolation all right so let's think about
back in the day when we were running
shared services on single hooks all
right we have these 1u pizza boxes and
you've had an old Hostgator DreamHost
whatever account back in late 90s and
it's all on one share host right
that was super fun because back then
when getting slash dotted was a thing
once I could take down hundreds okay so
the virtual machines came and became up
commonplace and then you got VPS is
instead quick little slivers of machines
and that way you know as long as the
hosts aren't over subscribed and also
there Jess I know that my environments
is kind of sassy and cactus thing so
that is going to keep my hardware my
resources to its own work part there is
though you've gotten a full new machine
you deployed as VPS is VM you choose
your operating system a whole new
operation boom you've got a whole new
kernel address space and everything with
containers against process isolation the
container host actually extends its
kernel into the container with an
overlay file system and its own
namespace and also the fun stuff that
are getting to tomorrow but with this
you have process isolations
you still have a little you know wall
garden around your application but
you're actually able to have
applications to deploy in a much more
dense environment so you're probably
thinking it's like wow well you said
it's more dense it's cool you get some
benefits from it
VMs are gone no not so much being still
have their place they're actually great
to move around
well not that great to move around but
you can you know in a succinct manner
and a whole configuration you can do
that also with a container it takes a
snapshot of that difft file system but
it's a little bit more versatile it's a
little bit more elastic you get that
elasticity from containers you don't get
that with virtual machines if I have to
scale up a virtual machine I'm going to
have to turn it off change the type and
scale back up the most hypervisor
environments all right see probably
thinking like wow this is container
stuff it's cool it's new you know not
too many people are doing that has must
be some hot jazz and they just
introduced actually it's not again
process isolation filesystem isolation
namespace isolation a lot of these
functions have been in the Linux kernel
for decades it's just been very
difficult to make manual system calls ad
hoc in Mass to orchestrate the
deployment of an isolated function okay
and then a few years ago the whole
doctor thing happened now you've
probably heard it doctor made it kind of
explode a little bit right so and those
for a few years up until recently we've
had an explosion of activity in this
ecosystem why is that well it's easy
like you said you run a command docker
bill tag it with your tag and your run
you run your you run your container
that's that's easy
that's it you do that right yeah doing
containers now I might even be able to
call yourself doing demos so that's all
cute and crating fun what happens when
you have more than one container okay
well we can put a bash script together
I've been doing that for years
just inception automation I'm gonna
build a couple different containers no
problem and then we're gonna run it and
then we have to link it to each other
right
this containers again in this process
isolation so for some things that are
denied by default for others you can
move differently that's why a lot of
people are doing containers wrong and
securely but otherwise you specifically
have to build out these sort of
relationships so containers and DevOps
in mass is actually very very difficult
and I haven't seen anyone that's
mastered it really but it's still
offering a lot of powerful capabilities
all right so our next victim of
dissection is Cooper days
is a hot jazz as a few years ago before
I give my explanation anybody care to
give their opinion on what kubernetes is
it isn't really hot stuff so kubernetes
is a project by Google
are they open source was dog food for
about a decade
graham but kubernetes is and i'll read
this off the screen I think it's pretty
succinct an open source system for
automating deployment automated
operations and the scaling of
containerized applications across
multiple hosts sounds like it's gonna be
the stuff of our DevOps dreams solve our
container conundrums right and that's
pretty close to what it does
you throw containers at kubernetes and
it's going to schedule these containers
across your infrastructure
you tell it how you want it to
communicate and it doesn't write well
anybody here deployed kubernetes
themselves couple all right so there are
a couple ways of deploying kubernetes
they're a bunch of points diploma Cooper
days actually one of them you might have
heard of is kubernetes the hard way by
Kelsey Hightower he goes deep level
setting up the SSL certificate authority
showing you how to manage your public
key infrastructure in order to just get
started right so there is a very
difficult way of doing kubernetes and
whatever you do start to build
kubernetes even if you go with the quote
quote easy way you find out that
kubernetes is not actually just your
end-all be-all you can't just stick in
your CIC pipeline and just call it a day
that would be great
we're gonna build out your kubernetes
cluster you find out that you need some
networking it does not come with
networking
so you've just got containers and pods
just chilling running in place
burnin energy good so you got a stick
some networking some employers just
throw in like flannel or weave OBS but
otherwise you gotta gotta bring that in
yourself all right
know where you're gonna get your
containers from huh everyone's first
answers docker hub yeah we're just gonna
pull in some random container right I
trust it but what would be better is to
not have every one of my nodes calling
out to docker hub every time that they
call a new container image to run and
pull down so we should probably have our
container image registry all right
that's gonna be very helpful like if you
want to call yourself doing kubernetes
they ain't gonna register you you're
doing something wrong all right now
again interacting with the kubernetes
cluster into through three lines but
otherwise it's all API base like if you
can make a rest call to an API endpoint
you can interact with kubernetes and
build platforms upon it to do some
really really cool things what it is not
really extended logging and get some
logs but they're not persistent not easy
to access again it's not easy so you're
gonna need some things that precipitate
that upwards to your users to your
developers to your operators we need
some way to manage your life cycles it's
what happened whenever we have a new
container image coming if you have a new
container engine your entry doesn't just
automatically go okay cool I'm going to
do a boiling point for that and you kind
of push that actually make some calls so
now we're building services right so now
that we're building our own services to
run kubernetes I guess we need a basing
like we're gonna need some Mongo and
some document storage to you know manage
the data that we're trying to manage on
this platform that we're trying to run
to build mmm there's a lot of a section
here right actually find a lot of
Quebecers
all right well you know since we're
doing all this and since we're building
a platform on this platform we might as
make a web panel for it to make it nice
and easy try not to stay in the crammed
line all day long
okay so you thought we were done you
thought that was Cooper Nettie's well
you're still wrong
there's still a lot of things they need
to build into it's actually make it
usable right and that's where you kind
of get hit with this like sharp again
there's all the fun kubernetes stuff
that you can go into there's some
networking options registry options some
configurations code options storage
options that's real fun what happens
when Amazon decides to you know call out
a new EBS store in a region that you
don't have nodes connected to so your
pods is calling up block stores that I
can't connect to that happens that's
real fun unless you figure out how to
fix that which a lot of people know but
either way and are you thinking you
thought you thought told you that this
is all easy now right but it seems
really complicated and it is that's
definitely true it's very complicated
anybody who does kubernetes tells you
it's very complicated deeper you get
into it more complex and more you don't
understand it so let's put the aliens
into perspective do you think the ease
of use is still not there
all right they buy your car
your car objectively is pretty easy to
use
right I need a motor vehicle what's the
thought that comes in your mind all
right your next objectives are
procurement I need some money
alright you go get the money you buy the
car you got the car good means put some
gas in the car you get going and what do
you do you're getting a seat you turn it
on as long as everything works you push
a couple pedals turn this little thingy
and you go that sounds pretty easy right
that is arguably very easy now
software is making it even easier to
where you don't have to do most of that
and it's actually running people over
but um otherwise we're not there Jetsons
yet otherwise whatever people think of I
need a vehicle they don't think about
all this this is complex this is the
factory these are the robots this is the
automation this is a standardization and
an optimization of workflows that gets
you that easy push start and go a lot of
people don't realize that right they
don't sit behind and see the things that
go on the background so when are we
using some of these new software
platforms like web flow which is pretty
cool as a tenured programmer I check it
out oh yeah there's a nice make webpages
but there's no code you don't cut it off
but everyone's website runs in a new pod
and a new name space on a kubernetes
cluster you pay enough they give you
your own cluster but I can go click
click click and have a new website it's
running on kubernetes in a pipeline and
also the fun stuff it's easy for me I
can get up and go and drive that's the
easiest right this is complex this is
hard so thinking about that Factory
let's think about what factories give
you all right
Model T great example I think for
software because again I mentioned
earlier there are other industries who
had these problems that have kind of
solved when software to start
ketchup so the assembly line for Beller
country the Ford Motor Company was
absolutely revolutionary right nobody
can argued that it took the process of
building a car by hand like you guys
want to build a car by hand okay and
those are a lot more simple than our
cars nowadays it took them 18 hours to
build a car so day and a half at least
three but whatever it took you a little
while build car it took that assembly
line that factory took the process of 18
hours to make a car down three and a
half so within a decade they went from a
ho-hum Motor Company to building over
half of the cars in North America and
about 40% of them in Europe that's quick
capability right that's what kind of
start to see today we're starting to see
that today with software factories okay
they're easy to use once then you got
them set up once they're ready to rock
and roll once you've operationalized so
once you've optimized your workflows and
made everything automated where it is as
easy as click click boom they have
pretty impressive capabilities USCIS has
a standardized software Factory and they
allowed their accomplishment of being
able to take a new developer and in the
same day having them deploy a production
system in their pipeline 80% of their
applications get deployed within their
application
it's pretty impressive stuff to be able
to upskill something backward and to be
able to get them pretty advanced
weaponry that quickly as well so
building applications all day every day
everyone is doing it right but not
everyone's doing it right leave you a
couple of thoughts where are you getting
your software from all right open source
software earlier open source software is
great but what's behind the sheets
what's under gutters sometimes can be
pretty scary there was some report run
the other day
that said there was only like 12 node
modules if any of them were compromised
it would in effect compromise the bulk
of applications running on know there's
a couple foundational packages right so
what packages are you pulling it now
that you're building these sort of
integrations with your github repo with
a vault cuz you got sort of secret
somewhere when you're kubernetes cluster
anyone can quickly access your building
all these different connections what if
something is compromised docker hub got
compromised not too long ago and was
found out that everyone's keys were
taken his left so if you had a github
repo attached to docker hub you had that
integration compromise something about a
lot people think oh now you're dealing
kubernetes like it'll get out of your
hands very quickly this very complex
system you need enablement you need
training you need up skill because I've
been working with stuff for years and I
still don't understand
I got make custom resource definitions
and some of the underlying subsystems
are still complex on top of that think
about this we've standardized on
kubernetes it's all written in go
there was a go ssl library vulnerability
discovered not too long ago and guess
what everyone's kubernetes clusters were
vulnerable
everyone's until you got this quick
patch but enablement is extremely
important so I'll be discussing some of
those tomorrow
am I not so secure software factories
discussion where a lot should be taken a
couple of these bits of park showing you
how to attack these software factories
and how to defend against them but
today's takeaways and software is eating
the world so don't let it eat you okay
Amazon pushes out their applications
thousands of times a day
if you've ever loaded amazon.com and ten
minutes gone back later when this looks
really different
not just the ads but just like actual
layout the page the way you interact
with it is different they do
psychological testing thousands of times
a day blue/green tests to see if this
version is gonna make you click and buy
more and faster more often and get you
into their ecosystem even deeper
that's your software Factory at Amazon
you know you need to learn automation
but whatever you do make sure to do it
securely I'd love to pick on Tesla
because they quickly deployed kubernetes
clusters everywhere they thought hey
we're paying someone $750 an hour to do
this kubernetes thing they must know it
pretty well except they left a dashboard
open publicly unauthenticated or
anyone's access in control
outside of that your CICE pipeline
should be treated like gold it should be
a first-class citizen in your
considerations wet mins anybody use
webmin it's like a it's like a cPanel
but free of sources lets you control
your linux servers with the gooiest it's
cpanel basically plus what weapons CIC
pipeline had been compromised and they
found out that had been compromised for
about three and a half years
so if you use webmin within I'd say
probably about the last five you
probably running vulnerable software on
your server not really knowing alright
if you're running webmin on your server
I mean unpatched as it is right now
you're running vulnerable server they
had their CIO DCD server Jenkins server
it was hacked and since it is the
automation server that builds all their
software they said well just stick this
in here and it's got web mins you know
PGP key securing the application it's
coming from web min you download it if
there's nothing weird or spooky about
getting this application when you look
at it you don't know that was built with
some malicious code I mean it came from
an era of web development that should
definitely been buried with the whole
geo civics thing so now everyone is
building software and you know everyone
has any company as a software company
now right and I think if you've been in
the tech industry for at least given a
few years you might have noticed the
uptick in vulnerability reports this
person got happens
this software is insecure this has got a
back door that's got default admin
credentials
we're probably seeing that because
there's just more software out there
there's more people active on there
there were more people using it there
are more people attack together they're
just more ovens so you should probably
learn how to build some software which
we'll be doing that tomorrow but for
this any questions comments concerns
problems Furies conundrums projectile
from a peanut gallery you're gonna be
attacking some software tomorrow yep and
showing you why you should think about
where your java components come from and
all sorts of fun stuff and hopefully
spinning up an actual software Factory
I've got one of these little things
automated just click click click and it
gives you all these little kubernetes
manifests and poison it's pretty cool
stuff but all right excellent well thank
y'all for your time thank you in here
again check me out on the tweets and the
Geats otherwise we've got another
fantastic chat coming up here
shortly
[Applause]