yep good for everyone so my name is
Tyler I am going to give the talk on
badge making I'm not a professional PCB
designer or engineer or anything but how
do you have a couple of couple badges
I've put together a couple PCBs and
together project sometimes so I figure
I'd share mine trials and tribulations
with you but see if I inspire something
elbow built to be around so Who am I
like I said I'm Tyler I live in
Huntsville Alabama
I work for an IFC company doing smart
lighting solutions
I do software development there and my
free time I like doing a CNC machine or
other laser cutters Mills stuff like
that
and obvious PCB design so just any
little one-off projects helping people
with their their stuff and liking lots
and lots and lots of
how did you said so some of you have
probably seen seen this this term match
life I kind of originated with the DEF
CON
drought they started putting together
conference about it just kind of like
these but with electronics
you know circuit boards there they range
from just blinking lights on them to
puzzles and games and interactivity like
connections you know alternate reality
games and just it just went crazy people
started doing a lot of really cool
things with them in the last couple of
years and so it's been really exciting
to see that kind of open up and become
more accessible to everyone so here's a
couple of examples of some some badge
life going on and you can see all the
different LEDs and different shapes
they're not your standard PCB because
you don't just get you know a green
rectangle like fun in your computer you
get crazy shapes and colors and lights
so these head like screens on them and
sensors and expansion ports and all
sorts of wild stuff so some features
that you'll find on a lot of badges are
usually battery-powered you don't want
to have to have an extension cable to
plug into your your badge while you're
walking around
tripping people yeah yeah sure yeah drop
down a little bit sometimes there's a
lot of sensors yeah
it depends some most of these are just
kind of people like me who just decided
to design some badges and have fun
they're usually sent off to a fab to be
made so they're not handmade or anything
like that but yeah they're usually made
pretty small no so so those badges are
created by a separate group and they do
about a small batch of a thousand that
they then hot drop in Las Vegas and you
kind of have to follow them on Twitter
to find out where they are to buy them
because these are not like DEFCON
regulated stuff they just sell them
freely they don't do licensing and stuff
like that because it's like you're a
seller in Las Vegas you can get in
trouble for selling stuff and not paying
taxes so there it's a very you know
DEFCON is I guess right yeah so a lot of
these are just kind of like kind of sort
of just community driven projects but
they do make official conference badges
- ten minutes
you do get a badge in there lately
they've been electronic badges so this
is from this year's Def Con it had some
sort of like NFC style communication
I've brought my Def Con badge from two
years ago the one with the game that's
built into it so they won't see that I
can pull it out there's there's there's
a lot of different ways that people do
pageants so compare
at Def Con its hundreds of dollars yes
they're about it because 300 or $40 but
yeah and there are definitely cheaper
badges and these badges are like 250
bucks but they also get you know party
yeah there's a there's a whole community
another another big thing about the
badges that has been really popular is
that they're interactive a badge that
disco since they're playing this is kind
of neat but if you can do something with
it that adds a lot of a lot of
excitement around it so a lot of them
have games and puzzles like mentioned
but some of them are just there hackable
they have ports exposed and they have
serial communications that you can
terminal in on your computer and connect
to its and commands and certain kind of
playing with the badge and that's always
really exciting for people and then most
importantly pretty much that's a
blinking light so I'm not gonna say I'm
not gonna say you have to but I'm so I
kind of touched on this about the
extension ports so one thing that's
happened pretty recently is they've kind
of standardized on a protocol for
extending onto badges and they call this
the sword art online so that's the
shitty add-on protocol it provides you
with a port that you can plug in tiny
versions of badges into the ports and
it's like a pseudo standard it's not
fully operable like you can't just
connect anything to anything but you get
close and so most of the add-ons are
just LEDs don't have any like
microcontrollers on them
there are some that are pretty complex
and start putting puzzles together when
you start connecting different things to
these ports so I'm going to talk a
little bit about the protocol so the
latest version of the protocol is the
1.69
this there are two versions there's the
11.0 and this one 1.0 only had four pins
this adds adds two new pins which kind
of helps with the ruggedness of the
connector and gives you a little bit to
to play with but in terms of
connectivity so that I have two
connectors one goes on the badge and one
goes on the add-on they connect you've
got a 3 volt rail you've got a ground
pen and then you got I squared C SDA SCL
pins and 2 GPIO pins at use for
controlling lights or you can use it to
detect what kind of add-on you've
plugged into your board but it that's
basically all the protocol specifies not
much more than that so I don't expect
everything just to work but you can kind
of at least know where your power ground
are coming from you can line up like
that
so the other other part is they defined
which pens are which so they have these
key connectors that have these little
not just cut out of them so you can't
plug them in backwards they're kind of
hard to find you can use regular pin
headers and they'll work it's a standard
pitch width but these specifically these
connectors are hard to find
those you can find everywhere because
they're used for cables to be plugged
into like other tools and stuff like
that because this is not a cable it's a
connector there's not often a whole lot
of use for plugging in a board into
another board like this so kind of
harder to find I'll give you some tips
on where to where to search to find that
is but don't worry if you can't find
them you can just use regular female pin
head or something
they won't suck it into that connector
behind and feel free to stop me if you
have any questions I'm just gonna kind
of there's no really the story to this
presentation it's just kind of things
I've learned and things I've seen and so
if you see something anyone asked
question about it kids to you so this is
the bench I built for this year friend
dusty had a good idea he was like we
should make badge ones like re what what
should it be
he's like heats up I was like alright
we'll do it and so we put together this
this badge right here looks like pizza
it's got some LEDs on it and the bigger
toppings would be a really cool way to
use the SAO
add-ons so I could detect which toppings
you have on there and you know that
having a pineapple on pizzas illegal so
the port's explode
so we put that together it didn't quite
get finished in time so I'll talk a
little bit more about about that but
it'll definitely be ready for next year
play with a cool pizza board so here's
what it looks like it's got the topping
slots it's got the the battery on the
back and so it it's using an ESP 32
which is so Wi-Fi Bluetooth micro
controller a pretty high power but but
it's a very neat board it has a lot of
really cool features powered by a single
double-a battery I'll talk about some
trials and tribulations for that part
too
it has capacitive touch pads so you can
touch on the back of it and that's what
can do some sort of interactivity parts
so you can touch the different pads and
do different things with that and it's
got 16 individually addressable r2b LEDs
which are amazing they're so fun to play
with they're pretty cheap they can they
just add a whole lot you can have
regular LEDs and they light up in the
school but when you can really do like
all the patterns and some colors and
stuff like that then it's got three of
the SAO ports for the toppings or your
own SEO add-on you can get a little kind
of weird it's kind of rotated in weird
way so if you get like that little
Pikachu ad on a movie sideways but you
want to be
and and so they said you have HIV
toppings I've gotta show you some of
them but yeah basically the whole
purpose this talk you can make your own
it's not too bad you can you can start
very simple you can move on to super
complex but you can definitely do it
this moment it's not too bad you need a
couple things to get started so there's
a couple software tools that help you
get off the ground
kicad is my favorite you know software
so electronic design so that's where you
design your schematic your PCBs and
that's where it will generate the files
that you send off to a fabrication house
and they will make your reports for you
if you're using a microcontroller
I really like Arduino it's really easy
to pick up libraries right and
everything from scratch and then for
graphical design you can use Inkscape
you can also use Adobe tools I use
illustrator alive you can use Microsoft
Paint it doesn't really matter it
doesn't have to be vector - sorry but it
just kind of helps keep keep things
clean and manufacturable
you'll need a couple of hard rituals
these top two are the most important
multimeter and a soldering iron even if
you get the board's fully assembled
populated still need still need those
two you need to test your board there
will be mistakes especially when you're
starting and you will need to make tiny
adjustments on your prototype boards
that you make glue so you don't get them
mixed up the real boards I had to run
wires back and forth just to make
modifications just to get the prototype
working and then I can order new boards
that have this fix is built into the
board it helps you have a nothin if
you're doing any surface mount parties
you can do a lot of them by hand but if
you're making more than 10 boards it
really helps to have some sort of more
machine operated process to kind of help
put those boards together did you say
open yes so this is an IR reflow oven so
these are used to solder up boards with
surface mount parts so when you put
parts on but on top of those solder
paste and that when it cooks in the oven
it melts down the solder grab some of
the part that's kind of lines them up
and it cools off you can have your
partner
this is a little bit easier so this is
the t96 to a I believe the picture I
grabbed a toaster oven will work because
it all that law does is you'd have to
pour the solder know you may have to
hack it a little bit first because you
gotta control the flow of the the
temperature increase edit or you can
you're watching the solder melt alright
well I've never thought about that
really like that yeah
this helps a lot it's press a button go
and just just kind of work so you can
get these for like two hundred three
hundred dollars any sense
ir yes that's that's the common of it
tight there are some convection ovens
stuff like that but the ir ones are
really cheap pretty pretty accessible
so your most important tool it's time so
that's kind of why the pizza isn't ready
this time I gave myself a couple of
months to put the pizzas together and
that's not enough so you you want to be
preparing very early especially if it's
more complex it's it's simple and just
have some LEDs even then you want to
give yourself more time but especially
if it has a lot of parts a lot of
unknowns so things that they contribute
to do time are ordering boards the order
of setup prototype boards it might take
a couple of weeks to get your boards in
then you get them in you build up your
your prototypes you test them you start
trying to figure out your debugging
what's going wrong and then you have to
order more boards so it's never it's
very rarely a one-time order a bunch of
boards and be done you always want we're
a small batch and then test those and
then order the full batch that you can
make any changes you need for me
so here's the checklist don't don't
worry you can't read it that goose
causing problems but basically there's
this is this is why it takes so much
time because there's a lot of things
that you don't know what's going on and
so on this list I've got you like a
rough sketch your feature list for your
board you select a microcontroller if
you're putting one of those on there put
together your power budget talk about
that design your power supply capture
the schematic map apart it's a place and
route the parts you draw the board
outline so that cuts out properly on the
on the router you do your silkscreen and
visual adjustments you work with a
prototype suggest the prototypes you
make your PCB fit to the fixes you write
your software you build all the boards
and put it all together sometimes you do
a lot of these steps over and over again
so like really you want you want to have
that time so don't don't try to wait too
long if it's coming close and you
haven't started yet go ahead and start
but plan for the next time don't don't
try to rush it it's usually not fun so
I'm gonna talk about the power budget a
little bit so these are battery powered
devices so you have to consider a lot of
things you gotta consider all the parts
that are going on the on the board so
you can extend your battery life if
you're doing something that's plugged
and you want to worry about this as much
but for badges that's very important so
consider all the parts on your board
LEDs microcontrollers sensors whatever
whatever else you have on there I go to
the data sheets see how much power they
draw add it all up it adds up very
quickly even even small things like LEDs
little sensors little flash chips it
adds up so go ahead and count all of
those things
consider the sleep modes of your chips
some microcontrollers have a lot of
sleep mode characteristics sensors often
have sleep mode options or sometimes
they just go into idle and go into sleep
mode and with that you need to consider
your duty cycle so when you have a full
word that is using like a
microcontroller for like this most of
the time it's gonna be asleep it's gonna
wake up whenever it needs to do
something it's gonna wake up with
someone's interacting with it it's gonna
wake up on a timer
every five seconds wake up complain
stuff like that you need to take that
into account when you're trying to
figure out how much power does this
device use and then you have to
determine what your expected lifetime is
so if you're doing this for a two or
three day con maybe four days it's long
enough don't try to make it last a year
you know you're just over complicating
the problem there and you're probably
missing out on a lot of interactivity
when designing a power supply there's
some helpful tools out there so like I
said you can do this you don't have to
be an electrical engineer to to do all
this Texas Instruments has a tool called
web bench and it can help you build a
power supply which is one of the most
annoying pieces of electrical
engineering this you've ever have to
interact with it does it for you that's
that's great you put in what input
voltages you're going to get and what
output voltage you expect to get and
what sort of current drawing you need
and it will go pick some parts and put
together a schematic for you it will
even do a little bit of a PCB design
layout and provide you the Bill of
Materials thing you need this chip and
these ambassadors and the
and doctors just little here and no
power supply this hasn't failed me yet
I've used it to build or buy power
supplies it's been really nice tells you
exactly how much it's gonna cost exactly
how much room it will take home afford
and it'll tell you like what the
efficiency of that power supply is so
imma beat says for example it has at one
double-a batteries and that's 1.5 volts
the LEDs on the on the board need 5
volts so I deduced that 1.5 up to 5 drop
that in here got a circuit build this
works great highly highly recommend
mister alright so onto some more
artistic parts of the board so PCBs are
designed in layers like an onion or an
ogre the middle layer right here is the
fiberglass so this is the non conductive
substrate that the whole PCB kind of
sits on it's got kind of a yellowish
tint I'm gonna pass out some sample
boards they keep will go
so y'all can look at them while I'm
talking
just pass these around take a couple you
can keep these either these are going to
be handy if you go to something a board
it'll kind of show up some of the color
mechanisms so you're designing things
like digital art usually have all the
colors that you can show on your screen
or on your printer on a PCB you're much
more limited by the manufacturing
process
I think that should be enough
you don't get one just so like I said
middle layer is the fiberglass semi
trans-pacific translucent it's a
yellowish greenish color usually
sometimes it's a beige color but on
either side of that is the copper traces
so when you're designing your PCB
anywhere even but copper lines or fills
that will be on top of the fiberglass
layer above that is the solder mask so
the solder mask is what gives
PCBs those that green color it's there's
usually a couple of different colors you
can choose from some one I'm passing
around as a blue solder mask the pizzas
used a yellow solder mask they have red
or black and white green just a couple
of couple of different options it's not
not infinite but usually have a set of
motions that you think from and then on
top of that is the silkscreen layer so
usually you only get one or two options
for color on that usually get white like
on the port's that are in your hands on
white PCBs usually get a black color on
this one sometimes you can ask for black
on a blue PCB some places will do it
some places won't another reason why you
start ahead of time so that
you can ask these questions and find a
manufacturer they will give you what you
want so the thing you got in your hand
is my little color swatch I put together
just to kind of show off the different
mechanisms for generating color with
such limited color options so on the far
right on that side you have exposed
copper plating and so that actually is a
gold plated material whenever you don't
have solder mask but you do have copper
that's how that will show up so you can
get that really shiny shiny gold color
if you're doing gold plating you get a
really shiny silver color if you're
doing the solder solder plating I'll go
into a little bit of that later moving
our way left
that's the exposed fiberglass it's
exposed on both sides so you can see
kind of how translucid it is if you hold
it up to the to the light it looks like
through its kind of got that sort of
soft edge where you can see the shadow
from the rest of the work coming in on
it that gives you that that's pretty
colored that's sort of beige color
sometimes you have to be careful because
sometimes that fiberglass layer actually
has printing on it just depends on where
they get their their fiber glass
substrate from
but it's a it's a color people don't
consider when I'm making PCBs they
always think solder mask and the
silkscreen to the left of that is the
their solder mask and copper so there's
copper underneath the solder mask and it
sort of lightens up the solder mask you
can kind of see a difference in color
there so if you're looking at it like a
standard green computer PCB you'll you
can see the traces under the green
solder mask and you can kind of tell the
two color differences and so that's
that's with copper under it further left
that's without copper I'm going to get
that darker color because there's
nothing reflecting light back up the
miss Halle underneath and then the other
three are just kind of little patterns
you can see that kind of do a little bit
of dithering but it's not you can't
really do true design but you can't kind
of give the effect of a gradient and
then on the back you kind of have some
other colors that kind of pop up that
are even more a little harder to think
about being kind of get that green red
yellow versions of the fiberglass and
that's because the green is where
there's solder mask on the back of the
board and that's kind of showing some of
the blue through the fiberglass the red
one is where the copper is kind of
showing through the back of the board so
there's a lot of really cool color
options that you can build just using
the different layers of the
or dismay from anyone have any questions
about that that's kind of kind of weird
that one is actually I think routed out
I think that's I don't that's a level
group yeah oh yeah yes true as it
displayed yeah so I think it is just a
big pita it's just a big hole yeah it's
it's crazy wait wait you send Denise
yeah yeah you can send these two baths
and they'll make it you know they didn't
ask any questions about this like why
are you doing this yeah yeah Banta money
American it's just as well are these
three different types of hybrid class no
for the three different colors no
there's just it's whatever's on the back
of the porch I agree okay so yeah the
middle ones got the copperish I think
they're on the back the left ones at the
solder mask shining through on the back
so it looks like they're different
colors of fiberglass because the
fiberglass is kind of see-through
yeah all the same yeah yeah pleats and
if you want more I've got plenty I made
them just to give up so people can see
them and have them in hand when they're
designing their own board think you're
like okay how's this gonna look as those
kind of about you gonna have a lot
of people contacting you I need help I
hope so
so like I said you can get different
plating you want the pads and expose the
copper pieces on the left this is Enoch
which is electro nickel immersion
it's gold lady you say gold plating
don't know what you mean but it's Eni
gee that gives you that rich gold color
on the paths it's really handy for
historic boards for a long time
that's why why was designed so they have
PCBs sitting in a warehouse and then you
can just pop it out assemble it the
others tend to corrode with moisture
over time so that's why they designed
this this process makes soldering a
little babies here but on the right is
hassle the hot-air solder leveling that
gives you that sort of silver color and
so depending on what your board is you
can you can use either once you solder
pieces onto here it's gonna be the
second sulfur color so keep that in mind
as you're putting parts on a board if
you are using just regular pads and
holes once you solder them up you're not
gonna see that gold color so you need to
make sure if you're trying to get that
gold hold effect to leave those exposed
and don't solder on them
so as sort of the process I used to to
do the visual aspects I usually start
with the board outline and work my way
through the different layers so this is
a shape that will be evident very
shortly I'm sure most of you have drawn
the shape in your life and don't have it
so you start with the shape it can be an
image it can be a vector image it
doesn't really matter the kicad has an
option where you can import images and
it'll create parts for you so I can't
really see in that third picture that
that's the board outline imported into
kicad and then that's the the 3d
rendering of the board cut out what
software use a PKI key Kevin okay I
guess yep yeah he Kent's open-source PCB
design software it's free it's currently
being bankrolled by CERN made the Large
Hadron Collider research groups of very
cool organization keeping that keeping
that project afloat
so after you get the board outline you
can start playing with the copper layers
and the silkscreen layers whatever else
same exact process you loaded in an
image we run it through the little bit
map converter you drop the part on the
board and then you get whatever whatever
you're trying to do you can so this is
using the silk screen using the white
silk screen you can also use a solder
mask if you want to do a different color
you use the copper plating you want to
show through that way just whatever you
need to do make your make your design
work so who here is not drawing us in
like middle school 203 now you never
never do the little s3 with all the
lines
so selecting carts got some tips here
consider your part technology
so there's surface mount technology and
three of old technologies through-hole
is sort of like the old school like you
have a resistor and it's got wires and
you bend them put up their holes and
solder the other side those are really
easy to do by hand they're not great if
you want to make a thousand boards just
because you can't really automate that
process very well it takes a lot of time
to bend the leads and put them through
the holes inside of the I decide flip it
over and all that stuff but sell it a
spit you have them soldered their own so
you can do that and that's and that's a
big a big plus there is if you're making
a fairly simple board and you want
people to assemble it themselves that's
really popular and you usually want to
use through-hole parts for that just
because it's a lot easier to put
together by hand
surface mount you get a lot of smaller
parts a lot cheaper parts a lot more
manufacturable pieces but yeah a lot
harder to debug and test can be done
consider the size of your parts you can
use really really tiny resistors and
cram a bunch of stuff on gear board but
it makes it harder to manufacture you're
using tiny parts that have tiny pins
that are underneath the board that just
you know you can't you can't put
together with a soldering iron it makes
it really hard to reliably manufacture
it yourself it even makes it a little
bit harder for fabrication houses to
expand fetcher and assemble boards but
makes your board smaller and I mean to
put more things on it so there's a
there's a balance that were just
something to consider when you're
picking your parts and most importantly
its cost that's that's a big driver what
what we did is solve a hobby for most of
us I can't afford to make $150 badges
every time especially we need want to
make a hundred of them so you can give
them out of the conference or so a lot
of conference or something and then the
number of number of parts it's a big
difference having a badge that has you
know a resistor and an LED on it versus
one that has 16 RGB LEDs and a
microcontroller or two power supplies
and three add-on ports and an i2c
multiplexer and stuff like that that's a
pretty quick every little part you that
on there just makes it more cockpit but
together so better mind so these are a
couple places I buy parts from Mouser
and ichiki on the left those are in the
u.s. they're very reliable getting part
to see very quickly very good search
mechanisms sometimes work connectors I
go to eBay
it's kind of weird but there's a lot of
Chinese sellers on eBay that have a very
inexpensive connector selection but it's
a lot less reliable so if you if you're
making one batch of boards and go to you
bet grab them but if you want to use a
connector that you can rely on wait and
use it as a later board
you probably want something else don't
yeah don't buy FTDI chips on ebay
they're usually clones almost always
funds work on ships at TBI it's a brand
that makes Cyril adapters and they had
and they were pirating fgi chips are
good and on ebay you can't tell which is
which they look exactly the same and MTV
I started cracking down and actually
speaking to you yeah yeah yeah if it's
less than $4 is probably not an empty
budget another good source I I found
recently is Ella
LCSC they're sort of like more like
Mouser and digi-key but they're based up
China elite they they have a lot of
parts that you can't buy on
do pixels for example the RGB LEDs they
have those on LCSC it's a little bit
more reliable than eBay but they're
pretty cheap no not exactly like you
said cutter than the same spot that I
use eBay when you're trying to find
particularly connectors it's really
useful but again it's kind of hard to
rely bender from like Aliexpress stuff
like that because they don't provide as
much information usually with like data
sheets and models and footprints and
stuff like that but II base usually a
little bit easier to get started with le
Express kind of got some weird payment
options and something that I think they
use PayPal now but for a while yet to
use like specifically a Visa credit card
and not a debit card there's weird
things to get payment through but now
I'll Express le Bob are good sources for
a lot of those parts too
so for manufacturing the boards I'm just
getting the ports printed cut there
couple options I've you smart
prototyping a lot they they can do
fairly inexpensive boards they have a
lot of solder mask of color options
they're the ones who made the beads of
words so if you want to see what kind of
quality they put out come with these
boards actually they made the boards
that are in your hand too
they have yeah like I said a couple
little solder mask color options they
have blue green yellow red purple black
matte black white so pretty much the
standard selection of colors a neat
thing about them as they let me put the
black solder mask on the yellow PCB
which is not super common jail CPCB did
not let me do that they have very strict
no this is how our boards are made so
you did no substitutions but jail see
PCB is a little bit cheaper and they
have a couple of options they're
actually run by the same parent company
as LCSC so you can kind of order parts
and pieces at the same time there's kind
of a nice thing and they just recently
started doing board assembly so you can
actually order the parts order the board
have them put them together ship them to
you fairly inexpensively but I think
they only do green PCBs and parts on one
side some restrictions there so I
haven't tried it out yet but inside it
too smart prototyping will do presumably
you ship them parts or give them a list
of parts to go by but that's that's
usually for much larger scale things
and then for prototypes I like to use
wash park there in the States and they
have one color option because the purple
board so it's usually if you see someone
with a purple board probably came from a
park and they only do the gold plating
but they'll let you order three copies
of a design for a couple of bucks get it
sent out to you in a couple weeks and
it's very good for testing out designs
without having to order three or five
hundred of thousand words and then
finding out get mistaken for all right
just add something oh Sh is open source
hardware and on their website you can
find other people's designs and they
welcome you to buy their designs and
it's shared among the community
there's a lot of little add-on printed
circuit boards on their website
yeah there's their great super cheap I
highly recommend they've done a lot for
the community I think it's four dollars
per square inch okay yeah yeah not not
expensive at all the others the others
tend to price things and brackets so if
something is 5 centimeters by 5
centimeters or smaller it's one price
once you move up to the next size board
just ten by ten it's another price the
OSH party does do the per square inch so
if you have a really tiny sign super
cheap so that's all I've got on slides
do you have any questions so when you
like say you're gonna print out a batch
would be more cost-effective to do a
bigger board and then do your design
across that board so that you just punch
it out when you get it or just say okay
I mean hey I know it's this dimensions
just send it out and say I want this
number so it depends the different PCB
manufacturers have different rules they
call it a panel is a tional so that's
putting one design in a big panel
shipping a panel out to you and then you
punch it out or it's mostly cut out and
you can break it away stuff like that
they have a couple of restrictions on
how you can analyze boards some of them
only do it where you can
he's there's a z-score bid that they use
that let's just kind of snap the board
doesn't leave a nice clean finish and if
you're doing a irregular shape that
doesn't really work so well but some of
them will let you route up the whole
board design except just leave a couple
of little attachment points that you can
break off and it can be cheaper if
you're making a lot of small things it
can make it a lot easier to assemble
them because you can put solder based on
all the paths of all the small things at
one big board chunk and then make 20
copies of a board at once it's effective
a symbol a tiny little pepperoni piece
and like on the money's but the drawback
there is that you don't get nice clean
edges around your words
so if you've ever had a piece of
electrons that's had sort of like I am a
little piece that kind of sticks out
that's a little sharp but yeah it looks
like a little like three that's because
they panelized it with if you don't
panelize it you get nice rounded edges
that are really smooth can't really cut
your hands so it's kind of a trade-off
there that you do for me I've never
really found it he's useful enough just
because artists tend to get cheaper when
they get smaller and parts tend to get
cheaper when you scale up the number so
if you are ordering ten boards cost this
much you're ordering 100 boards it'll
cost a little bit more so it can usually
you know kind of you say things are
getting there okay when you order your
boards do you have to specifically tell
them you want it like you're doing
surface otter mouth do you have to
specifically tell the manufacturers I
want a solder stencil included yeah so I
don't have any of my senses here but
those are used for putting together the
surface mount parts onto PCBs
it's basically a stainless-steel sheet
or mylar sheet with little holes cut out
that with the laser cutter that lets you
squeegee solder paste onto the boards
drop your parts on throwing the ir oven
all three of these companies well the
top two will definitely manufacture
estimates before you use stainless steel
Josh Park has a like a sister company
that I think it's called Austin tensile
and they'll give you a stainless steel
of aware that a little mylar sheets or
just a little bit little bit extra cost
oh yeah those are this receipt for
helpful everybody together a lot of
boards I have have you done of picker
parts or pick you know picking place
with any of the manufacturers yet I've
done that with a smart prototyping and
some boards assembled by them it's
pretty complex period of doing just a
few smart prototyping they start in here
if you want to use the air pick and
place machine to put boards together you
have to have an 800 dollar minimum order
or assembly that's the sort of base cost
for that because it takes them a lot of
work and cycles to put the program
together have you heard of macro fab so
they're they're like a small batch of
pic parts okay if you if you so they
they have a list of all the parts that
they have that sit in their reels and if
you use their parts it actually becomes
cheaper then if you say I want these
specific parts they'll be like well now
we have to get the reels for these so
how about you just use our parts so they
have a list of parts and if you actually
build it all with theirs and they'll do
the pickle part for the whole damn thing
okay and they're kind of what jlc piece
PCB is just started down it's like if
you use their parts lesson will work for
you that's all I'm cheaper yeah so I
noticed like if you're doing a small
count it's more expensive per board but
the more you ramped up it's like all of
a sudden the cost per part starts
dropping drastically but and then you're
spending come yours and that's that's an
easy trap to fall into user
these PCBs you'll want to order a small
batch alike ten boards for example
because that sort of like usually promo
order quantity must use like aa spark
and it'll be maybe 20 bucks to order 10
boards and then you'll see that little
little slider and you'll drag it up to a
hundred boards it'll be like 25 bucks
that's what it's worth
Underwood's right probably did it right
and then you drag that slider up to 500
boards and it's only like $40 my god
it's five times as many boards and you
can just sit there and read that slider
over and over and over again
you know before you know you're spending
six hundred bucks on PCBs that don't
work right yeah they get a double wire
so you gotta be careful uh that happens
with the boards that happens with the
parts of the components you're buying on
bouncer you buy one part it's ten cents
you buy 100 parts that are sitting up
nice so it's very easy to start picking
up all these things and you have bags
and bags resistors that you don't be
yeah it's so easy you just gotta you got
to be careful that'll be a little little
diligent about that
you bitch yeah bitch that's Texas
Instruments this T is website you have
the web manager power power designer
yeah super useful tool highly recommend
it it uses TI parts so you know just
keep that in mind that's what that's
what it's here for it's sell more of
their parts but it relieves you a lot of
mystery and unknown with electrical
engineering design they can be an easy
button for your power yep it's such an
easy button and this is this one
generated I think 17 different power
supply designs that I could have picked
for these three hours will let you dump
that straight in the Chi cab
dorky cat or do you have to recreate
this in kicad I have recreated it I know
there are some outputs or cut it either
tools I don't know exactly what they are
all right they're usually small enough
it's only a couple parts I just rebuilt
it I did look at their PCB layout output
and sort of based my design off that
just because inductors have to be really
close to the pads and all this stuff
usually it doesn't matter a whole lot
but just try to try to match what they
give you this this should work
sweet look to be a he had on call a
while back and you know well it's pretty
clear if you're making the main badge
and you're making the add-on getting
cool things with GP iOS and digital's
but you're just making an add-on is
there any sort of convention I mean is
there a tiny signal and you do one that
you should be a contender a or anything
you should do
there's it's it's really not a standard
I call it let's do the same to standard
yeah you know the things that you can
rely on our power ground you do have
this too high to see pens but even I
spritzee the protocol doesn't tell you
anything about the data so there's
really not a whole lot maybe they'll
change over the next couple years maybe
you know a group of you know aspiring
hackers can start to agree on work with
stuff organize their volt unless like
you said you're doing both sides so on
the pizza boards there's a new prompt on
each of the topics that identifies what
the topping is and the board is designed
to go read that so you can see which
which support has much topping in it
like I said just yell at you the
pineapple on there alright now you said
you problem know how big the data I want
to say these words excited you can you
can identify parts using just a couple
of resistors and measure the voltage
across them of EEPROM how many boards
that pineapple has been plugged into so
so what is the interaction when you plug
in a pineapple so it's the light at the
top just to go nuts so right now it
doesn't do much of anything okay
yeah but the idea of these boards is
that they've got Wi-Fi and so
build a couple of different puzzles and
games for you to play on the court and
then there's gonna be a leaderboard
where past you know the sort of gates in
the games would upload your score up to
like a leaderboard and your avatar would
be your selection of toppings we put on
the board be like oh that's the guy with
all the pineapples on his pizza give I
see you first with the head you just
just kind of like a silly little little
thing there but yeah it's mostly mostly
visual okay you know the boards how much
you looking to sell those for at defcon
uh probably probably $45 not very
expensive but these will come in a nice
little silk screen this one just just to
come a couple little fun things it's
just mean what you can do
yes
what's your favorite medium to be
contacted on you can reach me on Twitter
at Tyler Crompton that's probably the
easiest one you can also email me typed
in that gmail.com yeah if you have any
questions about PCB design please please
let me know and I can help you get get
through your first one especially get
stuck in somewhere with the electronic
design article trying to figure out how
to get some of these color options that
are on the little swatches that's
alright it's a lot to sort of think
about when you're in the design tool
like multi layers because the design
tool is just a flat 2d design so when
you're trying to figure out how to get
these different colors which is why I
made these could just have it in my hand
and see them here's this is how you get
this color did everyone get the color
swatches if you didn't get one please
please come up and grab one
they look anything else new ee I I'm a
computer engineer so it a little bit of
EE but mostly software so I had a little
bit of background the college but most
of this I learned just just from doing
that just having fun that's why I don't
design my own power supply so just let
the tool do it for me yeah you don't
have to be a W thanks