I'm going to go through this fairly
quickly I have a video as well and it
was supposed to be part of the slideshow
but for summer in the PowerPoint didn't
like my video it won't go in the right
place because I'm going to try to breeze
through this and then I'll just start
the video and you guys can come up and
take a look at things and touch things
and ask questions then is that okay cuz
videos a little bit too long to show the
whole thing but you can watch it in the
pocket all that at the end so call it
tales from the torture chamber because I
sit in a torch all day and I'll show you
pictures and once the torches are like
and how we do it we're gonna go into
open a glass history here actually very
little is known about the origins of the
last sort of a mystery that that showed
up over a few centuries the first hints
about it are from about 4000 years ago
in Mesopotamia I think it was inspired
by like working with ceramics and
pottery metalwork and probably by
accident one group seemed to think that
it came from cooking on the beach the
Phoenician sailors would would stop at
the beach and cook and use pottery and
then it would melt the sand underneath
but that's been debunked because it
doesn't get hot enough to melt the sand
but they actually think it kind of
developed organically like in different
places you know it a little bit of time
and they started sharing the place oh we
found out it does this if you add this
to it you get color and again this to it
it's stronger and it just kind of grew
it developed as a unique substance
nobody had seen anything quite like this
and the pottery was kind of dirty
didn't have quite the same chemical
makeup what was really exciting was when
they discovered you could add the
medical excusing metal oxides to create
the colors and the two most favorite
ones were blues they're still struggling
to find a purple for us even to today
that's a good purple but using cobalt
oxide and copper oxide you can get these
kind of colors that of course these
aren't old pieces here but I just want
to show you the two colors and what
we're talking about and then um one
thing they try to do is imitate natural
stones and precious stones lapis was
really really of a sought-after stone as
was turquoise so all of a sudden the
artists and the palaces and all could
have those colors without the cost of
actually having to get the stone now
early controlled blast work was done
over an alcohol lamp and today you'll
even hear what I do refer to as lamp
work lampwork glass beads and we used
lamp in a long long time I use the
special torch it's an oxygen propane
surface mixed torch I'll have a picture
of it in a minute here so I'll show you
believe it or not there are dozens and
dozens and dozens of different specially
made glass bead torches it's that big an
industry ok this was just for fun I
found this online and it's an early
glass recipe and the reason I have a
pinterest thing up there is because it
reminded me of pinterest you know when
you find a recipe but you have to read
about what their dog did that morning
what was doing six years ago but how
they feel and stuff in the recipes like
roll and yes girl that's kind of how
this was because over here the first
part was when you said upon the
foundation of kiln to make glass you
first search in a favorable month for a
prophetess day and only then settle the
foundation of the kiln and then he goes
here about you you regularly perform
libation offerings before the Cova
images and on the day when you plan to
place the glass and the kiln you make a
sheep sacrifice and I felt that part out
over here's the actual recipe and a lot
of this over here I'm not going to go
into it's the same thing we used today
sand certain types of ash different
oxides and this goes into how you get
the fire to go and everything that's I
buy mine there are people who actually
still make their own glass but that's
I'm not patient enough for that okay a
quick story of how we got to where we
are today about two thousand years ago
glass making made its played in Europe
and it ended up mainly in Italy for a
couple of reasons there was a high
concentration of people who landed there
because it was an island and secondly
they could put these huge glass making
places in the middle of the water on an
island so it didn't burn down a city
that was a real problem still is
everyone's gonna have a big fire but in
the 1600s Venice became a
major glass capital they supplied the
whole world and there were so secretive
of what they did the the workers there
were under the threat of either
dismemberment or death if they shared
any of their secrets okay that's a
pretty good reason not to however
eventually some of the people escaped
there and went north as far as Germany
they ended up in Laos shut Germany is a
capital where they make a lot of glass
German ornaments and these people found
work which energized the German glass
industry and Malaysia is now a major
capital so um in 1800s Native Americans
were traded for glass beads for the
European settlers that was a big change
over in the 50s and 60s in the United
States the studio glass movement started
and by studio glass I mean people who
have studio at home and a burner and
they got glass and they melted it now
nobody really knew what they were doing
but everybody was trying and there
wasn't the communication that we have
now so people were like in their little
cocoon they're melting and learning and
coming up with tools and eventually some
of them came up with some pretty good
ways to do things however in the 1980s
the Society of glass bead makers was
formed which is now the International
Society of glass bead bankers which was
started as an American group who know
people in the West Coast did this that
they got together and started sharing
ideas techniques tools they come up with
some of we're building our torches and
they shared ideas on that
like PC work now you know people talk
about how they build pcs and different
things they can do in the 1990s
god bless the internet that caused a
huge boom because all the stuff that had
been secret and then hard to disperse it
the internet everybody willing to make
glass beads it seems like a lot of
people think probably not to you there's
probably about three or four thousand of
us in the world but this gave an
opportunity to share ideas and to say oh
if you put this glass with this oxide
with this glass that has this metal in
it you can melt them together you get a
new color in between them or a new
reaction or it looks you'll get a new
green instead of the pink and the green
that you put together you may get a
totally different kind of green and just
as an aside here when I'm talking about
it when you put glass together he
doesn't mix like paint red and blue do
not make purple because of the medes
they'll react to one another and get
some other odd color based on whatever
they've gotten those two colors later on
Europe and the Asian countries got
involved in glass bead banking and now
it's a worldwide industry Russia is
really big Germany the United States is
kind of floundering a little bit we kind
of had so many people doing it for a
while that it was hard to sell your work
so a lot of people are hanging up there
towards you going on to do something
else but yeah it for me I'm sticking
with it
okay today we have national and
international conventions several online
groups from Facebook Instagram lots of
other places regional retreats I hope
co-host to retreat twice a year in
Asheville North Carolina we have 30
different artists and show up from all
over the country plus a couple from
Europe three days of just making glass
and having fun
there are several glass and tulle
suppliers this is probably one person's
rack of glass right here that looks like
heaven to me
and then there dozens of specialty
torches for beat work and guys if you
have any questions to holler man I'm
trying to bus do this so I can get to
the video okay so how far we've come I
want to show you some of the things that
people are making now glass these are
some other artists I really admire Brant
Pierce and I'm takes a personal friend
of mine does these beautiful pieces
they're huge this is a marble
and this is a friend barbell she does a
lot of sculptural pieces now the glass
that we use and I'll talk about that in
a few minutes does not make for doing
this it's soft glass it's made for
making round beads so pushing the
envelope ashtray bride down was a South
African artist and she uses enamels on
her beads and I still don't know how she
does this I've seen her doing us still
don't know how she makes them work like
this
this is a Lee Van de Graaff she's in the
Pacific Northwest she was 20 years old
she is such one where to blow glass she
made scientific glass in college ended
up working for Oakbridge laboratories to
a specialty scientific glass and she
start making these beads and that's um
that beat is probably the speaker she
uses probably I think it's four rods of
glass which I'll show up here to make
the base and it does the decoration the
drawings on there are thin hair thin
pieces of glass that she draws with
which is very very difficult because it
melts as fast as she put it on so you
have to get just at the right speed and
you draw with both hands basically
you're drawing with the base band with
the springer to get it to where you want
it to go the glass she used on this
particular one is one that's impregnated
was silver so it's got that nice shiny
surface to it and this is Holly Cooper I
just had a class with her not too long
back she uses a lot of enamels and does
a lot of stringer work there that's
three views of the same vein she likes
to make
cuz of Phoenician things and just to go
backwards just a bit this is where we
came from these are some early beads
here and then these are some Marini
beads which we'll talk about just a
moment slices of glass that's been put
together but you see how far the
techniques have come and how clean the
work is okay the types of glass this is
one of mine right here this is actually
a sculpture it's a little Christmas tree
stand and then crystal the Christmas
fish on top it was a special order there
are basically two kinds of glass that
are used to make beads either
borosilicate or soda lime glass
borosilicate is on some of you may be
old enough to remember going to a fair
or a mall and seeing people making
little animals at a clear glass and they
would lay them on the counter little
cool off for me to buy them that's a
totally different glass in what I use
that is similar to what your pirates
dishes used to be made out of and it's
got a different coefficient of expansion
than the soda lime glass which just
means it's a number of side of the glass
that tells you how much the glass
shrinks as it cools off and your glass
you can't mix two different cos because
you get stress in the glass speed break
soda lime is the traditional venetian
round bead glass against usually
for round beads it's manufactured Italy
Germany China Czech Republic India and
the United States all have different
companies that makes the glass
interesting that there used to be a
Chinese company that make glass it was
really horrible a woman from Canada
started a company she bought one of the
horrible companies in China she runs it
like a Western company they have now
have some of the finest glass you can
find and she's very very good to her
workers too so we like to support them
but their glass is really expensive
the glass they use begins to move in the
torch around a thousand degrees becomes
molten around twelve or fourteen hundred
depending on what's in the glass what
kind of metals or whatever they use and
my torch goes up around to 2,000 degrees
I hardly ever use it that hot listen I
am might need some borosilicate work the
glass can be transparent we can see
through it clear or you know a color
that you can see through it can be
opaque which in the glass world is
called the pest
and you'll be corrected by the
old-school people who can call it opaque
striking which means it starts out as
one color but when heated in the flame
and let it cool and then heat it again
and pick it out of the flame it turns
bright red or bright orange or bright
yellow those are fun and then the oxides
and the Oh pacifiers then put in the
glass make every single color feel
different in the flame white glass when
you put it in the flame we call it baby
snot because as soon as it gets hot it
just drips everywhere you have to really
learn to work with it and if I get the
video to work I'll be making a fish you
can see some of the the white glass it
turns absolutely clear while you're
working with it if there's cools off it
turns white again some of the stiffer
glasses like I think there's some cobalt
blue going around this transparent that
stuff is horrible to melt because it's
just so sticky there's so much stuff in
it to make it that deep rich blue that
you can hardly get it to melt and you
have to be careful with the different
colors because some colors do burn
yellows will bubble Reds will get what
we call liver spots on its
it's a constant learning curve every
time to pick up glass and you color you
have to play with it see what it does
and then if you're going to put it with
another glass to make a decoration on it
you may have to char the two together to
make sure that they will work together
they have today as doing some basic
glass work to be specialized specialized
shapes of the tube right right that's
how that Brad Pearson who made the big
marble he got his start we have a lot of
folks who started in scientific glass
they've moved over to the art world I
guess they were making too much money in
the oh yes
availability of soda lime glass and I
understand yeah what is that like
nowadays like is this available if you
want yeah yeah they're the company I get
most of my my glass from is Mountain
glass arts in North Carolina and they
specialize in borosilicate glass they
get a lot of sign backs that's the more
expensive the they have some Chinese
borosilicate clear I mean you know
usually you're gonna do something simple
with that I'm not sure where the color
borosilicate comes from it has always
been very expensive and very fickle you
don't know what color you're really
going to get till it comes out of the
kiln so but yeah it was a big problem
when the borosilicate market drawer the
supplier dried up from
okay we talked about the torches this is
the Nortel minor burner this is like the
toyota corolla of vice big making
torches it's not fast it's not hot it's
not sexy but it'll run every time you
turn it on and it melts beautifully how
many of these will yelling probably
fifteen or sixteen of them because I
teach classes and I take them through
the classes and you throw them in a box
and you take them to the next class you
take about a climate of a stable a table
hook up to the hoses of oxygen and
propane and they fire right up so
they're great little torches this is
called the cricket I think this is cute
I always think of men in black with a
little gun the cricket that's what it
reminds me I agree this is the Bethlehem
champion and you can see it's got two
hosts is the two red are for the propane
and the two green and for oxygen that
just gives you more oomph you can build
bigger stuff and as the torches get
bigger we refer to them as compensation
torches
this is a barracuda not many people need
this much firepower but people buy them
this torch right here the one that I
took the the first one the miner is
about $200 and this was about 1,500 the
Bethlehem stacks which is interesting if
he notice it's actually two torches yeah
it's got the the big one for actually
melting the glass and then the tiny went
up there for doing detail work that's
somebody doing this kind of stuff
couldn't do what I do because they'd
have too much fire going I actually work
with real tiny flame and I like to work
slowly and then you get to the mega
miner this looks like it's gonna take
over the world and these are interesting
I threw this in because the Japanese
have the kind of glass it's a totally
different CoA than anybody else it's got
a very high co e so it stays malleable
for a long time it's so soft when you
melt it that you could basically hold it
over a candle and it will start to move
it won't melt completely but it will
actually move it we're talking two rods
like they're going around there so they
use what's called a volcano torch the
flame comes straight up but you notice
there's no place for oxygen right here's
a little nozzle and what they do is it a
bit aquarium pump to it
and that just keeps the flame going
straight when I work with my flame and
you'll see if I get the video going but
I light it up I turn it on and it's just
a messy propane flame and it's going
everywhere it won't melt the glass it'll
just get it all sitting and make it warm
but when I had oxygen to it it cleans up
the flame and makes it earned very very
straight clean and it'll take all the
slip right off the glass there's my baby
the Bethlehem alpha I love this torch I
can with this particular one I can have
the flame up big and I can do what
horses look at icicles and things like
that or I could turn it down and do what
I liked it was very very tiny detail
work like I've got some little tiny dots
up here and I've got a seashell it's got
a crab living inside of it I did him
with that little tiny flame
the basic tools that I use and I have
some of this up here the manuals people
say how do you get the hole in the glass
I kind of start with a hollow which is
the mandrel and put the glass arm out of
it these are stainless steel 316l
uncoated the welding rods stainless
steel like I said they're dipped in this
clay mixture which is like a clay slip
just a water you play make sure that's
got graphite in it the end of its dipped
and everybody always says putting out
those sparklers because that's exactly
what it looks like when it's sparklers
that dries and then you make the bead on
to where that clay slip is and then if I
need it right on the metal rod stick to
the metal and break this is a spray and
you're running Pam make your brownies
the glass rods which just went around
here and then the panel over there is
graphite but we're shaping and making
long skinny beads would roll the glass
you don't want a tool that's going to
suck the heat out of the glass if you
use brass it's going to cool it off too
fast and put stress in it
graphite tends to not soak up the heat
so quickly and you have little working
time and then on the end here these
glasses we call these birth control
glasses because nobody looks sexing up
they're actually a special coating is
called goddamn em and when you put the
tort by the glass into the flame there's
a sodium flare that is intense yellow
but hurt your eyes yellow it won't
damage your eyes like some of the
borosilicate can it's so bright you can
actually burn your retinas with the soda
lime glass it's more of a hindrance it's
so bright and some yellow that you can't
see what you're doing so when you put
these glasses on it's like magic
it's always funny to have visitors to
the studio it's like okay look at the
put on the glasses and be safe but
they're working and say that look over
your glasses and they raise it up and
everybody was good
Wow because it's just this intense
yellow there are better looking glasses
than that but not much I actually worked
with a little bit of borosilicate so I
have a flip-up shiny that's darker it's
not gonna be working on soft glass and
then decide to make some icicles out of
aura flip it down and I've come to
stronger protection some things that we
use frit is just round up glass glass
blowers glass it's very very
concentrated you can make your own but
there's a couple of companies that make
it this is Bell Cox's line she has lots
more than this where she's come up with
mixes of glass that complement one
another or do things in the flame people
we have posed a threat now they want to
come right up and go with their favor
telling them not to one of the coolest
things she was doing a demo one time in
Scottsboro and alchemy actually torches
out outside she has a shield up and
she's actually making the beads so
people can see it a couple little kids
come up what's the first thing I want to
do reach for the flame Terry when it
Kevin Linda muy caliente their eyes
basically speak Spanish you know huh
it's so cool not expecting Spanish we
talked about how what's in the glass
makes different things happen and I just
pulled out an example this this
particular it's called aqua violet and
that's just foul came up with a name for
that's what it looked like to her and
she made it on these different beads
those are all the same frit on different
face beads so what you do is you make
your bead and then you roll it in some
friend melted in easiest bead you can
make so it's just kind of interesting
that when you put it on different colors
it does different things and some of the
glass is really really drastic that what
he does sometimes and sometimes it
reacts horribly like ivory colored glass
if you put what's called a reactive
color when it turns to mud it just
doesn't look like anything sometimes you
get a whole new colors sometimes you get
there's a purple glass we have which I
said they're still trying to get a good
purple it's an opaque purple number 862
it's the number of it but we call it EDP
evil Deventer fine purple because when
you put it in the flaming and work it
causes crystal growth
like a white frost comes out on the
surface of glass and then you have to
reheat it make it go back in but you got
try to turn it and reheat everything
exactly the same amount and it's really
hard to do but yeah usually you try to
get something that either blends or
highly contrasting especially might need
eyes when you say it Alex when you
mention the ribs I figured that you'd
probably be watch a little sharp uh-huh
it's broken glass and it can be either
like almost like enamel or it can be
great big chunks you can get it
different sizes okay
Morini this is one of my favorite things
to make and it's very very
time-consuming you can take your glass
and Bank
these are rods it's somewhat it's make
where they made it gather and glass
which is a blob of glass and they took
another broader glass and drew those
little curved lines with it real thick
and then they encased it meaning they
wrap glass around it and then they head
on a handle here and they took another
rod of glass and stuck it to it and they
turned it it might be this big and they
turn it when it gets hot all the way
through they start pulling and pulling
pulling until it narrows down against as
small as they want and they clip it off
you can cut it into these little slices
right here and then make a bead and
adhere it to the bead and it looks like
roses these down here are different kind
of marry me and then some folks have a
lot of fun we're doing with cartoon
characters and things so it all depends
on what you want to spend the time
learning to do I've got some samples of
some uini up here you may have seen this
this this floated around on reddit for a
while and it's been in the news a lot
want all those Wow have you seen this
kind of things this is Lauren stumps
work and like over here this is a
close-up you can see the detail in there
this slice they're sliced it off is
about that big $500 a slice what happens
is he had to do that like I told you how
the erosion was made all those layers
that you pull it out was skinny he does
that with each individual part each
eyeball each knows each mouth it has to
pull out like that and then go back and
put them together and melt them again
and pull them out
so it takes ages to do something like
this if you take us fights with lurid
stuff you basically work from 8:00 a.m.
to whenever you finish the next morning
because there's just so much to do you
can actually see on this one right here
the clear glass word was pulled so I
don't I'm going to give a quick shout
out right now to beat the courage it's a
group that we support all beat makers
beads of courage against handmade means
to kids who have catastrophic illness as
a way for them to record and tell their
stories when you're four and you're in
the hospital for a year you really don't
know how to explain that but if you have
a little yellow bead for every time you
got a shot and a black bead for every
night you're in the hospital and
glow-in-the-dark bead or whenever you
got an x-ray I mean they go on and on
and on when the kids hit a milestone
they get a dream beam they get sent off
to a bead artist and have a specialty
being made and if a child passes we make
butterfly beads for the parents it's an
awesome awesome program so if you're
ever looking for someone to support
they're wonderful wonderful people beads
of courage don't work if you want to
take a look and I got a few of my pieces
going here I'm gonna try to get the
video going in questions before step
forward handed out do is twisters yes
and there's gonna be one made in the
video
right it doesn't work you take two or
three or 40 pieces of glass get them hot
get them connected to each other twist
them and you pull them out to get them
that small then Terry will use them to
literally well what I say draw on the
glass so that feather is blast just like
this is or to do the little black greens
around that would just be a plain full
black but shows you all the different
things I'm talking so you can put your
video if you would like to come up and
take a look at any stuff I've got
examples of print and mandrels and jars
that I've blown we do that actually take
piece of stainless steel brake line dip
it in the clay mixture wrap the glass on
the end and blow it so it's what you've
seen the people on TV blow the great big
ones I so many questions
give me just a minute here and I'll try
to get this video going if you're
interested in the big loan stuff a lot
of time to think about blowing glass I
would recommend Orbitz pop glass it's in
Fort Payne Alabama
he's been on when Oprah and her show he
was on twice as a yeah favorite things
and Christmas is here you can actually
go there and they have bows and Prince
lei now take out the trip
you want they will gather the glass on
the blowpipe and let you blow into it to
expand it yes Jen initiative Asheville
bunch of a Nashville does that one and
then they roll it and the sprit and do
all that stuff
yeah
you know I say to me bad things I'm okay
so this is my little Alfa right here
I've got some white glass and with the
soda lime with more silicon you stick an
appointment i cough for silicon it's
fussy so you have to kind of tease it
into the flame but sticking your toe in
a hot tub of water would you say that be
the Alpha that you have is a good
beginners tour yes yes there are torches
you can get it at Hobby Lobby $75
they're frustrating and you actually use
a can of matte glass and hook it on the
table so you're sitting there with a
bomb in your lap yeah these torches are
much safer and you learn a much much
quicker on these okay there's the white
glass you can see kind of turned clear
I'm gonna pull a stringer one time T
really teaching the scientific
glassblower how to do the soft glass and
like you said
before so just think it complaining did
she kept warning him you can't do that
with soft blacks you have to tease it
well that's the second time I further
say that I start backing away and I saw
Terry back in a way lo and behold a few
seconds later tip of that just blew up
so I pulled the string up skinny and
laid it over the side this is one of the
stainless steel manuals they come in
different sizes
I've got tiny ones I use for jewelry and
then these bigger ones I use for not
blowing the little jars on them or
making Endora beep okay so I'm going to
start to make the bead I've eaten up the
mandrel and the tricky thing about this
that everybody is always surprised about
is when I'm teaching class it's the
first day of class awful okay here's
your here's your homework for tonight
thank this rod and learn to roll it in
your hand so you can keep it moving
and level and then after you learn to do
that
do the other hand to most if it did one
hand and then if you get that
now do it backwards come towards you so
you have to feel how the glass deflated
on there as to whether to go forward or
backwards what I've done here is I've
made a wrap around and made it like a
disc beat you see it's kind of like a
rope wrapped around the mandrel and I'm
gonna put a little dot here on the end
so that you can see how slowly I'm
turning it and when I turn it it's a
little hard to jump you can see that
little dot on the end there and it's
switching over to my right hand because
I can balance a little bit better now
I'm heating the outside edge of that
that disc just the other edge because
when you heat glass has an interesting
property
it wants to be round so if you can
balance it it's going to turn it into a
ball as you're working so I'm trying to
heat the outer edge and have it sink
down on itself so that's a big fat round
rope around that mandrel just what make
speed
a lot of the shaping is done outside the
flame that's always surprising the
people who try this when they first
start out I think you've got to get in
the flame and get it soupy hot and then
it gets floppy and it starts to spin out
of control you learn to turn it get it
bright orange like this and come out of
the flame and keep turning and the glass
will continue to settle down it's all
about heat gravity and heat control your
glasses actually that's with the glasses
you're looking through a diamond plating
it's probably three or four times that
bright without it
and likes they won't hurt your eyes but
you'll be really really tired your eyes
will be dry very quickly okay can you
see that melted down into like a basic
they were called rondell shape or a
doughnut shaped bead now real quickly if
you want to be a beating snob I'll tell
you what I think the look for we around
the hole if we've got the bead laying
here and the hole is on top the sides of
the beach come up and dip down so that
the hole is in the little Valley two
reasons one it protects whatever you
string it on just straight up and down
it makes a saw out of it and if you make
sure it's got the Creole valleys on each
end that shows you had the workmanship
to make it like you wanted you'll
accidentally get those sometimes but if
you consistently get those on your baby
whurling here I'm putting dots on
the bead I took that stringer just heat
up the glass and put the little dots on
there I'm gonna go back over here put it
on the side in an alternating pattern I
talked about Brad Pearson the one with
the big marble I showed you first he
taught me how to put dots on and he's so
intent he actually does it between
heartbeats
to get it hit at the right place I hold
my breath when I do it I have a little
pattern I did where I touch and it's a
good pattern to get into a good rhythm
when you put the dots on cuz that's
harder than it looks to get them in the
right place I have to write them out
each time and you've probably seen beads
like this with the little rows of dots
on them
never needed a little more
someone turned into flame and trying to
heat just the dots I've got my face the
way I wanted I don't want to melt it
again I want to keep it warm though if I
let that bakes cool off it's going to
break in half or explode I am now
because I'm trying to heat the little
dots and I'm trying to get the heat to
do the same all the way around pretty
quickly and when you first put the dots
on I think with a tip each other they
stand up like this if I want to do is
heat them enough that they spread up
make a dome because if they're tippy-toe
of filling them into the ball if you
bump it the fall off you want as much of
that area touching the base as possible
do you have to do you have to use a
higher melting glass for the initial
let's use large glass
now as you melt those dots they they
sink in or smooth out so I can leave the
dot standing up where I can milk them
until they're actually smooth with the
surface of the surface of the bead and
right there I'm just trying to check and
make sure everybody's melted in see the
dots disappear they turn clear and you
come out of the flame and turn and they
turn back to light so when I see that
clear where the white should be I know
that how hot it is it's extremely
running hot there you go all the dots
are disappearing it's trying to melt
them in and then they come back
and then once I'm happy with that I'll
grab some black I was trying to get
colors you can see on the video you come
and put a dot on top and you notice
these little handlebars I have right
here those are just little wrist wrists
and they're not firmly in position I
just got those like when you go down
your stairs at home any put your hand on
the rail look you don't give it a death
grip you just kind of lightly put your
hand on it to kind of get your balance
you know as you drop down the stairs
that's kind of a beastie thing they let
me put my hands in a single location and
that way I'm not moving and without
realizing it so there's a little black
dot right on top of the white ones there
and then when I finish a bead it goes
into a kiln if I were to put that down
on the table or in a bucket of sand or
vermiculite let it cool there's a lot of
stress in the bead when you put the bead
in the flame you get it really really
hot so those molecules are really going
crazy and then you pull it out to
decorate it in the freezer the shape and
they put your decoration on you go back
into the flame and they start moving
again if you once they're so excited you
can never get them lined up again so
there's a good Network holding that
thing together so what I do is take it
when I'm finished put it in a kiln it
sits at 960 degrees for an hour which is
just below the melting point it lets
that be it's exactly the same
temperature all the way through and then
my kiln steps down it cools off over
several hours
it's it's a very slow cooling process
your crap score beats they don't do that
they're just stuck in sand if anything
or they're just they make on the rock
drum in a pile so basically it's an
annealer yes okay I'm gonna try to speed
this up a bit I'm making a twisty I've
got a metal rod with no none of the clay
slip on it and I'm putting some pea
green or as we call it Kermit green and
I'm just putting a ball on the end of it
we'll try to speed this up because I
realized I was putting a lot of stuff on
here I came back in after made the ball
and I put two white stripes you can see
that on there and I'm gonna come back
and put some turquoise stripes on it
and I think I actually need to put a
little bit of black on there too
yep there's the black when you work with
glass that thin you gotta learn
Niq techniques to get it to go where you
wanted to go without melting in half
and then
I'm gonna check in another no I'm sorry
fix to the black right there
I took another metal rod heated the end
of it stuck it into the glass so I've
got a hand only beside those are called
pun T's and now I'm turning my hands
together you say the lines are staying
kind of straight over all the colors I'm
going back and forth what I'm trying to
just get the heat cook all the way
through I tell my students not cooking a
chicken if you put it on a rotisserie
and spin it really fast you can burn the
outside still have raw chicken in the
middle what you want to do is with this
is turn it slowly but the heats so curly
you see how it's turning orange all the
way through now there aren't any real
dark spots in it
the students dip rods will transfer heat
and glass does it transfer heat there's
some ambient heat to the side but it's
not hot and then I'm turning one hand in
one direction one in the other I have
some samples I love baking these turn
fast and pull apart turn fast and pull
apart and then the glass says I'm done
it firms up it tells you when it's done
you twist it far enough rate let see if
everything's I've let go with the other
hand in the help no I haven't liked it
you gonna burn it off and there
sometimes it breaks off on one end
whatever you're doing that and will
superheat that and stick it with water
that glass will shock and break off and
you can use that metal rod again and
with the other side I have to take my
very specialized Ace Hardware pliers and
dip them in water yeah if it doesn't
melt we'll use it for it too
okay fish sculpting i speeded this up a
little bit and try not to keep you guys
too late i took one of my stainless
steel rods different than clay make sure
but I'm working off the end I'm making a
sculpture so all I'll do this with one
hole in the bottom of the fish then make
a stand and sit on top of it but I'm
just making a ball of glass there and
you can see this kind of turn into a
ball pretty quickly remember the white
melts really really
so it's gonna farm up into or shake up
into a ball
see you around that is already
Wow bus want to come in okay this is
nice and warm now and I'm gonna heat it
up a little bit and see the red up there
in the little gold that's Frick
it's what Frick the ground of last we
talked about the intense colors so we'll
get that nice and warm and I'll go in
and get some Fred and then just put it
back in the flame and melt it in and it
just be some nice models decoration
you know what's good for just a little
bit I've shape the glass by holding it
in the heat and letting one side droop
down and I turned over at the other side
root down so I've got a fish body shape
you singer homeboy I do
sometimes I think out loud keeps me from
cursing time okay so they put some high
balls on or at least basis for the high
ball just a little bit of Blackcomb
there to give me a pad to put it on and
that's just a little too I used to match
the dot down and make it a flat circle
that's why I don't put them in the flame
okay so if you make big you're gonna put
some white on
okay and then come back and put a little
dot of black and C's personality
starting to come out
and then we put a clear lens over each
eye just to magnify and make it look
this year
if make sound effects when you work with
glass - okay here I'm putting this I
guess her lips on I used a bright red
and I put a big ball of glass on the end
looks like she's blowing bubble gum and
I'm gonna heat it up and take my trusty
now I even come on hurry what I'm doing
is I'm trying to heat it up and then
tilt it back on top so that it melts
down it doesn't like stretch out because
it will just stretch out the drip okay
so got my trusty little knife and I go
in and cut that in half and rock it back
and forth and all sudden she's got big
luscious lips visually I call these book
toxic Guppies carp dashians you get what
you pay for
okay so now I'm gonna go in with a
little bit of clear and I'm gonna put a
stripe down and back malefic that was
fun and I'm gonna put some on the tail
and if you see I keep going back in the
flame I've got to keep that glass some
warm so I've got it in and out of the
flame to keep it warm and still because
I put big thick stripes on the back and
the tail
do you have that one here I don't and I
don't know that I have a fish with me
we're gonna go about the studio I'll
pick it up on the way and we got your
running light and just didn't get it
okay you can see this big thick on the
back there and now I'm thinking about
flyers my handy-dandy base Flyers
non-serrated Flyers I'm heating all of
this and because the thin and tail are
really thin I'd be careful about heating
I've got to keep it warm but I can't get
it too hot or it's gonna melt then sink
into the other but I want to keep it
from breaking so I'm heating up the sack
then I'm gonna take my pliers this isn't
through a moment and pinch the Flyers
they just go around the edge
those are dick pliers let's get a little
bit pardon oh and you're ruffling the
yeah I'm ruffling the fins on it with
the pliers so spin that around so it
gets the warmer and the mantra right
here is to be right don't break them
then you put too much glass on a rod and
then you just go oh yeah oh yeah you're
only getting the glamor shots here good
ever to be pretty bad a beat goes bad we
got a cup of water for putting on little
bits of glass in and stuff and sometimes
we call it water and kneeling if one
just goes south so far it can't be saved
just Shh it's quite a satisfying sound
when you had a naughty beating you get
to give it a very listen
okay so you see there's a little ruffled
feathers the minute up feather spins and
then I'll go in I like to go one step
farther and actually twist them a little
bit so it gets motion so it looks like
the fish is in water got some motion to
it I'm guessing you sell some of these
hopefully yes cuz it's an expensive
hobby my glass lot people ask about the
glass the glass runs about 10-12 dollars
a pound which is about 20 sticks
football sticks depending on what's in
it that's pretty cheap there's some it's
$100 a pound you use that very sparingly
but there's fish
there you go just pour mine in the fish
fryer I've tried to spin it bets just to
get a little heat in there before it
goes in the kiln and
my vices cut off
[Applause]