whoo I am here today to tell you 10
making is not cheap but it is fun
a lot of people ask me why I get in the
Fed making and this is legitimately the
conversation that went down between a
co-worker and I they heard I had a
length in my workshop and I told me off
I got one for my grandpa that my dad
gave me and they were like you should
get them to make depends because the guy
on the square makes a lot of money doing
it sounds like sure why not what could
go wrong
so about $14,000 later in the past two
years I've made about sixty seven
hundred dollars
what I what do I use to make pens delay
by using the bottom as a nova comment
too I also you don't need it but a drill
press comes in handy did you have to
drill the center of the pen blanks out a
disc sander comes in handy also for
sanding the ends of the blanks flushed
with the metal tube and miter saw a
bandsaw table saw some sort of way to
chop it down to the right here wait and
I use carbide tip shows you can make do
with smaller cheaper ones but I went
with the big ones because I also like to
turn bolts
you're gonna need a pin mackerel this
allows you to take the bushings link
put it together like this up here and
what that does is it holds it really
tight so that when it's spinning at 4000
rpms it doesn't catch on your chills the
bushings you don't have to have bushing
you can do it the old-fashioned way and
use calipers this is a lot easier
because it guide you on each end you
know where you need to be flush at the
center can be anything you want but in
order to match it match up with the
metallic parts it needs to be flushed
with the bushings and then if you decide
to finish with a CA glue
you'll need some CA glue we also can you
CA glue Gorilla Glue 5 minute epoxy any
strong adhesive them to glue the metal
tube into the end blank and I used to
use sandpaper but not so Sandlin but now
I preferred the murca mush I also I
didn't bring any with me but I used own
a paper to polish instead of micro mesh
and for the the very last piece I do is
I use hutt ultra polish and that gives
it the last little bit of shine that
needs
so I spent a few grand on equipment and
supplies now I I broke this up in the
phases because I've learned the assemble
lining assembly lining the process
allows you to make more pins in the same
amount of time phase one is to get your
preparation done you want to pick a bike
any kind of length you want and then you
think the tip that you're going to want
to go with it
and every kid has its own set of
bushings so then you find your set of
bushings if you don't keep track of them
then you waste more money buying some
more bushing once you found the correct
bushings and you got everything ready
you got trimmed blanks you actually take
the metal tube out of package
and normally these are longer but you
can cut it down so that it's the right
length and leave about a sixteenth two
or more on each end of it so that if
you're drilling it and the acrylic for
wood splinters at the end you have
enough where you can sand it off so that
it's you can still use it
and once you do that you take it over to
the drill press or you can get you can
drill it on your legs if you have that
set up and if you're really desperate
you can use a hand drill I would
recommend the hand drill and then once
you have the hole drilled you glue it
and buy one of these nifty little jigs
for your just standard I think this was
about twenty dollars of well worth the
$20 but you take just a bunch of stuff
that you can get at Harbor Freight and
you match the one that's the closest to
the diameter of your you tube you slide
it in there and you just saying that
gives you a nice flush surface when you
sand it with the sander these two
Mountain turn
now it's one part
the actually only fun part he mounted we
put the
bushings on the plank
and then
I've turned all my films at 4000 rpms I
I tried to think of a way to tell you
how I do it there's just it's not
something that I can put the words
there's something you need to just kind
of watch and which is why I was hoping
to do a demo but it would have been too
much sawdust and strings of resin up in
the air and probably got caught the
chandelier and once you have it turned
down to the shape you want
that's one of my mess ups where the it
was a coloring pencil and at the very
end part of the coloring pencil flew out
but once you have it you have it turned
down you sanded stand it some more and
when you think you're done sanding you
stand it a little bit more but there's
some more examples of mounting the pen
blanks and delay lets degree resin
is the finished product Dean pins that
we yes
this was yep this is what I did it for a
custom order customer asked me to make
them a two hundred dollar pen so I spent
about three days working on this this
one this one it's 300 something to
millimeter by two millimeter by two
millimeter squares all glued up together
in a spiral
what's the minimum wage I make nothing
so far I mean you know that into
woodworking cuz you like doing it yeah
do you have a picture of that finished
perfect I do it's Maya it was the
profile picture on my sculpture oh yeah
I might have enough I might have one in
here again I'm not sure I made these
slides like a month and a half ago phase
three four would I have to I broke it up
into two different phases because I do
wood differently than resin with wood
dry say on the wood to 400 grit wipe it
down with denatured alcohol and before
applying to see a finished I like least
and with 400 again I have cut myself
numerous times and of course this
fingertip right here is I nearly cut it
off completely it's it's a bloody
business was working but once I do is
see the see a finish see a is basically
like type of superglue and you just
apply numerous thin layers onto the pin
as its spinning them slowly and once I
have the CA finish done I use ona paper
in increments from 300 or 330 micron
down the one micron
it's a right side on acrylic ya survival
it's a special super glue I use mercury
flux which
is designed to flex a little so that it
won't completely crack and then I polish
with a polishing cloth and sometimes
depending on whether or not I still see
fine scratches I will buff with jewelers
Rouge but it really just some of whom I
do the polishing and it looks great some
of them it needs a little bit more oh I
haven't found the rhyme or reason I
don't know if it's something my process
that I'm doing differently or if I'm
having a bad day or yeah phase three for
resin
I like resin because it makes ginormous
mess and if you get up just right you
get these long rip ribbons that just
keep coming off and during phase three I
wet sand to 400 grit I may or may not
apply a CA finish it sounds honest it's
got wood in it really I'm doing a hybrid
you know I'll do a CA finish and then
the rest of it's just like doing the the
wood ace for is assembly sounds easy
and normally it is easy except for when
the distributor sends you
you putting together a nice fancy
fountain town and they send you two of
the same part and not one of the other
and you're sitting there trying to and
not all of them have pictures either a
lot of them are just words where they're
like tell you didn't put this and this
and this and so that's been a steep
learning learning curve also it's just
being able to decipher some it's
probably converted over from Chinese or
something but a lot of them just don't
make any sense
step 5 profit no problem with that is I
only have so many friends a family to
self instead and after going to my first
show I found out there's two other Penn
Turner's in my small town also and I
also found out that Etsy charges up the
absentees
but it's easy and funnels random people
to my site it doesn't take nearly the
work that it would trying to run my own
site and advertise so it's kind of worth
them taking 40 to 50 percent of Asics
denial keep telling yourself eventually
I'm gonna start making some money
meanwhile developing two did an
addiction for cool-ass tens and I start
swapping with other fin makers around
the world where I worked more over time
with my day job
so that I could pay my debt and then
this past summer I dropped out of the
grand on an air conditioner because when
it's a hundred degrees 100 plus degrees
outside and a metal building it's not
very cool
now that I'm in deep
why don't try to save some money start
making my own inclined pen blanks that's
an example of one of the blocks I've
returned recently it had some sexually
the one this one's made out of it's got
some glow-in-the-dark in it that's the
it's not a pressure cooker
it's a pressure pot it's a it's a
converted big spray-paint like
automobile automotive painter that I I
kind of feel bad for destroying kind of
because it was like $1,000 almost brand
new paint pot that had like the
automatic mixer and everything in it and
I just ripped that out and bolted it up
with some jb weld to seal it up and
built the contraption up top to show me
the pressure I've got the got the
emergency release valve on in case it
for some reason and I put too much
pressure in it so it doesn't blow up in
my face and it's got the I don't know
how well works but it's supposed to
filter the water out so the water
doesn't get into the the pressure pot
from air hose I'm down here we have my
casting bench
it's covered with HDPE eighth inch
material because you can just wipe the
or pop the resin right off of it it's
the same material that the molds are
made oh that make it easier it's just
remove any resin I just let it dry and
then pop it off maybe twice a year what
could go wrong I learned the hard way
that silicone molds are only good for so
many times and then the oils in them are
sucked out by the epoxy and it dries
them up to the point where the they
stick you go to pull out go to pull the
the tube out or the blank out of the
mold and it just pulls part of the mold
with it I also learned the hard way that
you only have so much time to work when
it's a hundred degrees in your shop and
the alumalite is ready to be put in the
pot at 95 the that's just I put it in
the pot after after work and then I
completely forgot to put pressure in the
pot and this is an example of what it
would look like without the pressure and
when you put it in the pressure pot it
doesn't remove the bubbles it doesn't
make the bubbles come out it actually
compresses them so small they're
microscopic and then that's why you have
to keep it under pressure until it's
fully cured if you if you drop the
pressure before it's cured those bubbles
will expand again and just cracker
resident oh I haven't learned that one
I've only read about it
letting in this worth it I'm one of
about 12 people in the world that have
figure out how to put playing cards and
inside of resin on a pen zoo as far as I
know I'm only one of two they do that
does it with collectible card games I
can make I can now make my own colors
here and make gifts I gave that one to
my mom for Mother's Day and here's that
that spiral one finish the $200 special
order on the far right there was a
retirement gift for my supervisor of 15
years I work my day job is in Telecom
and that was all those pens and the
display were made from wood that was
pulled from a wooden test panel that was
removed in 1989 but another co-worker so
I was able to take some of that wood did
they had salvaged and had sitting around
and I turned fins out of it and gave it
to him as a graduation or retirement
good and also five star reviews on it so
you're kind of addicting
now it's time for the live demo
so they wouldn't let me not Larry once I
returned so I'm gonna be making an
alumina light block I'm gonna be mid
using blood-red screen and antique gold
[Laughter]
I'm gonna try to make it like a
Christmasy color okay if we took it
outside would you be able to turn we
could if I brought my leg with me that's
something you want me to do next year no
I can do it outside yeah
where she want to start with some gloves
you really don't want to get it on your
hands and from experience if you get it
on your clothes the clothes are trash
because the resin will harden and it
doesn't sound so bad and so the resin
then cracks empty washing and then your
clothes have big like cracks because it
breaks apart the fabric and everything
no because before I wash I let it dry so
this block right here takes 600 grams
alumalite is a 1 to 1 a 2 B side by
weight I'm going to be doing 250 grams
of red 250 grams of green and a hundred
grams of gold so I just want the gold to
be kind of like an accent color we're
going to start by pouring 125 of a 125
of a and 50
and these are new branded models because
Tuesday I want to start packing and I
found out that my hardener had
completely crystallized it been so long
since I used it because I prefer to use
royal foam resin though it's got a
longer work time so I can do more than
just two or three colors if I wanted to
but due to the limited timeframe here
I'm going with Illumina like slow
because it's got to work time with 12
minutes and then I can Diebold it in two
to four hours and the 12 minute timer
doesn't actually start until I mix beat
the b-side in
so the colors of those alumalite as well
the colors are I most of my coloring
that I uses from caster's choice it's a
powdered michael so it's not glitter but
you can use glitter if we wanted to
Commission you to make a glitter pin
that's the one just like normal blue tur
when I turn it it gets all over the shop
like
yes I've made a few pins out of glitter
although I've started when I want a
glittery effect i order some there's a
gentleman out there Tim McKenzie that
makes blanks with diamond dust and it's
a lot spark more sparkler than clear
how's that are your carbide tools cuffs
right through because it's it's not
cutting the diamonds yes they're really
fine particles
is that the B side this is the color the
mica color it's a very fine dust that
specifically says don't breathe it in
because I'm assuming some dumbasses but
the more you use the better obviously
you don't want you to dump a little
thing in because this cost about five
dollars a jar caster choice makes some
pretty good colors
but I've learned from experience you
don't use enough then when you turn it
down and if you're doing a end with a
very thin edge you will be able to see
through to the the to the graphs to so
by having too much
mica we make it less likely to be able
to see through in the fence boss
wiping the sides yep to just try to get
it you mixed in universally right now
but when I mix the when I mix the b-side
in scraping the sides will be to make
sure it's uniform in it they were trying
to cut me into the sticks I swear
like so much work in the bottom isn't
perfectly fine has a little Ranger and
over and you can also introduce regions
lets you sand it after you cut it but
the bottom isn't the good life
when he first mix it in you don't want
to like just jab in there and start
going at it you want to kind of gently
mix it in otherwise you're going to have
a pool of mica into your face
all right now that the colors are mixed
up put it on the scale and reset it so
that it zero
and now we're going to start with the
b-side
is there any kind of reaction like heat
or anything that happened yes it's a
thermic branch and it's going to create
heat this so I'm going to test it for
the temperature and when he gets up to
1/2 of the colors get the 95 is 1 I'll
mix it in pour them all
we're part equal amounts of envy yep by
weight my grams you mistake my heritage
either get out after but it doesn't
matter what it wanes right now is my
included home I hit zero altitude now
has a way to zero
now you mix
the next five minutes will probably be
me too
yes as it starts to set up the care gets
thicker inside 95 degrees there should
be enough thickness that it won't when
you pour it in if all the colors
won't just mesh together there'll be a
degree of separation scraping the sides
to make sure I get any of the part a
that was on the side mixed in with Part
B in the center
and before we started I sprayed the mold
with your thing mold release so that
when I take it out in the morning it
will hopefully buff out a little easier
if not I've got a hammer there's a guy
into the next room that probably has I'm
pretty sure anyone around the room 158
he didn't me this afternoon when I
charge my but if anyone asked it wasn't
me
seventy-nine
and the way I'm measuring it as I'm
stirring it and lifting the popsicle
stick right and measuring it at the on
the popsicle stick to get a more
accurate reading of the internal
temperature because the resident would
stop and start to pull off you won't get
an accurate reading of what the
temperature is inside so may human it
cool tricky once you make an you think
that it's not as far as it is and then
it'll start setting up on YouTube not
too warm but you can tell there's a
reaction on the four midget
for
yep
now historically the from dealing with
these Micah's for some reason the red
heats up quicker I'm sure there's a
scientific explanation you started first
no even it's just the last one it'll
warm up quicker than the other colors
Frank you that
and go over some other stuff all that's
hearing when you turn in always protect
your lungs and personal experience
protect your face a bowl that I've
turning forehead and then about 20 yards
into the yard and then I know order to
mask off Amazon
luckily mist my glasses otherwise I
probably would I really don't miss and
this is what I used to press the metal
fittings into the brass tubes just
insert supports in here except the
there will push them together
so if you wanted to make a bit what's
the minimum you can get a you get
suppressor you gotta have a leave well
you can get by without doing this with
some C clamps padding you need you can
get a cheap legs off of Harbor Freight
you can get cheap turning pull off
partner Frank you will need a a mandrel
or turning between center set and that
just comes down to personal preference
some cap some pin centers like the turn
between centers which instead of having
the rod that goes through we just clamp
onto the two ends turn it I've tried it
we already 95 they're three
[Music]
all right we're coming up to the poor
part visually we have another 1919 this
is where the medley happens
and this is where your artistic
prevalence is whatever you want to
however you want to front for it
pouring it in because of the sand away
between 45 and 50 and it's good it's at
49 this is set to go off at 52 and now
at the corner for the next four hours
like items in there to join someone that
does like fishing net yes she knows
right yeah cast them in solutions but
usually if you're gonna put things in
it's gonna be more of like a bottle
stopper we have a bigger area and you're
not cutting out the center that way you
can do like book there's people that do
like beach scenes was it was stand those
tiny shells in there yeah
how does a guy drilled through my fish
hook it's hardened steel no he bends up
around the tooth oh and then cast over
it kinda like what I do with the cards
and then I get I also do circuit board
pens but I pay a cheap Chinese labor for
them because it's winning I can't do it
for a bracelet they specifically
threaten the circuit boards just support
but no offense
[Music]
and the faster you write alumina like
regular heart is extremely fast I'm
gonna have the slow but this other resin
could you tell us about that
thank you royal palm resin yeah it's
made by a guy down in Florida I just
started using it mate and it's a it's an
epoxy resin but instead of having mixing
at 95 degrees you have until about 125
degrees so you got a lot longer to if
you want to do multiple colors or like
when I'm doing I don't have to do colors
when I do these but I have a lot of
little molds that have to pour into so
the longer working time is a lot easier
I don't know what it's made out of but
it's also low VOCs no Xbox or kinky
that's good info it's a I got it because
I also wanna start casting in my house
like they're the winner during the
summer it's climate-controlled in-house
and the Royal bomb resin is a little
VOCs so you don't have to have two
organic compounds
yes either plan to upgrade it'll be
early right now
I'm fine with my $500 legs vs. that's
the one I got yeah I think there's a few
things but ever wanted to turn those or
something if you want to do like larger
bowls where you can get an extension to
actually probably do a baseball bat but
it's more like the wider oh yeah yeah
because of the distance between the
spindle and the bed you can only turn as
far as casting yeah I haven't cast
hidden they have turns just a lot of
woods from around the world they of
course the better-looking ones are the
burrows which I don't know if not larry
has it on him but last summer he went up
he went hiking and he had a walking
stick that broke so he gave it to me and
I made a pen out of it it's it's no
fancy wood it's just it was a pion stick
that he used but it's it's more of a
kind because of a sentimental value tone
that's something that concerning what
you do 115 may or may not go up on a
table in the atrium tomorrow
that's a that's a rollerball thank you
with a they sent me a few refills for
roller balls that you can don't have to
be capped for up to a year normally
rolled Laurel has to have the cap on it
so it doesn't dry out another's work I
do roller balls fountains regular ball
points and I've done one dipped in one
of the slides showed showed two blanks
on the lathe at the same time is is that
because you were using a pattern to make
them identical it's because it was a pen
had two tubes so I was just turning both
of them at the same time top part of the
pin in the bottom part doubled your
efficiency right there yeah it took me
three nights 3045 minutes each night
because I have to like I had to break it
up because what I did was I took two pen
blanks and I cut them lengthwise and
blew them up alternatingly
and then the next night I took it the
other way so that it looked like at the
end of the fake a little chessboard and
the third night I cut them all up and
created a spiral then the fourth fourth
night is when I could actually turn it
[Applause]