all right thanks for coming everybody
this is project room service and a
little introduction so my name is Robert
ward this is my bio that I wrote five
minutes ago so in my day job I'm a
software developer so I wrote most for
what you're gonna see today and this is
Joe Joe by day is a security analyst who
helps keep all of your medical data is
secure if you go to Washington
University for any sort of an ailment so
what is project room service the does
anyone else take way too much with
them when they travel like especially
electronics and gives my us and stuff
like that so we were sitting around
after DEFCON a couple weeks ago talking
about like it's just a pain to get there
and have to set everything up and have
all this trouble plugging everything in
well drinking beer yeah that goes here
that goes without saying so the goal of
room service was to put all this stuff
into this for the record that that's a
photo of our hotel room at freakin 19 I
think everything that we had on the tour
beds you can see lots of gear obviously
if you look really closely I'm actually
mid Linux install on my laptop there so
basically when we check into a hotel we
spend hours hooking up our own little
private land in the hotel room before we
can actually sit down and relax and
project room service is less about
trying to reduce the amount of crap but
more streamlining it just if you look
closely in that picture among the things
you can see multiple laptops multiple
raspberry PI's Wi-Fi pineapple
Perdue bunch of tools like that multiple
tablets hard drives more than we would
ever actually hook up during a weekend
here but we bring it anyway because
probably compulsory yeah
gadget guys or something like that so
what was our goal with the project there
we go
I heard it's project goals so we wanted
to be able to hook up a small land you
know in the hotel room so that would get
enacted all of our devices have the
internet feed be from the hotel Wi-Fi or
land wherever is provided gets us around
any kind of device limit in some hotels
they say okay you only have two devices
or something like that we can plug
everything we have we wanted an
instant-on VPN access because usually we
go to hacker conferences and we don't
trust any of you plus you know video
screen to the TV so we've got a little
Media Center in there on everything
accessible by a touchscreen interface so
that we can for simplicity sake and like
I said media storage so there's a hard
drive in there for plenty of media
storage so decided maybe notice if we
had like some sort of security system so
that we know if somebody entered the
hotel room out even if it's just the
cleaning staff but you know we're
clearly we bring a lot of expensive
equipment with us we'd like to keep it
somewhat safe or at least notice or have
someone notify us if it is been stolen
and have any kind of events or things
triggered by the on the win by a
notification via email so other design
goals as far as physical construction
wanted everything to be able to look
easily accessible so we can get in
repair stuffs while comments if need be
ruggedness we wanted to put it in like a
big sturdy case so we want everything in
there to be fairly secure as well just
the case we don't want just the case of
survive you want the hardware engine
inside to survive as well upgradability
you know this was just kind of the first
phase of the project idea we had we want
to be able to expand it out add even
more gadgets and gizmos to the whole
thing and of course ease of use because
like I said the whole point in the
project is just to come in plug in
and go and have that be that so this is
what we came up with you can kind of see
the top-down picture there Joe so you
can kind of see we've got got the
touchscreen some storage for wires
storage for the camera over there a
power supply a bunch of other stuff Joe
and Joe will talk about this more in
detail we've got our own little mini
raspberry pi server rack right here with
a few extra spots for when we want to
add stuff how many pods are in there
just two right now and we have space
with three more space and power which I
think we've tested if we add all five
and we would have to put in a bigger
switch but should that shouldn't be too
big of a deal
so next up
yeah so going over some of the hardware
choices I would think first off we
basically have a big kind of multi port
USB charger I'm sure a lot of us have
these at home for $50 phones and devices
and stuff usually I got a couple of
bankers at home I found this one though
a particularly designed Adhan
specifically because it's got this
little elit LCD that shows you the power
draw on each port and we thought that
you know we've got a lot of stuff
plugged in that way beginning to have so
we went with that also the goal of this
was to have as much power on USB as
possible well both of us do a lot of
dabbling and electronics and building
stuff engineering power supplies is not
one of my strong suits or nor is it Bob
so we thought if we keep did a USB all
the way through for the first round that
would keep things nice and simple so
obviously there's also a couple of
raspberry PI's in there they're simple
cheap again USB powered we thought about
going with Pi fours but we weren't sure
that the power brick would give the
appropriate output to run the PI 4 at
full power so we stuck with PI threes
because for what we're using it for it's
good enough they'll run the media server
in a future upgrade we want to look at
upgrading to PI fours but that's gonna
be the next revision plus we are I
already had several of these citizen
around so that's saved on cost next up
is the display when we first looked at
this we looked at it was either this or
the official Raspberry Pi touchscreen
display and we were thinking about the
official PI display just because for
accessibility we were like alright
here's the piece you go get because we
want other people to be able to build
this but the more we looked at it this
device I found on Amazon has a higher
resolution as well is it being driven by
HDMI cables to the thin little ribbon
cable came into play with the
rugged ability I was worried about that
cable being damaged versus the SD HDMI
cable being a little more bright also
with the Raspberry Pi display that have
been shortened I mean you get longer
cables with those ribbon cables but
you're really kind of limited in length
so it would have really affected our
design placement where we wanted to
everything at all so this was cheaper at
$50 versus the other monitor with the
official PI displays about getting us
and what's wearing name on that I really
had a brand name then but you'll see at
the end I do have build materials of all
the parts we cope with Amazon everything
was purchased off in Amazon except the
acrylic and hardware I went to Lowe's
and so that will be posted online with
everything else the hard drive so
obviously since rugged ability we don't
want spinning rust in there we wanted an
SSD and the choice of SSD was pretty
simple I've got a good friend who is an
ax drug data recovery experts she also
recently gave a presentation at this
past year's Def Con in the hardware
hacking village so I said hey what's the
best SSD for my use case she said
Samsung t5 I said okay that's what we
want this I only went with 500 gigs
peasant's thought about going a full gig
or terabyte but I was like yeah how much
binge-watching can I really do in a
weekend especially when I'm supposed to
be out of the conference I probably
could still do quite a bit but I think
500 gigs is still going to be enough
it's just a trick that not all
we're going to go for again the official
Raspberry Pi camera model we thought
about we want to put a cup on a camera
to the surveillance system but again we
have the same ribbon cable issues with
screen also limited placement just like
with the screen so that meant we would
have all right do we attach it to
another PI like a PI zero then we're
adding additional PI's how do you
connect it can't do it over USB it's got
to be either Wi-Fi or suffer or hook up
that dongle it was it wasn't going to be
as simple solution so Bob found this
online and you know it's a megapixel
resolution it's got IR night mode and a
really long ago that's designed to be a
security camera and with the really long
cable we could like we weren't limited
by where the plugs were in the hotel
room we could hook it up and then move
the camera somewhere else kind of run
the cable a little bit and make sure
it's pointed at the door and then kind
of one of the more important pieces is
this network switch you gotta put these
PI's up together there's only so much on
the little travel router so this is a 10
100 megabit USB switch five port that
runs off a micro USB I mean I don't
think it's like full duplex but again
it's one of those hey it's good enough
things it's just it's super tiny and
something you could throw in your bag I
really like the idea of it so I do here
in one of my back but there's also kind
of perfect for this because again USB
powered we don't have to mess with any
designing any kind of power supply or
anything like that but if you do need
something faster there is actually
gigabit port on the router which we'll
get to in a minute meeting our own eye
not super exciting but I was coming I
was excited when I found this we went
back
fourth on GUI include remote for the
Media Center does that mean guys so I
are is it gonna hair to like try to
mimic the codes of the television in the
hotel room but then I found this one
when I was searching online it's yeah
it's meteor remote but it's basically
functions as a wireless keyboard
so it's 2.4 gigahertz over a little
Wi-Fi dongle which got rid of any IR
things they'd have to use the app and as
you can see on one side there's actually
a little mini chording keyboard with a
trackpad plus it's got like a gyroscopic
Mouse that you can turn on and off and
it's so all the media functions are just
going through the media keys on keyboard
like when you hit function f2 to hit
play and pause on your laptop so I was
really kind of tickled by that it was
like 80 bucks or something like that
it's pretty cheap and so it was a lot of
we were really excited to find it and
then the router this is really kind of
the heart and soul of the whole thing
it almost we've been kicking around this
idea in some form or fashion for years
every time basically every time we have
a trip and we pack all of our gear but
this thing to kind of almost tank the
project from the start because it's so
versatile anybody ever seen this I know
they're pretty popular now are getting
popularity it's from a GUI net model
number Gio ar7 5 0 s if you want to look
it up it is an open work based router
it's got three gigabit ports on it yeah
ac and under into one Wi-Fi 128
megabytes of RAM micro SD card so you
cannot load files and stuff onto it
again USB powered micro USB and I it's
kind of designed to be hackable like you
can open it up and you've got access to
the antennas so you can replace the
antennas I think there's even like like
a TTL connection over so you can
actually hook up and use a serial
connection they really wanted to be
tactical winning
made these little things and it's about
I was 80 bucks I think and so again it's
another essential even if you don't
build one of these just an essential
travel router really handy so this is
the whole bill of materials we actually
didn't put the fans in this version
we've thought about cooling fans and
this Ida it's gonna be open should have
plenty of airflow it didn't come out
quite as cheap as we want current
tallies about six hundred and
thirty-eight dollars we were a little
sticker shocked by that because it's you
know there's a bunch of them everything
every piece is under a hundred bucks
over life and this will be pretty
inexpensive no not so much but uh pay
for a fun project anyway anyway so just
kind of going over the the off-the-shelf
software there's a little bit of custom
stuff for this but a lot of its just
kind of plug-and-play parts we put
together the media centers the first one
it's just a standard kind of
off-the-shelf Coby install pulling media
off of the local driver you you have to
make sure that your media is transcoded
correctly to get hardware decoding on
the pie so that's kind of a little bit
of a pain you got to make sure it's
h.264 I think and then then it works
pretty well but if you're trying to
decode something the pie doesn't have
native support for it just kind of
chokes but it works well it works great
with the with the media remote we've got
an external port drilled into this so
it's really easy to plug in the HDMI
cable run it up to the TV and then
you've got your own little private media
center you're now
about you know whatever weird thing the
hotel has for you the router is talking
a little bit about this offer on this
Joe Joe touched on it this thing is
really slick you if you connect to it
directly it has a nice little user
interface in that sits in front of the
the default openwork interface and
handles stuff automatically like a VPN
client a VPN server both Open VPN a and
wire guard makes it easy to set it up in
repeater mode which if you've ever tried
to do that with with open work directly
is a huge pain that this just makes it
trivial and then has a convenient lead
to just boost you back into the default
open word interface if you want to do
something like set static DHCP or any
you know more advanced kind of stuff
like that
most probably most importantly it's
designed to handle splash pages when you
connect to guest Wi-Fi networks so when
we connect it to a hotel Wi-Fi it will
break it'll route that page through and
bring it up on whatever device you're
browsing on yeah some sub routers will
hijack the DNS and make those kind of
pass through captive portals impossible
this actually has a specific setting to
kind of allow those captive portal and a
DNS redirects through motion I don't
know does anyone here use motion before
the security camera system I have no
experience with it this thing is really
slick it's a very kind of Unix II
security camera tool it just does one
thing it watches a webcam you know a
bunch of configurable options to say you
know watch this type for this type of
motion and then do that and then all of
its other things are call out and do a
script so it's not trying to include all
the batteries and include all sorts of
other stuff it's just watch a webcam and
when you see something do some other
stuff and then it leaves it up to you to
what that other stuff is we have it set
up so that it stores all the videos
locally and cleans them out every
for hours and it also posts an alert to
our custom software so that we can send
email alerts and stuff like that but
again all motion is doing is just
calling that script so really kind of
great great handy little tool yes yeah
it's it's called motion it is a little
minute it is kind of hard to Google so
make sure it's like motion video
surveillance software or motion because
not even just the motion software then
you get like motion capture software
yeah I think most of the mimosa mimosa
Tori's but trying to try and when you're
trying to look it up to find the
documentation that's where it gets
tricky yeah it's right up there with
like looking up grow yes did you look at
some minor at all so minder actually
uses motion under the hood okay Wow and
yes I have his own minder setup at home
the goal here was we didn't we wanted
everything I'm going to talk about the
custom cell for the minute dependent go
through one user interface so I didn't
want to try to boot so minders interface
into something else so I'll talk a
little bit about the custom software if
there's actually not that much it's
probably like twenty five hundred lines
of code total so there's a front-end
react wrap app that's designed to be
touch friendly mobile friendly very
limited functionality you know we're not
trying to replicate everything you could
do by you know editing the motion config
or login into the router directly the
goal here was that you can open this
thing up and using that touch screen to
get your system online without getting
up your laptop to log into the router
and configuring a bunch of stuff the
back end it talks to a node server the
right node software that's my day job so
you know if you've got a hammer
everything looks like a nail
it proxies through to the router and the
camera feed so that everything goes
through kind of one server hand
authenticate to the server for you so it
just kind of makes all that transparent
proxies the camera feed what we'll see
that in the demo in a second then it's
it's just got a handful of utility
routes for like two checking if you're
on the internet controlling whether or
not you get alerts things like that so I
think I'm on time yeah so we're gonna
try to do this live prey to the demo
gods for us yeah so Joe's already set
this up and plugged it in it's already
powered up and this is what you get when
you power it in and it's a little hard
to see here but we've got some
screenshots so you get to the hotel you
power it up this is what you can see
you'd go ahead and hit the connection
tab there and we'd give you a list of
well you've hit the Scan button and a
little refresh in the bottom corner yep
so I've done that see here this is the
Status page where work comes up
initially thank you so we're gonna go
ahead and scan for Wi-Fi networks see
what's up I'm going to go ahead and
disconnect once the scan finishes from
the Clarion once so we can demo this we
had to set up earlier once you've
connected to a Wi-Fi network it's gonna
automatically reconnect this kind of as
you'd expect
so disconnect that
connects to Clarion Inn & Suites
and then of course it would pop up the
password problems if you needed a WPA
key or something like that which we
don't really have a great solution for
that yeah okay so you can see it's
connected but it doesn't actually
connect that we can get up to the
internet that assumes we're on a captive
portal so I'm gonna hit the open button
and it's going to open up
I think that's what we've still got
cashed the connection so even really
disconnected and reconnected the portal
anyway okay that's one thing that didn't
work but it's trying to open up a
captive portal doesn't seem to be able
it's not triggering it that's kind of
hit or miss if you've ever tried to use
the the captive portal detection of like
an iPhone or anything like that
it's spotty as to whether or not you can
actually detect when you're trying to be
forward into one so back to the status
screen you can see it's going to say
that we're connected now oh that's why I
left the VPN can I do so if the VPN is
connected it works with a kill switch so
it won't allow any traffic that's not on
the VPN so obviously that includes not
letting us out to the taptic portal so
I'm going to go ahead and turn that off
there's a screenshot of you can page
there's you just list the profiles you'd
have installed on there just flip them
on and off there we go we're connected
to the Internet now the VPN is not
connected but that's just a simple
toggle switch the security camera it's
pretty simple interface you can see
what's on the live view coming from the
camera we've got to sit here point at me
and as I'm moving around Bob's probably
getting tons of emails right now I have
the alerts turned off because I was
smart good job so you can see the live
view there you can go ahead and turn it
takes a little bit to catch up but
there's everyone there on the screen if
I now do enable alerts
we promise we won't close down here it
really just
and I waved my hand in front of the
camera oh I'm an evil person coming into
your room to do something yep this is
the part of that the presentation where
I check my email it takes a second or
two to come through so yeah we
eventually want to make it so that it'll
either text us as well and ideally we
want to figure out how to push out over
signal maybe okay once you go that's all
it takes to get it set up and then you
can kick back watch some movies in the
hotel room
and enjoy the rest of the conference
there's the if it's actually statement
still it tends to look real better as
opposed to yeah the so future goals for
the project right now all the software
in stuffs and configured by hand
we built the PI's by hand install the
software we'd like to get some setup
scripts because we are going to open so
push it out all of our software and
schematics for the components out to
github so anybody else can build this if
they want we also like to eventually
implement some software plugins we're
just trying to figure out how that would
look as far as I don't think neither of
us why don't do a whole lot develop at
all but Bob's never developed a plug-in
system before so he's trying to figure
that out if anybody wants to help by all
means we are actors so we'd like to put
in some like automated like network
scanning see if we can detect any like
cameras on on the network that may be
like in our rooms or anything like that
like you know this is full projects born
out of paranoia so we've toyed around
about building in a UPS and powered
speakers in case you know the speakers
on the TV kind of suck and you just want
to play some tunes thought about it like
a tamper alarm they either like an on
switch or a gyroscope so they have
somebody like picks it up and moves it
while it's running that uh you know
alarm with sound or send us a
notification part part of it as part of
the whole security system
I thought maybe in a group integrating a
some kind of smart assistant like
Mycroft or something so we could kind of
have our own kind of problem brew Alexa
in the hotel room just complete overkill
we thought about adding you know retro
game system I think Cody has some
emulators available for it that you can
install so you can play some video games
- one of the things the router has is
cellular failover if you had a block
cellular modem so you'd like to
implement that and you know if the Wi-Fi
drops out you can go ahead and
automatically failover to that SDR we're
both hands and radio geeks so we both
kind of want to put a SDR in there
either it was just like an RTL SDR just
kind of scanning and seeing what signals
it picks up be kind of fun just to have
it up Waterfalls played on the screen
involves doing that any other sensors we
can think of you know air quality or
stuff like that you know I've got a box
of components so whatever I can find
I'll probably just cram in there at some
point
final shutter server will probably just
do a quick that'll probably one of the
first things we do throw in a like an X
cloud server probably I connected the
kodi server so you can just easily
upload your media as
- uh I haven't removed the hard drive -
advisor much then he could share it
share it out over the anybody else
connect to the hotel room self-destruct
I mean who once who doesn't want a big
red button they can press in that case
no distance Wow
so again just have eventually we'd like
to you know do full disk encryption on
the PI's and then you know just have a
big red button that you hit that delete
the keys remove the systems and
everything scrambled and you're good to
go
iron masters kind of really dropped on
bribery since we've got pretty slick
Wi-Fi remote now but it'd still be nice
to turn on the TV the use case for that
would be if we're not using HDMI because
the PI's do have was that
ECE or whatever whatever the extended
protocol for HDMI to give some control
over the TV the PI's do have it and I
think Cody uses it but that might not
work in all situations so like I said
full disk encryption and then uh you
know I designed all the brackets and
mounts and stuff in here I'm
particularly proud of like the the
screen mount and the power brick mount I
wrote a project box generator and
openscad and used them both before that
and I think they came out pretty
slick-looking but some of the other
brackets and stuff in there could use
some tweaks I think we could rearrange
things a little bit better get things a
little lower profile and so I'd like to
work on that as well anyway this isn't
going to be the URL where we're going to
post this it github STL 2600 because Bob
and I both present our host of local
2600 in st. Louis Missouri at the arch
reactor hacker space all
all of the the software is up there now
you can check it out
it's mainly just the custom software and
some instructions on setting that up
we'll add all the the files and assembly
instructions kind of as we as we get
them from I've got I've got the document
I've written most of the documentation
for how to set everything up I've also
got all the models for the components if
you so you can print and laser cut them
yourself if you have means I intend to
post them this weekend I'm not going to
make that promise because I'm horrible
about that kind of stuff questions
hey do you intend to make a commercial
version of this in the future uh I don't
think so Bob and I are both I mean it's
all off the shelf of parts aside from
the practice of stuff we really didn't
design any electronics or anything I
don't know if there's anything really
Bob your pen guy is there anything
really patentable in this now I didn't
think so so uh yeah no and we're both
pretty big open-source guys we'd rather
have it open let people do it themselves
plus you saw the building materials the
cost is in and honestly ninety look like
they said 95% of the benefit and the
thing we made this for is in the router
like if you just want a nice easy secure
network you can take with you grab that
router and plug it in and it does most
of what you need we almost didn't build
this project because that router exists
yes
I would let you know I'm looking for
glass re yeah no we just finished this
this was an empty box yesterday morning
here is there is a 3d printer in our
hotel room this printing out mounts
we've been working on in a couple months
here's here's a here's an important tip
when you start a big project don't do it
when one of the team party members just
had a kid in both team members buy new
houses and move during the course of the
project that really paints a cramp on
your on your ability to work on projects
we should've gone to bed time management
talking for the airport you need a
little just one little speaker in there
that I tried to convince Bob that we
needed a big countdown clock I am
actually quite curious because last time
last time one was her airport I got a
pie top which didn't have a hard drive
through guess I must have checked it
previous buddy brought it up carry on to
Vegas this past year and it they they
put it through the x-ray five times only
by the fourth time I was like I will
disassemble this right here now for it
if you want to take a look inside it
like the panel just slides back it's
really easy well right now we're all
right and so yeah I'm really curious to
see how this goes through please
any other questions
yes so I carry ham radio equipment and
computer equipment through through
airport security all the time all I
would say is avoid airports in Texas
that's probably fair I used to travel
for business probably 15 years ago and
even with just a regular toolkit like
airport security
the TSA varies wildly from airport to
airport it like there's no consistency
some of them want to search it some of
them want to search it with you there
some of them don't care some of them
will take your empty butane soldering
iron but leave the butane in the
compressed canister like there's no
rhyme or reason for any of it so yeah
you know the more parts that you take
out and put separated bins and things
the better they feel about you yeah
that's true yes
thanks everybody if you want to