alright thanks for showing up I know
it's a kind of a different talking for
the others so how many you guys are
familiar with di Capri oculars everybody
a a lot of people probably familiar with
them from school they're very expensive
very overpriced devices that schools
require you to buy or use a math class
some people are probably also familiar
with the fact they're programmable that
you can make them do all sorts of things
with math assignments - taking notes for
science classes and then of course
you're playing games yeah but what
people outside the community might not
might not know is that they're a good
learning tools for getting into
programming and reverse engineering a
big chunk of what the community knows
about programming Africa alligators we
know because we figured it out ourselves
so we wrote code not knowing what was
gonna happen we run tests hardware
experiment with it so on so that's never
more applicable than with trying to
break the security that's built into
these things so my goal here is to
provide a personal and historical
overview of what the calculator
community is how it started two major
things that have happened in it where
we're at now hopefully we're going
starts out as kind of like an overview
but it gets really technical really
quickly
there's a lot of slides here so talking
fast but if you have a questions
so Who am I I'm just a guy with a lot of
calculators probably too many okay there
what got me started in the software
development industry and now security
industry these are not complete pictures
because I do have more than what you see
here but as far as I know it is the
world's largest collection of Texas
Instruments graphic calculators and
accessories by that I mean in terms of
variation there are one or two people
that have more of them just in terms of
sheer numbers but as as far as every
model this is everything that I have at
least one of every model that's ever
been married so that's every model from
all over the world every hardware vision
every color very separate one because
there's just so many different colors
every view screen or teachers edition
version every easy spot yellow school
version and a number of one-of-a-kind or
close to one kind of prototypes of
engineering so yeah I grew up with these
things they they gave me my career my
life so I love them and I want to make
sure that they can do absolutely
everything that they're capable of doing
and make sure that everybody else can do
because I'm not the only one they've
actually jump-started a lot of different
a lot of careers and knowledge about
low-level engineering
embedded devices software engineering
and hardware and software so my hope is
that I can share with you a little bit
of my journey with these devices how far
they've come and learn
this phaeton so what is a graphing
calculator well first and foremost its
calculator it's capable of doing
everything a scientific calculator can
do but it also has a large screen
capable graph equations for tracing tray
solutions along the graph or drawn
whatever you want it's got a two point
five millimeter i/o port or in some
cases USB so that you can share
variables and programs between two
calculators or you can connect it to a
computer share them with the
programmable which means you can create
programs like I said that we saw mad for
engineering problems do that using a
basic like language that TI invented
called ti-basic
it does have some very basic commands
for programming games like gather key
parts input and draw on the screen but
it's way too slow to really utilize the
hardware to its maximum potential so for
that we have assembly language and in
one form or another every model with the
exception of the ti-84 unning the
arbitrary neighbor code so some of them
have this capability built into them and
then some of them had to be hacked first
so if the models that came first with
dialogue models or C log I'm
appreciating pronounced it's a log but
I've always said C log so
but these use the zilog z80 processor
which is a very old processor that's
used in a number of devices or devices
in new devices because it's actually
pretty nice it's a very versatile chip
it's six megahertz or on some models
it's been sped up to 50 megahertz
it's an 8-bit CPU is 16-bit addressing
which means it can access a maximum of
64 kilobytes of memory at once and it
has an 8-bit IO port interface so you
can interact with the hardware by
outputting or inputting from one of up
to 206 logical ports and they have
anywhere from up to 32 kilobytes of RAM
while we have to the 128 kilobytes and
some of them the most interesting ones
have flash memory which ranges anywhere
from one megabyte all the way up to four
megabytes
now the first model capable of running
the native assembly programs was the tid
5 very old model that you don't see a
lot of these days rumor has it that TI
employees actually had a bet as to
whether we figure out a way to run
native assembly programs and that turns
out that was a safe bet because the
community did figure out a way and it
was through something called Z show to
explain on T show works to elaborate on
what on a particular feature that some
of these little models have and that's
to transfer backups via the chat graph
link ok exploit millimeter I ok that's
what connects them to the computer and
so these backups are actually just dumps
of the entire gram not just where
variables are stored but the system's
Ram as well and there's also the
calculator software system also supports
something called custom menu entry so
that's what that red arrows pointing to
with a custom button on the keyboard and
so you can add your most commonly used
OS commands in here and be able to
access the
and interested in the way the OS stores
things in this menu is by just keeping
track of the address of the code that
would handle this OS commanded to
selected my dear Anna and it keeps track
of this in system rank which is included
in that computer backup so what that
means is all you have to do is change
the address of one of these custom menu
entries to point to code that we also
embedded that ran back up and execution
and that's what Z shows it's just a
small program that lets you run other
programs so that secret right since you
can even write programs to store them on
the calculator in the form of string
ridiculous
then the tid too came along and it also
had to be hacked in order to enable
executing native assembly code
unfortunately though it has no custom
menu so another method had to be found
but it does have memory backups so we
start taking a look at other things that
are stored in the system Ram
now that the opera system on the
governor is essentially just a series of
water called contexts we're just kind of
like built-in applications things like
the home screen the equation editors the
graph screen things like that in each
context is a table of addresses that
point to handlers for different things
like what happens when you press the key
and the key press handler is the most
important one it's called the CX main
handler and whenever you switch to so
whenever you switch to a new context
these handler addresses gets stored in
the consistent Ram so our goal is to
find a way at runtime to override that's
the X main Handler and that's done by
another piece of functionality that is
storing values to variables like real
variables mathematically real Erebus
complex variables those are stored in
RAM as 9 bytes and then when you copy
from one variable to another those 9
bytes are just copied from the source
variable to wherever the data for second
parallelism so if we modify one variable
like X with the bytes that we want if we
modify it with the address of code that
we have bed in that memory back up and
then modify the location of a second
real variable like why it's a point to
see X main instead of the actual data
for that
the Macan overwrites the x-men by just
storing X to Y so just over rice just
copies 9 bytes from one place to another
so once you do that CX mains overridden
and then the next time you press a key
you got Cobra so that gives us a shell
we wish to run other programs just like
you see show link came along the ti-83
it's at this model actually has backdoor
in it the T I put there which allows
directly running assembly programs that
are stored in RAM and that backdoor is
hidden in the send command which is
normally used for transferring variables
from one calculator to another using
that to my report but if you put a nine
right after the command
they won't transfer the variable at all
instead execute it as the over native
code so the th piece the first
calculator I ever had so this is right
around the time that I and then when T I
saw that there was a big booming
interest in assembly programming through
this backdoor they decided to add really
nice assembly support to the taking 6
which is a new and improved 5 and that
calculator has a brand new command ASM
which is intended for running assembly
programs right from the beginning so
they not only provided some basic
documentation for how they used system
RAM and how you sir Ram is laid out they
even included OS hooks so we can
integrate with the OS and expand its
functionality which is really and then
came Flash technology so these to me are
the most interesting models because they
are upgradeable in terms of OS upgrades
flash applications which have tighter OS
integration and they're stored in
Flash's the RAM USB ports and security
application implementations to protect
some of that and whenever something's
designed to keep you from doing it
so just the note in Europe they make
these model numbers really confusing it
makes it really difficult to collect
them so first they made the teddy 3 then
they may be taking Plus and then they
may get 84 plus so there was never
actually a plain old ta before they just
went straight to the plus so that would
lead you to believe that because there's
no plus in the name might not have flash
memory but actually just doesn't exist
and then then they made a model call the
Katy for Pocket FR which is just a
physically smaller 284 plus so it is a
plus but they didn't put plus in the
name it's otherwise identical in every
way and then they may be to give you
four plus pocket SC which is just a
physically smaller ta four plus Silver
Edition except they did put plus in the
name so it's just then there were all
sorts of duplicates so the exact same
calculators so doesn't spread they just
left a different name on it so like the
tape do stats and TT stands afar
my apartments France by the way they're
really just EIU threes then you have a
given T plus thought fr which actually
could be referring to two different
calculators they use the exact same name
of your binoculars one is it just--it 80
plus and then the other is t4 plus
Silver Edition then there's a taking two
plus which is just an 83 plus exact same
thing they just put two minus two or
three and then the ti-83 premium see he
which is exactly the same as T plus C
and then they made it a 4 plus T stands
for test but that's actually just t4
plus Silver Edition so it's just and
they're still really just release two
more
so while the z80 models are by far my
favorite we're on the most knowledgeable
there are of course others such as the
Motorola 6800 models at least starting
with decoding TI 92 which came out
around the same time isn't e85 and it
has a QWERTY keyboard which is which is
cool but unfortunately like I said
banned on most standardized tests
because it's technically considered a
computer desk one thing that's unique
about this model is that had actually
had an expansion port on the back of it
which would let you add features or even
turn it into an entirely different model
so these models are really rare because
there's the TI 9 T 2 module 1092 2
module and there's the TI 9 to me module
II for Europe and that just adds more
RAM language options to it and then
there's the TI 92 plus module which is
by far the most interesting one it's
equally as rare though it turns to TI 92
well it turns a TI 92 into a 10 92 Plus
which gives it flash memory and upgrade
ability and that model is basically the
same as the TI 89 which is that black
except the TI 89 doesn't have a great
keyboard and then the TI on titanium
next to it in grey which has some minor
hardware changes and it adds a USB port
to it which is really useful then
there's the ti-nspire models which are
ARM based I really hate these
calculators because they're really big a
volume and they're not really useful
they're more educational tools and are
really practical devices but they do
have swappable keyboards and probably
the most significant one is the TI 84
plus keypad as a most significant keypad
which if you snap that into it causes it
to emulate the TI 84 plus which makes it
kind of sort of useful again and then
there are versions that that don't have
a cast and then versions that do cast
means computer out for system
[Music]
then they have the ti-nspire CX models
again both the cast and Anan cast
version those have color LCDs and
they're redesigned to be a little bit
sleeker but they're another big reason I
think these is that they're completely
100% locked down unlike all the others
until you understand lockdown no way to
execute native code at all unless you
jailbreak it for lack of a better term
there's something called endless it's
kind of like the Z show that lets you
read it real Abel's unsigned code
execution on for some reason ci fights
this really hard they try to fix
vulnerabilities that uses as soon as
they can weigh more than the autumn of
other models which is why they why did
we focus on the worst ones I don't know
and then finally we have the EZ eight
models these are the newest models that
have color LCDs you go to Walmart this
is what you see unlike the z80 models
these have what's called an easy a TV
for enhanced I guess nobody really knows
this is CTU supports a 24-bit addressing
and it has backward compatibility with
the basic and the hardware interface
that's inside of the calculators
completely new
it's totally redesigned with security in
mind so unlike the z80 models which have
like a paging or bank switching system
the easy idea models have a flat memory
model which change the security based on
that
the TA through premium Cee hardware-wise
is identical to this model but it has a
different OS on it which includes an
exact math engine that's only sold in
Europe
so one thing TI really wants to prevent
is being able to run that nicer OS on
the US ta for plus C but there and then
the then there's RT 84 + c e - t team
for test which is the european version
of the plus C it's actually got a
testing led on and then playing steering
the tests you know that's like a special
testing mode where you can access
documents or notes or anything so you
can't cheat so take a good look at your
desk
so having said all that there are some
really cool things you can do with these
to have absolutely nothing to do with
calculators nothing to do with math or
school or even games since some of these
models have worked on the go USB ports
it's possible to connect any number of
years before it rolls to it so instead
of plugging in the computer you can also
plug of the devices into it so anything
from Bluetooth or Wi-Fi adapters so the
cop goes can communicate wirelessly with
each other serial adapters - keyboards
and mice even using flash drives hard
drives floppy drives all that actually
exists except for the Wi-Fi one but the
others do exist and they have a these
hapless have a great unique on the go
USB controller USB controller one that's
really flexible and allows you to do
things that really should not be able to
do real or pieces of DSP protocol and
the best example of that would be the
PlayStation 3 jailbreak which they might
remember
that happened shortly after our OS was
taken away long story short there was a
USB based exploit that required
connecting a teensy or similar device
like that to your ps3 to enable unsigned
code execution but when it came out of
course teens is all over the world sold
out and we're back order nobody could
get them so they needed some other way
to trigger the exploit so I looked into
how it works and realized that it's
basically it's basically simulating a
USB hub and it's virtually attaching and
detaching devices in a very particular
order to trigger a memory corruption
exploit and the way that it does that is
the USB peripheral like the teensy has
to be able to pretend to be other USB
devices temporarily by changing its own
address in software so that it can
pretend to be these virtual devices that
it claims are being attached and
detached and that is something that the
calculators are able to do so I
implemented it and like two days after
that came out people were able to
jailbreak the ps3 using these
calculators and then of course you know
you can also simulate other devices
other USB devices as well such as wispy
keyboards mice Skylanders Portola Disney
infinity portal I have included a
calculator or a computer off off these
doctors might put it by having they tend
to be using a flash drive for the blue
Amazon and then of course yeah so why
have security in calculators well with
flash memory first came into the car to
the world see I actually sold plastic
applications for $7 and $15 a piece in
their online store and these would range
anywhere from pocket organizer
applications to spreadsheet applications
to figure out table applications to you
know everything to enhancing the
built-in math capabilities they even
release games and they would provide an
SDK for free so that you could make your
own but then they would charge $99 for
the right to release three applications
in their online store or for free so
they turn $9 fee so you could make three
free applications and naturally they
wouldn't want these applications to be
pirated so they had to restrict how and
where these applications
install and then of course they also
learned prevent cheating in the
classroom so you can have students
accessing notes or they type to enter
programs that would solve you know the
problems for them during tests so they
had to they one of the Condors to have
like I mention before I have some kind
of restricted mode for the duration of
that test so by the can look at notes or
view programs they wrote or just type
notes into it and then they wanted to
prevent tampering of the operating
systems so we could because if we could
modify that system then we could just
easily patch these in fact I'm convinced
I'm convinced we can actually make a
better OS than them in terms of
capability performance so it's not
really the TI wants to enforce all these
protections they really amounts to
pressure from educators and schools
teachers types of people like that so
they're forced to create an ty
achievement applications like something
called test guard which you can connect
to another calculator remotely delete or
disable programs applications and they
have something called Presta tests which
is a feature in the OS where you can
hold down the key combination and it
puts it in that restricted mode and you
can't get out of it and so you transfer
another variable to it so if you're in
the classroom they could just come by
press those keys and then get run games
you can't do anything unless you get
back till you get back home
which that doesn't keep anybody else
we're doing the same thing so somebody
really hate you they just welcome to
your calculator press those keys now so
I really don't like that feature and
then there's the this is the user
community this that's another key player
in this that that wants to be able to
maintain control over this so if this
really overpriced hardware that we may
be forced to buy so this couch does
countless numbers of things we can make
them do which not only help the kana
community but so now that we know a
little bit about who those players are
start getting into the technical parts
how these work how the security is in
them and how can have will continue to
so at a hardware level the z80 models
really consist of three things you have
the async which is the flash tube and
then all the other hardware that basic
interacts with such as the LCD display
must be boards the i/o boards the
keyboard and all that this is not a
percent accurate because the hardware is
changed over the decades
for example the RAM wasn't always
internal to the async and either the
ASIC by the way is the chip that's all
the subtlety that was singular Schiavone
so the RAM wasn't always in there and
either most the CPU but this is the most
component the most common configuration
that you come across so as I mentioned
the z80 is a six megahertz CPU 16 bit of
dressing can only access 64 kilobytes
memory at a time so since the OS is much
larger than that they have to utilize
something called Bank switching which is
where that's 64 kilobytes split
logically into 4 16 kilobyte pages or
banks and each of those banks can hold
any 16 kilobyte region of memory that
you want so if you what you want access
is the curly swapped into one of those
four banks you just reconfigure that
Bank so that it points to the
two kilobytes which one and then you
access it by accessing the memory
address for that bank as far as
accessing the hardware the znd has 8-bit
IO aggressing so there's a maximum
attune Orca to six IO ports that it can
talk to and the purpose of each i/o port
is different for each model but the
flash models all follow the same basic
pattern which is everything from 0 all
the way up support AF they do everything
from AC configuration LCD access
keyboard input USB control everything so
there are a few rules about how the Bank
switching works in 82 plus in 84 plus
series like I said is split up into four
banks 16 kilobytes each starting at
address zero four thousand eight
thousand and sees the first Bank except
there's some weirdness during the cold
boot it always has wrong page zero which
is the start of the OS and the second
Bank is constantly being used to swap in
different chunks of the OS which is way
bigger than support otherwise I'm
constantly swapping and what it needs
when it needs it and then the third and
the fourth banks typically have grandpa
just swapped in meaning there's usually
32 kilobytes of RAM accessible to the OS
at any given time some of that is
usually a m-- and some of that is the
hardware stack and then the rest of the
system ran with us can use internally
and as you can see the last big banks
all have IO ports that control of those
the last two banks on IO ports that
control what pages swap them so if you
want to swap rompe one into the second
bank you just write a 1 into IO 46
that's the second box or if you want to
swap rampage 81 into the third bank you
write 81 to IO 4 7 so now the most
important i/o port in the entire ASIC is
which controls flash unlocking and
relocking so whenever the flash chip is
blocked which is almost always the case
right in a race commands to the flash
chip are ignored
so essentially you can't modify flash
and save a market
and the only code that kind of mock it
is the flash so I can only modify itself
so it also controls whether certain I of
work that I used to be modified so we
court is like that we call that a
privileged i/o for it because / it's
going to be a lot before you can write
to it so it doesn't always deal with
class that's just what it's come to be
known by and the way it works is very
simple you just write a one to unlock it
or a zero to lock it back what's not
simple though is that you can only write
to that port in certain circumstances
there's a special sequence of z80
instructions which are this five there
there's a certain sequence of
instructions that say like I am one and
Row 1 and D I disable interrupts that
has to be run in order for a right step
or stick and those instructions
explicitly prevent interrupts from
running and interfering with this
process it can't steal control of
Saturday the privileged paid ranges are
mentioned there but as you can see the
only pages that are allowed to modify
clash are the flash which is the OS so
you can't modify the eyes unless you are
yes special sequence is just required to
make it work or is enforced to prevent
it's required it's required to make it
work if you don't have not not I'm on di
if you just if you just simply you know
put one and a and then right now you
have a go for 14 nothing happens it gets
ignored so rights to that port are
ignored unless that it's preceded by
those instruction so there's some
hardware that's looking at what
instructions are going on exactly
yeah there's hardware that actually
looks to see to make sure those
instructions are fetched from a
privileged page otherwise the rights my
custody
so to give an example of with howhow TI
uses this protection there's logic
behind receiving here's the logic for
receiving and installing an OS upgrade
so in a loop the boot code will one
receive a chunk of the OS data and where
should be written to you on the flash
chip to unlock flash using that
privilege sequence and then writing the
one to port 14 and then it checks for a
whole bunch of tricks that we might use
to still control away while that's
unlocked and then three it writes the OS
data to the specified area of the
question and then finally for a real aux
flashback using the same privilege
sequence as poor writing a 0 to lock it
back so anytime do is does something
involving modifying flash it will unlock
it performs some simple operation as
quickly as it can in the relocker
flashback it's a try to minimize so as I
mentioned the checks for trickery
specifically it checks one checks to
make sure that the SP the stack pointer
lies between C 0 0 and F F of H so
that's the last Bank and it does this to
make sure as B's pointing somewhere in
that last bank somewhere in RAM so that
when it returns back to the caller it
gets what it assumes would be a valid
return address from the stack C one make
sure you can't mess with that too it
checks to make sure or 6 contains a
privileged faster flash page because
that's where any flash 1 locking code
would be running from 3 it checks for 7
to make sure it contains rampage 1 or
system Ram mess and what the OS would
consider the normal running operating
scenario and then for and compliments to
fights at 8000 and Caesar 0 which
confirms that the third and fourth banks
contain writable rampages so in addition
to this there is Harper checks so why
would t I care if we point SP or the
stack pointer to an area of flash well
let's try it and play it out
for starters modifying flash is
complicated it's not as simple as
loading a register value to a memory
address it requires a sequence of memory
management
commands like get chip ID or a sector
program bike things like that so if we
point to speak to a location that's
definitely in ROM such as 1000 which is
in the first bank it's deep and on page
0 first bank and then we jump into some
code that unlocks flash and calls some
sort of sub routine something
interesting lat
the call instruction is gonna attempt to
write the return address to the location
pointed to by a speaker but because s
B's pointing to wrong like if this
screenshots as punch of 80 bytes those
rights are going to be ignored as it's
not following the sequence of
instructions the flash tip instructions
in the exam so when it in violent when
that subroutine finally encounters a
return instruction will do what the
return instruction always does it reads
the first two bytes pointed to by SP
which is 80 and 80 and it'll jump there
so that means no jump to address 8080
not at all what the code intend to do
but because we messed with SP it's
exactly what happens so this would be a
really cool way to still control away
from the OS and the boot code but they
did think of that that was the point of
that check so what do we try next well
this is where the harbor is interesting
we learned through experimentation that
the privileged sequence of instructions
only needs to be read from the
privileged page it doesn't necessarily
have to be executed from that page so
that requires thinking about what
actually happens on the day of us when
instructions are actually being executed
by the processor so when it goes to
execute the RLC which is rotate left
with carry instructions the first yell
over it first has to read the bytes or
the op codes that make up that
instructions that's how it decodes that
is our OC and because it uses index
register IX that's a four byte
instruction and z80 so it reads d DC v
zero zero zero from that privileged page
and then it has to actually execute that
instruction and to do that it has to
read the third bite at IX at offset zero
that's the Eenie byte from the filter
space so there's an awful lot that goes
on just in that one instruction then it
goes to execute the load HL into D
instruction is the second Galdo
instruction which means it has to read
that off code so that's 56 from the
purpose page and then it actually
executes it which means it has to read a
3 by 2 from the printers page so the z80
equivalent of all those instructions all
those bytes is not that I wanna be
which is the unlock sequence so if you
proceed the output support 14 with all
that and set up some memory just set up
IX and I'll set up some memory correctly
so that those mites will be fetched then
at work and the big advantage here is
that none of those instructions actually
disable interrupts they don't set any
remote one which means that after it
runs we could steal control away from
that code or allow other things to run
it could have a nurbs run so all we have
to do is find the instructions in yellow
on our privilege page somewhere
unfortunately though they're not
anywhere
and so as awesome as this is we can see
but it's useful if we make our own OS
because now we can along flash and write
to it without having to disable
interrupts that's something I can't do
since we don't care about the security
we can so
well then comes along the ti-83 plus
Silver Edition which is an enhanced
version of a ti-83 plus it has 128
kilobytes rooms that are just 32
kilobytes it's got a flash chip twice as
large and it's CPU as capable switching
between six megazor megahertz and 50
megahertz so it's actually fine faster
at certain times it takes it got a few
upgrades as well namely IO port five
that's a new i/o port and this i/o for
it actually allows controlling the
rampage has swapped into the last week
forth something that you couldn't do on
yours Mayan plus the thing is though see
I didn't actually update their trickery
checks to validate that the value of
four five makes sense so this can be
used to our advantage
so the OS always expects rampage one to
be in the third bank and it always specs
expects rampage zero to be in the fourth
map but what happens if we swap the
rampage into the last two mates so both
of them have the same rampage well now
things are all kinds of screwed up
even though SP the stack pointer which
has to point in the last Bank even
though it's pointing there the stack is
not there anymore so now we have the
same page swapped into two banks at the
same time so if I were to write a value
to the first byte of the third bank
first drive diabetic box I would
actually be able to read that same byte
from the first byte of the fourth
second redbones so that's definitely
very interesting so what we need to do
is we need to find a section of the OS
or the boot code that unlocks flash
writes a value into the third bank which
is for system Ramos and then attempts to
relock flashback and as luck would have
it there is a very convenient block of
code that does that there is a
particular bit and in fact an entire
fight of the certificate region of flash
that holds whether the OS is valid or
not if it's valid as it usually is
because you're running code on it the
value will be zero so what we can do is
jump directly into the boot code at the
point that it unlocks flash just before
it reads this bike from the certificate
it will read it and it will store it to
an area system Ram called op1 which is
in the third bank and it's that address
84-78 so since we've just used i/o port
five to swap Rampage one into both of
the last two banks writing a zero to
84-78 will also write as area c 478
which is exactly 16 kilobytes ahead in
the fourth bank so if we can craft
things just right we can set the stack
pointer SP so that by the time it gets
to that right to 84-78 SP will be
pointing to say 478 so it will corrupt
itself so when it performs that right
it'll corrupt the return address the
espys pointing to so if the return
address used to be 40 61 writing that
zero will change it to zero zero so as
soon as the code hits the return
instruction it's gonna it's not gonna
return to the boot code it's gonna
return to zero zero you wanted a which
is deep in the OS NRO's
name wrong babe zero and we can use an
OS cursor up at that point there's still
control away from it clean up the stack
or store the value of horn five back to
what it originally was and we still have
question so great for us to use so
that's great but this four five trick
very only works on the apt plus Silver
Edition and up not the original and even
worse we had to use an OS hook to steal
control back made hard code the value of
sv based on the call stack for that
particular OS version Emma had to hard
code a return address that starts at
zero all of which could change from OS
version to OS version so we could be
able to version so what would be really
nice as if we had something that worked
on every more every OS version every
boot code version every hardware
Fishman's to do that you're gonna have
to attack functionality that not only
exist on all models but isn't likely or
you're even able to be changed easily
one such feature is the OSS ability to
receive flash applications from a
connected computer or have the copper
cooler since flash applications are
fixed to multiples of 16 kilobytes in
size even the smallest flash application
can't fit in RAM all at once so that
means the OS has to in the loom receive
a chunk of flash data on long flash
write that to an arbitrary location of
large arbitrary is important and then
relock flash back over and over again
total all the application of the she'd
written the flash now that functionality
has existed in every OS version for
every model since the beginning and they
can't take it out so if it's possible
that would be the perfect name to attack
before something to do as could unlock
splash writes data to an arbitrary
destination we know we have to you know
we have control over the destination
flash page and address the number of
lights to write and device to be written
but we don't have control over is the
source address which is a gram
that means this seven of eight in C 80
there's register pairs HL is a 16-bit
address so H would be the height like
so v 7 of 8 will always be set because
it has to be in RAM and it one of
register iy plus 25 for main reset so we
could set it as in this code the code
that will the wraps de around from 8000
back to 4,000 won't run and then this
routine this routine will write data to
address above 8000 which is all RAM so
it effectively would turn this command
into a Rams Ram copy instead of a
blaster
that's actually a good thing because we
can use this to overwrite the data near
SP SEC corner to all the same values
such as 8080 like in that screenshot
before so when this routine hits a
return instruction they'll jump to 8080
instead we can take control
clean up the stack and return the splash
zone so how do we ensure bit one of our
levels 25 is set even when this routine
will start out by resetting it use
something very similar to 4.0 why - 25 -
a one can flash for a bit one is set
then the boot codes attempt to reset it
with a simple reset bit instructions the
instruction won't work because it's it's
annoying so that simple remember
modifying flash involves memory magic
commands to program a single byte at a
time so these sydney's set and reset
instructions aren't gonna do anything
so if data that's wrong so we can force
it to effectively ignore the effect of
executing that instruction so that's
entirely dependent on the fact that they
never set Iowa after Flash's online they
say once when the OS starts and never
touch it again so it's fixed easily
enough in the OS if they would just set
it again right before this code runs but
similar functionality exists in the boot
code and that can't be easily fixed so
they're not having systems you can't and
if they diffic sit there are a number of
flash other flash on lock exploits that
can be used and there's a dozen of them
I've never disclosed so they ever decide
to start getting aggressive with this
being able to unlock flash and modify it
ourselves nice but if we wanted to write
our own OS we have to rely on custom OS
receivers which are platform dependent
error-prone and just trouble so the best
way it would be nice if we could just
pass the OS and have re-sign in
ourselves or write our own OS and sign
it it's T is private RSA key but of
course they're gonna have to Sam that
key over to us flash upgradeable ZD
model started out around the time that
the TI seventy-three came out
that was around 1997 in 1997 512-bit of
RSA keys were looking pretty secure and
if you don't know are as they strength
isn't the inability to factor the public
key which is an extremely large number
it's a two prime numbers and computer
power competing power not being what it
is today that was considered to possible
way back to night time to seven but last
word ten years or so and one person
decided to give it a shot anyway on his
computer they used something called the
GFS Jennifer Jennifer field sieve which
at least at the time and maybe still is
was considered the most efficient known
method of factoring numbers into primes
so he kicked off the process for the 83
plus OS signing team I'd let it run on
his computer for about two months before
it finally spit out the primes so he had
actually proven what was long
disregarded that it actually was
possible to factor those keys after
enough time passed so we posted about it
online and very shortly after TI
silenced him
they actually actually sent someone to
his home to talk to him strongly
encouraged him not to work on the same
wall or talk about it which is you can
imagine scared the crap out of them but
the damage was done and the community
knew it was possible so we took the
remaining 13 public keys we started a
distributed computing project to factor
the rest of it so we had hundreds
thousands of people all open to factor
the keys as quickly as possible before
we knew it we had all thirteen keys just
either month all under the nose without
them fun you know since nobody had ever
had the OS Keys before or even
application keys on other models there
were no tools to sign modified OS sister
applications so I made some validated
that every key was correct and could
produce the west's and flash
applications that each calculator would
accept which I could do because I had
all the characters and then publish
those tools along with the key files
needed to use and that seemed to be the
final straw and there's security for
these things because well it's the final
straw for Ti because they actually sent
me a DMCA takedown notice
which you don't know the MSA stands for
digital millenium Copyright Act versus
the basic estates behind you if you feel
your copy rights being violated you can
send a takedown notice to the offender
and then that person says four hours to
remove the offending material and if
they don't they have a right to sue the
person
so we're it not for the e FF which is
the Electronic Frontier Foundation
stepping in offering to defend me
legally against TI's threats I woulda
been forced to comply with that but the
EFS sent a letter to Texas Instruments
stating that you can't copyright a
number which is essentially published
and they should along because it's not
worth destroying a person over just
calculators see I did not respond to
that letter so matters dropped and I'm
still hosting all fifteen bucks over the
keys to this day knowing that they had
lost this particular battle see I
started using impossible to factor
2048-bit RSA keys in newly manufactured
models at the table plus silver issue
and since the hardware was never
designed to validate such a large
signature it's actually invalidating the
OSI being transferred knew of an Oso
great now takes six minutes where before
was instantaneous now you have to wait
around six minutes for it to calculate
this so that's just accepted so we're
gonna fall back on the flash Lamacq
exploits to get rid of that six minute
validation we have to understand how the
calculator moves and how OS upgrades
work when you first turn the that
are on the boot codes the very first
thing that gets controlled so it does
some basic hardware initialization and
then it checks the OS valid marker just
one sector zero with the flash to a bar
and if that marker is valid it jumps
into the OS and the coder starts
normally if the markers not valid then
it waits to receive a new valid OS or
link boards and for a typical OS
transfer the first thing the blue code
will do is it will invalidate the OS
quotes in the certificate and by erasing
flush lectures or reset the OS valid and
then a balloon keeps receiving small
chunks of the OS over and over into ram
and then unlocking flash writing back to
its destination at the relocking
flashback once that's all done it's time
for the boot code to validate to five to
a bit signature in the OS which is
effectively useless now because
speaking generate that signature
ourselves but then he goes to validate a
2048-bit signature if all those checks
pass that marks the OS is valid
intersections ero and certificate man
jumps into it so digging in a little
further we look at how the Ballet's this
2048 mid signature unlike the original
phytolith signature this new one is
stored linked indexed so that means
there's a word at the beginning
indicating that is 206 why it's a big
that's how big if you but if you know if
you know this things 24 a bit or
eternities explains why are you storing
the length it opens up the possibility
that it could be exploited as it turns
out yes you can they don't they don't
bounce check this thing so we can take
advantage of that we can embed a really
really large signature into the OSLC and
because the boot code doesn't check that
it's the same value it will blindly copy
the signature to the start of RAM at
8,000 so we can store 80 bytes of
garbage there then is the 80 jump
instruction which is all come c3 and
then the address and then to put lots
and lots and lots and lots and lots of
80s that eventually will totally
overwrite ran including the stack so the
next time the code tries to return it
it'll jump to address 8080 where we have
is a jump instruction that'll jump to
where we calculated our payload will
actually be at so then we get execution
so once we get control we can do some
cleanup such as marking the OS valid and
the certificate ourselves but they're in
the flash sector because we flash don't
launch so we can modify it ourselves and
then just jump into the start of the O's
the nice thing about this is that no
custom OS transfer tools are required we
just create a specially crafted OS
update file with this big signature and
this exploits the read-only boot code so
all in all models manufactured up to
that date are vulnerable so any question
yeah why does the number 80 80 keep
appearing that's just my favorite number
it's okay that's thing number repeated
8080 is very near the beginning of
system Ram which is kind of a scratch
space in the OS and the leuco
so just a convenience so it actually
gets better so another big discovery in
the community and another nail in the
coffin in the security of this has to do
with modifying what should be read on
the boot sectors one thing I noticed is
that you have the ti-84 plus a need for
plus supper addition loop sectors are
almost identical in fact other than the
fact that the first one has a one
megabyte flesh tip and the other one has
a two megabyte question they are
identical calculators every way except
for one little I or I in the loop code
so when the caterpillars first booting
and initializing hardware and IO it
writes either a 0 or 1 - I owe 421 this
is a protected port which means flash
has to be unlocked before it can be
written to and by the way you see the
unlock sequence after these right before
the port 21 22 23 rights you don't have
to have that I don't think that even
they understand why how it works
the - you have to have it's only 414
yeah they actually have macros that but
both copters run exactly the same OS so
the OS actually reads the value for 21
bit 0 for 21 to determine which model
that's running on so they can have the
exact same OS run on both calculators
and it's just intelligent about which
one it's running on so it's critical
that it notice because the OS is
actually organized into two halves two
sections so here's the flash layout
fancy 84 plus not the silver additions
is just the regulator for plus the
smaller it has 40 hex splash pages the
first OS sections at the very beginning
of the flash chip at sector 0 that's the
yellow area runs from flashback 0 to
flash page 8 and then near the end of
the flash chip and greet is the second
part of us these are the privileged
pages and that's why it has to split up
into two the green part has got the
privileged code
so both the upper o s range which is
ingrained within the book page read or
privileged but the booth page is
supposedly read only and then in between
the two other sections that Brown area
is the user archived events where flash
applications archive area better support
so the here is the flashlight opportune
for plus Silver Edition which is twice
as big basically the same except the
silver editions got twice flashed by
something the boot page is now 7f
instead of three it's higher and then
the upper OS page range is 7 c m7 d
instead of 3 c the boot code initially
sets the value of io 421 indicating
which model it is what would happen if
we unlocked flash and we modify it
ourselves
so 14 84 plus Silver Edition went to 0-2
421 and the OS would believe it's
actually a TV 4 plus nan so Perdition
and vice versa by the way the reason I
thought about doing this is I thought
I'd be willing to make a virus that
could run on somebody still radition and
it would cut the flesh size in half and
they no matter how much they reset the
ocular reset the OS or whatever it
wouldn't it wouldn't it wouldn't fix
itself so they that's what started
normally this would just after writing
the wrong value normally this would just
crash the calculator because suddenly
it's looking at page 3 seen for example
when it really wants to look at 7c
advice person but I had an idea that I
could just witness virus words as I've
had an idea I would just copy the upper
OS pages and the boot page so the green
and red boxes to the middle of the flash
chip ranges 3 C 2 3 F so that when you
modify that port in the OS actually goes
to look for the OS data pretty see it
would actually find it and it would
contain functional the thing is though
instead of the dark orange area in the
middle it would only consider that first
dark orange boxes news archive so that
would affect the cut it in half so
that's that's what that was the thought
it would cut in that brown area in half
but when I tried to do this by changing
port 21 and copying pages 7 see there's
7f 2 3 cm 3 of the coffee operation will
work it turns out there's an excellent
when I changed it by a port 21 I
actually changed which page which range
of pages was read-only so I changed
which region was red so by changing the
value for 21 I actually changed the
protection from one region to another so
all this time we thought the flash chip
was edit locked on the booth babes it
was the hardware was controlling it but
notice this the ASIC it's just port 21
on the a stick that's keeping it at
large so by temporarily flipping the
value of course when we can actually
modify the boot code and then there's
anything I've said making it possible or
about a good code and modify it we did
we put diagnostic utilities in there we
admitted them in the book page so that
it was impossible to permanently break
it and most importantly we just patch
out the 2048 bit signature check so
naturally when they figured out you can
do this they changed the way the
congressman factory they now edit lock
the boot sector onto flash tip and
hardware so the basic protections
actually redundant so it's Hardware
doesn't have that a see the ASIC does it
and the hardware doesn't look that hard
what matters here's the really fun part
shortly after tea I came up with their
first and only z80 calculator to have a
color LCD not only did it have a color
LCD but it had a four megabyte flash tip
instead of a two megabyte flash chip and
they call it the ti-84 plus C Silver
Edition C for color
the only difference that's the only
difference between that in the other
models they even used exactly the same
AC even though it wasn't designed to
work with a flash chip that was larger
than two Meg guys the problem isn't the
for Megan Wi-Fi chip has a different
sector layout compared to the one
megabyte
2 megabyte watch juice so the supposedly
read-only pages at the end of the 2
megabyte flash chip are now in the
middle of the 4 megabyte flash chip
which is now part of the new calculators
use archives they need to modify that
but their ASIC is designed to protect
against that so what did they do they
use the word around they temporarily
talk about which region is protected
because they can't just turn it off all
they can do is misconfigure in a
different way do their rights and then
toggle it back so to think it the idea
from us so the constant toggling a 421
actually slows the calculator down to
the
the performance really isn't that great
so they actually ditched that model
don't know by this yourself and the
distant in favor of the ti-84 plus CE II
which is a brand-new color calculator
with a different easy a DCP now the EC
eighty sports Society backers
credibility so that you could run
regular LZ instructions in addition to
the new easy any ones which support
24-bit addressing and a 16-bit higher
range they just make marriage this they
have twenty four bit of dressing now
they ditched the Beijing and Bank
switching madness in favor of a flat
memory model like lazy down here they
also revamp the port protection since
there are no privileged pages anymore
now certain address ranges are
considered privileged and certain i/o
ports mainly where the height is zero
artists that are protected and uncle and
can only be written to from a privileged
address range like the red or yellow
berries the MOOC region had started the
flash tips now it started too much
difference at the end it's read-only in
order it's locked in harbor and always
privileged and then the variable size of
OS politic and then the rest of that is
user archive since the OS the the size
of the OS can vary from version to
version the ASIC has to be configured
somehow so that it knows which parts of
the flash tip to consider privileged and
that very much ranges configured be
configured via protected i/o ports zero
zero one day through 0 1 F which can
only be modified of course my code of
the privileged reasons so how did the
protected I oh well with any privileged
i/o port right t I must load a constant
value into register white that value to
the protected i/o port and then
immediately verified at that register
contains the same constant value they
just loaded they have to do that because
otherwise we could just jump right into
the boot code right before the court
right with our own value
so it's tedious but they like I said
they got a bunch of macros to do that
constant problem though is that the OS
is is variable not constant so it's not
something that they can hard code they
can't do that with these right
specifically so we could set around
register value and jump into the boot
code right before the port one D I over
maybe still control away through a
variety of means air ups there's a
method that's even dumber
the easy Eddie as I said as microts
compatibility for running cozy a vote
the easy Eddie mode has something called
it's called a something called haenyeo
mode
that's where 24-bit address and come
into play but even better any individual
instruction can run an ad Elmo or NCAA
so in ATO mode you can actually call a
subroutine that runs into dat mode and
then it returns you're back in eighty
OMA and even better than that and the
z80 mode subroutine you can have a deal
instructions such as those 64
ministrations so surely the protection
on the protected IO ports works when
your whether you're a DM oh no no it
doesn't so to effectively negate the
protection we just set the upper bounds
of the privilege range to be really
really high way out there something like
that beans or so on line 27 of this
screenshot it temporarily jumps into z80
mode to execute a single instruction the
one that writes to protect the ports one
day through one F which really should
not work and then it returns back to a
do so someone over there really
should've caught this these new models
are actually way less secure the ones
for twenty years ago and they were
actually trying to version 4 5 so in my
opinion the original unlock protection
used on the older models for plus series
it's actually perfect as long as they
stay on top of code related exploits but
they didn't and I don't think they're
going to but as far as this protection
the i/o port protection is likely in the
async just like before and they can't
fix it through software updates and
after the fact that they can reuse the
original a stick and need to make the a
4 + C Silver Edition and use that for 21
workaround instead of just simply
disabling that feature in Nasik that
leads me to believe that making even
minor change to the ASIC is cost
prohibitive so this really dumb exploit
is likely here to stay they can't afford
to change to make a view ASIC to to fix
it but just the case is not there are
and just a breathing school circle there
is one new model called the teen to
advanced which is really just a ti-84
plus non silver edition without the 2.4
movement or IO port its European only
very lockdown compared to the others no
more assembly program execution no more
flash applications transferred with a PC
they're actually hard-coded and built
into the OS and they put an LED and like
I mentioned before the bling stirred
test instead of that IO board so how do
we have this thing well the obvious
thing is to resort back to the original
t82 hex
there's OS even after all these years
still pretty much rhythm still pretty
similar this one so to do that many
brand backups
that's no my something that happens over
the g15 longer IO port which we don't
ever have but unbeknownst to most people
ran backups actually do work over USB
sort of no link software supports it cuz
nobody ever bothered to look but the
code actually is there there is code to
handle it so I came up with a memory
backup especially crack the memory
backup corrupted real variables as well
as a script to transfer that Noreen back
up from DC to the calculator using that
code and it does work you can't get
coded execution on it and you can even
unlock flash same as the ones but then
they went released another model very
similar to this one called the t-84 + T
which is just a Silver Edition version
of this womanhood except they removed
the back in functionality so that
function is probably disappear stick
well it does work is probably gonna go
away so overall where do we go from here
well there's still plenty of X place to
release endless with daily inspires
constantly being fought mighty I like
enrichment so helps always appreciate
their you know they just went over we
need a method code privilege code
execution with the table advanced or
just T that's kind of an old-school
challenge that's still outstanding I
still get emails from people really
wanting code execution on this thing
specially in Europe and it's not
particularly just needs to do it I just
on time and then of course there's TA
for plus C e family where we need to
stay on top of new developments new
hardware revisions new OS versions you
never know when CI is going gonna make a
manufacturing change or an OS update
that has a big impact in community more
than once I've seen release OS updates
that have very serious bugs in them that
mess up programs that have been around
for decades so if we don't let them know
about these things
and the technical details to play into
wrong and how to fix it so in conclusion
hopefully you see now these can be great
educational tools they're simple devices
on the surface but they're actually
incredibly complex they have a rich
history behind them they show up early
in people's lives in high school or
sometimes even earlier for me it was so
great
the community started the community s
surrounding them have to deal with the
same issues that you see in other
communities things like exploit research
legal and ethical issues surrounding
what you work on or the least as well as
planning and why and you learn an awful
lot about embedded devices both high and
low level programming reverse
engineering game programming everything
really cannot recommend them enough and
they get a lot of people start in a
programming and reverse engineering that
you mean so whether you just start now
you just might take deeper into this
kind of thing also don't live legal
threats intimidate you if you're
upsetting someone you're probably doing
something right standing up to that kind
of intimidations
how change happens so that's
so if you're scared you know you're
purple yeah okay
it's there links that so you know if
you're scared about what you're working
on reach out you know there are people
out there that can help you if you need
it first you have to do something that
requires you to get help so don't fret
don't put something off because of the
way you're afraid might have them do it
first and then see what you can do with
it so my opinion here we squashed a lot
of problems in the calculon community
over the years but it's never over the
community needs your help or your kids
help your students out the case may be
there's always something more to do even
in this talk I'm into some of the
security related things that still need
to get done so it's important this kind
of research continue not just at this
community but just speak it generally so
we discuss stuff interests you stick
with it I promise you it's worth it so
my contact information is there on the
screen this is my website spring bebida
net and that is the YouTube channel its
tid programmer