okay I'm gonna get started this is about
my adventures or misadventures with
Armand coatings for the assembly
instructions it's a little bit about the
tact but more about the journey so if
anybody knows we have been doing the
ignorant stuff with x86 for a while and
in the back of my mind I kind of want to
experiment with arm but I didn't have a
good starter it was harder for me to
emulate and I didn't really have any arm
devices to be able to really play with
because I wanted to work with bare metal
and then I realized for like years I've
had a Raspberry Pi so that was kind of
my starting to that I didn't know
exactly where to start with learning
assembly for arm because it seemed like
there is less books out there for it but
I've found on the raspberry raspberry pi
forums they're all kind of pointing to
this one resource it's a kind of a ebook
or a website to had a book about
programming for like assembly from arm
and specifically on the Raspberry Pi so
that's something perfect I started there
but the annoying thing is the guy I
thought most assembly books were bad and
I don't want to super criticize people
that much this guy knows what he's
talking about but the approach of
teaching assembly by writing a C and
then compiling it and then disassembling
it to try to illustrate assembly I think
is the worst possible way to teach a
newcomer assembly I know this is a nice
chart I'm not really intending to zoom
in I'm just saying then this is a
screenshot of him writing a seed program
to implement the static then compile it
and then deep compile it it's just the
most confusing way to try to teach so I
kind of skimmed the book I really read
it that detailed and I gave up on trying
to read textbooks or any kind of books
on our and I knew what the real source
of information was going to be like I
already read the entire like all three
volumes of Intel manuals so I thought
I'd find that our manual read that thing
as well
so I read that and at this point I'm not
even at hello world I just read the
manual first and I'm really getting
hyper focused on the machine in coatings
of the assembly instructions because
that's what I do
in fact by then I by the end of this
talk when I even get to the main perfect
concepts of everything I've done even in
the end of my research at this point I
still had not written below world
because it's too high level so this is
just an example of instruction and
assembly instruction for move and in the
bottom is kind of some ASCII text of how
that's encoded in binary so every arm
instruction being 32 bits for this
32-bit architecture with exception of
thumb instructions which I didn't focus
on so you kind of see the fields broken
out like they have four bits or a
condition and you have someone sincere
as that define that it's move
instruction you have your register
fields like art nrm and this kind of
elasticity of ASCII text because I'll
get a little bit graphic lad for this
but this is how it's looking up them all
and the thing that immediately I thought
was interesting about this instruction
and a lot of instructions related is you
see ones and zeros but you also see some
zeros with parentheses around them and
the our manual is very just architecture
in general was very organized
categorical broken down really well
explains what all those one since your
own fields are supposed to be except for
those ones in parentheses TLDR there
don't hear bits but it doesn't go so far
as to say there don't hear bits it's not
like I discovered this myself it was
pretty well known but those bits are
already but I didn't know I wasn't in
touch with our community so I focused on
these don't carrots I wanted to see what
they actually did
but speaking of how I love the army
architecture house broken down down the
road I'm I made this atlas researching
but to show you say there's a
subcategory a split there is conditional
instructions and
instructions and an arm as opposed to
x86 most instructions are all
conditional and not just you know your
jumps and those kind of things pretty
much every instruction is conditional
it's kind of cool but in the conditional
instructions the subcategories of that
are defined by like this two-bit aqua
one field and another one if you follow
this yellow line
kind of over you can go to one of the
subcategories which is a very common one
which is the data processing and
miscellaneous instructions and you can
have a loo subcategories like data
processing with the register data
processing with immediate values and so
on and those are all further defined by
the on and on two fields you see in
green at the top so if we start the
follow of that billet line we'll look at
the register ones over here you have
done a processing register instructions
and I'm going to kind of go down the
line here a little bit and we see kind
of towards the top there's our move
instruction that I had for ASCII text so
that's how I'm going to look at it now
same information but conditions are blue
registers - they're yellow all the
machine stuff the specific instruction
is red and just a further explained kind
of break down into categories for
conditional data instructions they are
all going to start with this is 0 0
machine code and if I were to follow
that now the subcategory all the wastes
of the zero zero and in it an additional
0 so that's kind of how that breaks
apart and then the extra four bits after
that down to wanting to find what actual
instruction sense so another thing again
I'm not going to say minutes it's not
really you don't just stuck in this code
the point is that it's a small script
again before trying to número world I
kind of retrofitted a concept of it a
little bit a while ago called
ml which is just converting
ask me hex in 2l Kampala can L run an
executable program for x86 I had a tool
like that interactively so when it makes
like that for arm and this is the whole
script is pretty simple I mean it's
doing a lot of system calls to bash this
is kind of a example execution of that
simple script is at the top they see me
typing some binary out by hand in the
nightma hit enter and then it tells me
that this instruction is move are one or
two and then below that I type some
binary for what is the same instruction
I just made all those don't care bits
ones and then I noticed that no longer
if it's disassembled is improve
instruction against disassembled is
undefined that doesn't necessarily mean
it's not a move instruction it's just
that this assembler doesn't know what to
do with it but I don't just take it it's
working for it I want to see what
actually happens so my first test is I
start to write an actual assembly
program I start by putting 0 and the
artist or register as a point of
reference just to know that it's
supposed to be 0 at this point and then
I machine code another move instruction
except for the only difference with this
is I'm moving the PC register into r0
and then flipping all that don't care if
it's to want to see if the instruction
actually does something or errors out
I mean it looks undefined but this is
still work that's my first question so
in my TB debugger if we look in here we
see the move R 0 0 immediate instruction
here and then we see an undefined
instruction below it and then it not
from that and in this view not this
showing up as read because it's the next
instruction to be executed meaning at
this point in this stage I've already
executed are undefined instruction so if
it didn't do anything that I mean if it
failed we would have already failed on
its program if it didn't do anything
that ever zero should still be 0 but if
it did do something than our r0 register
should have the PC value which in this
case should be 1 0 0 6 0 so we look up
there our minister
one zero zero six zero so it still works
we can screw those don't hear bits it
doesn't matter what we make them the
instructions still work except for when
you disassemble them they just kind of
cool
so in conclusion with that those bits
couldn't be any damn thing and in this
case but whatever you want in there or
more familiar kinds of things to some of
the people here is you know whatever you
use to put anything in there so
implications if I were to run with this
concept and we're saving a little bit
because we need a statically disassemble
you know maybe all the instructions look
undefined which is confusing
steganography because you can pack
anything in there you know you can pack
information in there as well
now we're signature busting I mean if
it's just hash based it's a quick and
dirty way to change the hashes and maybe
a better exploit development because you
can remove nulls and that's it so the
point about that is that whole process
from noticing that instruction that move
instruction it was probably after that
maybe only 10 to 15 minutes of
experimentation like this like 15
minutes and here I had these these
theories and I see sometimes in our
community it stops there like you see a
cool theory somebody tries to explain it
in a way that Jeremy I mean that like
they've already done that's the percent
of it like they're so cool the problem
is sometimes it doesn't always work out
that way you know you know in theory in
theory in practice are the same but in
practice they're not and sometimes we
get lucky but really without proving it
I just think it's just lazy because I
mean this is happening we have computers
we can test things to just stop that
theory it doesn't make any sense to me I
mean my religion is proof of concept I
get the out the perfect concepts
have really high currency if you don't
have it you don't know so that's kind of
point with that like I made a lot of
bold claims here but I don't know
necessarily if these things are possible
and really even how trivial it is to
implement them so while this this talk
has technical parts to it it's kind of
just a sermon delivery content you know
a little little preachy in that way and
and it's it's more just about process
just the profit process that coming up
with a proof of concept even if it's
something as stupid as manipulating
don't care this the process is hard and
it's worthwhile so the first thing I try
to experiment with was the question can
i define all the instructions that was
kind of the first claim I made you know
in this screenshot can they all look
undefined like that so you can't do with
all of them scroll through every single
instruction and kind of catalog which
ones I don't care which one day so then
my first proof of concept at this point
playing around so I wrote a script that
would go through on iterate through in
every single instruction identify which
one it is and then for them say like a I
don't care a big field of like four
zeros it would just put that last arrow
until one making it undefined and to do
that for every single instruction in a
binary so I tested it out on these are
games were my favorite instructions when
I disassembled it I had some undefined
amounts in there is kind of consistent
with the amount that I expected to be
undefined and it still works though it's
kind of cool that first test was pretty
successful in the theory that if you can
change anything you want
works and now I'm going on some detours
here that I had more questions like that
is a theory of anecdotally but really if
I flip any of those don't care bits
couldn't convert into a different
instruction and really didn't know it
became more clear to me when I made the
arm machinist athletes which as an aside
this this is talking about I broke down
every single instruction in its binary
form so it became visually easier to see
things so now I'm and the first test I
did was a just like we mapped out every
single instruction binary did some fancy
rednecks just to see that stuff didn't
overlap so as a kind of another detour
why are they don't care if it's you know
because you don't really have that x86
part of it is because arm isn't very
fixed my instruction set so you're gonna
have some bits and some instructions
that might not matter and I think these
two instructions go straight up really
well although they're not all like this
but this is consistent to conceptually
with x86 when you come here subtract and
compare instructions subtractive you do
a subtraction but it also has a side
effect of setting some flags like
overflowing and Karie and all that in
this case you're subtracting RM from RN
and historical result and RD the result
of a subtraction is in the Rd register
what compare is like subtract that just
isn't supposed to store the result all
it does is set the flags for the side
effects so that you can feed into logic
for doing additional instructions if you
notice the machine code is is very very
similar if not identical except for like
you know this this born bit field is 0 0
1 0 and this one is 1 0 1 0 sin
difference and then you'll notice that
that the s flag is the thing is supposed
to define if you're trying to set the
flags are not because norm you can
choose whether the flags are not and
subtract that's optional but in compare
it's not optional to hard-code into one
so that's what it's doing it's
definitely always going to be setting
the flags and then we have
this which is for the destination
register because we're not storing it so
that's kind of how that looked it's it
looked similar but being that we don't
hear about the destination or the output
you can put any one or a zero in that
field and it won't change what happens
to the comparator what you can do that
changes what happens to the compare
instruction is if you change the
hard-coding of that one to a zero which
there's no assembly for that it's too
high level if you do it in machine code
this is kind of what it looks like this
is the compare instruction but I have a
zero there instead and if I compare it
and disassembly and disassembles it's
the same thing but the machine code is
slightly different we have a five minute
four here instead and this is me just
assembling it out and you know
assembling linking running and it
actually is an illegal instruction it
doesn't work because it one makes sense
to run it and a compare setting doing
the thing that is supposed to do
anything getting done so quick little
mid presentation demo here what I'm
going to do is do this armwrestling so
playing this I'm gonna do obj don't to
disassemble and what I'm disassembling
is what we did itself I'm just looking
at the assembly for me so section the
first 30 lines of that and there's no
defined instructions this is what it's
supposed to look like so the next thing
I do is I run my tool arm behind I'm
gonna undefined those bits
objdump WTF you know like that all the
instructions so it's going to crunch
through that and when it finishes I'm
gonna have to then make WTF and now I'm
going to run this messed up objdump that
has undefined instructions and I'm going
to do
and I'm gonna run it against itself and
then looking for the first few
instructions of disassembly so I had
this modified version this fucked-up
version of objdump the hassle is not to
find instructions now that still works
and it's running on itself its
disassembling itself and it looks messed
up I just like how amendment that is but
so there's a perfect a perfect concept
or how usually you can define all these
bits and it doesn't change the
functionality instructions so now as a
tangent something that's not as fun as
the research I've been doing so far but
it's still kind of necessary if I want
to progress forward I know I mentioned
that I had a script that kind of
profiles through all instructions and
changes them as they go and I'm smart
enough to short-circuited if you find
that it's such-and-such construction it
modifies it then moves on to the next
instruction it doesn't try to interpret
it was that this instruction isn't this
instruction and so on
but at this point I had to all the
instructions in alphabetical order and
performance wise that's terrible I
really should be doing in those
instructions that are the most common
first for the short-circuiting that
profoundly affects in performance by an
order of magnitude however I don't know
what the most common instructions are
and I don't know any easy list out there
that tells that for me so I had to
figure that out for myself and in this
case I've seen screenshots me this is
just me doing alphabetical this is kind
of an order of instructions as they're
most common which this is legitimate so
what I end up having to do is I write a
script to profile an entire resume an
operating system I go through every
single instruction and I count and being
then at this point I was using my
original Raspberry Pi one be it took
about like days if not like a week but I
finally get my my data and implemented
this script and it's a lot faster but
now to be a little bit even more meta
what about including even
kind of modify instructions that have
don't care bids would it make sense to
add back instructions that don't have no
clear bits even though I'm not modifying
them it will help performance wise for
the short-circuiting because if it's an
instruction that happens the most
frequently whether I'm doing anything
with it or not at least I don't have to
check it against all the instructions I
can just be done with it
but then again if I start adding
instructions that don't have don't care
dates that don't have infrequently that
can hurt performance so I have to do
even more benchmarking to see what that
sweet spot is and this actually took
even longer to figure out than the first
benchmarking point is super super
time-consuming not interesting but still
needs to be done so I had another side
question as a curious person had a lot
of questions and this is this question I
wish I would have got to later even
though it was a necessary question but
at this point it just confused me and I
got back to it later but my question was
in the wild are there actually
instructions in real programs that's not
standard no it's a real question to have
but I really don't want to know
so when I do it I find something out
that surprised me on average all
instructions have 0 to 13 percent rate
of having instructions that have the
don't care it's said not suspect the
manual which is really weird like if
you're thinking about it what what
compiler is actually going to do
assembler or come on what what if some
other is actually going to do that
legitimately and why like this doesn't
make sense why is this occurring and
there is an answer for it but I'll get
to that later but in the back of my head
this is disturbing me a little bit other
assumptions because this is an
assumption we make assumptions when we
have all we have is theory without
testing it is these are a hundred and
forty instructions with don't care bits
can I assume that if I change them
they're all going to show up it's
undefined and really quickly the answer
is no because as I was comparing that
subtract and compare instruction the
disassembly the instructions both showed
up as compare you know it did any show
this undefined so now I have to
catalogue that also time consuming got
to figure out when which instructions I
exploit this way and it wasn't as simple
like some instructions like this first
LD are a car ext instruction I had to
flip all the ones to zero as if I just
flipped a couple of bits they would
still show up as the correct instruction
so I had to flip all those bits some
some instructions would like not to find
it on like the compare or to see MN
instruction no matter what one or what
no matter no matter what series to
change the ones even all of them or some
of them it would never undefined you
know pointing that phrase it wouldn't
different undefined the instruction so
now I have that in the back of my head
which was really demoralizing when I get
to an instruction like Mrs because
there's numerous don't care bits I think
there's about eleven don't care bits so
and really just arbitrarily change even
zero one or one who is zero didn't
define it so now I have to exhaustively
go through every single iteration which
I think before eleven bits is probably
about 2000 different experimentations to
then arrived at the conclusion that no I
can't mine define it and I have a
hundred and forty instructions to check
like this also time-consuming but I'm
thorough
I don't like to stop at just theory and
you know I'm talking mostly about low BJ
dummy maybe radar this where is
disassembling but you know obviously the
disassembler you're using matters too so
we've been seeing those context but you
know what about Ida Pro is that
different and you know I was working
with my my friend average Joe he was you
know the full version of might approach
I sent some samples
checked out what that would look like a
matter Pro on the fascinating but in
practice it works a little bit
differently generally it is disassembled
more instructions it recognizes more the
downside the first instruction it
doesn't understand everything after its
data even valid instructions so I
consider that to be a bit worse with
this assembly so that's going to go into
snow move on to the other claims not
you know making stuff undefined that's
my thing that's kind of the most
interesting thing but we'll get to the
other things like randomizing those bits
which in this case the purpose of it is
to change the hashman so you have the
same program functionally size-wise
instructional eyes but the hashes are
all different and that's kind of cool is
pretty easy to test that is retrofitted
that same arm-wrestle type script and
instead of flipping one bit I just
flipped all of them there in a ramekin
kind of a way it worked out perfectly
you know you have be running the same
time now the claim of steganography
turns out this is the most complicated
thing to pull off and I think in my
opinion the dumbest thing I've talked
about steganography here and there in
other talks but if you don't do it
really well
steganography is just really stupid and
in this case it is really stupid and
very detectable but again I wanted to
run with it as an exercise so I need to
have some metadata to make things more
convenient for the user so I haven't
been a data for how large the file is so
the program itself can know when to stop
carving to define that as a user and
kind of a conceptual way of how this
works is you have some instructions here
like move multiply multiply that's what
it kind of looks like a binary in red
and have your don't care miss here and
then as a sample assembly program cannot
result straining move and sine x Mary
this is that whole program and what I
want to pack into it is the phrase POC
or gtfo and binary capacity so this is
what it looks like
they don't changing those don't
character fields this is interspersed
four bits at a time the text appear gtfo
it doesn't change the functionality of
instructions and a heck stomach that
looks like this so these are all the
changed bikes and that's high-level how
that's working it's really not too
sophisticated so does it work in general
with that metadata in the down I'm
putting in there I can write a script
and check data in there however I
realize at this point I've been doing a
lot of hacking around but I collected a
test run the programs after I finished
stay going down so I might try done real
quick and it signals something up and
this point I don't know what I mean I
haven't done anything that there are
some instructions in there where the
don't care bits are set incorrectly
which I still don't know why so I
decided to kind of investigate that a
little bit hoping that it would answer
my question so I started isolating off
some of those off spec instructions to
try to see the context why like why
there we run when it stretches around
them and then you know correcting the
instruction actually making into spec to
see what would happen and it's way too
turned out that when I made the the
instructions correct
it actually seg faulted that way like if
I went to a default executable and I
changed one of those off spec
instructions to be the correct version
of it that made the program break like
it was an integral that the instruction
had to be wrong for the program to work
so what I did is I used bokken because
it's a good graphical representation of
a disassembly and it gives really
helpful hints said found with those
problem instructions and then I look for
backlink references to that instruction
and I found an instruction that's
referencing it and
was helpful enough to get would comment
saying it was data so in this case I
have data in the dot text section which
is not necessarily weird or problem this
happens you have like jump tables and
stuff like that it's not necessarily
data in the sense like strings are data
these aren't really strings they might
just be memory addresses or something
like that that do what make sense there
belong in a dot text section but they're
not instructions so this kind of makes
sense as to why you have data
instructions in there that disassemble
like instructions by barn and how they
don't care base said differently because
they're not real instructions so that's
a data problem it might be solvable but
it's way more complex than what I'm
doing right now so I'm trying to find
some clever ways to work around that so
I'm gonna do more profiling I want to
see what data instructions are the most
common like I already saw what assembly
instructions of the most common now I'm
gonna do it for data because my hope is
that maybe just luckily some of those
false positive data instructions are
really really common like maybe it's
only one or two and I could just ignore
those type of instructions for my stay
going to be done with that problem turns
out though it wasn't the case it was
fairly evenly distributed I mean there
was like no attempt and I made up maybe
90% of the instruction set but I
couldn't just ignore instructions
outright I had to handle it in a
different way so my idea was maybe to
dynamically blacklist these instructions
like do a first pass of looking at the
whole program and seeing which
instructions were set incorrectly and
then deciding dynamically to blackness
those instructions and then even have to
record it in the metadata because the
program that's extracting it needs to
know which instructions to skip as well
you have to communicate that that's what
I end up doing but then you're thinking
okay that requires more metadata and
what if you're shoving like what if
you're showing that meta done
instructions that are actually data and
then you still have the same problem so
how much my I'm fed it down it is not
going to take and also going to put that
metadata in the very beginning of my
data as to try to reduce the risk even
more and I'm able to get that metadata
into one bite
like literally doing a dynamic blacklist
of the entire instruction set of which
ones which instructions I want to skip
I'm reporting that down in one bite and
this is my reasoning say that the top
three instructions that the false
positive is data are like load our
datastore in a star storage in this case
this is accurate to this is an arbitrary
so if it really is in that order of most
comments at least common if I'm
profiling when I see strh show up I can
kind of safely assume that strd mmm I'll
dr game are also in that blacklist as
well because they're even more common
than strh and that's my logic i only
record the most least common one that it
actually finds and just assume that all
that other more common statistically
instructions are also going to show up
there as well
and that's how I get it into life in
this case I just say but what happened
is did I still if that's still not
enough like if that data destruction
happens to be one of the first
instructions if there's overlap with
those top ten places and fortunately the
top 10 for data instructions in the top
10 for actual instructions with don't
care bits is almost mainly exclusive may
be a lot harder if they weren't they're
the same but I'm thinking in theory is
rare and if it could happen but I really
have I want
against that and it took some research
but I found something that did prove
against that on the raspbian system
these are been GA tool you find here and
I would say the move instruction for the
medium form is one instruction of
overlap like if you look at the top ten
of both those lists the move instruction
is the only instruction shared and this
move instruction comes in really early
on in this binary so this method still
doesn't work it's a rare edge case but I
still want to solve it and the
convoluted edge case is to just detect
the educate America so I know so I can
adjust accordingly with some other
arguments that I have to develop later
there's also false negatives it's like
when I'm broke modeling I might find a
data instruction that just happens to
have the don't care basis set correctly
so that's another problem too it hasn't
come up in practice but that's another
issue so my solution to kind of all
those past problems is to have a
blacklist override like I can actually
manually override that blacklist and
sets a higher threshold so if you know
you stay going in sec : so you can make
that blacklist more aggressive and it
won't say long anymore because you're
skipping over the correct instructions
it's just now you're gonna have less
data space to code data into and then an
education education sometimes hit a
point where were blacklisting so many
instructions that we still say you know
it's it's a small interface but it
happens so in this case all I can say is
if you run the tool
you still get a seg home I guess you
can't say go to that program now this is
a small problem though and then finally
this is noisy if you were to look at a
binary
question well did somebody stay on this
program in this method well you have a
point of reference on what the
instructions are supposed to be looking
like so if it was stay ago all these
bits are going to be changed
so you can with some confidence say this
program I stay go so in this context
this is why I said steganography it's
stupid there's a lot of heuristics I can
do I can just definitely say if these
don't miss respect then this is
definitely stay ago I can't say that
because there is a range of instructions
that are going to be data that will
throw that off but if the program has
been staying most like name is
significantly higher than that 13% rate
like really just by random luck only
about one in 16 of the don't care mid
fields are going to be normal looking
for instructions that only have four
bits of don't care but you know even
higher so we can look at look at that as
a profile although I would say is a
bench case librarians tend to have way
more than 30% so you got to kind of keep
that in mind as well but there's other
things like I am reporting metadata so
in my stake over the program the
metadata would be larger than zero
obviously and fortunately don't care
bits are typically zeros and a lot of
instructions so if you do see 0s or
metadata then it probably wasn't
staggered you can kind of coordinate
this information also if the metadata
isn't 0 like it's not 0 but it would
seem to indicate that the amount of data
is larger that the programmer even
looking at well then these are just
random ones and zeros very don't care
bits that couldn't mean it's stay go
because you can't pack more data into
less data and then you know our
blacklist information we can correlate
that to we can like actually look to see
how much instructions which should be
blacklisting and compare it to our
actual blacklist in the metadata and you
know we can assume whether or not it
really matches or it combines in that
way in a couple of different contexts
you know also the very last name which
not going to cover too much for reasons
the shellcode part so I can say with
confidence that you can use this method
to remove nulls completely out of some
instructions on the side here I have in
the middle section here we have all
these instructions this is the full list
of instructions you can do this with
other instructions if you can't so we
have the machine code on the side here
all these yellow highlighted nulls or
the corresponding bits and on the right
side here so in theory this does work in
practice I'm not going to say I'm
not exploit developer I haven't tested
it and I think it's a responsible estate
if this is going to help your
exploitation especially since really if
you look into it
Arvin's thumb instructions it's a little
compact encoded in there 16-bit they
tend to usually not have no lights in
them and for the ones that do but again
this isn't my thing so I'm not going to
actually boldly claim that this is going
to help you with exploitation because
that's lazy I'm not a contestant doing
pulling information out of some
executables and by the way and I pulled
apart behind me because it's armed but I
didn't was because decade ago it was
steganography tool written for x86 kind
of similar in concept like say like some
instructions like say Hanks or there's
more than one way to do like X or on the
X DX that's actually
that's exchange but anyway you can
encode it in a couple different ways
they're both found in eilerson
one way but if you were to do
alternating ways and your binary and
that's kind of one of the heuristics
that they sent me my implementations a
lot different but the concept is very
similar so that's why I call this so
let's go ahead and look through this PMC
here so I'm listing when I have in this
directory I have a file called our PLC
I'm running fine line up to see what it
is it looks like an elf executable
executable I'm gonna run it to $20 and
you know it does something it's kind of
dumping like a file so it's okay so now
I'm actually comparing this our POC with
actually business CMP nsv to save
mouthsize but if we check the hashes
against each other 30 economists egg
analysis we see that the hash is hard
different that's cool so we're gonna run
behind against it we're gonna extract
from our POC our output is going to be
mystery so and this is also a program so
we've talked a program inside of a
program that's kind of cool
let's make it executable and it just
says clinics so the comparator you name
and let's go ahead of mystery out sizes
cool right it worked let's prepare the
hashes in that just in case those do
what happens
so we're typing that out or extract any
names you really need to hashes are
different so inception we extract
out of that mystery no doubt and output
that mystery to demo and run file
against an and see it's a
text file so be candid cactus Coola so
that I think that's really cool you can
on multiple layers pack the data and
that's a quick perfect concept for
which I have on github in the last slide
I'll link to that so in conclusion
regardless of you know what this talk
was about are behind messin don't miss
my arm and all that
theories are quick and sexy it's easy
like to do all this work it took a lot
of testing and took a lot of profiling
half which had nothing to do with the
progression mr. babies performance or
answering some questions but those are
really important and crucial as well
that took me like four to five months
but to come up with a theory took me 15
minutes so I wanna give a perspective on
the difference there the process just
takes a lot of work a lot of time and
it's not really that sexy I mean the
majority of this talk might have
actually legitimately been boring but
that's that's an important point I'm
just saying it it's crucial to do it
like there are theoretical fields that
exist and that's okay this isn't one of
them we should just talk about a theory
we should do it so really that the
sermon is if you know how to behave like
and I have a little quote up here I'll
zoom into it but sometimes we have
friends that say things like this and
it's just really really cringey like not
saying they can't do this but shut up
until you do it and this is the actual
end of the talk not a lot of people but
if you have any questions
yeah Joe of course I mean like on a like
batching him he's asking you know if it
can be scripted out are you talking like
a Qing a bunch of in this case as it
stands now and it's open source but it
is limited to an elf executable because
I am doing some pre-processing first to
it it won't actually run if it sees that
it's not an elf executable it actually
does look specifically for the dot text
section and only applies its logic to
that because obviously if it's if it's
like considering the data section is
instructions it's going to it up so
I do have to be very careful about that
however that's just referring this tool
it doesn't mean that you couldn't apply
the same process to shellcode it's just
as tool as it stands doesn't do that but
of course this with shellcode you could
change those don't care bits to anything
you want and it would work the same as
this but no my tool doesn't do that it
doesn't do matching by default but it is
a command with arguments and it's not an
interactive program so you could
probably write a you know a one-liner
that does that it should work
one other thing I described a lot in
different ways as profiling and
researching that are all time-consuming
I didn't literally tell you all of the
things so it was even more
time-consuming that I'm giving away
because I had other random questions
that don't apply to this but I did have
the question how many don't care bits an
elf executables how many don't care bins
total are there
rasping system I asked that question and
I profiled it I think this is when I
when I didn't have my Raspberry Pi 3 B+
so it took a while maybe two weeks to
find the answer this question and it was
something in the word like 500 megabytes
that's really cool that's like free data
you know I mean and it's easier said
than done
because if you really wanted to like
store a lot of data and all that and
have to add more complexity because
you're going to be splitting that data
across several executables we gotta
track that but you know it's kind of
interesting too as far as like batching
another kind of application about if you
wanted to do that I'm in practice I
don't know so really say it works or
I've done it or any other questions just
Jo that sounds like a normal talk for me
alright thank you
[Applause]