(digital music)
(audience applauds)
- So we want to
talk to you today
about a different kind of
computer and that's the one
that sits between your ears
because as you're doing
your forensic examinations,
I think everyone in this room
would agree that that is both
the most important computer
and the limiting factor
sometimes, right?
In keeping up with everything
we have to keep up with
and doing the work we do every
day, whether it's the hard
nature of what we're
dealing with content-wise,
or whether it's trying to jam
another fact into your brain
and then use it later,
this is hard work.
So we've been talking
about this for a long time.
Ryan and I met?
- 2012?
- In 2012 at some
forensics event.
(man mumbles)
We're debating which one.
I was giving a keynote.
It was either Stranger
in a Strange Land
or it was about elephants,
but also about forensics.
- Yeah.
- And afterwards,
I came to talk to
his class of students
and I'll let you
take it from there.
- So I'm an adjunct professor
at Champlain College
in their digital forensics
science graduate program.
And at the DFRWOS meeting
in Monterey that year,
it was kind of the inner
residence where the students
got to come and do
their resident time
for their graduation
requirement, I was need
of a keynote speaker.
I didn't have one and
somebody said, "Hey, how about
"Cindy Murphy?"
And I had no idea who that is.
Uh oh.
- Oh, it's okay.
I jumped, sorry.
- Okay, and they said no,
she's great, she'd
love to do this.
Contact her.
I reached out to her,
she was very gracious,
she came to talk to the students
and we got in conversation
and long story short, we
found out we had a ton
of things in common.
Not only were we super
snappy dressers, but we also
(chuckles) were musicians,
and not only were we single,
excuse me, single instrument
musicians, but we were also
learning to play another
instrument that was not
our primary instrument,
which we thought
was very interesting.
And she shared and said,
"I think there are a lot
"of musicians among digital
forensic professionals."
oh, that's very interesting.
I had heard that as well
and it was just kind of
a topic of conversation,
we went our separate ways,
stayed friends.
- And you know the weirdest
thing we had in common?
We both played the banjo.
- Ah, the banjo.
Right.
- Yeah, it was pretty weird.
- The third individual that
you see up on the screen
is a guy by the
name of Matt Linton.
Does anybody know him?
(Audience member shouts)
Yeah, Matt's awesome.
So Matt used to be the
answer to response lead
at the NASA Center, where I
currently work in California.
He defected and went to Google.
Their gain, our loss.
But he and I are close friends.
He is also a musician.
He plays the fiddle, or
the violin, and the cello.
- And the ukulele.
- What's that?
And he and I started having
the same conversation.
He said, "There are a lot of
IR folks that play music."
Well, maybe this was
starting to be a thing
and so we kind of sparked up
this three way conversation
about whether or not this
was a thing, and if so, why?
So we kind of got the idea
for some original research,
a survey that we put
together that we sent out
to a particular sample.
It was a purpose of convenient
sample for those of you
statistic nerds out there.
We targeted Iasus and Sands,
and all kind of communities
that we thought might
have DFIR professionals.
- And one quick backstory.
- Yep.
- There's a person in this
room that also sort of
helped us along, too.
Frank McClain.
- Oh yeah.
- Wrote this great
blog piece on fiddling
and DFIR.
- Where is Frank?
- Frank is right there
in the middle.
- Ah, there he is.
- And so, that was also
an inspiration to us.
It was just another person
who had brought this up.
We know Mike Pore often would
come with his instruments.
Josh Wright also plays,
so all sorts of musicians.
So anyway, we put out
this survey.
- Anybody take it?
- Hands.
- Frank?
- Wow, it's so hard
to see out.
- Oh, there's that one
back there.
- Yeah, there's,
you know, 10 or 12 people.
- Okay, so we sent this out.
We actually got 206 responses,
which based on the size
of our field is a pretty
decent number, we thought.
And we started to break it down
from there and we found out
some really interesting things.
So the first thing, or
one of the first things
that we found was that among
the respondents, we found that
almost 50% reported that they
were musicians or regularly
played instruments of some
sort, which was kind of awesome.
We found that number to
be kind of remarkable,
but that really didn't
do us a ton of good
without some normative
data, trying to compare that
to the general public
because that's really what
we were talking about, is
is there really kind of
an increased instance of
musicianship, or playing
a musical instrument, or
singing because we included
singing, among
people in our fied.
As we did this other
research and tried to gather
these statistics, we found
that ranges were estimated
different surveys anywhere
from five or 6% up to the very
top end, closer to 34.
But as you know, if you've
ever tried to do research
about statistics, they can
be very dubious and they can
be made to say kind of
whatever you need them to say.
And so we spent
some time evaluating
kind of the provenance
of these statistics.
- [Cindy] But really,
what it came down to is
no matter what statistics
we looked at, whether they
were from the music industry
or whether they came
from the US Census, the
numbers we were getting
of DFIR professionals who
were musicians was close
to that 50% mark, where the
hightest, most skewed number
we could find for the general
population put it at around
38%, so there was definitely
something different
in this community, or at
least it appears that there
is a trend.
- So we wrote a paper
about this, it's in
the Sands reading room,
so all the good, raw data,
and all of the research
and backstopping and everything
related to the statistics
that we got from our survey
and why those things might be
is in the paper.
We encourage you to read
it, but one of the things
we definitely want to talk
about is what we came to figure
out was and acknowledge the
established link between science
and music.
- And there's a huge one.
So one of my great
heroes, Albert Einstein,
we all think of him as a
physicist and a philosopher,
but he's also a major musician
and if you start doing
a little research out
there, he said on a number
of occasions that his
little theory, you know,
that theory of relativity,
was a discovery of musical
perception, something that
came to him through music
and that may sound fuzzy, right?
And it may sound really fuzzy,
but music is a language.
It's about patterns, it's
about putting down data points
in the right order in the
right pattern and creating
something in the end that
is a program our brains
understand as music.
So if you think about it in
those terms, it's a really
great analogy for computing.
- There was a very large
study that we cited
that,
- I'm waiting for
the first laugh.
(Ryan laughs)
- [Cindy] Does anybody
get the joke here?
Come on (laughs).
There aren't any musicians
in the room, maybe.
- No, music (mumbles).
- Yes (laughs).
- All right, our survey
was wrong, it's wrong.
(chuckles) one of the big
studies that was cited
was a group that
looked specifically at
what they considered
to be a high
performing scientist.
So these were Nobel laureates,
members of Sigma Chi
and some of these elite
scientific societies
and contrasted them with
just other scientists
in the general public.
They wanted to know what
made these people different
and as an aside to their
study, they noted that almost
universally, the scientists
that were most high performing
in their fields among which
Einstein would be one,
they had experience,
non-scientific
avocations or hobbies
that were rooted in music and
art and so they associated
these very closely and
covered a great deal of ground
in showing that not only
were these high performing
scientists also musicians
and artists, and that is
in part what's
seen to set them apart from
the other non-high performing
scientists, but that their
participation and success
and these non-scientific
hobbies were also not a function
of higher IQ, which we found
very, very interesting.
- Yes, I found that
actually really rewarding
because I've said many times
I might not be the smartest
person in the room,
but I'm really stubborn
and I'm really creative
and those things probably
make up for, and by the way,
I'm really, really
smart, so many rooms I,
but in many rooms I am
the smartest, but boy,
you get into a conference
like this and you start
to wonder, right?
We have that imposter
syndrome that sneaks in
for all of us, and this
was very comforting to all
of us.
Matt said, "Thank God," right?
Thank God that it's not
all about that IQ number,
that these high
performing scientists,
the highest
performing scientists.
Something about the
combination of creativity
expressed through music and
the science and technology
helped them to succeed.
- So creativity is a very
important word, specifically
scientific creativity
and perception, which
I know something
that's near and dear
- Yes.
- To your heart, how
we experience the world
not only as a function of
what we do as digital forensic
and IR professionals,
but also as musicians.
Will you elaborate on that?
- Absolutely.
So really, perception is
where it's all at, right?
So how we see the world
around us, we can't
look at any of those little
MAC times or the capitalized
MAC times unless we're able
to conceptualize what those
various timestamps mean to us,
what the pattern
underlying that mean
and unless we're able
to creatively parse out
the way Lee does, and
Heather does, and Sarah does,
and Nicole does, all of
those differences that might
be a possibility.
Unless we're able to
conceptualize the testing
that's going to lead
us to those answers.
- So several sociologists
and psychologists went so far
as to say that the best
scientific thinkers,
those individuals that were
most scientifically creative,
were also among the
best concrete thinkers
and they linked those two
skills very intimately.
So through the original research
that we did in the survey
and the backstopping we did
with the literature review,
we started to think
okay, so if we take
the fact that we think we
have a higher percentage
of musicians in these fields,
it's a very interesting
data point, but what use
could music be to us?
So let's say you're
not a musician.
Why do you care?
- [Cindy] How many people
in the room are not
musicians at all?
All right, there's
quite a few numbers.
- Guess what?
- That's okay.
- There's something you can
do to help your forensics.
Something fun, they call
it playing, in fact, right?
- Yes, it's really nice.
(Cindy laughs)
We enjoy it.
So the second half of the
paper, we shifted our focus
to the potential personal
and career benefits
of playing music for
DFIR professionals.
So this comes in
many different areas.
Principally, it comes in
areas related to stress relief
and just playing
and feeling better.
- Brain plasticity.
- Yes, comes in the area
of brain plasticity and
it can come in the area
of team building.
- Absolutely.
- So if you want to talk
about it personally?
- Sure, so actually,
I want to talk
about brain plasticity first
- Okay.
- Because it's on my mind,
right?
- Okay, cool.
- So brain plasticity,
basically, is our ability,
our brain's ability
to develop new
and unique neuron paths in
order to physically change
itself as we learn new
things and this can be active
your entire life.
So if you keep your brain
active, if you use it,
you won't lose it.
And there have been brain
studies that have shown
that people who practice
music into their elder years
actually suffer less from
dementia and can slow down
the process of dementia.
But once you have developed
your brain's ability
to create those new pathways,
it finds it easier.
It's like any other muscle.
Well, I don't really know
if it's a muscle (laughs),
but that again.
- Yeah.
- If you exercise
it, it will grow.
Musicians have more white
matter, more gray matter,
and more connections
between the different sides
of their brains, and that
helps us to learn more things.
Simply the act of listening
to music will stimulate that
and so one of the
questions we asked was
do you listen to music
during your exams and if so,
what kind of music
do you listen to?
We were looking for those
patterns and we found a great
deal of variety in
what people listened to
and we found some, a
surprising number to me,
because I listen to music
during exams, but we found
some who don't like to listen
to music because they find
it a distraction.
But it has been found that
the benefits of simply
listening to music are
there, but if you pick up
an instrument and start
to play around with it,
if you do those, if you
practice the motor skills
that help you to learn
to be a musician,
the benefits are
increased many times.
- Absolutely.
It really struck
a chord with me.
On my mom's side,
I have a really
excessive history of,
- It struck a chord?
(laughs) it struck a chord
- It did.
- With you.
- History of dementia.
I have a 92-year-old grandfather
who's deep in the throes
of it now.
My mom has started to show a
few signs, so that was kind of
important to me.
As we mentioned earlier,
one of the other areas
that can help us, beside
the brain plasticity,
because who among us wouldn't
want to grow our brain
and be better at what
we do professionally
by doing something fun, but it
can pay big dividends for us
as far as personally
enhancement, enjoyment,
and stress relief as well.
If you are a digital forensic
and incident response
professional, you're
in a stressful job.
Even if you like your
job, it's stressful.
For those like me
in law enforcement,
I mostly do intrusion compromise
stuff now, but I started
doing a lot of child
pornography, a lot of child
exploitation, a lot of sexual
assault, a lot of things
that were really tough.
- Shootings,
Stabbings.
- Absolutely.
- [Cindy] Yeah, people
hurting each other,
killing each other.
- There's some really
great quotes in the paper
from somebody who
described in great detail
what it's like to be a
digital forensic examiner
professional sometimes.
And IR professionals
don't have it much better.
They're dealing on a daily
basis with compromises,
intrusions that cost
their companies all kinds
of embarrassments and data
loss, and in some cases,
like the Sony hack, some
estimated that that cost
upwards of $2 billion with a B.
That's a lot of pressure,
so when we start looking
for things that deal with kind
of stuff so that we don't,
I don't know, get divorced
and push everybody we love
away from us, we start
looking for outlets
and there are plenty
of unhealthy ones.
You can drink and do drugs,
and go to fight club,
and you know, all
that fun stuff.
(Cindy laughs)
You know,
we happen to think, obviously,
because we found it,
but playing music
is a better choice.
There is a remarkable
program in Wisconsin where
Cindy lives, but do
you want to talk about
the pressure of that
since he is your neighbor?
- Yeah.
The Tires for Vets
were also warrior songs
that Jason Moon, my neighbor
right across the street.
I'm not sure what twist
of fate made that happen,
but he's heavily involved in
this program and basically,
the Department of Veterans
Affairs has staffed
and funded studies about
PTSD and music, and specifically
about teaching music
and learning music, and
how it can interrupt
a stress response, how
it can just cut it short
and sort of act
as a release valve for
pressure in the middle even
of a PTSD response and how
practicing music and learning
to play music can help veterans
to retrain their brains
to turn down that stress
response and to really
help them not only make
it through acute responses
to stress, but also
lessen the number
of those over time and
for some people, even find
lasting peace.
So it's a really great program.
- [Ryan] They did a great job.
I was in Kuwait and Iraq for
13 months and when I came back
is when I first started
being interested in music.
It did a world of good for me.
One of the last things
it can really do for us,
and we're talking about
career enhancement, is help us
build more effective teams.
And we're going to give you
a small demonstration of that
here at the end, but in
general, the team that plays
together stays together.
When you're in a situation
where you can participate
with people that you have to
deal with in a professional
situation, particularly if
that professional situation
is very stressful, having
an activity that you can do
that's very low
impact emotionally
that's very easy to
get into that provides
a lot of co-sharing of
the work and support,
it can have a tremendous effect
on how you work as a team.
If you're an IR team
or investigative team
and you're having to deal
with these types of things
on a daily basis in
your professional life.
- [Cindy] Sure, there have
been some really incredible
studies in this area too.
They've hooked up musicians
to brain monitoring equipment
and have found that
their brainwaves
actually sync together
as they're working through
songs and their breathing
and their heart rates
all come together
and so if you're talking
about good, solid, nonverbal
communication, you're
not going to find it
much more quality than
you get playing music
with a group of people.
There's a wonderful
quote in the paper
that I should have included
here, but it talks about
how music is the one time
you can lose the pitiful me
and really become part
of a group and experience
what it means to work with
other people in a team
and lose that worry about
making mistakes, right?
Because if I hit the wrong
chord, I bet Daniel over here
has got the right one and
his solid chord covers mine
just fine and it might even
sound like I was intentionally
doing some sort of
strange harmony there,
so a lot of the mistakes
musicians feel themselves make
actually contribute to the whole
of the music that
they're playing.
- [Ryan] You've been
listening to us say this now.
It sounds like we're
in a cult, right?
- Right (laughs)?
- [Ryan] A religion.
Testify!
- Yeah, that's right.
- You know, you can be
musicians too, but
you know, it really is
one of those things that
we just kind of discovered.
I mean, it was an
evolution for me.
- Well.
- I didn't wake up one day,
I'm going to be a musician.
This is awesome!
- To be fair,
to be fair, Google
knows about this,
right?
- Oh, yeah, yeah.
- [Cindy] They have invested
in an entire building
full of practice rooms for
their employees and so lucky.
- [Ryan] And so when
we say entire building,
it's not like a gardener's shed.
It is a full-size office
building and when we say
that it is stocked with
instruments, it is stocked
with instruments.
You go into every room, every
room, and there are stringed
instruments hanging on the wall.
There has got to be 30 freaking
drum sets in this thing
and just every room
is for employees to go
and take instruments,
and play, and de-stress
and do the things they need
to do to be happier at work.
Right, we all know
that Google is into
keeping their
employees happy, right?
They get free food and
slides from the third floor
down to the lobby and all
that kind of fun stuff.
Well, they also have the
opportunity to make music.
And Matt and I play regularly.
We try at least every two weeks.
No matter what we
have going on at work.
I'm at Aims Research Center
in Mountain View, California,
so we're right up
against Google.
We share a fence.
So Matt and I are still close.
- Yeah, and you
know an interesting,
Matt, and interestingly,
Matt has told stories
where he will say to
people, "No, I'm sorry,
"I can't attend that meeting."
This is my scheduled
practice time during work.
So they really do, they've
invested in their employees'
musical brains to that level.
So there really is
something to it and it helps
on all sorts of levels.
- [Ryan] So we definitely
want to share two more things
before we get into the
little bit at the end here.
- [Cindy] Well first, I've
been putting quotes up
and you probably noticed
that some of them
are from musicians and some
of them are from scientists,
a lot of theoretical
physicists, but I love
this quote from
Jessie Cornblume.
Anybody know Jessie?
You should, right?
You use his tools, I'm sure.
And he used to be a Sands
instructor, so Jessie
the other day on Facebook
quotes, throws this quote up
and says, "Conventional wisdom,
you shouldn't send an email
"when you're emotional or upset.
"Less well known or equally
valid that you should
"also hold off when you're
listening to Poison."
He was listening to Talk
Dirty to Me and sent an email.
And regretted it (laughs).
So this is real and
it affects all of us.
It's a question of whether
you notice it or not.
- [Ryan] So in our survey,
we also, in addition to
trying to get kind of the
vocational demographic data down
and learn about how people
in our field play or not,
we also asked them
open-ended questions
about do you listen to
music when you do exams?
Do you think music has an
affect on the way you do
your job?
What do you listen to?
Things of that type.
So one of my favorite
answers to the question about
how do you think music affects
the way you do your job?
Well, somebody said doing
digital forensics is like
putting together a
really good performance.
It's like putting together
a really good song.
I have to be creative, I have
to follow where things lead,
I have to be solid, and
people have to understand it.
A good forensic report is like
a good musical performance.
When you deliver it and you're
done, you want the audience
to flick their Bick
lighters up in the air
and wave them back and forth.
(Cindy laughs)
I loved that,
that was one of my
favorite quotes.
- Yeah.
- One of the other things
that we asked participants to
do is if they listen to music
while they do their exams,
give us their top five.
We want to know what
their type five songs were
that they listened to
when they do their jobs.
- [Cindy] And we're
giving that back to you
- That's right.
- As an extra bonus.
- So we put together
at the end of the paper
in one of the appendices,
is we made a list
of the artists and song
names of all the songs
that all the
respondents gave us.
- It's weird,
- Yeah.
- It's very weird (laughs).
- It's really eclectic.
I think we went up to
about 173 songs and we have
a little addendum of
like, 45 more where people
didn't say a song.
They said like, "Anything
by Zach Brown band,"
or whatever it is
they listened to.
And one Barney the Dinosaur
song made it on there.
- Yeah.
- A couple of things
by Weird Al.
- There's always
a smarty pants out there.
- Tie Me Kangaroo, Down Sport.
(Cindy laughs)
Where is the Aussie
that was up here earlier?
Yeah, we got Tie Me
Kangaroo, Down Sport
made it on there, so it's
in the paper, but we also
created a Spotify
playlist that's public,
so if you want to go
listen to this, it's called
The Ultimate DFIR Playlist.
- Yep.
- You can find it on Spotify
and you can listen to it
to your heart's content.
- Absolutely.
- And we stay on the topic?
- Well I mean, so much to say.
- Oh yeah.
- [Cindy] We did a one hour
webinar and we also did
the forensic lunch,
which was another hour,
or at least most of an
hour in preview for this
half hour talk, so there's
a lot of information
that we've already put out
and we thought that we would
take this opportunity to
share with you kind of
in a different way, realizing
that this is, in a lot of
ways, outside of everybody's
comfort zone a little bit,
but I think Lee Whitfield
a couple of years ago
did a talk about forensics
and mental health
and how we can support ourselves
and we wanted to follow up
on that with the research
that we had come up with
as well.
So we're hoping that you enjoyed
this and then we're going
to go way out of
our comfort zone
and do some music for you.
And before we do that, I'm
going to get to the slide
where we have the chorus
because we're hoping.
I know, it's like church, right?
We're hoping.
I don't go to church, by
the way, but (laughs).
We're hoping that you'll
maybe get inspired to join us
if you feel so inclined
and Frank, you got those
bones out?
- All right, so we're going
to buy Frank out.
- And does anybody
play the ukulele?
- And Ishmael,
where did he go?
- I'm serious.
Anybody play the uke?
It's such a common instrument.
- Where did he go?
He brought his guitar with him.
(banjo and guitar music)
(man mumbles)
- Keep going.
♪ Heading down south to
the land of the pines
♪ I'm thumbing my way
into North Carolina
♪ Staring up the road and
pray to God I see headlights
♪ I made it down the
coast in 17 hours
♪ Picking me a bouquet
of dogwood flowers
♪ And I'm a-hopin' for Raleigh
♪ I can see my baby tonight
♪ So rock me momma
like a wagon wheel
♪ Rock me momma any way you feel
♪ Hey momma rock me
♪ Rock me momma like
the wind and the rain
a south bound train
♪ Hey
♪ Momma rock me
(acoustic guitar
and banjo music)
♪ Running from the
cold up in New England
♪ I was born to be a fiddler
in an old string band
♪ My baby plays a guitar,
I pick a banjo now
(banjo music)
(man laughs)
♪ Giving me now
♪ But my money made a
focus so I had to leave
♪ But I ain't turning back to
living that old life no more
♪ So rock me momma
like a wagon wheel
♪ Rock me momma any way you feel
♪ Hey
♪ Momma rock me
♪ Rock me momma like
the wind and the rain
a south bound train
♪ Hey momma rock me
(banjo and acoustic
guitar music)
♪ Walkin' to the
south out of Roanoke
♪ I caught a trucker out of
Philly had a nice long talk
- Ooh boy.
(man coughs)
♪ But he's a-heading west
from the Cumberland gap
♪ To Jackson City, Tennessee
♪ And I gotta get a
move on before the sun
♪ I hear my baby calling my name
♪ And I know that
she's the only one
♪ And if I die in Raleigh
at least I will die free
♪ So rock me momma
like a wagon wheel
♪ Rock me momma any way you feel
♪ Hey momma rock me
♪ Oh rock me momma like
the wind and the rain
♪ Rock me momma like
a south bound train
♪ Hey momma rock me
(bass guitar and drum music)