(applause)
- So welcome to The Cider
Press. This is our talk.
We don't get to talk
together too much,
but we decided to
do a talk this time.
This is The Cider
Press, we're going
to extract forensic artifacts
from Apple continuity.
- I'm Heather, or
Arnold. Sarah's my twin.
We like to compare
ourselves to twins here,
so we thought this
would be interesting.
Phil essentially introduced us,
we're not going to
spend too much time.
So, worked for SANS,
worked for ManTech,
smartphone nerd, I like
bourbon, sip wine, horses.
(cheering, applause)
- I'm Sarah Edwards, of course.
Again, another
author-instructor.
I also have a day job, and
it's weird, cause we get
to work together in our day
jobs, and our SANS lives, too.
You can't pull us apart,
therefore we are the twins,
and unfortunately,
I get Danny DeVito.
I don't know who wins or loses
on this one, to be
honest with you.
So, what is continuity?
Continuity is across
all Apple devices,
whether it's your phone, your
iPads, your Mac, your watches.
It's the seamless interaction
between all of these devices
to do fun stuff, to help
you do certain things.
There are certain
requirements, there's software,
there's hardware requirements.
It's on some of
the newer devices,
so if you have a
really old phone,
or a really old Mac,
it probably won't work.
It needs specific wireless
and Bluetooth hardware
to actually get this
functionality to work.
There's a few other
requirements, as well.
For most of the
interaction, you need wifi
and Bluetooth turned
on, and you need
Handoff to be selected, as well.
So we'll go through
some of those things
and the requirements
for each particular
piece of Apple
continuity itself.
- What we did for
our evidence sets,
what you can see here...
So we used my phone
and Sarah's phone.
Sarah's the jailbroken one.
The artifacts that
you're going to see today
are from my actual device,
so no jailbreak included.
We do have some
caveats built in.
We both had our Macs, running
two different versions,
which don't really play all
that much in differences here.
Old watch, new watch.
And then, what you don't
actually see at this point,
and you will see in
the future, is Phil was
sitting behind the
scenes and capturing
network traffic
going back and forth.
One thing that was difficult is,
Sarah and I chose something
that you really need
to be in proximity to
create data sets on,
and we don't live
close to one another,
so were trying to do
this from Philly and D.C.
So on some of our evidence here,
you will see where we
were talking to ourself,
versus talking to one another.
So we do commingle it, and
you'll see this in the slides.
- So first, just as
a little start-off,
I'm gonna be referencing
a lot of different GUIDs
and hardware pieces
within the slides.
So, where do you find these
things on your own devices
when you're doing a
forensic analysis?
Got a couple of
screenshots up here.
These are my Bluetooth settings.
So this is for my
phone and for my watch,
so it's called "miWatch"
and "miPhone7,"
just to put that into
perspective for you.
So, you will see the GUIDs
here, the F7s and the C9s,
throughout a lot of the
logs I'm going to show you.
We'll also see a couple of
different Bluetooth
addresses, as well.
So these Mac addresses that
are actually shown to you here,
we don't actually get to see
this in the logs too much.
It's more or less
referencing those GUIDs
that I showed you on
the previous slide.
So when you're doing
keyword searching,
you might wanna pull
out those GUIDs first,
and then keyword
search those logs
that I'll show you about
in just a little bit.
And of course, on the
iOS side of the house,
you still got those
UUIDs or those GUIDs
that you can search on, as well.
So the plists are pretty
much the same, this one just
happens to be in the database
because that's how iOs works.
So how this all works together,
there's a little thing
called Bonjour, and this
is Apple's name for,
basically, zero
configuration networking.
You find zero configuration
networking on lots
of other devices,
Windows has their own,
other mobile devices
have their own, as well,
but Bonjour is a
Mac-specific technology.
But it's built upon, pretty
much, industry standards.
So, just a little skit
that we have here for you,
how it works in the
most simplest form.
And there's plenty of
documentation out there
to show you how it all
works in more detailed form,
but this is generally
how it's going to go.
So you get a device
here saying, "Hey.
"I just turned on AirDrop,
what can I do with it?"
So, hey y'all, I got AirDrop.
- I'm over here by
myself. I have no friends.
Who can I AirDrop with?
- Oh, I can be your
friend. Let's AirDrop.
- Excellent. I'm gonna
drop it like it's hot.
- Yeah.
So, there's that discovery,
and the publication,
the resolution of
all those things.
I mean, this is
extremely simplified,
but there is that interaction.
We'll see that in
the logs, as well.
- So, with AirDrop, we have
different scenarios here.
We spent a bulk of our
examination time in AirDrop.
The log files are
really overwhelming,
and we redacted a
lot, which you'll see.
So we did different scenarios.
You can see here some
screenshots from Sarah's device,
from my devices,
from our computers.
So what you will see,
each of the headers
going forward, you're
going to see Mac to iPhone,
iPhone to iPhone, iPhone to Mac.
So, just make sure you're
reading the slide titles
when you actually get
copies of these files,
if you're trying to
replicate what we did.
Important for you to know,
is you can AirDrop to anyone,
so you'll see we broadcast to
everyone, which is shown here.
You'll see we were
broadcasting yesterday
in the restaurant
downstairs, and we could see
other people's random devices.
As long as you're in proximity,
a peer-to-peer connection
will be established and you can
drop files from one another.
So you will see
this in our slides.
- So, AirDrop, first
off, is the technology
that allows us to drop
different files back and forth.
So we're gonna show you
a few examples of those.
First thing I'd like to
show you are different IDs
and identifiers that you
can search on in your logs.
Mac and iOS pretty much
has the same thing.
For the Mac, we got two
different plist files here.
One's called
"SharingD," the other's
got "SharingD" in it, as well.
So if you're looking for
continuity-based stuff,
look for that term
called "SharingD."
That's the sharing
daemon associated
with a lot of that sharing
continuity interaction.
Same thing on iOS.
For these two
examples, I wanna see
what the
discoverability mode is,
whether it's set to
everyone, or contacts only,
or if it's turned
off altogether.
But I also wanna take a
look at the AirDrop ID.
I'm gonna reference that in
the logs that we're gonna see.
So, that's how you
tie a certain device
in the logs to other activity.
So, we have this scenario here.
The screenshot here shows you
that I'm on my Mac right now,
and I see two different devices.
These devices don't
have any icons,
they're just the gray bubble
with the white head in there.
One's called
"Dadephone," and the
other is Heather
Mahalik's phone.
So, I'm on my Mac right now,
and I can see both
of these devices.
What does that look like?
And this is just a
discovery of the devices.
There's absolutely no
file transfer just yet.
In the Mac unified logs...
Now, Mac unified logs are
a brand new logging system
on all the newest Mac-based
devices, so Sierra,
iOS 10, and all sorts
of good stuff like that.
These are the newer
version of those logs.
I have a whole other
presentation on how to read
those unified logs
that you can find
on my website, if
you're interested.
So, this is just the discovery.
So I open up finder, and
saw these two devices.
What does that look like?
In the logs themselves,
if I do searches for
that SharingD term again,
and more specifically,
the Com.Apple.Sharing.AirDrop,
specifically,
it's gonna show you the
different categories
of different continuity
items in here, as well.
Just a few items that I have
bolded here, you can see
the server's been initialized,
the Finder entered AirDrop,
meaning I selected AirDrop
in my Finder window,
you see some Bluetooth
scanning going on here.
It uses Bluetooth LE scanning,
so you'll see that all the time.
These logs are
extremely verbose.
There are hundreds,
perhaps thousands,
of different log entries.
We've only cut it down to a few,
just to show you the different
type of activity here.
So we get some
Bluetooth LE scanning,
starting scanning mode,
so this particular one's
doing contacts only,
versus everyone.
You'll also see
some mDNSResponder.
This is very much associated
with the Bonjour activity
that we were talking
about before, so
you'll see a lot of
these items in here.
One below that,
you see the AWDL.
This is that peer-to-peer
communication.
This is the Apple
wireless direct link.
It's another interface
on your Apple devices.
It's not specific to en0,
it's not the en1 interface,
it's specific only to that
direct link type of interface,
so it's almost like an ad hoc or
peer-to-peer kind of
thing, and that's how
all the continuity stuff works.
Then finally, we
see some other items
in there with the
AirDrop terminology
in there, Bonjour
discovery started.
[Com.Apple.Sharing.Browser],
this means I'm actually
browsing for different
people to communicate with.
And then finally, at
the bottom, we have
the Com.Apple.SharingD,
No AirDrop People
Discovered After 8 Seconds.
So it's constantly looking
for different people,
and if you have AirDrop
open on your Macs right now,
you can see people
popping up back and forth.
Now, if I can continue
on, there's more stuff.
So, this is now discovering
these two devices
that I have here.
So I got Bonjour discovered,
and I have this number,
this ED2A number, I
have a couple of these.
This is that AirDrop ID number
that's associated with
a specific device.
So if you need to tie
two things together,
you're gonna need
that AirDrop ID.
Finally, we get some more
Bonjour and mDNSResponder,
and then we can also
see associations
to the name, the host
name of the device.
In this case, I'm seeing
Dadephone in here.
If I keep going a
little bit further down,
I'm discovering Heather
Mahalik's phone.
Then finally, in the bottom,
we have
[Com.Apple.Sharing.Browser].
Now it sees those two
devices that I showed you
in that original
screenshot, the Dadephone
and Heather's iPhone, with both
those Apple IDs
associated with it.
- So then, we did a transfer.
If anyone's not aware
of this, this is the Mac
on the left-hand side,
this is actually a fire
that happened in Rob's
mom's hometown, here,
that you can see,
and it's terrifying.
The end, oddly, of
the video gets gory.
So, when Sarah dropped this
to me, instead of showing
the beginning of the fire,
we found it very strange
that it showed the
end, which is why
it's blurred out,
it's a little gory.
So what you're seeing
here is several things.
On the left-hand side,
we see Sarah's Mac.
She had it set to see everyone.
So when we were sitting
there sharing files,
we saw other people
who were around us
that weren't even
a part of this.
We considered sending them
the fire, but we didn't.
On the right, you
can see my iPhone.
Because Sarah and I are not
on the same iCloud account,
it asks me do I wanna
decline or accept.
And I'll cover this further
in my slides, but we're going
to actually look at what
this transfer looked like
on the Mac, and then we'll
cover it on the iPhone.
- So, from the Mac itself.
It says AirDrop server
enabled on 48770.
You'll see that port number
used pretty often, so
if you wanna search by that,
you can go ahead and do that.
You can see TCP
connections being
started up, it does
an SSL negotiation.
And I have highlighted
and underscored here
the received verb.
So the verb, they're gonna
tell you which direction
it's going into,
so I'm gonna point
that out in a couple
of different places.
In this case, it's doing a
received discovery request,
it's receiving this, it's
receiving a video from miPhone7.
That miPhone7 and that
informative text section there,
that is actually on
my Mac, that little
pop-up notification window
that comes up, saying,
"Would you like to accept this
movie from Heather's iPhone?"
or from my iPhone,
or from wherever
it's coming from,
accept or decline.
So, to get that
notification information.
And finally, we get the
received upload request,
adaptive compression, so it's
moving all this data back
and forth, not necessarily
across the network,
but potentially over
Bluetooth as well.
And then finally,
the transaction end.
So we see a server transaction
begin, and then end,
so you know that that
transaction actually happened.
Then finally, we can
see the AirDrop ID
that's been
associated with that,
and there's that
ED2A again there.
A couple of items
that get transferred.
It's not just about
logs on the Mac.
On the Mac, actually,
AirDrop stuff
is much easier to look for.
So if I receive certain
files, movies, pictures,
whatever it might be,
there's some other artifacts
that I can take a
look at, as well.
For this one, just in the
simple downloads directory.
It's one of the
default locations.
If somebody's gonna
AirDrop you something,
you can accept it into
your default downloads.
So that's a first quick look
at where that
stuff might happen.
Some of the timestamps
actually get saved.
So this movie here was
actually taken on June 15th,
while I received
it on June 18th.
So you get some preservation
of timestamps here.
In the yellow highlighted,
the permissions, sometimes,
not always, you'll see
that access_bpf permission,
the Berkeley Packet
Filter kind of thing going
on there, so you know it somehow
got moved across the
networks somehow.
But I'll tell you right
now, it doesn't happen
on all AirDropped stuff,
so just be aware of that.
We also get extended
attribute information.
If you take my class,
you know I love
extended attributes,
love them to death.
And we get some information
associated with that,
specifically two that
I wanna talk about,
the
Com.Apple.Metadata:KMDItemWhere,
and the Com.Apple.Quarantine.
KMDItemWhereFroms
basically says,
where did this thing come from?
Now, it's a binary
plist, but you can
see the strings
in there that says
Sarah Edward's iPhone,
miPhone7, in there.
Now, in the quarantine
information, you'll see
that it has that SharingD
process in there,
and that hex value, that's
actually the timestamp
that it was AirDropped
onto the system.
And if I happen to open up
this movie in QuickTime player,
that quarantine
attribute may change.
So it's not always gonna be
the SharingD, if potentially
it was opened up in a
different piece of software.
So, something to
just be aware of.
And of course, if it
does get opened up,
we can still go back to
the quarantine database,
where all the original
information is being stored,
to get that original
timestamp and that SharingD,
who did it come
from information.
In this case it was AirDropping
to myself, so it has
my name in there.
A lot of different pieces here
that we can start
to put together.
There's also this purgatory,
as I like to call it.
If somebody's sending me
something, and it's somebody
I don't know, it goes into this
purgatory area, this
Cleanup at Startup.
It's gonna store it
in here temporarily
until I view it or until I
see it, that kind of thing.
Doesn't happen at all
AirDropped information,
but it is a good place to
check, so take a look at that.
And it does get
cleaned up at startup,
so once I reboot that system,
that all gets flushed away.
Something to be aware of.
So, one more thing.
From Mac to phone.
How do you know which
file it actually sent?
So, it'll actually store that
information in there, too,
and I have a couple of examples.
If you just do a file://
search across all the logs,
you'll see different examples.
The top one here is
the catalog note ID
for a particular file.
But sometimes if I'm AirDropping
from within an application,
if you look below that
Com.Apple.Sharing.AirDrop,
starting to send
files, you'll see that
in that bar folders
pack, you'll see the
Com.Apple.Photos.BundleID
in there too.
So this is me using
the Photos application
to AirDrop those things out.
So, kind of gives
you a better idea
of where those files are
actually being stored on disc.
- All right, this
is where I wanted
some sound effects, wamp wamp.
So, just to warn
you, if you strictly
have a newer device,
we're using the iPhone 7
on my device, it's
not jailbroken,
so you're essentially
stuck with a backup file.
The artifacts that I
got, you're going to have
to get really, really crafty,
just to caution you here.
With the phone here,
you can see I'm getting
an AirDrop from my
husband's device,
he's not on my same
iCloud account.
You get an option, "Do you
want to accept or decline?"
If you accept, and it's
a photo or a video,
it's going to the
default DCIM directory,
and we'll talk about what
this looks like in a second.
If it's not, if it's a text file
or a .pdf or something
else, you get
an option on how
you wanna open it.
The bad news is, if you
decline, at this point,
I have not been able to
find any logs showing
that it was even offered to me.
So, you can see why you
would want to do this,
but right now I
haven't been able to.
For devices on the same
iCloud, so now I'm talking
to myself here, it doesn't
even give you an option
to decline, it's auto-accepting.
Here we can see that it's
going straight to DCIM, or,
I was sharing a text file
with myself, it's saying,
"What do you want
to do with this?"
In this scenario here, what
I did was, I sent myself
a text file, and it was a
link, in that text file.
I saved it to my Notes, and
then I opened it in Safari.
Now, are the artifacts going
to speak to you that way?
No. I know this happened
because I sent it to myself.
Again, no option to decline.
So now we're gonna look at what
this actually looks
like in the artifacts.
I will caution you here...
And that line looks very weird.
But I will caution you, I
knew something occurred.
So at this point, you
knew from other evidence,
maybe you had Sarah's
Mac, and you're like,
"I know she AirDropped
Heather something,
"or I know Heather received
an AirDropped file,
"because someone was looking
over her shoulder and saw it."
So, you know AirDrop occurred.
What you could do is, the
very first thing you can do
in that backup is, you
could go to the Push Store
and see if AirDrop
is even enabled.
Does the user have this
enabled, yes or no?
You can look at the
data usage, SQLite file,
which I have in a slide
coming up, and say,
"Okay, are there artifacts
showing AirDrop at all?"
At this point, you know
the AirDrop was used.
So what you can attempt
to do is timeline,
but I wish you the
best of luck, because
things don't always fall into
order as you would expect.
Sarah was seeing one way,
I was seeing another,
so we were confused,
and then I was able
to replicate what she was
seeing two out of three times.
So what we have found is,
when an AirDrop picture
or video came in, it
didn't necessarily fall
in the correct order on where
it should be in that DCIM.
It made no sense, sometimes
it did, sometimes it didn't.
And it was the same...
I did .png files several times,
one time it worked,
one time it didn't.
So be careful with
timelining on this.
Other places you can
look. EXIF data? No.
We were hoping that it
would say it was sent from
or taken with Sarah's
iPhone, or captured
with Sarah's Mac,
and then shared.
Didn't get anything there.
Pure desperation at this point,
because you know, someone
told you Sarah sent
a text file to Heather
through AirDrop.
What you could then do is,
you would find it in My Notes.
So if you were looking
at all the databases
on my device, you would
see it was in Notes.
You can see that I show it
in Safari on the far right.
You can open it in
third-party apps.
So at this point,
you are literally
on a wild goose chase, and
do you have time for it?
Your saving grace is this
datausage.sqlite file.
Here, you're actually going
to see sharing SharingD,
so you can do a
search for SharingD,
Sarah already mentioned this,
and we can also see AirDrop,
so you could do a
search for AirDrop.
But that's really
all you're getting.
You will see some of the
Bonjour activity, as well,
but you're not getting the
file that was shared, the date,
timestamps, all the good
stuff that Sarah showed you,
not going to exist on
these backup files,
from what we've been
able to find so far.
If you get crafty, and you
then go for a live analysis
and start doing
dynamic analysis, you
will get log files.
Here, I connected my
iPhone to iBackupBot,
which is free, and I started
doing dynamic analysis,
and just copying
out the log files.
You will see I get
some of what Sarah got,
but not even close
with all the artifacts.
So we can see that my
Bluetooth LE scanning started.
You can see that the
mode was everyone,
so I wanted to
connect with everyone.
You can see scanning
started successfully.
And what you will see is
that it will start scanning,
and it will drop off if
it doesn't find anyone
in that point of time.
Continuing on, you can see that
AirDrop has been initiated,
and it found me.
Sarah mentioned the GUIDs and
the unique IDs for AirDrop.
You can see my AirDrop ID
there, for my Mac, and then,
new AirDrop connection, so a
connection was established.
We can see the handshake and
the negotiation going on.
We can see the request,
and then it's parsing,
it's received.
But it doesn't tell
you what is received,
so you just know that
something was received,
and something is
trying to be shared.
So now, you're still guessing.
What you can get from this,
though, is the
settings on my device.
If you look down
at the bottom here,
where it says Notify
From, FaceUp -> Portrait,
that's how my device is set,
that if my phone is face-up,
I'm gonna get a portrait saying,
"Sarah wants to AirDrop
this file to you."
If you look at the alert
item, you can actually go
into my log file, and it
will tell you what kind
of tone plays, or how
I'm alerted, does it stay
in my notifications, is
it persistent or not.
So you can dive through
and keep digging
into these artifacts.
The final thing that you do get,
you see accepting transfer,
and you see this GUID up here?
What I recommend is
exactly what Sarah said.
Take that GUID, and
search all your plists,
all your databases, anything
you have on the iPhone,
to see if you can associate it
to any way one of our devices.
It doesn't give you information
that even a movie was
sent versus a picture.
You don't get to see
it, so you don't know
that this actual
picture was sent.
The reason I have it there
is because I know I sent it.
And then, you'll see the
server connection drops off.
So it's better
than a backup file,
but chances of you
actually getting the iPhone
and doing live analysis
while an AirDrop
is occurring is
probably slim to none.
Especially if you're
doing forensic analysis
and isolating from the network,
this shouldn't be occurring.
But this is the major
difference on limitations
with iOS on what you will
not get at this point.
With Handoff...
And I'll hand that to you
while I talk with this one.
- You'll hand it off?
- I'll hand that off to you.
- So, that ends AirDrop. Now
we're gonna talk about Handoff.
So, what does it look like
when you start an action
on a Mac, and continue on a
phone, or add in your watch?
Handoff allows us to be lazy.
The lazier we get, sometimes,
the better the evidence is.
Sometimes it makes it harder
to ascertain where
something occurred.
We are going to try
to do that, as well.
But, Handoff allows you to copy
something from your iPhone,
continue on your Mac,
and continue through.
Some prerequisites here.
Bluetooth and wifi
must be enabled.
You must be on the same
network, so you have
to be on the same wifi network.
You have to have the
same iCloud account.
So, it's not that Sarah can
continue onto my devices,
it would be all
hers or all mine.
And Handoff must be enabled.
You'll see in the
slides here, we show you
how to enable it on your phone,
how to enable it
on your actual Mac.
And you'll see on
the screenshots here,
the little icons are
showing you that continuity
and Handoff is actually
enabled, and this
is where it's going to continue,
and where you can pick
up where you left off.
So as an example, going
back to those Mac logs,
again, those Mac
logs are gonna be
your key evidence
from this case.
So we go again, SharingD.
We're looking for
Com.Apple.Sharing
instead of AirDrop,
like we saw before.
We're gonna look for
Handoff specifically.
And again, we have
those different GUIDs
that are bolded in there to
show different transactions.
So I might be interested in
this particular transaction,
I'm gonna do a search for that
one string that starts 476ED,
and look through that whole
list of different log events.
And again, it could be hundreds,
it could be thousands
of different events.
Below that, we have SharingD:
Received A New Advertisement.
So it sees that I have a
device-unique ID, it is F9B.
There's that GUID
again, that I want
to look across all my devices,
perhaps look in my
Bluetooth plist, to try
to match it up to
a specific device.
In this case, it's very nice,
cause it actually shows me
which device it's
associated with.
Sometimes you get that,
sometimes you don't.
Sometimes you have to
search within context.
So if I keep going down
into that one log entry,
I'll see device name
is miPhone7, and
the make and model,
which is the iPhone 9,3, which,
in human terms, is the iPhone 7.
So we'll see a lot of those
items going back and forth,
which can be very helpful
to tie to specific devices.
Now again, we're gonna
look for that F9B.
That is my miPhone7
unique identifier.
You're not just gonna
wanna search and filter
on those Handoff or
the SharingD stuff.
You're gonna wanna look
within context, as well.
Cause I'm showing
you another one here,
it says Dock: (UserActivity)
[Com.Apple.UserActivity.Main].
And this is gonna show you
certain information associated.
So this is that little icon
that pops up if I'm working
on a text document or
an email, that says,
"Hey, would you like
to hand this off?"
That shows up on the doc itself.
Now, this one I
highlighted specifically,
cause it says
UserActivityHasWebpageURL.
Sometimes you get hints
of what type of data
is being pushed back
and forth to devices.
And I'll show you
another one here,
with the Bird: or the
(CloudDocsDaemon).
A lot of this stuff happens
over iCloud, as well,
so you don't wanna
filter out of everything,
you wanna look within context.
And again, you're
gonna be looking
at thousands of
different messages here.
There's a lot of
things to look at.
So just don't get
frustrated, and get used
to seeing some of these things.
I was actually worried
that these logs
wouldn't be very verbose.
Unfortunately,
they're more verbose
than you even want them to be.
But I say, more is
better than nothing,
so I'm willing to take it.
- With an example here.
So, a little scenario.
What you're actually
looking at, and you have
to look up top, the
iPhone to the Mac.
On this specific
scenario, Safari was
opened and browsing
on the iPhone.
The screenshot on the
far right is the iPhone.
When going to the Mac, the
Mac was set that Chrome
is the default
browser, not Safari.
So the Mac is smart
enough to know
that the user wants to
access what they are doing
on their iPhone in
Safari, in Chrome.
So you will have
artifacts from both here.
What you see on the iPhone,
browsing Safari, one continuing
on the Mac, you see the
little iPhone by Chrome.
When you click on
that, it continues
exactly where you left off.
- What does that look like?
If I actually click
that link on my Mac
in Chrome, what
does that look like?
So, UserActivityD is gonna say,
Queuing Fetch For BestAppUUID.
It's basically looking
for the best app
associated with that
particular data.
In this case, it's gonna
be my Chrome browser.
I get a few other things,
like Fetching Payload,
Requesting Payload, Request
To that specific UUID again,
associated with a
specific device.
And finally, Requesting
Handoff Payload,
and so on, so forth.
Next one we're gonna see is
that SharingD item again.
But we have a
different item here,
(Com.Apple.Transport.IDSConnect.
It's using this
identity services stuff
to show the different
interaction between the devices.
And you can also do
searches for the continuity.
Com.Apple.Private.Alloy.Continu,
you'll see that in these
logs every once in a while.
So you get certain hints
on this type of activity.
You also see this
IdentityServices,
Continuity Connect To Peer.
So I can tie that one
GUID to a specific device,
and, if I look
within context, I see
some Google Chrome
activity happening here.
(Com.Apple.CFPasteboard.Entry),
we'll talk about
that one a little
bit further on,
but that's basically
saying, "I got this URL
"in my pasteboard, and I
wanna provide it to you."
And I (mumbles) that
in the UTF plaintext.
So you get an idea of what type
of data storage it's
holding off here.
Then finally, Received
Requested Handoff Payload
From "miPhone7," and you can see
that it's been shared
to my Mac itself.
So, kind of figuring out where
application was being used,
you have to look within context.
These are all separate
events on here,
I just wanna point that out.
So, if I'm sharing a Notes,
look for the Notes application.
Reminders, mail, maps, numbers,
all this can be handed off.
There's many different
applications.
You always have to
look within context
of that Handoff log activity,
and try to figure out
which application was
actually being handed off to.
I usually just do a search for
that copy data, and that seems
to be a good standard key term
to look for, in this case.
So, from the Mac to the phone,
if I'm in the Maps
application on the Mac itself,
on my laptop, and I wanna
send a certain location
to my phone, maybe I'm gonna
go drive there or something,
I can see that I have
the Maps: (CoreSpotlight)
going on there, the
BundleID:Com.Apple.Maps.
The SharingD Handoff log
activity is there, as well.
You see it's connecting
to my iPhone 7,
it's received items, so,
instead of sent, it's receiving.
And then finally, you get
the model identification,
the name, and the IDs
associated with that, as well.
So you can correlate
this stuff back and forth
pretty easily
using the Mac logs.
Now, we also have Ready
To Respond To Handoff.
These things are
extremely verbose.
It almost seems
redundant at times.
So, responding ready to Handoff,
Received Payload Request,
and then finally,
you get the Bird:,
the cloud docs information,
the iCloud information.
And then finally, we have
Requesting Handoff Encryption
Key From "MiPhone".
So we saw it sets up SSL,
it sets up encryption keys.
Honestly, from a
network standpoint,
we've not looked at that yet.
We told you we are going
to look at it, eventually.
It's gonna be really
interesting to see
if we can see anything, because
of that encryption on there.
- Now we have a few other
tiny sections here for you,
just to summarize other
things that we've seen.
So, Apple Pay.
On my Mac, in
Safari, I browse out
to this Etsy site, which,
Eric, if you're sitting
in here, this is
what those bows are.
I went to an Etsy site, and
looked for Tiny Vibes Boutique.
From there, I had the
option to use Apple Pay.
So I used the touch
ID on my phone,
and it saved to the Mac,
and also, on the phone.
This is where the
artifacts could get tricky.
The good news is, with
Safari, you'll see,
under the history database file,
you can see the
origin column and say,
"Did it happen on
this device, or
"is it associated from another
device on that same iCloud?"
So you could then say,
"Okay, it's something else
"that Heather was on, that's
logged into her same iCloud."
And if you go back to
the very beginning,
where Sarah showed
all my devices
that my iPhone recognized,
it would be one of those.
Also, the recents.
I recovered the
actual transaction,
where I got the
transaction receipt sent
to my email, I was able to go...
I deleted it, because I
delete everything as quickly
as it comes in, even when
I'm creating evidence.
And I was able to go in
and actually carve it out
of the hex and recover
this information.
But again, this is
really what you got
with the Apple Pay artifacts.
You can see that I go out to
Etsy, that I purchase a bow,
that I paid for
it with Apple Pay,
I got the transaction receipt,
and then you see the picture
of my daughter with
the bow on her head.
- So, one more. We
got Auto Unlock.
This one I was thrilled
to be able to view.
Auto Unlock is
the activity where
I can open up my
Mac with my watch.
There's certain
requirements for that.
I had to be on the
same iCloud account,
I had to have two-factor
authentication, Bluetooth
and network have to be
enabled, all sorts of stuff.
All the moons have to
align for this all to work.
But it does actually
work out quite well.
This just saves me
inputting the password in,
because it's authenticating
through my watch.
Very useful. So what
does it look like?
That's not gonna happen, sorry.
(laughter)
We got a few more slides here
left to go. So, Auto Unlock.
Again, we have these
Apple unified logs.
We have different lock states.
We'll see the lock states
just in general logging terms.
It doesn't necessarily
associate to Auto Unlock.
So I'm specifically gonna look
for that Auto Unlock activity
and those log entries, and look
for the different
log states in here.
There's also other things
that we can look for,
the Bluetooth, the
wireless proximity,
nearby agent, sharing Handoff.
Handoff gets used as
a subset for a lot
of other Apple continuity
activity, as well.
So, actually unlocking.
You can see the Begin
Unlock in there.
You can see the device
information, the make and model,
the Apple ID
association with that,
and a few other
devices in there.
So the SharingD: AutoUnlock
Scanning For Bluetooth IDs,
that's my phone and my watch.
So it's got a proxy
device, meaning my phone,
as well as the ID for the
watch itself in there.
Once the unlock
actually happened,
you can verify that with
these couple of items.
It'll show you
which user account.
My user account name is Oompa,
a bad nickname that
I got many years ago.
I think it's cause I'm short.
A couple of different
Bluetooth IDs, again,
the watch identifier
information, whether unlock
was enabled, and whether
it was locked on my wrist.
So if I had not put the
PIN code on my watch here,
it's not gonna unlock,
so it is a locked device.
Then finally, if I keep going
down here, I'm gonna see
some Bluetooth IDs and
ranging information.
It's basically
saying, "Is this watch
"within proximity
of this laptop?"
And different keybag
states and lock states
associated with that.
One note on this
Mac address here.
Apple uses Mac
randomization for a lot
of the Bluetooth and
wireless information.
So you might see these
Mac addresses in here
and try to pair it up
with a certain device.
You're not gonna have a
whole lot of luck with that,
because of the randomization,
so just a caveat there.
You see it, you wanna
associate it with something,
but Apple is not
going to let you,
from a privacy standpoint,
so you gotta look
in different areas of
the logs themselves.
A couple caveats.
If you do open up,
unlock your Mac devices
with the watch itself,
it doesn't look
the same as other
unlocks in the log.
Sometimes it doesn't
get recorded at all.
I'm still doing some
research on that,
to figure out why it's
not being recorded,
cause from a
forensic standpoint,
that's gonna be really
important information.
So in different logs, it
looks slightly different.
- All right, I'll go
through Clipboard quickly.
You do get these slides.
So, Clipboard here.
We're on the Mac,
copying from Notes,
pasting it into the iPhone,
and sending an email.
We're just going to
take a quick look
at what this looks like.
When we look at the
log files on the Mac,
what you're actually
going to see
is the copypaste, so the
app that's being used.
We can see the payload
request, that unique identifier
that Sarah had mentioned
earlier, we see it's associated
to the iPhone, and we see
that this was a text file.
If you look at the
Flavor: at the bottom,
that's what you're seeing there.
Continuing on, we sent
two more flavors here.
Flavor one was a
.jpeg, and then,
flavor two was actually
going to be a movie file.
As you go through here,
you're going to see
the payload request and all
the sharing information,
as well as that it was remote.
The device is not the same one,
so a remote device
was reaching out.
Here, you can actually
see where the iPhone
was sending the
movie to the Mac.
That icon at the end there
is what it looks like
on the Mac when the
movie is coming in.
You can see from the log files
all of this remote access
actually happening
with the continuity.
- And finally, one last topic
for you is Instant Hotspot.
So I have my phone
that I can tether to,
so when I have crappy hotel
Internet, which I'm sure
we've never come across before
ever, I can tether my phone
to it, so I can actually
get some decent signal.
It uses that same continuity
features on there.
Again, Bluetooth and wireless
need to be up and running.
And I can just select it
up in my wireless settings.
Instead of AirDrop or
Handoff, I'm gonna look
for Sharing.Tethering
in this case.
So you can see it's
starting to browse, scanning
for available tethering
devices, it's gonna find
my phone in there with that F7.
Discovered new device, you
see the wifi agent in there,
miPhone7 and all the
other identifiers.
But also the battery
life, what type
of network it's on, and
the signal strength.
That's signal
strength two, meaning
it's got two dots
filled in on my iPhone,
versus the normal five
if you have good signal.
A few other things.
Enabling Hotspot, so you can
see if it was just searched for
or if it was actually enabled,
whether credentials were
passed back and forth,
the different channel
information on there,
and finally, that it's
enabled, and the information
associated with that
at the very end.
- All right, so these are
our final two slides,
Rob, we promise.
Our caveats here.
Mac artifacts are more
fruitful, and we do mean that,
we do, with Cider, and the
pun, and everything here.
We literally scratched
the surface here,
so we have a ton
more digging to do.
We intend to keep presenting
this at further events.
What we're going to
do is, we're going
to throw in Phil's network
respective with this.
Sarah and I are going
to keep digging.
We want to focus a
little bit more on iOS,
and also throw in
jailbroken devices, and see
what it actually looks like,
so you know what you can get
if you have a forensic
image, versus trying
to do dynamic analysis
on these devices.
Just be aware that the
timestamps are tricky.
Do not rely on them
when it comes to iOS.
Make sure you are digging
through these logs,
you will get buried in
them very, very quickly.
It's a lot of data.
- It's exhausting.
It is exhausting.
So, again, if you
wanna see more about
how we evolve this presentation,
we're gonna give it
at a few different
other locations.
If you're interested
in just general mobile
or Mac forensics,
come to our classes,
we got a few of
them going on here.
We're both here
for the whole week,
and Austin, which
is gonna be awesome.
But we do travel to
other places, as well.
- You can still transfer out of
your other classes and
come to ours this week.
(laughter)
If you've changed your mind,
we'd be happy to have you.
- Absolutely. All right.
Thank you very much, I hope
you enjoyed the presentation.
Slides will be
available later on.
(applause)
(suspenseful music)