(applause)
- I am Tim Ball, I
currently am a professor
at Southern Utah University.
Been there almost a year now.
Prior to that, I was,
I'll just give you a little
bit of background on myself
very quickly.
Prior to that, I was
at a private college
in Central New York,
you can probably
just research that
and see what it was.
The incident that I
am talking about today
was at that college,
not the one that
I'm currently at.
And before I was the
college professor type,
out in central New York,
there's the air force
research laboratory,
I was there for quite a while
as their lead researcher
for cyber operations.
And I was recruited
by the air force
while working for the navy
at their naval
undersea warfare center
in information insurance.
So I have not been, and
I'm telling you all this
so that I can just say I
have not been in academia
for very long.
Are there any
academics, academians,
what do you call them?
People like me, here today,
that teach at a college
or a university?
A few.
Any students here today?
Full time,
professional students.
After today, if you decide
that you want to cheat,
you might wanna rethink
your method for cheating.
This is a case
study in cheating.
This is something that
actually happened.
I'll go into what
all of this is.
This is a real case,
this actually did happen.
What I have come to realize
in my short time in academia
is that cheating is
fairly widespread.
It kind of shocked me.
Maybe I was a little
naive going into it,
but it happens often.
Actual events, it
really did happen.
I did change the
names, a lot of stuff,
some of the things you'll
see have been redacted.
I'm not here to embarrass
anybody or anything like that.
I'm just here to
provide information
and some techniques.
They are common tools,
they are common techniques.
I don't know that there's gonna
be anything new here for you
other than it's a new
application of techniques,
or maybe an uncommon
application.
What it is not is
highly technical.
Again, common tools,
common techniques.
You'll probably be familiar
with most of the stuff
I'm gonna present.
It's not personal.
I actually kind of
liked the student.
He was a good kid.
He was not a troublemaker
or anything like that.
So it wasn't personal,
it was all professional,
it was all something
that I just found myself
in the situation I had to do.
And it is not the first
time this has Happened.
Again, this is kind
of a common problem,
it's fairly widespread.
My initial purpose
for doing this
was to provide a tutorial
for other professors.
If you are familiar
with college campuses
and I'm assuming some
of you probably are,
the computer
forensics department
is not really a department.
Similar to a lot of law
enforcement departments,
the computer
forensics department
or branch of law enforcement
often is just one guy.
Or girl, whatever.
One person doing it.
So very, very small,
contained group.
And the rest of the college
campus, or police force,
or whatever, law enforcement,
is usually non-technical people
that sometimes are faced
with having to do something
technical.
And so this was
more of a tutorial
of how to do those
kinds of things.
All right, so the
background of the case.
Student A was caught and
accused of Plagiarism
in a computer forensics class.
This was the third semester
of computer forensics
that this happened in.
That means I had this person
for forensics one,
toe, and three
over the course of
three semesters,
and this happened at the
end of the third semester.
I would've thought that by
now, the students in my class
would've understood
that this kind of thing,
probably you should
not be doing this.
Student A used student B's
work from a previous semester.
It happened to be the
semester right before that.
At this particular college,
I was teaching forensics
one, two, and three
every semester.
There were a lot of
students coming through.
So student A used
student B's work.
Try to keep that straight
as we go through this,
student A and student B.
Student A is the
one that cheated.
Student B was the one that
did the original work.
At this particular college,
they had a grade
of F for cheating,
it actually is called
F for cheating.
It actually shows up
on the transcript,
the official transcript,
as F for cheating.
So if you are employing somebody
and you require transcripts,
take a look at them.
If you see an F for cheating,
that probably would
raise a red flag.
Now, the student can appeal
at the end when they graduate
and get that F for
cheating taken off.
But having talked to
a couple of the provosts
at the colleges,
sometimes they won't do that,
sometimes they'll leave it on
as a message to employers,
might wanna think about
this before you do this.
And of course, student
A denied any wrongdoing.
I would never cheat, I've
never done this before,
I would never do
anything like this.
Adamantly denied any wrongdoing.
And got his parents involved.
That's never a good situation.
Thankfully, I didn't have
to deal with the parents.
I thought for a while
I might have to.
But apparently, the parents
were very, very irate
because their son was supposed
to graduate that semester.
This was a private college,
tuition, kinda high.
Having to add another
semester on there,
I can assume the parents
probably were not very happy.
And as some of you
who are parents,
maybe your kid can do no wrong
and so you're
blaming the school,
you're blaming the professor,
you're blaming whatever,
the parents were not happy.
So let's talk about the case.
The informant,
in a lot of criminal
cases, there is a tip
from some informant.
The informant in
this particular case
was turnitin.com.
If you're not familiar
with turnitin.com,
this is a website
where I can put through
student's papers,
we use it on campus,
you upload all the students'
papers to turnitin.com,
it will return you an
originality report.
The higher the percent, the
more was copied and plagiarized.
So you wanna keep
that percentage low
if you want to fly
under the radar.
This particular one came
back at 30% copied overall.
In my classes, we use a template
for our forensics reports.
So I expect that there's
gonna be some percentage
of similarity between
all students' papers
because it's a template
for the report.
A lot of the
sections are similar.
Some of the wording in
the template is similar.
But the students write
their own reports,
or they're supposed to
write their own reports.
It came back as 18% similar
to a particular student.
Now, when it comes
back from turnitin.com
and says 18% to a student,
it shows that student if
it was one of my students
and I had uploaded that.
Well, I had access to that paper
because that was my student
and it was a
submission in my class.
So when you get to the
higher percentages like that,
it's a, I think in turnitin.com,
that's even a red flag.
Like a literal red
flag on the website
that says hey, you might
wanna look at this.
So I looked at it
seeing as how student B
was in the same class
the previous semester.
Took out the paper, compared
the papers side by side.
So I did my visual inspection,
I've got my evidence
in front of me.
In a lot of the cases
you might encounter,
you wanna do that triage step.
You wanna just look at
see if this is serious,
if this is something
that's worth pursuing,
if it's worth continuing on.
So I typically do
my visual inspection
just to see what's
going on here.
File properties
is the first thing
that I usually check, just
to see what's happening.
Check the file properties,
check some of the wording.
So what turnitin.com does
is it will actually
highlight and flag
the wording that it
found that is similar.
So as I put these
papers side by side,
I saw yeah, some of the
wording is similar in these
and in some cases, it
was exactly the same.
And the screenshots
between the two papers
looked the same.
I require that as my students
are going through
their investigations,
that they are documenting
precisely their procedure
and their process
and their findings,
and then they
provide screenshots
that support these
things that they have
and some of the screenshots
looked very similar,
appeared to actually
be the same.
So I have a case, I have
something that I need to pursue,
I have something that
needs to have a little more
in depth look.
Took a look at the
file properties,
it was created by me,
it was a template that
was passed down to me
from a previous professor.
I modified it, I updated it,
I did some changes to it.
So that's created by me,
I would probably expect that,
I've got the author's
name there crossed off,
but you can see
the modified there,
last modified by student A,
that's to be
expected, that's fine.
Two hour editing time, though,
that's a little suspicious to me
because this was an
extensive investigation
that they had to perform.
And it was given two
weeks before it was due.
So obviously, students
procrastinate,
obviously, they're gonna
wait until the last minute,
but highly unlikely
that they could
complete the investigation
in two hours.
But you have to give the
benefit of the doubt.
So there's really nothing here
in this particular
file properties
that says that this
was plagiarism.
They started it the
day before it was due.
So waited until the last minute.
It's not uncommon
that that happens.
As I said, this has
happened before,
it was in the same course,
in forensics three.
I know he's kind of mesmerizing.
If you stare at him too long,
you probably start to get dizzy.
I had an online version,
this was the first semester
that I'd actually taught
at a college.
This was when I was
adjunct for the college.
I was teaching the same
course, it was forensics three,
it was the online version.
I had a student that had
some family problems,
had some things come up
and needed some extra time,
asked me if they could
turn the assignment in late
because of these family
problems and whatnot,
I don't remember exactly
what the excuse was.
And I said, you know,
being my first time
teaching the class, I was
like yeah sure, whatever,
I don't care.
I since do care a lot.
My assignment policy
has changed quite a bit
since this first semester.
So I get the paper a
couple weeks later.
And I'm reading through it
and I'm having this
sense of deja vu,
like this all sounds
very, very familiar to me.
And part of the assignment
was that they had to
create a text file.
And just put some
random text in it,
it didn't matter what it was,
just put some text in there.
And this particular
student put in the lyrics
to Ice, Ice, Baby.
And then I was like oh, okay,
I know I have read this before.
And this is my first class,
so it had to be in that class
that I read this before.
So I went back and looked at
the other students' papers
that I'd already graded.
And sure enough,
there's a paper in there
from another student
that their text file has the
lyrics to Ice, Ice, Baby.
That's not a common thing,
so yeah, it stuck out.
And pulled up the file
properties of these two
because I had them side by side.
Again, I had both
papers right there,
I don't know what people think.
But I pull them up side by side,
they're almost exactly the
same all the way throughout.
Wording, screenshots,
layout, everything.
And so I pull up
the file properties
and sure enough, created by,
the student from a
couple weeks ago,
last modified by the student
who turned it in late.
So file properties,
yeah, and having that
evidence right there,
it was enough for me,
I was like okay, fine,
F for cheating.
And don't think I throw
out the F for cheating
just like candy.
That's usually in the
very very extreme cases
where something like
this has happened
where they've intentionally
stolen someone else's work
and tried to pass
it off as their own.
Normally, it's just a warning,
like hey, you forgot
to quote this thing,
you've got some text here that
is similar to your friend's.
Great, you're working together,
but just make sure
you're turning in
your own original work
and I'll throw a couple
warnings out to them.
But in cases like this
where it's extreme,
then yeah, highest penalty.
Let's go off of him.
So back to the original one,
oh, and by the way,
on that one too,
when I filled out
the official form
and I have to put
and I have to say
what the violation was
and what the result
of this thing is,
the student was like oh,
I've never cheated in my life
and I would never do
anything like that,
same thing,
and so I just replied
with a screenshot of
the file properties.
And I never heard anything back.
So here we are,
student A, student B.
This is going back
to the original one,
this is the case at hand,
the one that we're
talking about today.
You can see the ones that I've
highlighted there in yellow
are similar, so student
A took some time,
probably about two hours, right,
that was the editing
time on the document,
to go through and change
some of the wording.
But if you look in the red,
programs are developed in
order to make the process
a simpler.
Same errors, same
grammar mistakes.
And then in the yellow again,
just took a little bit of time
to change one or two words,
hoping maybe to bring that
originality score down,
I don't know what
the intent was.
I don't usually tell my
students that I do turnitin.com,
I thought it was
common knowledge.
If it's not, it probably is now,
since this will be posted
and they will all know.
This again, is the
visual inspection,
this is just me going through
and looking at these papers
side by side.
This is the list of figures.
In Microsoft Word, I have
my students do their work
in Microsoft Word, the
template I give them
is a docx file.
Microsoft Word, you know,
if you have the screenshots,
you just right click
the screenshot,
you do add a caption,
it puts the caption in.
And then Microsoft Word
will auto-generate you
a list of figures, table of
contents, things like that.
That's part of the
requirement of this template,
is to auto-generate these lists.
These references.
But if you take a closer
look, figure nine,
if you look at all of them,
I don't know if in the back,
you can actually see them,
they're all the same.
So that means that two students
labeled their screenshots
exactly the same.
That's highly unlikely, right.
And even on figure number nine,
I kind of expanded that one up,
blew it up a little bit
so you could see it there.
Figure nine, check washing
gogle search, or gogle,
whatever that is,
it's misspelled.
Exactly the same
on both of them.
So still doing the
visual inspection,
I'm thinking this
is open and shut.
This is obviously plagiarism.
And then I saw this.
Two students, I am to believe,
took the same screenshot
and highlighted it with
the red squiggly lines
exactly the same.
Third semester forensics.
This person has been in my
class at least three times,
I think I even had
him for four classes.
I don't know, maybe other
professors don't read papers
and just give a grade
and throw it back to them
and say here you go.
This one, you
probably can't see.
But so I put that up there,
student A, student B, again,
the search, they
had to do a search.
The search was performed on
the 24th of October in 2015.
If you remember from
the file properties,
the student started this
paper in March of 2016.
So he has some advanced notice.
He knew what was coming
in this class, I guess,
he got started
early on this thing.
All right, visual inspection.
After that, I'm like okay,
that, this is done, it's over.
And so I gave him
the F for cheating,
I did the whole paperwork thing.
I submitted it as
I was supposed to.
Again, I only do it
in extreme cases.
I usually give them a warning
or something like that.
But the student decided
to appeal this grade,
they decided to appeal
the F for cheating.
Because of the appeal,
and because of the
appeal process,
I needed to have something
a little more solid here.
I needed to do more than
just the visual inspection.
If the student follows
the appeal process
all the way to the end,
then it'll go
before a committee,
and I needed to just
have something that was,
you know, undisputable.
So the tools.
I like 7-zip.
I'm sure you
probably know 7-zip.
I like my tools to be portable,
I like them to be standalone,
I don't like to have
to install stuff.
I like to have my toolbox
on my little thumb drive.
7-zip is great for
that, I love 7-zip.
HxD, same thing, small,
lightweight, hex editor.
Don't have to install it,
just run it from
the executables,
portable, standalone,
and some file hashing.
So those are the
things that I used.
Again, common
techniques, common tools,
things you've probably seen
before many, many times,
probably used many, many times.
For those, maybe
who aren't familiar,
again, the audience was
non-technical people,
for non-technical professors
who probably have to
use something similar.
So I give a little
description of file hashing,
it checks for the
file integrity,
it checks to see if the
file has been changed,
it checks to see if two
files are exactly the same,
if there's any difference,
then that message digest,
that resulting number that's
calculated from the file
would be different.
File hashing, as you know, is
a many to one relationship,
where there could
actually be collisions,
and the collision is when
two files that are different
result in the same hash value.
It's uncommon, I think in
this particular presentation,
I used SHA-1, which
thanks to Google,
we don't use anymore, right?
Or shouldn't.
But at the time, Google
hadn't released their stuff.
SHA-1 was suspected
to be compromised,
but again, for my purposes,
for what I was doing,
it was good enough.
So file hashing, I used,
just to see if I could find
any kind of evidence there
with file hashing and
see what was going on.
All right, so here's
my little demo of HxD
doing a file hash.
Analysis, check sums,
and choose the SHA-1,
and boom, calculates
your check sum.
Fixed length, depending
upon the algorithm you used.
So this is fixed length,
there is only a certain number
of hash values available,
but unlimited number of
files that you can hash.
So again, you get that
many to one relationship.
But for our purposes,
for my purposes,
the SHA-1 was good.
All right, so file hashing.
Again, in another example,
what I was demonstrating
is a small change
to the text in the file.
So the original file
said hello world, period.
The second file, hello
world, exclamation point,
resulted in an entirely
different hash value,
something that you could
easily just look at quickly
and say oh yeah, the files
are completely different
because the hash values
are totally different.
It's not like, off by one
character or one number,
anything like that,
extremely different.
All right, so I
have the two papers,
I have to build this case.
I have both word
docs, they were docx
and docx is a file
container, like a zip file.
So first thing I
did is I used 7-zip
and I extracted the docx files,
I extracted all the information,
all the artifacts, everything,
from the docx files.
I accessed the original images
that were used as screenshots
within the documents,
and I created hashes
of those screenshots
from both papers.
So here we are with 7-zip,
extracting my docx, again,
a tutorial for those who
have maybe never
done this before,
extracting a docx file.
Okay, boom, you can see
now I have a new directory
called student A.
If I go into the documents
and into student A,
open up the Word folder, media,
there's all the screenshots.
So then I could
take the screenshots
and I could hash them.
Now, what I did not do
is I did not use a
command line tool
that would hash the
entire directory,
all the images at the same time.
You can do that, there are
tools that we use in forensics
that do that
automatically for us.
But again, remember
the audience here
was more of a
non-technical audience.
And so I wanted to show a way
that could be done
easily through a more,
I don't wanna say user
friendly interface,
but a more common interface
that they might be used
to doing something with.
So rather than
going command line,
that's why I took
it through the HxD,
so that they actually
had a GUI and a tool
and something that
worked nice for them,
that they didn't have to type
stuff in on a command line,
stuff like that.
All right, so going
back to this one here,
it's obvious by looking at it,
that these two are the same.
But when you take
the hash values,
you can see the
hash values prove
these are the same image
from student A and student B.
All right, final
nail in the coffin.
I give the same investigation
semester to semester.
It changes after a while,
but what I do is each semester,
I change certain things
about the assignment,
so I'll ask different questions,
I'll say something like on
this date, at this time,
how many files were created.
Or give me a regular expression
for finding phone numbers
and how many phone
numbers did you find
on this drive that
we're investigating,
something like that.
So every semester,
there's about four or five
of these things that during the
course of the investigation,
they have to find these
specific things on that drive
during that investigation.
And those change.
And they change for a good
reason, because of this.
Student A answered the questions
from the previous semester.
So again, when confronted
with this, the verdict,
so the student first
went to student affairs,
that's their first stop
if they wanna appeal the grade.
Student affairs guy and I
kind of knew each other.
He called me up on the phone
and he says hey, what's
the story with this one,
he's disputing it.
And all I told him was well,
he's got two screenshots
in his paper,
I didn't go into
the whole thing.
Two screenshots, and the
dates on those screenshots
are from the previous semester,
there's no way
they could be his.
And I gave a little more detail,
some of the wording is
similar, I think I told him,
and he's like oh, okay.
He advised the student
not to pursue this,
the student affairs guy
knew me fairly well.
But the student decided to
appeal further up the chain.
Went to the program director,
I think because the program
director was his advisor,
typically you would go
to the department chair,
that's kind of the
chain of command.
But anyway, he went to
the program director.
Program director took him in
to see the associate dean.
The parents were involved
this whole time, by the way,
so parents were at student
affairs pitching a fit.
Parents were in the
program directors office
having a fit.
I can't testify to that, I
wasn't there, I don't know,
I was just told that they
were very, very upset.
So the associate dean
called me into the office.
So I'm in the office
with the associate dean
with the program director,
the department chair,
who finally got
involved with this,
and I think there
was one other person,
I can't remember who that was.
But the associate dean
also knew me very well,
knew that I don't
just do these things
because I want to
be cruel to anybody.
He says so, what do
you got going on here.
And I said well, and I had
copies of the two papers with me
when I went in.
And I said the papers
are very, very similar,
they're almost exactly the same,
the screenshots are the same.
And he basically took
this other guy's paper
and turned it in as his own.
I didn't even give
him the papers,
I didn't show him the papers,
he was just like
okay, that's fine.
So they denied the
appeal to the student.
Next step for the student
is to go to the provost.
So I get called into
the provost's office,
and if you don't know
what a provost is,
because I really didn't
know what a provost was
until a couple years ago,
the provost is the head
guy over all academics.
So he's like my boss' boss.
And he calls me into his office,
I'm sitting there like in the
principal's office as a kid,
thinking I'm in trouble,
but you know, I'm
not in trouble,
I didn't do anything wrong.
But this kid's parents
are having a cow.
So he calls me in and
he says what's going on.
And I said well, he took
someone else's paper
and turned it in for his own.
And again, I had the papers,
I had all this stuff,
I had this stack,
and he's like okay,
well the student said
that he only took
two screenshots.
I'm like oh, yeah, okay,
because that's what I told
the student affairs guy,
right, was that he only
took those two screenshots,
I didn't say that,
but that's what this student,
he kind of latched onto that,
and he's like no, no, I only
took those two screenshots
that had the wrong date.
I'm like no, it was
everything, I told the provost,
it was everything.
So he says well, there's
two different stories here
so we gotta get
everybody together
and let's, you know, come in
and have a chat about this
and let's talk about it.
So that's when I went
and built the whole case.
When I had to go in
front of the provost
and I had to
confront the student
and I'm thinking in my head
that I'm gonna have to confront
some pretty angry parents too,
that's when I had to
build the whole case.
So I come in to that
meeting, a few days later,
I've got like this
stack of stuff.
And I'm sitting there,
I'm ready to go.
I'm like all right, get
these parents in here,
the student, whatever.
I was ready, I had
everything I needed.
And the student sits down,
the parents didn't come in,
I don't think the
parents were even there.
The student came in, sat down,
the provost says
we're here because there's
two different stories.
He says to the student
you're telling me
that you took two
screenshots and that was it,
but professor Ball is telling me
that it was the whole paper,
what story is the right story.
The student kind of
looks down and he says
the second one.
So finally after all that time,
the truth comes out.
I sat there in that meeting
and didn't say a single word.
I didn't say anything,
the provost laid into him,
like read him the riot act,
of all the time that was wasted
and all these other
resources and everything.
I didn't say anything,
I just sat there
with my stack of papers.
So lesson learned for me
is if this ever comes up again,
just walk in with
a stack of papers.
That's all you need, you don't
need any of the rest of this.
Just a stack of papers.