good afternoon everybody my name is
Brian going to look like introductions
my name is Brian Lawrence I'm the
manager vulnerability research we're
going to be talking today about abusing
adobe Reader is JavaScript API we hope
you enjoy the presentation go today but
kinda quick agenda what we're going to
be talking about First we introduced
ourselves and our research project that
we we did talk about the attack surface
that exists in Adobe readers JavaScript
API ice now kind of areas that most
people have not thought about yet and
we'll talk about how you actually look
for vulnerabilities in this JavaScript
API set what to look for how to find
them and then finally will close with
constructing the exploit and chaining
the vulnerabilities together taxi gain
remote code execution a quick
introduction
my name's Brian Lawrence I run I worked
at HP security research organization and
I'm the manager of vulnerability
research my primary responsibility is
running the zero day initiative which is
the world's largest and diagnostic
bounty program the program has been in
existence for 10 years celebrating our
10 year anniversary and over these last
10 years we've purchased over ten
million dollars worth of vulnerabilities
and exploit information from the
community we've disclosed over 2,000
public public advisories help fix a
large percentage of Internet Explorer's
use after free vulnerabilities Java
sandbox escapes and now Adobe readers
JavaScript vulnerabilities I'm also
responsible for organizing the
ever-popular phone hacking competition
where we asked researchers from around
the world
to come to our contest and try to
exploit the world's hardest attack
surfaces including browsers browser
plug-ins and mobile devices and we've
actually held onto mobile to mobile
version of the contest mobile phone down
here in tokyo over the last two years
have my partner here introduce myself my
name is Abdul I'm a security researcher
working for the CIA which is part of HPC
18 research for now I do a lot of good
cause analysis by hunting and Export
Development I work on my own office in
Canada besides running this year and a
nursing program at running the Punto
contest we do a lot of internal research
and so we are both countries in our own
rights and what we're going to be
talking about today is a set of internal
research that we did what we started in
December 2014 in which you can see on
the screen here are the patched
basically all of the vulnerabilities
that we've discovered to date and in
which ones are patched in which ones are
unpatched they're all that the vendor
waiting to be fixed and in fact last
patch Tuesday Adobe released another
patch for Adobe Reader in 45 of those
vulnerabilities were on this list in the
unpatched section there now fixed and
and that attack surface is gone away
from from attackers over the lifetime of
this research is almost a hundred
zero-day vulnerabilities that we've
discovered in Adobe Reader JavaScript
API and will continue to do research in
this space
so we're gonna be talking about the
attack surface and the vulnerabilities
that exists within them before we get
started we need to come to understand
the prior research that has occurred in
this area
first we'll cover a set of research done
by a researcher at the last name owner
and he was really the first researcher
to highlight the JavaScript API bypass
issue did a presentation discovered a
bug in and got it fixed in 2014 and it
was it was fixed and according to Adobe
this vulnerability could lead to
information disclosure and when Moammar
did his presentation he kind of
highlighted how it worked and provided a
proof of concept which would disclose
information from the attacked at a
computer on the ghetto bleak link there
if you wanted to get an idea of that
type of research the next presentation
will talk about is MWR labs where they
did an assessment of why would a person
bother auditing popular software with
the assumption being that all of the
low-hanging fruit and all of the heart
of vulnerabilities have been discovered
in really why would you spend your time
there and focus elsewhere as a new
researcher and they highlighted the
various tax services that existed in the
product and they hire and one of the
areas that they talked about was the
JavaScript API it's so again this
research which started in December 2014
the primary reason we did this research
is because in the zero day initiative
program we were not really receiving a
lot of vulnerabilities from the
community in Adobe Reader and we were
very interested in this attack surface
because we knew that it was being used
in the wild to to break into
corporations and we wanted to kind of
get an idea of what was going on and we
also are we also wanted to kill as many
of those bugs as possible
and hard in the attack surface so that
the corporation would not be compromised
from these type of Honor bilities this
in internal research really discovered
of various types of bugs and we took a
different approaches on fine I'm looking
for them first we developed a set of
fathers which we ran on the JavaScript
API ice we also did code analysis static
code analysis and looking for
vulnerabilities by hand we also reverse
engineered how the shared memory works
within the software looking for
vulnerabilities and we discovered
basically every different type of an
ability that exists in a piece of
software including memory corruption
vulnerabilities
information disclosure vulnerabilities
use after freeze elevation of privileges
and the most interesting for us was this
JavaScript API restriction bypasses
really something that hadn't been talked
about outside of mourners research and
we wanted to explore that area more and
we're going to cover all of that so what
exactly are the JavaScript API's well
they expect spose functionality to
document authors that allow you to
generate really complex and and that in
interesting documents for the end user
they allow you to interact with
multimedia they allow you to process
complex forms you can do collaboration
with the API's there's really a large
amount of functionality that exists in
these API is available to document
authors and there is security
restrictions in the JavaScript API then
we'll talk about those in a second with
the idea of privilege context and non
privilege context you get really good
understanding of what of it what is
available in the API's by reading the
documentation that is available from
Adobe been a kind of documents
everything that it can do everything
that you can do so let's take a look at
some of the medications they do exist in
the Adobe Reader JavaScript API first
there's this idea of privileged vs non
privileged context and this is defined
in the documentation
and API's that are available and that I
have security restrictions on them
need to be executed in a privileged
context and you can see in in privileged
context I can only be executed in in
several spots in the console when you're
executing a console mode when you're
executing in batch mode and when the
application is that is initializing and
finally you can execute privilege API's
if you are trusting the document
certificate there is a lot of
functionality that is not privileged but
an example of a privileged API is
launched URL which he see on the slide
which allows the doctor and author to
basically pop up a browser and any
address that should they wish and you
have to be in privileged mode to
actually get access to the API itself if
you try to execute the API from what we
call the doc contacts are within a
documents you're going to get a security
warning like this now as a security
researcher or as as an IT as a hacker
you're not going to want to see the
security warning popup on your victim's
machine it's going to clear them in that
there is an attack underway that you're
trying to do something in the document
that is security restricted to the goal
is to make sure that this security
warning doesn't pop up is also the idea
of trusted functions which allow you to
execute privilege methods from 9
privilege context and you can see here
on the code this is an example of a
trusted function and to define a trusted
function you do this with the coat on
strike happened . trusted function and
you can see here here aan verifier
comments is a trusted function because
it has that line in it and then within
that function the code that needs to be
executed in a privileged context is
surrounded by apt up again proved and a
p.m prove and so in this case after
alert is being executed in a privileged
context online 2027
so why would you use the the trusted
functions well if you're trying to
automate some functionality in a PDF and
you want to do a lot of batch processing
you can use these trusted functions to
do that and get access to the privilege
API's that you need for your processing
is also this idea of folder level
scripts which you see on the screen here
and there inside of a full there you can
put these scripts the side of a folder
as you can see on the screen and they're
used to implement functions for
automation purposes
you can use the trusted functions inside
of these for the level scripts and
luckily luckily enough for us
Adobe Reader provides the end-user a set
folder level scripts upon default
installation they're called Jas bytecode
win . been and in this bin file there is
a set of JavaScript API ice they get
loaded up on an application
initialization and they contained
trusted functions which which have
privileged functionality all of this
will become very important for us when
we start doing our vulnerability hunting
all these API's are loaded into root
context upon application start the
exposed to the document authors through
the doc contacts exposed to in to the
doc when it the document is open so we
want to get access to the code that is
in the JSE by told wind-up been so we
can start auditing that code for
vulnerabilities and you can decompile
this code it is this
been filed is actually spider monkey XTR
by code and in this been like I said
there's trusted functions and privileged
code being executed now I'm honor when
he did his research back in 2014 he
published a Decompiler for this been
filed and the code is available as
ghetto blink and you can actually
decompile it and it will spit out a set
of JavaScript that she cannot it by hand
and the output of this D complete
compilation is really messy so you need
to pass it through a beautifying process
so that you can actually audit the code
and what you see on the screen is you
know about 10 lines of the 27,000 lines
that exists in this javascript been file
you can see here you can you can clearly
read that this is the color conversion
function and there's some sort of
processing going on there that you can
then audit for security vulnerabilities
so now we have a really good
understanding of the code that exists
and what we're going to try to find
vulnerabilities in and so we need to
look at how we're going to discover the
vulnerabilities in the spin this code
base the first thing that we need to
think about is when does JavaScript make
implicit method calls that the
application developer may not understand
is happening in this case there are
various three areas in which the code on
the screen
actually makes implicit calls the first
is in the if conditional its argument .
attribute not equal value in this case
we attribute property is actually
calling again or function implicitly and
you can actually redefine the
functionality of this Gator using
javascript to to explain the next place
in this code where an implicit method is
being called is in the apt alert air
this is not a valid value plus argument
the plus argument is actually implicitly
calling a toString function which can be
redefined by the attacker to change the
way the code executes finally there is
the setter method on the argument that
attribute equals different value this is
actually calling an implicit setter
method or mutated method and you can
redefine the way that functionality
works in JavaScript to change the value
that's coming in
leave the value alone he can do whatever
you want using
redefined setter method and so how do
you actually change the way to the code
functions were in JavaScript you can
actually overload the method or property
using underscore underscore defined data
underscore underscore this will allow
you to assign a function to that
property which will do the functionality
that she wanted to say the attacker
wants to implement you can also use
underscore underscore defines setter
underscore underscore with what changed
the mutator of a property and will allow
you to change the functionality and how
that implementation works the next way
to do it is through inheritance using
underscore underscore proto underscore
underscore in this in this case you can
define a new property using an object in
a sign all the object to Prado what you
inherit the methods that inherited
methods and allow you to redefine the
way that a property works on an object
so I'm going to turn it over to him
doing now who's going to explain how to
out of the code to look for
vulnerabilities alright so physical
let's say we compiled the main file and
we have the source code so the next step
is to choose or to find spots where we
should I write so the first thing that
we should look for alcohol and sign that
specific areas that we did you compile
the reason for this is that if we were
able to hijack or gain access to one of
these evolves then we're going to secure
execution inside they would context
which is the first step to achieve the
bypass so you guys can see if we grab
through the Jets we have we have a
couple of sites that we can target
hijacked that caused so the next time we
should look for a privilege black and
just like Brian explained that a
privilege black basically it
it's cool that lies inside begin prayer
band and basically this blog has to be
inside trusted function so when we get a
system we're gonna have to escalate and
escalation should be happening inside a
trusted function that contains alright
so this is one of the codes that we can
we can actually hijack the evals a week
and hijackers you guys can see if parts
date it it takes an argument cold like
entry and this this function is exposed
to us that the user so basically we can
forge long entry and if you see at the
end of this function there's an eval
call that caused the log entry quiet so
basically we can control our country and
forced car at and gain access to and
this basically gives us a system-level
or root context if we were able to do
that we will have to to find a trusted
function without with a privilege black
with something inside of that we can
hijack this is one of the function
inside the compound JavaScript code
basically to trusted function without
with up with a privilege to block it has
three arguments arguments is interesting
which is deceased or CRL basically the C
source URL
passed to the Islamic Center URL
collected is dark center which is inside
the trust trusted black college park so
the plan here is just to hijack or
overload dysfunction with the with a
function that is basically privilege so
in that case we're gonna we gonna be
able to execute a privilege function
from inside the privilege but so is a
clear chain all this together we have to
find an evolve that basically allows us
to gain execution inside the right
contacts and the second one the second
second step is basically find a trusted
function and hijack a method that lies
inside this privilege black and finally
we are to trigger the car so putting
putting this all together this is how it
works basically we called AF price date
and a half price later actually gain and
give us access to that involve
basically will will will excuse exploit
function that exploit function contains
the code that does the privilege
escalation and basically whatever you
did here is defined and you object coca
coca lab and I highly overloaded as Doc
Center URL method and I replace it with
other ones URL URL is basically a
privilege function and then I said the
product of collab to app which is
basically inheriting all of the methods
of the properties and methods of have
been putting in the psych lab and
finally secured see be shared review
security dialogue with that specific
object data created and that would
actually secure an execution inside the
privilege block which is which lies
inside the trusted function and
basically that's how we can escalate
I'm gonna get a video that demonstrates
if if if if anyone wants to execute a
privilege API from inside the normal doc
privileges how it looks like basically
throws a warning because they are you
trying to execute privilege API which
has a potential in this case from inside
the doc religious so just United you
from doing it pops up morning so I'm
gonna show a video that demonstrates the
escalation and like a successful
escalation basically it triggers that at
lunch lol which pounds I E
with whatever target area you are right
so before it before the public for every
patch this blog basically allows it
allowed us to override system objects
like collab spells search all these
system object we're able to override
them whatever objects we want and we can
overload whatever method they contain
with any methods we want to this is
before the patch so after the patch the
the released version called Adobe Reader
Dec and basically what they did is they
denied us or disliked stopped allowing
operating system objects so they kind of
securities objects from being overridden
and from having decent the methods of
these objects being overloaded
a quick recap in order to have a
successful bypass we need that excuse it
inside the root context and then when it
already overloaded function that's being
called from inside a privilege block
which lies inside a trusted function
right so the exploitation by the whole
when one more like baghdad reported this
blog Adobe like flag this magazine
information we could bug and that was
quite interesting for us it was a
challenge we wanted to take this to the
next step which is gaining icy lake or
execution out of this basically if you
wanna do that we have to play by the
rules which is basically using the
JavaScript API that I exposed by a
reader so in fact we needed as we needed
to find an API that would allow us to
write their own discs dumped a file on
disk and we need that API to relax
restrictions basically file types file
contents and stuff like that so what it
is like I went through the whole API and
and search for for all the API and other
communication and social for all the API
allows me to dump files on disk and
basically I tried all of them and I just
failed because basically these API's I
kind of design in a way that wouldn't
allow you to to dump files in certain
directories of certain types so they
really hard and so so we kind of gave up
on the idea gaining I see I think this
and just went back to fighting
corruption basically so so one day I was
I was designing a moderating a model 225
the collab object so I went back to the
documentation just to to read how
collapse
methods and that should be collapse has
basically I don't be documented three
methods in club which are limited so I
was kind of curious and and went back to
the console and and when it would impose
ambassador methods or just to make sure
that everybody has everything documented
so that's what i got I found out that I
don't be that collaboratively has 128
methods so if we do them at its
basically 125 undocumented
methods among these methods there
there's there's a bunch of functions
that start with Uri that are quite
interesting as you guys can see here
there's your I create for the Delete
Folder X files the fire you guys can you
imagine what these guys do so I wasn't
convinced that these AP as well not
really
documented so I went and they researched
one of these API's on Google and a fight
I found only two heads no information
about it
one if one of the heads is just a risk
report from the Australian Government
that just like threat modeling Adobe
Reader and so I'm gonna go through
through these AP I really quick just to
explain the audience they take so the
first one is your I put there are
basically takes two arguments the first
argument is the path of the Father you
wanna dump their to the second argument
or data which is basically the data that
you want to jump to the far side the
file so that it was basically takes one
argument which is the path and that is
the only true you are I create well
they're just as the name implies its
creator for their takes one argument and
I came into the path of the for the day
want to create and you made files is an
API that takes also one argument which
is the path and basically what this
function does is just list the contents
of the file of the folder that he wants
to it just kind of lucky to have you
ever sell API URI delete files as the
name implies it just delete a file it
takes the path of the other guys want to
eat right so now we have a set of API is
that basically allows us to do whatever
we want and described so just an
overview these API's I used
as part of the collaboration feature
that crater exposes which is basically
allows you to share files submitted them
for your views and stuff like that so
one thing one thing coming among these
API's which is the delightful they're
grateful they're put there and this is
it basically these are a privilege EPS
files is is basically an excuse it
without being without being put in this
context we can actually missed whatever
father's identity from the doc context
2011 one thing in common between all
these API's is that they take a path
basically the spare despite is a UNC
power so it has to start with assembly /
/ 45 / / so things that this API is a
lie is that they they don't really it
doesn't they don't they only sanitize
the path so basically you can provide
SMB / last localhost / see and whatever
path you want and that works quite well
it doesn't there's a price they don't
check the file time they actually
jumping to anything like that's
basically what they're gonna put their
specifically in doesn't check for the
data that since i text so if you guys
wanna dump like an exe file idea and
file it doesn't mind you can just do
whatever they want whenever extension
you want we know that we can dump files
on disk using using the URI put the file
contents should be a fan or data object
type but if we think that if we think
about the old data object weather
what they object so basically went back
to documentation and and start looking
for clues about how to create an
ordinary objects and basically we found
nothing but during our testing we found
out that if we pass a no stream object
instead of the only downside basically
it's gonna pass so all three months
after being treated as objects and it
works so I'm a screenshot here I tested
the URI put there are basically the
method and I gave it a path and I gave
it an Austrian object which is created
by the stream from string and I give it
a string so basically just wrote
whatever whatever I gave it in the
father that pointed to it is in this
case in this case is ADA taxed so now we
know that we can actually create or
stream objects using using attachment so
basically if you attach files to PDF so
you can extract the contents from these
attachments and store them in a stream
object so this is this is a good thing
we can use URL put there at the house
that we want on this but how can how can
you actually get RCR do this so
basically there are two matters do that
for the first method which we call it
like the choking method method which is
basically dumping of fire
understand that the profile so basically
you with Newegg need the tiger to log
off and log n to get the code executed
or we would the box or anything like
that and and the second letter is
basically dumping and lol and waiting
for Acrobat to actually load that there
and we're in touch so just to recap
underfunded vulnerable versions of Adobe
basically all the other provisions
vulnerable to this specific attack the
only difference is the rear as a sandbox
limitations or doesn't allow you to
actually done for us and explain this
because I like all the jobs cuts calls
are being routed to the to the broker at
Basildon broker and basically denies
that Acrobat Pro basically it's a little
because they don't have sandbox
technology available on both Windows and
Mac OS X so i didnt includes a version
number is because the first time I don't
get past it we broke the patch the
second time they pass away but the past
and the third time which is which was
last time we brought the patch as well
and they're being fixed right now but
it's a different factors and other times
you just discussed so let's put this all
together basically we have to attach our
payload which is at the end to the PDF
and then create a javascript that will
execute when when the document is open
this javascript should be composed of
code that actually extract the contents
of the of the attachment to attend
Allstream object and use one of our
bypasses to execute your I put there and
done the file on disk and basically just
wait until Acrobat and then we're gonna
have a code execution out of it I'm
going to play a video that demonstrates
the whole team which is basically our
CEO on Acrobat Pro basically the girls
being open the file is being dumped in
the front desk and then we're gonna have
to wait a little bit of our loaded
basically Google account so we changed
we bypassed 22 game code execution and
really which is under MacOS X as well so
this is a video that demonstrates two
bags which is the the bypass and another
bug which is a codex command execution
but it works well this was on the latest
version of Mac OS X reader so this is
the latest version pre-order back then
basically we've got company so so in
order to actually gain I see I do this
we needed to to leverage a couple of the
couple of stuff which is believed with a
bypass system with a trusted function
hijacking of a method call inside the
producer bloc and then changing it with
one of the undocumented API is this
identify landers and GRC out of it so
that we'd like to thank you for having
us out here we hope you enjoy the
presentation we do run the zero day
initiative program it is a bug bounty
program we work with researchers and
vendors around the world to to purchase
their own abilities and work with the
vendors to get them fixed in a
responsible way we're really like I
think everybody could live for having us
out here and open during the
presentation is there any questions
a lot of the research that we do inside
of the zero day initiative program is
actually the core output of this purpose
of this research is filters inside of
the TippingPoint intrusion prevention
system and so all of the vulnerabilities
that you saw earlier in the presentation
Hall hundred of them are being filtered
and detected using the TippingPoint
intrusion prevention system and and in
his ear at a fashion show we're able to
stop the incoming attack because we've
done a set of research on this attack
surface in helping protect the
enterprise prior to the vendor releasing
the patch
yes so in this in our case for the
TippingPoint IPS is a signature-based
detection
fashion shoot at the theatre Academy
must gather myself included