afternoon my mommy's Jackie from the
create universities and then I teaching
the undergraduate and graduate students
in my universe is when I arrived here
I'm so surprised
three times first I'm so surprised
called Blue has so many spouses and in
the second time I'm so surprised because
there are so many ideas I heard up more
than 600 people attend here today so
very congratulation to this papal ticket
booth and I'm so surprised at their
because the step of the color blue
design one hour for my presentations but
unfortunately in my presentation there
are no source code there are no demos
and there are no audio and video clips
just attacks so I'm so worried that I
ripped my presentation will be all you
don't expect so don't blame me too much
about it if we have a special security
situations because the North carriers so
our government promote so many human
resources development problems about a
cybersecurity all the talk about
I wanted covered 7 topics about it first
politic talk about the cyber security
situations of South Korea and after that
I will show you what our government and
private organizations and academia
devote themselves to develop
about the cybersecurity and then I'll
talk about other promotion and education
programs of the South South Korea's let
me introduce myself yes I now
Korea University's exactly Graduate
School of Information Security of Korea
University's our greatest school was
established in 2000 it was first for the
first time is established in the area of
the information security and then our
students in 2009 and 2010 I was serious
won the championship of the DCD still
fresh challenges and also in
2015 in this year our team has a
championship integrated video for 2015
especially in 2012 our unique University
makin new education problems hold as
Department of cyber defense it is fully
supported by military sectors career
University Graduate School of
Information Security in creating the
biggest one in South Korea is a living
institutions in recession education
about cybersecurity we have 17 full-time
processes and to aging processes and
other eight provinces until now more
than 1,000 students created our schools
and they were in everyplace related to
cybersecurity over South Korea and
especially formerly president of our
graduate school called Jonathan Lee was
appointed as president
special adviser for the national
security
yeah I'm lucky man and the decision the
Chinese characters and then I got his
degree about the cryptography manual and
from the 1998 to the 1997 from the 1998
and to the 2004 I walked in the Korea
Internet and the security agencies for
the public sectors in there I was team
leader be a cryptographer technology
team and also the leader of the city
violation hearings in Pisa after leaving
Kisa I walked in this ongoing
universities for seven years something
that is something that university is
famous because of the Samsung because
something is main sponsor its annual
universities so something valuable to
the hazard departmental semiconductors
all of this series of department has a
full scholarship from some songs and
after their graduations they should work
for eight years in some some recordings
from the 2011 I worked in the career
universities and teaching materials
about the information security and also
from 2011
I made by organized hacking group called
the Haro and also I organized and
international security and hacking
conference call this week inside yeah
rowly let me introduce about how far is
established in 2011 and is an acronym of
the Pakistani Union
I think that this group is how is one of
the biggest association of enduring on
the underground hacking groups and
communities can carry this man very dry
very dry the man over there is president
of the Sao Paulo we also have a more
than eight honorable members Blackpool
security company and also the rehash
claimed to be established for offensive
security restrictions and security is
very famous
China information security providing
service and also the school is biggest
biggest online learning site for
elementary and middle school and
high school happy as they make a stop to
learning that encouraged from death and
also we have a famous companies such as
I need cops and AC works in also an HTC
I i heard that Mr her releases its CEO
of the company and I heard that and its
HTC is one of the sponsors of this could
also responsible for the security
analysis and evaluation laps I made
these in 2011
fortunately I have so many Syrians in my
last I have I have a lion and animal
species also my cereal and in Silverdale
history of Amy's home and CEO of the AC
works which is located in the Silicon
Valley of the us- and other good
practice is in my laps and and all of
them is also the Member behind you
yes let's start by talking about the
cyber security situation of South Korea
in career tribal warfare is not a
virtual one is really because north
Korea continues to expand its
cyberwarfare capabilities in every day
so in Korea and I S National
Intelligence Service is known as a
career CIA
Internet traffic for detecting malicious
network activities according to Dan from
2010 to until be 2014
75005 attacks against our country our
government announced tap North Korea
Times billions of cyberattacks against
our government and private corporations
of South Korea
especially five years ago when she was
hit by a computer virus that took over
20,000 comparison had dammit at banks
and a television stations and so our
government company handed bat north
Korea has a total of 6807 soldiers among
damn 1700 are dispersed and five
thousand and one hundred members are
supporting members
to narrow the gap between the North
Korea and South Korea our government
have been devoting themselves to raise
more security expert
let's not talk about the South Korean
government efforts to narrow the gap
between North Korea and South Korea have
a major government bodies related to
cybersecurity they important one is who
have national security office is harbor
of the South Korea and chief of the
peace organizations is equivalent to the
minister in rank
they overseas or the government
diplomatic and security policies and
legally time
another important part of our government
is and I i National Intelligence Service
is known as a career CIA exactly and
Cesc national cybersecurity centers on
the NIS is an important one and css3
National Cyber Security Centre of NIS
has a central point is a central point
of government for monitoring and
preventing cyber attacks in public
sectors and sometimes they cooperate
with the public sectors and military
sectors showed information and and co-op
for preventing several texts and so on
and also has a solid National Security
Research Institute as government
affiliated agencies once and I make some
security policies for government sectors
tan and assault a quick technical
support
for the private sector's we have we have
a Ministry of Science ICP and future
planning on the IP there are two
agencies the first one is Lisa Korea
internet and security agencies once I
miss IP makeup artist than kiss our
technical support and also there is
another agency called a tree is another
18 Dec is kind of R&D Institute the
difference between the case our NXT is
that actually a more focused on the
development of the fundamental security
technology career we have a city this
walk for the protection of citizens
personal informations
we have four more government bodies and
I Ministry of the Interior
walking for the e-government system of
the period and accuracy and FSS is walk
for the financial sectors also we have a
ministry with your friends and we have a
subcommand Cyber Command bees launched
maybe 2010 depending on the type of
attacks from North Korea as purely for
the exists for the investigation of PSI
per crime
yes and then let's talk about the
nonprofit organizations we have so many
private managed organisations related
with cybersecurity but the most
important one is why I see this means
the Korean city of information security
and cryptology it was established in
1994 promoting the academic mister she's
like I i CEO of Japan they host several
international economic conference the
famous among them the famous win either
I see I see skis I think focuses on the
new policy and research focuses on the
system and network security and also we
have a PCR hey I is that is
representative body for the warden 157
secured companies inside the period we
have more than one hundred and fifty
security companies on terror 2012
to the many things for promoting their
interest of the information security
industry South Korea
concert means the constitution of the
computer emergency response teams it was
established in 1996
d'amato of the Second City's top I will
protect my informations by myself
the company members of the country for
sharing the cyberthreat information is
and it's time to respond against these
dumb as a box office of South Korea and
also we have many nonprofit
organizations but the important one is a
hollow talk about the school education
program of South Korea's or talk about
the university and college education
problems
the underground on the religious schools
we have thirty-six Department relatively
the cybersecurity and also in the
Graduate School so we have a 32 the
number of that these increases increase
in every year
University symbol university established
the first cybersecurity undergraduate
problem in South Korea and after top it
has been growing quickly every Muslim
University of some kind of a joint
educational problems with the cigarette
companies most of them have a full most
of the students of that joint problem
has a full scholarship of guaranteed
employment that means that after the
graduations they should walk that
supported companies
and also we have colleagues we have
eight colleges related information
security that difference between the
University problem and it and college
program University program has 84 Yukos
but college has adjust to your costs
year 2012 is very special in 2012
government was inspired by his rivals
target problem and made Department of
cyber defense under the Korea University
is a joint educational program with
their Korean army exactly cyber comment
mysterious of that department has a full
scholarship and after their graduations
they should walk the walk in the
military sectors for seven years as a
senior lieutenant Korea top one
percenters hearings in the national
college entrance exam can have other
missions
introduced about Israel's I talking
programs popular means the best of the
best in hebrew in 1979
Styles P target program to train the
nation's most promising high school
graduates for developing
high-technology weapons they spend three
years in sturdy and should have walked
for sixty years in the military service
our program Department of cyber depends
defensive career he's worth inspired by
his target problem of Israel and also I
was serious
can get the financial support for
starter after day their obligations
deals with many aspects of information
security especially we teaching we teach
these theories about the patriotism and
strong work ethics because he's like
double ax this world
in 2015 this year the team called a
tough call their first prize it is
comprised of a series from department of
some cyber defense and three members
from the korea-based korea-based
security companies and other two members
is came from Korean students who studies
in the you s
besides regular school education
programs we also have not regulate case
of problems we have to kind of
non-regulated vision problems the first
one is government to even try by the
kitchen problems and the other one is a
private company driven education
problems again the government even
education programs is divided by two the
first one is education and training
problem
public officers and the other one is for
the non public offices for ordinary
citizens
and also we have a private company
driven secretive occasion problems until
2014 there are 25 private cybersecurity
training problems inside himself curry
public driven programs for public office
the first one is a system is managed by
and as all and it's all as I said before
and it's all these affiliate the agency
under the National Intelligence Service
of Korea and another one is it was
managed and organized by physically
internet and security agencies this is
allocated invasion and then this is
located in it so
and also we have a government driven
education programs for non ops
non-public office the first one is the
first one is occasional problem
managed by kieso 2013 and it aims at
raising very highly skilled cyber
security experts until 2017 our
government plan to produce 5,000
government certified experts
we also the GOP program this is one of
the best one in career is the best and
it is organized by
ITRI plea means the Korea Information
Technology Li Technology Research
Institute
special point of view POV problem is
that it has very strong
mounting problems they has a mentoring
programs to collect very skillful all
the hackers with young one most famous
actress in korea like a beast and
service and all of them
mantle of the pupae problem
was once entering into the beauty
program muslims terrence Cody
eight-month costs in Bab program has a
pic of form of survival programs so the
final 62 days really get around $70,000
for each person
I talked about the typical in case of a
typical among 13 members and members
came from UB students or mental
also government many to be online
learning site about the information
security every year our government
spends money to use the IIT least search
capabilities of University of career
during 2002 the 2014 our government
spent four hundred and fifteen billion
Korea one of it-i capabilities of
university in this item problems there
are three or four four centers for
centers there are three or four slot
we also have so many cops
school there are lots of information
security class and also in from the 2006
and Psyche have been encouraging and
supporting security costs eight
universities until 2014 45 cops are
selected has supported by money became
intense on some very famous at the world
class at Korea University and go on at
Christ and passed him and also we have
heard so many fucking petitions
conferences maybe Golden Pond Hockey
countries was how in career for years we
have three international international
hacking conferences depressed when you
step inside and the security code again
in the third one EPC and we have a
dumbass conferences and a white hat
hacker contest and discount and equally
each side is managed by the by how do
and our university and college is hosted
by the Korean security company called so
for him and also pues si was organized
by a Chinese company and also issued a
check on is made by he saw and white a
packet contest is managed by Ministry of
Defence and also the National
Intelligence Service and is supported by
the financial sectors and so on
begins at 2011 it was the by hacking
communities Haru and the careerist
increase calm and kiss her acct ravinus
are pre-qualified for the constitution
and from 2015 inside began contest for
the first time in korea we call it then
as the bug contest to be
and the other one is cokie DC's first
international hacking countries Imperial
and also the corrugated serious are
pre-qualified for the end of call
and the other one is a check on this
email is mainly managed by his heart
disease August one but domestic
probably activated in information
security country in the station and
Human Resources play a key role in cyber
security especially our current cyber
security situations pressure to invest
more and more in cyber security areas
our program also have some problems we
should move from quantity of growth
tutti qualitative crew you think we
should think about the right of the
hackers after the graduations all of the
all of the students graduate our problem
and get the real good job like doctors
and lawyers and so on and also we should
change the education of growth we should
change the educational goals from the
information security to the information
assurance
for example yes yes government have some
special educational program called as I
E P that means that National Information
Assurance education and training program
this is a couple of the certificate the
education problem of college of the
University of the U S B
criterias of yes government can use
government give them the search came in
this case we cannot find award
information security is that we can't
find a water information assurance is
not information security education
problem is Information Assurance
education problems
the late of the nineteen nineties
Department of Defense of you use the
term information assurance
information assurance
with so many aspects like a security and
safety and the reliability now available
attention in ICT period not always
secretly but also has packed like safety
reliability and also available
becomes more and more important in this
case ie information assurance with all
of this aspect
their own should be safe from the
Packers and from the errors and from the
digested and so on so we should change
our focus from the information
securities into the information
assurance we need to do this we should
have every with all the experts in other
areas of the comparisons
so every time I said to my series you
should become a martial art players
start yes likely yes the
yeah it's all thanks all of you for your
attention and interest if you have any
issues I do my best
why do even though they have they have
not not its infrastructure in January
why north korea yeah used by my career
army and government I thought it came to
have came to have such competence in
cyber attack are you human
why North Korea government support
raising hackers yea and yea though I
wonder why they have competence in
cybersecurity compared with other
developed country country north Korea
has no comparison no internet yes yes
yes I put to talk about these and what
some people asked about the same thing
I the dependence on the high-technology
the South Korea has a big dependencies
on the cyberinfrastructure we have so
many internet banking systems and
e-government systems and so on but north
Korea does not depend on the internet
much so they can attack so many points
of southern South Korea but we cannot
attack back because there are no second
period and then there is no internet and
furthermore most of hackers from north
korea are located in Europe or China is
doing so because of the North Korea
government support so many hackers
because the dead that's very practical
practical practical solutions for
fighting against the South Korea and
your second question is that there are
no computers Tennessee North Korea but
how they teaching about the happenings
to be very people you're right I heard
bout
there are so many good pictures from the
Europe and China zone so they teach them
about the information security and
hacking their song and also there is a
report that analyzed the computational
complexities of North career in that
report the Arthur pointed out North
Korea as as as an alternative you know
that India is very strong for the
software technologies North Korea is
normally nominated as alternate even its
ok im gonna go through my sympathies
your car
sorry no offense but I'd like to know
why do you think
Korea is the most active country in Asia
I think that one of activists coach
that situation
yeah it is very important that we should
expand job opportunities
good job opportunities for trade hackers
but in case of Korea there are very few
global security companies so our
government try to make some security
space 3 Department inside of the global
company like as Hong Kong and a
gentleman and then probably be some
amenities between the small companies in
the POWs scary so how so how to yank
companies so it's much better to have
some solace special security department
in the Indus corporate government and
motivated Korean companies to have those
security space vehicle department so
because the company is also need two
more cost money but that's very
difficult so to the best of my knowledge
we don't have clear solutions about it
just sayin say it's a game to the global
companies but but nowadays
nowadays Samsung makes them
I think that Samsung has some plan to
make big decisions related to be the
city really bad people will will retain
control all of the part of the Samsung I
heard they were similar they must got
doctor I just haven't smoked question
about the education here to do you think
in your opinions for cybersecurity
education and general education
university to think any difference
between the sides
record precious yeah but I think that is
saying I think the then when we make
Department of cyber defense we combined
to cart comes to put one thing is from
the computer science and European is
from the information security so in
everything in our universities muslims
tutors should finish should cap one
hundred and thirty-five credit but
Department of cyber defense W patient
finish it the more than 160 170 credit
because we combined the essential
something from the computer science and
information security so you mean
students you should be equipment more
demands knowledge and the MoMA practice
no I think that basic understanding
about the basic technology in their
damage is very important but most of
young hackers tend to just learn about
the hacking tools and I saw on making
sure have to preside over the year
general neurology different view because
sometimes we maybe try to happen and
specific attack but in general view
maybe it'll be good defense so sometimes
students they have some turkey arrested
about that we say more but in case you
know case we cannot reach about the
domain bathroom knowledge is because we
cannot see the detailed data about it K
should belong about it after their
graduations like an encounter with a
medical factors so I think that in the
education program about the information
security it is very important to relax
to make some relation with the
internship respective companies
ok I got it thank you thank you very
much
those took a tour of the white hocker so
in case of Japan I think the white
hocker the security engineer is kind of
volunteer because they count how many
saudis so but in case of security I
think the money is very important topic
so how is seen South Korea very good
very good factors also serve South Korea
now there is a very money
salary is very important point when take
a job but we sure as to our South that
they hockey's becomes an office in good
university we shoot
considerable p on other opportunities
for some reason there is someone I think
so
ok