ladies and gentlemen
here
and I'm excited to share with my team
has done this is my first time in Japan
and am very excited to be here let me
introduce myself my name is Bob national
men and I work for Intel Corporation in
the United States my team is going
advanced countermeasures intrusion and
response we deal with the advanced
adversary of the target Intel and my
specific areas of focus on trade
intelligence and data analytics today I
will be talking about thread actors and
how we can use funny hashing techniques
to cluster minorities by the Trek actor
who created them in a way this
presentation is about the journey of my
teen when we were trying to solve the
critical challenge in deciphering
malware by Andys in a short amount of
time before we continue I will give you
a few disclaimers research India
presented here on my own and do not
represent intel and the other one is
just a long form legally saying no
computer system can be absolutely secure
just into lawyers I write this is the
agenda that were gonna work on today but
I'll give you some background on white
can be valuable to focus on trade actors
to improve incident response how we can
help us improve the process and the
defensive stance of an organization and
we will talk about what we can do what
we want to focus on my mind at ease and
tried actors we will look at some
algorithms that can be used to connect
minorities and we will see how we can
get some data and ground troops to death
those methods I'll show you the result
the day God and found the clusters that
we found and finally we conclude with
the takeaways in future direction so I'm
gonna talk a fair bit about trend actors
today and referred to apt research that
has been done
done by security companies leg McAfee of
course keep in mind that etcetera but a
lot of my peers in the incident response
community don't believe in the
importance of identifying trend actors
according to them the only important
thing is detection and eviction I would
like to disagree with them when we talk
about attribution we're not heading to
law enforcement style identification
what we're talking about creating
intelligence around actor profiles we
want to identify the motive of an
adversary we want to identify the tools
than the commonly used availability of
that they go after what example one
particular actor group might have to
focus on MS Word or internet exploded
related vulnerabilities whereas another
actor might focus on PDF and flash
exploits so this kind of information can
help us identify what are the specific
research that the activist doing and the
final response accordingly such
information can also help us make
strategic investments in our own defense
what are the sort of product we want to
install in our environment and when do
we want to invest in our research and
finally it can help us refine I didn't
respond let me let me share a little bit
about how we can do that how can knowing
the origins of the militias binary give
you an advantage in the incident
response process what is the value of
connecting on my 99 bad actor in
connecting a binding to an actor give
you an advantage in your response
process yet first if we can find
minorities in our environment that
connected to a thread group that we've
previously look bad then we can apply
our existing knowledge about the
motivations and capability of adversity
but I response but example if I know
that a particular tobacco is likely to
find a fishing message to steal
credentials
and then attacks the mail so vote than
15 feet away from that attack I know
where to look for next and secondly if
we can connect the different malware by
no means found in the environment to
think that after the nineteen billion a
complete picture of a concerted attack
against my organization instead of just
seemed random isolated infections so how
can we make those connections best that
is the question that we were trying to
answer tonight own team and automation
with a big factor in this and you all
know reversing is a very time-consuming
and tedious process and in the short
amount of time that is available for
responding to an incident detailed
reverse engineering is not always
possible so what we wanted to do was
build a database of APT deleted by
native related actor that we have
analyzed in the past and then have a
short guide new minority to those
methods we also wanted to collaborate
with industry friends and peers so that
they could we could use the same metric
when talking to each other and having
conversations such as have you seen this
adversity on this mining before and can
you share information with us about it
so I first candidate in such an
algorithm was the impact of them into
the pretty simple algorithm it is just
calculate the md5 hash of the import
address table after P E minor if it was
proposed by us- company called mandiant
in 2014 and the premise of that threat
groups like apt one they use the same
tools and environments to build their
militias mind at ease so that is a
software development team almost that
sitting there and building on this
malicious code and they end up using the
same compilers the same libraries etc
the import address table can be
indicative of the binary having
originated from the same threat actor
and quick checks with this message heard
and it seemed to have relations and a
lot of false positives so I decided to
look outside of that mattered under
algorithms that have been traditionally
used to measure court similarity this
group of technique is quite funny
hashing and I looked at two specific
algorithms and steve is commonly used in
forensic applications it measures the
similarity between two files instead of
just creating one half of the entire
file it breaks the file into smaller
chunks each piece and then create the
combined hash of the whole file and then
similarity can be calculated by
comparing each of the smaller chunks
between two files in fact there was some
interesting research done by an
organization called shadow so when it
was found that finally have that had a
high similarity scored using excess deep
we're likely from the same family so
limited that we looked at was St hash in
this was proposed by a researcher
capacity to serve in 2010 it uses
probabilistic feature extraction extract
features they don't occur randomly it
has been put them in a Bloom filter
which is another probabilistically the
structure to compare the similarity
between two files the Hamming distance
between two computers is calculated so
the idea behind that is that if the
files are similar in a statistically
significant way then they were probably
created by the same threat after each
treatment holds they calculate semantics
in a very different way in past years of
the quality of the other to use
similarity distance to get to be any
involvement could have walked away in
connecting apt miners to each other but
we didn't know which and to find that
out we had two major problems
the first one was there where can we get
a day decide significant data set of
binary of related to apt campaigns as
you all know companies are hesitant to
share this data because of privacy and
legal concerns but it also makes it
difficult for researchers to get this
data and run algorithms on so that was a
foot problem and the second problem was
that if we do get a native of
non-trivial say how do we have hundreds
on mine it is then we have about 5,000
Art Basel Miami is to check and we can't
manually go through all of this data
manually classify each of the
correlations as a positive or negative
to conduct any research on it so this is
what we tackle these problems the first
one of gathering the data we collected
all the apt white papers that were
created by various researchers from
January to March 2015 we got $0.25
research people as in we used text
analysis techniques to extract oil hash
things mentioned in those papers really
created that can extract I receive from
several different from different file
formats and that's good hopefully you
guys do find so we had only five and we
downloaded everything that had greater
than 10% maliciousness score from
vitals.com is a popular website that has
a huge database of militias and
suspicious files so now we had to do to
be related to busty beauty campaign
through testing methods on and since we
know which research paper each binary
had come from we knew which actor that
was connected with my family which
campaign etcetera
so what we did we had these minorities
we calculated the tree similarity hashes
and then we use some Python to connect
to make all possible connections it
might hurt cluster in the binary
differently and the next step was to
judge which connections were true and
which connections before we do that
here's what we did each hash with
extracted from one or more white papers
and eat white paper talks about a mile a
malicious actor Mel at Hamleys campaign
etcetera
so we manually analyze this data from
white papers and created a dictionary
out of them if the correlation binary of
shared an actor campaign or malware
family the correlation was judged as
true for instance if we know that to my
knees were used for use by the film
actor at some point then we can say that
they're connected and the coalition was
judged to be a true positive this graph
plots the recall and precision of the
connections are made by each method of
the percentage of true positives that
was found by each met code and we can
see its new house which is the blue
column that had the highest recoil at
ninety percent and impact which is the
red column had the lowest recoil at 25%
precision which is which is the
autograph that is the percentage of
correlations of true positives vs false
positive if his team had perfect
precision a hundred percent and St has
had near perfect precision with only
three false positives let us look at the
results from each individual method but
I'll show you what we got from in
patches this is the score distribution
of the impassioned heard since import
hashes use equality of you can see only
one score bar 800 we can see they regard
about 580 correlations from this
mattered and only four hundred and eight
were true the 2012 high fidelity by
which I mean that the bindings that had
the same impact work very closely
connected they were the female version
of the similar just different samples
some of the other things we looked at
was whether this method could connect
mine it is used in the same campaign
used by the female actor in different
campaigns the impasse had two
correlations of this time we also asked
if this method can connect binaries that
are different versions of the same lol
compassionate goodnight and we aren't
inclined any connections whereby nearly
that good news by the same actor in
different parts of the kill chain what
connected by this method so some of the
criteria we had been evacuations and
you'll see that the other matters did a
little bit better than the impassioned
echoed these clusters made by this
method
this is a force directed graph made
using a software co going to be treated
Jess each point is a single malware
finally and they are color coded by the
research paper from which they were
extracted this leptin let us get a
visual image of the connections made by
amp ashes we can see here that the
connections are pretty sparse six
clusters with more than seven wineries
and there were several false positives
those are the the clusters with red legs
let me show you these clusters in detail
on the left in blue we have four samples
of Comrade this was a remote
administration tool that was used by the
Tory attack group in cyber espionage
campaign against the government entities
in Europe Middle East and the us-
research has shown that the smell it has
been used since 2008 in different forms
it was first known as agent not be easy
and comrade and now it has this same
code base has evolved into a street kid
the family discussed in this specific
last overall version 1.5 of Comrade and
they were all compiled on the 25th of
March 2008 and all the fort Campbell's
of this particular malware that would
indicate effects were in this cluster
and under different versions of Comrade
that will preserve president the data
said and the phone different clusters
using the compassionate own so while
this method can connect minor these data
from the same version it can connect
across the oceans
and this is a limitation in the incident
response process so if I get a new
mining and I want to see if this is a
new version of the malware that I'm
already feeling that this method won't
be able to help me right we see the
large red cluster which is a group of
samples of my work out we plot the
sample had the timestamp of $50 2013 and
this was used as a first day to drop by
the Walkabout that group would also
linked together by the impressions
we have two cases where import hashes
matched by nearly across campaign the
founder of the left are both comrade one
of them was used by the water pump group
and the other one is from the toilet
campaign on the right we have samples of
the Commonwealth which is an
intermediate droplet one of the samples
with a used in the project Cobra and the
other one is from the carbon analysis of
false positives that were found by the
impassioned heard all of the one hundred
and seventy-two false-positive these two
clusters in the damp stopped last only
have nine it is from six different
campaigns including operation desert
Falcon the inception apt framework and
attacks on the Tibetan activist and a
few others between all of these campaign
there is no commonly nor Attribution no
common malware family used and the
samples were from different parts of the
kitchen as well so somehow they all
shared think import hash which is a
false positive in the lower class till
we can see samples from two different
actors one-third of minorities was used
as a credential steal it and dropped by
operation added Viper and on attack from
the israeli government and then import
ashes that connected to an attack on the
Syrian government one possible reason
for these false positives can be Packers
Packers are programs that are used by a
malicious actors to evade antivirus
detection that the signature based in
freeport hash method looks only at the
import able it is possible that it can
be misled by applications using the same
factor we will notice that other methods
don't have the struck back we got from
steep this is the score distribution we
can see that we got 856 good relations
which is almost twice as much as what we
got from impact and there were no
false-positive so that's pretty good we
found one correlation connecting
binaries used by the same actor in
different campaigns and there were
several instances of correlation
between minor versions of the same hour
and there were no good relations where
this method could connect minorities
used across parts of the calgene so we
see that it is deep short a definite
improvement over the impassioned at home
but it has some downside from the
perspective of wanting to create a
database of previously analyzed apt
minor Eve and compelling new ones with
this method the impression that is
relatively easy because you only need to
compare our search for the MB five
string of the impact to a database on
the other hand with SSD you have to run
the distance function between every two
pairs of files to determine whether you
have seen this file or something similar
in the past and this can have a
computational overhead so this might not
be a problem for different organizations
depending on your infrastructure but
this is a drawback of this method for
the graph the overall connections made
by the compassionate heard we can see
several large clusters let me show you
some in detail I wanna point in the
large cluster and the bottom that's in
blue that consists of samples of Comrade
which we had mentioned earlier was used
by the toilet actors with the
impassioned heard we saw small clusters
of the smell with each cluster
containing only the same version of
technology we have a giant cluster of
different across different versions here
we have sixteen different varieties of
different versions of the comrade
compiled over a period of three years
connected together by the food court
similarity
incident responded looking for
information about an unknown binding if
steve is more likely to be able to tell
you which malware or which passed sample
is your new sample connected to
somewhat correlations made by the St
Medford as you can see the cluster that
significantly bigger which means that
your chances of being able to get
information about a new binary I hired
the clusters and green are sampled of a
back door that was used in operation
desert Falcon that was researched by
Kaspersky there were 680 correlations
related to this matter that was found in
our dataset and the average score was
25.13 and at the bottom we have three
minor is connected together these were
different versions of the carbonyl our
that were used in project Cobra and the
watermark campaign this was an example
of SSDs being able to make connections
between minorities used by the famous
actor in different campaigns and
mentioned there were no false positives
that were found by a steep
bahash that the final method this is the
score distribution for St hash this is
the method that give maximum
correlations about 1,400 and had only
three false-positive
basically we found that threshold at 10
so all the connections with a score of
less than 10 were disregarded this
method found connections between binary
is used in different campaigns by the
same actor it was able to find
connections between different versions
of the same away and it was able to
connect my money is used in different
parts of the kill chain on the flip side
it has the same drawback as a fifty if
we want to create a database of known by
now leads and compared a new one against
that we have to calculate the distance
between every pedophiles additionally if
this team generate the hash which is no
longer than in defining how she just
loved limited-length
St hash generate some stores doom
figures which are significantly longer
their length is typically about two to
three percent of the input file that can
again be a drawback depending on the
infrastructure that's the organizer
haitian season two clusters that were
found you think if the ash we can feel
bad that we don't sit and have a little
connections leaving the customers that I
found most interesting that was created
using esli eshe the larger red cluster
contains of twenty different samples of
Baroda through cared for by the span of
three months in 2013 and the second
cluster on the right that's really nice
the samples info booth at the drop of
the stage 1 stage do and the injected
library of the Cobra system described to
be used by the toilet actors and the
sample the red and those used by the
carbon tool used by the Whataburger
attackers there have been some research
that suggests that Cobra and Carmen are
actually just one of our framework with
various plugins that can be used to
generate by Moody's for different parts
of the killing four different parts of
the attack and the Etihad method with
able to identify enough for two
melodically between those finally that
have different functions to link them to
each other so in the incident response
process that can be a very useful to
have and this was done by the only
people in the investigation to build a
better time line of an incident
leaving the false positives that were
found in the SSE has never heard one
comment back those used in operation
desert Falcon to the scan box tool that
was used in the anthem attacks and the
other one is another binder from the
anthem attack that got into the car been
a key bTW there is no known link between
these two minor leaguers for this is
just a false positive so we looked at
the results of the evaluation and the
clusters generated from each method for
what do their conclusion I started this
discussion with high-level strategic
question about why we want to connect
minorities detractors and then we did a
deep dive into the technical methods now
let me come back up again the goal of
this research was not merely to find
which method is best for connecting
wineries what we really want to do it
engineer systems and algorithms to do
this for us we want to be able to
visualize the actions of an adversary
and thereby simplify the process of
investigations and incident response the
stock is really about automation we want
to create a lookup table for the two
that bad guys use a big push is to set
up such systems group constantly realize
they're told they create new versions of
the malware that have used in the past
in fact there was an excellent people by
fire I talked about how eleven different
targeted campaigns had used towards
creating my by one thing the group of
torment so-called can be automatically
can be an excellent way to connect those
two attackers and lastly it is important
to know your adversary if you know that
you know where to focus our intelligence
effort you can monitor for all data
about their tools and tactics you can
learn about the types of vulnerability
of the go after and that can help you
make strategic investments about the
defense of it open
elation and not just to chase the next
infection that is all I have for you I
would like to thank my colleagues Jeff
and Chris for guiding me in making this
presentation and I would like to thank
all security officials who do apt
related research particularly kidding
bundle of networks with the maintainer
for apt notes and lastly I would like to
thank my love story that have made their
data available free of charge to
security features my email address and
Twitter handle it up there if you want
to share ideas comments thoughts in the
future and that I open up your questions
mundhanai you need to do is to invest
that are targeted at kmart.com I gotta
say I gotta get this study must I do to
question the first you mention and you
use a cheeky man where you were like I
want to know if this matter can be
applied to other ways as well and the
second question is I think three message
you mentioned in this stock only applied
to state that they are static ways to
correlate anywhere but we know that they
are some where who retain show code
which can be abused skated easy so
regarding this kind of malware do you
have other method to Coronation the
first one first
you asked if this these matters will
also be similarly applicable to non
educated binaries and while I have not
done the data analysis behind that my
estimate would be that would be true
research done by shadows over which did
say which which limited the SST method
specifically and it's that bad if to
remind me of highschool internet
esteemed then they are likely from the
same ballot so yeah some of these
methods might help coordinate based on
mallet family for different first crime
readily to mind you and your second
question was if there is a show called
or some other well something that we
cannot statically analyzed do you've met
her they look into bite pattern of
the file that is covered in in the case
of an investigation on an incident that
is life so if we can if you paying that
those types of connectors have a bite
pattern which in judging the familiarity
of which will be helped with Danielle we
can use these methods but that also in a
limited sense but for the second time I
mean those this show called me know
where they are they can they can be
easily upgraded the same poem called in
for example just acts or or something
like that though I don't think this will
weigh on this matter is always so the
opposition party is valid for all
different types of minorities if a
particular credit a codified stay with a
new method of application something
custom perhaps or encryption then none
of these methods will work in that case
and that holds for smaller files as well
anytime any other type button because
their fight back and we'll get up get
down and then these methods in that case
thank you gotta see myself everyday this
month
get there so that she could you call you
wouldn't be that if you do not want your
ID
you're trying to differentiate between
militias have been much higher than what
we found with it because here we have
more than 10 percent so if you want to
apply this method heard in India life
one would have to have some checkpoint
or some heuristic the judge that the
file is militias and then these methods
can be used to cluster either by malware
family or by AP writer dr. simply to use
this method for judging malicious files
versus good Windows files would result
in high false-positive did I answer your
question
through the vast majority of the door of
the difference between if we could be if
we can do that then this would start
acting like another antivirus product
and that's not what we're trying to do
here with a look at the same as you are
talking about anyone else do you want to
convert a pretty but I was not it didn't
give a damn I must say nothing
thank you for your issue thank you for
sharing I just happened
simple question if I were an attacker
and I would like to reuse Michael the to
any suggestions about how to record this
season
thank you a lot of this research is
based on the fact that apt trade actors
that often companies and their dead leg
enterprises and because they don't want
to reinvest the time that they have
spent in building one piece of code and
that is why the continued modifying it
and creating different versions because
that that's a hard job to create good
rootkits and that is what we're playing
on if put instance one apt group had a
lot of resources and they decided to
scrap their old code base and start a
new the bike pattern similarity with
keys to exist and these methods would
fail these methods are not doing a
dynamic analysis of the functions or the
actions taken by the binary on hosts on
the network they are literally analyzing
the bike back on and those rely on the
same code base being used again and
again though if you if you were an
attack on you wanted to work around this
you just have to you would have to
create your audio drop it from scratch
okay thank you I set up here I was
really scared