hmm
good afternoon everyone welcome back
last day of hope i hope you're all
enjoying it everyone having a good time
still
all right are you ready for another
great talk
all right so a couple quick notes
closing ceremonies at six o'clock
tonight in this venue it will be
simulcast in the dac 206 which is on the
second floor instead of a little theater
so if there's not room here go down the
second floor go to 206 and there you can
see the simulcast
uh
if you have any feedback for the con for
the conference please reach out to us at
feedback hope.net and leave any comments
criticisms ideas whatever you have for
us stay hydrated
dorm room checkout for those of you who
are staying in the dorms is it 8 p.m
tonight if you're staying through today
and 2 p.m tomorrow if you're staying
through tomorrow so with that we'll pass
you off for the next talk revolution
during disintegration lessons from a
brief history of yugoslav computing by
vlado vincey
[Applause]
thank you so much and uh thank you so
much for coming everyone
and i want to just give a huge shout out
to the organizers this has been a
fantastic conference and it's so good to
be back here
so
there's been
sort of a
series of news stories over the last
couple of years
describing how tech companies from
certain countries are getting banned
from operating in other ones
the famous one being huawei the chinese
telecommunications giant
that's been banned in the u.s parts of
europe
and ever since the russian invasion of
ukraine on february 24th
a huge number of tech companies have
stopped doing business in russia as well
partially this has been as part of
larger sanctions but tech in particular
has been in the focus as
it really is an integral part of so many
industries
that even
you know
manufacturers of cars
depend on so much that the russian car
industry has been largely hit because
they can no longer get electronics to
put in their cars
considering the world that we lived in
for the last 30 or so years where
free trade and communications
dominated most of the world these types
of stories are somewhat new to us but
they're not really new
in the wider history following the end
of world war ii and through the end of
the cold war um we lived in a block
system with really
two main warring sides that
had very little
technical and economic corporation
during this period
the
dynamics that were common at this time
were
soon forgotten as we as we moved into
the 90s but um we we might be getting
back um to to some of those and what
i've decided to do today is
tell you a story about a country that um
was
somewhere in between during this cold
war period and that country is
yugoslavia
we're going to take a look at
specific technological developments in
this country that no longer exists and
then we're going to try to take some
lessons for a potential new world that
we're moving into that might have
a little bit more barriers um and
borders and limitations than we've
gotten used to in the last 30 years
but before i get into that i'm going to
quickly introduce myself and tell you
why i'm telling you about all of this so
this is me my name is vlado i'm a tech
worker i live here in new york
i don't live in midtown manhattan i like
this view though
i live in brooklyn
however i i grew up in a small country
uh on the adriatic coast um that country
is now known for uh people going on
their on their vacations there it's
called croatia
however uh up until um 31 or so years it
was called yugoslavia
and
the story of the yugoslav state is
really complicated so i'm going to try
to give you basic facts because i
presume a lot of you don't remember it
and some of you may not even know what
it was
i'm gonna try to do this in three
minutes or less i could probably not do
it in three days or 30 days or less but
just bear with me
yugoslavia was founded after world war
one technically but we're going to
ignore the state that existed there in
the
uh brief interwar period and we're going
to focus on the state it was founded
after
the anti-fascist liberation movement of
yugoslavia liberated the country after
world war ii
this movement was led by yugoslav
communists so they also founded a
socialist state
following the war
this state was aligned with the ussr for
a very brief period about three years
and then um tito the leader of
yugoslavia um got into a fight with
stalin and we broke off from them um i
don't know if this story in the tweet
above is true but that's basically the
sentiment that the yugoslavs had
following this split
this was quite significant
because at the time
the world was getting increasingly
polarized and especially so in europe
where essentially every other socialist
country
fell under the iron curtain whereas
on the western side of the continent
most countries aligned with the united
states and nato there of course were
some notable neutral ones uh marked and
gray over here but yugoslavia as a
socialist but not soviet aligned country
was quite a bit of an aberration there
following the split in 1948
yugoslavia focused on developing its own
mode of socialism that very soon
started to revolve around this idea of
self-management where instead of
kind of doing top-down central control
that was very common in the ussr
they would basically develop work
theories of how workers could take
active
decision-making roles within
organizations and companies there's of
course a lot of debate how successful
that was but it did made it quite
different than its peer
eastern bloc countries
additionally
starting in the early 50s collaboration
with the united states and western
europe
was rising both in terms of trade
academia even military aid but
yugoslavia never aligned itself with the
west
instead it sort of tried to exploit this
middle ground
and it did so quite well
in the
late 50s early 60s it founded the
non-aligned movement
along with
egypt and india and a whole bunch of
other countries most of which were
recently independent post-colonial
states
and
it really tried to use this space to
establish itself on the world stage but
also
to use it for its own internal
development
similarly how both nato and the warsaw
pact were not just military alliances
but also economic blocks where the
countries leading them were using
this environment for trade and
influence onto others so did yugoslavia
so during this period a lot of the
yugoslav economy is focused on exporting
the
engineering and other types of expertise
into what we now refer to as the global
south at that time they called it the
third world and it wasn't the derogatory
term
the third world at a time was the world
that wasn't
nato and it wasn't the warsaw pact it
was everybody else and there was
actually quite a lot of everybody else
now uh yugoslavia was was quite
successful in this but um it always had
its eyes to the west
in the late 80s you may have
seen the infamous hugo car which was um
the final attempt to break into the
united states with
yugoslavia's car industry this did not
work so well
but all of this of course
ends in war
the scope of this talk
is not to talk about the war that
followed
in the early 90s but
you will see
as we get to the later phases of the 80s
the um
the fear of conflict starts to influence
everything including technology so just
keep that in mind
the
war in yugoslavia was a tragedy and
it always um the the moments that i'm
describing here with tensions in trade
with with blocks
there's always this this fear of war and
with us living through a time of war
right now i just want us to keep that in
mind as we think about
computers
let's talk about computers
i'm going to
tell you three distinct stories
the first going to be about enterprise
which is sort of a weird term um but
it's basically going to be a story about
uh what was happening in the actual
computer industry in this country the
second one is going to be about normal
people i'm going to tell you a
fascinating story about a diy
microcomputer that was developed by a
young engineer essentially as a solution
to bring microcomputers to yugoslavs who
couldn't get them
and finally i'm going to tell you a
little bit about networks and that's a
story where those two
earlier stories converge
the first story is about iskra delta
that i'm going to call a yugoslav
startup although that is probably not
the right and
precise term but it's a company that i
think
really includes a lot of these
interesting dynamics that develop in a
country that is at the same time
both sort of closed and limited in its
access to what is happening
in america where the computing
revolution is really centered
but it has quite enough access so that
it can break through and basically
develop its own version
of silicon valley culture
but before that let's look at the first
yugoslav computer so this is the cr10
mainframe from 1960. this is a vacuum
tube mainframe that was developed
completely internally and domestically
in yugoslavia
it was finished in 1960 and was used for
about 10 years in different types of
institutions
this one is from the tanya news agency
but
it got some work in the military and
generally big big yugoslav companies
however
even though in that early phase there
were big ambitions to develop a domestic
computing industry and mind you in 1960
not a lot of countries had something
called a computing industry
there's this thing called cocom
the cocom was the coordinating committee
for multilateral export controls a body
of the us government founded soon after
world war ii essentially to
establish a mechanism to enforce the
types of controls that we're talking
about here so uh when you have a world
with an increasing number of countries
that are
dividing themselves in blocks
an institution like this will help you
basically prioritize what you are
allowed to sell to whom and under what
conditions
it was used to essentially limit export
to of course the eastern bloc but also a
lot of the third uh party countries and
um yugoslavia found itself in kind of a
good position here as a third country
cooperation country meaning that while
it wasn't a member of kokom most members
were nato states and a couple of
neutral ones like switzerland
it was a good enough position that most
american companies by the late 60s
didn't really have a problem setting up
shop and of course they did
the uh
big blue was one of the first but others
followed as well honeywell dec they were
all there and
they kind of did what they do else
everywhere else
they just take over the internal market
so the
domestic cucus of mainframe industry was
essentially dead um by the early to mid
70s companies were increasingly using
western-made computers
these companies would have
their representatives their teams that
would install them support them and for
the most part it was it was it was
really led from the outside in
however
a company that had a slightly different
approach was digital equipment
corporation
and
what they did was start forming very
close partnerships
with certain folks in the country
particularly in the
western republic of yugoslavia slovenia
and
a lot of locals from yugoslavia ended up
going to the u.s to get trained
to support install
and work on these computers
and they were having such a great time
and such a good collaboration
that they soon started doing their own
work
initially under the umbrella of an old
uh of an older bigger company called
electro techno founding their digital
department
and
soon splitting into their own as delta
and finally merging with another company
called iskra into iska delta computers
all of these are just sort of
not particularly important details but
what this meant was that suddenly in the
late 70s you have a domestic company
that really grew
within a couple of years
into not only a
partner of a big american corporation
but essentially something resembling an
oem
and this partnership
was not about cloning or copying
equipment
it was about working under license from
an american corporation to develop
products for the domestic and also
export market
by the early 80s there are
yugoslav versions of the pdp-11
there's two of them one of them being
the pmp-11 that was developed at the
institution of stefan and the delta 800.
so
these are essentially pdp-11 compatibles
developed in partnership
with an american company
there's uh licensing agreements and you
know it's just business as usual but not
something you would expect
with a socialist country
they also expand into microcomputers um
the two notable examples being the
treeglove or the trident which was a
really interesting machine
built to support two different cpus
depending on what you needed it also had
this adorable
all-in-one
case that also had a special box in the
rear for pencils so that you could you
know access your important tools when
you're working on your computer
unfortunately or fortunately the trend
of multi-cpu as needed trend did not
necessarily continue the way the
slovenian experts imagined it but
another more traditional one was the
delta partner
which was sort of your more typical
early 80s
micro running on a z80
the final accomplishment of iskar delta
was getting a huge contract
in china in the mar in the mid 1980s and
just to contextualize this this is a
period when china is really only opening
up and in terms of technological
development they're really trying to
catch up and they're trying to catch up
very quickly
they somehow stumble upon iskra delta at
the um in from information technology
fair in zagreb and they end up hiring
escrow delta for this huge project
essentially connecting 10 of their
largest cities into a network that will
be used by the yugoslav
pardon me chinese police
this is a
sort of an unprecedented project for a
company of this scale
the distances between chinese cities are
larger than all of yugoslavia is
but they actually managed to do it
there's a lot of stories about the
details of how they managed to get the
licensing to actually operate in the
public people's republic of china
but
this is sort of the pinnacle of the
yugos of ict
in this non-aligned period so they are
using this advantage of
having a privileged relationship with
the united states of working closely
with an american corporation and then
they're basically selling this expertise
and
building networks and computing
environments sort of on the other side
by this point they're also doing some of
those things in other eastern bloc
countries since this whole tito stalin
very um very hard and intense split of
course has gotten a little less intense
um in the 30 years since it happened
so this is a story about what was
happening at the higher level uh what
was it like for people
i'm gonna tell you this story through
this amazing history of galaxia because
unfortunately in the early 80s
things were not so great for everyday
yugoslavs
even though
we were accustomed to a higher level
a higher standard of living than our
peers in the eastern bloc
even though we had the right to travel
we had passports which could freely
travel to the west without visas
a lot of products that folks were really
used to in western europe and of course
in america were just not available
to yugoslavs due to restrictive import
policies some of which were there to
protect the domestic industry
interestingly even though there was this
very developed enterprise computing
industry there was really no
microcomputing industry so
in the early 1980s yugoslavs really
could not buy any computers at home
so what'd they do they would travel to
trieste
in italy
this is the famous ponterosso square
where for 30 or so years you could find
yugoslavs from all over the country
buying electronics vcrs computers
levi's jeans
anything that there wasn't available at
home
the
trick about this was they couldn't
legally bring them home
so um this is this is a comic strip from
from the period um someone trying to
import a zx spectrum
the import limitation at the time was 50
deutsche marks and not even the zx
spectrum could be bought for
50 deutsche marks
so
even as late as 1983
yugoslavs couldn't technically buy
microcomputers and
this wasn't great a lot of them wanted
them but the only way to do them was you
either had to have someone living abroad
who would bring it to you or you would
go to trieste and then you would smuggle
one a lot of people smuggled them
however come the summer of 1983
a wonderful story happens so
the two gentlemen over here are voya
antonic and dan ristanovic
voya was a young engineer
taking a holiday on the adriatic coast
kind of liking that photo that i showed
earlier
and of course he didn't want to spend
time on the beach he was hanging out at
the hotel
scribbling something in his notebook and
designing a microcomputer
on a piece of paper
meanwhile de andrestanovic was a young
magazine editor journalist
living in belgrade and working on a
special edition of the popular science
magazine galaxy or galaxy
that would focus solely on computers
considering that folks couldn't get
computers
freely they wanted to bring the story of
computers to them through this magazine
now a mutual friend introduced them and
they soon realized
they should collaborate on this
so
voya and dan
spend the next
five to six months
and of course a lot of other people
helping them
working on a special edition of this
magazine called computers in your home
now what's the deal with the computers
in your home
a magazine not not a big deal
it wasn't just a magazine it was
basically a large media project
that would
introduce not just computers but also
instructions and education for folks to
build their own computer at home if they
couldn't buy one legally if they would
have to smuggle it from abroad
why not give them a way to obtain all
the necessary parts legally because the
computer was designed to be just cheap
enough that you can import parts
yourself and assemble it
and then make it yourself
so here's what that computer looked like
in terms of configuration
not unusual for
actually a little unusual for the mid
80s not unusual for the late 70s early
early 80s and what you can notice here
is it's
definitely a little underpowered but the
reason why it is underpowered is because
it's designed precisely so
that when you order all of your parts
you need to get from the outside they're
coming just under that 50 deutsche mark
mark
this works really well
folks got schematics they get all
necessary instructions
they start making them at home
yova is the man on the right in this
picture
he and the team around the magazine
spend the next year
basically supporting thousands of young
mostly teenage yugoslavs
desperately waiting for their part so
they can assemble their computers
and
they
they really do more
for
the development of
of computing for regular folks than
anyone else really up until that period
some records show that uh
80 to 90 000
issues of this magazine were sold and
that at least 10 000 people ended up
building a machine
so for a small country like yugoslavia
this was this was unprecedented thanks
to this one
project
computers are suddenly and seemingly
everywhere so
this is what this magazine looks like
this little piece of paper contains
everything necessary for you to build
your own computer so what did i do when
the pandemic hit and i was stuck at home
i built one
thank you
[Applause]
and i built it
really mostly following the instructions
in this magazine which is which is
fascinating to me because folks were
doing this 40 years ago i had the whole
of the internet and human knowledge at
my at my fingertips they had the
magazine but they they still attempted
and succeeded in doing it
you can also do it yourself and i just
want to give a shout out to north starch
press
because
down on the lower level they have this
wonderful poc or gtfo volume 2 book
where there's a full translation in
english with all the instructions and
you can do it today
you can also get the pcb today
and voya
40 years later
is still updating the instructions now
on hackaday
so check out the references at the end
of the presentation if you want to build
one
however
this project was so successful
that by the end of 1984
the law that limited the importer of
computers from abroad
is expressly changed and everybody is
just getting their zx spectrums and some
commodore 64s
so this is
very indicative of this dynamic where
the limitations imposed on the folks and
the limitations that really caused this
burst of creativity and ultimately
success
they sort of end up defeating themselves
in that by being so successful
the limitations are then taken away
and none of none of that domestic
ingenuity is really necessary i think
that is quite a quite an interesting
bittersweet a little bit beautiful
dynamic
um it also results in some bizarre
instances so
even though the um
limitations for folks to import this and
buy this stuff themselves were dropped
yugoslav schools were still under a
mandate to purchase domestically
produced computers
so what did one company do
they put in zx spectrums into a keyboard
case by make and ended up making a
really good keyboard for the zx spectrum
but essentially selling a domestic
computer that's made in the uk
now um this is not a clone um yugoslavs
could get by this point real zx spectrum
so
sinclair was just selling them the
boards and they were putting them in
this in this case
what happens
with the networks at the same time
we've looked at what was happening at a
high level in enterprise we looked at
what happened with regular folks by the
mid 1980s computers are becoming
sort of
easy enough to access for folks like you
and me
but
even though we can now access computers
and even though we have
a computing industry
sophisticated enough to develop a
large-scale network in china what's
happening in our own country
let's take a look at what's happening in
in europe and the us at the same time
they are trying to figure out what
they're going to go with tcpip is
gaining traction in the u.s the
europeans are really stuck on the isi
model and x-25
really through the uh 1980s
and the yugoslavs well
we're just trying to figure things out
very slowly
in the 70s
they work on the sntij or the system now
technology information yugoslavia
which is basically a way to
connect libraries it doesn't really go
very far
through the 80s academic institutions
and
mind you academic institutions from
different parts of the country are
trying different things
but they're connecting to different
types of european networks some examples
are the euro net uh eu net er e a r n
that one's actually quite interesting
because it actually provides a
connection to the american bit net which
can then provide you sort of a
connection to the wider internet
this is based on ibm technology
in the very late 80s there's also unit
and
unac which eventually end up being the
projects that finally connect the
yugoslavs to the internet literally as
the country falls apart
in 1991 this is what the networked world
looked like the countries in purple are
directly connected to the internet and
then the countries in red which
yugoslavia is one of
sort of have a connection to the
internet through these x25 or
proprietary networks
like the ibm v-net um basically most of
the world is not online in a sense that
we know it today
but an interesting project that emerges
in the early 80s
is the upak or the yugoslav packet
switching network
which develops as this sort of very
top-down bureaucratic project
being developed by the yugoslav
post telegraph and telephone service
um it sort of struggles along and it
mainly struggles along because um just
like everything else in yugoslavia at
the time and this is definitely sort of
announcing some things to come
every republic is developing this
project independently
so
out of the six republics
each one sort of goes through their own
process of identifying the vendor hiring
them developing this network and upak
really struggles along the project
starts in 1983. uh it's operational in
slovenia by 86 croatia by the 87 serbia
by 89
most of the rest of the country is never
connected but here you can see you know
in the initial 1983 plans they were
supposed to cover the whole country with
this x-25 network uh trunks were 64
kilobits
it wasn't a fast network but it was a
packet switching network and upex sort
of just stays in the background as a
project nobody's actually actively using
it almost until the very end
and the very end comes around 89.90
the woman in the picture is borca yerman
blasic
she is a researcher in slovenia who
was working
in the late 80s
basically doing academic research on
networks and she went to a conference in
santa fe probably 88
and
she has this quote she said
i saw how terribly deprived we were in
comparison to others and this is a
reference to her seeing her colleagues
and even her european colleagues
whip out their luggable computers and
connect to their emails
from the united states meanwhile since
her university and her sort of very
limited email really had no connections
to the outside um she could just sort of
sit there and and
and wait
she comes home and she registers the dot
y u domain uh this is in 1989 um and
this is probably the 20th or so
uh country level top level domain um she
registered sit with ayanna and she
starts working on
finally connecting our country to the
wider internet
this is a dramatic process that
is really happening
through
the moments that the country is rapidly
disintegrating
there's uh
basically a number of bureaucratic steps
that need to be taken
and the jurisdictions are starting to
get sort of mixed up between different
republics she is taking planes to
belgrade she's meeting with security
services but you know she's she keeps
this going and of course there's a
number of other colleagues
working on this as well
they get their primary dns server at uc
berkeley
and in late 1990 they make a request for
the first ip range for yugoslavia and
that this is soon delivered
uh meanwhile
the country sort of doesn't even exist
anymore in a full sense there is
basically open revolt
between the republics
um the last congress of the um
yugoslav
communist party is
dissolved as the croatian slovenian
delegates
leave and protest
and
while this is happening they actually
make a connection to the internet they
connect to tcp via x-25 through a node
in vienna
and then the war starts
the
june 25th 1991 proclamation of
independence of slovenia and croatia
prompts a 10-day war in slovenia that
begins on june 27th and one of the first
targets
are the transmitters on the border with
austria
this actually interrupts this internet
connection for the first time it's
eventually repaired and over the next
couple of months there's this sort of
no man's land in terms of the internet
as the countries are basically becoming
independent
but the infrastructure is still
interconnected
recently there was a fantastic talk at
the
ripe ncc southeast europe conference in
ljubljana where
yelena chosich and soboda markovic
presented this graph really showing the
relationship between assignment of ip
ranges to what was happening as the
country was disintegrating so
we can kind of see how
slovenia declares independence and ip
range is given to
university of belgrade
unac this project from the 80s that was
supposed to bring the internet to
yugoslavia gets his first subnet in
september 91. mind you at this point war
is actively going on in croatia
croatia then declares independence in
october after a three-month moratorium
and
april 1992 when the war in bosnia starts
is generally used as the point where
this country really and fully no longer
exists and then we can start to see how
additional ip assignments are actually
getting
assigned to individual countries so
in
may of 1992 a first ip range is given to
carnet which becomes the academic
network in croatia
we're not going to talk about this
further because at this point yugoslavia
is no more
i'm going to give you
just a quick little story about what is
happening to everyday folks at this time
so we're going to go back just a couple
of years
all of these
big academic networks are inaccessible
in a similar way that a pdp-11 was
inaccessible and what escrow delta was
doing wasn't necessarily relevant for
everyday folks in their everyday life
but
in the late 80s first bbs's start
appearing
in yugoslavia the most famous of which
is probably the sesame bbs which funnily
enough was founded among others by dan
ristanovich of the retronary vashikuchi
and galaxy of fame so everything sort of
comes together
and
interestingly enough sesame is still
sort of offline except i've been unable
to get credentials for it someone is
running it on a vm
where apparently everything is still
kept
but i was lucky enough to obtain this
instructions manual from
from from the late 80s so every day
yugoslavs do start talking to one
another in the late 80s over bbs's and
they start spin getting spun up around
the country there's probably a couple of
thousand people talking at this time and
they do transcend these republic borders
at a time when politically
these republics that will soon become
independent countries are really
drifting apart
in major and major ways that eventually
end up in war
there are some messages that you can
find online the authenticity of which is
somewhat difficult to confirm that
basically show you the types of
interactions that we're we're sort of
used to seeing nowadays on twitter when
conflict like the war in ukraine happens
where people are arguing about what is
real and what is not and we actually
have examples of that um from 1991 as
the wars in
yugoslavia are just getting started
but there are some positive stories
there too
in the spring of 1992
the
war in slovenia is over the war in
croatia is ongoing the war in bosnia is
just getting started and communication
is becoming increasingly difficult
the phone lines are working only
sometimes other forms of communications
like transportation you can no longer
take the train you can no longer drive
to the countries that are now at war
so
a couple of anti-war groups
get connected to some of these remaining
bbs operators and they organized them
into the zamir transnational network
zamyad meaning for peace
which
gets started essentially as a link
between folks in croatia and serbia
which are now essentially at war so they
can talk to their friends they can
collaborate so that people fighting
against the war can collaborate across
these borders
and
1994 they also make a connection to
sarevo which
at this time is under siege for two
years and communication is increasingly
difficult so they basically provide a
first public link outside this city for
regular citizens and just as a reminder
tens of thousands of people were living
in sarajevo during this siege
and
they also make a connection to the
internet of course so even though folks
are basically talking through what is
by this point an old-school bbs the
communication becomes global and your
messages and emails can get from
occupied sarajevo
to new york or ever anywhere else
within less than 24 hours and this
becomes incredibly important for
basically doing humanitarian work such
as missing person service so you have
hundreds of folks looking for their
loved ones who may have become refugees
themselves and this is a truly important
link
at this time and it really comes back
from that initial hobbyist movement that
originally started by folks trying to
build their own computers folks that
eventually ended up being building their
bbs's and essentially acquiring the
expertise necessary to provide what at
this point
is such an important service
in war
so what are the lessons of all of this
i consider making these types of
comparisons
very complicated
and
not necessarily
simple enough as saying
the sanctions we're seeing right now are
like
the embargoes during the cold war that
is not true
the needs of folks in occupied
territories in ukraine are not the same
as the needs were for folks in these
other wars these wars are not the same
however
i'm going to try to make
a couple of assumptions and a couple of
couple of things that maybe can help us
as we think through this
when we think about sanctions and we
think about limitations on import i
think what we can
surmise from this story of escrow delta
from the story of their business in
china is
technology finds a way and countries
find a way to obtain what they need
that doesn't mean that
sanctions are
always unjust or that you shouldn't do
them
it's just that
it is quite complicated to make them
successful
especially in a world that has different
types of sort of intermediary
relationships and countries that are
sort of in this middle ground status and
i think we're seeing that right now
as a lot of the world
that is not um aligned and allied with
nato directly is sort of taking a middle
ground uh with sanctions on russia
when we look at the story of galaxia i
think
we see how concepts like
open source and hacker culture that have
been associated with
the silicon valley in america for so
long they exist everywhere and under
specific conditions they they really
come out in in really creative and
unique ways and
in a certain way they're no different
regardless of the system that
they got
started and developed in
and lastly by looking at this story
about yugoslav networking but especially
these efforts to connect during the war
and provide valuable services for people
impacted by war
i think there's something important for
us to consider about maintaining
connections with others even during
times of war
this is
hard and emotional especially when we're
dealing with conflicts where we can
clearly identify aggressors
but we have to remember that
not
everyone is responsible and the fact
that someone comes from a country that
may attack another country does not mean
that they are the ones doing it
it's a complicated story
but i hope that some of these examples
are interesting enough for you to
consider them as you as you look at
news as you look at current events as
you think about
what the role of technology can be
moving forward and
how we can all together
use it for good so
thank you so much my
different internet locations are up here
um i have sort of an obsessive number of
twitter threads if that is
um your platform about this and many
other topics and um lastly i'm going to
post this on twitter after after the
talk here is a
sort of a growing bibliography that can
help you get started thank you so much
and i will take any questions you might
have thanks all
all right audio questions we have about
five minutes
we have at least one question from the
matrix chat and excuse me for the
pronunciation greetings from scope j
how did you come across the information
for this talk and is there are there any
interesting media or documentaries you
could point us to
yeah thank you so much for this question
this is actually a great question um
the information for this talk and um
again a lot of this is in here but this
is only a fraction of what i've used um
a lot of this information is very hard
to obtain
the
most of it comes from um materials in
serbo creation or bcs bosnian serbian
creation
um
the
information about yugoslav computing is
mostly limited to folks who are from
that country
and it mostly can be found on obscure
forums facebook groups but there's a
couple of exceptions
so um a good resource to getting started
is the aforementioned
retro vashikuchi magazine which you can
find a copy of in one of these links and
if you don't speak
bosnian serbian creation there's also
this great book by no start press
there's um
a couple of documentaries um most
recently there's been a crowdfunded
documentary about the galaxy computer in
particular
you should just google it galaxy a
documentary there's a great talk at the
um ccc probably 2014 that you can find
on youtube um so it's sort of a mix of
things uh what i've really been trying
to do with my work is uh to expand
access to this by uh almost exclusively
talking tweeting and writing about it in
english so i'm hoping more folks can
access it that way and we can develop
additional interest and perhaps produce
some works
that really summarize this a little bit
better than just sort of like going
through all these loose sources
so you talked about
how yugoslavia was a
importer of western
technology but i'm curious whether much
went to the other direction is in its
status as a sort of intermediary
did
the west try to exfiltrate russian or
eastern bloc tech through yugoslavia
uh that's a great question um to my
knowledge um specifically in the realm
of computing technology that wasn't
actually the case
the primary reason being that yugoslavia
to my knowledge didn't really get
any soviet computing technology for you
know obvious reason that it was really
at that time quite behind
it is possible this happened in some
other areas
the yugoslavs worked extensively in
later years in the eastern bloc
but i'm actually not familiar with any
cases where for example
a soviet computer would get to the
united states through yugoslavia for the
simple fact that almost no soviet
computers would actually get
imported into yugoslavia in the first
place
thank you
yeah thanks for that question
all right any other questions
great thank you so much for the talk
vlado thank you so much everyone
[Applause]
[Music]
so
you