[Music]
uh
all right welcome everyone to our four
o'clock session
just want to remind everyone put your
phones on stun or vibrate
um stay hydrated it's hydrated it's hot
today and i know there's no bottled
water so there's water fountains around
the corner there
again if you have any issues medical or
otherwise look for someone with a radio
or a
a staff shirt
so i have the pleasure of introducing
julia corona and alessandro podoro
and they had the most creative title of
i think that this the whole day today
um
porn flap porn platforms hate them for
exposing their mischief with these two
weird tricks welcome
hello everyone hello
thank you we are alessandra and julia
alessandro is a lawyer i'm a
communication designer and data analyst
and we are part of this european
organization called tracking exposed
who does
algorithmic auditing
algorithm accountability and focus on
digital rights
uh in this talk we will present you our
research on pornhub
and
we also investigate tiktok and youtube
currently
uh so check it out at
tracking.expose
what we do
basically we um
we analyze platforms
uh not people
we want to collect data to understand
the property algorithms uh for public
interest
in this example
we use the
pronoun tracking expose
browser extension
and
the idea is that
platforms can conceptualize
gender
and other social constructs
and can
verify
conceptions about it
and can shape
affect maintain
status quo and general
identities
so why porn and why pournam porn because
we can consider internet as a
pornographic technology
if we think about uh football
or
[Music]
how they are made now to
let's say uh
get your attention visually and uh
stimulate your gaze
why for now for now because it's uh the
first and the biggest uh of the
pornographic platforms uh yet at the
moment
um
it is a platform because first
there is identification of the user
they have content and there is a
standardized
based on popularity and predictability
and they also have
targeted content and ads
third
they have this data porn so they use
their blog year in review
as a
communication strategy and
form of advertising because they claim
this is a transparency
tool but actually they decide what to
tell you and what data they can share
and what data they cannot
so
we know that algorithms are black boxes
and
there is
no knowledge about
how
fair and unbiased algorithm should look
like we don't even know if it is
possible
we know that
automated
surveillance
is something related with the
conservatives
but now
we give it for granted and we just think
that it's biased and there is a
universal truth but
we are not sure about it
and
[Music]
we
cannot think about a different uh word a
different
alternative to this system and to
surveillance capitalism
so what we do
we do scrappyism is web scraping but for
artistic emotional or critical answers
this is what sam lavina says so we find
ourselves in this
we have html websites and pages with
non-structured data all nested around
and we created this extension to extract
parse them and do scraping
then we have a structured json or csv
that we can analyze and compare
to also document what's happening with
the platform
our methodology for this paper was
actually considering
one sexual interest over the three
pernap allows us to have so we can be
interested in girls guys or girls and
guys but then we can
have different gender gender identities
this is all in the
registration process
so there are 10 general identities and
we had
we
decided to focus on 10 accounts
we got like 1 600 on pages and there
were like 46 videos per page but we
understood that unique videos were
far away less
for this study
how does it look like this is one video
one entry for one video on the page so
we have a different metadata
title author name author link and the
size whatever we focused on section name
because we wanted to analyze the home
page from a section point of view
because there were
there are different sections
as you may know
or not i don't know
now i will show you how personalization
can look like from um
from a visualization point of view and
the graphs were made with the open
source tool gefi so check it out and
this is how
content that is not personalized look
like it looks like
we have the 10
triangles here that are
our
our accounts we created
and the videos in the middle so shared
by everyone
and these were
this was the case for hot phone videos
in your country most viewed videos in
your country so a geographical
personalization
uh um our bots were all from the same
country so that's why you see it like
this and recently feature videos
uh as well
but what happens when you
give a look to another section like
recommended category for you there is
different
uh
and it can also not be present for
different gender identities so we just
got it
in six
accounts
and
we can start to see um
that there are
protoclusters
so um some accounts that share a lot of
videos and others that
uh don't
um
in the last and in
the individualizer
personalization
in the recommended for you category so
for you section sorry
we can see two different clusters and
they are really uh well defined so we
found found out that there was a
heteronormative
cluster so male and female together
um in a more standard
cluster because they were they were
sharing like a lot and then there was
another cluster but
always depending on on the
um
on the main one um
there is a
less
heteronormative but puts all together
and is the case of trans men non-binary
same-sex
couples so female so lesbian
and trans woman
the curious thing is that
in the gender normative
we had the
models channel and porn stars
but
in the other we
were not able to find channels and so
production companies there are
uh
for
property uh as well so this uh was a
little bit uh
tricky we don't we still don't know how
to
give a meaning to this
um
but basically our main argument is that
the platform
and the algorithmic suggestions were
fostering a heteronormative perspective
on sexual desire
and
they were typical of a
heterosexual white and demonic
masculinity
so what comes next to this um
we would like to raise awareness about
topics like the gdpr like we are doing
here i don't know uh all the algorithms
uh consent and especially desire
we would like to
hold more the platform accountable for
the lack of transparency
with the respect of the tracking so
we also decided to proceed in a
different way and
to give a better look at
cash and
cookies
and then we would like to do some more
color for
action through our tools
so the next step was actually to create
this
new software called guardoni
because
we
understood that gaining data from
volunteers is great to have an empirical
first
example of what's happening and some
anecdotal evidences
but then to prove them and to say okay
we saw them we need to have a
clean environment and
a sort of a clean setup
even a small browser history can buy us
everything
so what are we now looking for we are
looking for third-party trackers and
how they relate to recommended content
and basically okay porn and how it uh
how it works uh how the rabbit hole can
be
can
make people become more
sadistic or
stuff like that
so this tool is
is available on github and
you can find it
in the methodology
directory
what can it do for us so it's a
laboratory setup
it can help us installing the
the extension on a clean browser because
it's directly installed
initialize a new uh
[Music]
chromium in this case profile
a new user data directory
um it can automatically navigate through
the website and
and gain some tracking data and
screenshots
we can have a look at the
the code it's basically a node library
with javascript extensions
and
the apis are quite
simple you can
launch the browser
wait uh
go to
a precise url take a screenshot and then
close it this is a simple example but an
experiment uh
that we do can be
exactly looking
like this
the experiment is a set of comments
uh we create a json with a list of url
we want to
access and uh for how much time uh if we
want to screenshot it's all defined in a
json you can create it with a
gist on github
and
when you give it to the tuerdo ani
iguadoni automate automatically
navigates through this
comments and instructions
the other thing we are doing is to
collect
the cookies in the local storage local
storage is a cache again
on your browser
it is different from a web storage
of cookies because it's a permanent you
have to uh
the cookies don't expire
so um as you can see we we collect the
cookies but also
we are
creating a sort of white list of
the domain pronable.comcdn.com
so we know it's
it's their cookies and okay but then we
are also extracting the third party
trackers
and um
yeah parse the the domain
so we can know who is
behind this cookies because
in the porn industry
online there was a
bubble and
no one wanted to
advertise on on porn platforms so
basically there is
a different uh
a different
market and a parallel ecosystem
of third-party service providers and
we would like to know more because it
has not been scrutinized yet but by
regulators or
[Music]
research community academics and policy
and
now alessandro will
talk to you more about the legal
perspective perspective
thank you thank you
[Applause]
sorry
okay can you
hear me all right
so yeah uh hello thank you for being
here thank you julia for the
presentation of our tools and the
research we have done with attracting
expos in the past years
so yeah
basically
my role here
role here as as a lawyer is to try and
answer uh to the following question so
how do we get here
how did it happen that
such a huge and invasive
market that deals with an incredibly
sensitive aspect of our culture our
society
how did it happen that this market is
basically growing unregulated
unsupervised
and
sometimes even
just
being a mockery of actually of the
principles that should uh inform the the
the digital sphere
we've seen that uh
especially when we investigated pornhub
we realized that on one end we have a uh
official and formal
statement of acknowledging different
gender orientation different sexual
preferences uh with the nine
possible categories of
of sexual orientation that a user is
allowed to uh
express
to the platform before navigating it but
in fact the algorithm is biased in the
sense that basically gives you either
straight heteronormative
content recommendation or the weird
counter recommendation you know
um is this even legal
how does it work right this is the the
the starting point of what i'd like to
discuss with you today um
and
the answer is not
that simple and this is especially
because of this word that you see right
here this legal vacuum
concept that uh may be not too familiar
for most of you for uh
legal for us legal people dealing with
the digital world it's actually the the
norm it's our everyday life is this a
legal context in which things are not
clear there is no applicable law or in
which some injustice
is uncorrected
this has been for a very long time the
as i said the general norm for the
digital world we are slowly trying to
fill up the void to
put
new solutions new ideas into this vacuum
of course
i can speak for the european
legal
context and many many step forwards have
been done but in the us is the same i
think for instance at all the new acts
that came out in california with the um
california consumer privacy act and the
california privacy rights act if i'm not
mistaken
so yeah
we are slowly and
slowly as a double meaning in this
context because it's the usual slowness
of the legal world and also the
the fact that the digital world is by
nature very very fast compared to the
other things of the world we we see it
every day and and so uh when you think
of the fact for instance uh julia
mentioned gdpr which is the general data
protection regulation in its force in
europe since 2018 well it took 20 years
to to to come up uh with that because
the the law that was existing before
that
was from 1995 and um
and yeah you see
i will talk more about it in the
upcoming slides but i'm what i'm trying
to do here is to give you the the
feeling of
uh the the different uh
uh pace different speed uh that
that you can experience in the digital
world and in the legal world uh compared
so about this legal vacuum legal vacuum
is a
it's a catch-all term we can actually
divide it a little bit more and try to
understand it and understand it a little
bit more of course it's the lack of
norms in general uh it's that's quite
intuitive but um in in this case um we
can think of it at every level every
kind of norm so it can either be actual
law like so
international conventions or national
law you name it uh or also other kind of
rules other kind of norms let's think of
internal policies of these platforms i
mean
maybe we don't even have
to talk about these
problems if only the pornographic
platforms were to have uh
decent policies of content moderation
and that
and protection of personal data of their
users but
here we are so apparently something
didn't work out as planned and um the
problem is that
that's not even the only thing that
we're lacking right here because lack of
concept
is also a huge component of this legal
vacuum
because you see
there is um
so lawmakers are basically people and we
are people too so we can somehow imagine
to be lawmakers ourself and if if we if
we try and imagine ourselves having to
create new rules
for the digital world especially when it
comes to the pornographic uh word
we actually don't have categories we we
we would uh immediately uh
meet a lack of principles um think of
revenge porn uh you might you may have
heard about this this very problematic
practice that is happening the it's the
proper term for it would be
non-disclosure dissemination of intimate
context basically is when
some somebody is sharing the uh a naked
picture of somebody else without uh his
or her them consent their consent and um
it took so long
to the legal community to start
acknowledging the concept of uh actual
actually the intimate material the idea
that a photo a video can actually be not
only just a good that you trade an
exchange an inter source of
entertainment but it can also be a mean
of sexual expression of an individual
and actually sexual expression is
another principle that it's not really
clear in the in the in the legal world
think of uh of that think of the gender
expression i mean it's a huge topic
right now and and
there are
of course uh everybody should have the
freedom to express themselves there is
the right to self-determination that
appears here and there in uh
everywhere
especially in the
western
judicial
cultures but um
we don't really have a legal theory that
encompasses all the aspects of what we
could understand as gender expression
and so this is this makes it even more
difficult and
of course
as if this was not enough already there
is also a serious lack of political will
to tackle these problems to to tackle
the legal vacuum especially in the
pornographic sphere online pornography
but also in the digital world in general
right now this last part that i just
said is changing because of of course
how catchy the the all the digital
topics are but imagine
again put yourself in the lawmakers
dress right in in in their shoes and try
to imagine going to your electoral uh
base to to to do the people that support
you and say that tomorrow you want to
dedicate your work and your time in
protecting the right of i don't know on
online pornography models or uh people
who want to
just access these
porn platforms right it's it's not
exactly the most appealing thing
given also the cultural taboo we will
get back on it very very very soon
[Music]
so
questions like uh
i don't know like
is it convenient for
a political figure to address the kind
of topics can actually be a slippery
slope and at least for sure it's one of
the main problems that is
making the filling up of this vacuum
very very difficult and now uh you see
at the bottom of this slide i i'm
quoting ludwig van der rohe the famous
architect with this very famous sentence
less is more because we may think that
actually um
sorry
we may think that actually
less
rules less norms especially i guess the
most uh libertarians anarchist people in
in the
in the room today may probably agree
with this uh not always too many rules
means less problems
but is it is it is it the case for us
right now
so let's talk about the
the european context again this is
probably a bit far away from i don't
know is there any person from europe or
is there is not from the us in the room
oh okay
okay so um but don't worry american
friends this can actually be a huge an
interesting perspective for you as well
um so um
you see i mentioned gdpr you see it in
the first line general data protection
regulation um this this has been a huge
thing for for us in europe but not only
for us because the gdpr applies to any
subject who is running business in the
eu so even if you're not european
citizen but you want to run business in
eu you still need to uh take care of
this uh
and and be careful uh not to violate
this rule so because the fines are very
very high
and
this rule
this this regulation specifically
as the merit to have introduced a
beautiful concept that
was discussed for a very long time but
it took very long to appear in a legal
text which is the concept of privacy by
design
as opposed to privacy by default so that
at some point um
platforms had to realize that to ensure
privacy of their users would not uh is
was not enough to just promise that they
will do it
it's not enough to just say don't worry
we will take care of it you have to
prove that the design of your platform
the cyber security measures that you put
in place the the the whole architecture
of your algorithms is actually
privacy oriented there was a huge
step forward for the data protection law
community and it only happened
four years ago let's say six because the
regulation was approved in
2016 but uh
still it's i mean computers have been
around for a bit longer than that
um
again going back in time we have the
privacy privacy directory the privacy
and electronic commerce directive that
you see since 2022
that was actually also very important
because it introduced concepts like data
retention uh the the limits to data
retentions and also was one of the first
attempt in europe to uh regulate cookies
that was a it was a huge topic back then
it is still now and also the e-commerce
directive the e-commerce directive as
the merit of introducing one of the
first attempt to categorize digital
platforms in the text of the norm they
are called intermediary service
providers
or isp also called internet service
providers if you like and they
introduced a brilliant idea of dividing
them in three categories three
categories
one
well not that it matters but one is
mere conduit one is a cash provider one
is hosting provider funny thing about
this categorization is that eventually
uh the last one the the hosting provider
category uh have become the the main one
and which is good for for for many
reasons because um
it's actually a gradual uh
increase of norms and regulation coming
from the first one that i mentioned the
mere conduit
going through the cache and then the
hosting provider so hosting providers
have to abide more rules than the others
that i've mentioned and right now maybe
some of you have heard about it uh the
digital service act and the digital
market act in europe these two two
[Music]
new
regulations that are about to be
put in place a couple of years hopefully
we'll also
implement even more this concept so i'm
i'm trying to give you some very basic
uh not even legal tools but just uh
juridical uh
ideas to play with uh
because right now uh we will start now
uh
diving into the any possible legal
solutions or at least a legally informed
perspective to this pornographic uh
word the online pornography where they
were trying to understand a little bit
better so
legally speaking what about porn
platforms
the first sentence that i decided to
mention here in the in the slide is from
potter stewart american uh legal scholar
judge and a lawyer um well this this
sentence is out of context but it was
during the trial he was trying to
express
uh what um what the pornographic content
is what what a paranormal parliamentary
material is i'm sorry for the loss in
translations we are not english native
speakers so sometimes i can get clumsy
anyhow he was talking about this uh
pornographic image and he said i shall
not today attempt further to define the
kind of this kind of materials but i
know when i see it
so you see when he used this sentence
well it was long ago i think in the 60s
or even late 50s anyhow when he used
this sentence um
he gave the perfect example of what's
the difficulty of wanting to talk about
something that we can't even define
and even more than that we don't dare to
define because of the cultural taboo
again we will get to it just trying to
plant a seed right now
[Laughter]
but yeah we still have this problem
nowaday it's it's still a a way to to to
giggle to to to think that it's uh
a bit of a
naughty thing to talk about pornography
right even though it's in the everyday
life of uh the majority of the people we
know especially the younger the the
younger generations
and and we can already see the the the
consequences of that so uh the idea is
to uh
the the the reason why i decided to to
start with this uh uh quote is because i
think that there is a
clear mistake that we should uh surpass
uh we should try to there and define
what we're talking about uh when we talk
about porn
producing selling and possessing porno
is still in legal in many nations
this is funny right because raises a
question when we want to find legal
solutions or any kind of solutions to
the pornographic word we still have to
worry if uh i mean is this a first word
problem
if you allow me this clearly uh joking
expression
um i don't think so
but in a certain sense it is uh for sure
uh when we when we look at the at the at
the
data when we look at the at the map of
the globe we see that uh porno is
illegal in most of the countries that
don't belong to the western bloc the
western quarter of the
of the planet
uh
nevertheless we can't deny that the
industry affects the whole planet
especially considering that many of the
actors
voluntary or involuntary actors that end
up on these platforms come especially
from the other parts of the world so um
so the problem is global but there is
probably a clear power dynamic going on
this is uh
also a way for us to be a bit more aware
of uh the the colony colonial
implications of of yet another part of
the world and not the digital world
and um
there has been a significant effort to
stop child pornography and
non-consensual pornography so the reason
why i mentioned that here in the in the
third point is because um after making
you feel guilty and making you feel a
bit worried probably about how big this
uh this issue is how big the problem
that we're trying to solve is um there
are actually already some very relevant
and actual uh
effective solution in place they are all
very uh
narrow in their focus given the the the
the huge dimension of the problem uh at
the end uh but yet the the they are
they're focused and partial uh to this
specific topic but yet very important i
think as i i was mentioning
non-consensual pornography but child
pornography is also very obvious in
these cases uh of course um it's easier
for a lawmaker to imagine a solution
first off because creativity apparently
they say works better when it's limited
in a specific context and also because
it's not only the sexual expression of
those who make porn porno or
consume porno but it's also
a matter of protecting the rights of
other people that may get hurt in the
transaction in the in in this in this
dynamic so what we can see
we can see a growing effort in
preventing underage users to access
online pornography
this is a this is another thing that uh
for instance right now in the uk
well right now a couple of years back
started maybe a little bit more but also
in other places of the world that's
that's a that's uh that's a topic that
it's interesting because it i mean
of course of course we we we want to to
imagine a a a safer way to to
to protect the the underage the most
sensitive people those who are still
maturing and creating their own their
own sexual uh
persona uh from uh an unlimited and uh
uh reckless access to these sometimes
even uh difficult to to digest to
understand kind of contents but on the
other end think of the solutions that
have come out
uh
when thinking of how to prevent underage
users to access online pornography the
idea of requiring an id when you connect
on the internet
that's that's that's even worse i mean
of course the the the problem of uh
miners watching porns can be very uh
upsetting but we always have to be
careful when we think of solving a
problem not to solve it with an even
bigger problem right because i don't
think that anybody here would be happy
with a
computer that asks you to show your
driver's license before you log into
whatever you want to log into that day
and yeah
an interesting debate has also sparked
over the addictive nature of mainstream
pornography content that's also very
interesting and and recent and again
talking about solutions um
well
imagine a word
where like for cigarettes or well
usually in
i mean
some of these
cigarettes is a good example actually
imagine a word where where you have to
show a banner that says porn is
addictive every time
you access uh
any video or any content that may
involve uh explicit uh display of a
human body it's actually display of
human body uh that that's a that's
another kind of solution that can be
that's that's a word we don't live in
that we can imagine and um
but then again it's uh
it can also be
give specifically when recognizing the
addictive nature of this uh of this kind
of contents it can also be yet another
way to to to create dystopian and creepy
uh solutions think of all those who just
would like to ban pornography all
together from the internet because it's
obscene because it's wrong because
it's not uh
it's not clean it's dirty right and and
so people would just like to suppress
that and think of all the people that
work in the industry and maybe have this
as the only source of income think of
all the people that just like to do it
can we really make that illegal this is
a question that i'm raising because we
will carry it with us to the next part
and the final part of this uh
conversation that we're having today by
the way in case you want to interrupt
ask questions
i don't know raise the point feel free
that there is a microphone over there
you can just raise your hand interrupt
me whenever you want
and just to i was just checking the
bible okay
some open issues
of course there are the the the the
issues that i just described are
actually issues where i could if you
want later on because we don't have time
right now point you some solutions
somewhere in the world where legal
people or lawmakers are trying to tackle
these issues but there are still some
other open issues such as this of course
is not a complete list sex worker and
prostitutes rights
we still have to remember that
again talking about pornhub for instance
it's very recent their decision to
remove from their platforms all the
non-consensual material that was still
there and think of all the people that
ended up without their will because they
were unaware of it or also those who
were forced to end up there what's
what's with these people what what's
with the sex workers
uh of course uh it this is yet another
huge topic uh and we don't we when we
think about the rights of sex workers we
always have to remember in my opinion
that most of them work mainly online
nowaday
what about the privacy both of of these
workers and the users
specifically this topic is uh is very
dear to me
also given the research that we have
conducted with trucking expos that julia
was telling you about earlier on um
[Music]
there is a lot of data going on in this
market i mean
this raises many questions for instance
is uh my search history on a porn
platform
sensitive data
that's that's a question but it sounds
very legal like this i can also rephrase
it in a different way would you share
your search history on your favorite
born platform with the with a friend or
an acquaintance or anybody or would you
actually think that that's um that's
part of your very intimate life i don't
know i'm asking you these questions
because i know the answer actually i
don't think that anybody can know an
answer that fits for
to all but because
we should
start
this conversation
we should try to ask ourselves if we
don't want
other people lawmakers figure powers
power figures to
decide for us we should start asking
ourselves what's the solution that i
would like to see in the world and
what's the role of pornography in our
society that's that's the question
i mean
is it just wrong
is it
is it maybe
natural or i don't know is it a business
that it's still worth preserving i don't
know these are all questions that
we should ask ourselves a little bit
more often i think
uh also because you see when we this is
the final part of the presentation by
the way when we when we think of
solutions when we try to uh harvest
do you want to ask a question at some
point
do you actually know about the
discoverability and retention period
of uh search logs import hubs properties
um i mean i know that they're that it's
written in their privacy policy but
there is no way for us to know actually
what's happening in their company's
server so
i think it's four years
was it the right answer
i don't know
[Laughter]
i mean their transparency report mostly
talks about their reports to the nick mc
and their content moderation policies
and not their privacy policy as far as i
could tell
yeah i'm looking forward to see their
transparency reports especially when the
dsa the digital services act will come
into force because there is an article
that will force uh large online
platforms to make yearly transparency
reports which we which not all of them
do right now
and also not only that they will have to
apply to very strict criteria so it will
not be your own made transparency report
will be much more well full of stuff
hopefully we will see
i don't know if i answer to your
question i have a larger question i i
fail to understand what your problem is
with pornhub's recommendation system
and
you know what the expectations of
pornhub users are about
what
kinds of videos are suggested to them
you know i can i built recommender
systems and i can understand how they
might be better at doing the
heteronormative
recommendations and categorization than
doing the kinky side of the the house
because there's much less history much
less tagging much less
crowdsourced information and metadata
about that kind of content so it
wouldn't be that easy for them to
categorize
people's kinks you know especially when
they're
you know they might cluster in strange
you know less traditional ways
so i'm not sure what your problem was
with them to actually go back to the
initial talk i mean i don't know if
julia wants to pick this one yeah but
it's not just our problem i mean since
the 80s feminism
has
if you could take your mask off it might
be better
i forgot about that
um i mean it's not just
our problem with that
it's a feminist problem since the 80s
there was
there were there were on pornography so
the idea that
these recommender systems can now
radicalize people and
[Music]
has i mean if you
see that
facebook
or instagram can
shape your reality
why
this platform shouldn't
shape your sexuality because a lot of
videos in pornhub are abused
are just uh i mean it is paid paid a
price film filmed the prostitution
so
i'm sorry
what were your findings that people's
sexuality was being steered in a way
that was inappropriate or wrong we are
not at that point yet because
there is a lot of work that has to be
done first and to
identify how this can
affect the population
as
[Music]
a sociological
problem
i mean uh can't be
technical
the solution
of a social problem no don't you again
if i may step in um
beside the fact that the that
you you you're perfectly described in
your own questions uh question the the
the main problem of it right you said we
have less less data for this uh outs
outskirt fringe of uh sexualities and
gender orientation so our algorithms
cannot be very uh
like as as precise as for the let's say
main
mainstream basic sexual orientations
right and um
wouldn't it be already enough to ask
ourselves if we uh are fine with making
these kind of algorithms and
just to answer the question of we don't
have evidences of the actual change of
sexual orientation or
any other empirical uh
measurement of the impact of this
content recommendation but if we want to
keep it a bit more simple it's quite
intuitive
we can imagine that
especially a young
person that is accessing a platform
without knowing how the algorithm works
without knowing how the content is
recommended to the to them well the the
these these young people will just you
know consume what they see and what they
have and what if the algorithm has
decided that you are heterosexual or
homosexual when actually inside of you
you are still
forming a consciousness about it what's
going to happen with you and we can we
we could still say that it's
their fault because they decided to do
that they decided to access the platform
they decided to expose themselves to
this influence of the algorithm
we could say that or we could not and
realize that this is still part
of of a societal problem this is still
part of something that we should not
turn our head away from
it sounds like no algorithm can do a
satisfactory job given the absence of
uh expectations and norms so i'm not
sure
i i think that many people would agree
with you i i i for one vote and i don't
know
could it be a reason to to to re imagine
these algorithms to i don't know
introduce a bit more of privacy by
design or uh i don't know respect by
design i don't know i i don't know if i
managed to answer your questions but we
can continue afterwards thank you so uh
that
dovetails nicely into this online
question traditionally the porn industry
has been the technology leader pushing
vhs over betamax dvd protocol selection
streaming technologies do you see them
leading in solving
this uh bias algorithm i'm sorry i i
didn't quite grasp the the
so
the porn technology porn industry has
traditionally been the leader in
technology selection
for social for for our media formats um
do you see them
being a leader in technology in building
and solving this uh bias issue
that was actually part of the final
slides that i wanted to to show
i i will try to answer this question
also i don't know i don't know how much
time web left five minutes okay let's
let's try
um
so yeah because the question was about
solutions and my final slides also so
what a nice coincidence
um as
as you see here um possible approaches
possible solutions i think that there
are at least three one is policy one is
advocacy and one is litigation that i
kept for last um
so policy uh currently most of the power
and agency over this field is in the
ends of the private sector so in this
case the the the platforms itself
and um
there are many projects to try and offer
alternatives to mainstream online
pornography embedding values like
feminism not conformity of gender sex
workers empowerment and more
these are all uh
interesting projects uh still niche
still uh
smaller than the mainstream platforms
and um and the problem is that the
public of or at least for what we have
seen is that the public opinion does not
seem to see this issue as a priority
also to this cultural taboo so
again
we are as i said before we should always
remember that we are not talking about
an emergency in the sense of a priority
that we have to address we can also
decide all together as a society or
individually speaking just to ignore it
but we've seen all the monsters that are
coming out of this problem if we don't
tackle it we have seen what happens when
we don't
care about the safety of those who are
exposed in these videos if you look of
all the hate that there is online
against uh well women
in
most of the times when they try to to to
express themselves to show
their body or also to all the non-uh
heteronormative orientations whenever
they show themselves online
there is
hatred there is tension and this could
also be part of the consequences of this
huge communication machine these
algorithms that we try to build as good
as we can apparently
that still only reiterate the same
models
over and over again
in an incredibly loud
way some extremists would even call it i
don't know means of a
dissemination of rape culture but not me
another solution could be advocacy
advocacy is
of course a way to go to institutions
and ask for
for them to solve the problems and uh
this topic is often not welcomed by
these political institutions uh pushing
for openness on these issues may
escalate in a moral panic as i said
because on one end you have people that
are trying to climb this mountain of the
cultural taboo and on the other end you
have people that want to push them and
actually stop it all together from
from the start and and
in a
blind fight against obscenity and other
forms of extremism just there is a
toxic debate it's always very difficult
to actually talk about these things
because sex has always been an
incredibly powerful uh
core element of our cultures or our
societies or our history and so it's not
going to be easy
um oh and sorry i forgot to mention you
see that there is in a yeah up left
reactive and proactive the policy and
advocacy solution can be both reactive
so you use them after there is a problem
or proactive you can actually decide to
try and prevent problems from happenings
from happening
and then there's litigation which is of
course only reactive when somebody
violates a norm you can try and and you
know make them accountable for that and
it seems to be the most reachable
approach at the present time is the low
hanging fruit at least for for our
experience allows to bring together law
and technology
uh
especially so yeah law exp legal experts
and i.t specialists can have very
interesting conversations uh about uh
about many things apparently with this
um and involves judges data protection
authorities and so uh somehow closes the
gap between people and institutions
also
in this and sets very important judicial
precedents
but what about you
if we still have time to talk about it
do are you aware of any issue what would
you like to investigate
how which methodology would you use if
you see any problem in the first place
but
i don't know
if you do
and and
and you would like to to the to discuss
it with us we'll be more than happy to
to to know what you think uh you can
again find a lot of material from our
project on our website attracting
exposed
tracking.expose is the main website the
for the porno project is for
nab.tracking.exposed
you can find
even the slides we just used today and
an academic paper that has been recently
published about the analysis of the
algorithm that were conducted from
using the tools that julia just
presented to you
and
that was it thank you very much
and i hope you had a good sign
julia alex thank you so much
they'll be available outside if you have
questions
[Music]
you