[Music]
so
do
[Music]
all right good evening everybody
welcome again to another presentation at
a new hope uh it is seven o'clock and 90
degrees outside so it's better to be in
here than out there
i'd like to welcome square matrix he is
a hacker and artist from san francisco
and his talk today is going to look at a
selection of online hoaxes and
propaganda and some of the tools and
tricks that were used to make them
happen
we're also going to be looking in
particular into some recent history so
please help me welcome square matrix
hey i'm going to get started
i'm a little anti-social but i'm very
excited to be back at hope as my fifth
hope my first time as a speaker so
see how it goes
i'm going to be talking today about the
evolution of online hoaxes and
propaganda while dissecting the tools
and tactics to become the modern weapons
of misinformation
i'm going to touch briefly on kind of
all these things today showing how
elements within them are being used
today to manufacture truth i'll then
show how i used these ingredients to
manufacture truth in the run-up to the
2017 inauguration i'll explore a hoax
that i created that convinced
conservative media to debunk in prime
time a conspiracy theory about paid
protesters that they themselves had
created and were promoting i'll share
with you the tactics i know putting
everything on the table the idea is that
hopefully you can do the same so let's
go
um so who am i i'm a hacker a software
engineer amateur animatronics and
electronics enthusiast and trans media
artist living in the bay area california
this is some of the stuff i build it's
mostly unsanctioned interactive art in
unsanctioned places usually for
strangers if you ever find yourself
going through a storm drain or an
abandoned building interacting with
robots it might be me
this is my first go at manufacturing
truth it's a battery powered box i built
that can be covertly hidden it makes
lifelike knocking sounds at random
intervals
ghost hunters want to believe that they
can communicate with spirits
those that have passed um and they
believe that some spirits will respond
to them via wrapping you know three
knocks for yes two knocks for no uh and
i wanted to give them the experience
that they were seeking
um i took my ghost box uh to a place
that attracts a lot of ghost hunters in
southern california the queen mary this
is a luxury cruise liner larger than the
titanic that was turned into a
stationary hotel and tourist trap and
museum in long beach california
and this is where i installed it this is
a watertight door where a man was
purportedly crushed in 1966
and then a week after my install i came
back for a paranormal conference to
covertly play with investigators um
ghost hunters believe that this area
specifically is a paranormal vortex
um so some academics have given a name
to this type of exploration of folklore
in the real world that these ghost
hunters are doing and they've called it
legend tripping and legend trips are
ritual quests in which people strive to
explore and find manifest the very
events described by supernatural legends
so if you've ever gone to a graveyard at
night like as a teenager with your
friends to see if like some ghost will
appear or maybe you hunted bigfoot
you're you know you're exploring a
legend in the real world um and that's
called legend tribute i'll come back to
this in a moment
um this is what got me first interested
in the world of hoaxes as a kid uh it's
an email that caused quite a stir
amongst many animal lovers
and it reads for everyone who loves
animals a site that we were able to shut
down last year has returned we have to
try to shut it down again a japanese man
in new york breeds and sells kittens
that are called bonsai cats this would
sound cute if the kittens weren't put
into little boxes after being given
muscle relaxants and then locked up for
the rest of their lives so the idea is
that someone is growing kittens in jars
and um
they say you know you got to forward
this email to 500 people and if you
click the link in the email you go to
this website which has way too much text
on it uh it's it's got like a store a
phone number uh has instructions on how
to put cats into jars um and it just
gets really really really silly like
it's it's
yeah you might ask yourself like who
would believe this a lot of people
actually believed it including the fbi
in 2001 the fbi launched an
investigation into banzai kitten no this
is not a hoax itself
and they subpoenaed mit to determine the
identity of a seemingly obvious hoax
website that was being run out of a
campus dorm
through a press release the article
quoted the creator
as saying i was surprised i really
thought that the fbi had better things
to do that's your tax dollars at work
this is actually one of the better
things the fbi has done
um so uh bonsai kitten is interesting
because you go from an email to a
website maybe you call the phone number
they have a store where you can purchase
jars to put your cats in there's a guest
book where you can get angry
and it like it encompasses all these
different forms of media to make it more
convincing and there's a there's a form
of art that uses these tactics called
trans media storytelling
and transmedia storytelling is the
practice of designing sharing
participating in a cohesive story
experience across multiple traditional
and digital delivery platforms for
entertainment advertising marketing or
social change participants assume the
role of hunters and gatherers chasing
down bits of the story across media
channels comparing notes with each other
via online discussion groups and
collaborating to ensure everybody
invests time and effort
in coming away with a richer experience
the first piece of transmedia
storytelling online started on bbs's in
the 1980s is an experience called aung's
hat and it centers on a real ghost town
in the new jersey pine barrens
and it begins with you receiving a xerox
catalog of rare books and maybe you
found it on a bbs maybe you found a
physical copy at one point these were
being put in visitor centers in the new
jersey pine barrens
and as you read this rare catalog of
books slowly a story emerges through the
curation of the books in this catalog in
the books in the catalog don't actually
exist
but you know one book might be a history
of ghost towns another one might be a
the history of quantum teleportation one
might be about a strange psychedelic
ashram in the the pine barrens itself
and kind of what emerges through the the
descriptions of each of these books is a
narrative about like these renegade
princeton professors who had been
conducting quantum physics experiments
and chaos theory experiments um and they
essentially built this dimensional
travel device called the egg and so
there were bbs boards of people
investigating this there were websites
of evidence uh people in some cases even
wrote the fictional books themselves um
and this all kind of created an
international kind of an interactive
legend trip in which you could kind of
explore this world that was presented as
real
and the ingredient here i wanted to like
really hit on is like you know building
an interactive complex world
is really important for a convincing
hoax or legend trip there's a great book
written about this i highly highly
recommend called legend tripping online
uh it's specifically about aung's hat
and kind of the birth of transmedia
storytelling on the internet
another early work of transmedia art is
project neurocam created by robert
henley an australian performance artist
in 2004
i was actually briefly a participant and
a briefly a producing collaborator on
this project
it starts with a mysterious billboard
that like leads you to an odd website of
an organization that like doesn't seem
to really say anything about itself your
only option is to join and if you join
you get sent on a series of assignments
that take you out into the real world
have you interacting with other
participants and learning more about
this organization uh what was
interesting about this is people who
kind of like played along in this story
eventually became producers of the story
and created it for other people and it
split off into other organizations and
projects and the ingredient here i think
is like inviting your audience to
co-create with you
in your kind of story there's a great
paper on this i highly highly highly
recommend uh called the parallaxus a
game of walking between worlds written
by jess kilby
that kind of covers the participant
experience the producer experience and
kind of why she left and the ethical
reasons behind it
so it wasn't just hoaxers and artists
who were using these techniques
companies in the early 2000s started
using these to create kind of commercial
variations often called alternate
reality games or args for short as
you'll sometimes hear and these are
typically more interactive experiences
where players are encouraged to solve
puzzles together to unlock additional
layers of the game
it was collaborative usually commercial
and goal oriented microsoft made one for
steven spielberg's ai and um a company
called 42 entertainment made one called
i love bees for the launch of halo 2.
the uh i love bees one's interesting
you're on a real like amateur beekeeping
website and it's taken over by this like
ai that needs your help to help like
reassemble itself and it sends you out
into the real world by giving you
coordinates and times and if you go to
the coordinate at that time you find a
payphone and that phone rings and the ai
gives you the instructions on how to
kind of piece it together
if this sounds familiar uh
conspiracy theories kind of like q and
on uh have a lot in common with
alternate reality games and transmedia
storytelling uh basically it's a series
of secret codes that participants
decipher together
participants often feel like the main
character in these stories is they move
between media chasing uh pieces of the
puzzle uh and they're typically told
across multiple uh platforms in this
chat in this case 4chan 8chan reddit
youtube there's even in-person events
conferences
it's a really rich
narrative world unfortunately it's very
harmful
it was not just hoaxers artists and
marketers that started using these
tactics on the internet
governments got in on the transmedia
story telling
band wagon 2.
so on september 11
2014 the internet research agency
russia's cyber warfare contractor
conducted a fascinating virtual
operation
so you imagine you're sitting on your
couch and you get this text message
toxic fume hazard warning in the area
until 1 30 pm take shelter check local
media and columbiachemical.com
columbiachemical.com just happens to be
the chemical plant down the street from
you that makes dangerous chemicals so
you get on twitter as any normal person
does
and uh there's like just a flood of
tweets about people tweeting about this
uh this fume the fumes and apparently
like it was actually an explosion and
the plant's now on fire and people on
twitter are posting videos of this
and they're even linking to cnn which is
talking about the explosion
and this is turning up on youtube and
then a video pops up on youtube from
isis claiming responsibility for the
explosion
this this series of events actually
happened although the explosion did not
um and this was kind of a dry run by the
internet research agency uh there's two
papers on this that are really
interesting um
they're up there on the screen um the
internet research agency agencies doing
a lot of interesting stuff probably more
than you know uh don't believe that
you're not a potential target of them uh
they're actively fanning the flames of
like every fire in america um so like
definitely read about them even if you
think you know about them read about
them
this is an interesting thing that i
found recently uh about a year ago
actually um
and it's a it's a mysterious youtube
channel uh that posts a lot of extremely
professional videos that are
anti-chinese communist party um and
they're just so well funded and well
produced that i was just intrigued by
this and i couldn't figure out who was
behind it there was no indication of who
was funding this or why they were doing
it
until a few months ago a donation link
appeared and i got really excited so i
went to donate of course
and i saw a reference to something
called the vision times and i'd never
heard of that so i googled it uh the
vision times is actually a newspaper run
by the religious spiritual movement fong
gong falun gong
who's obviously uh persecuted by the
chinese communist party and suddenly it
makes sense you know why they would have
this kind of propaganda channel
they're the same people who do shenyun
if you've never heard of it god bless
you that's a good thing
they also run a major conservative
newspaper here in the u.s called the
epic times and the epic times is very
fascinating it's very anti-chinese
communist party and it's very very
pro-trump and they employ the same level
of professionalism that china insights
has
very very slickly produced stuff
podcasts videos
and the most interesting thing about
them is they employ this really novel
tactic
they use farms of mass ai generated
profiles including computer generated
photos of people's faces um you know
potentially even computer generated text
to spread this content uh the content i
recommend uh looking into this the
content is incredibly well produced it
hits on like every emotion uh these guys
are masters of propaganda and it's worth
studying uh
really magical stuff here uh in a bad
way
um so we talked about early uh hoaxes
trans media art alternate reality games
propaganda and kind of how their
ingredients have been used for
manufacturing truth but i wanted to like
really concretely show you an example of
how this can be used even inadvertently
in the real world to have massive
impacts
so these are the georgia guidestones
they're built in
1979 they were created by a local
eccentric who wanted a monument that
would serve as a guide for humanity
after a coming great disaster that he
believed would took place uh so he
thought that the the you know humanity
would be wiped out and that they would
use these guide stones as a way to
rebuild it works as a compass a calendar
a clock it's
unnecessarily complex he's carved 10
commandments on it
in eight different languages and um
conspiracy theorists for the last 40
years have been really
obsessed with the first three
commandments
the first maintain humanity under 500
million in perpetual balance with nature
a little creepy guide reproduction
wisely little creepy unite humanity with
a new living language that sounds cool
and they believe that
and they've told this story through
books uh
and then through documentaries and
movies that this is a plan by a
luciferian cabal to establish a new
world order who wants to
depopulate the earth and then i guess
take control or something and alex jones
has gotten on the bandwagon he's
produced one of the documentaries
this thing's 40 years old so like
there's even early internet websites
about this
and most recently people are connecting
covid to the georgia guide stones in
that
they're saying that the vaccine is how
they're going to depopulate down to 500
million
and you might think this is silly who
would believe this
this is a candidate for the recent
republican
prime uh this is a candidate for
governor in the recent republican
primary in georgia from may 24th fun
fact she has a phd
this is her website uh her primary uh
her primary kind of campaign platform is
demolishing the guide stones uh she
talks about ridding uh georgia of this
satanic evil and she makes this pledge
support my uh fight by contributing as i
and watch as i turn the georgia
guidestones into dust so 40 years of
conspiracy have sort of like uh
culminated into this um you know
a
person running for governor
of georgia and this is her campaign ad i
just have to show it to you because it's
it's just so bonkers and it kind of puts
this all together
i'm using sound here
over 4 billion people have been injected
with something that took just nine
months to create
ask yourself why
back in biblical times human sacrifice
was a form of demonic worship
we're still doing it
in present day by killing our unborn
it's the same demons it's the same
sacrifice it's the same sin
it's just a different time
we've watched as people have destroyed
our history and monuments and in their
place they have erected statutes to
their own gods
the new world order is here
and they told us it was coming
it's a battle far greater than what we
see in the natural
it is a war
between good and evil
so uh that's from her campaign ad she
doesn't say what the other executive's
orders are which i think is interesting
on her website um and you might ask
yourself you know like what could go
wrong in this alternate reality we've
created you know this this conspiracy of
fiction that's been told for 40 years
between like books documentaries radio
programs
well this is what happened next also new
tonight we have our first look at the
explosion at the georgia guidestones the
gbi just releasing this video hours ago
and you can see there is a bright flash
and then part of the structure explodes
so uh it was like a couple months after
her failed run at governor uh the
guidestones were blown up um so you know
there's real world consequences to 40
years of you know this ridiculous story
so i'm going to talk now about something
that i created using these tactics
that was pretty effective but first i
want to tell you why i created it and it
starts right here so i was actually at a
fundraiser for a legal defense fund for
water protectors taking a stand against
the dakota access pipeline in case you
don't know north dakota's brought like
800 cases against mostly native peoples
who are protesting the construction of
an oil pipeline on their land
and
the woman running the fundraiser was
one of the mediators between tribal
people and law enforcement and she said
at the end of their first meeting
the law enforcement was like oh you know
we're so relieved to know that you're
real people you know we've been told
that you were kind of paid here
paid to be here by environmental groups
and just trying to cause trouble and
like that comment just like really for
some reason just like really hurt me
um and i just felt really really sad um
and
i i can't say that i was surprised i
read conservative media because i want
to know how to talk to conservatives and
a common trope is uh that you know
the enemies are essentially like paid
agitators or paid protesters this is
something that's like been around for a
while and is someone who's like
literally marched in the streets um
it's offensive because you know
tens of thousands of people aren't
marching because they're um being paid
they're marching because they're pissed
off uh the math just doesn't make sense
um so i asked myself like what would it
take to debunk the idea of paid
protesters uh and i came up with an idea
i call the credibility trap and this was
my plan i would create the thing that
people believed in a paid protesting
company i would then get the attention
and be the only real tangible proof that
people could point to
and then it would become silly and
ridiculous causing those spreading the
information to then have to go correct
their readers or to put it another way
the idea was to get the media to report
on something that turned itself slowly
into a ridiculous spectacle to show
people that the topic itself was made up
and i gave myself two rules for this one
never give up on the story no matter
what never admit it's a lie and two
slowly become more ridiculous and i
thought those two things would play off
each other
so i did when anyone does i started by
creating an unnecessarily detailed
website uh it was fairly silly the math
of how many people we had on the streets
didn't make sense it was mostly
believable but it had like weird satanic
references
um i created an unnecessarily complex
job application form that asked all
sorts of very detailed questions i made
a phone line that started with the
number 666 and created a very
complicated phone tree i made a
operative login thing so that it seemed
like people were logging into this site
or something um and then i just started
placing job ads as any real company
would and i targeted the largest
conservative majority cities uh and
where i thought i would have a good
chance of getting attention and i placed
ads on like backpage indeed
trying to hire paid protesters
i then also placed google and bing ads
and i targeted
journalists and news organizations so
that they could be hired to be paid
protesters
so at this point i have a website a
phone number job postings an operative
login i got i'm sending these
newsletters on a weekly basis i have
google ads
and i'm really kind of starting to blend
this together
i then spent the next couple weeks
every night posting comments on infowars
gateway pundit and other conspiracy
websites 4chan reddit's the donald uh
and soon it wasn't me posting it was
other people posting uh and and the
discussion sort of uh got you know
started kicking off in these weird
conspiracy corners and a lot of people
started coming to the website
um and uh
people started taking the bait first it
was like small little websites that i'd
never heard of weird blogs that just
seemed bizarre and then it was like
mainstream conspiracy blogs uh things
that a lot of people read that you may
not read
uh spudnik news took it uh newsmax
started reporting on it and i love this
quote though reports of paid agitators
have been debunked as fake news demand
protest has a working phone number um so
the bar is very low folks for newsmax um
and then uh infowars word of story and
then i think the best one here is the
washington times after a 30 minute phone
call with me wrote this article
which you know washington times is like
an almost respectable conservative
newspaper um drudge report ran it at the
top of their uh page um so it was really
taken off uh and i started getting a lot
of job application
applications which is something that i
didn't anticipate or think about so i
had to shut that down
that just felt bad i felt
people were actually applying which was
scary to me and the phone numbers
started getting flooded with phone calls
and i just wanted to play just a small
sampling of them this is a message for
you [ __ ] in san fran i'm an american
i support donald j trump
you [ __ ] up big time
your number has been posted on the net
and we will find out your address so
kiss your asses goodbye [ __ ]
hi
um
demand protest wow
i noticed that the first three digits of
your phone number are 666.
i just simply cannot believe any
organization like this exists in the
united states because you cheapen the
value of protest
hi
i just called to say that i think you
people are disgusting
the whole concept of your business i
can't even believe that some [ __ ]
thought it up and shat it out of their
ass
and whoever [ __ ] it is is your boss
owner
yes this is a real call i hope you do
record these calls
my name's
i'm not being paid to say that i'm
outraged at your fake outraged
protesters
now why don't you all go snort some coke
and have an orgy and [ __ ]
every one of you i took that advice yeah
here's my message you [ __ ] douchebag
[ __ ] piece of [ __ ] [ __ ]
guess who's in charge of your life god
donald trump is the best president ever
you guys are [ __ ] losers
go die
um so by this point we were getting a
lot of attention uh most of it was
fairly uncritical um but there were some
exceptions uh there were some small like
local publications that called us out uh
some guy named corey doctro at a website
called boingboing called us fake he also
spread some misinformation by saying we
had a non-working phone number uh snopes
uh called us unproven which is the most
charitable thing anyone's ever done they
also said we're demand progest uh i have
no more faith in snopes
um and some actually a couple local news
stations did stories calling us almost a
hoax trying to give activism a new
bottom line this seems really suspicious
we showed the ad to andrew dobbs program
director for the texas campaign for the
environment the fifty dollars an hour is
really suspicious the the super super
suspicious part is that twenty five
hundred dollar a month retainer as the
leader of a grassroots nonpartisan group
dobbs says the numbers are budget
breakers i don't have any evidence that
it's not real other than the fact that
it seems
completely stupid
if the demand protest ad is a ruse it's
an elaborate one to get more information
i went through an online application
process that's running in austin and
more than a dozen other cities
but after submitting the application and
calling the company's san francisco
phone number i've gotten no response i
think it's kind of interesting ut
government professor eric mcdaniel
evaluated the ad i think it's most
likely a hoax ad he says
so it is a hoax anyways
at this point conservative media was
eating it up um there was some weak
debunking by non-conservative
publications but it seemed like the lies
were getting a lot more coverage than
the truth um and i was starting to have
an ethical crisis because i wasn't sure
how i was going to spring my credibility
trap
and i was starting to wonder if it had
maybe spiraled out of control and i'd
just done a bad thing so at the depth of
my feelings i got this email which was
uh
from tucker carlson
and he wanted me to be on his show in
four hours and i was having a really bad
day at work uh it was it was like a
really bad day so i was not in a mental
place to do this so i go on social media
and i said anyone want to go on tucker
carlson's show tonight uh you have the
opportunity to say whatever you want and
i knew like i was gonna have one
opportunity to get ridiculous
and i was like this is it like this is
where we have to just have to get
completely unhinged uh and a friend of
mine uh responded who's a documentary
filmmaker he'll be in the q a uh via
video here uh we had a quick phone call
and agreed on some ground rules they
were start by playing the story straight
refuse to acknowledge it's fake ever and
slowly get more ridiculous and uh this
is the result this is all improv on his
part he was just fast thinking on his
feet um yeah more on that up ahead but
first good evening and welcome to tucker
carlson tonight
friday's inauguration looks like it
could be a protest event for the ages
with thousands of anti-donald trump
agitators descending on the city and why
wouldn't they advertisements posted more
than 20 cities have been recruiting paid
protesters to come here to dc to help
disrupt the inauguration the group
demand protest which describes itself as
quote the largest grassroots support
organization in the united states says
it will pay professional protesters
fifty dollars an hour in addition to a
two thousand five hundred dollar monthly
retainer to support their efforts we're
joined now by dom talipso director of
operations in los angeles for demand
protest dom thanks for joining us
tonight
yeah no problem tucker
so um this is a sham your company isn't
real your website is fake the claims you
have made are lies
this is a hoax let me start at the
beginning however with your name dom
talipso which is not your real name
it's a fake name well he ran you through
law enforcement level background checks
and that name does not exist so let's
start out with the truth tell me what
your real name is
it's dominic
to yeep so it's uh
ells are silent that's a lie and you
know it's a lie and we asked you for id
at the los angeles bureau and you said
you didn't have id with you but dallas
you have a wallet on you every grown man
does hold up a credit card you can cover
the number to our camera and show us any
piece of documentation with the name
dominic talipso on it and you can't
because that's not true
sure sure um absolutely i'll do that in
just a moment um
i might just begin with uh kind of
wondering uh tucker you're not accusing
this me of being a hoax
are you
i'm saying that your name is fake and
this company is fake and that the claims
you've made on your website are false
and so my question for you is why
is this an effort to discredit the
protesters at the trump inauguration is
it an effort to convince conservative
news organizations to pick up the story
and therefore highlight their
gullibility what's the point of the ruse
that you're perpetuating on the american
news media
sure absolutely great questions uh i
mean
basically there's no way that a
legitimate news agency would have
somebody on uh that didn't really know
what they were saying or was just kind
of talking out of their behinds there's
a certain amount of vetting that goes on
behind every news organization so i
would assume that i wouldn't be given
air time on a national stage
unless i was legitimate
well i'm vetting you right now and i'm
beginning by saying you are not
legitimate you are lying
we know that
you have fooled other news organizations
you did not fool us
and my question is why are you doing it
and and i guess let me just satisfy our
viewers who may be thinking well maybe
we're miscalling this on your website
you claim that you pay a retainer to
operatives
every month now if that were actually
true that's 54 million dollars a year
you're spending just on retainers it's
another 30 million a year if you're
paying them for six hours a week work
that's demonstrably silly you're not
doing that
no we're actually doing 80 million a
year um so i don't know quite where you
got those numbers but those are
definitely uh obviously dated um i i i
do want to mention the fact wait wait so
hold on
you're not conceding that this is a hoax
you're saying that this is a real
company that's engaged in the activities
you say it's engaged in that you're
hiring protesters
you have 1800 of them already on
retainer for 2500 bucks a month and
you're affecting american politics by
doing this
yeah we actually changed our mind though
about um about we're no longer actually
going after donald trump we're actually
going after the protesters at the
inauguration um so we kind of changed
our minds actually recently and that was
a result mainly of uh the enormous
amount of hate mail that we received
people you know making death threats and
they they basically just really talked
us into changing our position so what
we're doing now is we're actually
protesting the protesters um okay with
that that actually didn't really
happen because you don't have a physical
address because you don't have a real
office your website was just put up your
facebook page same thing you haven't
been receiving hate mail because you
don't exist okay so if you do exist why
don't you give me some evidence that
you're real beginning with your actual
name which is not dominic tilipo and by
the way your business partner doesn't
exist either so let's just be straight i
mean let's just be real
yeah
what is the real story here why are you
doing this what point are you trying to
make yeah
uh the main point basically is that um
we are
greatly greatly supportive of national
treasures such as julian assange edward
snowden peyton manning right and we
really support their efforts to really
get the truth out there and in the case
of the current client that we have right
now
that client is
very interested in releasing the roswell
papers
i don't know what really so you're
pretty supportive of peyton manning are
you
extremely you know
okay you're not gonna i mean obviously
this is performance art i will say
you're pretty good at it when you
convince papers like the washington
times which ran this pretty straight
to run your lies to run this hoax which
i will concede is kind of amusing
what was the point of that i mean beyond
just amusing yourself are you trying to
make a political statement
um i don't know i mean
it's pretty pretty darn easy these days
to just say whatever the heck you want
on national tv and have it passed off
his truth um yeah and you know uh it's
pretty uh i don't know it's just pretty
incredible to me how easy it was to get
the coverage we got by the way i'm not
saying any of this is a hoax or any of
this isn't true we've actually got a
hundred thousand protesters going to
washington dc to fight anybody who is
opposed to donald trump i mean the
reason we shift another main reason we
shifted uh from being against trump to
trump about 30 minutes ago
was basically we realized initially he
didn't really like
he didn't really like julian assange or
peyton manning and
when he kind of changed when the
election and the assange connection was
made
he
essentially became a supporter of
assange and so we are now supporting
trump in the hope that the roswell
documents from 1947 are finally
uh released and put back into the hands
of um fischer stevens the critical
roswell documents all right well give my
best to peyton manning and also to mrs
uh if you would thanks a lot for joining
us
whoever you are i can't believe it
please last question i'm sorry did you
think that we were going to fall for i
mean be honest do you think you're going
to go
come on
you put me on
that's what's surprising
well because it showed up all over
across american media and i'm reading
this i was like well that's not true who
is this guy so i'm glad you came on to
semi explain well god god bless you for
for fact checking even if you did it
when we were on the air
so
[Applause]
we'll we'll bring mr tulipso on in a
moment um but you know uh
this is prime time fox news most watched
channel um this is like the audience
that believes in this [ __ ] and this
is the channel that's spreading this
[ __ ] so that was the trap hopefully
some people learned uh even like
extremist conservative websites like
gateway pundit ran articles uh praising
tucker for exposing the hoax i love this
quote carlson his team did significant
research into mr talipso and exposed him
on the show as being a complete fraud
this was their original article so i
wouldn't applaud them too much
and the washington times just silently
altered their article saying it was a
hoax after the fact
which
is kind of sneaky but if you go to the
wayback machine you can see that they
lie
a number of legitimate publications
wrote interesting articles about this
the washington times one's kind of cool
my favorite is this spin magazine
article uh coolest journalist ever
so i thought like okay maybe this worked
like maybe some people got this message
maybe i've dispelled it for maybe i
don't know
20 percent of people um and then i saw
this tweet
this is from ari fleischer the white
house press secretary for george w bush
a month after this he tweets uh outraged
at demand protest so uh people are still
being fooled unfortunately um i don't
know if this was a good thing i'm not
doing political stuff anymore back to
paranormal
so anyways uh if you want to do this
sort of thing i have some advice have a
message that confirms beliefs or targets
an emotional trigger
mystery creates intrigue leave your
motivations up to interpretation
study transmedia storytelling tactics to
create an alternate reality
and seed your ideas in small communities
of your ideal audience and then kind of
grow from there some great books on this
legend tripping online i talked about
earlier uh trust me i'm lying from the
former marketing director of american
apparel very great book on media
manipulation he lays out all his tactics
and magic and showmanship uh it has a
lot of great kind of it's for magicians
but it has a lot of great tips and sort
of like presentation and attention uh
what can we do to maybe uh combat
manufactured truth um this is just my
two cents i think immerse yourself in
communities filled with views you oppose
i read conservative news every day
because i want to know how to talk to
conservatives
i think if you if you hate a group of
people you should read about them should
consume the media they're consuming so
you can speak to them and understand
where they're coming from we also need
to i think vocally challenge the
veracity of unsourced claims this is
really unfun and makes you unpopular
sometimes
but if we don't do that we're kind of
screwed
collectively i think we need to fund
free public news media that is
accessible and engaging the new york
times costs like a hundred dollars a
year the truth can't cost a hundred
dollars a year um npr is great i love
terry gross although she doesn't fact
check fresh air is wonderful but it's
not accessible and engaging to most of
america we need to do a better job here
pre-bunking or we need to build trust
ahead of those that might manufacture
doubt
so that they're prepared for those
messages
and this is going to be controversial
but i think when possible avoid forms of
censorship that will end up pushing
those censored into extremist echo
chambers like parlor truth social and
gab go check out those networks those
are where the people who are banned from
twitter go they they pick up all sorts
of new things uh it's a real problem i
don't have an answer but it's it's
terrifying to see this happen
uh so thank you i'm square matrix get in
touch if you want to collaborate um or
you want to cause trouble that's my
email you can scan that qr code for all
the resources if you want to contact dom
that's his email we're going to do q a
and we'll bring
dom
dom on somehow oh there he is
[Applause]
hello everyone
good to see you i haven't uh i haven't
watched that in quite a while um yeah
that's a hoot
thanks mr uh talipso
it's teep so
yeah
all right i'll start q a i have one
quick question just out of curiosity did
fox or tucker show did they do any kind
of follow up with you i'm just curious
they did um
yeah it was interesting uh we got an
email probably a couple months after
uh saying
you know they asked initially oh where
are you based and i i was based in the
uh los angeles headquarters of uh demand
uh protest as the media outreach and
community uh organizer or demand protest
based in los angeles because that's
where all the actors are and uh where
would the best crisis actors be but in
los angeles so anyway he um
he reached out or his assistant reached
out and said i'll be in los angeles i'd
like to get dinner with you
and we go to this italian restaurant in
santa monica um i go in
there's this strange little uh room in
the back and i go in there
and
uh he's there his assistant's there she
looks like she's like 10 years old um
she's just very young i'm there's
nothing nothing untoward there but um
but there's another person uh sitting
there as well who's got a snap down cap
uh has a big beard a huge beard glasses
on and they're kind of like tinted like
uh jeff goldblum in jurassic park
glasses
and it takes me a second and then kind
of like um
scout
uh finch from to kill a mockingbird when
she sees like boo radley at the end i'm
like looking at her and i'm like
oh hi billy
and it's billy bush from access
hollywood sitting having dinner at an
italian restaurant with tucker carlson
and i'm like this is so
surreal um but one thing i did before
that that i thought was really important
is he did ask for my id
and i'm sorry i don't have it pulled up
or ready to share with everyone but you
know during the interview asked for my
id so i did uh you know
i went
right before that spent five minutes
photoshopping my dump to eepso id
and uh first thing i did was when i
walked up uh was
uh hi i think i'm supposed to be here
here's my id and shared it with them and
you know
i don't want to make
i it's not my job or my desire in any
way to make tugger carlsen laugh or
anything but i have always felt that
like a laughing jury never convicts uh
kind of thing and if you can get
somebody smiling if you can get somebody
laughing their guard drops it's just a
vulnerability so
he he thought that was hilarious and
then literally we just spent the uh the
next like two and a half hours talking
about the grateful dead
that's it i'm not kidding like we didn't
talk about anything political at all um
and maybe i should have but what am i
gonna do tell them to stop being
a terrible person like i don't that's
not my job you know so we just talked
about how you know we both had uh
deep love for grateful dead which is
also weird because it isn't like ann
coulter also super into the grateful
dead i don't know but um there's a weird
like
and well i don't want to get political
but anyway that i hope that answered
your question a little bit
uh whoever's at the mic yeah so i just
wondered if you heard about an artwork
that is i think just opened in mexico
city by a couple of conceptual artists
joshua okun and juan obando
they actually found a company that does
pay
protesters
and they made an artwork
in a museum where they paid these people
to have a sort of uh
bogus like insignia or something like
that and then they created as a sort of
video installation i just
it shocked me
seeing this here because i they were
telling me that these companies really
do exist and i wondered if you'd heard
of those companies the real ones yeah so
um
there are companies that you can hire
for like crowds on movie sets in fact
it's rumored that trump hired
one of these crowds for his announcement
for uh presidency um
they are not hiring people on the scale
of tens of thousands of people marching
in the streets against trump that's
ridiculous that's a lot of money
no one has that kind of money and can
keep that kind of secret um so uh yeah
there are you know there are people who
will fill out movie sets um i get a lot
of emails to the demand protest account
of people wanting to actually hire me
which is kind of terrifying i've thought
about maybe publishing who those people
are
um but yeah so there is a if someone
wants to start an incredibly unethical
business there is like on a small scale
um
people who are trying to do that but
certainly not like at a nationwide scale
um people are actually pissed off
ah makes sense
well hey we we talked about propaganda
and how or
basically just fooling people and in the
matrix chat they're asking if you have
any recommendations to teach others
especially those who are younger how to
defend against falling for that
disinformation
i think it's um probably about going to
original sources
which is getting more expensive to do
i think
it probably
probably depends on the piece of
information but
you know making sure that the website
you're going to is is one that is
remotely credible uh it's an you know an
actual news organization that's
hopefully been around for a while and is
known
i'm not the best person to answer this
but um
yeah you have to research everything
individually i don't think there's like
a blanket answer
cool
anyone else have any other questions
all right well hey thanks for the talk
that was great thanks so much
[Applause]
[Music]
you