how can reference and there's more stuff
going to be referenced as september 1st
here in the united states as legislation
and laws that are going to be driven by
regulators that crest will be managing
but the things that are really
interesting that you may want to
reference is just sure i'll take the
first one um if you are in the avionics
industry if you're flying planes if
you're doing satellite work if you're
doing things that are going to be tied
to human life on you know planes uh
there's a process there which is
considered critical or non-critical and
the regulators of the equivalent for
sure is what the faa is here in the
united states
and they require these organizations to
do the assessments to be able to have a
certain level of quality
seabest we manage the program for the
bank of england and we've done that
since 2006. so we manage a program for
the bank and all that communicate with
the bank of england and this helps those
organizations have assurance and quality
of services
ncsc right the national cyber security
center again another area for incident
response forensics being able to when a
buyer when a buyer has the most worst
day of their life and they have to go
ahead and reach out to get help because
they need assistance and getting
assistance after the fact is always
crazy right they have to know sort of
who are trusted service providers that
can help them
and again our registrar helps those
organizations sort of get to the right
people
quickly
so again we have lots of different
regulatory items that we do for
governments regulatory bodies
and of course
measurements of standards which are
again consistent and very affordable
so the crest community continues to
evolve right we continue to sort of work
with academia we work with grassroots
efforts like hope right as a sponsor
here
we work with a lot of the universities
here in the states now to sort of
demonstrate what good looks like
we're doing some work with this nsa
center of excellences across the country
uh the goal here is to sort of help uh
set some some syllabuses and help inject
some quality items into these items that
are useful so when people come out of
university they can then get into
careers or get into jobs right both on
the defenders side and even on the uh
the service provider side
so
if you came in you may have seen two
things uh the first thing he came to the
door on is a little what is crest right
so a lot of what i just talked about is
here right but what was released today
uh is this document here which is useful
um
my day job uh is the cio for an
international law firm i spend a lot of
time working with lawyers i'm not a
lawyer uh but i know a lot of great
lawyers and i help them a lot of
technical components right like
interpreting
ip issues interpreting security issues
data breach issues etc
and a lot of the problems that they have
as attorneys of course is to in a court
of law determining you know where
liability falls
and crest has done a really great job
with trying to help align themselves
with that sort of conversation because
what is commercially reasonable security
i'm not sure anybody here can answer
that question clearly because most
organizations would need to do the
following they would need to pick a
framework that they want to measure
against they would need to then measure
against that framework with
organizations that have the experience
to do that sort of work they need to
report on that and then take those
corrective actions as needed and
demonstrate the process that they are
able to
you'll be commercially defensible
when organizations have problems because
everyone will everyone does
when there are situations that get
litigious with lawyers and no one likes
lawyers
but when you get into a situation of
pointing fingers saying well what have
you done to try to demonstrate your
organization's ability to secure the
code your rote code the code was
compromised resulted in loss resulted in
human human life
let's go back what did you do how did
you manage your code so if an
organization can come back to you and
say well we use the owasp asvs
version 4
we do a level 2 this allows us to take
these controls relative to the owasp
guidance for software security and we're
good to go because that's how we manage
our software development program
right you can manage and map to that
that may be useful in those
conversations if you get assessed to the
center of internet security version 8
and you use that as a methodology
fantastic if you're using national
cybersecurity framework you see where
i'm going there's there's items here
that businesses need to put the flag in
the ground and help manage too right
again crest is there to assist in that
process uh in the complicated cyber
security space
but in this document it's the crest
approved penetration tests or cap-t
which is uh interesting so what is a pen
test again doing this personally and
professionally for over 20 years from
source code analysis to threat modeling
et cetera
it's always different somebody says i
need a pen test you're like all right
well let's have that conversation what
are you looking to do what's your goal
well i want to do a code analysis of the
software is that a pen test or hey i
want you to scan the outside of my
company and see if a bad guy can get in
is that a pen test i want to send some
phishing emails and try to hook the
browser using beef is that a pen test
there's a couple things that you know we
need to clarify so trying to have that
laid out is very very helpful and it's
confusing for the industry and for the
folks that deliver services or products
in the industry to try to align some of
that vocabulary and i blame marketing
right i might blame marketing to have
these different terms and you throw the
ai word in there it gets real confusing
so it gets down to sort of competency
so the cap phases that are described in
the document are really important and
again we've been doing this for a long
long time so since 2006 this hasn't
really changed but it helps formalize it
in a document that can be referenced
right being able to scope being able to
do delivery being able to sign off and i
know our partner here will be speaking
about that so i won't steal his thunder
um but understanding that we have uh
recognized levels of individuals and you
might agree that there's lots of
different people in the room including
those with some gray hair in their
beards right so we have the idea of the
the practitioner right the practitioner
has about a year experience you know
he's been doing is doing his homework
working real hard in the space and is
registered as a crest practitioner
there's a crest registered individual
that's got about you know three years of
experience verifiable he may have gone
out and taken oscp he may have done giac
he may have done some education work may
have done some hands-on but he can
demonstrate a certain level of expertise
and then they're certified which is
about five years of verifiable
experience those three things are very
helpful in trying to deliver
organizations to what they are asking
for independent space
also consistency again you may as an
organization if you're a consumer you
may require things in a quarterly basis
you may want things annual you may want
things in electronic format you may want
things in a certain process well what if
we laid out what reporting should look
like and what if that helped normalize
the industry because reporting
vulnerabilities reporting problems and
corrective action should be in a
consumable manner that people can use
so again i mentioned other organizations
and i want to call that out because i
said crest does accreditations
and yes we need to do some
certifications as well but
accreditations is really what's
important in the bigger picture of crest
because we're really helping the
normalize the international space for
cyber
and we recognize and we embrace a lot of
our peers right our peer organizations
that are doing certifications
accreditations right across the water
here we have our new york university
folks that do you know seesaw st john's
does a fantastic job in our cyber
security program each of the different
organizations brings something to the
table and we're really trying to help
map that and measure that to what good
looks like and what's repeatable so with
that i'd like to take the time to
introduce one of the crest members one
of the crest partners
this organization has been with crest
for a number of years and i had nobody
better to speak to what his pen test
program looks like than one of the pen
testers let me just swap over guys
thank you
[Music]
there we go all right so uh
first of all thanks tom for having us
here sharing the table with you
i'm going to give
an introduction of myself very spread
and how we approach the
cipt
specification
with a real case study of a recent
engagement that we completed
[Music]
that's the agenda basically
um so i'm the leader of the offensive
security practice at verse sprite i go
by wacko which is easier than the dragon
i have um plus 15 years of experience
doing pen testing
so verse plate is a global
security firm
it has a global presence i have my team
spread in barcelona buenos aires there's
people in atlanta people in romania
we are crest accredited
as tom said for a couple of years now
we are offensive minded
but with
a focus on risk actually our ceo is the
author of the pasta framework which is
a thread modeling framework that puts
customer at the center of the scene
and gives context to everything that we
find
there's uh
there are certain cases where maybe
technically an issue can be considered
critical because it is nice you could do
maybe run code on a on a server and what
not but in reality for the business it's
not that urgent maybe to go and and take
care of that so uh we use pasta to give
context to everything that we do
so um yes i was saying uh i've been been
testing since
i was 18 years old i think
and i can definitely say as tom was
commenting before the definition of
apprentice is
right now broader than ever i could say
there's no single definition there's no
one that can actually
say
or define for everyone what a pentas is
we even have as tom said i mean
marketing created this nice uh thing
here
telling customers or potential deals how
we interpret each of the many services
right vulnerability assessment
penetration testing red teaming each one
with their own testing methodology
each one targeting different targets
but despite having this kind of broad uh
interpretation of what an exercise could
look like
uh i think and and i i i'm gonna use a
quote from one of our customers that i
think was quite nice
to do a recap on everything here
it's about the process behind the
methodologies
and that's what actually the
specification for cipt comes to solve
right the the process i focus on the
process for scoping the process for
delivery or the execution of the
engagement as well as the signing off of
the
of the testing so with that i wanted to
um
bring a case study of a real engagement
we completed
customer was calling these when they
reach out a cloud security operational
assurance
for acme i'm using acme here
and um basically i mean the word
assurance was there so we knew that
customer was gonna most likely be using
this to show they are doing things right
they are being diligent
and they may be also be using this for
regulation purposes because customer was
coming from a
healthcare industry right so
we already knew
this was
serious matter you know i mean
there was going to be people taking a
look at the results so uh we wanted to
do um our best along the entire three
three phases that we have here
and
the first thing that we have to do is to
talk to the customer as tom said i mean
you're calling this a cloud security
operational assurance so what do you
mean by that right what's the scope of
work what what are the goals what are
the objectives would you have in mind
right what you're gonna be using this
for so
um
when talking to the customer uh we
define a couple of things we identify
they
were looking to assess the overall
infrastructure but with a big focus on
on the cloud portion
they were looking for adversarial
exercise exercises so we already knew um
we would take kind of a red teaming
approach here they were not willing to
share any information so definitely a
black box approach more of a red teaming
not so much of a pen test
we were
free to actually touch on everything
that was public so the targets could uh
vary a lot i mean they were talking
about public infrastructure but we also
found that they had uh mobile apps in
the stores that we could take a look at
and so on so um brought the scope here
um they were also looking to determine
how we could abuse everything that could
be found publicly
via ocean or some other means
and then we discussed about some rules
of engagement which are quite important
they wanted daily updates obviously
specifically around critical findings
and
they were not looking as to do any kind
of extraction during the proof of
concept for post-exploitation they were
just looking for us to show the
um potentiality of the the issues
of course as with every single
engagement avoid at all cost disruption
of services because we were testing
production
so that's good i would say that's normal
nowadays
so um once we knew what was what this
was about
um we started working on the team
assignment
um
we really needed skilled people
not only during the scoping process
which i was part of
also courtney here from sales and
the way we work with the team was
having a principal
security consultant leading the whole
engagement
and this was a teamwork because of the
size of the scope and the time we had to
do the work
so we then assigned a senior consultant
a security consultant i was overseeing
the entire engagement along with a team
lead there's a pm project manager and we
also have a client success manager and
we work as a team during the whole
stages of the project lifecycle which
i'm gonna tell a little bit about now um
so this is the process right i was
talking about um
no matter the methodology that you
follow the process is key here
and everything starts i mean once the
sow is signed
everything starts with a
preparation time
uh there's a kickoff call that takes
place
we'll review everything that was agreed
on
there's an initial ocean for us to see
maybe if we can
purchase a type of domain or do
something that needs a certain time of
maturity after
uh before going to use it
we do a quick risk based analysis
trying to
learn more about the customer
main business use cases
vendors that they have
a little bit about the size of the
company and whatnot and we always
obviously do the initial setup of the
attack service
then we go into the kickoff uh where we
send the kickoff email detailing all the
things that we agreed
we go into uh this uh pasta framework
taking a look at different stages of it
um
we do the ocean and recon
and then we go into the in-flight uh
phase where we are basically doing the
the entire methodology for whatever we
are testing right uh here the targets uh
were quite different
uh we had apis we had web applications
we have mobile applications we have
cloud infrastructure so each one of
those good you use a different
methodology when it comes for testing
but more or less it was like the phone
assessment the manual testing and phone
analysis exploitation post exploitation
and then reporting
there's a winding down phase where we
work on documenting everything that we
did
on the report
we also tell about the attempted attacks
maybe
some observations that didn't end up as
an issue but are worth mentioning
we have a wrap-up uh
stage
and when we have this clean up process
as well we don't want to keep anything
about the customer once we complete the
testing
and then we have the closing
with the closing we deliver the report
we go into technical debrief for this
particular exercise there was also an
executive debrief
and there's a retest coordination and
then
the customer sacrifice satisfaction
follow up
so
um
i'd like to show you about um one of the
attack patterns and especially we are
going to be
taking a look at
how the methodology works on this area
and then we're going to have a demo so
to give you some context
um
first with ocean
we discovered an android mobile app that
we reviewed
and we found an end point that we had
missed during the oceans
it was it was quite shady it was just
being used for user statistics
statistics
so with this new endpoint we then do
some further recon
uh we tried to brute force directories
and paths and we found three new
endpoints
from from this host
one of those had a js file
and that we
statically review manually review
we were trying to find more
endpoints
and we finally found three that were
that caught our attention i'm going to
show you
in a sec
and for one of those when we went to um
i can show you here for um so basically
we have here i don't know if you can see
that uh we decompile the the android app
we
took a look at the
the java
code
we found
we
refused some of the endpoints that we
found here and then finally came across
these three
endpoints that caught our attention
for one of those
that
was the rest api invoked teams
when we were calling that with no
credentials because this was blackbox
and we didn't have any so far
there was a stack trace
that caught our attention because
basically we were seeing a token an
authorization bearer
for an
endpoint that was saying
graph.microsoft.com
so
what we did was
like okay what's microsoft graph and i'm
going to read this literally because
this was insane
the google search was saying
that ms graph is the gateway
to the data and intelligence in m0365
and this is nice it provides
a unified programmatically model which
is basically a rest api
um that you can use to access the
tremendous amount of data in microsoft
365.
okay so that that was
uh certainly something interesting and
i'm gonna show you um
we tried to recreate the the issue here
and i'm not doing a live demo because
they don't always end up good but we
have this recorded
to show you a little bit about what we
were able to achieve with this
um here you can see the rest api
being called with no credentials
there's a stack trace
on this staging environment
which basically
looked like
it had some kind of trust relationship
with whatever was in production because
there was a talking there so naturally
we want to see what's what's in the
token and what kind of uh roles or
privileges
it supports
and we have a bunch of them
right
there's um a sites with all user with
all mail sent
uh call initiate
um there's there was even um an option
to read uh
all the teams chat for any user
crazy
so
here we are trying to learn about how to
call the ms graph we were not sure at
that time
i mean
how big the ms graph was and the amount
of data that it could contain so
we are here trying to see how we
create the request and try to use that
token
this one in particular is to list users
on that tenant
for the tenant
asia id tenant
and of course we are adding the token
that we found on the stack trace
and there you have it i mean
it was an station app that was
disclosing this token on a stack trace
and it had this huge trust relationship
with their own
o365 environment
we now
have the users each user has a user id
and with that we will be able to use
or to call some of the other methods
here in the demo we are showing just a
few of them
there's one here that you can use to
list
anything that that user has on their one
drive drives
and there's another example that we then
used
to expand the the exercise because
basically we found a way to send emails
directly from this rest api
um
impersonating any user basically on
azure id so
it was crazy
so here we are trying to see how to
create the entire
request and get one file as a proof of
concept basically
the interesting thing here was that
the um
the response was given
a direct url
that you could use to grab that file
and
you could just put that on a browser and
it would download the file for you here
that's the name of the file
and this rest api was giving that for
free
we are using the excel report that like
looks more cheesy
there you go
so couple of things here um
uh that i want to talk on while the the
next proof of concept is how we uh
managed to send emails impersonating any
user on their own 365.
um
challenges um obviously this was a broad
attack surface so many different
methodologies that we used during the
engagement
uh having a defined process tested
process right that focused on
all these three main areas scoping
obviously if if this hadn't been scoped
correctly we wouldn't have the time
to uh do things properly right because
the scope was quite broad and large
um
this project like life cycle
that
ensures the
the whole engagement is delivered
accordingly and then obviously the way
you present all of these right because
you have to connect a lot of points
um
that was a a big challenge um
then also i mean despite we have
a clear defined project life cycle you
still have to account for
any surprises during the engagement
um
here what happened was that we had to
immediately immediately informed the
customer about what was going on
obviously this was production and we
found this with no information
whatsoever so it was out there for
anyone to exploit
and they asked us to pause the the
testing uh they did some remediation
they wanted to make sure that this
wasn't
exploited before
and then we could uh continue so
accounting for many for maybe roadblocks
or hiccups that's also important keeping
a fluent communication with the customer
across all faces
that's that's key
so
this is the
the last proof of concept where we are
sending an email impersonating one of
those
issue id accounts for our customers
there you go
so
[Music]
that that was a demo and yeah i just
wanted to show you i mean
um
despite being framed within the cipd
specification that doesn't mean
that you cannot do cool stuff right i
mean this is not boring stuff at all
and
you do need this kind of specification
when it comes to doing a student's
activity so yeah so so so thank you for
that thank you
[Applause]
uh no we're good
so so again i think that you know one
thing that that speaks to is the example
of it's not a movie right like it takes
time to look at the controls relative to
an organization being assessed it takes
people that have the knowledge and
experience to do the testing and you
know the crest layout of what good
should look like to the end buyer
is very helpful in all organizations
sort of forming a process that's
somewhat repeatable to demonstrate how
that
technical example becomes a reality for
everybody in a room i'd like to play a
quick game it's the same game we
actually played in 2010 at hope
but i think you might get some giggles
out of it
so
imagine for a moment that you walk into
a room okay what i want is i want people
to shout out the answers as quickly as
possible i'm going to give you a short
amount of time to do that you walk into
a room and there's a light bulb the
light bulb's in the middle of the room
there's a switch on the wall but you're
not allowed to touch the switch
how do you shut the light bulb off go
there you go so you know we've had
feedback about pellet guns have somebody
else do it uh maybe shut off the power
don't pay your bill throw a rock at it
right there's all different ways to
approach the same goal and i think
that's really the spirit of what we do
in the space of security right we we
look at what i call loose approaches and
say okay so here's kind of what we're
going to do we're going to walk in and
we're going to assess we're going to
look we're going to make sure we're
approved to do those type of things now
let's go deal with the right guys so
however the end goal is reached that's
sort of one of the very important parts
of the penetration testing side but
you'd imagine if you're on the other
side of that and you had a really bad
day and you had instant responders walk
through the door you're looking for them
to save your ass right you're looking
for them to give you answers to
questions and help you identify where
the problem was so you don't really have
a lot of time to waste you don't really
have a lot of time for you know them to
figure it out you want sort of the best
and brightest to go do the job so as we
look at you know that sort of piece
again just pulling back to what crest is
all about right on the back of your
program guide you know it has a little
summary of what crest is
i for those that haven't heard about us
i wish you taken an opportunity to learn
more about what crest does if you're a
buyer if you're a service provider if
you're academia or if you're looking to
you know go on your career journey
you know we have a lot of opportunities
and a lot of member companies that have
you know internships and jobs
so it really becomes sort of a holistic
approach within the community to try to
make things a better place so with that
um if there are any questions about
crest or penetration testing in
particular
or the the crest approved penetration
test specification i'll be happy to uh
to answer that and i know there might be
some maybe questions online we're also
in a nice cool air-conditioned supporter
area over by the registration booth so
once the talk's over please feel free to
stop by and say hi
um back to denise is there any questions
from your side
excellent
so please with certainly
lots of
resources to to talk about any uh
questions that you may have we'd be
happy to answer them
i'll give you our opinions again there's
lots of tools out there that we can
recommend a lot of them but obviously
into i always say my wife i can't paint
the house or fix the fix the door but if
you're walking to home depot there's a
whole row of tools
tools don't make anything happen right
it's the intelligence behind the tool
sir
question for wacko
this demo was good but what are the
actual deliverables that you produce for
the
c-level executives at that firm to the
end client that is not as technically
savvy as most of the crowd probably
would be here this is all good for us
how do you take that what's the
methodology what are the deliverables
and different final results that you
give to them on that level basically so
there's two pieces there
from from the service provider
perspective his opinion or his answer is
going to be the right one for his
company
in the guidance that is available for
you crest does outline what that good
look does look like for the purposes of
mapping it to the purpose of being able
to feed it up to be
uh be able to be demonstrating due
diligence due care
at the end of the day
your reports may be slightly different
so please speak to that
but the goal with all the crest
assessments is to follow somewhat of a
standard process so that they're
consistent and that's the issue the
breadth of it
yes yeah now that that's a good question
obviously
this was a technical demo um the way we
present um the issues on the report
basically we we do have two main
sections three main sections i would say
on our report uh there's an executive
summary where we um
we speak at a level that can be
understood by anyone there's like no
deep technical uh wording there
um then we do have a technical detail
section and the last one is for every
attempted attacks and maybe observations
on the executive summary
the way we try to convey ideas is from
this
business risk perspective and to give
actionable items so there's a i mean
after we go through the the past
methodology and the risk-based uh thread
modeling there's a risk analysis that we
do at the end so we give to the customer
like hey you know what i mean
we tried to summarize everything that
happened here at a higher level so
you had um
basically a station
server that was public
and it had a trust relationship with
your asian id it wasn't been tested so
we tried to let them know
when they are not doing that good you
know like giving actionable items uh we
also say where they where they are where
we tested and they they were doing right
okay so that's the idea that we have
when it comes to the executive summary
and if that answer your your questions
yeah yeah so so that that is probably
the the number one um problem for the
buyer right is getting consistent output
and if they have a regulated need to
comply or provide data reports then uh
digestible format which is similar is
very important and also each of the
different service providers we have
about 300 of them by the way worldwide
currently
as we
make strong recommendations for a
process to be followed
you might agree then it becomes sort of
soft touch as well service providers
should be doing a soft touch out to
brief you know debriefing with their
client should be making sure that their
um the check signer
is very clear as to some of the goals
and probably even along the way the
threat modeling piece that was mentioned
what's the dollar value of the impact
right so we can kind of bring it back to
there um most of us that do technical
work right we're kind of in our own
world we don't really care about that
right so it's like here's a technical
report you know go fix that then there's
another another layer usually the other
layers okay so what was the impact of
this how does it really affect your
business and then sort of doing the
downstream effect so um so crest
definitely calls those items out for our
organizations to
address and again we do our best to help
level up the organizations now
one thing that's a suggestion uh is
if you do happen to go to the crest
website uh which and you do look at the
member list of companies which is
completely free to the buyer right um
you're going to come up with a list of
organizations some of them you may know
by brand by name right so there's a lot
of great companies um
when you inquire with them you need to
be very clear
if you're looking for a pen test
you're looking for a crest pen test
the reason why i say that very clearly
is because every member of the crest
organization that provides services
that's accredited and certified has a
crest id
and many organizations will provide a
pen test or a crest pen test so my point
is no you know buyer needs to understand
some of those things as to what they're
looking for and then of course crest
does get involved as any sort of
contract issues any sort of issues with
these deliver deliverability of the
information and we serve as a mediator
right because we are the accreditation
body the
best thing that we can do for the buyer
is help quickly
solve issues that are going to be
popping up between buyer and seller and
for the service company if they are
grossly negligent they will be removed
from the accreditation list and then
they will be globally removed from those
procurement opportunities which is
usually significant for them so there's
a win-win for people to work together uh
hopefully that answers the question
sir
so i
yes also but i am curious and i think
this will be valuable for everybody else
in the audience is do you have any stats
on the percentage of organizations that
come to the accrediteds
do you have any stats to really show you
know the number of organizations that
come to crest to be accredited but are
unfortunately turned down because they
don't meet requirements and i think that
would really demonstrate to the audience
how valuable and strict the crest
requirements really are
in you know making the cyber world more
secure
sure um so so the organization does
produce that material um as an
accreditation body our group is not a
we're not an audit pass fail type of
organization right we're there for an
organization to understand what they're
going to be measured against have them
submit their materials have a
organization get audited and come up
with a answer to the question of are you
doing commercially reasonable standards
so when there's deficiencies uh our
crest team which is like 50 of us around
the world uh we focus on helping that
organization understand where some of
the deficiencies are if you have the
greatest pen testers in the world that's
fantastic if your back office is a mess
that's a problem right if you have a
greatest pen taxes in the world and
you're not securing client data you
don't have good contracts you don't have
appropriate controls in place that's a
problem so we would basically reject the
application and point out where the
problems may be and that they can go
ahead and fix those and resubmit
the point is to have everyone sort of
level up and that's kind of where we
take the regulatory approach of what
we're doing for regulators and
governments and say these are the
programs that have been managed that we
manage on their behalf
in order for you to be on that program
that's how it works right it's kind of
like here in new york if you ever
running on the new york state contract
as an example there's certain things you
got to do why because new york says so
great if you apply and you don't meet
the requirements you may not be on that
contract or you have a certain amount of
time to sort of meet that meet that goal
but from a perspe perspective of numbers
i would say at any given time there's a
hundred or so applications and those
organizations are typically getting
coached along the way until they're able
to mature and then be able to be on that
list also they're reassessed
so individuals are reassessed every
three years for competency
organizations are reviewed every year
right they have a business review
any significant change to the business
acquisition changes people in the
organization those those type of things
may result in the organization no longer
being on the approved list
also
organizations like yours
are
potentially global
uh they're accredited by region so
there's a global accreditation and
there's regional accreditation so
organizations that want to crest
accredited assessment here in the united
states from your company as an example
your company would need to be across the
credit company in the u.s make sense so
that's sort of how that all flows out uh
it's super important to um you know just
understand uh what chris gives to you
the consumer or the buyer to protect the
end customer which ultimately is for
privacy and security so it's sort of a
you're trying to help level up uh as a
as a helping hand in the space hopefully
that answers your question
cool
sir hi thanks uh i'm a practitioner this
is my first hearing about crest so uh
thanks for sharing that uh my question
maybe is to uh wakeem a bit when you
found that credential was there guidance
in the cab t that that was going to be a
critical finding and uh to was there any
guidance about how to handle that like i
noticed you kind of tried to explore the
capability of that credential was that
the correct approach or should you have
gone back to the client right away and
said hey i have a credential
what's it all about
yeah yeah that's a good question
um when we saw
the potential things that we could do i
mean we
actually had to test them i mean
when we tell the customer and we're
going to let them know about something
critical we cannot go with a false
positive you know
so
as
we graph a working proof of concept
and we understand what the impact is
because we have done this previous uh
threat modeling on their business
and we can share that with some context
you know um
so
validating the credential would be the
appropriate yeah yeah yeah yeah we we
needed to do that i mean
um
because we couldn't go with again a
false positive or a false sense of maybe
criticality
lends itself to the maturity of the
organization requesting the requirement
so the it's two two-sided right and
you're in a practitioner you get this if
the service provider is going to speak
to their client about how they would
prefer to do the work and the buyer is
interested in that and there might be
some conversation there um i know from
fire and forget sort of offensive
testing right i'm very much focused on
okay am i approved for this am i
approved for that am i proof of this
proof of that yes fire on target go so
as long as we understand what the
terms are we're good commercial sector a
little bit more fuzzy obviously the
government sector has a little bit more
gates to cross so we bring those worlds
together a little bit give a little bit
of what good looks like and people can
operate thanks for the context thanks
i think we are just about at a time but
if there's any more questions please uh
grab a ice cold beer or a college right
about ice cold
water we'll be happy to talk thank you
for your time thank you
[Applause]
welcome to our next speaker
as a reminder please when you're indoors
and conference spaces please remember to
wear your masks thank you
[Music]
you