how much is actually credited to that
particular account
got our hands on an employee card
it says no free access but
it's for free access so i don't really
know what they mean by that
test purposes only
basically this one is expired so we
weren't able to use it at all but when
we swiped it through
welcome to another evening at hope we're
nearing the end of our second day
thank you to everyone that's come to the
conference
in person and virtually and welcome to
everyone watching around the world
our next speakers
this is i've been looking forward to
this talk
medical devices are everywhere
and they are just getting more complex
less secure and easier to build all the
time
our speakers rna pam and via remote jim
will talk about security and privacy
issues with med tech and demo some very
interesting devices
thank you
thank you jen
gotta get the slides up uh close that
browser but now i know how okay
okay
and now it's so safe
say something about error
okay that was a really cool video of
eric at the very first hope conference
and he was actually about to introduce
jim who is not here but
he asked us to play that video for that
reason so
sorry about that skip this slide we
don't need the other video you know how
to do it right here you go yep okay
okay so we have with us today rna also
known as regina
um
she has done the bulk of the hard work
on these slides so please enjoy them um
me i'm pam i have uh
a long history with this conference but
from many many decades ago and uh she's
the first organizer of the first hope
and the second that was yeah
[Applause]
don't worry i have one of your medical
devices and the only one you'll see down
demoed live so
we'll embarrass you with that that'll be
embarrassing enough trust me
oh yeah you know i'm the daughter of
sound man and i forgot that so this is
my first time speaking at a conference
at all i usually run them
for like 30 years
so
thank you all for attending our talk
um jim will be attending um he asked
actually to call and i i asked to limit
it just to the question and answer so if
you have questions you might want to ask
jim as this talk goes on think about
them
but
we'd prefer questions first too because
he doesn't speak very well he had a bad
stroke
anyway those are our rules they're very
minimal
i don't know if i call them rules
they're not really wrong
and we were gonna play you the cool he's
dead jim compilation but
um many people reported that was too
morbid he is not dead
jimmy joke it's a joke it was actually
his request yes
but it's a joke oh look there's all the
details about me that i probably said
half of
so i have been hacker me almost since
birth my dad was at bell labs in the 60s
it was inevitable basically he taught me
how to take things apart and look at
them and put them back together
ah
i love to do that anyway um
my first speaking
uh engagement was with the amateur
computer group of new jersey when i was
10. i demoed a cool we had a digital
sound crossing chip processing chip
we went among the first people to get
one and we put it in our trs-80 and then
we could play four-part harmony music
and no one ever heard anything like that
before so we programmed it me and my dad
and then i demoed it
so
anyway um been a part of this crowd
since the early 90s pardon not work if
anybody knows what that is off the hook
sometimes decades passed
and
as
we've already heard too much early hope
um i also was
momentarily half a second famous for
paging the white house paging
scandal transcripts back in 19
i don't remember all four living
presidents appeared at an event in
philadelphia
and someone intercepted the paging
content
and could read it
and someone gave it to me at a ham fest
many many months later and i published
it online and then it went viral like
crazy picked up by the national news
japan
international wired uh
the white house had to put out a press
briefing about it oh my god we know our
paging trans our pagers are insecure
we're switching but we can't do it yet
whatever they did a little dance and
then that's it that's everything about
me really that's relevant except i am
also going to demonstrate my own medical
device later
because i push the wrong button hey this
is rna
again do you want to read your own self
no okay so she has also been a part of
the hacker crowd since the 1990s
actually at least one month longer than
me because she met my husband at a
meeting and he said
you're really gonna like pam
he did and he was right yes she's my
best friend she was the second person i
met at my first 2600 meeting
and she has volunteered at every hope
conference except for that very first
one
otherwise she would have met me there
and then whatever
uh but
part of original not work which was a
cool little hacker collective
and
this is really cool early user satan at
a university in a major metropolitan
city which i will not name
um
and ran it and got
i would say
not as severely reprimanded as i
expected
but you were reprimanded they didn't
like you definitely remember the yt
department it was in the early 90s they
didn't like it
but she still had a job
okay and then there's jim who'll be
we'll be calling in later for questions
and answers he's the guy who started the
reason for this talk because he has an
implanted defibrillator
and um
pacemaker but he also is the metro hard
card hacker also known as red balaclava
jeopardy jim he's got like three handles
okay one isn't enough for him apparently
uh he's also got involved he'd been
around the community a little bit
earlier but
didn't really get involved in meetings
until the early 90s and as we just said
he predicted our friendship before we
ever met so that's kind of cool for us
anyway um he has spoken at many hope
conferences about the metro card and
about some other stuff
and including the first and second ones
in 94-97
famous as the metro card hacker front
page of the new york times woohoo
okay
and this is the only graphic gym ever
designed we just thought it was cute
it's a doonsberry he cut and pasted our
faces over a dudesberry cartoon however
it does say nothing is sexier than a
geek girl on a coding run i'm the coder
in the family not him
but he did that
like 30 years ago okay oh off to me okay
let's talk about medical devices what do
we know all right so
um
we're going to talk a little bit about
medical devices security privacy hacking
and you
um but in case anyone wants a synopsis
of the talk i can oh here's the
microphone i can give it in one line in
general
electronic devices are not secure i
think we all know this i don't mean step
on any infosec people's toes but they're
just not secure everybody in this room
has a
smartphone yeah you're being it's i call
it my spy device i'm not the only one to
call it that they're not secure the end
we can all go home
don't do that
yeah please don't leave so
knowing that why would you want to put
something that can control your body
through electrodes and talk to your most
intimate organs and you know what would
impel you to do something so foolhardy
so there's a lot of good reasons so
we're going to start with the positive
these devices it's very appealing to
have some information about your health
these devices monitor and improve your
health that's what they're
supposedly designed to do
some can directly affect your body
pacemakers insulin pumps right we know
this these diseases monitor and manage
conditions
uh replace functionality your heart's
not doing well we're gonna make it work
better you're missing a limb we're gonna
give you a limb right we're gonna
implant it and and have it improve um
improve your health improve your
well-being if they decrease all-cause
mortality and they greatly increase
quality of life they do that
um since we're talking about privacy of
healthcare information i'm going to
point out i specifically have permission
jim our friend jim had heart failure
which is a very serious disease of high
morbidity and dangerous fibrillation
ventricular fibrillation
again high morbidity he was tried to
treat with medications very very common
medications don't always work so he has
now an implant that can do a better job
than any physician you know any kind of
monitoring he could live in an emergency
room and he's still going to do better
with an implant constantly monitors his
heart rate looks for deviations from
patterns scans for irregularities if
detected they can be re-synchronized if
his heart goes into a full-scale
defibrillation which is a
life-threatening event
you uh you get a shock
re-synchronizes restarts the heart
and his device is called a crt a cardiac
resynchronization therapy and
defibrillator so it does two things in
once can you say something yes yes
here's the mic
uh he also has this cool wand which
he can't find that he's supposed to
wave over his heart if he feels weird
that actually there's
it'll make a report it will immediately
report the telemetry to his doctor he
has a cell phone
expressly only from abbott labs for that
purpose no less than five feet away from
him at all times except you lost the
wand yeah so so we're talking about
communications right so there's so
you've got the near field communications
from the wand and then it communicates
with the phone which goes right out over
wireless so there's yeah that's you're
fine
so you've got leaks right there so pam
has this intractable chronic pain very
sad so sorry um medications help reduce
it but they can't stop it so now they
have spinal implants and i'm going to
say most implants like as in general
because i'm going to show you some
pictures of a lot they all have some
electrical way to connect to your body
and give it instructions in a sense they
all do the same thing they give you some
kind of shock in a very specific way
right you vary the power you vary the
pulse length um you you vary the the
rate and uh surprisingly at least
surprisingly to me all of these things
can do
can do things to your body that help
improve your health in in in a generally
a safe way
um
okay
so and her tell us about your uh implant
how much better is your pain okay um
just in a sentence though okay one
sentence i'm normally at an eight from
where the device is from here down i'm
at a four
yeah that's huge so that's a pain scale
that goes from being unable to do
anything to being functional
yeah functional
and we're happy much happier so back to
the title jim is not dead but your
privacy may be so we all like having
good health i kind of maybe just sold
some of these medical devices to you
you're probably thinking of what's the
problem so my medical information leaks
out a little bit okay so let's start
from the basics do we want privacy right
i'm gonna start complaining that these
things leak out your medical data and
your privacy they impair your privacy
so there's a lot of people younger
people especially that feel that privacy
is not that important anymore who needs
it you know i don't care if somebody
knows my heart rate or my temperature if
my temperature goes up and i'm a covered
risk or
an influenza risk like that's okay i'm
going to stay home maybe somebody tells
me to stay home and that's good because
i didn't know
it's all good um however it turns out
even though that's what you you might
feel is true by by just talking casually
to people when people are polled and
explained explicitly what kind of
information is being released 95 percent
of people polled do not
want
their medical data released they want it
private so people in fact do want
privacy and they do understand when it's
explained to them they do they do feel
and understand that they don't want to
share that data which makes total sense
to me there's been studies done over and
over so let's just say that that's an
understood thing so people possess
various levels of privacy just to kind
of break it out they possess bodily
privacy uh as well as personal
information financial right territorial
so the drone doesn't come and look at
you communication privacy which we all
have lost because the smartphones um but
bodily privacy for the first time in
history uh is now can be accessed by
medical devices medical devices they
might surprise you include fitbits
smartphone apps and maybe it doesn't
surprise you retinal implants which are
have been around since um i think 2009
getting better all the time they now
have wireless communication with retinal
implants and they can upload data to it
that's very interesting
wireless blood pressure machines right
genome tests you might not think of that
as a medical device but it falls into
under the corpus of the data that's
provided personal health information tsa
body scans not intended as a medical
device but they can tell your weight
they can tell your height they can tell
your gait they can tell a lot of
information from a tsa body scan and
guaranteed they do not delete those
things
the collection of data from your daily
activities when you walk when you run
when you bike
when you sit how fast you type that's a
biometric uh
information that's collected when you're
on your smartphone may not seem like a
big deal okay over time your typing rate
may change and that may indicate a
mental health problem or an aging
acceleration so and you may not want
that information out that's too bad
because it's going to be out um without
your permission with or without your
permission your eye motions how do you
track what you're seeing on the screen
that's collected your sleeping patterns
we all know that's collected because
your phone politely goes off at night
and perks up again in the morning
personally i think this is too much
information but you know let's keep
talking all of these may be combined
with each other and correlated to come
to very surprising conclusions and
combined with health data from all other
medical devices so
that's something
so
again about your privacy so here's an
example
this surprised me i hope that you guys
find this little surprising
not too surprising google bought fitbit
okay they paid two point something
billion dollars for it
must have some value your walking data
right who cares okay so now they have
fitbit so they own all that data your
data and then they went out and bought
the um electronic health record company
ascension
this should really
irritate everyone in the room and
everyone listening to that they this
talk they bought your electronic health
records your private health records that
we were assured when this program
started would remain private there your
conversations with your doctor your
interactions with your physician all
your medical health data whatever you
tell them whatever prescription to
everything that what you tell your
doctor not only isn't private it's been
sold and it's been sold on this massive
scale it's been sold to google it's been
sold to amazon it's been sold to
facebook it's gone it's gone i mean it's
gone now some of you might feel well
it's probably anonymized we'll talk
about that
in one second so um
so here's a fun fact
five days of walking data from a fitbit
or any walking app
they don't have to be contiguous so just
five days of your walking data can be
used that data to uniquely identify you
from a medical database of over
100 million individuals a hundred
million individuals of anonymized data
so you take your little fitbit you know
your gate however you walk around and
they pull out your entire medical health
record from an anonymized database
that's just one thing
right there's lots of data out there
this is just walking data um google
in addition to that google publishes
research uh regularly on how they can
use the apps that they collect from your
smartphone we're not even talking about
hacking or medical devices yet we're
just talking about medical information
they
have ways that they count as reliable
and they're published and they and
physicians agree with them i don't know
if i do i don't know if you're going to
after you hear this they can take your
walking gait and say that they can
predict that if you will or will not
have alzheimer's
that's weird in my opinion they can say
whether or not you're depressed or
whether you have any mental health
issues again this might sound really
good but think about what if they make a
mistake are we all reading in the news
now that uh this has nothing to do with
medical devices but the serotonin
reuptake inhibitors the antidepressants
that have been on the market for decades
uh now are being shown like oh my god it
looks like depression doesn't have
anything to do with a problem with
serotonin reuptake uh too bad you know
we've been prescribing all this time so
there are mistakes made in medical
diagnoses mistakes that the whole field
will make for decades and then somebody
will say oh no this is a new paradigm
now so what if google has an algorithm
that is accepted by everyone that says
you have mental health disease and
furthermore for public safety
you have to have this medication which
we put little rfid tags in so we know
whether you've taken it you're going to
have to show us that you've taken it
because for your neighbor or for the
community or to reduce everybody's
health costs because we're all covered
by insurance i find this to be a highly
invasive problem that i don't think
enough people are aware of so i hope
i've drawn a picture that makes some of
you say hmm is this okay is this
socially okay do i feel good about this
maybe you can't tell but i'm not a fan i
don't
yes so here's so there's medical devices
that we're going to say more about and
the ones that are implanted well they
have um unique ids like your phone uh
and here's the information that is
freely broadcast on by these devices
when they're used by everyone who has
any kind of medical implant that's a box
no it's actually showing them right okay
it's information yes oh oh yeah it's on
that if you wanted to then
this in for this number is on the side
everyone has unique information your
name
your name your physical address your
date of birth your social security
number with every transmission boom all
over the world wherever it goes on the
internet social security number you're
along with your name and physical
address your your um date of birth email
address date and location of the data
collection so if you're moving around it
doesn't have a gps it'll triangulate
from the towers that you're
communicating with your phone number
your fax number your medical chart
identifier which is a unique number uh
your physician and or hospital medical
insurance carrier the ip address that
the information like a ping information
how it was transmitted the unique
identifier of the medical device and its
serial number and a software version and
the data command communication path or
tower id
that's just normal that's just what they
send out that's a lot of information i
don't normally even send out my social
security number in like email or text i
mean hope nobody in this room does but
this is that's by itself and i don't
like to to disclose that so now this is
this whole corpus of information that's
just the header that's just the header
then there's the then there's the
payload of the actual medical
information
so
jim is not dead but your security may be
and this is the security of the device
is what i meant by that so it turns out
that these have been studied and
probably many people in the room because
people have been chatting with me for
two days now about this a lot of people
are aware of the different flaws in
different devices
there's not a medical device out there
that doesn't have a security flaw boom
okay done so they all have these
security flaws and there's tons of legal
cases i mean i have some references
embedded in my talk i'm happy to share
the slides but
all you have to do is take a phrase and
google it it's like not a secret so they
have tons of security flaws there's tons
of legal cases google's been sued for
leaking data i don't even think they've
had it for more than five years i've
already had some some large cases about
that that they've lost
and the reported incidence of violations
per year
has gone up it does not decreasing so
these things are revealed right various
hacks or abilities to reprogram or
different problems security flaws and
there may be some are fixed and then you
get new ones and maybe some persist for
years even though they're known security
problems
separate from this fact is what we've
already said that your health data is
shared and sold uh from these devices
and from many other places somehow while
also complying with hipaa laws so you
start to get the feeling that these
things are happening
and we're not really protected it seems
to me a no-brainer you got a medical
device you got medical records you got
this private stuff should it be sold no
let's have a look against that because
that doesn't seem right i i don't know
how much you have to think about it when
you meet to make laws
but yet we're not protected um and
anonymized data as i showed is a fantasy
this is people can say well we anonymize
it so don't worry about it it's okay we
got this under control
it's not possible there's no anonymized
data there's no anonymized health data
um so we just said that your walking
data can identify you and i i pointed
out that i think that's really awful and
your phone every phone now has an app
for walking data did you ever wonder
like why it's like the weather app which
i think a lot of you may have heard is
also famously insecure and steals a lot
of data while it's serving you the
weather
that it doesn't need
except you know to steal it and resell
it so your phone collects your walking
data did you turn that off i turned mine
off but it doesn't matter it doesn't
matter you can tell me you turned it off
but in fact they collect it anyway when
you turn it off what it means is that
you don't see it
right uh it doesn't mean that they don't
see it they collect it and it's either
in the eua when you get your phone
because people are going to say no if i
say no they can't collect it they can't
collect it it's too valuable not to
collect it's something that you can't
trace and you can't prove and they can
sell if you can't protect it yourself
and you can never prove that it's been
stolen i guarantee you that someone's
taking it that's just common sense um
and it's too easy it's too valuable and
it's too easy
so there's another study there's tons of
these studies that show how you can
de-anonymize data
but i liked this particular mit
study and this is an article it's not
really research paper from 2013 okay
from 2013 which means things have gotten
better since then and what they found in
this paper what did i say you said
better the worse you know what i mean
it's after 10.
so what they found is four
imprecise data points
over a population of 1.5 million
individuals allows unique identification
of who the data points belong to 95 of
the time and what i liked about this
study is that they specifically made the
data points imprecise now we'd have to
go back to the paper i actually don't
remember what the four were i remember
one of them was an insecure location so
they would triangulate the position with
the towers but they didn't use precise
location they used like a radius of
several blocks or something um so
there's an imprecise location i think
that was imprecise i don't want to say
too much because now i'm guessing some
kind of imprecise medical data uh and
two other things and they specifically
designed it to be imprecise which i
think i just said that twice because i
found it so impressive um
and unique identification of the
individual 95 time and if you made one
of the measurements precise the unique
identification percentage went up to
almost 99
so
that's how little data you need how
sparse the data can be and you can still
do a unique identification this is
another way that i'm showing that
anonymized data like forget it
um
is somebody talking
is that you
somebody's better okay i'm going to
ignore it it's fine um so here's just a
panoply of wireless implantable medical
devices they're scattered all over the
body i don't really need to
i mean i'm happy to fill up questions
but you know it doesn't matter what they
are they all work by electrostimulation
um they're all implanted and i added two
because i thought they were very
interesting one is a neurostimulator for
headaches and it's interesting if you
google it i should have put a graphic up
because it's this long skinny thing that
just goes up your nose
and and stimulates a nerve that goes to
the brain and actually allows vaso
dilation so that when you have it and
it's for very severe headaches you don't
just go around sticking this thing up
your nose it's indwelling and um so if
you have a migranure or cluster
headaches and you can't treat them you
just put this thing well they implant
this thing up your nose and for some
reason i found that very amazing because
headaches can be chronically
hello can everyone can hear me right
you're not sleeping or anything okay
thank you thank you i heard that it's an
aura um and epiretinal implants oh yeah
i just got much louder epiretinal
implants i also find fascinating um a
colleague of mine sheila nirenberg who's
at cornell actually is one of the people
that's designing this so i can talk a
little bit more um knowledgeably about
this because i've actually seen it but
it's a it's a it's an implant that
actually goes in your eye they actually
take out all the vitreous fluid they
take out your cornea they actually dig
in there and they do this with people
who are totally blind or who have
various diseases where they you know it
leads to blindness and they want sight
because i can't think of another reason
that you'd let your eyeball be dug out
but but they work amazingly so they they
sit on your
retina and if you're blind the retina is
not working it's not sending signals
through your um optic nerve to your
occipital region and so you're not
getting any information from the
environment any photonic information
from the environment
so these these devices have been once
they're implanted people can see
outlines uh um and uh figures and they
can actually navigate the world they
can't quite drive but they can walk and
they can see things and it's an amazing
and this is just the first generation
it's like when we had black and white tv
and it was grainy and everything um you
know and you'd say well where are they
going to go with this and now look what
we have did somebody have a question
you know what i heard about that and
they had a very interesting problem they
had these companies
that uh
it was like they maintained the software
or something yeah
yeah and then those companies closed
like shut down where they had no more
support oh wow
wow
now i have this like device yeah
yeah what do i do
and that's another issue that's not even
in my talk that's thank you that's a
very good point yeah what happens when
this device like the operating system
gets outdated or the company goes out of
business or they just don't feel like
updating because they want you get a new
implant so thank you for bringing that
up and it's it's something to consider
you know you get your smartphone every
few years but it's a little harder when
it's in your body and under your skin
so
um
okay so i'm i hear i'm running out of
time so okay so meta thank you medical
device communication right i haven't
actually said anything about the way
that the information is getting on and
off these devices except by leakage uh
as i was saying earlier so i'm gonna
start with the little picture on the
bottom it's very simple and and i'm sure
a lot of people in the room are already
aware of this but
it gives a reality to the to the devices
so they're very simple right they have a
microcontroller and the microcontroller
talks um to actually five things so
there's a sensor
actuator actuators if you have like an
artificial arm and a sensor is what
you'd use to collect data and you could
have multiple sensors too so if it's a
defibrillator you have a sensor that's
maybe a pressure sensor or an electrical
um signal sensor that's telling you how
fast the heart is beating because that's
the important information so what you
also have is this information is analog
and i left this off the slide when you
transceive it it says communication
device is going to be a transceiver just
a normal transceiver um you're
transceiving you're sending digital data
so you need an analog to digital
converter in there that's going to
probably be on the controller and then
what else would you expect right you
have memory so that you can do
uh management of the data you can prune
it you can denoise it um you can
pre-process it much like the retina does
with the data that it gets um if you
have multiple channels coming in you can
fuse it to save bandwidth whatever you
need done there might be an ai that
makes decisions on the data you've
collected the frequency of the heartbeat
but now you have to know is it does it
pass a cut off uh where it's dangerous
and the device has to do something so
there's some decisions uh that are made
on some devices
um so that would happen on the
controller so you have the memory for
that right for the comp computations the
power supply the transceiver and the
sensor and that's pretty much it it's
actually very simple to get to get this
into your body oh
and we'll sort this out so the
communication frequencies that they
transmit on are going to be in the ism
band uh that would be the industrial
scientific medical bands and it has many
frequencies the
allure of this is that these are um
you don't need to be licensed in order
to use these frequencies so you have
this is not in much use right now but
the 173 these are megahertz 433 i'm sure
if you guys are familiar with these and
then the most common is the right around
at gigahertz um which would be 915 and
it's 2400 2.4 gigahertz i wrote 2400 um
or uh 5 gigahertz and those are the
common bands you don't need a license
which is makes it very easy for the
manufacturers there's bluetooth
communication it depends on the device
and devices can multiple antennas
there's zigbee which i don't know if
people are aware of that but that's what
your appliances use to communicate with
the world and i don't know about any of
you but you know i don't know why i need
to wirelessly communicate with my
washing machine and my fridge and i
actually had to get a fridge or fridge
that exploded and right during covid so
it was sort of a pretty urgent thing but
anyway i had to go out and get a fridge
and the first thing i did was i opened
the grill on the top and i climbed in
there
to bro to pull out the wireless antenna
which was was on its separate i mean you
got many of you have seen this right it
was on a separate chip you just unplug
it i was very pleased that i was able to
find it so quickly because no the
manufacturer wouldn't tell me like no
one would oh you can't take that out
okay well you can pull it out but it
turns out also this device was um
whatever the one i got was was a couple
of years old now those chips are on the
main board you can't pull them out so
easily if you disable the communication
device on your appliances they won't
work i have a problem with this too i
don't really know how to fix it right
now and that's not what this talk is
about but i'm making you guys aware of
this
so
okay so i'm really cutting it close um
they
they use one watt of power or near field
communication so now i'm gonna
zip through this so um this is a code
this can be arduino code you can go on
hacksterio that's what that
link is to and this is a high school
project like ninth grade or something
and you can get and all the instructions
on where to buy the pieces are like a
texas instrument temperature sensor and
an arduino you put this code in and
you've got a continuous temperature
monitoring device for yourself or your
cat or whatever you want to monitor the
temperature and this is just a few words
on what kind of sensors there are
so
what could go wrong is maybe really what
could go right
right we already know what can go wrong
as the whole talk was about so what goes
right um well the good thing is the
devices on their own rarely simply
misfire they they work fine right the
problem is all with the security and
keeping the the information oh my god i
just remembered i have some slides i
really want to show you guys um they're
based on older existing devices you know
i'm just going to skip this but that
that's a problem because if there's a
security problem it just rolls over and
yet the fda prefers you to um you they
give preferential treatment if you use
an existing advice you can get it
approved and on the market within 90
days so it's a it's a competing um
interest and the peer the person who
suffers is a consumer
so this slide basically just says that
when
companies that do threat intelligence
this particular company i have to say it
has a global network of sensors and
honey pots they collect a hundred
terabytes of data per day
when they do this this information
probing to check for security they found
that um
there was high vulnerability
with all personal health information
including medical devices so i'll skip
most the slide you can see the numbers
um medical devices
were probed and found to be horribly
insecure and they've been shown
repeatedly to be insecure
um remaining so in 2022 this i only
picked 2014 because this one was in all
the news this company norse and sends
they do this every year and the numbers
have not gotten any better but this one
was in the news interestingly even
though it happens annually and the
numbers stay the same not so newsy
anymore so um and keep in mind newer
medical technology and testing devices
radiological tests ct scanners mri
machines network attached information
goes out because your doctor might be
remote you know you want to see what
your skin is
along with the rest of the world anyone
who can intercept those packets
i'm going to skip this on the dmca but
i'm just going to say that somehow
um the dmca weakens the security on
medical devices unintended consequence
and important it has important effects
on making sure that none of us have
really good security
so this is i think interesting and then
i'll end after this these are some
unclassified slides these were
classified uh from 2010 and the reason i
find it interesting is before
medical devices before the ubiquity of
smartphones
and this is a from a series of seminars
that was given by the nsa paid for by
your tax dollars where they were
targeting high value individuals and
they were using
the stupidest name i can think of for
finding your the corpus of your medical
information they called it the medical
pattern of life i don't know why i think
that's really goofy but the point is
that the nsa was interested and they're
serious organization right they're not
frivolous they're not fooling around and
having a party or they're not supposed
to be
you know putting projects together um
they're using their signal intelligence
to enable what they're calling human
intelligence and they're collecting all
the medical information and i will speed
through these i found these fascinating
and there's a link to these that i can
provide but they define medical
intelligence and look at this last nine
medications medical tests medical
surgical treatments hospital and doctor
businesses before right all this
electronic health records you know for
sure that's going to be in there and
medical devices all going to be in these
files um
that they collect on a high value
individual oh but wait a minute in 2010
high value individuals might have been i
don't know osama bin laden right but now
we're all high value individuals compute
power has gotten enormous compared to
2010 um the the the fact is that your
medical information has a financial
value that makes each of us a high value
information and it's so easy to keep it
on each individual facebook has proven
that right we all have a file and it's
very easy to populate it with
information okay i hope you guys don't
mind i'm going a little over um
so
let's see did i go backwards yes
so and here's from 2010 again here's
their picture so clearly they're
anticipating medical devices and they're
showing that they're tiny they're
embeddable they can be um
uh queried covertly they have accuracy
despite horror signal environments um
which i interpreted to mean inside the
body it could also mean if you're going
over harsh terrain i suppose uh and at
that time they're talking about rfid
which is very small short range but the
point is they were anticipating medical
devices so now you have the nsa
who has an interest in this information
to me that just underscores it's
definitely valuable i mean we know it
but here's another proof of it
so i'm just going to read the title poor
security is just a well-known
vulnerability you can see all these
quotes and stuff but i think i've shown
it to you
um so what about right now in 2022 so
i'm going to skip to this
the second part of this slide 75 after
some studies and quotes from these
people and all these other things um 75
of medical internet of thing devices
have known security gaps this is 2022
and 75 percent so i just said this they
have these security gaps these are
related to 40 known vulnerabilities and
52 remain open to two known
vulnerabilities with high and critical
severity ratings that are things that
were that are those are openings that
can definitely be used to kill you and
these were first disclosed those
particular ones 2019 so i guess they're
not that worried about it encryption
some other time and now i'm going to
hand it over to pam who's going to talk
about the specific devices that they
have thank you very much and we are
going to go a little bit into the q a
time sorry
um so jim's device is super cool it
keeps him alive okay because first it's
a pacemaker that does the normal work
and then it's a defibrillator oh my god
his heart is stopping he will give you a
very short video in a minute where he
pretends he's having a heart attack it's
very silly
and then shows you what he would do to
send the telemetry to his doctor um but
he will also be available for q a in a
few minutes um anyway that's what his
device does and it it looks like that on
the inside it's actually two separate
devices then they plug them together and
he just had a new battery he needed a
new battery
it's it is it's
i did not want to show everyone a
picture of my husband's naked chest
sorry you would not be impressed but
it's about that big and
and then the defibrillator is actually
probably about that big but
you know
it looks like a lump and it goes right
under the skin by the way i don't know
if you guys hear me visibly people
surgery and then they thread the two
leads to your heart through your your
vein your i don't know if it's art of
your vein but they thread it through and
they use um like radio radiological like
microwaves or not microwaves i'm sorry i
don't remember what they use but they
use some kind of imaging technique to
make sure that they fluoroscopy
what was that fluoroscopy do they use
yes absolutely that's a lot of radiation
yes it is they use it for mine anyway
uh we don't really care about these
words we just use half of them if you
really want to know you can have the
slides afterwards
this
yes um this is more words about how
jim's device works really not that
important but really excellent
great research
uh
i don't know if this will work
oh shoot that's not good well
um
i will send it out to anyone who cares
but jim filmed a very silly 30 second
video of himself i could probably hold
it up on my phone and play it for you
but um pretending to have a heart attack
and then what he would do with his
device and he didn't really remember it
is a little sad he doesn't have any
memory loss he just didn't remember what
he was supposed to do so
sorry
okay my device however i know everything
about and it's here with me and i can
even demonstrate it uh
it is always with me at all times
because it's in my it goes from here to
here
and if anybody couldn't see that it's
like from the bottom of my where my
brides which is t8 if you know your
spinal column issues down to my sacral
area um and i have a cool new battery
pack first i had a little test for a
week that had its own tiny battery like
a watch battery but now then they had to
go in and implant a huge battery pack
which i now have to recharge about once
every 10 days
so
i have a remote control which makes me
feel like i'm a robot i also have two
programs which also make me feel like
i'm a robot um i don't know if that
makes me a robot i don't know show hands
am i a robot if i have a remote control
programmer okay
i'm a robot i think i'm a robot i also
have a lot of titanium implants uh here
to hear c3 to c7
uh yeah
cyborg i like that that's better it's
better than robot yeah okay so this one
makes a lot of beeping sorry sorry sound
people first it makes beeping to tell
you i guess it's alive
but what this stand out there so people
can see
but then it won't be by the mic i don't
know okay so this thing
okay now it's telling me
it's telling me almost in range but it's
not because my battery pack is right
here
and that thing blinking if you can see
it
is supposed to tell me how close it is
okay now it realizes it's not close at
all
and it really should not be through two
or three or four layers of fabric which
it is right now
but that's that's what it does this
rubbery thing
goes
up against this thing that looks like a
scar right here
because i only had it done a month ago
and it recharges my battery quite
literally
it easier to show oh and talk into mic
about
what what um
not that long but hey
uh i can show you oh wait the chargers
no it's right here if you want to
examine the charger you can look at its
frequencies if you'd like but it takes
the whole thing to to recharge itself um
about four hours
so this is my programmable remote
i have two programs um i was on the
first program for a very long time and
then i said to my doctor should i change
the program he was like you haven't
changed the program yet so i did
um
right now it shows me the strength of my
battery i don't know if you can see it
but it's at three out of four dots it's
pretty strong i haven't charged it for
like a week
um
i'm at a four out of seven intensity on
my program and i'm on p1 today just why
not i was screwing around with it and i
left it there
right now
i turned up my intensity now it's it
went up a notch and i'm also going to
change what the program is
to two now the number two is blinking oh
my god
i changed my program while i'm standing
here
is that a communication channel keep in
mind that she's communicating with your
device
we did actually stand next to each other
with her rf meter and try to capture all
the packages i have a little trouble
capturing the channel is the question do
you want it just curious
when you turn your intensity up does
that reduce your pain it's supposed to
yes and actually um i haven't really
needed it to and i probably wouldn't be
here today and i only had this put in on
june 21st so
it's reduced my pain already from an
eight to a four every day and i can like
walk up hills and walk around whereas
that would have really hurt me and i
would have been in bed for the rest of
the day
even a month ago sure please
so i just i just want to give some
detail in case people are interested in
how it works so it has two i don't know
if you can tell from this picture
actually it's not in the picture so you
can't tell it has a couple of leads that
go into a main nerve fiber and what this
does is it obfuscates the signals that
the body's sending because when you have
chronic pain you're you're maladaptively
sending like pain signals to a light
touch or to an inappropriate stimuli
um everything for everything and you're
constantly it's like you're constantly
on fire or constantly having pain so
this thing interrupts the transmission
of those signals up your spinal column
by specifically uh sending a 10 000
um kilohertz and i keep saying megahertz
that's wrong that's a 30 meter handband
so it's 10 000 kilohertz
right and the interesting thing about
that and i think her i'm not sure if
your program one is this but the older
programs are much lower frequency
they're like 30 um
hertz that's much lower it's closer to
the biological frequency the natural
frequency and with pa that works but the
patients experience the tingling because
that's a frequency that your body can
recognize
so the new
program that she has it doesn't have
that it's called paresthesia that
tingling but it interrupts the
transmission of those signals so back to
pam that makes total sense to me because
i can't feel it at all
um even when i have played with it okay
i'm a hacker i have turned it up to
seven on both programs to see if i could
feel it i cannot
okay this is what it's called it's from
the ancient greek i don't know how to
pronounce that in ancient greek or any
kind of greek but
never
really really awesome so it
says the same sounds the same
in english and greek
oh hey regina look sends two signals we
have two wires that are implanted in the
dorsal horn of my spine
did you not just say that oh but there
is no login or password and it it um
that crazy yeah you know so if you all
want to come up here and try to hack it
you can but there is no login or
password um my doctor might have one if
he wanted to make a new program
i don't know but i will ask him when the
next time
he he uses the same this is a near field
communication device i think we just
said this right yeah and it's uh that
they consider that secure because why
would anyone else have this i don't know
don't take it from me yeah and you just
have to be near enough to the device to
do an upload
so don't hack me either bros
i know
okay i'm going home now no i could never
do that anyway um awesome rules
uh details thank you um so that's how it
works
yes there's this thing right below my
waist it's a big lump right now because
this hasn't really fully integrated into
my body but it really has completely
changed my life in under a month
right oh wait wait two more days past a
month sorry but um i just did the live
device demo so
questions toastman oh wait
i promised i promised
mr james he of the defibrillator that
when we have q a in case anyone wanted
to ask him a question i would call him
so but questions for us
any we do have a microphone over here so
that our friends watching online can
also hear your questions
just a
recommend it suggestion
medical devices but um appliances like
uh on the internet you can block it at
the router level right yeah um and if
it's like using rf
they they sell those pouches where you
put your cell phone in and then
you mean like the refrigerator and put
it in yeah
yeah i i would try that i have an rf
meter and that might that might work so
that's that's a suggestion
so you get exactly what they are um
yeah yeah
so i want to actually say something
about that because people buy those rfid
bags all the time to everybody
and actually they as you go up in
frequency they work less and less
efficiently and this goes back to
maxwell's laws for physics you know
college physics but um you need the mesh
to be tighter and tighter and you need
the thickness of the metal to be
increasing in order to block those high
frequencies so they're not all as
effective as you think who am i looking
at you should be at the mic oh i'm so
sorry can you guys hear me
not really oh gosh you should have
screamed at me i'm sorry
rfid bags oh that is much louder they
don't work as efficiently as you go up
in frequency so with 5g phones if you're
putting in that little pouch they're
still tracking you by the way as a
commercial message your friend jim who
this talk was partially about is now
attending via video okay
[Applause]
did you have a question or i'm sorry
i feel like we do need so you've talked
a lot about some very interesting
vulnerabilities that these devices have
uh in terms of bigger pictures what's
going on there
is does it just seem like no movement
ever
what do you see next um so that's an
interesting question i
i have a little uh trouble looking ahead
because what i don't see wait that thing
is talking why is that talking i'll tell
you why in a minute okay what i what i
really don't see is without people
having knowledge of this and being upset
about it and demanding privacy i don't
see this going backwards um it's very
easy rf communications are invisible
unless everybody walks around with our
rf detector and then still what are they
going to do i have a detector all the
time and i go there's a big signal here
you know i can't go and hide myself in a
little faraday cage so i think
what i would love to see is if i raise
enough consciousness that people object
and then the manufacturers have to go
backwards in this
if is that a question or a hello
hello
ah ah okay good all right thank you and
i am sorry regina but the reason
we're on time delay jim is on time
delays i'm hearing yourself speaking
through oh wow that is confusing
right
any other questions or
hello oh hi hi so uh just a random
question if you do lose oh there we go
uh say you lost your remote or it breaks
what's the process like to get a new one
do they have to switch out your device
and you're back or there's just like a
keep like repairing with a different
device
totally i'm sure i'd have to go to the
doctor's office but they could give me a
new one and then re-key it to my device
i've
they actually told me that when they
gave it to me but
and i had a different remote for the
seven-day trial one two and i didn't
lose that one either but
i have no intention to lose it
uh
however oh i learned a cool new fact
today by the way if anyone else in the
room has a medical device or knows has
family with medical devices
um i keep my
favorite little gadget which is my only
computer most of the time with me in my
pocket and if you have an implanted
medical device you really really
shouldn't do that it should not be
within your pockets
at least six inches away from you at
least six so i just learned that today
while doing the research for this so
okay other questions
thanks again
okay all right that was awesome thank
[Applause]
we did it sorry there was no questions
for you jim but you got to hear it and i
recorded the whole rest of it
hanging out if anybody else has
questions and you see us just ask
no the pacemakers can't be six inches
away
oh uh
yes
recordings for all the talks are gonna
be made available
and i will add that link to this talk
and we do have one more tonight
and hopefully you'll join us for it i
will no problem you packed that
all right this was
you