[Music]
checking test check
check five seven three
two three can i like should i pop into
the microphone a whole bunch
piss off everyone at the av thank
everyone we should have a round of
applause for the av guys right now
[Applause]
the ultimate in diagnosis is figuring
out that your hdmi cable was the problem
uh i'm just going to do a real quick
audio check since like we were literally
running around trying to figure that out
so this should not be loud but
i'd like to make sure
that it's okay
yeah it's not too bad let's see if i'll
turn this down
huh yeah michael
i should be right up in its face
[Music]
all right
you'll see that demo in a minute uh
i won't jack this up too loud uh for the
sake of the av guys but uh if the if
we're watching something with thumping
tunes i'll uh i'll turn it up so you can
enjoy it
uh welcome to the demo scene 2022
electric bookaloo
[Applause]
uh i really can't see any hands so i'm
probably gonna ask you to make noise
instead of like
raise your hands or whatever who came to
a previous demo scene panel
all right
how many of you come to just one or did
you watch the one last uh hope online or
okay
um i'm i'm a very
i don't know um
maybe maybe i'm not a
unique presenter but i i prefer that
people talk to me and
yell at me and you know like whatever so
that's that's fine
uh this is intended to be entertaining
but also you know so that you can learn
something so
uh hopefully we'll do a little bit of
both uh i promise not to get too
cerebral if you have a question
uh you can ask it you know like uh maybe
i'll i'll try to like stop at the end of
any slides or you know every couple
slides and just ask if i've you know
lost anyone or whatever
um the beginning of the of this we're
gonna careen
through because most of it is demo scene
history
can you make some noise if you came here
and you have no clue what the
demo scene is
don't be shy if you don't know what the
demo scene is i want to hear from you
um
but um this this is just an amazing uh
computer art and music and programming
and everything scene that
i find fascinating i'm a part of the
scene
most of the stuff that you're seeing
tonight is not my work uh i think i
might make a sneak appearance in one or
two things
um but uh this is this is not me even
though you probably you might be here
because you got a slip of paper from me
in the vendor room selling chiptunes or
something like that so
i just i want to make sure that that's
clear i'm kind of trying to put my scene
on a pedestal not me
um
so uh why don't we just go ahead and get
started because i just put myself uh 15
minutes behind schedule accidentally
um so there there are some uh
flashing lights
flashing colors
uh if you are photo sensitive if you
have epilepsy or whatever maybe this
panel is not for you
uh or hopefully you've taken your meds
so uh be careful please i i don't want
to
have uh experience any problems with
that here uh
you should be healthy
uh quick shout out real fast
these are working right yeah okay good
um
i run a museum in maryland just north of
baltimore called the bloop museum it's
inside of a larger museum called the
system source computer museum
and that is inside of an i.t company
called system source believe it or not
so
i would love if you would come and visit
me i can show you our like 15 000 square
feet of space with
the stuff you see up here
and we've got some pdps that work and
we've got some craze that don't
um and you can sit on the couch you know
naugahyde couch and take a picture of
yourself with the cray like get a selfie
or whatever if you want
um we're all about being hands on
um so we would we would really love if
you came down and you know like i don't
know speed ran oregon trail and got
dysentery or something
um not real dysentery um
but uh and a couple people here uh
actually uh are here at this panel
because i told them about this panel at
the museum so uh
if you've been to bloop then please feel
free to make some noise right now
so see there are even like three people
in the audience that have been there so
it's a real place
um all right
um
so so what is the demo scene maybe what
i should do real fast is uh you know i
do have this like
cool slide thing where i'm like hey the
demo scene what are this and like by the
way these are recycled slides from
uh 2018 and 2022 which is why i'm gonna
go through them quickly you can watch
you know previous hope slides on youtube
and whatever but uh they're they're
still relevant and that's how we're
going to catch everyone up hey here's a
pretty picture
you know uh here's another pretty
picture you should look at you know like
all right uh you know here's one more
the previous two kind of look
algorithmic this one doesn't what if i
told you hey
we just watched something about movies
and hackers right anyway um
so uh
you know like all of that
doesn't fit on maybe a piece of paper
this tiny but
these these are pretty small programs
and so i want to give you an example
of an incredibly small program
uh we'll show you one demo just like
right up front
this is something that
can i just like fling you onto my other
display that would be really nice
hello there we go
here's a dos demo
did did everyone catch the file size
just now
[Music]
we've got audio
we've got a
rotating heat map
[Music]
it's 256 bytes
you can write tweets longer than this
it's pretty wild
granted that's all it does most of these
that are this small are just kind of
looping animations and sound possibly
that do something like this but
the music is very apt yeah it's like
think about the possibilities
[Music]
and then it ends because someone hit
escape or you know it crashes after a
certain amount of time
all right so um let's let's talk about
this just a little bit more i want to
catch up
uh does does anyone in here not know
uh about this this thing that computers
can do called communicate with other
computers
um
these days this is really easy but maybe
i should rewind just a little bit
uh so you know back in the tape we're
writing software and it's on paper tape
uh and we're using computers that look
like giant refrigerators and then
eventually we move on to the computers
that need refrigerators et cetera et
cetera but uh really we're just trying
to exchange ideas
so uh actually i think i like that one
better i don't i don't know which one
one two one two
one you like this okay
so so back in this era right here
um the internet looks like this um it's
not very big
um and eventually it gets a little bit
bigger but uh you know i mean this this
is good at least i don't have to figure
out the ip address is very
it's it's not difficult to get in touch
with your neighbor right um in fact it's
really not difficult to get in touch
with your neighbor your neighbor
uh will get connected to you by uh you
know a pretty girl behind a console like
this and you're using you know
a phone that looks like that all right
so eventually
uh
we we move into the future a little bit
and the internet starts looking a little
bit more like this and uh that's that's
pretty cool
uh and i i especially am appreciative
that texas
is just a place and utah is just you
know like can i tell that ntu utah
yeah
you can also telnet into illinois
i don't know
just some guy
there's also gunter down here
i think he's i think they might have
misplaced a dot from germany and just
put it in the u.s now um this is this is
pretty fascinating era
where
uh you know i mean
in the late 60s uh open source gets its
start with
anyone
maybe a little bit of eunuchs and maybe
well and there's plenty of patent and
governments i'm sure but
uh also with space war
so you know
mit gets their first uh pdp a pdp one
one computer for the whole school
uh and they decide that they're gonna
have a housewarming party for their
computer because they're a bunch of
nerds
um and uh it turns out that wine and
cheese doesn't keep someone in one place
for four hours unless there's a whole
ton of wine and cheese so they
decide they're gonna write a video game
for the pdp-1 and it's also going to be
a burn-in test for the pdp-1 so
instead of finding out four years down
the line that that resistor was
uh they can just you know like find out
that that resistor is dead now
eventually other schools start getting
their computers and they're connected to
this
internet thing
and uh you know they're like hey we just
got a pdp one can we test it and start
getting
space war over the internet and you know
they call up mit and they're like hey we
made it so that if you hyperspace too
many times your ship blows up isn't that
cool and they start passing around the
code and it gets better and now then
eventually we end up with computer space
and gravity game
uh which are the arcade versions of
space war so this is a burn-in test it's
party entertainment
and
it's open source software sort of that
you know ends up in the hands of other
schools
um mad hacks so you would have to get
this directly from someone over the
internet somehow
uh but you know like
maybe you didn't go to school maybe you
hate school maybe you're just you know
stuck at home and you want to reach out
and touch someone some other way maybe
you have something like this
you know so um
you know if you've got one of one of
these things on the right
uh i don't know what that is i think
they call it a phone
um
and uh you know maybe you've got some
floppy drives or a commodore or
something like that and
uh in this era uh for those that don't
know again probably half of the room
does but
it's actually against the terms of
service with the phone company to
connect anything to your phone line
um so
this isn't just like you know
dade in hackers where he's like you know
got an injunction against him or
whatever
you know you you actually sign up for
phone service and they bring you a phone
when they hook up your line and this
this gets eliminated kind of in the
beginning of the 80s you know people
actually start having phone jacks in
their home and they've rescinded
the policy that you can't plug anything
into the phone line but for now let's
pretend that this is still uh you know
something that is required and you're
renting your phone kind of like you know
if you have a cable modem or whatever
they make you rent it they don't make
you rent it but they they strongly
encourage
uh you to rent your cable modem right so
you everyone the problem is is that if
they've got to deliver millions and
millions of phones
uh to people in their homes then they're
gonna deliver this phone over here
and it's going to look the same in
everyone's house and because it looks
the same maybe
you'll come up with some sort of device
with a microphone and a speaker that you
can just drop the phone on hey i didn't
connect anything to my phone line
uh you know i just got one of these
plugged into my computer and it listens
to the phone every once in a while it's
like an answering machine you know
um
that ends up being a great idea so
you do this
and by the way a bunch of these are like
some of them are
images i blatantly ripped off of the
internet but stuff like this is stuff
that you can see in the museum
so
here's a cool ass 300 baud modem if you
open this door there's actually a sewing
kit behind here that you can repair the
modem with which is pretty wild
um so i just thought you'd like to see
that but uh here here you go here's a
micro modem 100 like the first
haze modem right and you've got these
pins over here that you literally just
take those pins and plug jumper wires
into this
and hook it up to phone wire so there
there you go you know here's some other
internal modems actually these have
phone jacks so this would be post that
era right
some other modems i've got
who had a sportster or a courier
all right good who had the competition a
not so smart modem
wow dead air good everyone had us
robotics uh
so meanwhile in chicago right um there's
the cbbs and cbs uh bbs actually
probably just stands for computer
bulletin board system but also
uh a dude named christensen and also
chicago so there's like all these things
that start with c that cbbs could be
um you know he's like i'm just gonna
like drop a computer on the phone and
like let people call it here's my number
you know whatever you dial in and you'd
see something like what's on the screen
i'm moving my mouse cursor around but i
bet you can't see it
um
is there a pointer thing in the uh
no there isn't
oh well i'm anyway
um
so
you dial into this computer bbs and this
guy would just like let you use this
computer sounds cool right uh in other
parts of the world you'd end up here's a
uh on the left is a french minitel
terminal and on the right is an angel
note which is a little
businessman briefcase model uh basically
the minitel thing on the left but it
gives you on ntt data
which is uh an information service
that the phone company offers that you
can do a lot of the same things that you
can do on minitel and what can you do on
minitel a lot of the things that you do
on the internet you know look at ads um
you know no um you can do online banking
or stocks or you know send messages or
even do something that i think a lot of
people would consider new you can order
food on minitel like this is not
actually a new thing uh so
anyway ntt data is now the the company
that you know like if you're a teemo
customer and you go to japan and turn on
your phone uh you'll connect to ntt
instead it's just the japanese phone
company
that you would get data service from but
by the way everyone knows what at t
stands for right
someone wants to shout it out
so what is
ntt
correct okay there we go
all right this is interactive right
um so
all right so serial port because we just
experienced serial killer
you call one of these other systems that
might just be run by someone that's
maybe a little bit more off they're not
than the government
maybe the government is off they're not
i don't know um but you get all these
sort of
interesting
things you know it's like
suddenly someone figured out how to call
another computer right like wait a
second
anyone ever seen any of these
this thing called compuserve you know
like we're starting to discover
who remembers this
i actually really liked prodigy
can i tell you a really good joke that
doesn't work anymore
um you used to be able to tell
someone you could say uh you know is
prodigy a band or an information service
and be able to figure out how old they
are
but now you can't do that anymore
because you say what's prodigy and
they're like
what
that's really actually it's really
disappointing because i like the prodigy
and i also like prodigy um
here's one of those things i got a
exclusive screenshot in the corner here
did anyone ever use aol for dos
down here in the corner is aol for dos
but most people probably use this
up here
aol for dos was blazing fast because
there was no windows overhead gdi is
um
and uh and here's an interesting thing
uh everything is related and everything
is a remix here's geos which is like
windows for your commodore 64.
if you can think about that for a minute
um and if you look back at the uh the
screenshot you notice how it kind of
looks like a new age version of geos so
this is geo works
geo works is like they they we're gonna
try and compete with windows and failed
miserably
but
you could actually get geos for a bunch
of different machines and operating
systems and run it
and
geos and your commodore 64
truth is stranger than fiction
aol didn't used to be call america
online it used to be called
q-link or quantum link
uh and if you've seen uh halton catch
fire where everything is like all j it's
like uh mother goose mix-ups except it's
with the i.t and tech industry
um it's actually a really good show i
like it a lot but um
here it is yeah like aol
negative five
and you could uh you can you can see the
beginning of instant messaging down here
in the corner
and chat rooms
and there was also this thing called
club career bay which also got released
as a standalone called habitat which is
recently
reverse engineered and revived so
if you want the earliest mmos
here you go
so we've got all these cool tools
to get online both dialing you know like
the nut job next door and
by you know like dialing into all these
commercial services and then people
start doing this amazing artwork right
where they're advertising their online
service that they run probably out of
their garage or basement or whatever i
should know i did one
um both the ansi art and running the bbs
actually because i didn't have any
friends um
you dial into one of these uh let's talk
specifically about bbs's now by the way
if you want the less fast version of the
bbs talk uh jason scott who i'm sure you
know
has a bbs documentary that is multi-part
and
absolutely amazing it's really good you
should watch it
you log in you can do the same that
you do on the internet you download
files
you can send messages you can play doors
you can post bulletins there's message
boards try to chat with people
chat with sysop doesn't always work
because the sysop might be like in
school because
he's not even a teenager yet
i'm making self-references here
uh
when you want to download files it might
look like this
you look through lists of files
you tag the file that you want to
download
you know so you could go over here and
say i want file number two and file
number five or whatever and then you
actually go to download it'll send you
your files
in the order you tag them
eventually you do something like this
oh hey it looks like i'm downloading
something i can run on my own dbs anyone
know what i'm downloading
excellent
you can also eventually get something
called rip term
which would give you graphics in this
like world of just text mode stuff
um you know this graphic is especially
relevant
not really um
but uh
but here's some some incredible rip term
art
so you download like vectors and
primitives
to draw real art like it's not
downloading raster images or pixels
because you know like downloading pixel
boobies takes you like
two hours
rip term could also it also had this uh
you know it could draw scroll bars
um you know and buttons and windows and
dialogs and this was really useful
because you know like
people that wanted a graphical interface
but didn't want to pay for aol finally
we can do this so you see stuff like
this and you can even download your own
rip art it's pretty great
um
also if you had rip term the files
section looked way better
right like you can actually like just
click on the files that you want and be
like download this is great
um and uh and so
there's this sudden divergence where you
know like
uh these people doing these antsy arts
for like login screens and bbs ads they
have to up their game right
and so they start upping their game in
the tech starts
department and then you've got the rip
term guys drawing new rip graphics and
there's a little bit of a game of leap
frog
but i want to go back to downloading
files for a second
i would download some stuff
i was a big music downloader
we're not talking about mp3s if you're
under whatever age that is
you download music
and it tells you what instruments are in
your music this is megamix88
uh you know has fun bass and whatever
these are all instruments that probably
someone ripped out of you know like a
korg or a roland or you know something
like that uh but every once in a while
you'd be like downloading these these
mod files that you listen to music
and you wouldn't get a list of
instruments you'd get like yo
i'm jester here's my phone number
here's my uh here's my address
uh you know if you're if you're
interested in hiring me you could you
know like call this up
huh
so
what did uh 12 year old me do
call them
i found one guy in the u.s
um
sidewinder and uh he lived in texas and
he was all about like
amiga and sega and being chill and
whatever
and in one of his mods he's like my cd
is coming out
and uh
me being the age that i am uh you know
like i can't uh i don't want to send
cash in the mail
i've never met this guy before and it's
texas and i'm living in bum idaho
um and uh and i just called a guy up and
i talked to him for like 30 minutes
about you know like his favorite local
pizza
and and whatever and then i get in
trouble with my mom for making long
distance phone calls uh but that's also
because i've been calling you know 30
billion bbs's and racked up like
hundreds of dollars
um
because i wanted to like follow
this path
of like discovering all of these
services that you know these people
call my bbs by the way here's your
legend of the red dragon on the right
finally that download finished
trade wars was also a big deal back in
the day
early space trading and combat game
and uh and because these boards are
single line you'd actually play like a
couple turns of the game and leave your
ship like parked in the middle of space
hopefully with like shields or something
like that someone else can log in and
attack your ship
uh you know if you there there was
eventually multi-line
uh bbs's where multiple people could
play trade wars at once and that was
kind of a game changer and very wild
uh and apparently they still have like a
trade wars leaderboard
and uh i just went to
uh again this is like my life is so
weird um one of the guys is like a top
trade wars champion
lives down the street from the museum
and we went over and played arcade games
at his house the other day
i can't make this up
so
then there's this other thing that we're
doing with computers that has nothing to
do with getting a line
we love big box games
this is actually from the library of
congress so i guess i can't buy
games from the library of congress but
uh if that were a software store i'd
sure like to rip it off uh that the guys
on the other side opposite sides are
holding a copy of ultimate
or ultimate let's try that again ultima
uh because they are the coders of ultima
and they went to software etc and
egghead
you know before newegg
and bought their own game just so that
they could
be legit
but
again
you know not all of us can afford to
subscribe to an online service so not
all of us can afford
to go out and buy buy software so what
do we do
i moved this slide intentionally further
to the beginning closer to the beginning
because in the 2018 talk
are you here whoever it is that yelled
don't copy that floppy before i got the
chance to get here
um
anyway so yeah you you do that
and sometimes you get a really nice
pirated floppy here where you could uh
you could actually
you know get get instructions on how to
install your pirated game or you know
how to start it up just type this
someone's bart's tale character disc
wonder if it's any good
mind shadow you know load star comma e
comma one
if you only have one floppy drive you
don't need that comma one
so if you pirate a game
every once in a while you get a surprise
turns out
you know kong strikes back was cracked
by abc
rad war up here decided to bring you
1942.
sierra online i'm sorry to say ken
williams aquatron
was uh
pirated by the freeze
i thought that was a superhero
crackers are trying to get attention
by putting their name somewhere so that
you know like obviously you know the
game is by someone else
uh but they they want you to know that
they cracked this there was copy
protection on here
or i i pirated this or i got the game
before it came out and
you know zero date it to all my friends
whatever
um
but every once in a while you see
something like this
you put in the floppy you start up the
game and instead of seeing the game
we're seeing like
the the pirate's name in the credits or
whatever
where is the mouse cursor there we go
instead of getting the game you get
stuff like this
little bit of epilepsy right
and you're like whoa this is how to be a
badass game of ski or die
this gear dies
not by these guys
wait a second the screen's still black
but this music's pretty banging
huh
imported by richie i didn't import my
copy of ski or die
i could call illusion hq
there's the phone number
look out for other illusion wares
now we enter this era of
gangsta rap computer style
shout outs to all my buddies here
if you get the right intro
you'll also get uh
they would say greetings to you know
such and such such and such and then uh
the the groups
that they hated
they would they would say go to
you know this one that one the other one
um
so
[Music]
interesting
if you had an amiga
sorry if you had an amiga
[Music]
oops that was supposed to play a video
do we actually get one there we go
this might look a little familiar
oh hey
if you want to join the coolest group on
the scene
or if you want to be one of our
distribution sites then contact us on
our hq nirvana
and remember interpol mess with the best
die like the rest
[Music]
and then you just get to read it over
and over again
[Music]
all right again pretty cool
um
but they're talking about distribution
okay for us that was bbs's in europe
they had a few uh a few more balls than
we did like three or four
um
and they'd be sending discs around in
this
in the u.s we were petrified that we'd
like
get caught by the feds
but in europe they're passing around
with graffiti on
them it's pretty wild
to the point where
people are actually sneaking
these and other things notice we've got
on here charts option seven this is a
commodore 64 disc mag
anyone ever heard of a zine
so here we have one of those except it's
literally on a disc
and here's an amiga version
the artwork is awesome
there's usually a tune playing in the
background and you notice you keep on
seeing this word chart
and you're thinking like what are the
charts well it turns out
just like some sort of stupid sci-fi
movie where people are trying to do more
hacks than the other guy
and score
and like you know they're having a
competition of sorts this is legit
happening where they actually have
these charts of who has cracked the most
games this month or whatever
and it's real
and eventually you watch one of these
and uh they've got all sorts of scene
drama in these mags and whatever but you
look up here
and you see something else
right next to this like phone that's
hooked up to the at symbol
i see something interesting
anyone want to tell me what it is
right up here
party
sorry about that
hold on
i've been in my basement for like 10
years watching these there's and
someone's telling me there's a party
something happens here
people start going through all these
disc mags and finding out that in europe
people are having copy parties
and whatever
and they're showing
these cute little intros
and demos
and crack trolls
on the wall as like
party entertainment
come and pirate any software you want
it's a giant ass land party
with amigas
and people are watching this stuff on
the wall
this is 40k by the way
so there's like a technical aspect here
suddenly these hackers that are breaking
copy protection are able to get noticed
because
they're doing this like cool sort of art
thing
full screen animations in 16 colors this
is big for this era
but they've they've got all these like
cool effects
i mean they're they're decent right
this is the kind of stuff you'd expect
to see on the wall in a rave
and these guys say something
controversial
they're at a copy party right and this
is this is entertainment for the copy
party or for the lan party or whatever
you want to call it
everyone's pirating software
this shows up on the wall
people are into it they're watching it
and then they say
what's the point in cracking games it
only ruins the future of the amiga a
piracy is a crime
there are some that will say
that was a joke
but
some people pay attention to it and they
actually stop cracking games
and they decide that they've spent the
past you know five ten years trying to
like leapfrog the other guy's cool intro
thing
excuse me
the end um
and that's the end of my pal no um
so
you've got a couple people that are very
serious about cracking games and you've
got a couple people that are like well
you know
maybe they've got a point why don't we
just like stop cracking games
we've been
like at war with each other
to like figure out how to do the coolest
visual effects and whatever why don't we
just like come up with the coolest
visual effects we can fit them on a
floppy disk watch them at a party and
like we could even compete and vote on
them or something and they do
don't worry in germany they're still
having copy parties
probably run by people that are 15.
this is one of my favorites i do show
this one pretty much every time i give
this panel
[Music]
something great will be happening in
hamburg
tbs
invites you to the biggest
mega copy party
ever made in
hamburg
north of germany
the whole world
yes
do you know why
[Music]
we don't
something was forgotten
three stars hotel
15 amigas
about 30 disk drives
and we hope no police
[Music]
[Applause]
we hope you hope too
but wait it gets better
so if you all don't wanna
come to enjoy the feeling
of 15 amigas
contact us for more infos right too
and here's their address
we're gonna run a piracy event in a
giant hotel oh we forgot the dates
it is the
2nd of june 1990
or
the 3rd of june 1990
both
credits go to now we have to credit
everyone that did the awesome scroll
text
and the code
it's very important to credit your
artists
music by benny b this might be how benny
banassi got his start
voltron and mr pet
[Music]
now the greetings
so you gotta shout out your homies
red sector is a good name that's still
around
and none of these other guys
[Music]
we finally just got our phil collins
drum breakdown by the way
and
so this is what happens when you know
you have a bunch of like 14 year old
germans or something and they're like we
can convince a hotel that we're going to
have
a piracy party
in a hotel and it'll be fine and no
police will show up
even though we're specifying our address
that's how it makes it legit i guess
and what does this look like so this is
what it looked like
i want the feeling of 30 disk drives
but these days it might look more like
this
what can you expect of these parties
food
tokyo demo fuss down here that's why
you've got the weird japanese pizzas
with mayo
i believe that's river wash up in the
corner which is in poland
uh i'm i'm awful and i don't know what's
up in the right i think the bottom is a
food truck
at revision
that might be break point in the corner
or something like that
there's also sleeping arrangements this
looks just like hope actually
does anyone remember the hotel pen
that's right here you don't have to
forget
uh it turns out these parties are
actually pretty serious inside
looks like one of the coolest lamb
parties you've ever been to
uh so
is this possible with the u.s well kind
of
um
these are every other week in europe at
this point
that people are doing this but we've got
demo splash in pittsburgh over here
we've got at party in boston
uh it used to be in somerville at
artisan's asylum but artisan's asylum is
moving now
so it will be in the new artisans asylum
once it exists fully
but
it used to be that i would only shout
out these two
and i would forget to mention synchrony
haha there's a slide with synchrony on
it now
synchrony starts in new york city at
baby castles
and you all hop on a train and you go to
montreal and you write your demos on the
train
and you show them in
montreal it's pretty cool
um
also an interesting addition is that
revision
which by the way i mean you saw how big
that was right
revision is probably the largest event
assembly looks larger but half of it is
like a lan and gaming party esports
event at this point i think assembly is
still pretty cool and it's also one of
the og parties that i really wanted to
go to
but i was like 13 and my parents
wouldn't let me go to finland
hi mom
but
because of the pandemic
you know like ain't nobody going to
germany we were actually planning on
going in 2020
and
wherever
some of my friends are
gonna make that trip
see there we go so we we we already have
plane tickets and then all the shutdowns
happened and everything was
um but an interesting thing happened
revision transitioned to an online
excuse me that was like a hiccup
um an online interactive experience and
they had actually been live streaming
revision for you know i mean like four
or five years or whatever they
eventually got them themselves banned
from twitch because uh you know like one
of the demos had like three seconds of
nipple
um and uh so then uh ccc actually
graciously picked up all the streaming
and whatever and things went on
kudos to them
uh revision moves on they actually still
stream on twitch they got reinstated
things are pretty great
this year they decided that they would
set up satellite locations and the
entire theme of the event was revision
satellites
and you could literally go to my museum
and watch revision and participate in
the event
and everything and there were the these
sprouted up all over the world there was
you know one in the uk there was like a
bunch of them in germany
um and you could literally just go to
revision and they even had
uh what made this really kind of special
is that the home office checked back
in with all the satellites
and you can see my ugly mug right in the
middle there
uh and you can see all of these
different spots all over the world where
people did this
and it was just really nice it was nice
to be
and actually from a u.s standpoint
europe has always been the serious scene
people for this right
uh and the us has not really we've been
serious about the scene here but we're
just so spread apart and like you know
few and far between
and whatever it's not like being you
know a bunch of nerds packed together in
germany or whatever
uh so it was very cool actually for the
us to receive recognition here
but uh i want to i want to rewind a
little bit and show you
two extremely notable demos
uh that
we're going to just kind of skip through
a little bit because what i want to do
is get us to
what's happening in the demo scene now
not what happened in the demo scene in
1992.
uh the important thing to understand
with what i'm about to show you is
previously we've been watching stuff
like what i just showed you right like
they're simple intros they have some
scroll text they might have some cool
visual effects hey look at what i can do
maybe even the scroll text says hey look
at what i can do
you know people are trying to show stuff
off and suddenly in like roughly 1992
uh we jumped to this sort of cinematic
thing
instead
and so
one of the first demos that i think
anyone in europe will remember
uh there are really two demos that blew
the envelope wide open
and one of them is desert dream on the
there we go our amiga fans are awake all
right
[Music]
and we'll watch like i don't know a
couple minutes of this because it's
really great
[Music]
screenplay written by
don't worry you don't have to like
remember this it's not going to be on
the test
[Music]
so
often threatened by vegetables
[Music]
sounds very personal
three
[Music]
that is a watermelon
and that's how it ends if you eat
watermelon i'm just saying
[Music]
[Applause]
let this be a lesson do you push veggies
on people
[Music]
introducing scene poetry
[Applause]
so
[Music]
field
here they say let's demolish some more
they're making a reference to
records
they want to demolish more limitations
and more records
of what people have done with this
machine so far
[Music]
make no mistake rotating twelve thousand
dots
takes a
a ton of math
[Music]
and doing this at eight megahertz is not
easy
[Music]
this is cute right here
sorry av guys
[Music]
so
psych
and then they ask you for disc two all
right
so
i'm going to the next slide because
uh
how many amiga people do we have in the
room at least five
one
i lost the other amiga people all right
who was your primary rival
that had better games than you or that
you had better games than and you were
constantly fighting back and forth
what kind of computer did they have
pc
so there are these guys that are doing
commodore 64 stuff
and they realize maybe
we should do some pc stuff
what i want you to notice obviously some
people in here have seen this can i get
some shouts from people who have not
seen this yet
excellent
i'm glad this is going to be new to you
because this is
quite possibly
with alongside desert dream like these
two demos are basically the demos
that made us go from like
piracy lan party to like indie film fest
mode
uh for for these demo parties so
these guys are future crew
and that was my slide
hello
click
there we go
and they decide to do
now i don't really know if they saw
desert dream and i should probably just
ask them because i know some of them
but
you're going to notice some similarities
here
it's kind of like a remix of the other
demo
it's true actually
[Music]
so
hmm
[Music]
so
get down
[Music]
i spent years trying to figure out what
this said
it says
another way to scroll
[Music]
you're welcome
don't kick us out saint john's it's just
art
[Music]
see he's not even an atomic playboy
get down
i think i spent about 10 years just
staring at plasma animations and
realizing
that's like what i see when i close my
eyes
like when you're trying to look at
something in your sleep
[Music]
whose spinning cube is better
time will tell
[Music]
[Applause]
10 seconds of transmission
[Music]
so
[Applause]
[Music]
and just when you don't think it can get
any more complex
they decide they're going to do one more
thing
[Music]
and then they give you a nice credit
sequence
so
it's about at the point where everyone
watches this spaceship animation and
whatever
in 1993 and they're like why aren't
these guys making games this is better
than any game i've played yet
and what you don't realize is that has
anyone ever heard of remedy
entertainment
flat out
[Music]
they made they ended up making that
uh a bunch of these guys as anyone ever
played bejeweled the guy that made the
music right now
that music ends up
in some of the pop cap stuff
uh
the guy that made the technoe music that
was playing earlier
ends up rearranging a bunch of final
fantasy music and going on tour
and does it does video game concerts
like these guys are still in the scene
and they're still doing stuff that
you've probably heard of
3d mark
written by these guys
it was just a few years too early that
they were doing this
so
at this point we should be
understanding that these demos are
something that we get on a couple floppy
disks from a friend or
uh that you know might even have been
mailed to us we got from software the
month club who knows
um but you might have also gotten them
from you know like uh you downloaded it
from a pbs or something like that and
there really is no purpose to these
others other than that they wanted to
show them at a demo party
and show off their cool chops
and do something cool and artistic
is everyone on the same page
okay
and also that these are completely
algorithmic there might be a couple
animations in here
uh you know but like there is a
technical aspect to this these are all
running on machines that are you know
anywhere from like eight to thirty three
megahertz
is the range of computer that we're
we're talking about with like you know a
meg maybe two megs of ram
something like that
again we all on the same page
okay
does any anyone have any questions so
far
this is where we kind of descend into
the next pile of slides
is
where i explain you notice
did anyone catch on to the similarities
between desert dream and second reality
you see a lot of the same effects
you start seeing a lot of the same
tricks
people are going back to their games of
leapfrog again where they're like i saw
that effect i can do it better
i saw that scroller i think i can do a
cooler one
that sort of a thing and
we start seeing
just interesting stuff
where we're you know like we're really
trying to explain this is just art so
uh these next slides actually most of
these demos i showed in my uh the ones
in the slides
i showed in the 2020 presentation so if
you want to watch full versions of these
uh you know please just pop on the
youtube and watch that
um i
have 90 or so minutes of brand new demos
that have happened within the last you
know
some odd like
two to five years
uh that i have not shown as a part of
presentation but i do want to show you
just a couple out of the slides and only
just a couple seconds
of each one to give you an idea
of what we're talking about here
so people
wherever my mouse cursor is are trying
to explain the scene to others
hello boys and girls
today we're going to learn the alphabet
but not the usual alphabet
no it's the demo scene alphabet
so pay attention and have some fun
ready
let's begin
[Music]
this is the one that i'll spend a few
more than
more than a couple seconds on
[Music]
it stands of course for the mighty
captain
it's for bite killer mega or tigger
it's you yes we love you
forever friends all together
is your entry that gets an award
is for fun cause we'll never get bored
it's for greetings to those far and near
[Music]
the party
because we sleep when we die
it's outside where the real party is
[Music]
oh
online
is for traveling to parties worldwide
it's for us ancient old school on
youtube
of demos on youtube
[Music]
you'll get 3d
me
[Music]
okay that's all folks
now you know everything about the
democrat alphabet
try to repeat and mesmerize it
and if you forget any letter just come
back and start this demo again
so a lot of people have tried to do what
i'm doing
some of them more successful than others
um
we're definitely not going to watch this
whole thing here but
this is one that takes a more
tongue-in-cheek approach
hcc abcde or abc hello kids my name is
spider final the dog
fine go final is my name
f heidi hoho
final repeat up to me kids okay enough
of that so
um
what we've tried to explain is that
there are these like not only there
there are common demo categories
and then
there are all of these repeated effects
that basically are memes in demos right
uh so enough looking at charlie here
um
stuff that we already saw we saw some
crack tros which is literally just an
intro and a cracked game
uh yeah we saw an intro which are these
small demos we saw a mega demo sometimes
called a dentro
um you know or a demo
somewhere in between these
people don't really use the term dentro
anymore
these are the kinds of things that we've
seen already
but
there are categories so
there are 64k demos
that are literally demos that are 64
kilobytes in size and do some pretty
amazing like
just to give you an example of what you
can do with 64k
this is an old 64k demo
[Music]
and i skip right to the part where it's
calculating
[Music]
so that is old and to give you a kind of
middle of the road here's 2014 mercury
does this really cool
water effect that really drew me in
but then there's so much more to this
demo than just that
[Music]
this entire thing the music
the video everything is 64k
it's just nuts
[Music]
they do this we're gonna skip through it
a little bit i'm sorry to mercury
oops and i skipped right ahead to
another slide too
that is not what i wanted to do here
well you saw some of that this the scene
at the end is also pretty unreal
uh looks like
pretty much a real city scene
[Music]
someone probably saw that
just trying to get here
[Music]
it's pretty incredible uh there's
another basically mercury
and conspiracy the other guys that are
doing 60 4ks are competing against each
other
conspiracy has been on a kick
um and i i don't know there's they're
sort of exiting the kick but as soon as
i say that i'm gonna see another one
where they've been trying to do these
like sort of photo realistic
movie trailer things
in 64k hello come on
stay on the slide
[Music]
and we'll jump
forward
conspiracy stuff is typically very
atmospheric
and you actually see something similar
to what we just saw but
maybe a little bit leveled up this is
much newer
wait much newer
somewhat newer
[Music]
jump ahead a little bit more
jump head a little bit more
[Music]
just give me an idea of you know like
very moody
[Music]
entire thing 64k
but we can do better than that how about
4k
one of my videos has been nuked
so these guys
did something i mean we're talking about
4k here we can't do a whole lot
[Music]
we decided to kind of get a little bit
uh existential go into space here's some
more my cube is better than your cube
does some more interesting stuff
eventually the cube travels
we build a building from scratch
and fly around in the building
this is from a time where ribbon
animation was also quite big
[Music]
and then eventually at the end we see a
return
[Music]
[Applause]
oh hey what's that it's the return of
the cube
[Music]
i like that one a lot this was from
evoke 2017.
and i'm just gonna say this over and
over like a broken record the audio
included in this visual experience that
you're getting is still
4k for the whole thing
[Music]
getting like a
half blade runner
experience here
[Music]
it's pretty serious okay oh and i uh i
should
we should show you oscar's chair so a
lot of these
are very algorithmic right because when
you're getting down to 4k everything has
to be written drawn by you know a math
equation basically
uh but these guys went in a completely
different direction
and decided to draw a very realistic
room in a chair
[Laughter]
and you don't really know what the story
of oscar's chair is but we do know that
there's a problem
there seems to be a pool of liquid on
the floor
near the chair
some guy named oscar
maybe there was an accident
it's pretty clear what kind of an
accident it might have been
but of course in the end the chair went
this was pretty game-changing for 4ks
and caused a lot of people to have to
up the quality of their demos
so
recently
there is a huge
movement into going even smaller
256 bytes or 128 bytes or
64 bytes
so what can you do with 64 bytes
well i guess the audio is out of the
question
but you can still do some stuff
and you saw that 256 bite at the
beginning
but
text message
works of uh
machine language and you do stuff like
this
uh by the way i did a i committed a sin
and checked my phone in the middle of my
panel and i saw a notice that someone
says the youtube live stream might be
down
so i'm shouting that out to the back
just in case
so size coding is becoming an incredibly
big deal
but
if you couldn't figure it out already
demos or memes we've already shouted
this out
you can see all sorts of examples of
this
uh you have definitely already seen some
scroll text
um
and
there's even
someone that did a parody and called it
elder scrollers
and said you know what we're just gonna
one-up this and everything in the demo
is gonna be a scroller
so there's all of this like
scroll text in this demo
of course i had to skip to the like
[Music]
one of their scrollers is just like
the scroller game keeps on getting more
and more serious
[Music]
whenever the screen is blank
you know that they're calculating
something
[Music]
3d amiga boing ball on a commodore 64
for example
[Music]
sorry i know we're watching like just
little tiny pieces of these but uh they
they are available and i want to get to
the new stuff
uh pixel and scene art
huge big deal
noon
stars
this this was a really cool demo with a
lot of artistic stuff in it i highly
suggest that
you saw this guy in the middle but
shout outs definitely appear in scroll
texts all the time they call them greets
and you know dots because pixel art
plasma
3d on computers that have no business
doing 3d
tunnels
you definitely saw a couple of those but
just in case it wasn't
perfectly clear what you can do with
tunnels
oops well
we didn't get to the tunnel part
sorry
let's try that again
[Music]
great example here
this guy is making that face because he
can't compete with this tunnel
[Music]
all sorts of ray tracing and ray
marching
you get scene references like references
to the party that people are at
uh this demo in the middle is debris
and i think we might have actually
watched debris at a previous uh
event but i want to show you the live
version of debris
uh in a second here actually
why don't we make it a literal second
i'm going to show you
debris shown live
because really to get an idea of what
these festivals are like i mean
certainly
y'all are like sitting here clapping
when you see a cool demo and oohing and
eyeing and wowing and right
but picture yourself in a room with a
bunch of people that actually write
these it's going to take a little bit
more to impress them
than it is probably all of us right
um so
what how how exactly
you know does that work how how much
does it take to impress them
so
here is a live capture
of breakpoint 2007 where they actually
showed debris
and uh yeah we'll just watch this
now you can feel like you're really
there
they have the system here that shows you
you know the name of the next demo
that's about to play the one that played
last
[Applause]
everyone in the audience is probably
drunk
i'm sure you've never seen one of these
before it's called a progress bar
but actually what's happening is they're
doing all sorts of pre-pre-calculation
de-crunching because we're watching a
64k demo
so it's actually unpacking you know two
gigs worth of crap into ram
from the 64k thing
[Music]
and what you probably don't know because
you didn't you weren't there or maybe
someone here was but
uh
this is a reference to the neighborhood
that they went to to go to break point
so
someone has built you know it's like
going to hope and someone built a demo
with st john's in it you know or the
hotel pen
[Music]
this is the ultimate my cube is better
than your cube
[Music]
oh
[Applause]
[Music]
bridge is coming to get you
security camera footage is nice that's a
nice touch
[Music]
so
these are their greets
[Music]
so
[Applause]
[Music]
and they ended with that one of course
[Applause]
sorry far brush i'm cutting off your
applause but
that gives you an idea of what it's like
to be there
there's a lot of fourth wall breaking
party references
uh there are hardware references
any amiga users remember intel outside
uh you also got
these guys referencing
you know their own hardware
so uh here's a super nintendo or the
beginning of super nintendo where
they're literally just
showing you hey
i wrote the step on a super nintendo
here it is
[Music]
so
you get all these people referencing
their platform and just showing off what
they can do
and i think maybe now is actually as
good a time as any to show off
one thing that i think i've kind of
ignored in past
presentations i showed a little bit of
this
in my 2018 talk where i showed some game
consoles doing demos
uh but normally the demo scene at least
back in the day
would be you know something you download
something you run on your pc or media
your commodore whatever
uh but people have been getting more and
more exotic
as time has gone on so
now people are trying to write
demos for some of the weirdest consoles
they can
just as an example i have here a 3do
demo which by the way
does anyone remember the 3do
does anyone that remembers the 3do know
what cpu it
had nope
this is going to be wild and this is
going to blow your mind and i learned
this recently or kind of recently anyway
it's arm
it's the first arm device we really saw
in the us
um so anyway i i thought that was
interesting and
maybe now that puts into perspective the
3do totally got knocked out by the
playstation right
but it was i mean
the biggest reason was probably no one
wanted to spend 700 on a game console
um but
people also saw that it was an arm at 12
megahertz and not you know like a mips
at 28 or something like that and they
were like oh well there's no way that 12
megahertz cpu can outrun that 28
megahertz cpu
looking back i think the arm probably
could have outrun that 28 megahertz cpu
but anyway that's not the point um i
just wanted to show you a and these guys
actually use the name dentro because
they call it a three dentro instead of a
3do
so
isn't it cute
[Music]
music by
pam
[Music]
so
it's a little bit new right
we haven't seen any demos that reference
discord yet
[Music]
and real 3do memes
so pretty cool there's now a 3do scene
and we have to go write some demos
so if anyone knows how to write code for
arm
which
hey might be a whole lot of people now
you can write 3do software too
so that's not the only console maybe we
could uh we could run a couple more
[Music]
not this one though
why don't we move on to
oh hey
anyone ever heard of a gamecube
it's kind of like a mac but smaller
you laugh but it's actually a g4 with an
ati radio
[Music]
this one's a little dark
so
[Music]
i hope you like breaks
there are many brains and demos
[Music]
so
hmm
[Music]
it's one scary-ass game of pac-man
so
[Music]
but who competed with the gamecube
they seem to have found those spinning
cubes from debris or maybe that's where
they got them from
[Music]
as fast as i can
so
[Music]
the future
as fast as i can
[Music]
so
[Applause]
so i keep running
so at this point you're probably saying
oh gamecube playstation 2.
i mean like
that's pretty cool
and it's not a playstation 2 or a
gamecube or whatever but maybe you could
impress me a little bit more
uh you know i i do think that that's
pretty impressive for the hardware but
you talked about all these old computers
being able to do
some crazy wacky so
uh we're gonna we're gonna take a step
back from
what i like to consider non-retro
consoles
uh i still don't think a gamecube is
retro
uh i still get slightly offended when a
kid comes in and says oh mario 64 is so
retro
um
but uh we're gonna go past the nintendo
64.
blow right past it and uh
how about we uh switch to some super
nintendo stuff
[Music]
for those of you that don't know the
super nintendo is three megahertz
it has its own sound mixing cpu which is
the only reason it's
even worth a damn at audio
[Music]
side note pandas are pretty cute
this is real time and no super effects
because they've destroyed one with a
mushroom
[Music]
so
feet
[Music]
we're still in the same demo
ah the greeted bit shifters
i've done stuff with them
[Music]
and then we get a repeat
anyone ever heard of a vectrex
[Music]
apparently there's a demo scene for that
too
[Music]
the carnegie mellon computer club has
taken it upon themselves to
write multiple vectrex demos
there's a special kind of demo called an
invitro that actually invites you to
their demo party
[Music]
so
i'm glad some of you got that joke
for those of you that didn't there are
no pixels on this machine
so
[Music]
oh hey
so
[Music]
moving on how about
one nintendo 64 demo
[Music]
i think someone accidentally a gamecube
inside of their n64
maybe not quite
[Applause]
[Music]
so
like
[Music]
is
you
[Applause]
[Music]
so
[Applause]
[Music]
but wait
there's competition in the vetrex
category you wouldn't know that more
people are writing vectrex demos
[Music]
do
does your vectrex have a physics engine
[Music]
i don't know if it's the camera man or
not but some of these effects you can
see the machine is clearly not happy
with this
[Music]
all right i get two more console demos
and then i'm gonna crane through a few
more slides
here's an interesting one i found
[Music]
we're now in game boy color land
a little bit of hacking is being done
[Music]
do
the game boy and the game boy color are
as fast as your ti graphing calculator
same cpu
[Music]
don't worry i can't read it either
so
[Music]
do
i'm going to jump ahead just a little
bit to atari 2600 lan because i want you
to see that too before i have to go
through slides
[Music]
this is dissonant as because the
atari only has 32 notes
but they're doing some pretty crazy
stuff on the screen
[Music]
who in here knows how much ram the atari
2600 has
there it is
everyone hear that
128 bytes of ram
does it have a frame buffer
it's a wonder that they even made games
on this thing
[Music]
all right we're going to quit this i'm
going to jump through a few more slides
because i really want to tell you
a few other things that are going on in
the scene that i think are kind of big
right
um
here's just a couple more like memes
that i'm just gonna skip past like
there there are a bunch of dancing and
mocap demos
uh there are demos that cover
other demos so
uh previously we we showed this in a
previous version of the panel
and you get to watch this you know like
pretty cool mocap demo and there's some
dancing in it
it actually starts to look more like
dancing here
but then
someone
went and did an atari 2600 version of
this
and you think i'm joking but like
and they even have the dancing person
like
where are you dancing person
there you go
[Music]
i can't believe that someone did this
you also get sample playback
on a commodore 64. they went crazy and
did a whole bunch of like
[Music]
you can listen to tom steiner look up
cubase 64. you can even run it on your
real c64
and
i wanted the rest of that
and you can do
all of these effects
anyway so that's fascinating
and
if you think that's great
[Music]
just wait
but wait
this is a commodore 64.
and they're actually playing
decent quality sample playback
dynamic range is very good
[Music]
and they have time for graphics on the
screen while they're doing it which is
just
wild to think about for a system this
slow
[Music]
and they don't just do these simple
effects
they actually do stuff that requires
real cpu time to run
for example
black screens
oh wait
[Music]
fast scrolling over high-res images
so just yet another example of some of
the crazy stuff they're doing
um this winter reality is second reality
done by jason scott
uh with
a video camera and video editing
uh i love the
fourth wall breaking in the dc5 demos
uh just a quick look at that
oops
so quick that we skip to the next slide
[Music]
and eventually
well anyway we're gonna skip past this
because
uh you end up with terrain generators
i'm sure you've seen this
but what's great about this is someone
decided oh i'm gonna generate mountains
but now
i'm gonna ski through them
[Music]
so that ends up being pretty cool you
also end up with these twisters you've
seen a couple of these in the demos that
we've been watching
so
what's hot right now
live coding competitions are hot right
now and this is one thing that i have
i've spent virtually no
time on in previous panels and i think
it's really
important but also has just like in the
last five years has just blown way the
up
um on the right we have a shader
showdown where people are writing gl
shader language live and they have 30
minutes
to write the coolest shader in real time
that they can
and it's one person against the other
and
you know some of some of these guys you
know like practice shaders and like have
an idea of a shader they're going to
write some people do it completely off
the cuff there are upsets there's all
sorts of amazing stuff going on
but there's another thing that i mean i
think a lot of people
that know about shade or know about the
demo scene might know about shader
showdowns
uh there are also bike battles
uh this is something that love bite uh a
demo party is doing uh love bite has a
whole lot of it's basically a size
coding
demo party
and
they ha their bite battle is uh does
anyone know what the tick 80 is
so uh there are these fantasy game
consoles
uh you have a virtual machine
for a game console that doesn't actually
exist
uh and it has kind of in theoretical
limitations and that sort of a thing
and so they write
size coded stuff in real time against
each other just like the shader showdown
but instead of the goal being to come up
with as cool as shader that you can
the goal is to come up with the coolest
like
pixel art animation sort of thing that
you can
so i actually have
uh they they released a little
uh sort of pseudo demo
from these guys
that showcases some of the effects
to give you an idea
of what you can do with a tech80 i'll
i'll do that afterwards but uh
i want to show you
[Music]
actually there's a there's also a
trailer so let's uh let's run that real
fast
[Music]
at love bite we will premiere bite
battle
a new concept where people from all
different kinds of platforms and
backgrounds can come together and show
off their skills
from amiga to atari or traditional so
you sit here and you write live code and
then you render it
and they showcase each person
[Music]
in a relatively short period of time and
while you're at the party you can
literally just vote on the person that
comes up with the coolest effect
like a limbo dance the size limit will
slowly count down from 512 bytes all the
way down to 256 bytes
the size will be shown in the bottom
right of the screen so the audience can
always keep track of how the contestants
are doing
who has the best effect
who has the longest breath
who can stay within the seismics
we will all find out the love by party
on march 12th until march 14 2021
get your vote key now
for the past
so to give you an idea of what the
system can actually do
uh even though it's not a real system
i thought that i would produce one
example of
a size coated entry
this is 512 bytes
[Music]
music might be simple but hearing any
progression at all
even hearing chord progressions at all
is pretty amazing for something sub 1k
[Music]
so to give you an idea of what you have
if you have a little bit more space in
your rum or
[Music]
whatever you can do this instead
so
[Music]
wow
pretty cool
another really big thing that i think
needs some attention
in this scene is there is a huge
executable graphics thing happening
right now
uh this this is technically always been
a thing and like isn't
the point of the demo to be like
algorithmic in the first place right but
like
there are bots on twitter that are tied
to emulators of specific platforms and
you can literally tweet code at the bot
and it'll draw stuff and tweet it back
at you
um so this is like an interesting cool
way to kind of
randomly become involved in the scene
and not even have to go to a party you
know i mean not that you wouldn't want
to go to one of these i think you should
but
you can do stuff and this this art might
remind you of something
does anyone see it and
see something else they've seen recently
so
someone did a
cover version
of the james webb telescope images
in one tweet for each one of these
and they just tweeted it at the bot
and it comes back with this and i know
this guy his name's paul
and uh he's crazy because like
i i just i can't believe and he
regularly churns stuff out like this
um and it's completely nuts um he
doesn't just do retro stuff though
he does
realistic looking
this is a four kilobyte executable that
renders this
and uh i was showing you scenes that you
might have seen in new york recently
so um
[Music]
this this kind of looks like something
you might be able to travel not too far
and
see scenery that looks like this
this is also not a photo
and uh
just just to suspend and and this is
again this is 4k
i have the exe file right here i could i
could like run it and wait a minute for
it to render it but like
um but but if you really
want to blow your own mind
or something like that
this is not a photo
he's got like
imperfections in the floppy disk
um you can tell it's not real because he
sent this to a demo party called outline
and he wrote it like on the usb stick
like
and uh and and here's a fun easter egg
you see the the line printer print out
this is actually
the shader code that renders this
inside
and he blurred it out and made it look
like a printout it's just completely
crazy so
this dude has some competition because
this is an actual category that you can
compete in
in a demo party so this this right here
i mean like this is beautiful right
this got third place
that means there are two
of these that people thought would were
better than this
and those are
this one
this one is by yx
is this your card i believe
uh the next one is pbr and i totally am
forget i'm just spacing out on the name
of this demo or you know executable
graphics this one's
a little bit more fantasy than photo
but it kind of
suspension of disbelief here in the real
world
just
amazing artwork in
four
kilobytes just nuts
so that is the end of the slides that i
have uh i have a couple other demos in
here
um i wanted to see how much time i would
have at the end of the presentation i
think i have like
five ten minutes at most there is
something going on in here at one right
i'm getting shrugs
um here's what we're gonna do i'm gonna
run demos until someone kicks me off of
the stage which is actually how this
worked in 2018.
um
i want to show you some cool hacker
relevant stuff
uh one that i think that you'll really
like
is this one
do we still have amiga fans in the house
i lost all my amiga i have a half of an
amiga fan
i have a constipated amiga fan
uh
all right
so this is a 64 kilobyte
they call it an intro just because it's
small
but this is something on the amiga
64k
and i think this will resonate with some
people
takes time to load okay
everyone has their favorite fake hacker
os
i think this one might be mine
uh
[Music]
do
hey man uh i found another interesting
signal but it totally crashed my machine
i have no idea what's going on uh can
you see if we can find it
one
[Music]
uh
y'all notice what time the demo started
at right
13 37.
[Music]
oh
this is his greets focus design black
lotus loonies
these are all the groups that he's
shouting out
secretly
[Music]
it's pretty cool for 64k i think
another very weird
so there's a category called wild where
you just enter anything that you can
enter because it doesn't necessarily fit
a mold
and i was really fascinated by this one
which is called lotto and that's by a
group called nupo
uh this guy had a previous demo of this
where he built a handheld lidar
that you could just kind of walk around
things and he like
don't ask me why i have no idea he has a
random ass toilet in his front yard
and walks around it with his handheld
lidar and 3d scans it
and then can do stuff with it
uh he decided that he would level this
up a little bit
and
he builds a like lidar into a wagon cart
and drives it around this like barn and
into the barn
and then takes all the uh the point
field data and makes a demo with it
and so
this is that
and actually we can see
exactly how big this demo is
so it's not small
he's got a lot of data that he has to
get in there
but
when you see what he did
i think
i think you'll find it much more
interesting
and there's you know like there's an
artistic and music aspect and
surreal aspect
up
and this is just written in a game
engine so like it's it goes to show that
not everyone that writes a demo knows
assembler
or whatever and they can still do
something that's kind of cool with all
the data that they have
so if you think you know oh i don't
write you know assembler for the
commodore 64 or whatever i can't make a
demo
you can still do cool stuff and submit
it to demo parties and
people pick it up
so
[Music]
[Applause]
real image
fake image
[Music]
fade back and forth just to you know
and there's his rig
this is just neat
oh
who was it again that came in like a
wrecking ball or something like that
you don't have to answer them
[Music]
[Applause]
oh
and kids that's what happens if you vote
for the wrong person this upcoming
election
give you another one
these two are requested by my partner
who i
cannot see but is sitting back there
somewhere
[Music]
do
so
[Music]
[Applause]
this one is 64k
and just a little bit different
[Music]
no
oh
um
[Music]
i can't even see how many people are
still in here you all into this
you want to watch another uh
live
demo
have a little bit of feeling while
you're there or let's do a little choose
your own adventure you want to see
something really exotic
choices
live exotic
exotic all right
so here we have
a commodore 64 demo
my name is matthias chris
and that is happening on the wrong
display
some of you have seen this don't spoil
it you may also know me as quest of
reflex and this is a standard c64
computer setup
monitor floppy drive also this is like
i'm now going to remove one of these
components and then play a demo on what
is left as you can see i've already
loaded our program
and the program didn't do anything
except install a driver on the floppy
drive we can now remove the c64 since we
don't need it anymore
so
so you're expecting him to load
a demo and then disconnect the floppy
drive but
there goes the commodore 64.
uh
our floppy drive has two output lines
data and clock we want clock directly
connected to the video signal and we'll
put a resistor before data this enables
us to generate three voltage levels one
for black one for white and one for
triggering horizontal and vertical
retraces you may have noticed that we're
not connecting anything to the monitor's
audio input since of course the floppy
drive is perfectly capable of generating
sound all by itself
and now we just have to open and then
close the floppy drive to start the demo
[Music]
so
okay
laughs
and you might be thinking okay i've seen
all i can see a floppy drive do
and you'd be wrong
hmm
you
poof
i've really just learned that people are
completely nuts and can do anything they
want to do really
so we'll switch over to the live one
uh this is an unexpanded amiga 500 that
runs at eight megahertz or you know 7.16
and
uh this one also blew the audience away
so i think it's a pretty good one to
show
[Music]
[Applause]
it's too bad our amiga fanboys aren't
still here
they'd really know how to shout out
their amiga now
[Music]
interesting quick note the black lotus
is known for doing
high spec demos not low spec demos uh so
they do a lot of like
uh crazy 3d rendering and high spec
stuff on like 68060s which is the cpu
that apple
really never used in high-end macs but
it ended up in high-end amiga
accelerators that are
impossible to get at this point
uh i've given up
but uh so you start seeing this and
you're like oh this is gonna be
interesting the black lotus wrote an old
school demo
[Music]
so
it wants disc two
[Music]
[Applause]
be
[Music]
oh
[Applause]
[Music]
my
[Applause]
[Music]
now
[Applause]
[Music]
so
[Applause]
um
we have some audience members who
actually got to witness us live
uh
some other stuff i have
uh the last few things i have let's see
so i have
an atari 8-bit demo that is like 15
minutes long
um and has actually has a really cool
aesthetic and a bunch of cool stuff and
uh i also from
uh you you noticed in the invitro the
there were two characters at the end of
it and one of them was ps
uh that's felipe he's a well-known guy
that does something called demo scene
theater 9000
um and basically does kind of updates in
the scene and whatever and i actually uh
looked to him
for a cool shader showdown that i could
show
and he sent me a link of a shader
showdown so
uh we could go in either direction if
anyone actually wants to like
watch
a 20 or 25 or 30 minute shader showdown
from start to finish and just see how
this works they're like there's a live
dj they can actually use the live dj's
audio as input
while they're writing a shader um and
you know there are people narrating and
being like what's what the is going
on here and some of the narrators are
like i have no idea usually at revision
which is i think what this shader
showdown is from they actually have a
very good idea of what's going on
uh but
we can choose your own adventure again
do we want atari first or we want the
shader showdown first i can show these
uh
and then i probably have to get out of
here and actually go to sleep
uh if i can break in here um
you know you are actually the last
person on schedule so you can go right
till 10 am if you want to
it's a tempting offer
how long can you go
well i think we should have last person
standing here
all right
how about we watch the atari demo first
uh i want to show you one more retro
thing let's let's watch the atari thing
and then we'll watch a shader showdown
uh does does anyone have any questions
like you can literally just ask me
anything i guess but uh you know about
demos probably
green maybe black
i don't know why don't you be the first
to
figure out if you can do a demo on a
non-computer
i can't see hands so you just have to
yell at me if you had something
all right atari demo it is
oops that is the wrong display again
i'm really good at this can you tell
i guess maybe what i should do since i'm
just basically running out the clock at
this point
um i'd uh
i've i brought cds to sell but they're
all gone
uh so thanks for your support
uh i do still have a couple pretty eight
machine vinyl which is the first nine
inch nails album on eight different
8-bit machines
um and 650 people were crazy enough to
pre-order this so i ordered 300 more
so i've got like a couple of those in my
bag if anyone wants to
help support my food budget or my uh
living budget
um
but uh yeah you can hit me up after this
or even really during this since we're
really just sitting here watching demos
i've never actually i've skimmed this
demo but i haven't run it run it and
like watch the entire thing so i might
just come down there and watch it on the
big screen
instead of like killing my neck
i am one of you what are you talking
about
um
but uh
if uh if you're not already like
following me on you know twitter or
mastadon i'm on both
uh i'm just at inverse face um
i guess i'm mastodon you need to add the
uh the server i'm on cyberspace which is
at c-y-b-r-e
dot space
uh so if you wanna hit me there
i do have an instagram i'm not a photo
savant
expect really shitty pictures i'm on
facebook but everyone should be off
facebook by now so
don't get on facebook on my account
um
i don't have a tick tock i think that's
like a song by kesha
all right atari demo
some more fourth wall breaking here
[Music]
do
um
[Music]
do
so
[Music]
do
don't
[Music]
do
so
[Music]
god
do
[Music]
so
with
my
[Music]
um but it couldn't have been too large
um a lot of atari demos are using up to
320k of ram at this point
uh but that still isn't that much really
you know um
i don't know if that was a stock machine
or not the uh
the file name didn't specify i could
probably look it up real fast here
i'm literally on the website that would
uh
specify some requirements
uh no so this uh there's there's a
confusion of atari's here the atari 2600
which is the game system
has no frame buffer
definitely does not have tiles uh only
has 128 bytes of ram
uh the atari computer
uh usually comes stock with say i mean
an atari 400 had 16k and atari 800 had
48k
800 xl would have 64k
um the 130 xe would have 128k
and this totally has a frame buffer and
uh you know the the sound chip is much
better as you can hear you know you have
more than 32 notes and they're not
terribly dissonant
um so the atari when when someone says
uh atari 8-bit they're referring to the
computer line
and when they say atari 2600 or tia or
vcs
uh they're specifically referring to the
yeah no problem um so yeah that was uh
ain't nobody writing doom for the 2600
and not making it look like that but
that still is an impressive feat
actually
uh all things considered the atari 8-bit
computer is still only a 1.79 megahertz
uh so like having
a
like a
raycasting engine on it is like insane
um they did
some pretty amazing stuff with that
hardware
so
we have a shader showdown that should be
watched
and uh
so a black ops black hole tell us a
little bit about your previous uh round
or how stressful was so these are people
the empty cores
fighting shaders against each other and
you'll see the person's name
[Music]
so one of the things that people will do
is i didn't have much time left not hit
save while they write a whole bunch of
code and then use it as kind of a
clincher moment
and uh i just started and you'll see
that
so anyway i'll let this run you can see
you know
all the people that this is about
from revision 2021
the idea for the fact
so this was
entirely online everyone was being a
commentator over discord and whatever
and i did a pac-man thieved thing back
then so it was sort of like
pulling forward i already had done i
guess going back but uh
with diffusion now
[Music]
had you ever done uh action refusing
stuff before or uh no
okay
awesome
how stressful was that to try to very
very it was very special i like stood in
my i stood in my bedroom and i sort of
sung to myself what the formulas were so
i could remember it oh wow
you're already on side
we have a sphere
we're both already in it like
immediately as you said started coding
this is going to be rough both had great
effects yesterday i mean it's going to
be a good battle i'm very excited to see
what evil comes up with because evil we
saw that giant um pyramid and the entire
like castle around it and now he wasn't
just a full full city and with
philippine we had more of a story-driven
idea of like a
i guess a glowing cube going off on a
quest i would say we put it all away go
to the bathroom at revision
it's a very long tunnel
so it takes a while i it felt a little
bit like philippine was redoing the cube
demo that she she made a couple years
ago uh but inside uh
a tunnel corridor instead of the open
air like in the demo but it was a good
idea i think it worked pretty well i was
i was a sucker for a writer's effect
though on that particular challenge i
really like the aesthetic of his but
very different from what we normally see
yeah
that's something i would have wanted to
ask you about like all the diversity of
the different shaders do you prefer the
3d stuff do you think that usually gets
the votes or do you like the
different experiments more
i absolutely love to see variance or
variety
um i think like with 3d it's actually
um
you can fall into this trap where like
it doesn't like it's 3d but there's no
like you don't really take use of it
like there's not a lot of camera
movement there's no like the models
aren't really like moving
um and with 2d you sort of have a lot of
control over like um like you have if
you have less things to have to deal
with so you can control more things like
animation
and like
placing things better and that kind of
thing yeah um
like even then the shader i just did the
pac-man s3d but like the only thing you
get from that is the shading
so yeah it's it's 3d but like is it
really 3d so um yeah it's definitely
like a a deal where um
how would you say uh
like with 2d things like you could
really
there's there's like with art you can do
like so many things more control
yeah and it's unconstrained as well you
have everything is a trade-off that you
decide to do so
give us a bit more good i guess
yeah but yeah
generally easier to think of like it's
it's very it's
3d is like kind of a pretty to
swear on stream but it's it's
it's harder than mine but 2d is very
very pleasant to work
it's more intuitive in a way because you
can see immediately on the screen what
you're working on and tell us a little
bit about that uh mathematical function
that you were using to make the pac-man
jump around the sign with a sign with a
tangent we were trying to
d
decrypt it a little bit on stream so it
would be cool if you had like an insight
from you on that that's the it's
probably the most inefficient way to
make a triangle wave so basically it's a
yeah
it's like it's like a wave where it goes
up and then it hits its maximum and then
it reverses direction and goes back down
so you can make that using uh by passing
aside or sine into a sine it's very slow
because they sign i think is one of the
slowest operations on the graphics card
but uh it's very easy to remember so
it's perfect for shader showdown
okay until your computer starts melting
from yes exactly possessing power
it's okay if this guard can handle it
that's fine
yeah i have some switching yesterday
evening
at some moment
19 minutes left still on the clock we
still only see two spheres on screen
even slightly more stylish with that
background but i think we're seeing a
visualization of the distance field on
what the inside where we're basically
seeing um actually it could be a fog
effect now that i look at it but
basically as the as our ray passes our
object we can track what the closest
distance it got was and then i could
tell that ray like even if it didn't hit
the object we can be like oh we actually
got like such and such close and we can
sort of get a fog effect from that or a
glow effect yeah glow i was gonna say
i've seen philippine use it as a glow a
few times
so looking forward to see what she's
gonna come up with but so far we don't
really have like a sense of oh some
lighting changes on evil that looks a
lot smoother now
really i always love right um on i
always love evil's lighting and evil's
uh material models like you can see that
like it's not
so in computer graphics there's the fong
shading model which is sort of the the
very basic model which has been around
since the 70s and you can see that um
although vigilant looks similar to fong
uh people's evil materials are a little
bit more um
what's the word refined like there's
there's like some back scatter behind
the sphere there's like yeah like a very
a very uh sharp highlight spot which is
very nice
so like small details but really
brings realism to the thing absolutely
yeah and it's something that he's been
working on for the last couple of years
and i remember his streams from the
beginning and we were a lot more flat
shaded and based on glows and metallic
reflections and so he's been
fine-tuning those things meanwhile
philippine has a revision logo yeah in
the revision logo on fluffy inside which
is
i i we see it repeated but also um i
think maybe she was just centering it
but
um
[Music]
in a very like
distinguished
sphere
yeah very nice looking
spearing spear that is
fearing my
uh
very
because i'm seeing the revision logo is
in 3d yeah so it is um
we are given a
two-dimensional revision logo and uh
normally when you do 3d you want to
assign distance functions so you want to
know how far away you are from the
surface
um technically
i think writer provided the sdf of that
i'm not sure
we weren't given it we were just giving
yeah
i think she's recalculating i'm
scrolling past her code here and uh she
she's basing it
she's doing the calculations based on
the texture
not using the sdf
right so yeah
so yeah we have a tunnel we have a
tunnel of
revision locals oh my god maybe we're
gonna fly through it that makes sense
yeah that will be very exciting
are you gonna hit the the the parts
though are you gonna
be able to go through the the slips in
the in the it's gonna be it's gonna be
like a game but you have to avoid them
ah
we're all on
board for the ride so
if we hit the wall it's all of us gone
maybe you can set up a box for the chat
so in the chat can control if the camera
goes left or right it should be it
should be doable right there we go
now
nice
yeah that's pretty cool really stylish
as well so we're not even at the halfway
point so it's it's all to play for so
there we go
this is absolutely yeah fantastic work
on flipping stream flying to revision
logo
[Music]
yeah maybe we'll see some rotation of
the logo as well
i'm very excited for it yeah you think
something like that would happen right
no philippines is going all out
absolutely oh evil just
doubled his chances of winning instead
of one oh he has two
wow it's still very well we noticed from
evil right he spent 10 minutes setting
up but it's still very modest
oh he's gonna turn it into a very
complex shape in the jiffy he's just
gonna
put some fractals rotate this a couple
of times boom the whole world appears
that we shoot into the sphere and it's a
planet full of life
[Music]
we have 14 minutes and a half left so
still plenty of time left to code
absolutely some so much can change too
like
uh
some of of these shaders showdowns their
rounds are 15 minutes in the
quarterfinals so that's 10 minutes less
than the standard 25 minutes
so
when even when there's 15 minutes left
you can think well
i could
if i did a quarter final that was 15
minutes like in that amount of time you
sort of it helps you gauge how much you
how much you can do in that time
into the logo
yeah it's moving
that was what i was fearing but i think
she has like a little bit of space where
nothing will ever touch it
except for the one little the one little
spit there's one spit that we crush into
oh there it moves it rotates
i love to see it this reminds me of lock
picking by some reason like i imagine
all those things be like
it does
it feels like we're hacking the
mainframe
but it's so and again like absolutely
too prose coding on the screen because
it looks so professional
philippine uh filipino uh black hole
question for you what i'm obviously
you're trying to be requested at this
moment yeah no oh look at evil
oh wow
oh wow cersensky style uh sphere
duplication that's very cool so sir
spinski is a type of
the sphere is moving
a little bit
did i elucidate no i saw that as well
although i think it would be inevitable
so the question that i had from black
girl was who who would you prefer to
have in the final against you but being
our evil do you have a favorite
um
i'm trying to remember who i've gone up
against before because i've gone up
against evil and i was destroyed
so
do you want a rematch or do you just
want to win
destroy it a second time but
it'd be fun to have a i don't know if
i've gone up against bluffing before i
think that'd be very very funny
we have a little
pipe holding the revision logo in place
slightly off center but uh she'll
eventually fix it and meanwhile evil is
just completely fractalizing it
all out i think i do not know what's
happening on evil street and i love it
boolean
subtractions or whatever is he doing
it's like
yeah i don't know it's like i almost
think that it's like a cross section or
something
it looks fantastic though it's like
absolutely something completely new
and not like it's also something
extremely evil extremely evil absolutely
wow look look at the the bottom there
like the cylinders that stack on each
other makes like a weird form
it's almost it's also we've got the um
isometric view that philippines is
played with where
is he messing with flopping by doing an
isometric shader oh my god what a move
what a power move
[Music]
this reminds me of the executable
graphics as well due to the refined
detail of it all and
still have 11 minutes left to black hole
they want to talk talk to us a little
bit about executable graphics did you do
anything for
um no spoilers but uh basically
executable graphics is like what if we
pack one of these shader showdown
entries into a into a program which just
boots up renders something off screen
and shows it to you so it's like
if you can imagine bundling
a program like blender where you can
render like any anything any still image
what if you could bundle that all into a
program that's only four kilobytes big
do it with the code do it with shows
should be a really good uh
compo like last year was so great and a
lot of the people who participated last
year they were saying that they were
going to do something for this year as
well so i'm very really looking forward
to that coming up with the still image
you can use your code to actually light
and portray your image and it's such
awesome
yeah you can do some really like uh
what's the word um
like you could do some things you can't
do in real time like path tracing you
can do like global illumination bounces
all that kind of thing
i'm very excited to see what happens we
had so many entries last year they were
awesome
such good stuff in there
so yeah some pipes on the side
give them our industrial vibe to it yeah
we're in the subway
yeah we're in the revision subway this
is the new toyota tunnel this is the new
toilet title you have to jump down and
not hit them oh my gosh
and only then can use the bathroom
giant massacre revision 2022 another
giant giant ventilator system to
ventilate the hall
with the
logo rotating in it
though yeah it's absolutely they're both
looking fantastic
and that the evil screen is just as well
4k graphics absolutely i want and the
background color is so nice it's not
even moving yet i assume he's gonna make
it move i
maybe he isn't how absolutely daring
would that be he's just portraying a
really cool image i think he would
actually get away with it at this point
i i've never i don't think i've seen
someone have a still image for shaver
showdown yeah exactly
if it's gonna happen in any at any event
i think revision would be the one
this yeah
this whole chatty shoutout has been
fantastically out of the box so
i'm super excited very different from
what we normally see in these cars
so awesome to see you grow and everybody
is always doing their a game it's it's
absolutely
fantastic to look at and also
if you if you were here at this point
what would you add on flop inside and
what would you add on evil side
what i would love to see on philippine
side is that the individual components
of the revision logo it rotating
differently i'm not sure if that's like
feasible within that as well with the
technical framework that philippine has
like
um i did it in my shader but it was just
a still image like i wasn't i wasn't
tracing through it was just a texture
but when you're tracing through it i
mentioned this in previous rounds but
whenever you're tracing through
um a 3d scene certain mathematical
constraints have to be satisfied
otherwise you get like visual glitches
so
it could be that if you rotate each one
individually it might break those
constraints and everything sort of
messes up which would look great
what we want here is artistic control
the only the only thing bad about
glitches is that they take artistic
control away
what about evil's evil evils fractal
city what will you change in evil's
fractal city to make it
i want to see movement i want to see
movement so bad i want to see this thing
i want to see either the camera moving
flying through or i want to see it just
warping
yeah moving and rebuilding itself i
think
small objects flying through it yeah
even that like but i i would also
actually be happy if it stayed still
because there would be such a baltimore
i would appreciate it really
yeah it's a fantastic round again it's
like nine minutes on the clock eight
minutes we're actually getting near
seven minutes left
yeah
seven minutes and a half you've heard
about a minute and a half and not no
movement in evil shadow yet
it's looking extremely intricate these
seven finals man it's absolutely
terrifying
unaccelerating i'm really because i've
yeah we have seen detailing i think in
the evening
someone made the joke that uh evil
shader the encoder really likes evil
shaders
actually
the cube in the middle for rotating
queue but it's gone now
yeah sneakily showing up
maybe that's the cube from last last
round does that help to finish its quest
yeah it's really supposed to fly there
it is it is and again
like last round
it's tumbling all
along i just do collision detection now
and then the physics inside the shader
yeah
five minutes left time enough
i'm sure you could do with the previous
frame texture um it just
i don't know if you'd be able to
improvise it
yeah
about six minutes left to do it
um we probably should repeat what the
hell we're actually doing here in case
there are new people around so uh black
will be wanna explain once more what it
is exactly that a shader coding entails
absolutely i always love to explain
shaders to people so basically what's
happening on screen right now is we have
two programmers one on the left and one
on the right and they have 25 minutes to
program from scratch visual
and they're programming this in a
language called glsl which compiles and
runs directly on the graphics card so
for each pixel this program that they're
running gets invoked and they
essentially just get the x and y
coordinates of the pixel and if they
have to decide in the code for that x
and y position what color does it need
to be
um they get some other inputs like they
get that current time they get some
textures that they can sample they get
the previous frame they can sample that
as a texture um and also the fft which
is the spectrum of the audio that's
playing so that uh that allows them to
do um audio reactive shaders if they
want to so as the music that uh who's uh
who's djing this round
yeah ronnie's great music um could
influence these shaders if the coder is
so pleased so how much time do we have
left by the way
five minutes five minutes okay and i
love i loved your explanation of like
for every x and y for every pixel it
gets to determine what the color is and
you look at these two effects you go
like
how what
so that's how evil made that blue he
just decided what pixel it should be yes
exactly
like there's there's a sphere here what
color should it be oh it's going to be
blue
i'm really i'm really wondering if evo
is making a static image it's absolutely
it would be such a ballsy move it would
be and and philippine with her indeed
the cube is now falling down revision to
always look looks absolutely fantastic
like it's flopping
in pro form it looks very fluffy as well
like the whole glow and the the bright
color sort of thing
both are shaders not super
colorful her theme for this revision
yeah do you think that uh
i think that last time she did some
previous frame stuff where we had this
weird fog effect or like uh
i like this keep it full bean please
keep it looks great oh my god five
minutes on the clock and this is again
like it was the previous round and i'm
looking at you black hole oh colors look
lights lights evil city has like oh my
god
is going for an aesthetic image i think
and it's looking absolutely gorgeous
this is again going to be tied to the
last minute like the previous round
oh my god my heart my poor heart
again the semi-final
yeah no matter oh it moves it moves
there we go in the last few minutes
again isometric maybe uh
not not technical ah multiple
points this is absolutely looking so
yes there camera
baller evil three minutes left to polish
this up philippine evil give it all you
got this is an amazing round
for this round who is gonna yeah who is
gonna take it up against black hole in
the final and black it is not worried at
all
no pressure in my mouth
[Laughter]
no biggie
no pressure
uh black will tell us a little bit about
what is the difference between coding by
the shader showdown and coding for like
the shader jam that we've been seeing as
well flopping just disappeared it's
evaporated oh my god now this is going
to be those 10s last minutes yeah two
minutes
is it more stressful or for the shade
well obviously it's more stressful but
which one do you enjoy more
yeah uh i like freestyle because you can
sort of like uh experiment like
with shader showdown you can experiment
with new things that you really really
really have to go as fast as you can but
with uh freestyle you've got like an
hour an hour and a half so you can just
sort of like play around do some stuff
it's also low pressure because there's
no winner right it's just do whatever
you want and
you might have some fun like you could
watch what the other people's doing
maybe uh react to them and to put some
stuff in your skater excuse me to
incorrect this has two minutes left
i'm
mesmerized by these two i'm i think this
is the best round we had so far on this
revision it's absolutely loving both
effects
i really really love the glow and the
the
interesting sort of chromatic aberration
type effect that we're seeing on
flipping side i don't even know how
you'd explain it but it's
okay oh my gosh
oh my god
[Music]
i don't know what the hell is going on
that this is absolutely true the force
of both of these shadow coders people
you're with you're witnessing history at
this point this is absolutely fantastic
work
i mean he's been working with some
morphing stuff for a
materials
it's like gold is one of the hardest
colors to pick because it's like is it
is it too yellow is it too green is it
too orange like yeah
i think uh evil other choice
i usually get up and do a silly dance so
imagine him dancing right now i mean you
have 20 seconds
to 15 seconds left round up your thing
it's both of them looking awesome
no pressure blackout
the brillskin the broski has such a
party
[Music]
second edition also on flopping and
looks amazing
my god
definitely one of the best rounds we had
so far thank you both flopping and evil
this was totally amazing
but there was so much happening at the
end just wow
on the chat i want to hear some noise in
the chat please
shout out your favorite
this is completely insane
i absolutely i can't see it but i assume
twitch is blowing up as well because
this is absolutely what a round
i'm watching
i don't know if you have some
some time to uh asks evil and
philippines some questions let's check
with the production
uh but uh evil and filipinos want to
unmute yourselves real quick and just
say something about what you did we
would totally love to hear your comments
[Music]
i knew it
see but but your shader totally killed
it as well philippine but
evil thing is like totally insane i i
this is crazy
what a show thank you so much what an
incredible tour de force broski what the
hell was that transformation how did you
plan that
just look completely it's like
and i thought yeah it's cool it's really
cool but i was like something
something needs to change and then i i
just came across
the idea is reclaim office space you
know off in space
we claim off these spaces let nature
take over make this topical it's all
covered in it you know what it is yeah
it really looks a lot more organic
it's what a god damn what a show i'm
speechless
i don't know if we get to see
i love every pizza
i actually saw it i thought it was a
revision
video like
it's not a render it's live golden
uh
[Laughter]
a couple of meters away running back to
the announcer winner loading
jokfully said it's gonna be a battle for
the
this is scene history being written
right now i i don't think uh i mad props
to both of you
yeah
philippines so whoever's left uh who who
did you think won
evil
you you like that more but like very
very nice i haven't seen you really like
it's shaky earlier
i said to you this is like
already
secret in the background
you turn it on just
what's now e
um okay uh i'll i'll take this one uh i
i guess to nobody's surprise uh evil
takes this
with the amazing display of
what the
mad drops to philippine i love this
shader obviously the revision logo is in
it so
and the glowing cube and the glass
effect yeah awesome very very very nice
stuff very well executed so uh yeah i
think we have our final which will be
blackle versus evil yeah so um so black
hole was one of the people
announcing
and commentating on this last one
and now black hole is going to have to
compete against evil in the like finals
or whatever
uh obviously we don't have time to watch
that right now
um
so uh
thanks to the i think we've got like
what six or
eight people or something left um thanks
for sticking it out till the end
uh i know there are some people on the
live stream watching i got a couple dms
and whatever
uh so thanks if you've been watching
this online
uh i hope that if this inspires anyone
to do anything it's to you know write a
demo or
uh do some sort of you know like art or
music for you know a demo party or
something like that or at least
hopefully
i've helped blur the line between art
and programming a little bit
for you so um
if you like what you see you know search
for demo scenes something on youtube and
you know watch some demos live stream
some demo parties uh go to some parties
in whatever
country you're in obviously right now
you're in the u.s so you know like shoot
for app party or demo splash or if
synchrony is happening again this year
that would be great
uh revision
will if they do a satellite thing again
we'll definitely have something
at the museum so you can come down to
the museum see the museum and
do a demo party at the same time it's
pretty fun but
um so i'm going to sign off our previous
presenter
dropped a vape pen so if anyone wouldn't
mind uh checking the floor near them or
something we're gonna try and figure out
how to bring up the lights
um
and see if we can see it but um and
actually
i asked what color
do i have an answer
is
black cover
gunmetal pale green
underneath
so if anyone sees that
uh
that's that's what we're looking for and
i'm gonna sign off and
kill my laptop and start packing up my
stuff if anyone wants an lp i think i
still have them out
and
thank you for literally all the things i
think i know everyone in here by now so
thanks for being here
you