do
uh
good morning everyone welcome back to
our last day of hope i know it's uh it's
sad that we're here the last day but
we've got another great talk lined up
for you right now the talk is using
security automation to organize your
cyber security threat intelligence
knowledge it will outline how the cti
open cti platform can be deployed scaled
for high availability using cloud data
strategies and utilized by strategic and
technical cyber threat analysts at any
seniority level
so we have a matrix chat thread for this
talk if you have questions especially
for the virtual audience go and enter it
into the matrix chat and when we get to
the qa section of this talk we'll
try and get your questions answered we
also have a qa section as a microphone
in back so when we get to the qa section
please audience members come back and
queue up and we'll we'll queue you up
for the speaker so with that let's
introduce andrew q for his talk thank
you
hello good morning everybody
um so right off the bat opinions on my
own and not the view of my employer and
should never be taken
seriously um my name is andrew um i'm
here because i love to give
give presentations or if you speak
minion bellow
so about my a few things about myself um
i was born and raised in queens not too
far from from st john's university
i'm currently a platform engineer for
the city of new york um some of the
things i do day to day um involve
kubernetes devsecops infrastructure as a
code
site reliability site reliability
engineering
and incident response
and this is my second hope in real life
so
let's let's identify the problem
cyber intelligence tooling is expensive
the licenses and subscriptions are not
cheap
um let's define cti so what is what is
cyber threat intelligence crowdstrike
defines it as in a very loose term the
collecting of possessing of the
analyzing of a threat actors motives
targets and attack behaviors to make
decisions using good judgments
gardner calls it hard facts backed by
evidence about existing or emerging
menaces or hazards to um to assets
so whether
it be like i.t computer security i.t
assets or it could be otics assets as
well
so in short to summarize the two
definitions together very loosely um
cyber threat intelligence is in which
third actors are tracked by what they
want what they do
what they have done and based strictly
on facts
so
uh like i had in the first slide um or
the first um the slide in the uh in the
section um we have too many vendors we
have too many feeds um some of these
names are maybe household friendly that
you've seen before anomaly that stream
third connect their intelligence
platform record a future is a is a big
name in cyber threat intelligence um and
we have palo alto um relatively new to
the space i um i um i'd say they're you
know maybe less than a year in um and
they integrated a threat intelligence
module in their um sort platform called
xor cortex xor
um and you know these these big brand
names used um in enterprise um they'll
charge an arm and leg um to use their
systems
not only do you need um
not only for um cyber threat
intelligence do you need a platform to
you know aggregate all your data you
also need and you also need
subscriptions and feeds you know
upstream so um here are a few that you
might you know you may also know like
crowdstrike intelligence and indicators
recorded future has wonderful streams
and threat feeds
msi fsisac if you're into like the
government space financial services
space
um mandiants bought by google and
previously known as or separated from
fireeye
alto's unit 42 third research group has
has
good threat feeds
and url house and um you know there may
be others
and each of these um each of these fees
each of these vendors whether or not who
you pick if you want like you know high
fidelity data and whatnot um you know
these feeds cost
you know thousands of dollars hundreds
of dollars in order to be a subscriber
of
and so um
knowledge is power powers knowledge you
can't you can't run you can't do you
know cyber threat intelligence if you
don't have
uh if you don't have the knowledge and
you can't have you can't uh conduct
cyber threat intelligence if you don't
have the power
so let's identify the solution right
enterprise cyber threat intelligence is
way too expensive so let's make it let's
make it cheaper enterprise cyber threat
intelligence doesn't have to be
expensive
so the the main the main topic that i'm
going to speak about today um is to
introduce you guys to um opencti opencti
is an open source free to use
cyber threat intelligence platform you
can find on github
it's
created by these lovely
individuals
outside
located in france paris
um
they operate under the um the uh the
non-profit organization called luitix
and they've been working on this product
for about
two to three years
um
and um they've just been making huge um
groundbreaking groundbreaking uh waves
in the space in order to make cyber
threat intelligence um you know open to
all free to use to all without the
limitations of like cost or anything
so about opencti
it's an open source comprehensive
platform that allows organizations to
manage structure store organize and
visualize their cyber threat
intelligence knowledge and observables
it uses a modern text stack
front end is written in reactant node
used back in python use graphql for
or it's api
um it's database you can use
elasticsearch or open search if you'd
like um
it uses a rabbitmq for its messaging
queue to um
to designate work and tasks
and use redis as a cache
for
you know non-persistent um
non-persistent stor storage
and um to reiterate it's open source
community empowered and free so you know
if you if there's a
you know develop the developers lunatics
um that make the program or that make
the platform um they have this policy
where if there is a you know if there's
a bug in the general release they'll try
to fix it within 24 hours
communities community suggestions um are
welcomed um if you if you use the
platform and you realize that you know
there there could be a like a you know
great idea that you know that would work
really well in the ecosystem you could
just submit like a feature request
and you know they'll respond really
quickly
and most importantly it's free
so um the core the core functionality of
the platform divides into essentially
three parts um the first being the
ability to organize and manage your
knowledge so
you know you as
you know uh an info an infosec team may
have you know intelligence people
working under you and you know your
intelligence team will have to you know
save their work do their work conduct
their research be able to you know
deliver deliverables in in you know one
sense or another
uh the platform the second core
functionality of the platform is to
visualize and graph um the knowledge
that you accumulate so the ability to
you know draw pretty pictures make
pretty relationships between you know um
your threat actors you
the threat tools that your threat actors
use and the targets the targeted
entities that your threat actors
target
and the third functionality is to
aggregate what you know what others know
and what you want to share to others so
the ability to essentially you know pull
upstream from crowdstrike from record a
future from mandiant from palo alto and
be able to
um you know save it um you know
on your premise um and have and also
have the ability you know to share the
data that you collect harvest ingest
analyze uh validate um to
downstream clients whether it be other
infosec teams within your organization
organizations whether it be other
infosec teams or cti teams and other
organizations or parent organizations
partner organizations and things like
that
um so we'll talk about
the first core functionality which is
organizing your knowledge um
cti for cyber threat intelligence you
can say that you can break it down into
two
two components two schools of thought
essentially
strategic versus
technical
where um first
for strategic cti right it's mainly
about knowledge about your threats um
the threat tools that your threats use
and related entities that are targeted
by your um
by your threat actors
so um so your threats could come in you
know
a variety of you know come in a variety
of forms right whether they be like
threat actors meaning
um you know russian fsb iranian military
um
korean korean peoples
the korean the kpa um you know the
chinese army and things like that
intrusion sets are more along the lines
of like
um your apts your worms your spiders
your bears
um things like things of that nature
not necessarily tied to you know an
organized real world um
uh entity
um and campaigns meaning you know things
like uh real world events like you know
upright government uprisings government
elections
um
big events in nature like solar winds um
things like that
threat tools
so um
strategic cti
threat tools fall under the strategic
cti through the use of you know keeping
track of the malware which is which are
you know the motion software that your
their actors are deploying whether it be
ransomware trojans worms etc
um the attack patterns which correspond
to
your miter attack framework um and
things like that
um courses of action which is minor
attack which is like you know minor
attack techniques and patterns but
without the miter attack
you know
identifying schema
tools so you know your cobalt strikes
your metasploit
your your empire your bloodhound tools
that your threat actors use um you know
in order to conduct their business
and of course you can't forget about
vulnerabilities right you have your
after all your throat actors are um
are um
are uh you know using are uh hitting
your um
or using vulnerability or using
vulnerabilities to their advantage um
and they're tracked by you know the cves
and things like that
so targeted entities targeted entities
falls under um countries cities
organizations and individuals pretty
self-explanatory usually um these would
be the you call it the victimology the
victims of of attacks and of threat
actors and and things of that nature
um and so we'll move on to the technical
cyber threat or cyber
technical the technical component of
cyber threat intelligence which is um i
guess probably what most people would
would allude to when you think about you
know cyber threat intelligence and
things like that which were just
observables artifacts and indicators you
know your ips domains url hashes email
email addresses
file names and things like that
so
um opencti the opencti platform will
aggravate all your strategic knowledge
as well as your as well as your
technical knowledge and kind of like you
know put it all in a single pot and for
you to draw relationships or
automatically have the platform draw
relationships for you in order to
organize your data
but how can it be done right
and this is where
um
we we take you know devops into the mix
how can we deploy um
opencti you know whether it be you on
your home lab for your organization
um for your own use for that matter
so score ecosystem like i mentioned
before um you know uses open source
tools and technologies
we have elasticsearch or open search for
your um for your persistent database you
know everything everything gets uh
written and read into it
um
redis keeps track of your um your
your cash your non-persistent storage
stores that you know
that doesn't need to be saved
um we have uh min io um
which essentially is just like a front
end for for s3 buckets um but anything
with like uh you know xml s3 xml api can
work as well so you could use google
cloud storage you could use azure
we have rabbitmq
you know open source amqp platform
to handle events
and we have a few openctac components um
which are made of
the react front end um graphql back end
um python connectors and python workers
so um for the last few bits you know
everything is
um strives to be like a micro service
oriented environment
but wait how can it be scaled how well
does the scale
so yes everything that you just saw in
the in the graph um in the graph in the
previous in the previous slide um could
be scaled for high availability for high
availability for example um
elasticsearch you could use a multi-node
cluster multi-regional cluster you know
to prevent outages you know
pump up as many replicas primaries as
you want rollovers and things like set
up index rollovers um uh
uh you know snapshots hot and cold hot
warm and cold indexes in order to keep
your you know the most frequently
accessed data um you know in hot
and keep your you know less used data in
cold so that you aren't you know using
crazy amounts of resources for
elasticsearch
redis can be also configured for high
availability high availability you can
use a multi multi-node redis instance um
that's perfectly fine it'll be resilient
to you know regional
regional downtime or zonal downtime if
you're in the cloud
grab mq like like i said before you
could you know you could also set up a
multi-null cluster for rabbitmq in the
events you don't want you know just
because your rabbitmq goes down doesn't
mean that your platform would stop you
know without processing tasks and things
like that
and min io which you can you know if you
have the ability to um uh
you know have access to an s3 buckets
whether it be like aws gcp or azure um
you'd have you know the
the cloud platforms um
word of like you know
99.9999 percent availability uptime um
which translates to about like you know
a handful of hours of downtime every
year
and the opencti ecosystem itself meaning
the platform the workers
the connectors
they're all stateless in nature they
don't hold any states if they
they go down your data won't you know
disappear as long as you know
everything's being written into
elasticsearch as long as you're
saving it to a persistent a persistent
disk um
you won't have to worry
um the opencti ecosystem is essentially
built off of like container technology
um so that you know everything is
micro serviced
everything is partitioned um you can
spin up whatever you want however you
want um you could configure you know how
you need
you know
100 front ends to service your clients
you're sure why not it's fine because
you know the data is being um uh written
and read and written into alaska search
anyways if you need you know if you see
a spike in
um
in the demand of your of your cti team
you know if they need to do you know
something um resource intensive you can
spin up more workers more consumers in
order to um get their work done um
during you know the rush
so adoption right um i talked about how
to what our um what the problem was what
the solution is
um gave you guys a little bit of of a
brief
a brief introduction about the um open
cci platform
um and i also you know describe to you
guys how to briefly you know deploy it
in your home labs um
you know organization workspace
environments and things of that nature
let's talk about you know if you even if
you didn't have a cti team in your
organization or you're thinking about
you know um spinning up a
cti team um
how would you
operationalize opencti
within your cti teams or infosec teams
if you don't already have a cti team
so
um
this is what
essentially what the platform would look
like the moment you know from a clean
slate you essentially have nothing right
um
how would you
the main question would be like you know
um how would you
um
uh pull data from upstream from your
vendors from your subscriptions from
your thread feeds have it all you know
pumped into the platform and then have
your um you know technical analyst
strategic analysts um you know go on the
platform and be able to you know conduct
their work
because at the end of the day right you
want your platform to look something
like this where you know you have you
know pretty graphs pretty lines um big
numbers things to show you know upper
management um you know
uh prove the proof of upper management
you know you're keeping track of like
you know you know thousands of thread
actors thousands of threats um and you
know have a running database of like all
the tools that um that you've seen that
you know that your
partners know and things of that nature
so um
you can't have a home without any
furniture right you can have a bare
metal shell um but if you don't have
your you know if you don't have like
connectors or enrichment or
um
ingestion um you won't be able to
um function really
um so a few instruction injection
connectors break into three parts which
are internal enrichment internal import
external import so internal enrichment
essentially just means that you know you
have a
ip or domain or a url you're unsure you
know you're unsure if it's like benign
or malicious or not yeah you can you
know go on virustotal you could type it
in whatever um but you know we we want
to try to like automate the process so
like if the ipv the url of the domain is
already on your platform you know from
somewhere whether it be like you know
uploaded um from somewhere um or you
know manually put in um
you'd be able to you know
uh run like a virus like a virus total
query lookup you'd be able to query
any any service that you have that you
have an api key for for the most part
you know to learn about you're more
about your entity
we have internal imports um which means
that you know in the event um
your team is not as super technical like
the way that you guys receive
information is through like newsletters
or like email or something like that or
maybe you have like pdfs or documents
that people send you about threat
reports and things like that internal
import just means that you can take you
know
knowledge and reports um manually and
you can upload them onto the platform
for the platform to like you know ingest
break down and parse
we have the external import
which
as it implies we'll
communicate upstream you know to your
vendors um
you know it'll constantly pull um for
uh
pull your vendors like threat fees and
subscriptions in order for you to get
the most recent indicators the most
recent um
threat actors and relationships and how
and even reports as well
and for e-justin
because you know you have you know open
cci shouldn't be your shouldn't be the
you know last station of the of the
routes in which your data flows from
upstream to downstream open cci could be
in the middle ground where um other um
other instances other clients it doesn't
have to be open cti you can use you know
any of the other vendor um
you know vendor paid paid programs um
products to hook into opencc open cti
has like a cool functionality where you
can essentially just like spin up like a
taxi you know uh threat feed and be able
to like whatever whatever data that
matches whatever filter um that hits
your platform you can just like ship it
off you know export it you know put it
in your put it in the feed um to be
consumed downstream
so
um
this
this um
this diagram here just kind of
breaks it down even further where um
starting with on the left side we have
the external input connectors so these
are the connectors that will listen from
upstream so if you need you know an
updated you know uh you know they put up
they put out like a new miter attack
technique and you need you know you need
you need your platform to like run the
update your platform will automatically
be able to pull the miter attack
techniques um uh
the csvs the jsons you know hosted by
miter um from their github you know
every day or something so you get the
most up-to-date information if you need
like
um
you know whatever taxi servers that you
have subscriptions to whatever taxi
servers that um that you that you pull
information out of currently you can
hook that into as well as an external
input
connector um
if you need an uh updated list of
running list of like your cves um you
know
cv 2022
whatever um
you can also hook that in into the into
the platform so that your platform gets
updated vulnerabilities and knowledge
about them
we have on the very top we have the
internal import file connector
which essentially allows you to what i
just described before the ability to
import um your pdfs that you receive
from you know partners over email or
stuff like that you could receive you
know
the you know you could turn the latest
like bleeping computer article or
something and adjust that into the
platform if it is uh relevant to you
and they'll be able to parse out your
your pdfs into sticks to json um you'll
be able to parse out your csvs into 60
json in order for it to be ingested by
the
platform um
right underneath we have the internal
enrichment connector um and essentially
it just you know it calls out to
whatever vendor solutions that you have
whether you have like a you know virus
total api key or something or if you
have like a you know palo alto api palo
alto auto focus wildfire api or or
something um and be able to you know uh
ask your vendor you know what do you
know about this ioc and they'll come
back to you with all sorts of data and
for that you can you know uh with a
click of a button you'd be able to like
save all that information onto opencti
on the right side we have the um
internal export connector um which just
parses which just parses like you know
csvs and um pdfs
into you know 62 friendly json
and of course you know if you have an
in-house like dev team you know
um to to to aid your um you know to
assist your your cti team your in-person
dev team would be able to you know write
any custom code write any custom
configurations took into your like
firewalls to hook into your store your
sims um in order to you know
fetch whatever data your sort and sims
are you know whatever is like sitting on
there and be able to like you know
respond back and forth like hey like you
know the sim found something let's look
it up on opencti opencti if opencs if
your opencti platform doesn't know about
it you can just you know write a
connector
to constantly pull your um you know your
aggregators from elsewhere um about like
new entities iocs threats and things
like that
so external import open the floodgates
essentially you know you'll get a ton of
data from threat feeds um from upstream
you know hundreds of thousand indicators
every hour depending on you know um what
you're tapping into and you have to you
know you don't want your your your cci
team to go through each indicator figure
out you know what is useful what isn't
useful you want to make sure that's you
know the indicators they stay
fresh they aren't stale you know they're
not they're not very useful if they if
they
um have came in like you know a year ago
you need something to you know
auto off-board them off your platform
just because you know indicators get
stale over time
um
you could get
external threat reports so whether you
get like a cisa advisory or like a
weekly report
from
you know from whatever government entity
that's that's giving out reports for
free um whatever roll ups whatever white
papers use letters and things like that
you know if it comes in pdf form you
know just pump it into the into platform
have the platform you know be able to
like you know pull out the the relevant
entities thread actors
indicators and save it all
and if you have data sets um you know
right because like the platform is just
a shell by itself without any data um if
you need you know uh references to your
miter attack techniques your cv database
um you could pull that from github as
well
so internal imports um
it's just like the importance of the
import
of reports
from your vendors from your government
entities from partnerships if
crowdstrike if mandiants if fireeye if
they're sending you you know
uh reports about threat actors and
things like that and you want to keep
track of it you know you don't want it
you know you know you don't want to like
print it out or whatever and just like
leave it to the side or like file it in
their file cabinets just put on open cci
it'll be your like um it'll be your file
cabinet for you
and you know whether it be from a taxi
feed or like a newsletter or a white
paper it'd be able to store it
um and the way that it would it would
essentially work is that um it'll parse
through the pdf it'll grab you know
they'll be able to grab
all the domains the urls the entities
and be able to save it
so let's take an example right let's say
um
let's say
uh you got this report right crosstrek
every year they'll give out for free if
you like give them like your name your
house number your email or stuff like
that they'll give you um like a global
threat report every year and usually
these these threat reports they're rich
in nature you know they're like 50 pages
long you know they've got you know the
crowdstrike stamp on it so you have you
know you know that it has to be
good but you don't want your cci team to
like you know you don't want them to
you know they could read it from cover
to cover but
you know unless they're like taking
notes or whatever you probably want to
you probably want to automate this
process
better right so
uh fairly simple you just like once you
get your pdf uh you just like upload it
to the platform the platform will have
um it will be constantly waiting for um
waiting for new work essentially once it
receives that that upload pdf which you
store it in your s3 buckets or min io
gateway um to be able to like
parse through the pdf and be able to
give you
um
a be able to give you like entities that
it found throughout your report so the
crowdstrike report um that i just
uploaded um will give you you know this
kind of uh breakdown
and the breakdown could sometimes be i
don't know
it doesn't show here but you know out of
that 52 page reports you know there
could be you know 500 entities 500
relationships about how entities relate
to each other and things like that
um uh you don't want to take
crowdstrike's word for granted and have
the platform just like you know create
your entities and relationships um in
which um
you don't want it to like what if uh you
know what if you need somebody to hold
your um hold its hand and um walk it
through for a little bit you want to you
want to be sure to validate whatever
findings that crosstrek is sending over
because after all you know there are
ones that are um writing the reports but
you're the ones that are ingesting it
and you don't want your you know your
ingestion to be you don't want your data
set to um
to go bad just because you're ingesting
it the wrong way so opencti it gives you
the functionality of pre-validating
anything you ingest into it whether it
be from the newsletter or pdf um you
know it'll give you it'll give you some
um
some drop downs and things like that and
you can um always
have the option to to choose not to
import something in just something to
choose not to build a relationship
between two entities if you do not want
to
so
after you adjust something after it runs
through the pre after you upload
something after you ingest it um after
you pre-validate it and validate it um
you'll end up having you know a huge
list of um entities you know typed to
their um
entity type which matches corresponding
to their sticks to um
sticks to type
and using your api calls um
uh you know if crowdstrike tells you you
know here are five urls that are known
to
um uh
be bad or malicious you can have your
security tools you know
uh re uh you know re-verify the data
that crosstrek is sending you um you
know upload your your urls upload your
ips and domains to virustotal you know
check your sandboxes hey have our um
have our malware analysts have our
reverse engineers seen this before um
you know if so like let us know um and
you'd be able to make the community you
know you'd be able to have open cti on
the platform be able to make the
callouts for you um in order to
do the enrichment
you can also uh use like showdown if you
want um you know look up your uh your
url see what showdown knows about you
from from the outs from its lens and eye
and
viewpoint and have it come back with
whatever data that um that it knows that
you think is relevant to you
so
for the ejection the ejection portion um
it's mainly catered towards like you
know other teams uh partners that you
have that you work with um or like other
um other event or even even vendors if
they want as well um so if you partner
with like industry partners or like
segmented segmented it teams you know if
they have their own instance of opencci
or if they have their um you know if
they use another vendor product or
whatever um that accepts like um
taxi feed streamings they could hook up
into your your platform
and if you ever um in the event that you
know in the event that there's a high
level high severity incident you need
something done quick and you need to be
able to give to um you know give a
deliverable give a presentable um to
your c-suite to your upper management in
to your upper management folks um you'd
be able to like ad hoc on the fly be
able to export everything you know about
you know an entity or threat
a threat group a threat actor a threat
tool
in order to you know write a report
about it
and the one thing that i want to um
uh you know emphasizes that you know
you'll be able to like freely share and
export um anything that you have on the
platform as long as it's like on the
platform or um already and without like
you know well without limitations and if
you run run into you know if you
encountered the issue of you know
of like resource restraints or resource
construction restraints then of course
you just like scale out
so after you have you know after you
have all these streams that are being
tapped into your your platform you're
getting all this data from upstream um
uh what you know what should your cci
team what should your cti team do with
it right so they could run analysis
right as as the
as a threat analyst um ideally their you
know their job description would be to
you know keep track of emerging threats
keep track of threats that are
persistent or have been um hitting you
know relevant uh sectors and um
uh relevant sectors and things like that
that might that may be harmful for you
for your organization for your parent
organization and things like that
um you can integrate um
you know in the event of you know of a
high severity incident you know uh your
incident response plan hopefully would
would um
there would be a section in it to engage
your cti team to have them threat hunt
about any um any uh bad actors in your
environment
a popular thing to do is to use multico
transforms so you know you can use
multigo
hook it into your you know hook it into
into every environment that your infosec
you know every environment that your
infosec team uses um including opencti
to draw the relationships between you
know between your source your sim um and
of course your tip now um
in order to enrich whatever that your
cci team is trying to investigate or
threat hunt
and of course um at the end you know you
write a you can have the option to like
write a report to share findings within
your community and you know on a you
know on a
on a granular basis be able to share it
as like a data stream um to your uh
to whoever is hooked into your platform
and what's most important um
that is a is a big proponent of the
which is a core functionality of
platform um which is to visualize your
knowledge graph
so this is what a knowledge graph looks
like from a report right we have
we have you know we have a ton of
clusters we have a lot of relationships
um the clusters you know
should be pretty easy to tell what a
cluster is and you also have like you
know these these long blue lines that
connect cluster to cluster um and things
like that
right but you know it's way too it's way
too complex um and so the the platform
makes it really easy for you to you know
uh uh adjust the graph adjust the view
of the graph whether you know if you're
not like a
visual thinker or visual learner if you
want like the hardcore you know the hard
facts the hard ips
the hard the hard data you can obviously
choose not to use the graph
but zoomed in we can see that you know i
don't know if you guys could see
um
but you know we have using color
coordination we have uh malware
related to different
file file hashes and things like that
and how different malware relates to
other malware how how it references
other malware or how it targets other
other entities so you'd be able to zoom
in and out of the graph and play around
with it to see you know on the grand on
the grand scale you know what does
crowdstrike know you know from their
2021 you know global threat report or
whatever and be able to draw a graph
from their pdf reports um to to
understand what they're talking about in
a visual way
so usage
um let's run through like a demo use
case um let's say um
you want to learn more about like the
cac bot the quack bot um malware which
is like uh like a banking trojan that
targeted like financial services
companies and things like that in order
to like harvest like user credentials
and you know um
uh do malicious things
so you'd look up you probably just you
know go into your platform you see hey
like you know i want to learn you know
what has crackbot done um so far so you
look it up in your platform and you see
what your platform has to say about
quackbots um you know all this data
the platform itself isn't making it up
but it's getting from upstream from your
um you know from your threat intel fees
and things like that and your enrichment
you'd be able to see you know um how
often has has crackbots been seen
by our by your partners from upstream
you know how how often has it um been
referenced in the reports that you have
ingested you know how often has it's
been you know how many indicators
um
has it come from like like a like a
threat feed um that has drawn the
relationship between that indicator and
crackbots
um
and things like that and you can see
like you know which vendors are the ones
that are mainly supplying you the data
about what you um about what the
platform rules about crackbots
we got a few more you know a few more
bar graphs some pretty charts
for you to you know enjoy
you can see you know which which uh uh
based on the knowledge found on the
platform the platform would be able to
graph it graph it to you um in a visual
way to indicate to you the you know
which countries are being targeted by
crackbots which countries are
are related to crackbots
based on all your findings that you have
on the platform
and again no if you choose not to you
know if you're not a visual visual
thinker if you're not a visual learner
you can always just use you know
plain text in order to figure out um how
crackbot relates to like any of the
other pieces of entities on your
platform
but wait you know like i said before i
think the first couple words of my uh in
my title my presentations um say
security automation so um how does
security automation um fit in
whether or not your um you know your
team has a sore platform or whatever for
your for your sock um security
automation you know fits in very well
with with opencti so you know your stock
can if your stock identifies like an ioc
um that that they believe
is malicious they'll have the ability to
look it up and open cti and run through
you know all the cti related tasks in
order to make a determination
um if you have a sandbox and your
sandbox you know spits out some um
uh you know spits out some entities that
have found some hashes that had found
you wanted to you know look it up
internally on your open cci platform to
see what opencci knows about the um
about your uh about your hashes and
things like that from upstream
if you have a sim you know you can uh
you know write a custom connection you
could use a custom you could use an
existing connection if they're if
someone has written it out already um
you know whatever your sim sees just
look it up in your opencti platform to
see you know what does openct i know
about it
um and one cool thing um that
i use day to day is that like you know
um in the event um there's like some hot
topic whether it be like solar winds
whether it be like you know ot ics um
whether it be you know
whatever uh uh log4j or um spring for
shell or whatever you know if those
keywords appear in the reports if any of
those keywords appear um uh from uh
if any new relationships are being
created from up street from uh from a
threat feed on the platform you want to
be sure to you know alert um alert your
your um alert your security teams like
via like slack or something or like um
microsoft teams chat or whatever and
that would be a pretty cool way to like
you know get that 24x7 eyes on glass
without actually having someone 24 7
eyes on glass you know refreshing on
refreshing the ui of the platform
oh whoops
and um just because i'm like a platform
engineer so i have to like you know show
this portion you know use infrastructure
as a code for everything right you could
use deployment tooling to automate the
deployment if you're on a home lab you
could use like docker compose you could
use like ansible puppet chef um things
like that um i mainly operate in the
cloud so i'm a huge proponent for like
you know container technologies like
docker podman and using kubernetes in
order to orchestrate your deployment you
know you'll be able to use like you know
cloud technologies in order to make a
really robust open source um straight
from the ground up um cyber threat
intelligence platform for like your
infosec teams to to utilize
um and of course you know like anything
implement guardrails and your ci cd
pipelines and your deployment pipelines
to make sure that you aren't like
deploying like bad code bad builds um
and things like that for deployments
because you don't want you don't want to
purposely you know fat finger something
and like you know disrupt your um your
uh your your service
cool so
wrapping wrapping it up you know if you
if
if you didn't if you
lost um attention um opencti is an open
source community supported um platform
um bustling community they have like a
you know a very robust highly um highly
active slack chat um many people are um
are on it many newcomers are asking
questions and many veterans are
responding back
you know it's a community supported
environment
and made by lutex
opencta organizes your cyberthreat
intelligence knowledge
it connects upstream to vendors and
feeds
for your cti team to like uh to parse
and ingest and correlate on the platform
and can be connected as like uh um it
can be connected downstream to your sims
and source
in order to um get to uh enable alerts
and um and logs um uh for whoever has
that 24i 247 eyes on glass stock team
uh and opencti can be used um
to track relationships between entities
you know has crackbots
um targeted france has crackbot targeted
you know canada um has it has it
targeted has it taught has it targeted
like your um you know your it
organization or whatever um and things
like that
and most importantly you know opencti is
used to allow your cci team and allow
your infosec teams in order to make good
decisions um using good judgments
so thanks that's all i have
questions
hi uh great talk i appreciated the
narrative structure of the whole thing
you started with a clear description of
the problem and it looks like you've
engineered a pretty robust solution for
it for your team
i was curious you had a lot of different
stuff in your tech stack what were the
guiding principles that you kind of
followed in making those selections
so on those selections um you
you're kind of locked into them you have
to use a lot you have to use
elasticsearch you have to use um you
know rabbitmq
if you choose to you can you can use
their um uh publicly built images of the
platform and workers and things like
that you also have the uh you know you
have the options to like you know fork
your own and build your own images and
things like that but um uh you aren't
you know if you wanted to if you choose
not to use elasticsearch you can use
open search if you choose not to use min
io you can use your own s3 bucket you
can use google cloud storage you can use
as your
azure storage as well
great thanks
uh thanks for the talk um
so the platform seems really interesting
and it's nice that it's open source
but it seems to me it's going to be a
limited usefulness
unless you have the upstream feeds
so
what would you suggest for someone who
was not in a you know in an enterprise
um which
which feeds should they subscribe to to
sort of play with this and like how much
would that cost
um off the top of my head um there are
you know there are open source um uh you
know open free to use like reports that
you can find on the internet you can you
know always use like you know pdfs uh
you could use like
let me try to think
i think alien vaults
alienvault might be free
um
there are definitely some like tlp white
sources that you can use um that pull
from upstream i know miter has a miter
has a good um
good good feed um and its connection is
already built into open cti
um for you to pull like minor reports
about threat actors and intrusion sets
that mitre knows about
um
but other than that um you know you can
always just you know generate a pdf from
from like a from a report like maybe
bleeping computer or something or
um i don't know what another
good news source is but you just pull a
pdf if you see if you like it you know
you just pull the pdf and just import it
and just into your platform and see what
your platform thinks about it
all right we've got two questions from
our matrix chat so we've got a number of
them but we'll start with two if you
have a threat actor taking actions in
your environment and you take action can
you record that in open cti or do you
just have to use a separate ticketing
system
um so you know opencti unless you
explicitly tell it that hey like you
know a threat actor you know conducted
some kind of you know operation against
your your you know your organization's
assets your own personal assets unless
you explicitly tell that to open cci
opencc i want to know about it
um if you had like if you integrate it
with like your store or sim um you know
obviously if you get on a security
alerts and a security alert tells you
that you know
some
tool is is was was used in the past like
you know you know hour
to hit like you know one of your systems
you know opencti would be smart enough
to be able to draw the relationships and
say like hey we've seen this hash before
we've seen the we've seen uh this uh
signature before and it's been you know
and recorded future or like crowdstrike
or mitre um
attributes this hash um to this threat
actor like hey like you might be in some
deep trouble
but other than that like you know unless
you explicitly tell open cci like hey
like i've been hit by
you know the fsb or like by an apt group
or whatever um open cc i wouldn't be
smart enough in order to like um make
that decision the determination for you
but you can
all right and last question i think have
you done sharing with industry partners
and what challenges have you faced in
doing so
um so definitely i think
um
generally like people
people don't like on unsolicited i don't
know
people outside of organization or like
people that you don't work with day to
day they might not be uh receptive of
like unso unsolicited data like they
don't care about like you know what's
happening in in your neck of the voids
or whatever um but i think that um
because you know cti um the whole
industry of like counter-threat
intelligence is all about like
information sharing sometimes like you
know
uh someone
says something
um and it's listen and it's heard by
someone else and that person
quotes the original author and someone
quotes the original the author that that
quoted the original author you get like
this loop um so that's not always good
um but
um definitely um
i think one of the big proponents of
like cyber threat intelligence just like
you know just be open be able to like
share amongst like those you trust
um and if they if you know if they want
it
they can have it but if they don't want
it you know it's the door's always open
for them to connect
excellent all right well thank you for
the wonderful talk and thank for the
audience for participating
and come back in 10 minutes for their
next talk electronic warfare on a budget
of 15 or less
[Music]
hmm
you