[Music]
oh
hi everyone welcome to our next session
from mind control to mind expansion
hacking technology to rebuild our world
um
geva and javier uh are gonna
give us an interactive session uh in
which they're gonna use elements of
virtual reality brain computer
interfaces and ai to applying the hacker
the hacker's spirit to it and showing us
how to use these things in ways that
are not really what people expect us to
use us so we're going to be hacking the
out of it
so a big round of applause to give and
ravier and enjoy the session
[Applause]
friends hackers it's uh so exciting to
be here and actually
uh gathered together for the first time
in ages and not a moment too soon
because
i think
we can all agree that we're sensing a
sense of global system crash here
that the engines are turning but things
just aren't working that what we're that
the um basic props that we are used to
holding us up jobs prosperity are
vanishing
the planet feels like it's in a
precarious place our technology that's
supposed to be running all of this has
fundamental design flaws and there's a
lack the very technology that we're
using has brought as has riven engulfed
between us that makes it hard for us to
find identify and choose responsible
leaders and representatives to guide
and regulate our growth
um
we hackers i would argue are in a unique
position to do something about this we
have a vision we can understand systems
understand technology we have the skills
to analyze and build things we have a
rich culture of openness and sharing
what we need is an actionable plan to
leverage our strengths for disruptive
change and so i'd like to talk to you
today about fixing society about scaling
our efforts as hackers exponentially
the growth hack our impact to all of
society because what society is the
seven billion people it's a total
addressable market of the billions of us
on this planet where we could help solve
for the future of work the future of
humanity the future of the planet and of
course the future will make it all run
money we need to reinvent we need to
fund society we need to reinvent the
economic growth flywheel we need to come
up with a new business models new
revenue models decentralized distributed
this i can't do another second of this
[Music]
thank you for sticking around we're all
worried we get walkouts there
um
we hear a lot of this sort of thing
that was um
i hope it was evident parody um but it's
all too familiar
um right we see this over and over again
and if you look at if you look at slide
one there
it looks almost reasonable for a minute
there's things not quite right in the
world
but over and over and over and over
again
we see people
standing up and trying to do something
about it nothing ends up going what
feels a little bit um off the rails and
so what we'd like to do today is kind of
take a step back and and have a look at
the system in which all of this happens
we're used to
hacking systems
um we want to have a look at the system
the meta system the system that stands
above that the system on planet earth
um and i want to sort of encourage
everyone in this audience to develop to
open up and develop a mindset of hacking
on planet earth hacking on the systems
that run the systems that we usually um
that we usually hack on
um
and
um to do that
we'll we'll use a number of metaphors
that come up often in
things like this we'll talk about
systems and machines and so on because
they're useful ways of looking at things
and because machines and so on tend to
be the space where culturally we hackers
are supposed to be playing and it's
where we've we're most used to applying
a certain kind of mindset i mean a
certain set of skills
um
it's a useful metaphor but it's also a
metaphor that has its limits because
machines they tend to be
it's a word that comes out of the
machine age which has been with us for
hundreds of years now
and has stuck with us well into the 21st
century and i would argue is one of the
reasons
that things aren't working quite the way
we might imagine them to because there's
still
way too much machine age thinking built
into this thing the idea of systems that
are monolithic
centralized solid they have
centralized knobs and buttons and an
instruction manual and a certification
regime before you get to you know touch
any of the knobs
um
and buttons there's a
there's another metaphor in the way of
looking at systems um that we often tend
to prefer which is networks we often you
know it's um
it's it's a space in which we've been
playing for the longest time um and we
often like to conceive of of complex
systems as networks it's a more flexible
fluid and open
um kind of thing um you it's it's more
dynamic it's it represents flows it's
multi-dimensional
you can imagine modes inserting
themselves removing themselves
reconfiguring changes
and it's a good way of looking at more
dynamic systems
machine land
um absolutely um
absolutely hates networks uh machine
learn understands machines best which is
why we've seen this huge effort to turn
our networks back into
centralized machines that's why we have
cloud computing it's why we have so many
sort of technology affordances given to
us through applications that use a back
end in a data center somewhere it's why
we've seen this pull
away from
um
networked way of doing things to much
more
to the original sort of mainframe
um
way of doing things so
we'll use these two we'll use these two
metaphors and there's a
um and there's a third
of a
metaphor that um
um i'd like to introduce here which is
the metaphor of a game
because if there's one thing we like to
do it's we like to play with stuff
um
all right um
all right we um
just checking to see if there's some uh
visuals that go with this but there
aren't so we'll just imagine those um
so
um
right so if we um
if we look at the the world as is
um what we
what we look at if we can if we can pull
ourselves out if we can step up and have
a look at that at the world from as a
system if we step out of the usual layer
that we're used to looking at look at
things to layer up is we can see
a playground there we can see so much
sort of potential
so many
um
um so many possibilities in the
resources and the technologies and the
energies that we have
um
but most of the people playing on the
playground are playing a game that just
doesn't quite seem
like the sort of game we want to play or
the sort of game that we want to get
into
um and it's the sort of game that's
heavily one of its defining
characteristics of the classic game is
that it's really really optimized for
high score now scores are useful things
um scores can be
valuable in their own right there are
they they if you're
sort of adrift in the cosmos trying to
navigate
in some way having
dialing in a destination having some
measurement of how
close you are to that destination in
some dimension can be can be useful
um and a score can be a focusing device
and narrowing things down and focusing
and attending to a narrow set of things
is what we do we're constantly
experiencing reality flooding in through
all of our senses and we pay attention
to a tiny narrow bit of it and that's as
it
should be
um
but being able to be flexible and shift
our attention is also
vital if you've ever
flown a plane in dark or in fog
you have to do it by instruments and one
of the first things that you learn is
not to pay too much attention to any one
instrument to develop a broader picture
to try and build a picture in your head
around these
numbers otherwise you end up you know
flying into the ground um
and they're everywhere this this this
scorism this score based mentality is
everywhere i don't know how many of you
have one of these whether it's a smart
watch or a
fitness tracker or a smart ring or some
other
self-quantifying device and they're
amazing they literally
shine a light
into our inner workings
and show us something that's going on
inside and show us something that
although we might well have a
ability to to have some physical
recognition of this we can't always do
that
these things will will give us give us
some idea of what's happening with our
with our bodies rhythms while they're
asleep
um for example what does it do it gives
us numbers it turns everything into into
raw data it turns our heartbeat our
respiration into a stream of numbers and
it's it's not numbers it's a rhythm
it's the rhythms of our life
um
and when you compress it down to numbers
it's a lossy compression
but then
what tends to happen is those numbers
rather than deriving meaning from them
get turned into a score if you ever use
that are the apps that come with these
these things it's all about gamification
and leaderboards and how well have you
hit your metrics and what's your bad
body battery doing today
and it's all about
someone else's idea of what your rhythms
should be and how did i do boss is it
bedtime mum do i get a gold star
so
um you know because some
authoritative app has decided that this
is you know
this is how to interpret these numbers
this is
what you should be steering towards and
whilst there are absolutely people in
society and who
whom we should respect we should respect
everyone for their whatever knowledge
and insight and discoveries they've made
and we should
pay attention to people who've gone
before in directions we want to go
elevating
um
you know elevating people to a position
of authority making them authorities
giving them authority over us
um becomes very problematic and scores
are a lovely way of finding those
because you you get the leaderboard that
shows you who's doing well at the things
you think you want to do well at and
it's very easy to go from a leader board
to leaders what should i do
tell me o guru oh lord
and once we're following a leader we're
now a team it's now a team game and a
team score
and
once we've got that it's best to have an
opposing team or at least something to
oppose a war on cancer a war on drugs
the war on drug users
which perhaps gives us a little less
cancer but gives us a whole lot of
scorched earth
in in the process
and see this
[Music]
and this is this is what you get
when you end up with a system that's
completely obsessed with score this some
of you may have seen is a video
um from some research that openly i did
in which they trained um an ai a
reinforcement learning system uh to play
a boat racing game
um and had it optimized for score that
was the reward function that was that
was the thing that told it how well it
was doing and so it did and it found
an ideal way found a hack arguably to to
to maximize its score by going round and
round in circles getting absolutely
nowhere burning a whole lot of up
um
and getting and getting scores
20 to 30 percent better
than the best human players who were who
were you know trying to actually finish
the race
um
and this is what tends to happen um and
the problem is
um that in
reality the things we burn up don't
respawn um
indefinitely and so we always have to
bring these things
back to reality
um and there's a huge connection between
these scores in reality because these
scores traditionally the ones in society
have mattered if you don't get a good
enough score
you don't accumulate enough if you don't
get enough social capital if you don't
score well on these boards you end up
starving or lonely or dead or wishing
you were dead
so historically the stakes have been
huge have been huge an individual level
at a societal level they've certainly
felt like it and that idea is baked
into the system
um
but
that's a particular view it's a
particular view of reality that seems
more and more detached from it in an era
we seem to have in some dimensions too
much
rather than too little
so
um
so it's time to do something that again
i think hackers are naturally very good
at which is um which is questioning
consensus reality and going well hang on
um
this thing that you have doesn't seem to
work
um
quite the way you think it does this
thing that you this this system of yours
seems to be broken in ways that you
aren't even aware of but also the system
of yours has capabilities and
possibilities you can do things
that are outside of your instruction
manual and potentially
way more interesting
so
um
we can do the same thing with
consensus reality as a system because
consensus reality at this point
really has its problems yes it gives us
vaccines in the eiffel tower and
whatever music
moves your soul but it also gives us
civil wars it gives us doom scrolling
and it gives us
a mechanism where in supposedly well-off
parts of the world
supposedly prosperous people
spend over a hundred thousand hours of
the most precious parts of their lives
um
doing doing things for other people's
purposes um you know because of this
this need to constantly generate score
now
so if we
one step away from that and reimagine it
what do we do we could
um
you know conceive of some alternate
reality but alternate realities have a
few problems one they sound science
fictional it's something that isn't here
right now
um
the other problem is if you if you're
opposing yourself as an alternative
to something
then you're you're letting that
something shape you as well as sort of
negative space if you're saying well we
don't want to do that we want to avoid
that thing and in those circumstances do
we want to look like that you're shying
away from things and you're constricting
your movements in the same way that your
movements are constricted if you buy
into the thing your movements are
constricted if you avoid the thing
so
um
so all right so how about virtual
reality let's start with a complete
blank slate and build up something that
we can see
probably that
problem with building something from
scratch apart from the difficulty and
finding somewhere to do it
is that you have to have a very if you
want a really complete open world we
want something that has affordances in
it for a wide range of people and gives
us all
the sort of things that we really look
for in life
and that's very hard to do from scratch
and it's impossible
to get right nobody can build such a
system
you know
even if it were physically possible
getting it right we've seen from smaller
experiments out in the world that
getting that that's
planning everything out centrally like
that
never never quite works so so much for
virtual reality what about augmented
reality what about
taking what we've got taking the society
that we have and adding
sort of layers to it um adding
shiny new bits sticking out the side um
adding sort of overlay networking
because we're good at that we do we do
overlay networks all the time we take
some infrastructure we take some
mechanisms up there and say oh we could
do encrypted communication on this we
could we could build a distributed
currency out of this we could build a
file sharing network out there and build
these overlay networks that add this
sort of extra functionality so there's
that
augmenting existing reality in some way
um
but
as soon as we speak of augmenting it
we're talking about taking what's there
and and making the edges softer making
it a little bit shinier opening it up a
little bit we're still again constrained
by what's there
um and what's there and we've seen again
history has shown us time and time again
that the the the mechanism the the
evolutionary mechanism that's that's
that's propelled this system forward is
outstanding at taking
augmentations taking things that stick
out a little bit and pulling that inside
using that energy to feed more of the
same
[Music]
look at what powers
all of these
sort of regressive quote-unquote tech
systems
um that we see right now it's open
source right open source powers the borg
um the system is excellent at pulling in
these augmentations and realigning them
to its own end so that doesn't quite do
it either
so then
um
so then we come to the
possibility
of switching buzzwords switching things
a little bit of extended reality um
if we use those words not in the
buzzwordy way but we think about them
literally as the words that they are
that idea of extending
[Music]
reality
so
what that does is it acknowledges what's
there
already but but it allows us to open up
the space we say
well what can we what can we build out
here
that opens up possibility space
that doesn't
attempt to
oppose that world
it doesn't attempt to ignore that world
there's an attempt to overthrow that
world we're not looking to try and grab
the steering wheel because we could
steer that thing better again we've
learned that never works
and we're not looking to burn that world
to the ground
for a few reasons there's there's
there's valuable things in there yes we
can see there's a whole lot of waste
there's a whole lot of misdirection
there's a whole lot of everything we
don't want to be caught by the sunk cost
fallacy here
um
but neither do we want to burn it all
down because that's extra wasteful and
also
billions of innocent civilians live in
that world
so instead
we're we're we're constructing
we're visualizing and constructing new
elements of
reality
that connects to
that that borrow from that interoperate
with
the reality that's there an idea
again that's very central to a lot of
what we do of adversarial
interoperability
of there's something in there that has
functionality that we'd like to use a
little differently to the way we're
quote unquote supposed to that we'd like
to use in our own terms rather than the
terms and
of the terms and conditions
you know
um we do this and we build out
this is already happening some of you
may be seeing this space some of you may
be working in this space that there's
um there's little dots starting to form
out of
um many of the resources and
technologies and things in that system
but out here in in in possibility space
drawing from linking from connecting to
um
the systems the systems that are there
in ways
that work in this larger space not in
ways that are necessarily consistent
with the system as it's been and they're
people who are starting
to be able to move and live and do
things in in a wider space and starting
to bring
other people
with them so what does this mean
in practical terms and um
you know this is all very sort of airy
theory what does this mean in practical
terms if if you if you you're sitting
here and you're sensing something
you know several things that's that's um
um perhaps you'd like to see
um differently in the world
um and you have some connection or
attraction to them but you don't really
know what to what to do with this and
how does this whole
sort of image
um help you and to make it a little bit
more concrete um
i think it helps make it a little bit
more personal and start with you
um because to to understand
where it's possible to move and where
it's possible to go
um for yourself
and
you're the sort of expert on that and if
you do that if you
figure out where you're standing in all
of this and what you're doing in all of
this
then in figuring out how to move from
being
constrained by the system as is to a
more natural position whatever that
means for you
if you solve that puzzle
how do i
loosen these attachments retain those
connections in ways that are nourishing
and helpful to me and operate in a wider
possibility space if you do that then
you open up the space for everyone
you've pulled the space with you and
you've opened it up for everyone
standing next to you and you've created
if you like a sort of proof of concept
right we love proof of proofs of concept
you're like somebody discovers a way to
do something and
demonstrates how to do it in some small
way and that may not
work exactly for the rest of us but it
shows that it shows us that it's
possible
and others can build on that
so take a moment to to
like think about
something that's
that matters to you maybe you're
concerned about
food systems or something in in in the
way we move move around the planet or
maybe there's something to do with the
way we connect over networks or how we
sustain each other or something
completely different large small
where you're noticing something that's
awful where you're sensing something
that could be
could be possible if only we
looked at things or did things a
different way and where you have some
pull some connection to that that makes
you feel like you'd
like to
like to sort of act like to somehow be
involved in realizing that possibility
that you can see even if it's not sort
of absolutely clear how
um and let's take a look
um at the machine again
um
with that in mind
let's sort of step up and have a look
at what goes on
in typical consensus reality and if
there's things there that we can that we
can borrow if there's things that we can
use on our terms
to make those things um
to power that possibility so take them
to think about that whatever that thing
might be and situated in space where
does it where does it sit relative to
the world as is
right now is it something we're quite
close to something we're far away from
something that's what's well connected
to what's there or something that
represents something of a break
where are you situated compared to is it
something you're working on already is
it something you can see at a distance
but you really don't know
um
we don't begin to know um how to do
anything about it
take the name image and now let's go and
have a look um
at how things typically um work in the
world and what we see is that there are
people creating dramatic new realities
on a regular basis
and there's a mechanism
for doing that
and if you doubt this if you doubt this
reality creation
process and the power of this reality
creation machine that's been developed
over there
ponder this on your way home tonight
in your uber
and ask how a couple of people with my
some different idea for moving cars
around cities
got from zero to covering the world in
the space of about five years without
actually buying a whole lot of
vehicles themselves or if you're taking
the subway
watch everyone in their daily devotions
to one of you know five or so websites
that give them their view on reality
and ask how we went from nobody doing
that to everybody doing that in a very
short space of time
because there's magic here there's
there's some kind of global growth gun
there's some powerful replicator
mechanism that these mechanisms use and
it's readily accessible there's there's
a simple there's actually a simple
password you can use to access it which
isn't written on a post-it note but it's
written on any number of slide decks
that look alarmingly like the one that
we saw
earlier if you haven't seen the password
before i'll tell it to you you simply
say
it's uber but for blank
where blank can be anything large small
absurd doesn't matter as long as it's
ever so slightly different to something
anyone else has said before
you take that you show that to the
gatekeepers of the growth gun machine
you get given the keys
a little bit more complex than that um
you know so there's there's a few
caveats if you're now looking at your
thing and saying well well if i took
what if we somehow found a way to take
that thing and and propel it through the
global growth gun well there's a few
problems one there's a little bit more
than a password there's a biometric
system as well it's a ship biometric
system um but you have to be able to say
the password convincingly you have to be
able to say with a straight face
um and the biometric system like i say
it's a system so it's used to
hearing that from a certain kind of
person so it helps if you look
a certain way the ideal
the ideal person is the sort of
proverbial mediocre white man
um preferably wrapping the mediocrity up
in the certificate from some main brand
university but it's possible to get
around that you might be able to get the
method acting right one way or another
and utter the password convincingly
enough
but that still doesn't work
to take the thing the sort of nascent
thing that you see and bring it out into
the world in this in this large and
flourishing kind of way because
the gun only works for a certain kind of
thing you have to
um
you have to
mold it you have to bend it
um you know there's
into into something that will fit
into that system and you have to then
take the strings they're attached you
have to build it into a thing that will
one way or another
cause investment money to increase
doesn't have to necessarily make a
profit uber doesn't
but it has to somehow grow in some way
that appeals to more investors and
brings in more investment money
um and that's a massive constraint and
the thing
that you're looking at probably can't
survive that transition can't survive
being squished even if it
could the growth gun is an incredibly
crude
kind of replicator it's powerful it
scales things to global proportions you
know blitz scales them in very little
time at all
but it's a very very crude replicator
and it makes almost exact replicas
so it spreads
indistinguishable grey goo or blue goo
or whatever your corporate brand color
goo is
across the world
that requires everyone to mold
themselves to it that that requires
everyone to discover that they need this
thing rather than
adjusting itself and molding itself to
the needs of different people in
different places
different times different parts of the
world
um different backgrounds and so on
um so again
even if you could ram your thing into
the into the input port of the growth
gun
it's not going to come out
if it spreads across the world in a very
satisfying um
way because what goes into the growth
gun is is a minimum viable product
that's all that fits that's the term of
art
in that world
which is the least possible thing that
could approximate looking like a product
that's not a terrible idea in its own
right if we translate that into our own
language it's a proof of concept
but no sane person puts a proof of
concept into a global growth gun
and so it looks at first
like the global growth gun is
incompatible with sanity
but if we look at the parts of it we
look at what people are doing with some
of the parts of it outside of that
system
then there's hope there's some very
interesting things
um that we start seeing because
part of what makes that possible is a
whole bunch of technology and it's
technology it's a certain amount
um
what we essentially have
is technology that in many cases we
developed um
right the the the
global growth industry has discovered
that digital things can replicate for
free can be distributed for free it's
like the sorcerer's apprentice
discovering magic
using it to serve some banal end and
things get completely out of control
it's magic that we understood
long before it went off in that
trajectory how did we get
from information wants to be free to
that
um
you know
but the the mechanisms are still there
and we can we and we know
better than anyone you know the
possibilities there think of
early file sharing and how that cracked
open cultural transmission
um because a lot of our cultural
artifacts could be easily digitized
music and then later movies
didn't quite get where it could because
um
the system
imposed artificial scarcity through
copyright and so on because those
systems themselves you look at nap state
it registered itself as a corporation it
couldn't resist
taking that form and so there was
something to sue
um
look at
look at uber if you will there's there's
physical things there's human beings
getting into vehicles and
moving around streets and consuming
energy
all based on flows of information about
who wants to ride where when
flows of information flow um
you know mapped onto the onto the real
world have enormous
enormous sort of power and loosening and
unlocking that power has massive
potential
um if you imagine alternative
transportation systems transportation
systems that open up to more than just
one person one driver one car internal
combustion engine
if you had that same informational flow
in a more malleable way in a way that
wasn't
tied to the servers of one particular
company that has to build things to suit
its business model it's not too hard you
know it's not too hard to imagine doing
exactly that
you know in a way that required no
centralized servers no centralized
middleman removed all of the deadweight
costs of that monopolist that would be
monopolist
made things better in the immediate
short term for the for the people
providing those rides and allowed us a
little bit more freedom of space more
openness to move from that
to a transportation set of
transportation systems that makes that
makes more sense
um
so
the technology um
um the this ability these this global
nervous system that we have to transform
and shift information to translate
between the world and bits and bits back
into the world is immensely powerful
and we have
a much more
um creative generative view of the
possibilities there
but it still takes it still takes more
still takes resources of some sort it
still takes
um
you know whatever you're trying to do
you can do it in a much more
resource-like way this is one of the big
sort of insights of the startup industry
you can have you know half a dozen
people um running a startup and again
scale that up massively without
building factories or taking on
inventory or doing the things that you
traditionally needed to do you can get
very far with comparatively little
but you still need something
and most of the money most of the
resources you know tied to money in the
system that we're working with right now
and most of the money is has has strings
attached
only there's so much of it
um
and so much of it has become an
abstraction so much of it has become
information in its own right flows of
information flows of utterly money's
always been a construct but in the last
15 20 years or so with the massive
growth of financialization with the
massive printing
of funny money to keep the party going
the quantitative easing central banks
printing money the debt that enables
commercial banks printing 10 times as
much money all of this money flooding
into the flooding into the world over
the past 15 years or so that's what's
enabled
a lot of the wildness that we've seen
all of the the sort of crazy growth gun
things where you can build a global taxi
company that loses money for you know 12
years straight
and still keep the engine turning
because there's so much funny money
and needing a home
um for itself it's why we see some of
the distortions the massive distortions
that we've seen in the cryptocurrency
market because it popped its head above
ground just in time for all this funny
money to be looking for an asset class
[Laughter]
yes talk about um artificial scarcity
right um
so
um
so there's there's there's massive
amounts
of money
floating around in this
that is this is completely
disconnected from
conventional
um reality
that makes it no less real it still gets
you still get to turn that into
vehicles and hamburgers and rent
and so on and it and and it flows around
in ways
that can be quite accessible
um
i'll give i'll give you
i really don't have enough time to get
in the details here but i'll give you
one very visible public example
wall street bets
manage to hack
one of the
money flow mechanisms reasonably
effectively
you know whether as a problem
take whatever view you like on that
thing one way or another
able to shift flows through the system
using the rules of its system itself it
wasn't it was an outstanding hack
you know it was based on some
sort of understanding of mechanisms and
how they fit together and how if we can
pull on this mechanism in a certain way
there's a switch over here when you
reach a certain threshold that will
force you know hedge funds that have
taken short positions to close out those
short positions and cause flows to
happen like this it's a it's a crude
example but it gives you some
sense of how in some ways these flows
are accessible they're more directly
accessible in the cryptocurrency market
where you have huge amounts of funny
money
moved around by publicly visible
algorithm they're visible in other
markets derivatives markets and so on i
don't have time to go into this here
we'll happily
um
discuss this offline with anyone who'd
like who'd like to chat about that side
of things or any of this
[Music]
afterwards so
we have um
technological resources
um and we have potential access to
to directly
to this
giant amount of
incomprehensible amount these tens
hundreds of trillions of dollars of true
funny money detached from anything else
floating around the information networks
of our world in addition
we have
mechanisms that have developed
themselves in the system that we can
adapt they're they're some they're and
they're crude and they're not they're
imperfect
but things around things like
crowdfunding kickstarter patreon
um
and so there are people supporting
themselves
in the system that is with with that
with with money that pays their rent and
feeds them
doing cool projects and making and and
making youtube videos around them it's a
horribly inefficient mechanism
they have to skew what they do to
whatever the youtube algorithm
wants
or whatever the youtube algorithm
decides to advertise advertisers want so
advertisers pay youtube for eyeballs
that the algorithm supposedly delivers
to them this video delivers
convinces the algorithm that's going to
deliver it enough of the right sort of
eyeballs for the algor for the
algorithms and the advertisers and
eventually through all of this highly
inefficient mechanism popular enough
people doing interesting things with
enough of a support base of viewers
get to do their things and are supported
somehow by this by this pool of money
if you look at all of those
inefficiencies and imagine
smoothing out those inefficiencies and
removing some of those inefficiencies
and creating more direct mechanisms
again it's not hard to imagine
you know more people being able to
support themselves
doing things that are valued by
some group of group of others around
them um even within the sort of
mechanisms that we're
um that we're used to
um
right now so there's um
there's a great possibility there and
there's there's thank you greater and
greater
um possibility out here in in
there's lots of things starting to
happen in extended reality there's lots
of there's lots of
movement and lots of um activity
taking that view of let's tap into the
the the power that's there let's tap
into the resources that are there let's
do it oh well let's link to that
and let's start creating mechanisms that
open up possibility space
that reduce the need for those resources
that use this power this technological
power
um this this
these things that we understand
um in more efficient ways in ways that
are more that aren't skewed to a
particular business model or something
and where the the logic
of the old machine system doesn't have
to apply this doesn't have to yes we
would like it to be sustainable yes we
would like it to to spread its influence
in a positive way as as far as possible
and and have some positive influence in
as many lives as possible
but it and we wanted to be sustainable
we wanted to grow in some other sense of
the word growth
wanted to flourish
but
we don't have to
bake in this resource accumulation this
this investment increasing this business
model
into the thing we can we can find um we
can very effectively because
these things are so cheap and simple and
light on their feet to get going and to
get
moving if there's enough people energy
around them
um there's a whole set
of new possibilities so um and
unfortunately
the wondrous technology that we have
um
seems to have failed us in this
particular moment so i'm missing a whole
lot of
visuals and visualizations that perhaps
would have made
some of this
even more
visual and apparent um to you i've
covered
a lot of fairly
high level ground here we do actually
have
um a few minutes left for questions i um
[Music]
um so i'm happy to
um if there are thoughts in your head
that this is
um
sparked off i'm happy to start
some sort of discussion right here right
now very happy to
talk to people afterwards a lot of this
has necessarily been very handy because
it covers a fair amount of ground
there's a lot of
substance and possibility behind this
i'm really trying to sketch out the
territory
if any of you sort of come away with
this with sort of energy to to explore
this territory to do something in this
territory to see
about
shifting what you're doing into a
position that's more comfortable for you
and ultimately more
valuable for
society um
we're going to be um organizing a sort
of ad hoc workshop to discuss these
things and get together
um and look practically at some of these
questions and put people together and so
on if that's of interest to you
catch one of us
after this we don't have a final
place and time for this but if you give
us your contact details
we'll we'll
get back to you with that and we'd love
to actually sit down and have a more
um
specific productive
session
um taking some of these very broad
wide-open possibilities um and looking
at practical ways forward with them
because there are many um so that's a
brief overview if anyone has any um
um short um questions challenges
anything else you'd like to bring up now
um that would be great otherwise um
catch us afterwards and we'll figure out
a time in place for us all to get
together and talk about this in some
more specific depth
[Applause]
all right oh cool all right so i
appreciate many of the abstract uh
many of the abstract examples you were
giving uh i was wondering are there any
particular
additional authors or works that you'd
recommend looking into to
for one to better
um
wrap one's mind around your material
wow okay that's that's um
um
so yes there are there are there are
definite um i'm not sure i can stand up
here um and give you a short list this
minute but i will be delighted to
um tap three um send some out um i'll
tell you what and i think um
um
i think
you want to see these talks are very
happy you've got some hope talks that
that loosely connect to this in some
interesting ways certainly
um
corey doctrine talking about
interoperability um he tends to talk
about that in a specific um internet
context but idea of interoperability
though of adversarial interoperability
of taking something that doesn't want to
let you in a certain way and pulling
something out of it anyway is hugely
hugely powerful if you go to that talk
and and have him explain as he
inimitably does
um what he's seeing in that space and
just imagine
take that thought and pull it out beyond
the sort of internet context more
broadly um that would be a wonderful
thing i think that's i think that's
happening tomorrow um the
uh four thieves vinegar collective
um spoke i think this morning so it's
wonderful that talk but if
you were at that or not but it's a very
very specific thing they're doing
there's this tiny um collective doing
really interesting things
um about taking one of the most physical
things
out there um drug delivery
and finding ways to distribute it
finding ways to make as much of it as
possible digital
um
um using
ai effectively fairly old school but
incredibly powerful ai to take
drugs that are exceedingly hard to get
hold of because the law gets in the way
patents get in the way outrageous prices
get in the way find ways to develop
synthesis mechanisms
that allow you
to make these at home with ingredients
you can get from a school science supply
store in a little bio reactor in a jam
jar with a few sensors and a basic
microcontroller in a safe and repeatable
way
um
that it's it's a very specific example i
think it's an absolutely lovely example
of some of the things
that we're talking about here where we
have these incredibly powerful
technologies that can take so much of
this process and make them digital
and use these things to collaboratively
with these machines that can search
millions of science papers and figure
out how to ask answer questions that
nobody's asking about how could we make
this safely at home
we can do this as effectively as the big
pharma companies do to optimize their
processes and open this up
um to everybody so just off the top of
my head like two hope talks that really
kind of resonate with that um
that comes to mind in terms of books
something that's like totally
philosophical
um
but um
resonates with a lot of this um this
talk um finite and infinite games
by james cass
c-a-r-s-e it's a really short book it's
a really quick read um
and um
it's got nothing directly to do with
with technology or the specifics or the
finance world or anything like that
but in terms of the mindset around that
um you could do a lot worse than than
than sit with that book for for a few
hours and see what it does for you
excellent thank you very much and i'm
happy to talk some more afterwards
appreciate it
and i think that's it
thank you very much
[Applause]
[Music]
do