thank you
foreign
all right everyone welcome to the next
talk yeah in our track three I just
couple lines of business before we go
into the Talk itself a couple reminders
uh it's really important we ask you to
please continue to wear your mask when
you're indoors if you need to take them
off step outside Master off our fine
outside but as long as you're indoors we
really appreciate it helps us keep
consistent with our our policy and our
code of conduct please try to stay
hydrated we don't want anybody to not be
able to enjoy the rest of the conference
or any other talks or the sessions of
the tracks so take care of yourself uh
please mute your phone while you're in
the session the audio equipment is very
sensitive and so it picks up any type of
beeps or Bings or whatever noise your
phone makes we have a fourth unscheduled
track for talks it is open to anybody
who would like to give some sort of
presentation or talk it's in the coffee
shop or in the coffee room you go to the
info desk to sign up just tell them what
you want to talk about they'll help you
find a slot and you can go give your
your talk
it's entirely self-service so you need
to bring your own laptop and plug it in
we don't have any equipment to help you
with that hacker karaoke is tonight at
10 pm and track one so it'll be upstairs
in DAC 416 on the fourth floor
please come if you can it should be a
lot of fun I won't be singing thankfully
but lots of people who can sing well
will be there will be some judges there
who judge it is a competition
and lastly volunteers are welcome
there's lots of volunteer opportunities
for the rest of the conference so please
if you're interested stop in room 301 or
go to the information desk and let them
know what you would like to do to
volunteer
so the talk right now is botnets are the
best way to measure user hostile
behavior on the internet with David
seedy so with that I'll pass it off to
David thank you
thank you very much
someone talk working at NSA once gently
informed Bruce schneier that worrying
about automated surveillance was silly
it's like worrying about your dog seeing
you naked
in many ways that comparison is wrong
you can't communicate with your dog
can't communicate with others and it
can't make decisions based on what it
sees they'll have a long-term impact on
your life for example
but one way it's not wrong is that as we
all know on the internet nobody knows
you're a dog or part of an automated
surveillance botnet of user hostile
behavior on the web
that means you can catch a service with
its pants down
and this can be a good thing for
everyone
so Sheldon Whitehouse uh is a senator
and he was wrong when he said there's no
good use for a botnet
I'm going to talk about botnets for
measurement of bad behavior on the web
as one example of beneficial botnets but
first I want to talk about some other
good uses
the general idea of coordinating use of
volunteers home systems to do beneficial
things isn't new the big example is that
botnets have been used for distributed
computing tasks
uh the first project of this sort that I
personally became familiar with was
folding at home which today has more
than 73 000 active nodes and focuses on
discovering treatments for a broad range
of diseases by simulating protein
folding
this was way back when I was on my
Packard Bell and my 14-4 modem
but the real First Volunteer distributed
computing project actually proceeded
folding at home it was distributed.net
in 1997.
and I have links there uh if you're
interested in the history it's actually
very interesting to read
uh so one volunteer Computing project on
distributed.net aimed to break uh
reduced round rc5 encryption and there's
a team of Hackers from Loft that
participated
similarly covet at home was a folding at
home project
and the root folds team which was
started by people from root owns gave a
talk at Hope 2020.
if you happen to see it if you didn't go
back and watch that uh
that talk
so Hacker's been involved in this stuff
from the beginning and continued to be
and I think it's not hard to see why uh
David P Anderson is the guy behind boink
which is an infrastructure used by
several distributed volunteer Computing
projects of this kind including the very
early um seti at home
so he's not a hacker as far as I know
but he voiced a very kind of hackery
idea
he said my world view is deeply
anti-establishment I root for the
underdog so the idea of volunteer
Computing which shifts power away from
corporations and the academic
establishment and puts it in the hands
of the people resonated strongly with me
he also went on to say
I have problems with authority figures
so to me privacy and hacking is tied to
this mentality groups of people
coordinating to use technology to
empower themselves directly without
dependence on others
boink is also interesting because it's
not just a particular project a
distributed computing project but it
provides a platform and an
infrastructure for developing new
projects
efficiently
and that's what I think we need for
measurement botnets too
so these distributed computing projects
are definitely examples of beneficial
botnets
but from the beginnings and through to
today most of them have been focused on
basic science rather than on
uh sort of an applied measurement of the
web
there are exceptions to that surveil at
home it's one used boink for web
measurement but it hasn't been active
since 2011.
I think but I'm interested to hear if
you know something else about that
and there may be a few other examples
that I've missed but for the most part
they're not used for measurement
but there are projects doing distributed
volunteer web measurements
some sites attack uh the privacy of
their visitors and I'll call that
um user hostile behavior on the web for
short
one use of web measurement is to record
user hostile behavior and so I want to
talk about a particular case of that
dark patterns
so dark patterns are a kind of
um user interface design pattern
in general user interface design
patterns arise from common problems or
use cases that designers have to handle
for example a customer needs to keep
track of their purchases and then
provide payment and shipping information
or a reader needs to find contact
information on a website
so what are the problems or the common
problems that give rise to dark design
patterns and what are the approaches to
solving them
so the problems solved by dark patterns
first of all belong to the service
provider and not to you the customer
visitor or other user of the service in
fact your behavior is what is treated as
a user interface design problem
addressed by dark by dark patterns
the problems designers are trying to fix
are things like stopping a visitor from
declining to receive promotional emails
while conveying to those who never tried
to decline that they have some choice in
the matter
or stopping a customer from canceling a
service um so this example is from
Project Iliad a project by Amazon to
make cancellation difficult with dark
patterns that was revealed in a leak
this year
so just to here's what it looked like to
try to cancel
with Amazon at the time
uh
go to the website click the hamburger or
the menu button
scroll down to find the Prime Membership
option
click manage membership
you then given some options in Gray you
click the lower one which says end
membership
seems legit so far
but then you're presented with a screen
you have to scroll down through and read
about the exclusive benefits you will
lose and look at a warning symbol
those include Prime free delivery Prime
video there's several things you have to
scroll through it's a pretty lengthy
scroll and then you get to a sort of
stack of buttons and you have to pick
not the blue one on top which says use
your benefits but the central orange one
which says cancel my benefits
uh after you click on that uh you have
to scroll again and read about how
you'll save money by switching to annual
payments
keep scrolling to learn about how
canceling you won't be eligible for
unclaimed offers
then you'll get to another stack of uh
buttons and once again uh
you might think you could click one of
those to to cancel but in fact nope none
of those lets you cancel your
subscription you have to continue to
scroll
and then at the very bottom of that
resulting stack there is a uh an option
to try to cancel
uh it says end now
and if you click that it will tell you
that your subscription will be canceled
in a month or so
so this came from the Norwegian
um data protection authority uh it's on
YouTube I gave the Nvidia slink there if
you're interested to watch it it's kind
of good to watch
um
moving
so firstly it would be absurd let me go
back it would be absurd to contact
Amazon even if there were some means to
do that without just flapping your wings
hard enough on Twitter to shift the
zeitgeist
it'd be absurd to reach out and complain
about the inability to cancel using
their site
the problem is not that Amazon's
designers messed up and they're unaware
of the effects of this cancellation
process for visitors
the design of that process is not an
accident on the contrary it's often the
result of very careful a b testing
against huge samples drawn from the
services users
so to understand dark patterns like
these you have to understand that people
hate them
but that it doesn't matter that doesn't
matter to the people who use them
so people do hate dark patterns you can
see there are many name and shame sites
where users take time out of their day
to complain in great numbers
here's uh at our design
uh there's also a tip line uh called
Futurity type tip line where people can
just complain there's a dark
patterns.games which focuses more on
addictive sorts of patterns there's a
dark patterns hashtag get all Mastodon
they're all vigorously stocked and on an
ongoing basis with comments from
exasperated users
so that's how the term dark patterns
caught on from this sort of scattered
reports from frustrated users wanting to
name and shame services with a
particular kind of user interface design
and that happened for long enough that
abstractions started to become invisible
a similar kind of UI solution to these
recurring problems that Services were
having with users and we're
um
fixing with UI
so dark patterns emerged in plain sight
from user dissatisfaction it's not
something that was revealed by research
work about recondite practices that had
to be uncovered these are flagrant
they're insulting their contemptuous of
the user in that they don't even really
bother to hide
at the same time the web is a big place
visitors are busy and mostly won't
report even openly hostile user
interfaces and the variety and
implementations of dark patterns
is large and there's they're evolving
so something more systematic is needed
to maintain an updated empirical
understanding of dark pattern use
and that friends is where web
measurement comes in
so dark patterns is a kind of nice
example for discussing measurement
because they're hard to model and so are
hard to automatically measure with a
kind of a trained classifier approach
but they also exist on the web in a
zillion different places which makes
them hard to measure just manually
you need sort of components of both okay
so let's talk about the two common
approaches to web measurement and why I
think neither of them is as good as
botnets
one approach is bot farming and that's
to kind of create and manage a fleet of
automated browsers that you host
yourself like a bunch of uh vps's or
servers in a university lab and that
have some sort of instrumentation on the
browser that supports measurement
the other approach is I'll call
piggybacking which is to convince a
large number of users to allow their own
browsers to be instrumented so that's
like using a special browser extension
so that the sites that they visit can be
measured
okay so let's start with Farming Farming
so creating a fleet of bespoke automated
browser Bots reproduces a lot of effort
lots of studies share require of of the
web share requirements uh including
things like invoking a specifiable
number of bots or recording the requests
and responses as a bot interacts
supporting keyword searches
it makes little sense to re-implement
these features every time a new web
measurement study is conducted
unfortunately in practice adopting some
existing web measurement project doesn't
help much because a large amount of the
existing code in this area is
unmaintained or it's difficult to
understand or modify or doesn't build
without special knowledge particularly
for people who are trained not to
produce such things but to kind of
design experiments and analyze data or
to understand privacy uh you know legal
enforcement to do with privacy
bot farming also requires a farm the
infrastructure for running the Bots and
that can be expensive in terms of coin
and time putting pressure on long-term
projects long-running ones like you
might use for monitoring so for example
for an academic there's little incentive
to maintain the necessary infrastructure
for a measurement study once the article
that it's sort of directed towards has
been published
so the benefits of a one-off kind of Bot
Farm project are usually pretty limited
for a regulator like the FTC Federal
Trade Commission in the United States
who might want who enforces privacy laws
at the federal level
and who might want to monitor the web
over time
re-running the study repeatedly to sweep
for new developments
another reason bot Services aren't ideal
for web measurements is that a bot's
behavior at a website has to be
automated in contrast to piggybacking
which we'll see in a moment and that
kind of artificial Behavior can be
detected leading sites to alter their
behavior so that's a kind of demand
characteristic if you want in the study
the thing being measured is uh is
changing based on its understanding of
being measured
and that that's a challenge to external
validity and web measurement studies
finally whereas economically and
administratively sharing resources among
the bots in a farm kind of makes sense
if you point diversity improves
measurement quality but achieving good
diversity is hard with centrally
controlled infrastructure right you have
to sort of
try to get
your hands on
resources that are spread around diverse
uh
in diverse places on the network for
whatever that means in for in your
context
so this is something for example that
studies of censorship are are very
interested in right diverse Vantage
points very crucial to understanding how
censorship really works
um okay
so how about piggybacking that's the
other approach I mentioned it's
convincing users to run some
instrumentation uh in an extension for a
measurement study on their on their own
browsers so that comes with its own
problems
um a nice example of it uh is AD
Observer
um which is an NYU project it uses an
extension to measure targeted political
ads from Facebook and Google it grew out
of AD Observatory and uh at one point a
few years ago Facebook sent a I think it
was actually before the 2020
election I want to say
um Facebook sent a threatening letter to
ad Observatory which was a predecessor
project and suspended accounts that they
detected to be using the tool
uh and I wondered if that might have
something to do with ghost owl which is
a Facebook team discussed in an article
uh by John Payne in 2600 a while back uh
and uh ghost owl apparently works to
circumvent privacy tools for Facebook
um
and to me you know it's interesting to
reflect on how these companies have
formalized a practice for circumventing
users attempt to protect their privacy
with these teams things like like ghost
owl maybe it's not called that anymore
this is a few years ago I think the
article was a little older but not that
old
um and also with projects like project
Iliad which we saw before from Amazon
so if you know more about those uh
please do reach out I'm interested to
learn more
um
okay
but maybe the most obvious problem with
piggybacking is that instrumentation is
a burden on the user's browsing it slows
it down and it adds to personal privacy
risk for them right so they're
participating in a study which is maybe
measuring privacy practices or dark
patterns or something else that's user
hostile on the web so they're
contributing to our Collective uh
privacy but they're also
enduring some personal privacy risk for
running this thing on their own browser
the example I always think of is there
was a something called the security
Behavior Observatory run by Carnegie
Mellon CMU that collected data related
to privacy and security behaviors in
from participant systems so they were
interested in usability questions in
particular
and uh sometimes this meant you know
collecting in particular for uh
sensitive content you know something
that they've uh gathered in incognito
mode to try to understand how people
used private browsing or incognito mode
so obviously that work is very important
the studies were valuable additions to
our understanding of privacy and
usability but it's also clear that the
Privacy threat there's a privacy threat
for participants and that's in those
kinds of studies
another problem is that piggybacking
measurements are taken on sites that the
user happens to visit so as a crawl
strategy whatever happens to be visited
is sometimes desirable but sometimes not
so particularly for studies with only a
small number of participants it doesn't
work very well
um and with piggybacking there's no no
real choice in the matter
foreign
our experience of dark patterns as overt
when we encounter them I just want to
point out that they rely on these kind
of subtle features of human psychology
how to word a warning that's presented
to you when you try to take an action
that the server doesn't want you to take
at what length a path of links is likely
to wear people down enough to give up
canceling their Amazon subscription
how many or how much scrolling they have
to do
um how to make clear that a decision
will result in a future bother forever
right yeah but maybe later button
instead of a there's a yes and a maybe
later
which is left open
how to color the accept and decline
buttons in a dialogue asking for consent
to share your information so that
declining is less likely
so the prevalence of dark patterns on
the web and their use of psycho
psychology like this that's difficult to
model means that to measure them or
especially to monitor them over time you
need to combine automation with uh
manual human judgment
you need a measurement botnet
so in a measurement botnet the Bots
performing measurements are hosted on a
volunteers let's say home machine
volunteers install a client that manages
their bot the client is responsible for
pulling down new studies running them
and returning results
in our implementation which is called
mbotnet we built the client UI with
Argos which parses the output of shell
scripts and generates a kind of simple
panel drop down menu in Gnome
um there's a related project called X
bar that uses the same
um
syntax to generate
um drop downs in the menu bar Darwin
from Mac OS so you get that kind of for
free by using either one of the two
they're both great projects they're sort
of like a zenity on steroids if you've
ever used zenity
we try to isolate in our implementation
the client from the host system and to
wait until system resources become
available to run these are lessons
learned a long time ago from distributed
computing projects
um we also try to claim only a fraction
of available resources on the system
while it's when when the client is
running
so for the right mix of uh
broad availability and kind of a you
know possibility of installation and
security we implemented the client-side
isolation on Linux with systemd
sandboxing
um we're building for Linux and Mac OS
first but I just want to say I also love
BSD I would love to expand if I can find
any help
um so I'm happy to get into the details
of what we did for isolation if you're
interested
um but to summarize uh we used kind of
straightforward set comp filtering we
restricted capabilities uh use
namespaces and then to manage client
resources we use c groups
with Mac OS we basically don't know how
it's going to go yet
I initially thought since it was BSD
based I could use jails but I think Mac
OS doesn't doesn't do jails
interested to know more if you have a
view on that though
okay
um
so when the client is running the user
volunteer can schedule ride-alongs to
see what the bot is doing this is sort
of a not that interesting as a picture
it's just a selenium instance running
but it was run uh by clicking in that
drop down menu schedule a ride along and
the next site that was visited by the
bot uh was shown to the user
and this is also the functionality that
allows us to ask the user for manual
judgments
so I'll get back to that in a second
the automated browser code we use is a
fork of open wpm which has been used for
some great bot Farm style projects
like the web census and actually for a
study uh kind of one-off study but a
really interesting one on dark patterns
uh it's developed by the people at citp
and still actively maintained and it has
some great instrumentation that's
implemented and we're happy hoping to
expand on it and kind of share backup
stream
um the client connects to the server to
get more studies whenever it has extra
capacity rather than allowing
connections to come in from the server
and we did that because it's easy it
doesn't require opening up ports and it
reuses functionality we need any way to
administer the server
a lot of this is uh
beating a a direct path to what we
wanted
um and it's sort of up in the air still
we're looking at design decisions but we
wanted to have something we could work
with and use to understand the issues as
well
uh you know sort of running
uh so once the study is complete uh it's
compressed uh the results are compressed
and signed and returned to the server
subject to disquota and it's made
accessible through a researcher portal
researcher portal just allows
researchers to apply uh to register and
to specify studies so I said apply to
register I don't we're not going to
allow anyone to register to run studies
on this uh at least
we don't think we will uh the how we're
going to do vetting though is still open
so we're interested to think more we're
sort of thinking about that
um right now
um
study designs include a variety of
options including things like whether to
anonymize you can you can access you can
have the bot uh work over tour
um whether to try to resist bot
detection
um and then some more detailed
configuration parameters for the browser
done through user.js
um and again we hope to expand on these
if you have ideas about things that
would be
um interesting like to know
um one important option is whether to
include in the study manual judgments to
measure something because that helps us
to sidestep the problem of modeling
phenomena that are difficult to measure
automatically
so for example the researcher can
schedule a manual judgment about the
wording used on a button to sign up for
a subscription and it might be a
question of whether this is high
pressure shaming of the user
um
it says yes send me the meal plan in a
big green button or uh
I can actually no thanks I don't like
delicious food in Gray underneath it
very faintly with low contrast
so is that shaming the user or maybe is
it too high pressure for a particular
group of users maybe the elderly or
someone who's buying something to get
help with a problem they're ashamed of
or something else
or is it just being funny right it's the
contrast difference between these two
elements too great for people with
visual impairments of different kinds so
on yeah
so right now we've implemented just a
placeholder version of this option which
props up a window to ask a question for
each page visited that matches a regex
right
so more complex filters are possible to
trigger manual judgment but we wanted
them to be driven by actual things that
the researchers want
okay so getting manual judgment like
this is building on the idea from the
history of distributed computing uh
called
um distributed thinking and that
involves the use of volunteers on the
internet to perform tasks that use human
cognition knowledge or intelligence
um over the years there have been
so this is actually from basa which is a
boink project not much has come out of
it but the idea is certainly present and
articulated and has been implemented in
this really cool way
um so over the years there have been
many projects that have uh done sort of
manual judgment with Bots for like
one-off studies and again what we're
doing is is not a standalone study but a
platform for running new ones
um so an example of one of these
one-offs is dimes that was a project
taking measurements to try to understand
the topology of the internet
um who's connected to whom where
how things are functioning uh it ran
around the turn of the century I believe
it was an Israeli project but they had
participants from all around the world
that's what this uh pie chart is showing
um yeah the large segment of Israeli
participants makes me wonder since it's
a small country
um and so you had these kind of
lightweight
um
uh Services running on clients and then
after they ran you could get uh one of
the kind of cool things you got to see
was your perspective on the network so
that's what's shown I guess it's figure
two here
um yeah in 2004 there were 800 agents in
50 countries for dimes
and here's a few more projects
um using botnets that might be of some
interest
um I I just list them uh due to time
constraints but they're all definitely
worth a look
um
citizen browser in particular is uh work
by the folks at the markup who also made
this shirt incidentally uh beginning in
um it's a platform for studies on
Facebook in particular uh uses the the
user's own credentials to log in and
then to capture information about how
Facebook interacts with with their
account
so that uh one of the things I think is
interesting about that project in
particular is the approach to redaction
because a lot of what they record is
specific to the account and you know in
order to collect it they want to to
minimize uh the Privacy risk
and so they have this kind of automated
redaction process
um
it's worth a look
they did also have a security audit back
when it was first introduced
um and it uses NG fetch which is a I
guess a proprietary automation Tool uh
from Neato graph but I don't know much
about that so uh if you do reach out we
can try to learn from it I think it it
seems that citizen
um browser has produced several really
interesting uh measurement studies
so it's probably a decent amount to
learn from what they've gone through
uh also Brave redirection tracking so
that's from 2018 it was a study again
one-off measuring prevalence of
redirection tracking so whether website
or maybe a third party automatically
redirects the browser to another domain
so if it's a third party what they're
doing is embedding uh frames and then
they kick off a kind of redirection
chain to persist data and the first
party case it's just the top level frame
that does the redirection
um censored Planet as another
relatively early censorship project
there are actually many uh of these not
uh not all it's not that common for them
to be
botnet
um
sort of design
so an earlier iteration of this talk
involved much more discussion of
censorship circumvention projects and
things that had um developed that were
peer-to-peer in one way or another like
peekabooty or a six four
um
and some of their successors
um but really there's a connection there
between the the architecture and and
what I'm talking about but it's not
super direct uh so it's
you know it's it's interesting I think I
think especially for questions like
isolation of the client
um it raises some interesting questions
but
um
you know it's not the same
and then surveil at home after I've
already mentioned
um was a boink project which was uh
design
so that's kind of the simple broad
picture of measurement botnets which
support
um a broad range of Empirical research
questions on the web not available to
bot farms and piggybacking approaches it
incl and includes questions about
phenomena that are
resistant to automatic detection and
questions that require ongoing
um
monitoring over like a large number of
sites something like an enforcement
agency like the FTC might be interested
to do
um so I just want I'm happy to take
questions about the details of our
implementation if there's interest and
of course also after the talk especially
um we've got a mailing list to talk
about uh some of the stuff whether it's
our project in particular or more
generally if you're doing related work
um but you know of course we like to
talk about the design of our project as
well
uh so that's the um the web uh the email
address
um and if you're you're interested in
contributing we've got projects going
looking at client isolation client
scheduling uh bot detection
circumvention also just packaging you
know we're
it's important that the installation be
relatively painless and that the system
be
the client be usable so also interface
design
um and then you know sort of on a less
technical uh note the design of
incentives we have fake Internet points
involved in this uh in this design but
you know how to how to do them how to
incorporate teams effectively especially
I mean I think that's a a big driving
um Force I think there have been
interesting insights from uh other
projects about the failures of external
motivating factors for participation so
paying people tends not to work well
it's kind of an interesting history with
boink in that
um so if you're kind of more economics
minded that that's something we'd like
to talk about
um and then also from people with ideas
for specific measurement studies so
we'll work with you to develop features
you want so long as they're likely
they're likely to benefit others
um as well okay so just to close whoops
uh that's actually not something I'm
gonna well we can talk about it if you
want to but not officially
um Sheldon White House is wrong botnets
can be beneficial and shouldn't be
blocked indiscriminately using bad
botnets as a pretext
uh from the early 90s at home projects
and related distributed computing
projects to today we've got we've had
volunteers banding together to
coordinate the use of private resources
in the public interest including teams
of hackers who were present from the
very beginning
so there's a like I said there's still a
rich ecosystem of measurement studies
that are more or less one-off
particularly for social media but also
for censorship and for a variety of
different kinds of practices on the web
so hope I've convinced you my view is
botnet so the best way to study user
hostile web practices empirically on the
web
all right thanks I'll pop on uh all
right so we have the opportunity if
anyone live audience wants to ask
questions there's an open mic right
there or if you feel uncomfortable with
the open mic just shout it out and I can
repeat it for David he can't actually
hear you directly he can only hear us
through the mic
there are a couple of questions in The
Matrix chat so the first one is for Mac
with running the Linux version of the
bot in a Docker container be both
functional and sufficiently isolated
yes thank you for this question uh sorry
if there's a little delay will I get
Matrix up
it's a little bit heavy with eight uh
one second okay
um
yes so uh Docker right uh yeah we're
doing a lot of things that Docker does
to achieve isolation
um
our feeling is that Docker is
introducing a kind of general purpose
thing that our users might not need
remember this is kind of a
volunteer-based thing it's really you
know adoption is really
essential just like anonymity you know
measurement
um measurement loves company
uh and so we
sort of felt like there wasn't much to
be gained by working with
um with docker
um
that's that's the short answer but
yeah we could we could talk more
um
it's also a nice approach to you know
interoperability making it work on
different platforms so there's a
trade-off there for sure
um
but for now we thought um better to do
it this way
all right next question from the chat
room are there safeguards to keep say
Amazon employees running the bot and
saying nah that's a perfectly reasonable
design pattern that would skew the
results
right yes so this is a great question
because uh so this always reminds me uh
Dave Clark who was one of the early
architects of the internet
complains forgetting I think in his book
designing an Internet that people always
come to him and say that the early
Architects didn't think about security
and he says it's not really right
actually we just had this really limited
conception of what security meant and we
didn't really consider the idea that you
know we were really concerned with two
trusting parties communicating and then
there's some uh Eve or Mallory in
between who's you know messing things up
but we didn't consider the possibility
enough of uh kind of one of the two
communicants you know being
untrustworthy you know you've got a man
at the end attack you've got a denial of
service attack you've got sybils you've
got right
um so um that's something we um
are thinking about we do uh have a and
this actually comes up in the earlier
history of distributed computing as well
where you want to have some policy for
um re-measuring the same uh site so that
you have some notion of inter-annotator
agreement
and you know it's it's possible to
overwhelm those things
um
but uh difficult and maybe detectable uh
so our current idea basically is to
um incorporate re-measurement
re-measurement of of the same thing to
prevent kind of poisoning like that
yeah there's the yeah there was a funny
uh
if the history of hacking there's kind
of interesting case of this where the
time top 100 most influential people
poll was attacked by Anonymous uh to
make it say well this was the the slide
I almost went to marble cake uh also the
game I think is sort of an acrostic down
the name the first letter of all the
names in the top 100
and at one point uh time introduced a
captcha
because uh it was you know they were
just stuffing the pole uh automatically
Anonymous uh you know participants in
the Opera and uh
so one of the first response that made
to that was to try to poison to make it
more effective more efficient by
poisoning the capture results so
the idea is that at that time capture
was showing two different
um sort of unclear words one of which
the answer was known what the word said
and the other one was an unknown thing
that OCR failed on and so the approach
of this group was to say penis for every
unknown word just penis penis penis you
know and then that would become one of
the known words and it would become more
uh automatable to defeat the system
um unfortunately it didn't work capture
is too big and there wasn't enough you
know capacity to do it but it's kind of
a fun since we're talking about
poisoning That's a fun and and actually
even further
um the subsequent approach by Anonymous
was uh was to Autumn to do a sort of
botnet style thing where they automated
the manual solution of um
of captchas
um and thought carefully about the
incentive structure including things
like uh like a link to viewporn while
you're solving captchas one after the
other
I think I have let's see I have a slide
actually that might be
Germaine to that
so yeah here's marble cake or the game
it's funny that this came up actually I
didn't think it was gonna
uh that was the top the top 100 and moot
was the number one
person and uh
yeah these are the different front ends
they made
um
this is the one I think that shows the
porn link there it is at the top so
anyway sorry
go off a little bit
all right are there any questions from
here in the audience the live audience
no none well I have one um do you face
any legal or regulatory issues or
concerns that you run into in trying to
promote or propagate this
oh yeah that's so great yeah wow this is
yeah
um right so
um yes one of the concerns involves the
Computer Fraud and Abuse Act
um so is it exceeding authorized access
to have an automated bot uh Circ you
know overcoming barriers that have been
put in place by the service provider to
keep out Bots uh well it's it's not
clear cfaa obviously is a dumpster fire
but at least Van Buren was a recent
decision that uh went the right way in
terms of uh protecting the ability to
use Bots
um
I interacted with a legal clinic at my
what was my home institution I've since
left but um and I asked them this
question and they were very
um
sort of a gun shy I guess would be the
word because the CFA has been
interpreted so broadly
um and there was questions about you
know tortious interference with another
company by by doing this kind of
measurement
um I think
there's so there's big picture questions
like that about how the law will be
applied there's also like narrow ones
like if your rate limiting isn't very
good uh if you design this thing poorly
and then like lots of people suddenly
start banging on uh some sites and they
and they go down and you effectively
DDOS them
um
you're definitely going to get into some
legal problems
um but I think you know one of the
lessons from the kind of private world
of scraping is that thinking carefully
about how to do that scheduling to
prevent you know rate limiting to
prevent
um you know resource exhaustion is uh is
important and is doable I mean these
it's being done I think pretty well so
yeah all right we have another question
from the chat do websites generally list
to users participation in a monitoring
botnet is a violation of their terms of
service
right yeah um so
I don't know you know generally I don't
read terms of service and I'm not a
person with nothing to do in my life
enjoys Agony
um but sorry no that's not fair I'm not
a lawyer I'm a lawyers read it maybe but
um uh but um
I guess there's a question about whether
uh
first of all whether something like cfaa
can be applied based on violating a
contract like a terms of service
um I think is more or less settled that
it can't you can't just put in your
terms of service you're not allowed to
come here uh and and then start you know
criminal prosecution
uh
but um
yeah I'm not sure how much
um
how that'll develop I know for example
on the high Q case which is another
legal case of Interest here
um I believe LinkedIn sent a letter
explicitly saying we do not want you
doing this
and there was a further legal question
about once you have that letter
sort of then does it more is there
different different issues that arise
um so I think it's a there's a kind of
Thicket of things and it's going to be I
mean one of the things one of the
reasons I think measurement botnets are
a nice approach is that at least for the
technical uh measures that are
um uh deployed to try to prevent Bots
um botnets are great right because you
can you have a human volunteer there
who's willing to explicitly say I uh
endorse this bot acting on my behalf
going to the site and doing its thing
right to sort of ask someone who comes
to a commercial site to have a real
intention of purchasing and not to do
anything that's not directly related to
that is seems like it's starting to
infringe on some other important issues
so
uh
right so so there'll probably be a
combination I think of things like terms
of service
um legal action maybe trying to make an
example of people and then
um
uh technical approaches as well but both
of them I think are
well handled by a kind of Community
Driven platform for for producing uh
botnet measurements
measurement studies
and are there any other implications for
doing this internationally or is this
something that is more protected
domestically
yeah I well I um
one application that we've been
exploring is tied to disinformation so
this is a project called the called idmo
the Italian digital media Observatory I
think is the acronym and
um we are interacting with them and
talking about whether we could use
something like a measurement botnet
to gain some insight onto into
disinformation campaigns
that's another area that are that's
difficult to automate it's rapidly
changing different people see different
things Viewpoint diversity is really
important
um so there's there's maybe some
potential but um
at this point yeah we're kind of more
focusing on making this thing well I I
guess I don't want to say that I mean in
some sense we're we're trying to be
responsive to the people who come to us
with ideas about how to do measurement
studies
and then produce the features that'll
you know be beneficial across other
studies as well
um so that that implies some yeah so
there's been some connections to
International Studies with idmo
um but other than that nothing specific
or any more questions
uh looks like we don't have any more
questions so thank you so much for your
presentation David it was uh very
interesting enlightening and if you have
any other information or links to
references everyone can view them inside
the Matrix chat for this this talk so
you can share them there and everyone
can continue to interact with David
after the talk if you want to learn more
or converse with them more so again
thank you so much David and thank you
audience for participating
thank you very much
stick around for the next talk in well
15 minutes 20 minutes which is going to
be on creating a general purpose
Wireless net through Network mesh