yep
welcome again to the final afternoon of
hope
for attendees that are here
keep in mind at six o'clock we do have
our closing ceremonies overflow is going
to be in room 206 and not the little
theater
room 206 will be where we have overflow
please come and join us whether you're
in the main room or in the overflow room
and now on to our next talk
whether we're talking about commercial
products like audit
sorry
allergies
non-profit projects like librivox or
community project or projects for the
community such as reading talking books
such as reading for the blind audio
audiobook production is nowhere near as
straightforward as it might seem
to tell us more about what happens
behind the scenes and how
how it gets how it gets done
a good friend neo
thank you thank you all
and uh i just before we begin uh there
was a talk i think was here yesterday um
one of the rooms where we were talking
about the history of hotel pennsylvania
we omitted something rather important we
forgot to thank the staff of hotel
pennsylvania for hosting us and putting
up with us for all those years
so corrections out of the gate
all right so
thank you for showing up
what we're talking about is writing for
the ear and now writing typically means
ink pen typewriter print paper it's a
visual medium
when we're writing for the ear we are
transmuting
print
into audio
so the scope of the talk covers a lot of
things you'll hear phrases like talking
book audio book radio dramatization
lectures i want to address them because
we sometimes use the word talking book
to cover a lot of things or audiobook to
cover a lot of things
so i'm going to start with a couple of
definitions about what is in scope of
this document
first and foremost what's within scope
is the talking book
the point of the talking book very
simply is to transmute the words from
the visual medium into audio such that
the printed copy is not necessary
that's an important point because not
only is a book it's content but it's
also navigable so some of you will have
older dictionaries at home and you'll
remember those little finger creases
that you can put on the side
so you can rapidly get to letter x or q
or h or o or p or e
that has to be translated into audio as
well
a talking book will focus on that and i
happen to have a record here for an
example
of jorge luis borges as a talking book
an audio book on the other hand makes
the written word available
in addition to or instead of print
so douglas adams read his own work and
uh it's not a bad read it's not as fun
as the radio play but he read his own
work and that is an audio book
on the border of what's on the scope of
this uh talk is going to be
recitations and recitals so morges
reading his own work reading his own
poetry
or george carlin's famous modern man
i'm a modern man digital smoke-free
ready for the millennium that's more of
a recital of poetry
but they do fall under the same heading
and there is some overlap between
what's beyond the scope are
dramatizations making words come to life
and there you have the bbc radio series
for the hitchhiker's guide which
everybody's familiar with i'm sure
lectures
borges again i harp on borges for a
couple of different reasons
but he gave some lectures called this
craft a verse basically it's the same
thing that's happening here speaking
about metaphor and lecture
and talking about the uncouthness of
certain phrases in translation
and finally with a shameless plug to rob
and gila who are not with us and they
are hope
uh
institutions
podcasts because podcasts you don't
start with the written word podcasts
just are the audio
so with that in mind and while i bonk a
second laptop out of position
we're going to move on to
the next part which is pre-production so
in any audio video image what have you
you have different phrases phases you
have pre-production production and
post-production
in the pre-production phase you have to
make certain decisions like is this book
worth reading and i'm going to just
start with the hot five that you should
never read first off bibles we are sick
and tired of bibles
bibles are everywhere everybody's got a
free copy of the bible you can get it
for five cents you can get it for free
librivox has a copy whatever your
denomination is i assure even the quran
has been read the tanakh has been read
everything has been read
another one children's books
children's books are very demanding
to read to a child is like teaching in
order to teach you have to do a lot of
prep work
and you have to enunciate from time to
time and know when to emphasize
leave it to the professionals you're
just going to drive yourself crazy
what's the demand for the book does the
book already exist who's your target
audience do you have the time to
complete these books
do you have the talent the funding
do you have the copyright clearances
and when it comes to fanfic
theoretically you have your own
clearances but trust me guys listen to
me
nobody
nobody wants your copy of 50 shades of
gray beard with the nft tattoo don't
read it
and finally hot books and this is where
tech comes into a bit of a problem
because hot books means these are books
that are going to be updated regularly
if i write a book about cyber security
if i write
it by the time it hits the press it's
out of date
by the time you get the audio book
recording of it it's not only out of
date academia is ahead of you
so you might want to avoid doing those
things
and consider books that might be worth
reading like magazines periodicals
serialized works the reason for that is
your time commitment your energy
commitment
to complete these products
is a big commitment so you have to
really think about it
from that pre-production position we now
move on to how to read and record so
let's say that you've been through your
work you've decided that the book that
you have in your head is worth the
recording
well first off you have to read clearly
you can hear a little bit of dryness in
my mouth
just a slight amount
it has to be clear consistent
coherent and the word really you're
looking for is authoritative you are a
representation of the book
going back to our example of the
hitchhiker's guide simon jones is the
voice of the book
when you hear simon jones's voice you
hear the book and it's presented as i
know what i'm speaking about
you are speaking on behalf of the author
who may or may not be reading it
themselves
the next up is we have two pieces of
guidance now i work in accordance with
the guidelines of the national library
service of the library of congress
because i produce talking books for the
blind the visually impaired the reading
disabled and people who physically
cannot hold a book in their hands
so
the guideline that i've been following
way up here
is billy west's
the art and science of audiobook
production it's a great crash course it
gives you some background information
and it's a very high standard
and it's intentionally to be high
standards
the other one with librivox they have
their own little wiki they have their
own policy pages and guidelines but you
will find the storytellers recording
guide
so refer to them
in the case of art and science of
book production
nls reorganized their website recently
but fortunately somebody
decided to archive it on internet
archive so it is there if you want to
read it
so those are your guidelines but we have
to conform to rules so librivox has its
policies regarding recording
text music and sound effects i'll spare
you a click no
languages
they have their guidelines their rules
so does the national library service and
those specs that you see up there are
what i deal with every day
ranging from narration
talking book mastering construction of
the books construction of magazines and
preparation of audio files from
pre-recorded commercial works
and even in the commercial world amazon
and find a way voices will have their
audio requirements
before you begin recording
learn these requirements those are your
goal posts it's not just about the
reading
and you have to learn from others and
i'm just throwing it up there
which i can't pronounce properly so i
should not read that book
instead we'll leave it to michael doran
and roxanne dawson because they are
friggin awesome and klingon is a very
interesting language
so once you're familiar with all these
rules
we start talking about the hardware
you're going to use
so i've broken this down into four
sections first and foremost don't use
all-in-one field production units
just don't
and i'll cover a couple of reasons why
not but the basic one is there are many
programs where you are recording from
home
even in this room
there is a little background sound
i can hear the projector up ahead i can
hear some fans and ventilation
the room has an echo to it
if you record at home and this is pretty
well soundproofed and reinforced by the
speakers on the side
in your own home where do you have such
silence
and also most people when they record
they don't have the microphone facing
them they'll have a little object on the
table pointed towards their mouth
while they're reading a book off at an
angle
now i'm off at an angle
i'm reading the book i'm trying to focus
on the print in front of me you'll
notice that nobody can hear me because
i'm not on the microphone i have to turn
in order to face the microphone my
levels go down and if you're recording
alone and you don't have the audio
feedback and you don't have a director
it becomes very difficult
the other issue is most people put those
devices on a table
a table
has echo to it
it will reinforce create reverberation
and you end up creating a very decent
reading but a very bad recording
so that's one of the reasons why i don't
recommend it the other is a lot of the
units don't have the specifications you
need to know
you need to know is this microphone
omnidirectional picking up everything
around it
is it hypercardiod facing one direction
you need to know what noise itself it
brings into the chain
so all these details tend to be missing
from the recorded home units
and the most important part is how do
you know if it's powered on
how do you know if you've run out of
storage space how do you know if it's
working at all
you may record three hours and
not have anything to show for it
so the easier parts are storage now
storage is very simple anything capable
of sustaining one megabyte per second
actually it's 1.1
in those first specs i'm taking dj
standards which is a sample rate of 192
kilohertz 24 bits stereo
you will mostly be recording at cd
quality or dat quality the requirements
as you can see are
greatly reduced
but also you'll probably be recording in
mono
with microphones we have a prime example
of a microphone right here it's the
generic shure sm 58
it's a classic it picks up in one
direction
dynamic
at the place where i work we use shure
sm7bs they're unidirectional dynamic
microphones very popular with speed with
streamers youtube channels
instagram you'll you'll see it
everywhere
we used to use the electro voice re27nd
it was a cardioid dynamic microphone had
neodymium drivers and it was very close
to what we would call a condenser mic in
terms of its pickup it did not forgive
anything
if you had lunch an hour ago we knew
if you farted we knew
if the elevator behind the studio room
where we were recording was going up or
down we
knew
your cell phone is basically a condenser
microphone
it is unforgiving it's cheap it's small
it picks up everything and if you want
an example of it try to make a phone
call to somebody who you really need to
speak to on a busy avenue and try to
hear them
over the background noise
most of the all-in-one units are
condenser microphones so splurge the
extra if you can
borrow i'm not going to say steal but
beg if you have to and get full
equipment
the last item is not a microphone
it's actually focusrite 2i4 second
generation the reason we have is because
these microphones have a connector
called an xlr cable connector
basically signal negative signal ground
and shielding and that's the connector
right here
we use these focusrite devices to
convert from the analog connector of the
xlr into a usb device
it just digitizes for you nice and easy
finally headphones because you need to
be able to hear yourself if you're
working in a team maybe you happen to
have access to a studio you need to be
able to hear your director giving you
instructions and you also need to hear
yourself
so
typically in our studios we'll use an
mdr7506 they're very comfortable they
are soft padded they're not open to the
world it's not like having an open
speaker
the cable is corded and it allows you
some freedom of movement so you can
reposition
as you're reading
they're
not expensive i'll i'll be honest about
that they might be a little more
say a project would start at about 250
so of all that equipment you can pretty
much do a lot of it getting away on the
cheap and easy the first couple of times
but do not and i i really i have to
emphasize this do not use open ear
open headphones anything that causes
feedback
so for example
i happen to like my cheap speakers 29
and if they break who cares because
they're only 29 bucks but they have
enough frequency response that you can
hear your own voice you don't need
studio engineering speakers that go from
20 to 20 000 hertz you need a narrow
range roughly between 105 kilohertz
uh don't use in ear earbuds
that's going to leak all the audio it's
going to come back to your microphone
you get a feedback
the final one and i know a lot of people
like headsets i happen to like headsets
but don't use a bluetooth headset please
don't
bluetooth is notorious for its latency i
know it's getting better and better all
the time but by the time you start a
sentence
have it transmitted over bluetooth
arrive at the computer commit it to disk
have the computer play it back to you go
over bluetooth and come back to your ear
you have already lost anywhere from
20 milliseconds to 100 milliseconds very
easily it will distract you it will slow
you down and you'll just be frustrated
to the point where you can't continue
software very simple and most of you
probably have two out of these four uh
the first one is the aph studio recorder
it's popular with our studios because
it's very easy for volunteers to use
it's sort of the dumbest recorder you
can possibly have and it works
for post-production as well as recording
we can use the hindenburg audio book
creator we use a specific version made
for the national library service and
affiliates
that's what allows us to take the
recordings and turn them into
full-fledged talking books digital
talking books ready to be serviced and
given to patrons of the library of
congress who are blind visually impaired
and reading disabled
audacity ah yes
the audio editing software made by
programmers for programmers
but there ain't nothing else
i mean realistically speaking
you could use socks i mean you could
just say pull dev input mic 0 and commit
to disk
and just do live recordings and edit it
afterwards but audacity really is the
only game in town the other audio
software that exists on linux is mostly
driven for music and you're not
necessarily making music you are making
a
recording of audio a voice
it's a very different beast
so we've talked about hardware we've
talked about software time to talk about
underwear your talent
now your talent breaks down into
basically four people a narrator
director and an engineer so the narrator
translates the written word and i'm
going to read off of this guy because my
my the laptop is shot
the narrator translates the written word
to the spoken word in a way that is as
consistent as possible with the intent
of the author thank you bill west for
writing that you saved me a lot
so the job of the narrator is to
be the author be authoritative
the engineer controls all technical
operations during a recording session
allowing the narrator to devote full
attention and effort to the act of
narration
so
checking your levels making sure that
you're not over plusing the mic
that you are in fact talking to the
microphone
that's his job or her job or their job
making sure the computer is running
making sure that you have storage space
that's their job the director has a
harder job the director is sort of like
a driver you know when you drive on a
road you have to look at the road you
have to look at the traffic you have to
remember the you know what the lights
mean what the rules of the road are when
you try to make a left turn make sure
you're not speeding the director has
multiple roles and basically the
director is responsible for quality
assurance of the content and its
continuity
they are the first listener of your
audiobook
now i'm saying listener for a reason
because there's also a first reader of
the book these books are red so the
director is concerned with tonality
inflections pronunciation enunciation
energy levels whether you are reading
correctly
they're also looking for digestion
noises or if you pick your nose and it
has to show up on the microphone they're
going to stop you if you sound tired if
you sound dry
and they also basically keep the
recording record that is to say metadata
about the recordings
finally
there's quality control but before i
continue to quality control because it's
another stage
don't try to do all three of these
things at once
because you can't be and i'm going to
just try this right now and you're
seeing it right now i'm trying to read
stay on the microphone check my levels
check the clock make sure that i'm okay
i've lost track of where i was where was
i
you end up doing a lot of frustrating
work trying to just stay on track
and quality control checks for errors
and irregularities in the recording and
notifies the talent of what needs fixing
so
quality control should be an unbiased
ear
it should not be you you should not
check your own work have someone else do
it for you
if you are working remotely you might
consider doing a zoom session or a skype
session or a team session or just be
have someone on the phone
listening in with their own copy of you
know the book that you're trying to read
and follow along
does not take much
next up we have the production
environment so hardware software
underwear and just plain wear
noises come in different forms and i've
covered a lot of them you know fans if
you're recording in your kitchen it's a
refrigerator typically
if you're by a busy street you have
traffic if you're out you know near jfk
or laguardia or wherever you have air
traffic uh lawn mowers
and your neighbors because your
neighbors are never cooperating with you
ever right
but sound proofing is a way of abating
extraneous noises now
there are two kinds of noises it's kind
that the structural noise so if you know
the ground shakes you can't do much
about it the building carries all that
sound
if the air has noise to it you can abate
it and those of you familiar with radio
statler from here at hope will remember
that we had polystyrene walls
with some graffiti on it but we're
focusing on the polystyrene it acts as a
buffer
so you can have
basically styrofoam walls small enclosed
studio
um the other possibility is use drapes
use curtaining use
a heavy blanket
but don't
don't don't read in the bathroom
why do we say that okay so a lot of
people who thinks they sing great in the
bathroom
okay i've got a lot of honest people
here so
you think that the bathroom is a great
place to read
because you're enclosed you're
comfortable
you have that lovely tonality to it well
again that's the room noise that's the
reverberation and the echo of the tiles
don't do it
because you sound good to yourself
but a microphone does not forgive
the same way that the human being
basically discards most of its
information and focuses in on those
narrow things that really has to pay
attention to and remember
your ears do the same thing your eyes do
the same thing most of the information
that you pick up
you just immediately discard the brain
is a lossy
medium
microphones don't forgive
so don't do it in your bathroom also
somebody else might need the bathroom
you never know
so once you've gone from the production
phase we now go into post production
where you have editing and then you have
distribution
with editing basically you are dealing
with a 16-bit wave maybe a flak
you're dealing with
cd quality or dat quality audio
and you're going to perfect it and
you're going to keep it under 2 gigs
the reason for that is one if your
recording is longer than three hours
you're doing something wrong
and two you should always expect legacy
hardware in use in fact i make a mention
of neo's mantra later on
but expect embedded devices
expect a 32 plus or minus one
bit
limit
your workflow for this is going to
basically be make sure that you have all
the components of the audiobook before
you sit down to edit label all the
logical sections
look at the
table of contents i mean it's stupid but
you open up a book you see a table of
contents typically in pieces of fiction
it'll be
you just jump right into the first
chapter know what the hell you're
reading find out how many chapters you
have how many parts you have to it i
mean we got one book
where
the first chapter was numbered one the
last chapter was number 36 we got all
the audio down to the engineers booth at
where we were editing it and we
discovered that chapters 24 through 28
were missing
if you just check the first and the end
you think everything's great
so make sure you have all your materials
make sure you have preliminary header
and concluding materials now this is
your metadata
this is the part where you would say
name of the book by author
if you have a serial number you throw it
in there and you say
narrated by directed by engineered by
recorded on such and such a date
for the benefit of under the auspices of
that keeps a record of not only who
recorded it and who's responsible for it
but who took part and there are some
projects where you can contribute for
money
and you know make a decent living not a
great one but a decent one nothing to
laugh
at but ultimately you are finessing the
audio quality
last
for the last 75 years the focus of
talking books has been to convey the
information
not make it entertaining
not to make it an audio experience
all you want to know is how the hell do
you spell a word you have to be able to
navigate through a talking book to get
to it or i just want to know what the
epic of gilgamesh is i don't need
and gilgamesh did
who cares about that just read the story
so we get to the point first and then we
finish the audio
and one of the ways you can do that i'll
mention later on in the do's and don'ts
is
writing the silence
foreshadowing
sometimes you're gonna have to transmit
files from here to there now admittedly
ideally you would be all working in the
studio
all your equipment would be present all
your people would be present but
sometimes you have to work across the
globe
so how do you transmit big waves well
one thing is you can knock it down to
flak
flac is recommended under these
circumstances
another thing you can do is you can tar
xz your waves uh in both cases you save
about 25 of the file space and
sooner you can transfer files the closer
it is to being done
for the love of god
tarball your entire audacity project
we received a very difficult book a very
lengthy book
to edit
and it consisted of about 65 kilobytes
of the edit definition list from
audacity because they sent the aup not
the audio that came with it
if you're working in audacity and i know
version 3 has a you know save compressed
format and single file format
expect other people to still be using
2.4 for various reasons
tarball your entire folder before you
transmit it don't just send open file x
at this time and include file y
and do not under any circumstance send
mp3 to editors and the reason for this
is very simple once you lose quality you
cannot get it back
there's a saying we'll fix it in post
we'll fix it in post no post can't fix
things
if there's an omission a gap or a loss
of quality you can't fix it you cannot
recover it
because it was never made
or because it was outright destroyed
mp3 is very popular for a distribution
format
but it is no good for editors you're
working on
finessed
pristine master
versions of your project
and finally use 8.3 file names because
like i said
expect embedded devices from the year
dot to still be in use i mean you can
use an atari st to still cut audio
so
income's neo's mantra
never underestimate the ubiquity of and
reliance upon
irreplaceable and unupgradable well-past
end of life
equipment fulfilling mission critical
production roles
expect old to still be used
and some of that believe it or not is
dos-based
once you have finessed the audio you can
account for all of the recordings you
have all the metadata we are ready for
post-production distribution this is the
part where you take your master reels
and you give it to the public
or your patrons or your club or whatever
um national library service uses 3gp amr
wide band that's their codec of choice
for their talking book medium
librivox will send out mp3s as a final
product not as an editing product at 64
kilobits if you go to internet archive
sometimes you can get 128 kilobit
commercial proprietary formats go from
aac to m4b etc but basically it's drm
encoded audio so it may or may not apply
to you
but this is the far speaker
as to say the last we're familiar with
the notion of the last mile the last
mile of telecommunications the bit
between the home and the trunk line well
here is your last mile
you can get away with a lot of stuff
simply knowing what speakers you're
going to be playing against
this will give you 20 to 20 000 hertz
these speakers here might cover this a
little bit more of the range some people
might be listening with in-ear buds you
can knock down the codec based on what
your finished product is but you can
expect at least one person to have a
good audio quality system going on
so always provide
a higher quality than you expect the
device to be
excuse me
always produce a higher quality end
product than the device you expect to be
playing it on
so now we get to talk about the workflow
we've covered pre-production
post-production was the book worth it
how are we going to distribute it how
are we going to make our master reels
the first part in the any project is to
commit to the project
if you don't commit to the project
there's no work to be done
you have to assemble your talent your
time and your money
yes money because even if you're doing
this on a volunteer basis time is money
it comes at a cost maybe you can't watch
the ball game or maybe you have to give
up your wednesday afternoons to listen
to somebody else's recording
and there should be a little bit of
compensation for all this work at the
very least something more than just
plain gratitude
but as you're dividing up the book into
logical chapters or sections to be
recorded
and let the table of contents guide you
divide up the work evenly and take
responsibility for each part especially
if you're working in a group setting
a production team which consists of a
narrator a monitor a reviewer typically
requires five and a half hours of staff
time to produce one hour of
error-free
product
this comes from the bill west document i
mentioned earlier
and a typical two-track original master
with just under three hours of inter of
listening time
requires not less than 16 and a half
hours of production time
so when you budget your time you're
being told to expect five and a half to
six and a half to one i would raise it
to ten to one
especially if you haven't done this
before
now you can record a section on its own
send it off to your quality control
person and have them report back as soon
as you finish recording
it does speed up the process and it's
easier for the person who's doing the
narration if they if they're told while
they have the content fresh in their
mind what they have to go back and fix
in a lot of places you will record
then review
the whole book
that can take weeks
do it while the iron is hot
so i recommend actually
either through github or some other file
sharing system or at least some
annotating system
convey what errors you find as soon as
you find them as soon as you possibly
can because the next recording session
someone might come in and say oh shoot i
have to fix five things well let's take
care of that before i get to you know
the rest of the work
once you've taken care of qc
and there are no fixes left
you might want to run through another
pair of ears just to listen to it
see if you can hear when
different recording sessions took place
at the beginning of a talk or at the
beginning of a lecture or beginning of
recording you come in with a whole bunch
of energy you're ready to read you are
ready to go and then after about an hour
you start to talk a little slower
and lose energy
so if you make a flub excuse me error
while you are talking slowly that's what
it's going to sound like it's going to
sound disjointed
when you make a mistake you don't want
to call attention to the mistake you
made you know if you say for example in
the beginning dog made heaven and earth
and you go back and you have to fix it
you say in the beginning god made the
heaven and earth
your end your listener is going to say
why is he emphasizing that word he must
have screwed up
so you want to be aware of your
continuity also
in studio recordings and that's sort of
the on-site system that we have
the narrator and the director work as a
team they really do the engineer and the
director
are
immediately
able to provide quality assurance now
quality assurance is the prevention of
problems quality control
is detecting problems
when an engineer and director work
together
they're able to prevent problems from
recurring they address it on the spot
this means you don't have to go back and
re-record
the director and quality control
cooperate with each other
quality control will say this has to be
re-read or i heard a sneeze here or the
guy
lip slacks in the middle of you know
page five
and you can deal with it
as soon as the narrator comes back
and the errors are caught in a timely
manner you don't have to wait weeks for
it
generally speaking
about 80 percent of the books to 90
percent of the books that we record in
studio as a group on premises
continue on to post-production
it's a very high success rate
road sessions on the other hand are a
little different about 80 of the books
fail to make it out of production and
here are the reasons why
if you're doing this solo there's no
director to sustain quality assurance
you have to rely on your own bias to
decide if you've done the right job
there's no engineer to maintain
technological assets in other words you
really can't keep an eye on whether the
computer is in good shape or not
there's no quality control because the
deadline is more
important sometimes you're on a deadline
and you're on a schedule and you have to
make the schedule and you have to
sacrifice and that sacrifice happens to
be the quality control so occasionally
you hear a book with a burp in it
it happens
lack of communication if you've got
people who are supposed to be taking
their part they don't respond back
we suddenly don't trust these people
life happens
you know
people lose interest
and if they lose interest they drop out
of the project
so to
quote someone who i remember way back
and you know back when the year started
with 1980
don't allow the task ahead of you to be
greater than the enthusiasm behind you
like i don't want to scare anyone from
this project but if you're going to
commit to this
commit to it enthusiastically knowing
what you are dealing with
recording at home has a very high
failure rate
uh some of the books that i've heard
from librivox would never have passed
quality control for an nls standing in
fact some of the books from audible that
i've heard even though i'm not
technically a client
they would not pass for the highest
standards for example you need 48
decibels of signal-to-noise ratio
minimum
if i were to take an audio recording
sample right now of this room
you would see a small flat line you
would think that the air is clear
but when you actually measure the number
of decibels
no this sounds a bit more like 42
sorry about that i don't know why i'm
going ding
but participants will drop out of the
project you know if they don't have a
success rate
people will be turned down
and also you need qualitative voices
now there is one caveat to all of this
which is that books narrated from home
using home studios tend to pass the
rudimentary quality control requirements
but tend to require greater
post-production that is to say if you
have a home studio odds are you know
what you're doing to begin with
so
go on
but because there's no one there with an
unbiased ear
you may have to do more fixes later on
therefore
i don't want to say don't do it but do
it
if you have talent you want to share it
do so
but i can't tell you how many times i've
heard this in the middle of a book from
liberty box where i can tell that the
narrator has a home studio
it'll just piss off your engineers so
post-production takes a lot longer while
you try to remove those defects rather
than focusing on the content
and for those who are recording from
home by the way
your success rate is pretty much 60
i mean it's not bad it just dies in
post-production
so the final
slide
is the do's and don'ts and there are
quite a few here
so i want to start off with what a
workflow would sound like if you were
doing this at home for your first time
maybe you're working in a team let's uh
just name a book that you happen to
think of off the top of your head
anyone
okay no participation fine
whatever book you you have you're going
to sit down you're going to record
you've got your microphone in front of
you you want to make sure that the
microphone is exactly where your voice
is you'll notice that if i talk down
here with the microphone above me you're
not hearing anything if i talk up here
you're hearing my voice very well why
because i happen to know my speech is
here it's concentrated in front of my
teeth a little bit below the jaw
not off to the side
not off at an angle
so i will know where my axis is
if i want to read this screen for
example
i would position the microphone where my
voice is going to go
where i can see the monitor
and read
not off to the side
and project my voice downwards
a lot of streamers
they work like this
why do they work like this
you are attacked and you know why
because you are using a cardioid
microphone where you expect people to
talk upwards the focus is not on reading
the screen the focus is on looking at
others
it's at looking at the camera at the
zoom
and who cares if there's a microphone in
your way you're looking at a mario
you're showing off right damn i look
good
realistically
you want the microphone beneath you
you're not going to be screaming and or
rating into the microphone
you're just going to be reading off a
screen do's and don'ts
this section is focused on narration
tips for directors engineers
post-production markup and collaboration
will be found at
and you just read
when i do my sections
at home or if i'm on the road or if i'm
giving you know new talent advice
i usually say start your recording
thusly
name the book
who's the author
who's reading who's directing
put in the day and time that you began
your recording
very important because it'll help you
keep a log
it'll tell you how much time and effort
you've put into work
and then shut the hell up for 10 seconds
why would you do that the answer is you
want the microphone to actually pick up
all the background noise
as an engineer we've worked with a lot
of books that have recorded back in the
1980s 1970s 1990s all sorts of
background noises
if you have a good sample of the noise
floor and the room tone where you are
recording
audacity has this nice little feature
called noise reduction
we love it
but in order to work properly you have
to give it a sample of noise
don't make me extract it from snippets
of audio
give me the sample at the beginning
so
you do your intro
you walk away from the mic for a few
seconds and then you begin recording
so that's a top-notch pet peeve
as you can tell
another one
ride
the pause
if you have a book and you're going to
have paragraphs and sentences read the
freaking punctuation i mean you're not
christopher walken even christopher
walken will respect the notion of a
sentence is a logical unit of
information
if you have a list a b
c and d
write the commas
why would you do that well for one thing
it makes it a lot easier to pick up in
case you make a mistake
if i say you know lettuce tomato onions
underwear
i can easily cut after tomatoes and
replace underwear with cheese
if you have less tomato onions and
underwear cheese
i don't have enough gap as an editor to
separate the cheese from the underwear
ride the pause you can always tighten up
a pause you can't stretch the two apart
without sounding processed
speaking of sounding processed
compression a lot of people use
compression they try to rise the levels
make it sound a more full sound of audio
guys this is not music if you adjust the
human voice
it's going to be audible it's going to
be noticeable it's going to become the
uncanny valley of your eardrums
so it'll sound a little more like
auto-tune and auto-tune i know i know
it's 20 22. i know we have really good
deep fakes with audio
but if
no it's not going to sound right it's
going to sound absolutely wrong
it actually
is horrific
so do not do not use compression try to
prevent needing compression in the first
place by getting your levels high you
want to keep it between
negative six
to let's say negative 12 decibels
it's kind of hard to watch because you
need a view meter and you're trying to
focus on reading
speaking of reading
please
read the damn book before you record
i beg you
because if you don't read the book ahead
of time and you're reading cold you it
will show it will sound you it'll be a
mechanical reading
be familiar not just familiar be
authoritative in what you read
people are relying on you and you and
you and you and you and you and you and
you
to present the book like a finished
product not like i'm just learning this
for the first time excuse me
just read the book and then read it to
yourself aloud
you need to know what words you're going
to trip over what pronunciation guides
you have
if you don't know if you are so naive
that you think it's written it's
pronounced nave
don't read the book
because if you pronounce naive as nave
all throughout guess what there is no
such thing as find and replace in audio
and not only that sometimes you're gonna
say nave nave
nerve and you're gonna replace it with
naive
gee jim was sounding very naive they're
all throughout
don't make your edits noticeable
if you screw up a sentence and you have
to go back to re-record it don't just
record the word you screwed up
or the sentence record a sentence before
record a sentence after
try to make it dovetail with the
correction
this is audio engineering 101
and it's very easy to do and if you ride
the pauses between sentences
you don't need to find where those words
are
so for example if i have a piece of
audio unfortunately i do not have an
example on me but if you follow up on
github later on uh probably next week
i'll give you a prime example
where the audio goes on for 24 hours
because some books go on for 24 or even
36 hours straight
i have to as an engineer without a copy
of my book
find where the corrections have to be
made
if you give a five second pause between
chapters
you have just made my life so much
easier because all i have to do is look
for the big gaps
one two three four five that's gotta be
chapter five chapter five
now i can narrow down my search for what
needs to be corrected
when you go from paragraph to paragraph
take a breath
you don't have to read a sentence in a
single lungful
you have the ability i mean we're not
doing this live
what we are doing instead
is committing to tape or in the case of
the 21st century committing to computers
you have so much storage capacity
use it to your benefit
take it slow
that will speed up the recording the
post-production the corrections
your levels will be good
ultimately you will be published
but you have to keep your standards high
at all times you have to make the
investment in the equipment
the time
the effort
the ability to take criticism
like if somebody's very nasal you got to
go back and say you have to re-record
this chapter you had a booger up your
nose the whole time
and take that criticism
realistically
there are some people who will read
sentences mechanically
they have a distinct pattern to the way
that they speak
you are hearing an example of it right
now
this is a major turn off
you need to sound
as normal
conversational
as you could possibly be
there are a few times when you have to
exaggerate i mean if you see an
exclamation point you have to exclaim
if there's a question mark
can you ask the question
and especially finally
because this is one this is a big
problem
there are a lot of books that are read
mechanically by computers now like i
said this is 2022 deep fakes exist
there are great ways of fussing with
audio to make things sound like what
someone said even though they didn't set
it because it's a computer-generated
thing but for the love of
no
if i give who here watches pbs i'm
familiar with the phrase viewers like
you
okay okay a cold reading of viewers like
where's the emphasis
if i say viewers like you
great
if viewers like you
viewers like you
these are three different readings of
the exact same phrase
if i say
i love you i love you
i love you
three different readings of the exact
same thing computers are at
figuring out what the emphasis should be
but for humans it's normal especially in
english we emphasize the word that needs
to be dressed to be brought to our
attention
emphasis
something that's not really good for
computers so please if i ever hear that
you ran any piece of text through
text-to-speech especially that tick-tock
voice i'mma kill you
i'm gonna kill you i'm gonna beat you
over the head i'm gonna take away your
microphone but most of all
we're not there yet
ai is not that good yet and it's going
to take more years for that
so for the human nuance and also for the
familiarity
we still need human voices
and i'd like you to join in this quest
to become the next set of voices
you know what you got to do you know
what you shouldn't do
thank you for being here and i hope you
enjoy
trying to become the next set of voices
reading to someone because it really
does change lives
you are being again a gap filler we have
a great degree of illiteracy in this
world still i mean it is 21st century
but illiteracy is an issue
when you become a book for someone
suddenly it doesn't matter if they're
illiterate
they're reading by their ears
and you will be writing for the ear
thank you
[Applause]
and i see we've made it exactly on time
so
if you have any questions come over here
to this microphone
wow
i think i did
i don't think i have that much court
well there's not a lot of questions but
let's find out
now that we've offered the opportunity
right
i am an audible
uh
well you want to call me subscriber i've
got hundreds
one of the things that i've noticed that
uh i used to just pull off books but
then i found read by author
and oh my god does that make a
difference i happen to prefer works that
are read by the author um this is why i
make a great
enjoyment actually of borges uh while he
was in the united states for a fairly
brief period he did give lectures uh
with the smithsonian and library of
congress he read some of his own works a
lot of his recitals i've committed to
heart better
through the year than through reading by
eye
one of the things that i liked was i
noticed that the author would emphasize
a phrase or a situation different than a
cold reading
not only a good reading but even in
translation for example the uh short
story burgess and i which is a sort of
an autobiographical
joke or jest
the english translation is a fairly good
read i believe it's available from simon
schuster
but then when you hear it in the
original spanish or actually i think he
wrote it in english originally i'm not
sure
but uh this is the problem with murkeys
he spoke too many languages and just
wrote prolifically but when his own
reading
he emphasized i'm going to try to get
this right i'll have an example up on
the github pages
he ends
so i do not know which one of the two
of the two borges
writes this page
sort of a matter of fact
the translation that came from simon
schuster was
i'm not sure which one of the two reads
this page
those are very different readings
you're not there to inflect for the
author you're there to
convey what the author has already said
the other issue is there's a lot of
music thrown in for i don't know why i
think it's just for decor
challenges questions comments fetches
coffee
uh you were talking about including
metadata at the start of your recordings
before that 10 second gap
uh
one thing i wanted to add to that
because this is something that i
experienced in the last few months
as you do more of this you're going to
struggle to like
the sound of the recordings that you
make and eventually
if you own a lot of equipment and
experiment with different microphones
you might accidentally create one that
you really like the sound of
and
there's nothing worse than going back
over your work and discovering that and
realizing that you have no information
about how you did that
so when you are including
that metadata at the start of your
recordings you might also want to
include things like where you positioned
the microphone
which microphone you were using what
your general analog equipment settings
were
because that would have saved me a lot
of time personally
absolutely when you start a project keep
your hardware and your software and your
positioning consistent this is
environmental factors obviously
the other thing that
is worth mentioning is when you finish a
recording don't just you know hit cut
and you're done um
take five seconds
and just say i'm finishing at such and
such a time on such and such a page
it makes it easier to start the next
section as you go along
uh also one thing that i think i forgot
to mention but record natural don't use
eq as your recording that you can do a
little more finesse in post-production
than you can live and you can keep it
consistent all throughout your work so
anybody i don't know if anybody listens
to the brian lehrer show because on wnbc
he's got that nice deep voice but then
you hear him on television he's got this
little teeny voice up here
that's because the eq is being ridden
record flat record natural
you know i noticed that you recommended
flac as uh the
file sharing kind of audio
format
why not wave
wave is a very large file format
so i mean just to start with one cd is
650 megs that should get you about
what was it
i think it was about i'm sorry
let me start from another direction
uh let's talk about the 2gig file limit
because some dos programs are still in
use that do audio adjustments that
should get you about six hours of audio
that six hour of audio at two gigs would
flow down to about a gig and a quarter
as a flak and also flack is lossless
you're not losing quality along the way
so you're shaving off about 750 megs of
transmission on a two on a two gig file
and also the other thing is flac is now
pretty much well supported by everybody
ogg is not as well supported
so
flat can be recommended at that point
but
basically i i tested against tarx
zipping wave files and flack and they're
about about the same
oh now i'm in trouble
by the way
so uh i think you kind of
very briefly touched on this but my word
background is not really an
accessibility thing unfortunately to
some degree is that like as a someone
who was a big star wars fan uh for a
while with a lot of their book series
starting with the original audiobooks
because it's based on a movie series
they often instead of just um relaying
or just excitingly read the information
they would do as you say make it an
audio experience uh where they would add
in
the movies reuse the movie soundtracks
put in sound effects from them that's no
longer an audiobook that used to be
the thing that was kind of unique to
star wars and some sci-fi but now
there's just pure audio projects where
basically they're bringing back radio
serials instead of trying to like put
out information i just wanted to know if
you want to elaborate like that sort of
proliferation do you see that as like
muddying the waters of the type of work
you're trying to do or is it something
where it's become i'll put it i'll put
in another parallel uh it's like saying
the difference between watchmen the
movie and watchmen the audio the graphic
novel um whenever you transmute one
medium into another there's a certain
adaptation that has to take place
um what the star wars series is doing is
being entertainment or a continuation of
the entertainment as if it were a radio
play if you were reading a book
then it is superfluous and you're
distracting from the message
uh there is one last thing i am going to
add to this because i don't think i
covered this quite uh in my slide deck
but i want to talk about foreign
language um excuse me foreign language
because this is the united states half
of all homes speak another language
there is a big difference between a
native speaker
and a native reader
you can be very you can be proficient in
a language and still flub it and if you
don't believe me how many of you were
here for hurricane sandy
and how many people remember michael
bloomberg's god-awful atrocious spanish
that's the difference
that's sort of the difference i'm going
at you can be very proficient but sound
horrific
if you have an accent it may become a
problem
and then finally because i see the time
is going
um
native speakers don't necessarily
be they don't necessarily become native
readers
you need fluency so if you're not fluent
in a language and can't read on a fluent
level
let someone else do it you can help on
the editing qc
just don't narrate yourself
all right i think we are out of time at
this point we are out of time so thank
you very much i know corey doctro is
still probably spieling as we speak
and for you to come here i really
appreciate it so thank you all
[Applause]
it'll be just a few minutes to set up
for this next time