all right thanks for being here
we're here
it's sunday it's getting towards the
middle of the afternoon i hope you're
staying energized there's a lot of good
content including this talk coming right
up here you're in the right place for
the three o'clock session i'll give you
a couple of quick announcements about
how the rest of the day is looking there
are still some other sessions going on
after this one including in the fourth
track in the coffee house you can get
that schedule on
wiki.hope.net see if there's something
you want to do after your
experience in this room and also we have
um closing ceremonies coming up at 6 00
p.m closing ceremonies are pretty cool
we just give sort of a nice thank you to
everyone that's attended talk a little
bit about how the conference came
together a little bit of the you know
behind the scenes uh information so
that's kind of a fun um thing to attend
and at the end of closing ceremonies
there will be a band a brazilian salsa
band starting up right outside room 416
and processing through the building
ending up out front on the plaza so
we'll have a little bit of a street
party atmosphere to wrap up the uh
conference here a new hope 2022. pretty
cool right
so the um
uh invitation is to stick around if
you're thinking of leaving early to beat
the traffic forget about the traffic the
traffic gets better later at night right
so stick around for closing ceremonies
and also
if you can please stick around to
volunteer with packing up that usually
takes us until 11 or even a little bit
later at night we got to remove all the
rental equipment pack up a bunch of
trucks
to some extent clean up the facility
take down our signs stuff like that
mostly unskilled labor we really
appreciate the help and then tomorrow
morning also we have to load up a couple
more rental trucks so if you have the
opportunity to stick around if you're
staying on campus or nearby please do
consider volunteering it is another hot
day so don't skimp on hydration just
because you made it this far into the
weekend doesn't mean there's not still
opportunity to become dehydrated so
please do
please do drink and that's all i gotta
say let's get rolling with um our next
fascinating talk please welcome our
speaker
thank you what a just a lovely community
it's so great to be back at hope hello
everyone i don't know if i should be
speaking directly into this
okay great well i hope you all are
energized i definitely have had a long
night so if i have to read my slides
it's just me trying to make sense um so
let's get started my name is jamie joyce
this is the second time i will be
speaking at hope um i am the executive
director of the society library and what
the society library is is a non-profit
collective intelligence organization and
what we work on is developing tools to
augment the way in which we perceive
social and political issues so that we
can make more informed inclusive and
less biased decisions
uh today
i'll be talking a little bit more about
what we do but the name of this talk is
hacking comprehension and what it is
about is essentially um
making sense of not only the big issues
like climate change and reproductive
rights and things like that but also
each other and that means overcoming
limitations of time attention perception
emotional empathy all the different
things that get in the way of us
understanding each other so i'm going to
be jumping into
an exercise to kind of show how we don't
see eye to eye but
um there are some other things going to
be talking about too so first not seeing
eye to eye
and then secondly i'm going to talk
about the work that we do at the society
library and how we try to improve the
information environment by seeding it
with different visualizations of
knowledge and steel manned knowledge and
then
thirdly i'm going to inquire into what i
think is going to be the next evolution
of media and where we should start
orienting our design uh in order to
augment the way in which we see the
world and each other
i'm actually gonna scoot down so i have
my notes closer okay
so uh not seeing eye to eye are you all
ready for this i'm gonna ask you to
raise your hands it's gonna be great
oh you all did it already
there's no reason yet but just we're
about to get started okay now raise your
hand do you recognize this dress have
you seen this before
oh it's like everyone in the room
wonderful okay
uh this is the dress that broke the
internet if you remember people fought
about what color this dress is
so question who sees this dress as black
and blue
okay who sees this dress as gold and
white
a few
does anyone know why
go for it yeah
well basically basically our brains are
making an assumption but the reason why
is actually extremely interesting
because not only did this dress break
the internet but it also apparently
broke our uh theory of vision because
existing color theory could not explain
this phenomenon why do people
some people see this as black and blue
other people see it as gold and white uh
it turned out that pascal wallish uh
published a paper in the
journal of
vision and he offered a reason as to why
we see the dress differently and it's
not because of like rods or cones in our
eyes are necessarily because of the
contrast although the ambiguity of the
lighting of the dress definitely does
have an impact but it actually has to do
oops
it actually has to do with your prior
experiences so the people who are likely
to see this dress as black and blue are
the ones who spend a lot of time under
artificial light
when the people see it as gold and white
actually have an existing prior of
assuming that it is in natural light so
it's literally your prior past
experiences that is shaping the way that
your brain is hallucinating color for
you to experience so you know early
morning birds and night owls completely
see this dress different colors based on
prior experience not physicality now the
important thing of course about
scientific hypotheses is that you have
to put it to the test and see if it has
predictive power and so after pascal
wallish published this in the uh journal
of vision i just want to make sure i get
that correct um they went ahead and
proceeded with some other tests
including this one
this was a image that didn't just pop up
on the internet this is something that
they actually intentionally produced
they produced similar color conditions
so i'm going to ask uh who sees the
these crocs as like green and grayish
interesting okay who sees these crocs as
pink and white
this is so exciting okay amazing i've
never seen this result before okay
so
can anyone guess why you all are seeing
these crocs as different colors
bingo okay perfect so the existing prior
of the dress was your relationship to
natural versus artificial light that
existing prior caused your brain to fill
in the ambiguity of the image and
hallucinate either a black and blue
dress or a golden white dress you over
there got that totally correct for
people the the existing prior actually
is correlated with age so people who are
older will assume that those socks are
supposed to be white when people who are
a little bit younger don't necessarily
have that existing prior of socks being
white socks could be any color crocs
don't really have a default color and so
that's where they found the distribution
which is extremely interesting so what
they concluded is essentially our past
experiences can exist as priors in the
way in which we calculate probabilities
under
ambiguous conditions especially when it
comes to visualizing
has anyone seen this image before
okay
so what's really interesting about the
dress and the crocs and socks is that we
can be looking at the exact same image
human beings can be looking at the exact
same image and conclude that they're
seeing completely different things
we can hallucinate our differences but
we can also interestingly hallucinate
consensus
does everyone see these strawberries as
red
yes yeah depends on the monitor
hilarious okay this this one right here
that i'm pointing at do you see it as
strawberries as red
i see nods i see nods okay would you
believe that there's no red in that
image at all
okay some more nods great okay i plucked
these pixels out because i couldn't
believe it myself i mean to me those
strawberries definitely look red but
it's again just our brain filling in the
details assuming what should be there
and generally a lot of people tend to
see this as as red it's not as divided
as the crocs and socks nor the dress
um okay so
it gets worse though not only let me
just conclude um so it seems as though
one of the reasons why we don't see eye
to eye is because even when we look at
the exact same image we can disagree
because we are hallucinating different
versions of reality and sometimes when
we look at the same image we can all
agree on what we see but crazy enough
what we all are collectively seeing
is a a hallucinated fabrication and um
it gets crazier because we're all not
looking at the same information of
course when it comes to social and
political issues we're not all zoomed
into the same data the same graphs the
same knowledge certainly not and all of
the ways in which we're interpreting
that knowledge are of course informed by
different experiences of life itself
different priors traumas lessons learned
tribes and apparently sources of light
and the experience of life and therefore
perception of reality can also warp
moment to moment depending on whether we
are rested fed sober caffeinated or
stressed which i can definitely attest
to i crushed a low-carb monster energy
drink right before this talk just for
you so i can tell like my reality's
definitely warped a little bit
moving on um and even we're really
trying to be rational we're really
trying to like survey the data landscape
put it in order be logical really
inquire into understanding complex
social and political issues like climate
change and reproductive rights and all
these things our brains are primed to
make over 300 kinds of logical reasoning
errors and there's over 190 different
cognitive biases that we can be
manipulated by as well
plus another way in which we don't see
eye to eye is because each of us have
different tools that we use to augment
our perceptions of reality many of you
in this room have a much different
insight vision understanding of apps and
software and websites because you know
how to program you can see and
understand it in a different dimension
not everybody has that we also have
asymmetric access to tools and
understanding of things as small as like
the physics of particles or as large as
climate systems of earth if i take off
my glasses right now i believe i'm like
technically legally blind
um
and luckily i'm aware of my terrible
eyesight and i've gotten glasses and
sadly my prescription increases all the
time but many of us are not aware that
we have blind spots
and uh we simply can't see what we can't
see because we don't know what we don't
know
now i'm going to extrapolate a little
bit because this talk is about social
and political issues and i think that
the way in which technology has
amplified the amount of information that
we're interacting with
has
potentially caused democracies to
struggle a little bit and uh it's no
wonder people see the world differently
and many of us would probably agree that
some of those differences in general are
being agitated or exploited and people
are being weaponized and propagandized
in battles over social control and
political power
frankly
i can understand why authoritarians may
find it to be an efficient strategy to
just make up people's minds for them by
strictly controlling information access
confining their experiences
propagandizing people into tribes heard
mentality or coercing conformity and
therefore restricting belief formation
and incentivizing decision making as a
social control and political power
mechanism
uh as opposed to just trying to get
hundreds of millions of people to
find consensus together that seems like
a very difficult thing to do especially
when people don't necessarily have the
bandwidth of attention to all zoom into
the same sets of information that are
scattered across different forms of
content
however uh my hope is that
our work at the society library will
make a contribution towards improving
that and causing change long term in
part by building and hopefully
democratizing access to new tools that
can augment our perception of reality in
order to increase comprehension
comprehension of at least as a starting
point the varying points of view that
exist on issues that divide us which can
be rendered in new formats so we can
make more informed free inclusive and
less biased decisions about political
issues if we choose to if we want to
opt-in of course
with such tools i'm hoping that we can
more easily see our blind spots see each
other's views and come to understand why
some of us see black or gold pink or
green or red or blue
so now part two i would love to talk
about and show you some of the work of
the society library a little bit and
then i'll talk about some open inquiries
we have about enabling comprehension
essentially i am really curious about
how far we could go augmenting our
intelligence and comprehension with tech
yay so let's talk about work
um
again the society library is a
non-profit organization
and we are dedicated to improving
humanity's relationship to information
that's our big vision we do a bunch of
things from building political
decision-making models to advising on
the creation of legislation providing
educational curricula to various
universities and training professionals
in our research methods but today i want
to talk about how we build libraries of
knowledge that are structured as
societal scale debates
in building these libraries our goal is
not to coerce someone into seeing a
specific world view or to arrive at a
specific outcome
we are just looking to collect and
compress knowledge to make wickedly
complex debates comprehensible we want
everyone to be able to see from
different points of view make that
actually possible
and um for the first time for some
make uh increased comprehension
regarding the validity depth complexity
and variety of points of view on issue
accessible as well as enabling the
comprehension of new concepts and
nuanced context of relevant knowledge uh
we will see some of the things that
prevent comprehension
uh i would say that includes as i
mentioned before limits in time
attention empathy patience and access to
information so what we're specifically
doing in the tech i'm about to show you
is save users thousands of research
hours and finding new ways to compress
knowledge so that we can start seeing
eye to eye a little bit more
but then i'm going to talk about limits
to that approach because of course there
always are
okay oh one more thing before i show you
the library collection a little
background how we build these libraries
is we actually extract arguments claims
and evidence from books textbooks
scholarly works government documents
television podcasts websites
documentaries and social media
consolidate that content into a database
in which we structure the data itself as
a debate between all points of view last
time i spoke at hope i talked about our
climate change collection
but today i would like to show you a
state level issue having to do with
nuclear energy so let's dive in
it's going to auto play okay
so here's the visualization of a
database that we've built the database
shows the different points of view that
people take on the last remaining
nuclear power plant in california called
diablo canyon diablo canyon's two
nuclear reactors are set to be
decommissioned in 2024 and 2025. some
people believe that diablo canyon should
remain open and others believe it should
be closed at uh face value it may look
like it's a polarized issue there's only
two decisions open closed um however
what we've found using our methods and
extracting knowledge from over 4 000
references including government
documents and newspapers and blogs and
petitions and yada yada we found that
there's about nine positions that people
take on this issue and our work is to
map out the arguments claims and
evidence that support and refute those
nine positions um i'm not confident in
my ability to switch and give you a live
demo i don't like destroying
the the flow that we're in um but as you
can see what we've got here is uh
conditions in which it should be opened
or closed so oftentimes we're forced to
be binary it's either open it's closed
it's red it's blue it's yay or nay pro
and con but in actuality in reality when
we really dive into what people think
there are oftentimes only conditions in
which someone will agree to something so
for example there is a position that
people take where they want diablo
canyon the last remaining nuclear power
plant in california to remain open only
if the current utility that operates it
no longer operates it because they're
deeply concerned about safety oversight
all these different things
some people argue that it should remain
open only if it becomes a polygeneration
plan or only if it gets certain upgrades
and things like that so what's really
important i think and what has been
called mindset breaking by some people
who've interacted with our work is that
we start to break down the polarization
because things are oftentimes not binary
even with that dress it's not just
people see it as black and uh blue or
gold and white there's actually people
who see it in a lot of different colors
which is fascinating and it's similar
and we should keep that in mind with a
lot of our different social problems
moving on we're going to dive into
actually uh this is just to kind of show
like highest level view we're gonna dive
down one little logical pathway and i'm
gonna show you both we're gonna zoom out
and see the breadth of it as well as the
depth of this argumentation because
again the whole purpose of these tools
is to start augmenting the way we see
social problems if we're interacting
with not databases of 4 000 different
references but instead just a news
article here or there a podcast here or
there it's very limited information that
we're being given and so what we're the
work that we're trying to do is greatly
expand our comprehension of complexity
of these problems
uh so let's take a walk down just one
argument pathway in support of just one
position
there we go okay position one states
that diablo cannons should be
decommissioned as scheduled due to a
variety of different reasons uh in part
because there are so many or because
there's so many arguments to support and
refute this position we've clustered
arguments by category so we have
economic environmental safety energy
related ethical and political
these are extremely high level
categories and because there's so many
very high level arguments underneath
these we've clustered them under these
categories but these claims that you're
seeing here are also very high level
vague arguments this one for example
says market forces financial incentives
and policy decisions have made the
diablo canyon nuclear power plant
redundant non-competitive and
undesirable that's made of a number of
different claims here's one specifically
about it being non-competitive and
financially undesirable due to supply
and demand we can unpack that further we
get into economic assessments and
argumentation about the specific impact
of various different things happening in
the economy that would impact the
viability of the plant that can break
down further there are papers that
respond to that and as you can see
there's pro and con argumentation
arguing over the veracity and relevance
of this data and so the work that we do
is just in collecting all of this
different knowledge that's spread
through different forms of media through
time from different groups and
organizing that as a societal scale
communication for us this is just a
state level issue um here i am
on the video unpacking just the
different sections so like that was a
very high level vague
economic claim that we just traveled
down but here i'm unpacking all the
other categories so we have economic
we've got environmental we've got safety
we've got energy related we've got
ethical and educational and we've got
political and as soon as i'm done
unpacking these
i'll zoom up and down and you'll
actually see like even the most vague
high-level arguments that people may be
like flippantly making on podcasts
can be full of knowledge and
argumentation about whether or not it's
correct
and so the work that we've done in this
particular database and thank goodness
this isn't how we render it for the
public although you can actually access
this if you want i personally love the
debate map view um you can see it's just
unbelievable amounts of knowledge and so
the purpose of visualizing it this way
is to be able to really easily zoom out
and see the complexity and volume
and hopefully that's a little bit mind
mindset shifting but we also render in a
different way where we deeply compress
all of this knowledge to make it a
little bit more comprehensible and then
also focus in on how do we contextualize
these claims provide really important
indicators as to certain dimensions and
characteristics of that
so we will move on
and do that now
okay so um this is a more readable
narrative form this is uh what we call
society library papers it is all of the
knowledge of the database but compressed
into narrative form so instead of the
claims being in each little node
they could be partial clauses in
sentences that read literally as a
series of papers that you can unpack so
here's an example of that
so here that's the first position and
all the categories are actually in line
and you can unpack
instead of unpacking trees you can open
it up uh not only by unpacking it as
you'll see here these are supporting
argumentation but you can also open each
and every single one of these claims
into like a wikipedia style
page full of knowledge about where did
that claim come from and there's
information about like uh what type of
media sources it came from we do backups
in the internet archive so even if one
of the links disappears you can go and
find it there's some additional
references so essentially you can check
the integrity of our work you can find
the original context and quote in which
that claim was expressed and a bunch of
other information on each one of these
pages um
since i recorded this ahead of time
let's see oh yeah and then we also have
this feature where you can opt into
different expressions so you can opt
into technical or simple versions of
each one of these paragraphs we still
have a little bit of work to do fleshing
those out but essentially like that's
another one of our features of enabling
comprehension which is what this is
about is like if you're reading some
technical claim about an economic
assessment
and it's using terminology with which
you're not familiar you can just flip to
the left and read a fourth grade reading
level like version of that or perhaps
you're an economist and you really want
to know that they're using a specific
model like the implant model you can
flip to the right and you can actually
see a much more detailed explanation of
that particular economic argumentation
and so this is just an example of how
like we're trying to pull in and
compress this knowledge uh to make uh
comprehension of these really complex
things actually possible in a format
that's really familiar
um but of course i mean haven't we moved
on from text on paper we're like in the
land of tick tocks and tweets and
multimedia stuff and the metaverse is
coming so even though the society
library is starting by just kind of
reinventing the piece of paper what's
amazing about the databases that we're
creating is i have no doubt that one we
will be able to render it in much more
vivid interactive and experiential
knowledge but i think we'll also have to
um
and
i mean yes more more and more diverse
ways to visualize knowledge are possible
so i'm not concerned about that i think
it's very easy for us to just give away
the data and designers can render it
however they wish and i hope there's
lots of experimentation and iteration to
make sure that uh it's meeting those
goals of it being comprehensible but
what i am concerned about which is a
part of what this talk is about is the
ethics of inducing comprehension
uh how do we decide what information
should be expressed to a level of
vividness you know what if it's too
impactful what if it's too persuasive
there's so many pitfalls
uh i imagine many people here who work
in security are aware of the nefarious
ways to force someone to comprehend
something through manipulation ways to
coerce someone to change their mind or
come to a conclusion without necessarily
having their consent this is very
popular in politics there are people who
hit the streets who have mastered
techniques to make people doubt their
own beliefs and you know i'm not saying
that's wrong or change their mind or
things like that politics is a is a
power game and so the society library's
not interested in that we're interested
in serving information needs without
being coercive so part of this talk is
me bringing to you all this ethical
conundrum of how do we figure out the
right way of visualizing this knowledge
without accidentally prioritizing
something and being persuasive we
thought a lot about it there's policies
on our website they're rendered as
google docs please give us feedback but
uh we're gonna talk about something in
particular um some of the tactics before
i move on though include like compelling
disinformation agenda setting
manipulative language appeals to
personality and psychographic makeup
outright repetition negging bots to
drive perception of consensus by playing
on tribal or in-group desirability deep
fakes and then like have any of you seen
that magic trick where
a magician will come up to you and then
they'll
engage in conversation but what they're
really doing is seeding everything that
they're saying with movie titles and
famous movie quotes where they're
actually like building a semantic web in
your brain so that you're thinking of
the lead actor of all of those movies
without them ever explicitly stating it
and then they ask you like to think of
an actor and of course you think of that
person because your brain that's how
your brain generates information and
they pretend to read your mind and it's
like
yeah that's manipulation too um and
obviously the easiest way to go about
avoiding these pitfalls in the work that
we do is just like not executing any of
these strategies intentionally but uh
they're also tough calls that we have to
make like who decides what language is a
dog whistle or not how do you go about
contextualizing content so that is
represented in a deliberation but not
given extreme undue weight how do you
give people enough information to induce
comprehension without coercing people to
a conclusion there's an argument to be
made that technology is not neutral and
that means it's important to be clear
about the intentions of the tools that
we make
at the society library our intentions
for producing these libraries are to
enable comprehension and appreciation of
the legitimate nuance and complexity of
our social and political issues we want
our tools to give people a new site to
overcome their blind spots that are
inherent simply because there's too much
information spread all over the web in
the world no one has the time to like
map all the knowledge that we have we've
saved you 6 000 hours of research just
by creating that database it certainly
won't take you that long to read it all
and
in giving people this new site it's both
the google earth and street view of the
issue
and we're hoping that what this does is
inspire increased intellectual humility
depolarize and de-radicalize attitudes
increase curiosity increase resilience
to disinforming content and we also hope
our products and services will increase
subject matter knowledge these are the
things that we're aiming for and of
course can test for but
this is where the talk turns from a kind
of like show and tell about what we're
doing
um and more of an open inquiry beyond
comprehension my question is can we
induce wisdom
i imagine many of you in this room have
read sci-fi or fictional stories in
which wise sages are depicted um so does
anyone want to tell me what are some
characteristics of like the wise oracle
the y sage the wise guide
yes
experience okay
fantastic so understanding all the
different points of view at the table
and the arguments that support them as
to why yep okay
not having a dog in the fight so an
objectivity interesting yes
no interest in fighting very interesting
anyone else yes
good question does anyone not have a dog
in the fight
fair
well everyone
great answers i'm going to add a few
myself just to weave it into the talk
i'm going to say they can perceive of
multiple points of view that's kind of
what this gentleman over here was
talking about
understanding the big picture
are able to make accurate predictions
and then i also want to add and i think
this is actually very important
empathize and comprehend emotions values
and culture
so i actually think that feelings are a
very like important distinguishing
feature to wisdom i think a wise one for
example may understand the frustration
of a young padawan predict the pettiness
of an enemy or empathize with the
devastation of the loss of another
and i am wondering if inducing wisdom
must include inducing a comprehension of
feeling and that's where we get to that
kind of like tricky part because
removing kind of feelings is a way of
removing bias to knowledge and yet if
comprehension of feeling is important to
that greater understanding that wisdom
how do we go about doing that ethically
and carefully
especially when sometimes the feelings
that are necessary in order to
understand a situation can be like
really harmful and traumatizing or
actually just like impossible to
understand
so perhaps to a certain extent fiction
can actually be a safe wisdom-inducing
psychotechnology by reading or watching
a story we can gain understanding
compassion empathy and insight and it
may improve our judgment i can at least
go far as to say that uh media can be a
feeling inducing thing we can even be
forced to feel things uh
based on completely imaginary things i i
simply like cannot not cry when i re
like watch one of those wholesome pixar
movies does anyone ball like a baby at
pixar there's a few yes that just i'm on
a plane i don't want to cry and it
forces me i can't help it it just
strikes me with it and then also uh i
will also forcibly acquire tons of
nightmare fuel if i watch something like
texas chainsaw massacre so like the
vividness of media which it seems like
hollywood has really mastered can induce
a comprehension of something but what's
kind of odd about that is that it can be
completely irrational it can be based on
completely imaginary things and maybe
that's not the thing we want to be
angling toward but maybe there are
things that we can borrow from film and
vivid visual media to induce
comprehension of other things
yeah and the thing that i'm concerned
about especially when we're dissecting
uh
documentaries and the videos that people
make when they're warring over political
issues that slowly what that's doing is
building up strong emotional priors that
may be really difficult to overcome we
saw earlier in the beginning priors can
be
like very impactful in terms of how we
perceive things and so like should we be
more careful about the type of media
that we're absorbing into our psyche
i think art to a certain extent is
provocative and irresponsible
so thank goodness a lot of movies at
least in hollywood have trigger warnings
so we can avoid the nightmare fuel
but i also think that there's an
opportunity to start translating complex
civic knowledge into vivid rich media
interactions that could induce emotional
comprehension and potentially wisdom
through visual stimulation story and
media perhaps we could hack our way to
opt-in wisdom what would be the costs
would there be trauma could we make it
an informed consensual process does some
designer have to know what wisdom is
meant to be derived or isn't that
coercive or do we just need to make
knowledge vivid visceral experiential
what are the pitfalls will it be so
powerful that we'll need emotional
trigger warnings where could this go
wrong who decides what gets amplified or
should anyone do anything
uh in our database about diablo canyon
for example there are arguments about
the degradation of pipes and so would it
be ethical for us to highlight and
suggest that readers definitely look at
these photos how do we know that this
wouldn't be disproportionately
persuasive are the visuals important to
comprehending the nature of the
perceived and argued threat of the state
of the uh nuclear power plant and then
in the database also we have a long
timeline of incidents when pg e's
negligence has led to death and
destruction is it important to those who
are advocating that diablo canyon should
remain open but not be managed by pg e
that people look at these videos of the
fires and see the faces of the people
who have died in explosions and
disasters or is that too traumatizing is
that extraneous and unnecessary is it
too biasing because of how impactful
feelings are in our sense making and
decision making there are so many
pitfalls so many ways to err into bias
perception which is totally antithetical
to our mission even a single word can
accidentally add undue weight and then
there is the impossibility of accounting
for how people's priors can shape how
people perceive the things that they are
seeing i can't imagine it all can be
accounted for and yet if we even
marginally increase the wisdom of people
in general what kind of impact would
that have
well i'm afraid i probably left you with
way more questions than answers sorry
about that it was again a very late
night
but i think that we do have a series of
important questions to consider like
is it possible to augment human
intelligence to help people overcome
biasing priors in order to see problems
and solutions in new light but also in a
manner that isn't meant to just overtly
coerce or persuade if we were to design
technology to help us hack our way to
wisdom what kinds of emotional costs and
demands would that require i'm not sure
we at the society library would ever
dare to assume that we would know the
way to wisdom but beyond enabling
comprehension of the knowledge we're
working with today it seems like the
highest ideal of knowledge management
work so we would love to hear any ideas
you may have hackers
and thanks for listening
[Applause]
i think we have time for questions in
case any of y'all have any
yes
well my
um you know my job is pretty much not to
have opinions on the things that we map
um and i will say diablo canyon is a the
first collection we will actually be
releasing because it is the only one
that has reached what we call meaningful
completion climate change covid19
election integrity these other topics
that we've worked on are
unbelievably enormous and what the
society library is really trying to do
is set a new kind of standard for rigor
i mean like there's like
a threshold of how rigorous people are
when they're forming their arguments
scholarly papers tend to perform the
best that i've seen government
documentation news and journalism kind
of falls underneath i'm constantly
shocked by like sub-standards of people
not sourcing their references and things
like that so the society library is
really trying to just like
introduce a new level of rigor a new
almost kind of language for how to talk
about our problems that is so
ridiculously comprehensive that we're
really trying to raise the bar so the
diablo canyon issue is a state level
issue and is something that we've been
able to fundraise enough
to reach meaningful completion and are
releasing everything else still needs a
lot more work because
they're international issues they are
enormous
yes
yeah that's a fantastic question and
you're so perceptive i don't know how
much information i revealed but you hit
the nail on the head right now we are
working on issues of contemporary
importance that are oftentimes fleeting
right now we're focused on high-impact
persistent polarizing issues in the
english-speaking united states having to
do with human rights resource management
et cetera but really the society library
is a very long-term institution i'm
concerned with i mean we've named
ourselves the society library because
i'm concerned with the knowledge
infrastructure that future generations
are going to be growing up with we have
old institutions that have not yet been
fully digitized and yet if we just
directly digitize them which is a lot of
what we've seen we've directly digitized
the newspaper we've directly digitized
the book we've maintained a lot of the
structure and format i think that's
inherently limiting so what the society
library is looking to do is what are our
information needs and what are the
technologies that we have at our
disposal to just like greatly amplify
the ability to induce comprehension
account for comprehensiveness yadda
yadda so really the work that we're
doing now is because it falls within our
mission people are willing to fund it
because they're interested in near-term
present issues but really a lot of it is
just r d to developing the pipeline for
ingesting knowledge processing knowledge
the ontological development and long
term
i think potentially even in my lifetime
depend because of how unbelievable ai is
accelerating with chain of thought
reasoning and things like that
i think we'll be able to see live
libraries being generated in my lifetime
which i you know would be an absolute
dream come true but there's a number of
different issues if you go to our
website you can see like the full scope
of the different topics that we would
cover and um i think also that some
issues are probably going to be
persistently problematic especially
around values and culture so those ones
are things that we also cover and most
likely we'll be mapping those things for
a while
yes yes yes
go ahead yes
biases but oh so we're actually
radically inclusive so we have 22
different methods for overcoming our own
research biases and essentially the
service that the sci library is
rendering or one of the services is that
we undertake the work of doing a lot of
steel manning so like even if something
seems like really obscure or extraneous
we
and like low quality content we treat
those like hints and we spend a lot of
time still mending then trying to find
evidence for it like for example there
was this one claim in the diablo canyon
database uh people persistently on
facebook and in blogs and even in news
articles would just persist this idea
that 1.5 billion fish would get i
believe was in trained and like boiled
and killed every year in the diablo
canyon cooling system and we just
couldn't find evidence for it and i was
beginning to think like perhaps it was
just a persistent myth we couldn't track
down the providence
eventually we found where the data came
from and what's really wonderful is that
now there's like this centralized source
where there's so many different people
who have referenced that number and now
there's a citation that they can just
link to um so we actually spend a lot of
time like steel manning content we've
got virtues and values on our page that
guide our orientation towards um
the information that we're interacting
with essentially we consider our duty to
leave no intellectual stone unturned and
in general the culture of libraries is
to be radically inclusive
i encourage you all to check out the
american library association's library
bill of rights libraries are super
radical they're like ridiculously
anti-censorship it's like pretty awesome
so we borrow a lot of that culture and
have imbued it in our own research
methods
and we have found consistently time and
time again that even if someone
immediately discounts an idea or like we
hear someone bring up an idea that
sounds ridiculous if you just spend a
little bit of time digging maybe the way
in which that claim was expressed wasn't
the best representation of the sentiment
and is technically wrong but if you do a
little bit of digging like it may just
actually be a representation a malformed
representation of something that is
substantial and it probably is important
that that could get surfaced and we're
grateful to the people who whether it's
on a conspiratorial website or an
uncited rant online for bringing that to
our attention
yes
uh
is
great okay so let me try and restate um
the gist of what you asked um so correct
me if i'm wrong but you are asking
essentially uh you know how do we
balance like arguments about
moral conscience and values and things
like that uh in comparison to collecting
facts and data and whatnot is that about
right
yeah great
so perfect uh so there's a very specific
reason why i use the words arguments
claims and evidence and that's because
claims can be facts or opinions they
could be moral arguments or they could
be you know evidence-driven arguments um
claims can be fact opinion right or
wrong doesn't matter they're just claims
they're assertions that something is
true and someone can assert that it is
morally right or morally true that
something is done or not done and in
fact for the diablo canyon content in
that position one almost every single
position has an entire ethics section
where people argue about the ethics of
something um which can be moral it can
be religious i don't know if i know of
any particularly like religious
arguments in the nuclear powerpoint one
but it's again we're very interested in
being radically inclusive because what
we're trying to do is create a one
centralized repository library where
someone can say listen i really want to
know all dimensions of this issue and
all dimensions definitely includes how
people feel about it the opinions they
have about it their morals their values
it has a specific section right and it's
identified as such unless that happens
to be evidence to support it and then
bam it's an evidence-driven claim
but those are important dimensions to
understanding ourselves as a collective
and functioning as a democracy people
cannot read those things if they choose
they don't have to read everything in
the library if they don't want to but i
think it definitely deserves
representation and so um how the second
part of your question how do we uh
promote that i mean
it's our human right actually as defined
by the united nations declarations of
human rights to have opinions and also
have religious beliefs i believe it's
article 18 and 19. so it is inherently
your human right to have an opinion have
a belief and like it does need to be
informed and no one has the right to
really like challenge or try to coerce
or change that um which is an ideal that
i don't think we have fully realized
because i think in order to realize the
freedom of like having opinions and
religious beliefs i think people should
have the freedom of choice to begin with
i think a lot of people inherit their
religious beliefs nothing necessarily
wrong with that but i think that even a
library of religious perspectives as it
relates to like fundamental
philosophical questions about the nature
of reality life in the universe
um could be something that people could
have access to so they can more freely
choose what they want to believe and
then that at least that's like a free
choice as opposed to i've inherited this
no one tried to take it away from me but
ultimately like it's all of our human
rights to believe whatever the heck we
want to believe
five minutes okay one more question yes
okay
uh
is
your question's about undue weight right
and like platforming things and giving
false equivalence does something look
like uh it has
weight it has validity just because it's
right next to something that you know
has a bunch of evidence and things like
that so uh i don't know if you saw in
the example but we actually do label
claims so if something has no evidence
there's a there's a whole taxonomy of
different things where we describe
something that we haven't been able to
find evidence for it could be that no
evidence was provided no evidence was
found yet we need to look for evidence
so there's like a whole like set of ways
in which we label and contextualize data
because we are also concerned with that
if people are just like reading at face
value all of these claims and absorbing
them right what is that doing to their
priors especially if they happen to
already like have uh an inclination to
believe a specific thing so we actually
put notes in front of things so people
see like this is a logical fallacy this
is cherry picked data this is outdated
we've not been able to find any evidence
for this this is so vague it's actually
not fact checkable like we let people
know and then as you unpack things you
can also see you know counter
argumentation and what the counter
argumentation is made out of so i mean
this visualization the paper
visualization is one of our our first
iterations of how to express this
knowledge i have no doubt and it is my
hope that we will partner with designers
that will make these things more obvious
um because this is all very important
right and this is kind of like getting
to the gist of the talk is like how do
we go about enabling comprehension
there's so many facets of absorbing
knowledge that are really important that
we really need to be careful about in
order to get as much knowledge in
without
like causing someone to end up at a
certain conclusion or manipulating their
thoughts so it's like just i think we're
at the dawning of like a new era an
enlightenment era of knowledge
management and consolidation and
presentation
and um yeah i'm hoping there's just so
much more to come so thank you so much
for your concern we also have it
yes quickly
so
sorry can you say that one more time
or attributes
so our um
we don't necessarily drive anyone to a
conclusion however
the society library does build political
decision-making models so we work at the
city council level we essentially
execute our method by extracting
arguments claims and evidence from
various forms of medium and instead of
rendering it as debate maps what we do
is we break down every single dimension
of a decision which can be along
categorical lines like economic or
social or whatever sometimes it can be
much more precise like those high level
like vague orientations underneath
economic and safety and those things
that you saw
and what we do is we show them here's
the packet of pro con argumentation in
each one of those dimensions and then we
visualize that so they essentially micro
vote i've got a talk on our website
about how we do this and we actually
give away a tool kit for making your own
decision making models so one of the
things that we do want to do is take our
decision making model process digitize
that and then make that an interface
through which our data can be rendered
so we're not going to tell anyone the
decision that they should make right
because
some of the stuff is pretty subjective
and value driven like do you value
safety do you not care about the
reputation of the utility like that's
kind of subjective but if someone
actually wanted to go through the
process of methodically going through
all of this knowledge we happen to have
a process for that and it just takes
them through step by step um so we're
hoping to raise some funds actually
we've got proposals out for that to be
the next iteration of an interface for
people to opt into and what's really
cool about that is that once people go
through the process they don't have to
remember the decision that they made in
the black box of their minds going
through potentially thousands of
arguments instead it mirrors back to
them once you have gone through the
process of looking at every dimension
this is what you decide along economic
environmental safety lines and that's my
time thank you all so
[Applause]
and you much as long as you want okay
thank you
you