[Music]
good morning again welcome to the seven
o'clock session
uh just a reminder that if you have your
phones put them on vibrate
if you uh you see the exit signs in case
of emergency
follow the exit signs if you have some
other type of emergency follow someone
or talk to someone who has a radio or
who is wearing a blue volunteer shirt or
a security on the back of their shirt
keep yourself hydrated there's water
fountains around the corner right now
we're going to introduce the panel for
the cfa
the cfaa has come a long way or has it
it'll be a hour and 50 minutes the
unfortunately the session on batteries
is um
has been canceled
due to some emergency so this panel will
be taking extended time
right now i'd like to introduce alex or
bellis he'll be moderating tonight's
panel
entitled the cfa has come a long way or
has it
alex is a cyber security attorney with
the law firm of cromwell warning and
previously served as a chief information
security officer of the national
football league this federal service
includes positions with the central
intelligence agency couldn't just say
cia
the u.s army jag corps
the u.s court of appeals and the armed
forces alex is a member of the
technology advisory board for human
rights
first
and
the ul security council and the
uniformed law commission committee for
the study of cyber crime
alex's published works can be found in
the financial times cnn the philadelphia
inquirer
the intercept and of course 2600
magazine alex
well thank you very much everybody
appreciate it
good evening new york how is everybody
everyone good and we're excited about
hope it's the first night of hope we're
we're all here in person this is really
exciting we've got a lot of people
joining online as well
i'm really excited to introduce a really
uh just a talented
you know multifaceted and i just think
absolutely
fantastic panel that we're going to have
here tonight talking about cutting edge
issues with the computer fraud and abuse
act and just by
by show of applause how many people here
have heard of the cfaa or the computer
fraud and abuse act
okay all right yeah or booze i guess
right but you know we're here to bridge
the gap and so to speak
so
i want to first introduce right to my
left uh sagar ravi so sagar is the
co-chief of the complex frauds and cyber
crime unit at the u.s attorney's office
for the southern district of new york
just uh across the river over there
and he has supervised and worked on
matters involving computer intrusions
national security cyber issues dark web
markets cryptocurrency money laundering
investigated you know lots of different
types of frauds and it's just a
all-around great guy and a fantastic
attorney we're lucky to have him to his
left is joel dicaprio
joel is a supervisory special agent in
the fbi cyber division
his day job consists of chasing a wide
assortment of ransomware affiliates
money launderers and online scammers and
joel enjoys spending his free time
tinkering like most of us researching
sharing knowledge about network security
and uh according to him writing terrible
code so you know not not my own
characterization and via zoom i hope
that we can see jay at some point or do
we there he is all
right our handsome face there jay so we
also have joining via zoom today
unfortunately we had some some uh
mechanical issues on the way here but
jay we have jay cramer and jay is the
managing director of the national cyber
forensics training association in new
york
jay is also a former supervisory special
agent with the fbi
and nobody's perfect jay is also a
lawyer
so
with that i want to jump into the panel
and and also level set here for a second
because uh
the next panel had cancelled so we don't
really have a time limit we're gonna go
on for a little while longer hopefully
and and be able to take more questions
and hopefully have answers to those
questions so let's jump right into it
on the 19th of may
this year there was a major development
with the department of justice they had
revised their guidelines for the
computer fraud and abuse act where
prosecutions with regard to the computer
fraud and abuse act and
to my knowledge i think this is the
first time that they have revised those
guidelines in about 10 years
and
what
was a major change here was that now
accessing a computer for the purpose of
good faith security research
was no longer is no longer to be
considered a prosecutable offense so
this is a major
and
development and could have a huge impact
on our community
ranging from how we collect cyber threat
intelligence to how we go about
defending our networks and and how we
research and even remediate security
vulnerabilities so there's some really
exciting stuff we're about to dig into
and we're going to have some really
interesting hypothetical scenarios in
which we'd all like you to participate
towards the end of this
but let's start here at the top even
though you do have familiarity with the
cfaa i want to pass it over to our
colleague online here to jay kramer and
and ask you jay
what uh can you tell us background wise
about the computer fraud and abuse act
from your perspective as a lawyer and as
a
fbi agent
yeah sure uh and thanks it's great to be
here i apologize for not being there in
person but thrilled to be here remotely
so uh computer fraud abuse act uh title
18 usc 1030
is has multiple parts but really is the
primary tool
used to counter hacking activity
a primary tool used by the federal
government fbi others
to uh
to uh enforce um or to pro to counter
hacking activity so
it has an interesting legislative
history
um for those of you who have seen
the film
war games going back to 1983 i'd ask for
a show of hands but i don't think i'd be
able to see that
um
matthew broderick high school student
stumbles upon
an enclave
the war gaming dod enclave and all kinds
of chaos ensues well
the then president at the time ronald
reagan
saw the film
and was so concerned with this kind of
activity
that he implored congress to act
and to pass a bill to criminalize
this activity a bill that he would later
sign in 1984.
so
um
reality in some cases is a bit stranger
than fiction and that was the impetus
for the passage of of cfaa
in in 1984
and significantly and we'll talk about
this throughout our session here
there were or there are a couple of
terms that are not defined in the
statute
uh and that's
two significant terms unauthorized
access
and exceeds authorized access
so neither of those which are key
components of the statute
are defined and that's led to really
almost
40 years or so or so of split authority
and and confusion that has been
addressed recently through this doj
guidance and some supreme court action
fantastic thanks jay joel what about you
as an active fbi agent your experience
with the cfa anything to add to what
jade mentioned so yeah so first i just
want to say thank you for for having me
um i am spot the fed on easy mode with
my suit jacket but surprisingly no one
came up to me and said hey you know
you're the fed i win the prize um so
maybe maybe after the talk now that i've
outed myself i'm expecting people to to
approach me um so cfaa so a little bit
of inside baseball with the fbi we don't
call it the cfaa we call it 10 30 10 30
is the actual
part in the u.s code that if you want to
find the language that was enshrined
with the cfaa it is section 18 usc
1030. um
i work cybercrime
and 1030 is one of the basic tools that
we use that
gives us authority from congress to
um investigate network intrusions
and as a
investigator the types of things that
i'm concerned about with the with uh you
know interpreting
1030 is um there's certain elements you
need to hit so for instance um protected
computer
if a victim or a complainant comes to us
and says hey uh we've been affected by a
network intrusion i've got to think to
myself is this a protected computer
under the statute and then if that
element is is
met then i move on and um
i have to look well was did someone
exceed the authorization they had if if
the the target had authorization to be
on the computer did they actually exceed
it and then the third
major prong is um did someone
not have authorization to access the
computer and that's basically like how
detailed we get i'm not an attorney and
so my job is just to bring the facts of
an incident and then let the
attorneys and the prosecutors do their
job to interpret what prongs of
10 30 are actually met for a um
for charges so also i'm i'm the only
non-attorney that's on stage here so i'm
kind of i see myself as the foil um
so i have a copy of 18 us code 1030 here
and
i'm reading it and i'm realizing that
when it was originally written it was
probably written by people that
had never used a computer
and so you get some really interesting
terms and definitions and you go through
it and there's
it's it's pretty long and you see that
there's indentations and you go through
it and it says if this you know then you
know skip to here and there's lots of
like ands and ors like if this and this
or that and then for definitions you
have to go to a separate part of the us
code to find definitions of stuff and
and it's confusing reading it and but
going through it as a layperson
i had a very similar feeling to when i'm
reviewing like code like like like
python or c
um and i came to realize that you can
read 1030 it has if statements
it has um lots of if else else if and
then it has the variables in the the
actual definitions um
so
just in general when i think about 10 30
it's confusing it's kind of like i would
refer to it as a spaghetti code that was
written in
1980s um
i i wish it was a little bit more more
clear for for the purposes of just
allowing people to understand what is
across the line and
easier for someone like me that has to
actually gather the facts and and
present them to prosecutors to
understand better um what actually meets
the the illegal conduct um
so my day-to-day focus though
a lot of the things i investigate it's
ransomware it's things that are very far
across the line um with loss amounts in
the
you know tens of thousands of dollars if
not the millions of dollars and so we
don't really have very much gray area
with with 1030 there isn't a whole lot
of debates about whether or not um
someone interfering with an election
system is actually um in violation of 10
30. so
like i said my job is just to gather the
facts and 1030 is just the tool given to
us by congress
to help us investigate network
intrusions
i love the analog that you made between
coding and the conditional statements
that were found in in 1030 and cfaa is
fantastic sagar i want to pass it over
to you to talk about any any kind of
lingering issues with the cfaa that you
want to bring up
thank you and thank you for
you know to the to hope to having me
here really appreciate it the
opportunity to speak with you all i do
have to make a little copy at the
beginning which is something that is
very lawyerly but although i do am an
employee of the department of justice
my statements here today are my personal
opinions and do not represent those in
the department so with that i can talk
freely
so um
you know the so as a prosecutor so i'm
thankfully jay uh joel has my help when
he's interpreting
the section 1030 here uh but he's right
you know it is a very complicated
statute criminal law you know generally
can be
very complicated but i think on the
spectrum of complicated statutes 10 30
certainly is on the kind of more
complicated area
and
it has a complicated history right think
about this it was written in 1984 right
there hasn't been any technological
advances in computing since then right
so
it is a statute that we are applying
sitting here you know
more than 30 40 years later
and to apply to
you know hackers today who are causing
you know real harm and my job is to you
know is generally
applying the statute i think you know
joe is right in that
every day in terms of the conduct that
we're investigating in terms of the
calls that i get that we need to
investigate with the fbi it's it's not
really
um
it's not such a fine line between kind
of what's clearly legal and what's not
the statute is clear on a few things
they define something as what's a
protected computer and all that means
it's a computer that is connected to
interstate traffic which is almost every
computer these days right
um
but the exceeding authorized access and
what is acting without authorization was
very complicated
and
you know just last year the supreme
court actually ruled in a case uh kind
of explaining what is the exceeding
authorized access language
explaining what it was and i'll just go
in that briefly i think it might be
helpful i think so that was a that was a
case where you know prosecutors charge
uh effectively a law enforcement officer
who um has access to look up kind of
criminal history records of individuals
uh that's part of their general access
on their computer
however they were kind of paid on the
side to look up
uh the same records uh as a personal
matter for someone that they were kind
of doing a favor with
uh and so there are the prosecutors kind
of
working within the law of their circuit
which is the 11th circuit there's uh
more than a dozen circuits here in the
united states so each one has its own
kind of law that is binding on them and
working within that case law
that they decided that because
even though he had access to do this
because he was doing it for a personal
matter not for a law enforcement matter
that he was exceeding his authorized
access and therefore
violated the statute and so
prosecutors tried to bring that case
and i believe he was convicted at trial
so a jury of 12 found him guilty of that
statute of this statute
and it was appealed to the circuit court
and the circuit court affirmed based on
that but then the supreme court came in
last year and reversed
basically explaining that if you already
have access to something uh
and you're in even if you're not
supposed to look at it right for example
if you're at work
and you're using computer for work
but you decide to check your personal
bank account arguably that is also
exceeding
authorized access because you're only
supposed to be using your computer for
work based on your employment contract
but i think ultimately the supreme court
decided that that
conduct can't constitute a crime
under section 1030
because
you already had access to it i think
what the supreme court envisions would
be a violation of the exceeding
authorized access is if you have access
to a computer but you're blocked off for
example from a specific drive or a
folder
through technological means
and if you decide to somehow get around
that using someone else's passwords
using you know whatever tools you might
have available to you
through technology if you're able to get
past that and get into that folder or
that drive that would be exceeding
unauthorized access so authorized access
so that's so it is a very complicated
area supreme court came in and explained
it and we'll talk about that and the the
regulations and the policies that come
out but that's where it stands yeah
absolutely and i think also in the
supreme court that you know the
analogies that they made for things that
would not violate the cfa in this case
were really interesting i think didn't
they also mention like lying on a dating
profile you know would not violate the
cfa because there were circuit splits
about this
if i recall correctly that established
that you could violate 1030 if you
violated terms of service under certain
circumstances exactly so on your
match.com profile which i'm sure many of
you might have um
uh you know if you
lie about yourself technically under the
the the contract you sign with match
which is very fine print
and you kind of click in order to
actually get access to it no one
actually reads that we all know but
technically according to that if you lie
on your profile
you are automatically
violating their user terms and therefore
you no longer have should have access to
the website so there is a was a kind of
aggressive reading of the statute where
if you line your profile you therefore
no longer have access to
the site but if you continue on it
you're exceeding authorized access and
that was kind of something that the
supreme court kind of shut down uh with
its opinion yeah i mean it was a
fascinating case but still so many
things i think remain unanswered about
it now with this background about cfaa
out of the way i want to
keep with you for a second sagar and ask
you to talk about
what what are the role of guidelines in
the department of justice and and and
jay feel free to chime in here as well
because you might have some
familiarity with this so can you tell us
about the guidelines how do they bind
you where do they come from
yeah so the uh the guidelines come from
the office of the
deputy attorney general which is you
know effectively the person sitting
under merit garland but ultimately it
comes from the department of justice
that very head
and it's they all the guidelines it's
very long
if you want to search you can search for
the basically the justice manual if you
search google search for that you'll
find
all of the guidelines that are issued
and that provide what are uh you know
what they are which are policies to
guide prosecutors and the government um
as to how we should be exercising our
discretion when it comes to prosecuting
these types of crimes so you know they
are
what they are their policies we do look
at it very carefully they're very
important to us and they provide
guidance in exercising our discretion um
you know and we're we are required to
follow them
that said you know just to be very clear
there's language at the end of every
single guideline that explains that
these are internal procedures they're
intended solely for the guidance of our
attorneys and they're not intended to
and may not be relied on to create any
sort of right benefits substantive or
procedural that's enforceable at law uh
in any litigation
but it's important so let me let me
interrupt you there for one second
soccer too so so with that in mind the
guidelines
they're not necessarily binding
on any of the us attorneys any of the
prosecutors federal prosecutors and i
guess it's an important distinction you
made there too is that they don't
actually change the law right so this
the computer fraud and abuse act is
still the computer fraud and abuse act
10 30 is still 10 30. it's just how you
interpret or the facts that would give
rise to a crime correct and you know we
are the you know where department of
justice is part of the executive branch
like you know we're under the president
of the united states technically but the
courts are not bound by these guidelines
in any way
uh
and and neither is congress in any way
this is simply something in the
department of justice
uh that we have to follow great so so
alex
go ahead jay i was just about to bounce
over to you too
yeah yeah
one second if we could just interrupt
you we is it possible for you to switch
the hdmi input over to uh
to the laptop here for a second is we
actually have the guideline there we go
split screen all right fantastic jay
right what i was going to relate because
we're here in new york is an example
that really puts
this struggle to interpret those
guidelines and to use 1030 as a tool
in in context so
many of you may remember the cannibal
cop case yes
in new york gill valley gilberto valley
uh nypd officer i i think he was a
sergeant or a detective if i recall and
in his personal life he was engaged with
a couple of dozen others on a dark net
forum
that was focused on cannibalism
basically they would talk about it how
they would how they would like to find
people to eat
and it's really strange
to to even talk about something like
this but it turns out that after years
of engagement in this forum
his wife found
a trove of documents and communications
that indicated that by the way she was
on that list to be
captured and eaten at some point and she
was so concerned about it that she
reported it to the fbi
and after a long investigation it turns
out that gill valley the nypd police
officer
had used
some of the tools given to him
access to which he uh
he was entitled through nypd
to
identify and and run license plates uh
queries uh motor vehicle records for an
individual that he and his
co-conspirators had planned to
kidnap and and rape and torture and kill
and ultimately eat
so a really bizarre case but the
relationship to 10 30 is that
that by the way that woman ended up
being an undercover fbi agent so that
didn't work out so well for gil
but he was arrested and charged with
conspiracy to
commit kidnapping
and the violation of
title 18 section 1030
for his misuse of the computer uh
systems
and running those queries and you know
on the one hand and this i think is the
the teaching moment on the one hand
you would say wow well he was entrusted
as a new york city police officer to use
those systems to further his job and
fight crime i can't think of a better
case where he's exceeded
his authorized access to use that
those tools to find someone to kidnap
and torture and eat
but after being found guilty
by a jury after deliberation
that jury that verdict was set aside
for a number of rounds but regarding
uh the second circuit and soccer you
mentioned this that the circuits were
split and that's the struggle that we've
had with 10 30. the second circuit felt
that no basically in essence shame on
you if you authorize someone you give
someone access to a computer system
if they use it for a purpose that you
didn't intend
well that's on you you know be more
careful with who you entrust with access
that's not the intent that wasn't
congress's intent in passing 1030 it was
more to prevent people from accessing
systems that they had absolutely no
access to not for those that were going
to misuse the access
and interestingly in the case that we're
talking about here the supreme court
case
uh just decided last year the facts are
very similar right another
law enforcement officer using a system
he was entrusted to for a purpose
that wasn't intended and this time the
supreme court said in in the decision
that uh basically you
what the intent of that statute was
means that you have to access something
that
was entirely off limits off limits was i
think the term used in the majority
decision that
it's not that you were you entrusted
with access and you misused that access
it's something that you were never
intended to have
you know it's fascinating so many
presidential cases involve law
enforcement officers tangled up with 10
30 or the cfaa
i wanted i want to shift here and dive
right into the actual guidelines
themselves now let's read them
for the benefit of those all the way in
the back there so the new guidelines and
this is a small excerpt but i think
a relevant excerpt that we can focus on
here in terms of our analysis so the new
doj guidelines that came out on the 19th
of may
say this they say the government should
decline prosecution if available
evidence shows that the defendant's
conduct consisted of and the defendant
intended good-faith security research
now farther down the guidelines it also
defines good faith security research as
accessing a computer solely for purposes
of good faith testing investigation and
or correction of a security flaw or
vulnerability now remember these words
because they're going to be very
relevant to our hypotheticals that come
up a little bit later so and or
correction of a security flaw or
vulnerability that's an important one
where such activity is carried out in a
manner designed to avoid any harm to
individuals or the public and where the
information derived from the activity is
used primarily to promote the security
or safety of the class of devices
machines or online services to which the
accessed computer belongs or those who
use such devices machines or online
services so jay
can you can you keep going a little bit
here and talk to us a bit about
these guidelines how they would relate
to the private sector and then i want to
pass it back to to joel and saga
yeah so
you know as as the threat landscape has
grown here
and uh the threats are coming from all
sides they're financially motivated
threats
their nation-state threats there's a
whole community that's developed around
the response to these threats
so
we have security researchers we have
digital forensics folks incident
responders i'm sure many in the audience
touch
operate within those circles
and
the ability to lean forward let's put it
that way to lean forward to investigate
and engage and understand the adversary
is impacted by 10 30
because
there's been that lingering specter or
that concern that if i'm engaged
and
investigating a bad actor
and and on a network or a system
it the potential for me to run afoul of
section 1030 and you never know who who
is on the line so to speak there can be
undercover law enforcement officers and
there could be members of the
intelligence community or other security
researchers that report on me
as though i'm an active participant and
a bad actor so
i think that's the concern that for
years folks that are operating and
trying to be aggressive and understand
the threat landscape are concerned that
their activity could be construed as
exceeding authorized access
or
being unauthorized in some way
and and joel i want to pass it back to
you now what about
these guidelines has changed the way you
do your business or your viewpoints
so not much has changed to be perfectly
honest with you
first i just want to say
if you have an opportunity and if you're
interested i would seriously check out
the doj prosecution manual it goes into
great detail about the things that
prosecutors need to think about when
they're
negotiating a plea agreement or when
they're determining whether or not
someone
deserves to be charged with a felony or
a misdemeanor and it's written in simple
language unlike the the statutes
themselves and it's really descriptive
and
it's a level of transparency that um
they offer that in practice when we're
sitting when i'm sitting with
prosecutors and they're explaining to me
why they're going to allow someone to
plead to a misdemeanor or something but
i see them actually go through the steps
so it's not just something
in writing that is performative it's
something that they actually adhere to
and um
it's it makes it
really clear when you have when you
wonder um like why why did they why did
the department of justice choose to
prosecute a certain crime and not uh
some other crime um but in terms of the
guidance itself so after a careful
reading of the the recent guidance i
think i think it does two things
first it it codifies uh the van buren
decision that sagar talked about and
basically it it mirrors the language
that justice coney barrett writing in
the majority
um
talks about in in the supreme court
decision that
effectively narrows the cfaa and
clarifies some things it turns
it turns 10 30 into a um
a trespassing statute it's not just a
a break a policy statute you actually
need to trespass into somewhere that you
don't belong and so i think it gives a
lot of clarity
the other thing that it does is i
it gives comfort to security researchers
who are acting in good faith who are
doing their job and incident responders
who might be afraid of crossing some
line and exposing themselves to criminal
culpability
um yeah there's a lot of attorneys that
usually get involved when there is a
network security incident
and
in my experience incident responders
they they're hard chargers they're
aggressive they're trying to um
expel the attacker from their network um
they're trying to get their data back
they're trying to mitigate um
and a lot of times they they might come
up with ideas that are excessively
aggressive and then they they talk to
their their attorneys and the attorneys
will will talk them down and explain to
them why you need to be a little bit
more circumspect before you um hard
charge one example and
some of the some of the questions that
get risen are pretty silly like
for instance if an attacker creates a
dummy account on a linux machine that
they use for persistence
um
is the owner of that computer allowed to
go into that account and
look at what's actually in there or are
they breaking 10 30. now
for me and i'm like well that's like a
silly question if i go home right now
and i see that someone has created an
account on my computer that like it's my
computer i'm going to i'm going to
investigate i'm going to wipe that
account but those are the types of
questions when corporate attorneys get
involved and they start raising these
types of issues where they're really
worried about the
any liability that a company might face
so when i read the part about good faith
security research and good faith
investigation i like to think it's the
department of justice messaging to
corporate attorneys and and the folks
who are involved in these types of
matters and saying hey look
you're not going to be charged for this
you're not going to be charged with a
felony for
doing something in good faith in fact my
understanding of criminal statutes is
you actually have to have criminal
intent in order to be charged with a
crime doing something in good faith is
usually the antithesis even if you meet
all the other technical elements of the
statute if you're doing something in
good faith it's really hard
to prove that that person
actually committed a crime
so
um
i think the guidance is helpful i think
it's helpful for the general public but
it doesn't really change anything that i
do uh just because we're not we're not
interested and and
we're busy we're very very busy we're
turning down cases
um where there's real loss amounts and
real victims we're referring those cases
to
state and local law enforcement because
we just we don't have the resources to
address them and we certainly don't have
the resources nor do we want to pursue
anyone acting in good faith to include
investigators security researchers and
the like
now it's interesting you say that too
because there also seems to be a little
bit of push and pull here
because
you know sagar you mentioned
the deputy attorney general lisa monaco
she's the one that promulgates these
guidelines right so they filter down
now what she had said specifically about
these guidelines are that they are
intended to quote
focus the department's resources on
cases where a defendant is either not
authorized at all to access a computer
or despite knowing about a restriction
accessed part of a computer to which his
authorized access did not extend
so why so if joel if it was the case
then
that we're turning away cases where
there isn't the mental element or
there's there there was uh or rather
there wasn't an absence of good faith
there's real cases that you're turning
down
why then did these new guidelines have
to come out why did the attorney general
have to do that i guess maybe it's
perhaps because there's differences
between jurisdictions when when it comes
to the investigation of these types of
crimes so i'm not sure i suspect
i suspect it was twofold it was to
codify ban bureau and just formalize
that of that hey this is the new policy
now uh it's been the law of the land for
over a year but now we just want to make
it clear that it's also doj policy um
and i think the other reason is just uh
to message
uh from the top
that
we're not interested in going after good
faith researchers that like
that isn't as far as i know
there's been no targeting of good faith
security researchers now
there are bad faith security researchers
for sure
um
but there really hasn't been any
targeting it but they just wanted to be
very explicit when they when they
message um
what what prosecutors are supposed to
calculate when they're thinking about
whether or not there's criminal
liability yep and sagar i want to pass
it to you for comment on that too yeah
so i think that look after the supreme
court decision came out on the exceeding
authorized access issue i think there
was an opportunity
to take a hard look at these guidelines
and
revise them
excuse me and
i think you know really the good faith
researcher
language that was just stated is very
different than the exceeding authori
those are two different
entirely different issues and i so i
think
the fact that they were revising the
guidelines anyway they felt you know
again i cannot speak to why they
included at that time but i think it was
a recognition that good faith security
research is is really helpful to the
community
and in fact you know
the lisa monaco the deputy attorney
general said quote
computer computer security research is a
key driver of improved cyber security
the department has never been interested
in prosecuting good faith computer
security research as a crime
and today's announcement promotes cyber
security by providing clarity for good
faith security researchers who root out
vulnerabilities for the common good end
quote so
um and i think she's right i i don't
think
if you look at kind of history of all
the crimes that have been prosecuted
under 10 30 i think there's a couple
that where you know it's arguable that
it was a
good faith security researcher who was
prosecuted this is not an area where we
are spending a lot of our time and
resources at all
right again i think as joel mentioned we
have more than enough nation state
actors
extremely malicious actors to deal with
we don't have the resources to go after
good faith security researchers it's not
a priority and and this kind of is a
recognition of it and just to add to the
you know i don't think that these
guidelines changed anything
from my perspective because
again it is a defense under the law if
you're acting in good faith uh that's a
standard jury strict instruction that is
kind of given in every jury trial and so
this just
is messaging to the public that this is
something we value and in fact we
oftentimes look at
you know threat security reports and
things like that when we're trying to
also do our investigations of various
apts and things like that
so a lot of the information that's out
you know public publicly sourceable
information is very helpful in our
investigations and i think
it shows we value it but ultimately it
doesn't change anything what matters is
um you know what someone's intent is
which is kind of what the guidelines go
to and i think it's also helpful to
mention you know
the section 1030 prosecutes kind of
generally real harm right it's not just
accessing a computer without
authorization if you go through there
you have to
obtain information
you have to cause damage you have to
have the intent to defraud and obtaining
something of value of more than five
thousand dollars we have to recklessly
cause damage um causing loss
trafficking and passwords things like
that you know these are real
it's not just
accessing computer it's much more than
that so there's actual harm that needs
to be done and and your position and and
it seems like joel's too is that because
of this mental element what we would
call a law the men's real right you know
the
the mental thing
uh that has to be present
these guidelines don't really change all
that much would you agree jay
yeah yeah i i do and let me highlight
what what i think is the most important
part of this policy change because sagar
you and and
and joel have both said in different
ways joel i think you've said rightly
that this doesn't change the way you go
about your business you've got a lot
more work than you can ever do so
you have to decide what's the most
impactful and where the best use of your
time is same for the u.s attorney's
office
and i'll say i've spoken to a number of
people about this a lot of former
prosecutors who've said well you know
yes it's good that doj has come out with
this announcement this good faith
security research
exemption let's call it
but you know that in the reality this is
the way we've operated for many years so
i don't see it as a big deal
the the
the big deal part of it i think and joel
i think you said this well is that it
and you two sagar that it's a signal
to
not the security researcher that's just
trying to help his or her community or
those even maybe they're going after bug
bounties but the in-house
cyber threat intelligence teams that are
working at the large financial
institutions or the large pharmas or the
the multinational retailers they're
trying to stay ahead of the threats and
are trying to get authorization
internally
from their legal departments
to engage with bad actors on forums or
to access um
parts of
of networks that
they because of company policy may
require some pre-authorization
uh to
to get the green light to conduct those
intelligence gathering
uh operations and for them i think the
very conservative legal community in
those large organizations have said for
many years well we don't like the
overall risk that this brings by you
engaging in this kind of activity
because well for one it could violate
title 18 section 1030
or it could draw fire from the adversary
so you know it's too much risk we're not
comfortable with that risk coming on to
our large organization so
we're going to deny this request and
that's caused great frustration so
when you guys talk about a signal
i think
excuse me the u.s attorney's office and
doj
is signaling that this community is an
important player government can't do it
alone
private sector can't do it alone to stay
ahead of the threats here we need the
security researchers input and we want
to
in empower them
to to go ahead
and and help inform this broader
public-private partnership community
of what's going on and how to stay ahead
and and prevent and mitigate threats and
just uh one thing i'd like to add about
the importance of
security researchers and people you know
in the community the hackers folks in
this room um
some of the fbi's best investigations
really all of them
they usually have security researchers
who bring things to our attention hey
did you know about these cobalt strike
team servers
um did are you aware of this ransomware
panel that that is open to the public um
or it's people saying hey are you aware
that on exploit.in um there's something
they're selling a network to
a power plant or a hospital
and it's
extraordinarily valuable to us because
as the government we're encumbered by
you know just well being the government
and uh
um
we're not we're not allowed to
do as much
stuff as folks in in the private sector
um
we
things are very bureaucratic and there's
layers of approval and so we are slower
and less agile than than security
researchers so very often security
researchers are on the bleeding edge
of
information and
some of the best fbi cases that you read
about in the newspaper
um
they have security researchers who were
behind the whole thing that were
basically pointing us in the right
direction and giving extraordinary
assistance
i i i couldn't agree with you more um
i've
i've even you know helped fbi on
numerous occasions myself
but i want to ask a really tough
question
of all of you here on the panel now too
is that this is this will this won't get
a little contentious because on the one
hand we're saying we have to
we need this public-private partnership
essentially we need we need the help and
also
we don't want to go after good faith
security researchers
and and part of i think these new
guidelines is helping bridge that gap
where there was a gap
possibly because of some history
and that history i'm referring to is the
aaron swartz case which was a 10 30
charge and was a charge under the
computer fraud and abuse act and it was
a a really beloved and dear member of
our community
here and so i want to i want to ask all
three of you on the panel your your
thoughts about the aaron swartz case and
and whether the guidelines today would
have prevented that charge years ago
so why do i hand it over to sauger
uh yeah i mean certainly that
case was a tragedy uh
regardless of kind of anyone being
prosecuted no one wants that to result
that's never the goal
um
you know it's interesting i you know i
was reading up on it and i and kind of
reading up on the facts of that case and
i saw kind of two different versions
when i was reading up on it you know
online if you're just kind of generally
looking at things
it was about a guy who you know had
access to a computer
uh went and kind of used something to
download a lot more things than he
in a in a quicker way the academic
journals the jstor journal you know
downloading all these journals and
you know
any person can go into mit's campus and
go to a computer right and you know
access these journals and download them
and look at them and could do that he
used
a tool
uh forget exactly what he was using but
he used the tool that allowed him to
download you know it was like automated
downloading keep grabbing dot p y i
believe it's called there you go um uh
you know all you know i think it
ultimately allowed him to get four
million or so
uh and through so he had access and he
then used something to accelerate his
ability to get things but
under the van buren decision and the you
know it seems like that wouldn't
necessarily be something that could be
prosecutable right now however i
actually pulled up
the indictment
from the
district of massachusetts and typically
i was not involved in any way in
prosecuting this case
absolutely and in fact i think anybody
on this panel was at all involved in the
swartz case yeah
but it talks about how you broke into a
restricted wiring closet at mit
accessed it and then access the mit's
network without authorization with a
switch within that closet
and that's how he was able to connect so
look i i don't know what actually
happened
these are allegations in indictment
which are not you know proven
um but you know the latter seems to be a
situation where it might still be
prosecutable under the the section 1030.
so that's that just shows the kind of
dividing lines there that's interesting
so it's still a pretty nuanced area so
the access perhaps you know through
through whatever cabinet he'd access
that might have been the 10 30 violation
but
downloading in an automated fashion
academic journals to which you already
had access based on the van buren
decision that came out not necessarily
the guidelines
it probably wouldn't have amounted to a
charge
interesting i'll pass it over to you
joel
so i i think what happened with aaron is
unspeakably sad um
and i didn't
know him when he was charged i was a
baby fbi agent i was still a quantico um
and i never really even heard about the
case until i uh
moved i worked public corruption part of
my career and then i moved to cyber um
seven years ago and um
i'd never heard of the case and there's
lots of stuff you can find
i saw the documentary you can find
articles um
about the investigation
but something like some what makes it so
tragic is
aaron's he was a writer and he was a
thinker and
you read some of his
his essays
uh
and i know he's famous for like
for reddit and for his political
activism but the thing that i
think is the most interesting is just
his
his clarity of thought on social issues
and um about privacy
and
even even things that he was just he was
very he's a curious person so
you can read his essay about
um
keynes's general theory on economics and
this is something that 19 year olds do
not read this is something economists
avoid reading and
it's just amazing to hear how clearly he
summarizes it um
same with like
david foster wallace uh he read infinite
jest and then he writes this literary
criticism as like a 18 year old
and
and i i think
like
it's awful that we don't have them
in this decade especially because i feel
like like now when we're talking about
things like like moderation on social
media platforms and uh
and we're talking about disinformation
and misinformation
i would just love to hear like what his
thoughts are on it um i think it would
be very very illuminating just to
have his commentary and see how how his
thought has evolved um
i'm not sure if the if the guidelines
that were were released as sagar was
mentioning really
would affect his case because
this this is more geared towards um
uh
security researchers and i think aaron
falls more in the bucket of
uh an activist a civil disobedience
which which you know our country has a
rich history of civil disobedience
bringing light to
to laws that are unjust and then the
laws changing through the democratic
process
um so i'm not sure if if this would
if this new guidance would really
address his
specific matter but i do think a lot
has changed in 10 years
in terms of the prioritization of the
type of investigations that the federal
government is interested in
ten years ago we didn't have nation
state hackers breaking into private
companies
um ten years ago there were no attacks
on our our democracy um
ten years ago there was no
ability to monetize network access for
100 million or 200 million dollars and
so i think just the prioritizations
themselves have changed from um
looking at these hacktivist cases
more towards the cases where there's
enormous loss
let me let me interrupt and ask you a
direct question about that too then
with the shift in priorities if this
type of case if if the schwartz case
came over to you as an fbi agent today
do you think you
would say oh my goodness there's there's
no way that we could go after this
would this be something you would put in
the
never to prosecute or never investigate
pyle or
what would happen
i mean so
the fbi's job is just to get the facts
and so
if this case came to me i mean this
isn't the type of cases i work um but if
the case came to me i would i would
gather the facts
and
i would go where the facts take me and
then i would give them to prosecutors to
make the decision
i wouldn't be particularly
[Music]
aggressive about
wanting to work in a hacktivist case um
because like i said
like we're turning down we're turning
down cases where where victims are are
losing
a lot of money and um
you know there's a lot
there's a wealth of targets that i think
would in my mind at least
we would prioritize over this type of
conduct but again it's it's not my
decision my job is to gather the facts
um
and to go where the facts take me gotcha
yeah i appreciate that
jay what about you
yeah um i had the benefit earlier this
week in fact on monday the deputy
attorney general was
over
in our space at ncfta
national crime uh um cyber forensics and
training alliance she was there for a
different reason it was really more
about how to develop
a cyber trained workforce
within the legal ranks and
while we were chatting
in a round table type setting
i said to her i said by the way thanks
for the guidance the ethical hacking
guidance
it's from all that i've spoken with it's
been very well received and she i think
was taken back a bit and said you're
welcome and i have to tell you it was a
very easy decision
it's time when this came across my desk
uh
it was time to to signal this change
that that's interesting you know it's uh
i appreciate all your thoughts and i
know that they're all heartfelt and uh
and speaking about this tragedy and i i
certainly hope that
the evolution that we've seen
coming from on high and the supreme
court together with the change in the
guidelines the change in the attitude
from the department of justice from the
fbi
the
the shifting prioritization i think is
is such an important point that that
joel has brought up that that we would
hopefully never see something this
tragic affect our community again that's
uh that's i think all of our hopes here
i i hope i speak and i'm actually pretty
certain i know i i i speak for the panel
in that um but with that i want to
shift gears for a moment and
go back to the slide deck here which i
believe we have on the screen which is
excellent and move into a couple
hypothetical situations here where we
can have some audience participation and
and get your thoughts on a couple of
different hypotheticals that our
panelists have come up with that test
the limits of what good faith security
research means and what can and what is
within and without 1030 or the computer
fraud and abuse act these days based on
these guidelines so with that let's move
into
hypothetical one
which i call you know seek and destroy
here
so
the facts are this you know an i.t staff
with a
a large professional services
organization they know we're talking
about you know perhaps a law firm
or maybe an accounting firm or you know
a gaggle of consultants i think that's
what you call a lot of consultants right
gaggle
respond to an emerging cyber security
incident alarms indicate unusual network
traffic and data movement
maybe some data has been exfiltrated
possibly you know internal staging
investigation reveals that a large
amount of this professional services uh
organization their data was exfiltrated
to a cloud storage bucket of an
unrelated organization we're going to
call that organization abc org
and the ir team the uh
finds that the config file needed for
access to the abc org bucket is there
and and can actually access that bucket
so with this fact pattern here
you know would the ir team
actually uh violate 1030 by accessing
this abc bucket i'm going to i'm going
to pass that how about right back to you
jay
okay yeah there i am and and let me say
at the outset that
this scenario is not
a pie in the sky or really contrived
scenario it's based on an amalgam of a
couple of incidents that have happened
very recently
that actual incidents so yes okay the
team responds to the alarm
and is able to trace back and see where
the data that was exfiltrated when into
this bucket
named something
indicative of ownership by some other
entity
can they go into that bucket
is that
authorized are they authorized to do so
to enter someone else's storage bucket
it's a good question so i guess what
that hinges on is is this good faith
security research under the definition
and when we look back at that definition
i don't know if we can click back on the
slide
um yeah
look at that the components of what
constitutes good faith security research
it says uh accessing a computer solely
for the purpose of good testing
investigation
and or correction of a security floor or
vulnerability
where such activities carried out in a
manner designed to avoid any harm to
individuals or to the public
i think it falls within within that
definition
well
interesting so why don't why don't we
play out the fact pattern a little bit
more and then i'll i'll pass it over to
joel so they get access to the bucket
and they find
right they i hope i'm not mixing up my
hypotheticals here right no yeah and
let's say they find the data of
their own organization but together with
you know let's say 10 other
organizations as data as well that has
been exfiltrated in the same
s3 bucket
what then do you think
an ir team an incident response team
could do i'm looking at you joel here on
this one
with their own data and other companies
is data that was stolen and exfiltrated
by the same threat actor group so i
think it's up to their risk appetite um
like look
as as jay alluded to you call these
hypotheticals but
this is what's happening in the wild
it's his real life this is real life um
and
according to my reading of 10 30 it
seems that
even breaking into the bad guy's
computer
um would constitute a violation
based on my reading um
now whether it's something that
we would be interested in investigating
from the fbi standpoint i mean imagine
imagine a victim comes to us and we're
like
hold on you you broke into the hacker's
computer like
you're in trouble now you know
it's just it's an absurdity um i i can't
imagine a scenario where we would be
interested in that type of
that type of thing and
according to the new guidance i can't
imagine
a situation where anyone would actually
be prosecuted for something like that
right but
as you say joel that comes with some
risk it does depend upon
your risk appetite as as an employee or
an incident responder on behalf of the
employee
uh uh behalf of the organization yeah to
be clear i mean according to my reading
of the statute it would still be illegal
i'm not going to advocate
doing something illegal um
but these are the types of questions
that are arising that i don't think
federal law is
really equipped
to give people
sensible answers to how they can how can
they respond when
when
when affected with this type of
situation
yeah just you know get some audience
participation here by by show of hands
how many people would think that
accessing that that bucket
should be
a crime
nobody right so i
i think you're in good company here joel
yeah i mean
it
sorry what was that
there were some hands oh there were some
hands okay sorry i couldn't say that the
lights are a little bright here right uh
but that yeah i i think the majority
would agree with joel here but i want to
pass it to you sauger for your view on
this as the actual prosecutor the guy
who makes these decisions yeah look i i
hear right i mean i think as joel kind
of indicated certainly i think just
accessing the computer
without kind of doing any again the 10
30 requires certain actions you have to
take you have to take information that
cause damage you have to cause a loss
there's all these other things that are
in addition to simply accessing
so
if
and if you are really doing it in good
faith investigation
and the facts the available evidence
that i have and that the fbi has to
you know show that you are in fact
trying to investigate your own
data leak you know i think arguably
would fall uh you know under the good
faith security research but again
you know i think it's also helpful to
note that
this kind of language about good faith
security research is part of
eight different factors that are in
these right guidelines as to things that
a prosecutor should decide whether or
not to charge someone
those other things include
the impact of the crime and the
prosecution on the victim in third
parties here are the victims actually
doing it the the uh the degree to which
the damage or access
uh raises concerns pertaining to
national security critical
infrastructure public health
the sensitivity of the affected computer
system
um and the deterrent value of an
investigation of prosecution right so so
let's let's complicate it a little bit
more with this fact
i think this one's really interesting
because you you mentioned one of the
factors that you think about are the
impact to third parties so we have 10
other companies data in this s3 bucket
the ir team sees this and decides you
know what i've i've had it with you know
this threat actor group they've they
ruined my life i haven't slept in five
days makes a rash decision and says i'm
going to delete
these other archives of exfiltrated data
that belong to other companies that then
leads the threat actors to get very
angry
and then let's say demand additional
ransom or
other or engage in other forms of
extortion with regard to those other
affected companies by the threat actor
so there has been in this situation in
the new fact pattern here a greater
impact to third parties after accessing
that s3 bucket do you think that could
cross the line
oh i was going to jump in real quick on
that alley go ahead jay because i think
they're really two key decisions first
okay it's one thing if you see your data
that's been exfiltrated
in this bucket that's
presumably belongs to another
organization and was likely compromised
by a bad actor
so there's one decision about do i do i
delete the data from my organization
that i know does not belong there
and then secondarily i see a bunch of
other victims there
should i try in good faith to help them
and download that data or delete that on
their behalf can you be sure that it's
not really supposed to be there
um maybe there's some partnership i'm
not aware of and that data's there for a
reason so you are taking on some
additional risk if you do delete the
data
and
i'll i'll tell you to complicate this
pattern what we'll add is in in the
instance that led to the creation of
this scenario that
while making those decisions
the the response team had not assured
that their network was completely secure
and they were locked down with
encryption
when the bad actor determined wow you
deleted your data
uh did you think that was our only copy
of your data the bad actor responded and
locked down with um drop some encryption
malware
you know it it it's
both you and joel jay had had mentioned
you know risk here too and i i think it
it's worth taking a tiny bit of a detour
about the cfa too because you know it's
not just a criminal statute there's also
potential civil liability under the
computer fraud and abuse act and as a
private practice attorney up here now
that that's you know arguably very
important because let's say that the ir
team the incident responders do that and
it leads to
additional extortion or or
a higher ransom demand for these other
companies
i think it's quite possible that there
there could be civil liability under the
computer fraud and abuse act for that
particular type of action because it
resulted in
some kind of damage or an additional
cost or extortion to these other
companies and so there is always this
civil angle that you have to think about
in terms of your liability under the
cfaa or 1030 it's not just a a criminal
statute but i want to i want to pass it
back to you sagar because i'm really
interested in your your uh analysis
under the more complicated fact pattern
here yeah i mean look again it's a
two-step analysis right one is there a
legally a violation of section 1030 and
then two you know based on the policies
and the guidelines and the facts you
know should
is this a case that we should charge
right prosecutorial discretion is a big
part
of every prosecutor's job whether we
should charge a case just just because
there's a legal violation
does not mean that we should so here i
think once they access it and then they
either obtain they download
the data even if it's their own data or
even the data of the other
firms i think it is
you know seems appears to be a violation
of section 1030
and then the question is should we
prosecute uh so that will depend on kind
of
what was the what were they trying to do
what was the point you know of what
their access was what was the harm that
was caused right um and so that's that's
a much closer case i mean
i think my
you know i think the message that at
least i want to convey is you know
before you do that you know
call law enforcement call us
uh and we can work with you to figure
out what's the right step you know what
i would do
is if i got that call and i've gotten
that call before
uh is you know oh you have the you have
the keys to get into this
this hacker's uh you know system
well let's you know that's great give it
to us and then i can get a legal process
of a court that allows us to go
preserve the evidence take the evidence
use it for our purposes and going after
the bad actors uh so you know from our
perspective if if someone goes in on
their own they could cause you know they
could lose the evidence they can cause
more harm they can which in this hypo it
actually leads to more harm because
everyone including the other firm's
data is encrypted um so you know the
message is to call us and we can work it
through and again we are not trying to
create burdens on victims victims we
take them very seriously
um all victims are
you know confidential we don't want to
re-victimize you and we want to work
with you as part of the private public
partnership to go after these these guys
it requires kind of all of us sharing
information to do it
that's such a great point and
i think doing it that way would nearly
eliminate any potential civil liability
that that an ir team or the company for
which the ir team was working uh could
face by deleting that data and and
and causing these these untold
consequences i mean there i think there
are a lot of
unforeseeable consequences to these
types of actions
and i want to pass it over to to you
joel do you want to do would you agree
with with sauger there that uh you know
the right action would be reported to
law enforcement
and if so how quickly do you think you
guys could act
so that's a tough one because we've been
in situations like that and to be honest
with you there's a lot of factors
it depends on whether the servers in the
united states or whether it's overseas
and if it is overseas it depends on what
country it's in um because the answer
might be you know we have to work with
law enforcement overseas and you know
give them the the configuration file or
the the password to get into the server
and then when you're talking about
overseas cooperation in law enforcement
things really slow down and it becomes
difficult but i agree with sagar here
that the right thing to do
um
and there shouldn't be any doubt with
this um if you're concerned about about
risk and you're concerned about
breaking
1030 and you're concerned about civil
liability is going to be pulling law
enforcement into the mix
spinning us up
if it's domestic we could probably get a
search warrant fairly quick quickly we
would need a search warrant for this
type of thing we can we can get a
preservation
faster
but
just just to
talk about the reality of it normally
when there's a staging server with exfil
data won't be on there for very long
we're talking hours
and so
we would have to be very lucky and have
to be very coordinated and work very
quickly in order to
be able to take action against it before
the threat actor moves it or sends it to
some other server that we don't have
visibility
and joel let me add too that of course
we're not
we're we're discounting the human
element too that these are teams that
have been working for and been up for
two days
tracking an incident trying to contain
it and when they find that data
the excitement of it being there and the
opportunity to delete the data and maybe
save the day and also perhaps be the
good guy and try to help some of your
partners
that that comes into play when time is
of the essence and
it in some cases is easier to
to make a hurried decision that that
does and i'm glad you mentioned alex the
civil
uh the private cause of action there a
right of action private right of action
element of 10 30 because
yeah if those companies incur
a greater ransom i think they're going
to respond saying you know a
notification would have been nice you
didn't have to go ahead
and delete it and put us in the bucket
with you
yeah i i tend to agree with you there i
mean if if i was on the receiving end of
the ransom demand yeah we'd probably
start
sending out the the data preservation
letters getting and getting the other
side ready for litigation i mean it's
it's such a crazy situation and and
bizarre and complex world that we live
in here um i think i i want to move on
to the second hypothetical here if uh if
everyone agrees yeah you guys good with
that all right let's do it so let's go
on to the next one this one i call the
the diy disaster
so hypothetical two here
said let's suppose that there is you
know god forbid a remote access zero day
uh discovered on many internet-facing
devices we don't doesn't matter what
these devices are they're just they're
internet facing they're out on public
ips so there's a working exploit proof
of concept circulating on twitter
and there's also been detection of
increased worldwide scanning for these
vulnerable devices looking for things
that you know can be exploited so here's
the question here and i'm going to i'm
going to pose this one to joel first
could some good faith hacker
white hat as we would call them
leverage this exploit to mitigate
certain vulnerable systems to take
essentially the the patching of this
vulnerability into her own hands
so they they certainly could um i don't
know if that would be the the best
course of action um
a lot of things come into play here
because the truth is patches break
things
and
if there's production systems that are
connected to the internet
um
if if you patch them and restart them
things
could could and will break
and although
and this again we call it a hypothetical
but this is something that has been
reported in the wild whenever you have
these big um
these big wormable exploits
inevitably you'll see
people building worms for monero miners
you'll see people building worms just as
you know hello world proofs of concept
um you'll also see worms going around
where it's it's
people
patching patching the flaw or closing
ports and trying to mitigate and it's
just it's pure like
white hat hackers trying to do the right
thing and trying to help a stranger
but there's risk to it there's risk to
it because there could be some
inadvertent damage that happens but
i struggle i struggle with this because
i also think you know and i like to
think in analogies and
if i was having a heart attack i'd want
someone to give me chest compressions up
on stage even if they were worried about
breaking a rib
um
so
like what's worse
someone patches your system and you have
some downtime or
uh you get hit by a
a ransom a wormable ransom
and so it's only a matter of time like
there's going to be a new rdp exploit
there's going to be a new smb exploit
there's going to be you know a microsoft
exchange exploit that's going to be
warmable and
there's going to be a countdown to
um when it gets ported into say
metasploit or when when someone is able
to
to take code from github and build
something that will just spread like
wildfire
and
um
yeah it's it's it's difficult i wouldn't
do it i wouldn't do it but
people will do it and they have done it
they have the people have taken into
their house i think you know it really
goes back to what you were saying
earlier sauger which is i think you know
it's about intent and here
if you go and take patching of
vulnerability into your own hands there
are foreseeable but arguably
unintentional consequences of what you'd
be doing but you know some of those
unintentional consequences for example
could could affect the hospital right
you know hospitals are notorious for
relying on uh older hardware that has
firmware on it that hasn't been updated
since you know dos 5.1 right and you
start monkeying around with those types
of systems things might go down patients
might not get care people might die i
mean it's all hypothetical of course but
these are some of the unintentional
consequences that that could happen and
i and i think your your cpr analogy is
really apt as well but but i think it i
think it might depend on the risk for
both sides perhaps i want to i want to
pass it over to you saga yeah no i think
that's that's right you know is this
again going to kind of the two-step
analysis right is this a
violation of section 1030 appears to be
you know you're accessing someone else's
computer and you're
uh you know transmitting a command or
code to do something um and it could it
changes the system right so i think
technically it is it is appears to be a
violation
you know but then the second question is
you know again looking at the policies
and looking you know is this is this
good faith security research is this
someone who had
no intent to harm you know i i'm not
sure kind of you have to look at the
facts also we'll have to look at the
harm that was caused we'll have to
consult with the victim of that harm and
you know we do take victims rights kind
of very seriously but i think
the real question is you know what when
they decided to put the patch on you
know what efforts did they take to avoid
harm were there other things they could
have done yeah to avoid harm and that's
right from the guidelines isn't that
right yeah yeah that that's interesting
joel i'm sorry not joel uh jay there's
too many j's here yeah jay what what
about you i would love to get your your
thoughts on this one
uh yeah i
i'm listening to the comments and and
i
i think this is uncharted territory
really i mean the
the
the the landscape is so complicated and
those dependencies i think joel you
refer to it are there's no way that even
the most well-intentioned
uh uh individual could
could understand the potential harm that
could be visited
by
pushing out a hurried patch that hasn't
been tested and validated
that
causes significant and
great unintended harm so
yes uh i think what
one of the potential solutions is here
is to speed
the coalitions through which we share
those
solutions
so that
more
fertile minds can come together more
quickly to evaluate
the potential solutions instead of the
rush to a solution
when the problem may not be entirely
known at that point a few minutes of
focus on the problem to make sure that
the solutions appropriate
would help
yeah yep i i tend to agree with you
there jay and um
you know i also i want to thank
everybody for
listening to us for this extended period
of time here and because
our uh the panelists that were in our
slot had cancelled we've been able to
extend this session and also want to
open it up to q a at this point
um
it's a little bit hard to see with the
lights but we'd love to to answer
questions from the audience here and i
think there's one in the front i don't
know if we're using microphones or if
there's a mic in the back is that
how's this thing working here
oh there's a mic in the back all right
so how about
yeah if you want to line up and ask
questions that would be great
you guys all good for time here do do a
couple of questions and uh yeah
fantastic sure appreciate that excellent
um
sir sir and the red
thank you sir uh thank you everybody um
so
good uh
thanks for asking about aaron schwartz
um who of course would be alive if not
for the actions of people the doj
and prosecuting him under this act
and
it's not the only time in history when
prosecutors were
too lacking in empathy for somebody who
acted in the public interest
i
do think this guideline is these
guidelines are better than nothing but
doj is not powerless here
the doj has influence over the law
we all know that 2001 the department of
justice said we'd like these things
passed and congress went ahead and put
them into the patriot act
so doj can't go to congress and say we
want to change the cfaa
and
i don't understand why a lot of laws
don't have more public interest defenses
but the cfaa in particular
doj could go to congress say we want to
you to add a public interest defense to
the cfaa so that
somebody
who releases information in the public
interest
that does not violate privacy that
doesn't have its
primary use being for the purpose of an
ethical business
is not going to get prosecuted and
that's going to outlast not just
it's going to outlast the current
administration it's going to be a
permanent improvement in the law
can you give any good reason why doj
does not do this
and just to be clear here you're asking
about essentially a lobbying question
here right why why is doj not
pressuring congress to change the law
you call it lobbying if you like but
it's a lot it's more intimate than
lobbying um the dog is more intimate
than a lot of lobbying doj does
regularly go to congress saying we want
uh more draconian laws or we want
changes in the law why can't they just
say we think this law would be improved
by allowing uh a this for the following
specific public interest defense
i'll pass it to sagar if you want to
comment look i i don't think i can speak
to that uh in my position all i can say
is that you know oftentimes i'm aware
that you know
i'm not sure whether we lobby for
legislation i know that congress
regularly inquires what when there's
proposed legislation what the impact of
that might be and you know i think we
have individuals that go and testify in
front of congressional hearings as to
the impact of legislation on the work
that we do every day
um but other than that i don't think i
haven't the answer to your question yeah
i'm just asking is there any reason why
doj should not do that any ethical
reason why you should not do that
well i i could
possibly make one comment in response
which is
you you would only really want to have
you know as a lawyer here's i'm speaking
him privately not on behalf of my firm
either but i think as a as a as a lawyer
you would want to have changes in the
law that would be necessary
and i think that
to have congress act while the supreme
court was still changing and evolving
the law as it was very active and doing
might be a little bit premature and i i
tend to see
the evolution of the supreme court's
interpretation
of the computer fraud and abuse act and
10 30 in particular
as continue as a continuous narrowing of
what would constitute a crime under that
statute and so arguably there wouldn't
be the need to go to congress from doj's
perspective to do this and i would see
the guidelines as you admitted i think
as a good first step here
but look i agree and as we addressed in
the panel it does the guidelines don't
change the law the law is what the law
is right and i think it's quite
reasonable to expect that there may be
other prosecutors in doj that might not
be as enlightened as sauger
and might have differing interpretations
and the way to prevent that would be to
actually change the law
so i i take your point and
you know i think it's an interesting one
and uh yeah we'd love to move on to
another question if that's all right
well let me add quickly alex that i i
think
yeah yeah i mean uh the
the person asking the question alluded
to it as
a first step and and i think we have to
recognize that
we're in the midst of an evolution here
it may be a little hard to see because
it's happening around us but the supreme
court decision
this necessary first step and and also
the evolution of
kind of the space that i'm in every day
a public-private partnership where
members of the law enforcement community
are working shoulder to shoulder with
security researchers threat hunters
members of academia you know as those
efforts bear fruit and continue to
evolve
if there's
if there is a a calculable or an
articulable
need to say you know we could take it to
the next level
but our security researchers are still
um concerned or the law departments are
haven't responded to
to this policy change and we're still
hearing no no no you can't do this
uh
that that's when i think the data call
will go around
for
uh friends uh
amicus uh letters and briefs will come
in um and the department of justice may
and i certainly don't speak for the
department of justice but
i know that there's a data call that
goes around every year to all the
agencies to ask what do you need to do
your job more effectively and if folks
like the fbi and dhs hsi and
uh
secret service say we need more input
and we think that that
uh a change in the law is absolutely
what's chilling folks from coming
forward that's what's going to prompt
congress to
to to lean forward and and deal with
constituent concerns which are
they're over indexed on frankly but
that's um
i i think it it takes time and we're
walking before we can jog jogger run
well you're describing a process that's
uh that's well adapted to widening
predicates but not to narrowing
predicates and if the supreme court
narrows things in one way that does not
mean that all the ways in which the law
needs to be narrowed need to be
addressed that's an area where crafting
legislation is important we all know the
supreme court doesn't do a lot of the
narrowing that's needed so
that's why i think i'm asking is there
ethical any ethical reason why doj
should not
go to congress and go in a narrowing
direction even though that's not what
they're used to doing
well we appreciate your comments and and
your question thank you
hello
um yeah i was just wondering like for
the hypothetical situations like how
would that
end up like in a situation where it's
in front of the doj in the first place
like abc org is not gonna go
this person i'm hacking has hacked my
computer back
do you want to take that saga or joel
i mean that
that's a good common sense
data point right it's you know usually
it's not going to come to fruition that
i'm even necessarily going to learn
that abc corp was hacked right of course
however in that hypothetical if
it leads to the encryption keys getting
out and
several other companies data getting
locked up
then it's something that might come to
our attention so that i think working
within the hypo that that's how we might
learn about it
yeah and i'll add i i think it would
take some time for there to be a
for there to be a disclosure or an
understanding of what really happened
as the company gets past the incident
and rebuilds its network or or pays the
ransom and gets the decryption key
there's often litigation by third
parties that were impacted by the
outages saying company
a professional services company you know
you didn't do enough you didn't prepare
enough your system wasn't secure enough
and i've been damaged in some way and
then in the wash
through discovery or otherwise it'll
come out that this is what happened we
we learned we did our best we tried to
delete the data
and and there could be some disclosure
that
that the company took some action that
impacted others but you're right would
they volunteer that to say up or bad we
met well but
we were trying to save you and we caused
you a little more harm
it wouldn't be immediately apparent to
those other companies
thank you great thank you
thank you very much my question is in
regards to bug bounties and like a
security researcher finding a bug they
do the proper thing they alert the
organization and they wait the 90 days
and in the careful reading here
indicates that if the company doesn't
reply to that and doesn't take any
action that there's still no cover for
that security researcher to do a public
disclosure if that disclosure was to it
was to create some type of financial
harm as i as
at least that's the way i read that
is that correct
anybody want to take this one on so
responsible disclosure
it's not codified into law it's more of
like ethical um frameworks that some
people have proposed uh you know what's
the waiting period for a company when
you make ethical disclosure is it 90
days is it one day is it three months um
i've seen some some different you know
takes on what's what the right thing to
do is in that type of situation um
and i think i think a lot of it depends
i think a lot of it depends you know
it's hard for
a large enterprise to patch their system
quickly
and so i think it would be unfair if
someone identifies a bug in a
company's
network and then says in three days i'm
going to the press
yeah i think i was trying to clarify
like that the actual the new standards
that say as long as you're trying not to
harm them you're okay but at what point
you know does that break
i don't know yeah
i don't know i mean it's something that
time is gonna have to bear out because
you're gonna have these situations in
the future um
one thing i i will point to um
so there's a lot of situations where um
someone will go through the motions for
responsible disclosure and then
they'll
they'll go to the press because they
want they want notoriety for finding a
bug um and
their motivation is they
they want their name in the newspaper
and they want to shame the the
enterprise or
i shouldn't say that's their motivation
but that's kind of like what comes out
of it
what i would prefer is uh
to make the ethical
uh notification and then to uh present
at hope conference and talk about this
really cool exploit that you found
without you know showing any of the
private data
to anyone you know redact we need to
redact but talk about um the technical
steps that you found or that you used to
define the bug and and the timeline of
when you disclosed and what the company
did i think that's more interesting than
someone going to a reporter and saying
uh
like hey you should
report this
thank you very much
one other point to i think to your
interesting question too
and i'd ask really you know sauger this
is really more of a question to you i
guess but you know whether it's
responsible disclosure or irresponsible
disclosure and you're putting that
information out into whatever the
ecosystem is
that is a lot different from the type of
affirmative activity that would equate
to
unauthorized access itself under the
statute right so talking about something
putting information out there would not
necessarily lead to some kind of
actionable charge as i understand it
under the under 1030 or cfaa
would that be correct i think that's
generally right yeah i would say it
probably depends on like some of the
specific scenarios like for instance if
you find a bug on
someone's external facing sql database
and then you you spend a month
downloading every single thing on their
database
um
like that's where it gets into that
blurred area of like well
why'd you have to do that like you had
the proof of concept you showed that it
was that it worked why did you have to
pull the rest of the data from the
company um so there are some gray areas
that you get into and it's it's really
fact dependent
yeah and joel 2 right
some of those those uh requests to
to apply for a
bounty that may be available or are no
more than thinly veiled extortion
requests
and yeah sometimes the activity is not
with
good faith that it's conducted it's
conducted in bad faith with
um efforts to
to cause some harm and
to
to agree to hide um
the damage or or to stop the damage uh
in exchange for some money so
the facts are important in each one of
those
well thank you very much thank you
thanks for your question great shirt by
the way
love it
hi and thank you i thought i wanted to
post a hypothetical in a different
direction if that's all right
so so imagine this scenario an employee
at the company working at the company
normally and with access to the company
networks however due to a bug that they
were not looking for they obtain access
to
documents they were not looking for that
they are not supposed to have access for
the using this they see that the company
has conducted activity that is deeply
and as a code though not necessarily
illegal
in the higher levels and they give this
to a reporter
the company argues that this employee
used unauthorized access to obtain
information that was deeply damaging to
themselves regardless of the veracity
and
ethicality of it so like as a prosecutor
how would how would you pursue this and
what do you think others that i mean the
prosecutorial realm in general would do
can i ask you one clarifying question
and you're hypothetical there too would
be so because it was a little bit hard
to hear and you might have touched on
this but
in your hypothetical where this employee
then goes and accesses certain data that
indicates the company has been doing
some untoward things yeah did the
employee
actually have the access to that
particular document or did the employee
have to get through some kind of barrier
in order to get the documents
let's say that the imp
that there was a bike in the system so
that the employee
there was some way for the employee to
get that information even though they
were not supposed to perhaps using some
different maps perhaps
would it let's say in your hypothetical
would have would it work that if the
access the employee was granted by the
company was incorrectly configured to
have given them more access to a
particular document would that fit your
hypothetical yes if say the access in
one certain obscure case were
incorrectly configured so okay
great i'll pass it over to you guys
yeah that that's an interesting
hypothetical i think of the
related hypothetical which is you know
you're always wondering what your bosses
are thinking of you
and
so then but on your computer system
somehow when you're clicking through
kind of various folders the folder that
you always thought you never had access
to all of a sudden you click on it and
it's available to you and it shows all
the notes that your bosses have been
keeping in your file it's a trap
so
if it's not the boss is saying if you're
going to access it
you know is that a violation i you know
it's it's a good question
um
i think it's gonna be hard to prosecute
that case yeah i i think under the
supreme court's decision because
um the supreme court kind of spoke of
you know you have to
it is something that you are blocked
from by some sort of technological means
and if you if they mess up and
due to no part no action on your part
you have access to it i think it's going
to be a hard case so when we think about
the two-step analysis you know is that a
case that
we should
we can prosecute
i think it's gonna be hard to yeah now
let's change our colleagues hypothetical
here for a second where the access
wasn't incorrectly configured but let's
say it's a
folder that had uh was password
protected and somebody brute forced the
password that would be a little bit more
clear-cut as a violation i agree yeah
yeah and now alex let me jump in here
because this is really interesting in
that
uh
at the fbi and joel you jump in here too
there are many times where someone will
report
some information of concern
and the means through which they
gathered
that information are arguably illegal
that doesn't preclude the government
from taking that information now
conversely if the person said i can get
it through this means i could easily
brute force that and crack it you
couldn't say go do that because then
they'd be an extension a government
agent and that would violate the law but
if they had done it and reported it
that's an option that they could report
it
and let
the government
um do what he can to mitigate the harm
from that so again the facts are going
to be important is it strictly unethical
behavior or is it something that could
be damaging and
worse
okay i thank you for that jay and thank
you for the the great question we i
think we're probably only able to take
one more question how many people do we
have left there is it just two
is it two
all
right we go hi sorry i'm gus andrews for
the moment i'm putting on my work cat
i'm with disarm foundation
i have a question that's a little bit
tangential to what we've been talking
about and that is
from where each of you stands
we talked about with that last case um
where it was like you could just release
a patch and i'm sure everybody's um you
know
release and development managers would
really prefer you not do that so it's
not just the law would prefer you not do
it but the you know the engineers would
too
um you said that maybe it sounds like
maybe what was preferential what you
prefer to see in that case is people
communicating with each other and saying
hey you know this is what we're seeing
um you know can everybody jump on this
from where each of you stand
what are the things that would be most
important to improve trust between
organizations communicating about things
like that
and to improve communication between
organizations
and entities around that
this sounds like one for jay and joel
here
yeah
uh
let me start here because uh as we
mentioned at the outset i i spent a long
career in government and then
represented clients and had a number of
stops in this journey and now i'm back
in the space where
i i see every day
what it takes to build those trust
relationships between
law enforcement agencies that maybe
haven't worked together as closely as
they should and then also private sector
partners and um
i i wish there was an easy answer to
that i i think it
uh the landscape is changing in that i
think there are people who are committed
to doing the work
and
uh um
being more open in environments like
ours at ncfta and others
but it does require a very purposeful
effort to engage i mean you can't
sit back in your office
or your home office or wherever you work
from and expect that you're going to be
able to build
the the trust relationships that are
necessary when you need to call on
someone to pick you up or to collaborate
with you on something really important
so
i i think it it requires
an effort to brief your leadership and
your organization to express the
importance of getting out and listening
going on a listening tour and working
with others to define problems before
uh solutions of rush to
it's there's no easy path it requires a
lot of work and i urge the folks that
are out there to think about ways and
out in the audience that is to
opportunities to meet with others that
may be a little bit of a stretch you
know a little outside your comfort zone
and and in your ordinary circle just to
hear what they're working on and develop
those
those connections that i think help when
those important and harder decisions
come down the road because you have
those built-in relationships that
that that can serve you well
yeah and you know jay i think is a great
comment and and allows us to kind of
segue into into wrapping it up here too
and um
you know i i'm i'm
reminded of um ambassador ido aharoni
who was the longest serving consul
general general of israel made a comment
to me about cyber security and and uh
and and foreign diplomacy and saying
that um
you know the the reason why countries
have embassies all around the world the
reason why united states has an embassy
in uganda and tanzania as well as paris
and russia's is is not because you know
we'd like to collect real estate in
foreign countries it's because you know
we're building these bridges and have
these relationships in place in case we
need them and we may be able to do in
and that in the cyber security sphere we
need to build those those same types of
relationships and i think
you know it's very obvious to us all
right now that we live in really
complicated and complex times and we
dwell
permanently in an area of nuance and and
greyness and
as as i think jay and joel and sagar all
alluded to earlier you know we cannot go
it alone at all anymore no party is
equipped to deal with the complexities
of this world just by itself i think the
guidelines these new prosecutorial
guidelines with the cfaa
really should go a long way into into
fostering this public-private
partnership
and and this the hypothetical private
alliance i think that is not just
hypothetical anymore and something that
that jay
cramer is actively working to forge on a
daily basis and and i want to pass it
over
for a moment before we conclude to to
sauger to make um essentially a couple
of statements and and maybe even a plea
to the community here yeah look uh you
know i think the the message i want to
communicate and why i'm excited to be
here just you know really two words call
me right uh call call call me call the
fbi if you see something uh
you know that's suspicious
you know we are we want to work with you
uh we we appreciate all of the you know
all the cyber security research that is
out there we can our jobs and our
investigations
where we are really prioritizing going
after real bad actors can only be done
kind of with the help of everybody so
please work with us call us
we want to hear from you um and you know
and as these uh new policies may occur
you know we're not interested in
prosecuting good faith cyber security
that's not what we're here for we're
here to go after the bad guys uh that's
what we do every day and that's what
we're going to continue to do and we can
do it better with your help yeah i
couldn't agree more and sometimes if you
don't want to talk to them directly you
might want to talk to fbi through a
lawyer
that's always an option as well and you
know we're obviously all friends here so
um i i really want to uh
we can even appoint you a lawyer that's
true absolutely yeah you can even just
call us and say hey i want to tell you
something i'm not sure if i can or
should and and if you can't afford a
lawyer on your own we can also even
appoint once that's such such a great uh
such a great point and um and look i i
want to wrap it up here because we we've
gone through such an extended period of
time and
um and give a really heartfelt thanks to
sagar ravi of the department of justice
jay dicapua of the fbi and jay kramer of
the national cyber forensics training
association
thank you guys so much for your time for
being here for speaking to the community
speaking from your heart
and
and for just being open to the
conversation we're looking forward to
having you back at hope and we hope you
enjoy the rest of the conference thank
you all as well
do
you