no
now okay
welcome again to a new hope
as a reminder everyone in the room if
you have any questions you can always
check through the matrix chat to ask any
questions same with our virtual
attendees that is the only way that
someone outside of the
event will be able to ask any questions
so let's allow me to introduce our next
speaker with a simple question
who here has not
had some of their data
found in some kind of a breach
well i mean obviously the question is
why isn't it simply
encrypted however according to our next
speaker philip allen baker that's the
wrong question
okay hello
so today i'm going to be announcing
three
open infrastructures
the first is a
infrastructure that secures data at rest
the second
is an infrastructure that binds together
a collection of devices
and makes them function like they're a
single device that belongs to you the
owner
and the third
is a mechanism that allows us to take
back control
of
internet services we depend on
but of course these are not three
separate
services
they're one and let's call the
mathematical mesh
now this is an open specification
open
reference code
and open applications based on that code
today i'm going to be showing you
the line mode
applications which are the ones that are
finished
but there are gui
i'm going to explain
as i'm going to explain the
the applications are not really the
point the point is this should be
infrastructure and this should be part
of all the applications we use
in our everyday lives
so let's start with the first of those
problems securing data at rest
and of course
every time we have a breach and
to to do this you know this is a billion
dollars worth of breaches
i just did the local the searched on
breach for news and these were just the
first five hits
and it's basically been like that every
day for the past 10 years and every time
the question comes up
why didn't they just encrypt
you know encryption is easy i mean this
is how we encrypt using the mathematical
mesh
alice creates an account
so she's got an account alice at
example.com
she's going to
she's got little diddly file here um
just a text file in this case but of
course it could be word it could be
solidworks inventor powerpoint whatever
and she's just going to encrypt it and
then she's going to decrypt it and it's
all going to work as you would expect so
there's our
encrypt file let's encrypt it
and
the
encryption that you're going to see here
it's uh all fairly straightforward stuff
that we've been doing now for oh 25
years
this in this case it's all jason using
the itf jose
approach but you know really
straightforward stuff have a bunch of
recipients the actual encrypted payload
is in the middle there
and we have a signature at the end yeah
yeah it's easy
encryption
easy
so what's the problem
well the problem is when you encrypt
your data you can't get it back unless
you can decrypt it
and just being able to decrypt it on one
machine
doesn't cut it
not if you're going to be able to use
that
data
in an enterprise or to share it with
your
colleagues or even if you're going to
just use it on your own
encryption is easy it's the managing the
decryption of the data that is hard
and see here we just decrypted the data
and we get the text back you know just
like we've done so you know here the has
uh rounded off a few of the rough
corners
that pgp and s mime exposed uh you
notice you didn't need to do the usual
musking around with keyrings it was done
for you but
yeah we've got to do better
before i can encrypt by default
i've got to be able to access my data on
all my devices i might want to use it on
and you know i have a lot of devices
i've got to be able to
share that data with all my colleagues
past and future
and also you know
what happens if i have a disaster what
happens if the house burns down
now this is something i've not got time
to go into uh here
but you know i have been spent a lot of
time thinking about how do you recover
the keys if a personal disaster happens
and also survivability
what happens if you've died
and all your data is encrypted and now
the family is trying to get
hold of your bank accounts
okay so at this point um
you know why am i wearing the steve jobs
black sweater well there's actually two
reasons here
the first is
if you have you know
steve is showing a bunch of this is the
iphone launch and steve is showing a
bunch of the previous smartphones did
anybody here use one of those
they sucked didn't they
they really really sucked
iphone raised the bar
and that's what we've got to do for
cryptography
the reason that people aren't using pgp
and s mime and so on to secure their
data at rest is that it is too
damned difficult
we've got to make it effortless
zero click encryption
zero click decryption
and that's why in order for the mesh to
really succeed
it has to be integrated into all the
applications we use on a daily basis
yeah that's why it has to be an open
standard
because the only way that he can happen
in a way that we can all make use of it
without some
god and awful you know
wall garden situation
is if there's an open standard that
every vendor of application software
every open source
provider can implement and we can all
use
so yes
the second reason is this woman
trust nobody absolutely
security is risk management it isn't
risk elimination
it isn't trust elimination forget the
zero zero trust is a stupid slogan it's
almost as stupid as deep
perimeterization which is the last one
you've got to trust somebody
but the key thing is to control who you
trust and to how what extent
and one of the mistakes i made in the
previous incarnations of pki
that i had something to do with
was we tended to concentrate
trust too much in certain nodes and you
all didn't like it you know cas
the mesh is based on two principles
least privilege
and separation and of duties
and it uses threshold cryptography
to enable that to happen
yeah even i don't trust me completely i
mean like
if you do crypto for a long for any
length of time you spend your time
wondering
did i leave a test dub in
did i miss out that signature validation
you know it's it's really grilling stuff
okay so let's go on to the first of
those uh
things that we have to meet in order to
use this data on any of alice's devices
she's got to glue them all together so
they function as one and this is
something that we need for applications
as well i mean
yeah
you buy your first laptop you install a
bunch of applications on it you know
mail contacts twitter flying spaghetti
yeah you've got all them running and
then you buy your second one and then
you spend
you know half an hour installing the
apps and then copying all the accounts
from one to the other and yes apple
promises to do that for you but only if
you enter into club apple and give your
uh application yeah so that never really
worked and then you do the second and
the third and so you end up with a bunch
of devices
and you don't know quite which of them
you can use for which application
so
the solution that i want to have is i
want to join all of my devices and all
of the applications to what i'll call a
mesh account
and have that be something that belongs
to me
something that cannot be taken away from
me something that i can move from one
service provider to another so that i
don't have to change this
at any time in my life no matter how
many laptops
desktops and mobile phones i
change between
so let's just look at how we can join
two
devices together
so what we're going to do here is oh
thank you very much
so i've got a second device here
and it's going to get that file that we
tried to decrypt earlier and we can't
decrypt it of course because yes it
belongs to me but i've not given it the
decryption key yet
so what i'm now going to do is to
request a connection between this device
and alice's mesh account
so she just posts the request and you
can see
nothing uh hideously
complicated there just
request to alice at example.com and then
the device in the background here is
going away and
generating a small pki just for this
device
uh there's a lot of crypto going on
behind the scenes here
much more crypto than used to happen
with pgp or s mime or whatever
and then on the uh original device which
is alice's administrative device at the
moment she checks for pending messages
you see here that there was a witness
value given out we're going to compare
the two witness values to check that
they are the same they are and that
gives us a work factor of 2 to the power
that secures that connection between
them
first time we accept it doesn't work
because and the reason for this is that
this is a least privileged system
i have i can't just say connect i've got
to say what privileges are going to
connect it to i'm connecting another
laptop here
if i was connecting a food blender
i probably wouldn't want to allow it to
have email
and you're all probably asking who on
earth has a internet connected food
blender in the audience anybody
i do
yes
stupidest idea ever i just had to buy it
it was in costco internet connected so
okay so we've accepted the um
request and now we're just going to
synchronize this laptop up to the
original and again this is actually
something that if we were in production
code i probably will get rid of it uh so
we device complete and now we can decode
the file see just work this time and we
can read that file back again so what
we've solved here is we've solved the
problem of encryption in decryption for
alice
she can encrypt her data on one device
and use it on any of her connected
devices
now
obviously this is not an ideal thing
you know if we're talking about
um
your medium term yes the specifications
but not the current code
supports uh using qr code connections
you can just scan a qr code and that
does all the connection again
uh the 120 bit
connection key is
hidden inside the qr code
[Music]
the reason that we've not done that yet
is
microsoft isn't delivering that code
until august or whatever
okay so what just happened behind the
scenes there well
the connecting device
generated a
public key pair this is elliptic curve
cryptography
uh the private key is a scalar and the
public key is
a point multiplied by that scalar
and so we send the public key
x dot p off to alice's mesh service
provider
and there it waits until it's picked up
by the administration device and that
generates a second
public key pair in this case y y dot p
and what we then
she then the administration device then
does
is it adds the two public keys
to get a new public key
which i'm going to call a dot p where a
equals x dot y
and we create all the certificates all
the credentials that we're going to need
to make use of this device within the
context of alice's mesh account
on the administration device so
the administration device can calculate
the public key
from knowledge of the public key shares
but doesn't have any knowledge of the
private key because it only knows why it
doesn't know x
so it then sends back y and the
certificates
back to the connecting device and the
connecting device can then calculate a
which equals x plus y which is the
private key for the composite key
so what we've just done here is we've
onboarded this device
and provisioned it with all the public
and private key information it needs to
act in the context of alice's account
and yes i've lied a lot of details
cryptographically but that's the
principle
okay so what we've been able to do here
is to share the key generation role
between the two
devices and the reason that that's
important is that
if either of the devices
does the key generation properly and
securely the final key will be
secure it requires both of them to mess
up to uh have a problem and we can
actually divide it further if we wanted
to we can have as many shares as we like
and we can also uh if we had
cryptographic hardware that was built
into a device during manufacture
we can now make use of that
cryptographic hardware even though we
cannot trust the
manufacturer private key yeah what you
typically want to do with uh private
keys is to device bind buying them you
know i've got my phone i want to layer
some keys onto that so that they can be
used on this phone and no other device
with threshold cryptography i can do
that without ending up being reliant on
a little black box that the manufacturer
provided for me
again the full protocol has more
controls as possible
okay so we've solved quite a few of the
problems for alice using encryption and
decryption for her own use
one that i'm not going to deal with
quite yet is what happens if she is
passing through customs somewhere
and her
device might be subject to
to seizure and we can actually
provision a key share onto alice's
device
so that we can turn the
decryption ability on or off
at a sep as an external key server so
that
alice can use this device to do her work
for the whole flight
turn her decryption capability off when
she's going through customs and only
re-enable it when she gets to her
destination
i've not got time to go into how we
connect up applications but we can do
that as well the existing tools will
automatically provision
ssh pgp s mine keys
to a device to to an account
and so once we've got the keys uh
provisioned to one device
all the other key devices that are
connected to that
account with the relevant set of rights
can now be automatic can now have access
to those private keys and so you
provision your ssh key to one device and
now all of your devices
that you might need to use ssh on can
have access to that
private key
without you needing to go through the
usual business of how you transfer
key private keys across devices
it also provides a set of end-to-end
encrypted catalogs so bookmarks
passwords network settings all the
things that
you really
want to share across your web browsers
but you don't want google
rifling through
all that can be stored in a mesh catalog
and it is stored end to end so the
service provider doesn't see it and the
contacts catalog i'm going to be coming
up to in the next piece
mesh contact assertions overcome a
mistake i think i made in
first generation pki where we thought
the idea of x509
pki was we were going to provide a
certificate that would be how you used
uh email or how you used ssl
and yes that kind of worked but it
it wasn't a good solution
what i now think we want to have is
a contact assertion where we can provide
all the information you need
to contact a particular person via any
of the modalities that that person has
granted to you so you can have a contact
assertion that says here's how you get
hold of me through the mesh
through skype through signal through
whatsapp etc and you probably would end
up having more than one of these
contacts and hand out slightly different
versions to your
work
colleagues to your friends to your
families to your golf club members and
so on
and
because we've got a
full pki a full personal pki backing
this whole system
the contact assertion is signed and is
authenticatable so once we've gone
through an initial context exchange
we've got the root of trust for the
other person and we can validate any
updates to that contact
and so what this means is that once we
meet somebody we bump phones we've
exchanged contacts
we've got a connection for life now
because that connection is between the
mesh accounts
which persist
rather than to the
messaging provider or the telephone
number or the address they might happen
to be using at that particular time
uh
trust management um yeah i spent most of
my career working on pki so
i think that one of the mistakes that
was made in peaks was
we thought that the idea of pkix was you
want to go to get a key you go to the ca
every time and you see if that key is
valid and
that wasn't a good model
the way that i think that we should be
doing it is we divide the trust
management problem up into two
the hard part the part that cas and so
on can contribute to is the problem of
establishing trust relationships in the
first place
if i meet somebody in person we can bump
phones uh i can read a qr code off a
business card i can go through the
remote
request protocol looks a bit like the
device request protocol
uh or a trusted third party can give me
that key
if i'm talking about a bank or a
business or whatever
ca broker trust is probably the way to
go
but once alice has decided to trust a
particular person
what she's really interested in is not
is this not going through that whole
establishing trust every time she uses
it
she wants to see is this party the same
party i dealt with last time
and so what
uh we need to do is for alice to be able
to track her contacts herself in her own
contact catalog and then she's got
bob's public key she knows
she's got bob's contact and she can use
that to verify bob regardless of which
service providers which protocols which
addresses whatever happen in the first
in the future
okay so
let's just see that happening so you
know
it's crypto we've got to do an alice and
bob example i've already done the
connection protocol it looks pretty much
like the device one and again it's
something that i want to get rid of and
put qr codes around
alice has encrypted a file and now bob
is going to decrypt it
um
okay
well that's just what we've been able to
do with the pgp and s mine forever
so you know nothing uh changed here yet
the problem is
decryption needs our dynamic
and this is one of the things that got
me you know when i was working for
verisign and even in a company that is
all about public key encryption
we weren't encrypting files and the
problem was that if i encrypted a file
and somebody else joined the key team
i would then have to add them to the
distribution list of that file
and if i didn't well that file has just
disappeared as far as they're concerned
and so
if you're trying to use
encrypted data
in a work environment you need to be
able to share it with all your
colleagues
including the colleagues that you
haven't yet met and this is something
that doesn't really work within the
canon of public key cryptography
[Music]
that we started with in the early 90s
so what i'm going to do here is alice
here has created a
encryption group it's group w at
example.com
and she's encrypted a file
fudoktext again
and encrypted it to that group
group w at example.com
and
if you can see here
alice has tried to decrypt it and it
won't let it hurt
and the reason for that is that even
though alice is the administrator of the
group
she hasn't been added into the group yet
she doesn't have the decryption
capability yet
since alice is the sole administrator of
the group she can add herself to it
but
we could actually use threshold
cryptography again to split the group
administration process so it might take
two administrators out of five
to add somebody to the group uh the fact
that alice is the administrator doesn't
necessarily mean she is allowed to
decrypt
so let's just go through and show that
uh we can decrypt that
and so we've added bob to that group
and now bob is going to synchronize his
account
and this time he can decrypt the
document
um
yeah the uh
the recordings on the uh
okay and we've got the file back again
so
what we this is this is powerful
we've got the ability to encrypt files
and decide after we've encrypted them
who we're going to share them with
and we can also delete bob
from that encryption group and now he
can't decrypt or the key server could
have logic built into it like okay if
somebody tries to decrypt more than 20
documents
in an hour then call their supervisor
because something bad might be happening
okay so what just happened behind the
scenes well
the first thing that happened was that
alice
generated a standard public private key
pair call it g this time
and sent the contact which is the public
key
uh off to somebody who encrypted a file
uh it's standard
elgamal encryption
the generate an ephemeral
and multiply the ephemeral by the public
key and
so now bob wants to decrypt that file
what he's got to do is that given
the
public ephemeral e dot p
he's got to find the value g dot e dot p
how do you go about it well
first thing that happens is that alice
is going to create a key share
first part of that is the alice
adsbot alice just creates a random
number
doesn't have anything to do with the
private key of the group at all can be
generated before the group's even been
created
and sends that off
to her
mesh service provider
so now we've got the value
scalar bob is
is stored at that
mesh service provider
she then sends the difference between
the group private key
and the scaler for bob
uh to bob
and then when bob wants to decrypt
what he does is sends an operating
instruction off to the mesh service
provider and it can perform one half
of the key agreement process
bob uses the value he was given to
provide the other half
add the two together
and we get the key agreement value that
we need to decrypt that document
i'm taking this
high speed
there is a series of podcasts that go
through it much slower
the point out the key point at this
point is we're sh
we're separating out the role of
decryption into two
we've shared that role between alice's
between bob's device
and that key service
the key service cannot be breached
because all the key service has is a set
of random numbers
it can control the use of decryption but
it cannot decrypt
and as i said we can split the
administration role and the full
protocol does have more encryption going
on
okay
so
yes
i'm saying this ease of use is critical
here
this is all better integrated into
applications and ideally what i would
like to be able to show you here
is an edge or a chrome extension
that would allow me to show you the
mesh
running in a web browser
and i just didn't have time to do that
so i wrote a web browser
okay this is this is a serious web
browser it's um
basically it uses webview 2
which is a layer a wrapper around chrome
that microsoft is putting together
and it basically allows us to take back
control the browser and do all the
things in the browser that
certain companies are not letting us do
of late
so what i've done is i've already
encrypted a file
um
and put it onto the server
and i've added the uh browser account
to um
to the decryption group and so now let's
just see what happens when we uh run the
example
and we can read the document
okay now let's take the uh browser out
nothing changes on the server
and we can't read it
so we can grant
and remove the authorization
to view documents at one website
on a completely separate key service
this is powerful and
the full protocols allow us to go as far
as end-to-end encrypted social media
you could have twitter you could have
facebook
where all the data
on the service is encrypted and the
server
and the service has no idea what the
users are doing
okay
oh yes
since i'm imitating steve i've got to do
one more thing there's also a second
factor authentication scheme built in
but it's not like these stupid numbers
you know if i'm going to do so you know
i i
well i think the second factor
authentication is the wrong idea
what i really want is a confirmation
when i'm about to do something stupid
you know
i think i should be able to log onto my
brokerage account with a password
but i would like to have it come back
and ask me for some
confirmation before i say buy 2 000
shares of ponzi
so what i really want is a scheme like
this
i try to do that
and back comes a message on my screen
saying
do you want to buy those 2 000 shares in
ponzi
and i accept it or i reject it
and
the acceptance or rejection
is uh signed
by the device goes back and we have a
complete audit trail of phil was stupid
enough to buy ponzi
that's what i think second factor
authentication should be
okay
so
the reason i'm here at hope
is that i need your help
i've spent the past five years uh
building this system
uh i have no external funding um
you know
i was web one point not so
i've been carrying this so far by myself
but
if we're going to make this work
i need to have more people involved
there's a ton of good stuff we can do
with this technology
and you know the possibility is
limitless and i'm only just showing you
the raw technology here
what we can do applying this technology
is far more important
an end-to-end secure messaging system
that isn't a walled garden yes i know
signal is an open protocol
but it is a walled garden
as far as talking to users i can only
connect to other
signal users
why don't we have an open
mechanism
for a messaging system where anybody can
choose their service provider and talk
to anybody else regardless
of which service provider they use
uh there's more work to be done on the
browser hooking up the uh bookmarks the
catalogs and so on
anybody here used delicious back in the
day
wasn't it great and it was taken away
from us
why
because we didn't control the service
wouldn't it be nice if we had an open
version of delicious where we could
browse share our bookmarks with other
users
and collaborate with them
end-to-end secure social media
it's possible
the dare formats are designed not just
for incremental authentication like you
get with a sock chain um
it also provides incremental encryption
and finally
iot
well
this is the model that every iot
user is trying to voiced on us
it is called razer and blades we connect
up all our devices to their service we
pay for the service and then all our
devices connect into our service
and of course it doesn't even work
because
we don't buy from a single vendor the
vendors squabble they you know some days
you can connect to your nest thermostat
with one stack and the other day you
can't
that is not a model that's working for
me
and anybody following adam savage's
build of the ecto-1 ghostbusters mobile
it was really great as long as it lasted
i bought into it you know i i'm 70 parts
into this 140 part thing
almost a thousand dollars
eaglemoss has gone bankrupt
so i now have half the parts for a necto
one
and
that reminds me of this
i bought a revolve hub
built my entire smart home around it
google bought revolve and shut them down
and now i have two and a half thousand
dollars worth of redundant
uh smart home equipment in my walls it
was three years before there was another
vendor that came up with a hub
that replaced the revolve one completely
that doesn't work
and you know what
if you start to read iot forums you will
see that a lot of people are getting
burned and getting fed up
this is the model that i believe we need
all the devices
connect to the users mesh account which
they control which they own and is
theirs for life
and
no racism no ray no blades
just
stuff working
when we built the net
it was intended to be it was you know
yes it was opportunity
but the objective of vint cerf and co
was to provide a communications resource
for everyone
something that everybody could use to
communicate
when i worked with tim berners-lee at
cern on the web
the web was a gift
it was tim berner's glee's gift
and it wasn't a gift to corporations to
collect rents
to sell our privacy
it wasn't a gift to the ponzi token
grifters
and it certainly wasn't a gift to
governments to help them control
populations
the gif the web was a gift to you
a gift to all of us and i'm asking you
today please help me to help you to take
it back
because you know what privacy matters
the net matters and our freedom matters
and i believe that
making use of
threshold cryptography is an important
tool that can make that happen thank you
okay i think that we do have time for
some questions so
yeah there's a microphone coming to
the microphone
hello
hi i'm xander um i have so many
questions i will probably have to talk
to you afterwards but i could ask a few
of them i'm curious what kind of
threshold cryptography you're using
threshold ecdsa threshold bls
i'm curious if you could give an example
a practical example
of who the mesh providers would be and
how we think about
potential collusion between the mesh
providers and i'm curious if you've
given any thought to um
proactive security of the private key
shares if you have any anything in mind
in terms of periodically re-sharing and
do you maintain the same public key
through that i'll limit myself to three
thank you
okay so
i will be in the so towards the first
part i'll be in the coffee shop most of
the conference so just hit me up uh
i'm here to make contacts
uh in terms of um
okay
in terms of uh who can be a mesh service
provider
uh well i had to take it out because of
time constraint
you can be your own mesh service
provider
all you need is an external static ip
address
and a domain name
now obviously at the moment that's ten
dollars a year for the domain name plus
five dollars a year for hosting
so you know that's like
70 a year that's probably more than uh
but
what i'm hoping for
is that in the you know
in the near term we will see some free
providers coming up to build the uh
community
and you know if you were doing this at
scale if you're
hosting a hundred or a thousand
you know
you're looking at a few pennies per
customer to support them
so i think that that will happen in the
short term but
longer term
most people have either
a cloud storage device
or an antivirus subscription
or an email subscription or whatever
and
looking at the additional effort that it
takes to
add the mesh as a mesh service provision
as a laid service
my hope would be to persuade the people
in that space
to step up and start offering it
and the uh the sector that's probably
the ripest for that is virtual private
network vendors
in that they're all about personal
privacy but you know
what does a secure pipe to their data
center really do for me not a great deal
i'm afraid but if i could have that plus
the mesh that would be starting to look
interesting
um
yeah
oh yes in terms of trusting the mesh
service provider
when i first designed the mesh i was
seeing seeing the mesh service provider
as being a zero trust service and i did
actually start using that term for a
while before it became popular
i don't use that term anymore
the mesh service provider never has
access to
any of the
encrypted data
of the user and all the you know all the
contact catalogs the bookmarks etc it's
all encrypted end to end
but it is trusted to withdraw the
ability to threshold decrypt so it's not
purely
zero trust and
yeah i mean this is where i started to
realize that zero trust is impossible
because
if you have a service out there
and you have threshold cryptography that
allows you to spread a roll between
multiple pieces you're going to start
giving
that service somewhere um something to
do so anyway so
so
first is a comment so you mentioned that
pki or public key encryption doesn't
allow for
the fact that if you want to decrypt
something and the user does not exist
yet
like you can't do that like you can't uh
encrypt something for future
uh purposes
um
but
if you think about like attribute based
encryption
in particular like cipher text based
attribute based encryption you can in
fact
encrypt things for like sets of users or
have like arbitrary policies
okay so when i was talking about public
key encryption i was talking about
the canon of cryptography was
established when openpgp launched
and one of the sad things is that it
closed
there's an incredible amount of stuff
like you know attribute-based encryption
um
you know um
recryption
uh threshold cryptography structured
cryptography well structured
cryptography we couldn't use because of
the patterns of course
and so you know what what i'm saying
yeah you need something else
beyond that original canon of open pgp
and wha and when you start to drill down
uh i mean originally uh when i presented
this the first time
i presented it as using uh proxy
re-encryption
i was only afterwards as i realized that
what i had actually done was to refactor
proxy re-encryption so it became a
threshold screen so actually when you
start to drill down
it all looks very much the same what is
important is the set of capabilities
and the reason that i'm
[Music]
focused on threshold
is that is a
we don't have a qualif uh uh
a standard yet quantum resistance
threshold scheme
but there are candidates that are
threshold capable that could be adapted
and so that's a route that i know that i
can go through to my quantum secure if i
need to
but
you know
there's a limited amount i can bring to
the table at once yeah and then uh
quickly the second question is if you
from like a business application uh
perspective would you say this is
similar to what octa does with like
single sign-on for like a variety of
resources
especially if you combine it with like
you know say like zero trust
quote unquote networks
uh i thought that octa's a saml vendor
are they
just from like an application layer not
like the internals
[Music]
i
think
yeah i i i don't know enough about their
product to comment uh
maybe we can take it offline cool thanks
is the code available today what is your
code available today oh yes absolutely
it's all up there on github
um
if you go to mathmesh.com you can
download um
the co the command line tools i've been
showing here
they run on windows mac and linux
all the code is in c sharp c sharp
itself is now
under an mit license or my code is under
an mit license
and the build tools that are used to
generate the code
are also on
on github and are also under an open
source license
thank you
reminders again please stay hydrated
today it is a scorcher out there also as
a friendly reminder
please remember that in indoor mask
space in indoor spaces at the conference
please wear your mask the only exception
is when people are at
a lectern or speaking like this thank
you