foreign
and my talk is on an empirical user
study of a decentralized identity wallet
our findings offer insight into
usability security and user control this
was joint work with Simon Parkin and
Paul Dunphy
much of our Lives has moved online and
as a result we need to identify
ourselves online and there are a number
of challenges that face this process
including the risk of identity fraud but
Additionally the fact that the user
lacks control over the collection and
use of their personal information
user-centric Technologies work to
address this by focusing on improving
privacy for the user we see examples
with the European digital identity as
well as offerings from companies such as
Microsoft
the identity wallet gives users control
over the transfer and disclosure of
personal information when identity is
Federated across online services
let's use a trust triangle here as an
example to help us understand this idea
we have the identifying party the
relying party and the end user the
identifying party can be a learning
institution which certifies that the end
user completed their studies there the
relying party could be a potential
employer who wants to verify this
information about the end user with the
identity wallet the end user could prove
that they were a student at that
institution and be able to control and
therefore choose not to share other
information with the relying party there
are several implementations of identity
wallets for example through every name
let's see and you port
so identity wallets combine multiple
security and privacy processes and these
are complex to understand and use
we see that this perception that control
over disclosure of personal data will
drive user acceptance however this is an
untested assumption
additionally we have few trials or
experiments that have focused on the
user experience
given this background then our research
question was what are the user-centered
privacy and security challenges facing
the centralized identity wallets
we carried out a user study we asked
participants to carry out three tasks
they needed to make a connection obtain
a credential from the identity provider
and build an identity proof
we then carried out a semi-structured
interview and we had participants answer
a mental model scale which helped us to
understand
um whether they got the difference
between these three tasks we then asked
them to fill out the system usability
scale to give us a sense of the
usability of the system
we were able to recruit participants who
were a mix of professional students and
retired individuals we had 15 male and
15 female participants 17 were based in
the UK us and 13 were from the UK and we
needed participants who had an Android
phone version 10 and above
looking at our results we'll just
highlight some of our key findings
we identified interesting
insights around the user Journey issues
for example with the use of QR codes
this was a challenge for participants
issues around for example focusing the
phone camera or being able to identify
that they needed to be on the identity
Wallet app rather than the phone camera
to capture information we identified
misunderstanding regarding security and
privacy for example users were unable to
distinguish or were confused by the
credential versus the decentralized
identifier did we also found that users
were uncertain around device switching
not knowing whether they should be
carrying out a particular task on the
identity wallet at the identifying party
or at the relying party
there were also authentication
challenges because participants had to
authenticate themselves using a password
so in cases where we had alphanumeric
characters this proved a challenge in
terms of just identifying where
particular keys were across different
keyboards and environments
results we found with the sqs
unacceptable score at 71 however we want
to highlight that this still shows that
there's more work needed
looking again then at the qualitative
results this is just to give us an
overview of some of what we found so if
you think about then security privacy
and Trust in decentralized identity we
identified four themes we have current
challenges with identity we see certain
assurances participants had about the
identity wallet service their
expectations of the identifier as well
as them examining the stakeholders and
their rules and trying to understand
that so I'll touch on a little bit of
this in our results
so starting off with current challenges
with identity we found that participants
were resigned to over sharing data kind
of highlighting well that's a ship that
has probably already sailed there's not
much that can be done about that we also
saw that some participants were
comforted by the fact that they were
asked for a lot of information thinking
it doesn't happen as often or that they
had some control over you know in in a
physical context for example being able
to hand certain information to you know
someone that they can see in front of
them
they highlighted life-changing problems
for example one mentioned because they
shared a name they had a common a name
that is common
um they highlighted that this you know
their name came up on a kind of watch
list and that caused delays when they
were trying to make some purchases and
we also see them highlighting
convenience and ease of use for example
just highlighting that they've been
improvements um processes used to take a
week for example but now they take uh
less time
looking at the assurances about the
identity wallet service users do not
perceive that they were in control right
they instead thought that the
identifying party or the relying party
had greater control in that scenario we
see them highlighting a fear of Bad
actors just thinking oh we're just going
to see a new breed of hackers coming up
we also identified issues that were
interestingly related to what um
caused participants to trust the process
here we see them kind of saying well I
don't think I trust my device I would
expect the bank has greater security or
you know has something better than what
I have and they also like the fact that
there was this separation of concerns
the fact that the identifying party
would not know that they've provided
information to the relying party that
was something that some participants
appreciated
next let's talk about what expectations
they had of the identifier we see a
sense of confidentiality they thought
it's kind of like a password and they
wouldn't expect to be sharing that some
found the procedure confusing thinking
that it would throw off the average user
um identifying um the identifier and
coding their identity they expected that
it would have information about their
address their date of birth just linking
it to what is familiar
um to them with other materials that
they would use to identify themselves
and finally we see them being confused
about how the identifier was generated
in the first place
finally when it comes to examining
stakeholders and their roles we
identified participants having
confidence in fallbacks so not really
seeing themselves as part of this
process and therefore having
responsibility kind of thinking some
other organization would be in place to
help me out or I can reach out to some
other organization to provide backups
and so on but they didn't really see
themselves as part of that process
others highlighted that it was
unfamiliar that it's definitely
different than a lot of other apps that
they've used and we also noted um
varying interpretations of minimization
others kind of saying well I might want
to withhold certain information but I
may not be able to say no
so in conclusion we are able to
highlight four key issues here
first off is just noting this perception
of security and the fact that our
participants Drew trust from the key
actors who are in the study scenario as
opposed to the technical mechanisms
um that are used in identity the the
decentralized identity wallets
we see a user understanding of entities
in control as a challenge so complex
Technologies a lot of this is hidden
from users so they didn't quite
understand or found it difficult to tell
them apart
the fact that the complete user autonomy
is expected was something that our users
didn't anticipate the fact that they had
responsibility for example of our
backups or you know recovering from
failure was something that they didn't
have in mind and finally we just want to
emphasize or highlight that ID wallets
need good usability as an example one
place to start is just with thinking
about how we can use terms that are
easier for users to understand thank you
very much for your attention and I
welcome any questions