foreign
Center
together with my colleagues from umio
University and teovin we investigated
security perceptions of anti-stock away
apps and compared them with the app's
actual abilities
so users face a problem of choice when
you search for anti-stock aware on the
Google Play Store you find at least 147
different apps with 50 000 downloads or
more
so as users have to decide somehow which
fulfills their security requirements but
we also know that on Android what apps
can see about other apps behavior is
very limited so we
assumed that some form of misconceptions
would be involved in this evaluation of
security
we wanted to investigate these
misconceptions to maybe improve decision
support and help users choose secure
apps
so how did we do that so we chose two
case study apps anti-spy Mobile Pro and
look at mobile and we use the app store
reviews to understand how users
communicated their trust in the app
and this works so many of these reviews
actually talk about privacy and security
things about the apps some also about
payment issues but there's lots of
information industry use and then
afterwards we looked at the apps
themselves
so we use cognitive walkthroughs to
understand how the apps user interaction
Works under regular use and also during
simulated security incidents so when we
installed stock aware on the phones
and then we also use static and dynamic
program analysis to understand the app's
actual detection mechanisms so what they
do to decide if something is a stock way
or not
so after our review analysis we found
five approaches of how users Enchanted
trust into Apps one of them was by
experiencing potentially harmful
incidents
so some of them were very positive so oh
this app saved me from this incident
somewhere also very negative so oh no my
app should have noticed this but it
didn't
um but the latter one was rather rare
because you actually need to know it at
the under attack
uh one also very common one was
reassuring user experiences so when
users straight up said it feels like a
guardian angel I feel secure
um also
some users build trust over time so
after a period of no major incidents
they said oh yeah this is a good sign or
also sometimes this is a bad sign it
should have found something
some users also straight up tested the
app's ability said oh no it didn't
detect so they installed stock aware and
said oh no it didn't detect this one
this app is trash
and very few actually use third-party
recommendations meaning getting advice
from family members who were I.T Savvy
or one actually used
a navigation from a magazine
so when we use the when we conducted the
cognitive walkthrough so in the
incidence of potentially harmful
uh security
incidents and we found that there was
often a lack of information about
consequences
so I didn't really say what kind of
effect on my life this would have if
this app would stay there and also a
lack of reaction option so very often it
was just the install or ignore which in
the use case of stock aware is sometimes
not what you want
and on the regular use especially if you
look at mobile we found lots of positive
feedback and also immediate feedback on
user interaction so when users did
something and immediately got feedback
this can help support mental models of
what's going on and one thing that I
especially liked was look at permanent
notification that everything is okay
and during our static and dynamic
program analysis we found how they
actually detected these stock rats and
and display Mobile Pro use the package
based block list approach which is a
faultier approach since on Android you
can just
decide which package name you want to
use
and in addition to that they also use
the heuristic based on app permissions
so if you got several permissions in
your app they said oh this is possibly a
buyable spyware application which is
also why signal is triggers this
heuristic
um and this block list does not get
updated during use you actually have to
update the app to get updated
information about which apps are blocked
look at mobile there's a bit more
sophisticated it collects information
from the package manager creates a
signature out of that and compares the
different local database and this
database is regularly updated uh to
bring use from a server I think once or
twice a day
so what we found is that user security
perceptions is mostly not related to the
actual detection abilities the only
approach where these two things connect
is when users personally test these
abilities by installing stockholen I
think this is one of the major ways we
could try to improve user users decision
um by helping support that
and we also found that user experience
of these talk away apps really affects
these perception perceptions and also
their choice so that is actually a call
for us to really invest more time in
designing that and thinking about how
the user experience may affect what
users think
but which also brings us to the problem
of potential security theater because
it's very easy to just have a permanent
notification that says everything is
okay but not actually doing anything
uh yeah and we recommend that these apps
maybe provide more context
context-specific advice and give users
more agency apart from the installing or
ignoring
we thought it would be really awesome if
we could find ways to demonstrate
stockway detection abilities to users
we're not entirely sure on how to do
that maybe with some kind of test kit so
that users not only get an impression
how good this detection works but also
how it works when something is detected
and lastly we should not forget
um operating systems still have a lot of
power on which stock aware works on a
mobile phone or not and we need to
leverage these abilities more so that we
reduce the problem of actually having
stock Orient phones
so to summarize
we analyzed users perception with App
Store reviews we analyzed how the app
works with cognitive walkthroughs and
program analysis and we hope that our
findings help decision support
um that we in future may be design
better secure experiences and also call
for a better operating system
limitations for stock aware
so yeah check out our full paper there's
link you can find me also on the hallway
later if you want to talk and I would be
open to questions