foreign
weisel from the Internet safety labs and
I'm here to talk about informed consent
and participant data privacy we'd like
to be sure that the data about our
research participants stay between us
and the test participant but are our
participants fully aware of the data
sharing agreements underlying the
participants use of these testing tools
the confidentiality agreement that they
have with us is only part of the picture
in this short talk I'll discuss how to
ensure your participants know their data
is collected and how it might be used or
shared beyond the scope of the covered
research project I'll focus on a mini
audit of several user testing software
packages that we performed based on the
10 attributes for a respectful me to be
commitments that underlie our safe
technology specification researchers
collect and store data with a number of
different research tools that in turn
use underlying technology that may also
access this data we call that a need to
T relationship knowing who might be
eavesdropping through the testing
platform's relationship with these
underlying tools helps you to evaluate
whether you are exposing your team or
your participants to risks that come
with access by these Technologies a lack
of notice and consent to share data is a
significant risk while the risk of the
researcher are similar to those of the
user testing platform the platform Bears
responsibility for ensuring that anyone
participating in a test on their
platform has an appropriate level of
notification of the data being collected
and shared as well as allowing the
participant control over whether to
continue now let's look at our audit
researchers collect and store data with
a number of different research tools and
that creates that me to T technology
relationship that we spoke of before our
mini audit it's not randomized and only
reflects the software packages that we
either have been using in our own
research or those that we've documented
in forums that we participate in but
you'll notice right here that most of
the software we looked at share data
with Google and other external vendors
at least one shared with Facebook and
two shared with Amazon and Microsoft you
can see that just for these eight
companies there are a few dozen
companies or company assets that are
also receiving data the ones in bold are
advertising or tracking software and
many of these tools aren't necessarily
exploiting user data but they are doing
ways to entities that now have some
access to your participants data for our
study we used a tool called track or not
that exposes tags allowing data sharing
between entities and what you're seeing
here is a map of the underlying
connections between the testing software
and various first and third-party
Technologies we were particularly
interested in advertising networks
analytics and trackers that are
represented in blue red angle we started
with Google and Microsoft forms because
they are popular free tools that a lot
of people use and don't require a lot of
expertise to set up we expected to see
sharing with their own advertising
networks but it turns out we only found
on Microsoft sharing with Bing ads a
Savvy user may see that Google has its
own privacy policy here at the bottom of
this form and they may also May note
that it would be in a addition to any
data policy for the study that you
present to them and also notice that the
this form here has a line saying that
the survey contains a completion code
for survey swap which is a panel
recruiting company and this indicates
that the participants might have some
additional third-party technologies that
are in play here but I don't see any
reference to privacy and consent
practices of these underlying
Technologies so maybe Google doesn't
share much but survey swap data
indicates that participants in the study
are potentially being exposed to data
sharing from the panel company pretty
extensively we ran a few other tests
here are the tracker maps at a couple of
usability testing platforms That We
examined and you can see that at least
one is sharing with doubleclick and
Google survey vendors tended to have a
relatively small number of tracking
vendors and the third group that we
looked at was those panel recruiters
where we actually did see a lot of
activity sharing with entities like
Facebook ads double click on Microsoft
marketing and Adobe metrics at least in
this one I mean when you look at these
you should be asking yourself whether
your participants are aware that these
entities may have access to their data
we feel it's a good idea to remind
participants about any meat to T consent
relationships that they may have when
they participate in your study so what
can you do product development is flawed
often there is no consent when testing
with potential users so researchers
should advocate for informed consent
through a form that highlights all
potential recipients of participant data
including any additional data policies
underlying the usability platform
software or panel recruitment agencies
software platforms should take a close
look at their data protection
responsibilities and make a greater
effort to inform participants and test
creators of their data sharing policies
and this should be not just once but
every time you create a new study and
every time your participants participate
through those Technologies I'm looking
forward to hearing any questions that
anyone may have enjoy the rest of the
conference