foreign
my name is Florian and I'm trying to
establish using virtual reality as a
research method in usable security and
privacy and I will just talk you a bit
about you know the idea of using VR
studies for the research we do within
our community
so on the plane to soups I had a yeah on
the plane to Boston to zoops right I had
a look at the proceedings last year I
wanted to see what research methods do
we actually use in our research right
and not surprisingly out of 36 accepted
papers last year more than 20 used
online service right so online servers
are great we can reach a lot of people
from different countries it's very
affordable actually to recruit people
and we can you know click go to bed
eight hours later we probably have a
huge sample right next to online service
we have lots of different research
methods ranging from interview studies
to lab studies to ethnographical studies
and so on so there is a lot of stuff out
there now talking about usable security
and privacy research in the lab I just
picked some random examples here you
know these are all great works which
basically propose a novel usable secured
in privacy prototype and they do some
user testing in the lab and often that
actually involves physical hardware and
you know
participants need to commute to the lab
to interact with this with these systems
the problem here is that
um two years ago I did an interview
study with uh with a few experts from
our community and the reality is
actually if we do such studies you know
we are recruiting participants by
knocking on the doors of friends and
colleagues and be like hey you know come
and do my user study I will give you 10
right this is reality actually this is
how people recruit participants and it's
really sad because also sometimes the
research we do is based on the hardware
we have available right and I thought
about okay you know how can we support
and facilitate researchers in the
research we do and you know push forward
this in in the space we are working in
so what I propose here is basically uh
instead of having the reality and
conducting user research in the lab with
physical Hardware we can basically
replicate that into a virtual
environment which we call virtual
reality right so virtual reality is
nothing else that basically immersing
users into a virtual environment and
letting them interact and experience a
virtual replication for example of a
real world space this basically means we
can create virtual replicas of lab
environments right so we can still you
know put users into a lab Environ
environment and evaluate our in this
case authentication method but we can
also create more realistic experiences
in this example here we replicated an
ATM and we went through an ATM
authentication process and we let
participants withdraw cash so why is
this important so first of all
um security is never a primary task
right so when you go to an ATM your aim
is to withdraw cash but you need to go
through an authentication and in in such
a way we can basically simulate a more
realistic authentication environment in
the lab through the help of virtual
reality so we in this uh virtual
environment here you can see a user one
of our participants interacting with an
ATM and we evaluate the novel
authentication system but the way in how
we present the authentication system is
more realistic than you know coming to a
physical lab sitting in front of a PC
and then you know authenticating so this
is actually what we can make here to
really support more realistic usable
security research in the lab so another
thing why this is important so I picked
here two papers one from the look at all
and one from Volcom at all and if you
have a look at these papers both
published at soups uh you know in 2010
and 2018
they try to understand how people
interact and behave in front of ATMs the
challenge here is that if you do this in
the wild you need to consider a lot of
ethical and legal considerations which
makes it super challenging to conduct
that type of research right but what if
we can move that type of research into
the lab through the help of virtual
reality because simply asking uh you
know Financial Industries industry
Partners to get access to the ATM is
probably not happening right
um
so now svr or you know using VR um you
know the golden future of what we do no
obviously not right but what I want to
um say here is basically we have this
usable privacy and security research in
the lab right and we move that online
through the help of online surveys we
deployed apks
we conduct browser-based studies and
that's a huge success right that really
forged forward the research we do and
you know as redmart says online surveys
or interviews those are key techniques
to understand and you know improve how
human decisions making affect security
so maybe also you know as part is like a
small bit of the research we're doing
the lab is actually research that
involves hardware and also to understand
how people interact with novel usable
security and privacy systems so maybe we
can use here VR as a research method to
make the same step we did with online
service right we could transition that
online as well because these days
millions of people have access to
Virtual Reality headsets right so if you
conduct a user study on a smartphone for
example you could do the same now with
virtual reality headsets almost 15
Millions have access to an Oculus Quest
2 device right and I mean there is a lot
of interest these days
so finally
um I just want to conclude with with a
question and maybe uh you know we as a
community start thinking about how can
we now make use of Novel technology to
you know support and facilitate
researchers and maybe other transition
um our Research into practice in the end
so you know maybe you can think about
this question uh review our specific
research field it might be suitable to
use VR it might not be suitable and I
think you know having access to more
research methods
um Beyond um you know more traditional
ones can be a way to really push forward
the research we do thanks a lot I also
want to thank all the institutions
all my partners who funded my research
so far and I'm happy to answer any
questions you can also get in touch with
me via email or on Twitter I'm very
happy to chat to you thanks a lot