okay so thank you everyone for being
here and thank you to Ada and Eleanor
for being wonderful mentors and just
people in general so this is a
replication paper called how well do my
results generalize now and explores the
external validity of online security and
privacy surveys
so this is based on a paper by Alyssa
red miles John Cross Michelle masrick
called how well do my results generalize
and Based on data collected in 2017 they
explored the generalizability of Amazon
Mechanical Turk or mturk to the U.S
population in terms of security and
privacy behaviors and experiences and
they found that mturk was relatively
generalizable for most things such as
advice sources experiences and feelings
of knowledge but it was not
generalizable for questions about
behaviors possibly because the people on
these platforms tended to be a bit more
tech savvy
they also found that generalizable
populations on these platforms tend to
generalize well for those under 50 or
with some college education
now 2017 was five years ago and a lot
has changed since then so welcome to how
well do my results journalize now 2022
Edition
and so how have the online platforms
that people use for surveys changed
since 2017. researchers still use both
mturk and prolific though prolific has
become ever more popular recently it was
not commonly used in 2017 but now seems
to be more popular than mturk and we've
also seen a drop in quality from Amtrak
data possibly because of an increase in
the number of bots on the platform
so this leads us to a few questions
firstly can we replicate prior results
about the representativeness of mturk to
the U.S population in terms of security
and privacy surveys and we ask a similar
question for prolific how well does
prolific generalize to the U.S
population
before we go any further let's talk a
bit about generalizability
right ideally we'd be able to survey
everyone in the United States including
Hawaii and Alaska and get them to tell
us their security and privacy behaviors
and answer our questions
that's first really expensive and also
not possible so the state of the art
used by Major organizations such as Pew
are called weighted probabilistic
samples so they make sure to recruit
hard to reach populations such as those
who are older not as tax Savvy or don't
have internet and they collect data that
after waiting is within a few percentage
points of the actual U.S population
demographics
now these kinds of large-scale
probabilistic samples are still not
feasible for most security and privacy
researchers they take a lot of time and
a lot of money so we turn to things like
mtric and prolific and so the question
is okay so how well do these platforms
generalize
and to answer that we did a qualitative
analysis of questions asked by security
and privacy research in the last year
and identified five major categories of
questions
the first one is behavioral questions so
actions users take so what they do would
do or have done such as their social
media use do you use Facebook
the second type of question were
experience questions so whether or not
certain events or experiences have
happened to the user so has someone
taken over your social media or email
account
third type was Knowledge Questions so we
defined these as those that have
factually correct answers so for example
what does it mean to have a privacy
policy and the way we asked these there
was one correct answer three to five
incorrect answers and a not sure or I
don't know option
there's also perceptions questions so
these are opinion questions about
attitudes such as trust Comfort levels
mental models so for example how
comfortable people feel with certain
uses of their personal data
and finally there are beliefs questions
so these are more Norms based about what
should or ought to be true so should
Americans have the right to have certain
types of data deleted
and so we identified a survey conducted
by Pew Research Center that had
questions in all five of these
categories and from each category we
took four to eight of these exact same
questions and asked them again on mturk
and prolific to compare the answers from
these platforms to pews samples answers
so let's take a look at our data sets
so the Pew Research Center data we
didn't collect ourselves it was the gold
standard to which we compared our
answers from the online platforms
because that's the closest we have to
the American populations ideas
for mturk we collected 800 samples and
we limited it to those in the United
States with above a 95 approval rate and
over 50 completed tasks because that's
the general default that most people
would use for decent quality data on
mturk
for prolific we have two samples so the
first one is the gender balance sample
and so we chose the gender balance
sample rather than a raw correlative
example I mean yes prolific sample
pardon me because in Fall last year
there was a viral Tick Tock and it
caused an influx of young woman to go to
prolific so even now I believe there's
around two times or three times as many
women as men on the prolific platform
and for Olympic was like oh this isn't
great because we're a survey platform so
to mitigate this they implemented a
feature called gender balance which is
available to researchers at no
additional cost that gives us equal
numbers of men and women when you deploy
your survey so that makes sense for
people to use as the default
and lastly we have the prolific
representative sample which the platform
also offers and it is generalizable to I
mean it is representative of the U.S
population in terms of age sex and race
and in terms of the time it took to
collect our data the gender balance
sample and amateur example are quite
similar around two hours whereas the
representative sample took quite a bit
longer similarly in terms of cost the
enteric sample and gender balance sample
are similar whereas the representative
sample costs more
so let's take a look at how these things
performed on the
y-axis we have each category of question
we asked and how will each sample
performed in each category
on the y-axis we have total variation
distance or TVD which measures how far
each sample differs from Q on a scale of
0 to 1. so this is a measure of distance
some smaller is better as the arrow
indicates and so if you get zero that
means your sample's answers were
identical to Q's answers
and what we see here are the prolific
samples performed similarly well in
terms of generalizability whereas mterk
doesn't perform as well now this is raw
data and most of us are not going to be
using raw data right we're going to be
using attention checks waiting and
things like that which leads us to
another question right what are the
effects of data quality measures on
generalizability and based on that what
are current best practices for online
surveys
and so our data quality checks include
reading attention checks so this one is
select the correct multiple choice
answer we tell you which one it is
this one is the free response text
question so we ask users to type in
their own responses to what is digital
privacy
and finally captures this one is click
the traffic light yeah
all right we also look at the effects of
waiting and breaking so as you can see
here the data on prolific excuse very
young and so very on a very high level
waiting is a statistical technique that
re-weights data to match the proportions
of your target population in this case
the US population in certain categories
and the categories we chose were age
education race and sex
so using these data quality checks we
found that over 39.1 percent of our
amateur example failed the text box
attention question so when they were
asked to type in an answer to Define
data digital privacy over 300 people
failed people Bots whatever no one
really failed our captures but most
people passed the other attention check
which was the select the correct
multiple choice which seems to imply
that Bots are getting ever more
sophisticated
less than one percent of either prolific
sample failed the text box attention
check so given this we wondered what
happens in a best case scenario so what
happens if we restrict the results to
those who are under 50 or with some
college education which are known to be
generalizable populations if you remove
people who failed any attention check
and reapply waiting
and so this is what we have again once
again Lower numbers are better because
they mean these match closer to the Pew
results and we see that the mturk data
quality improves significantly right
though it's still a bit worse than the
best case prolific data also similar to
findings from prior work the categories
of questions are not similarly
generalizable in particular behavior and
knowledge do not seem very generalizable
whereas experiences perceptions and
beliefs are
so in summary what did we learn overall
it seems that both the prolific
representative and gender balance sample
are fairly similarly generalizable and
so it'd be up to researchers to
determine trade-offs between time and
cost
in terms of mterk the best case scenario
does fairly decently and it is still so
much better than a raw M Turk
sample
we find that for certain categories
particularly experiences perceptions and
beliefs online platforms do tend to
generalize fairly well whereas for
things like Behavior particularly social
media use and knowledge they do not
perhaps because people who use the plus
platforms tend to be more online or more
tech savvy
if you believe that your sample might
have a lot of bots we do suggest text
box attention check questions over other
types of attention checks it seems to
have the best effect on data quality and
in terms of waiting and raking we didn't
find that parametric this had too much
improvement in generalizability but
perhaps that's because we have to decide
on what categories to rake on and we
didn't wait on things like text
happiness Etc which might be important
so overall researchers can definitely
learn a lot of useful information from
online privacy and security surveys but
we have to be aware of the limitations
whether it be from platforms populations
or just the types of questions we ask
thank you