foreign
you've heard the title of the
presentation already it's a study I've
conducted together with Victoria Park
and Delphine Reinhardt we're all from
the University of cuttingen
so first
um
there we go first thing about
differential privacy I will not go into
detail just a little overview
we focus on the two models of
differential privacy the global model
which you can see on the top and the
local model on the bottom what does
differential privacy do it basically the
idea behind differential privacy is to
perturb data in such a way to protect an
individual's privacy while keeping the
underlying data distribution intact by
adding noise to the data we can see here
on the top in the global model that the
data is perturbed so the noise is added
globally so to speak like on a like you
can imagine a company server whereas in
the local model which you can see here
on the bottom the data gets perturbed
locally on for example the users device
and only project data leaves the device
so
to to take away basically is that raw
data never leaves the device in the in
the local model which means it is more
privacy preserving
so what did we do uh we kind of like saw
the idea behind our study and the
original study which we replicated is
can differential privacy increase the
user's willingness to share data why do
we need the data for example for machine
learning applications
so as I've said the original study was
conducted by iping Shong and colleagues
in 2020
and we know
um that uh country's culture and privacy
regulations among comp among continents
impact privacy attitudes so therefore we
thought it was worthwhile to replicate
the study in another cultural context we
can see here the
small overview of about the differences
of our sample in the originals
our sample was Germans
representative of the German population
in terms of gender age and education
whereas you can see in the original
study which was conducted on mturk it
was heavily skilled skewed towards
younger higher educated people primarily
from the US and India
so we conducted two experiments the
first one it was an online questionnaire
where we put our participants into a
scenario where we told them you just
downloaded a health app called orange
health
and this app requires certain sensitive
information of you
um
and the app needs that information in
order to improve the app locally for you
to recommend certain things for you and
we also want to improve the app globally
for all users for for example for
machine learning applications so we had
three groups three conditions one was
exposed to differential privacy one to
local differential privacy and a control
group and this all is in line with the
original study and we also copied the
questionnaire basically verbatim from
the original study
so this is basically what our
participants saw they had this mock-up
basically of an IOS app
um where they were post 14 questions for
example date of birth weight height but
also more sensitive questions like
income level medication
um
like medical history and so they did not
actually have to answer these questions
but rather
um indicate how they would their
potential answers to be processed so
they could choose to have it used only
by the app locally
which would be in line with people who
are a bit a bit more privacy preserving
it could be used by the app locally and
the server so basically give the data
away
uh and also of course for those who
don't did not want to give out the data
the potential data
um to not share with neither the Apple
model server or they could also choose
not to answer
so what could we confirm from the
original study that our participants
just as in the original study did not
differentiate between differential
privacy like the global and the local
model of differential privacy answers in
both conditions were very consistent
very uh similar so there was no
difference between among these groups
um we have however some new findings
some differences that are in our sample
the communication of differential
privacy in both groups local and Global
had in fact an uh an effect on their
willingness to share data especially
when it comes to high sensitive data and
also we've asked an additional question
which was not asked in the original
study whether they use a health app in
their private life and participants who
actually use the health app showed more
willingness to share data
now for a second experiment uh it was
the same scenario you download the
health app that requires certain
sensitive information and so but in this
case we had in line with the original
study 11 different descriptions of
global and local differential privacy to
find out which of these descriptions
showed the greatest effect in the
willingness to share data but also in
the understanding and the comprehension
of differential privacy so
we were first asked do you want to share
data and and why or why not and secondly
and more importantly in this experiment
the focus light on comprehension
um so it they could self-report their
understanding of differential privacy
but also later kodam had to answer five
comprehension questions an example you
can see here can an attacker see real
data if they get access to the database
and for other questions in this in this
line
so
uh I will just show one interesting
finding from from the second experiment
uh if we focus on the y-axis one moment
we can see here we post five
comprehension questions they get one
point if they answered a comprehension
question correctly so five points is the
maximum and you can see that the scores
these red dots here are very very low
and
if we look at the x-axis here these are
this is the time spent in seconds
looking at the description of
differential privacy so basically people
who just spent uh less than 20 seconds
on the description scored
significantly lower than people who
spend around three minutes there is no
increase afterwards which suggests that
um participants who actually spend more
time reading and understanding or trying
to understand the description also
understood uh differential privacy
better
so what could we confirm we had a very
similar overall sharing rate con
compared to the original study around
also roughly 50 of our participants
wanted to share data on the differential
privacy and we had an overall
difficulty to comprehend rate which was
also very similar to the original study
meaning 13 around uh indicated that they
found it hard to understand differential
privacy which if you remember this slide
you know they were wrong uh so we have
some differences and additional findings
so among our 11 groups there were there
weren't many differences
um so so the differences were there but
not as Extreme as they were in the
original study
so we had very like homogeneous results
basically we could correlate the I.T
background like a self-reported I.T
background of our participants with the
difficulty to comprehend differential
privacy and also the actual
understanding which both show uh higher
results when participants had an I.T
background and also again the usage of
Health apps
significantly increased the willingness
to share
so for discussion and future work it is
clear from the original study and
through our now I would say like
validation that differential privacy is
not well understood in its currently you
know performance currently uh
transported form
um our participants had an like All or
Nothing mindset meaning they either
didn't want to share anything or they
wanted to share with uh globally and
locally so with a server and and the app
meaning that the difference between
Global and local differential privacy
was also not present in our study
and we know that text is not the ideal
way to communicate any privacy related
things like privacy notices and anything
so also for differential privacy we need
better
metaphors which we will uh hear about
later I guess but also like graphical
descriptions of differential privacy
so this concludes my talk and thank you
very much for your attention and I'm
open to questions