BRANDON WILEY: Hey, everybody.
(applause)    BRANDON WILEY: Thanks for coming out.
Okay.
Well, I got a lot of slides, so I'm going to try to just burn through them.
We will just power through.
Try to pay attention to the first five minutes
of slides so that, you know, you'll be there
with me when we're hitting through this stuff.
Okay, I'm Brandon Wiley.
I have done some stuff.
I wrote a thing called Freenet in 2000.
DEF CON 2000 oh, thank you.
Raise your hand if you have ever run a Freenet node.
Yeah, my people!
Thank you.
National heros, every one of you.
Yeah, my first talk ever, I was 18 years old.
It was at DEF CON in 2000.
I presented about Freenet.
The entire description of my talk was this is about Freenet.
I drew the slides with Crayons.
And it was a packed room of people that came to go see
a talk based on that information.
And at Blackhat 2000 I presented Curious Yellow which was my
superworm design that was designed to destroy the Internet.
Purely theoretical as you can tell because the Internet
is still here.
You can hear that Charles Stross has a book call "Glass House" which
Curious Yellow is the thing that destroys humanity.
That was a great moment when he put that in there.
I used to work at BitTorrent.
I was there when BitTorrent bought uTorrent.
So I apologize for that.
But I did a lot of stuff at BitTorrent.
And then since then when I was at BitTorrent
is when I first saw deep packet inspection being used
to block BitTorrent.
In fact, when BitTorrent was when we noticed
that Comcast was blocking BitTorrent, before any of the press heard about it,
I was the guy that they sent to Comcast to try to reason with them.
Well, you know, how that worked out.
So I started doing I have been working on kind of anonymity stuff
and mainly kind in the censorship resistance side
of things for a long time.
So I know the folks from Tor from back
in the day and I have been helping them out more recently
with their new obfuscated protocols because Tor is being blocked in a lot
of places so they need a new protocol that's not blocked.
And then, finally, I have I wrote part of a book called "Peer to Peer"
for O'Reilly a long time ago.
So, anyway, those are my credentials.
Who cares, whatever.
I'm just putting this up so that I can establish my credibility
with you guys so when I start showing you pictures of cats,
you don't just be like, what is this?
I'm out of here because there is a lot of pictures of cats in my talk.
Thank you much (applause).
Cool, cool.
All right.
So let's get into it.
So my slides are taken from two different sources.
One is my children's book on Internet free done called "Free As
in Kitties."
The other slides are from my Ph.D.
dissertation so I meshed them together.
We will see how it goes, right?
So we'll start out with the Internet, what is it?
Let's define some terms.
Hopefully you guys have checked it out.
If not, it's pretty cool.
Should get on there.
There is a lot of stuff on a lot of cats and stuff.
And then how do we Internet with this Internet once we know what
an Internet is?
And then we get straight up into binary classifiers using
(inaudible) inference.
And that's fooling classifiers with polymorphic protocols
and then Dust which is what the talk is about which
is the polymorphic protocol engine and then I have info graphics.
If we have time I forgot to start my timer.
There we go.
Then we will talk a little bit I want to talk a little bit
about realistic fair models versus the fair models that everybody
else uses.
So, yeah.
First of all, the Internet.
It is the greatest technological marvel of our time and
the pinnacle of civilization.
It is an unprecedented way to deliver pictures of cats.
(laughter).
So I know what you're thinking.
You can't take a real cat and transmit it
over the Internet.
Believe me, I've tried.
It doesn't work.
That's and that log cat.
First step is we have to turn it into pixels with what
they call pixitization.
And then we get it into pixels and that's
a digital form that we can transmit over the Internet.
If we take this exact cat, we make it into pixels.
We have this, it is a pixel cat.
(laughter).
Fun fact, if you go on Google images and you are
or just on Google looks for things like 8 pixel cat you
will find girls who live in Oakland.
True story.
Okay.
Great.
We got this cat.
Now we need to turn it into numbers because as we know,
like computers they use numbers and stuff.
That's pretty easy.
We have all these various color spaces and things.
So we get a number mapping for each color and then we run it
through there and then we get, you know, a map of numbers, okay?
So now we're good.
Now we have something computers can understand and we can transmit it.
So first we got to do in the Internet, for some reason when
they designed the Internet, they didn't think it would be handling,
like, you know, big chunks of data like cat pictures it can only handle very
tiny chunks of data.
So we split all of the data into all these kind
of just randomly sized different things.
And then we call them packets.
And then we transmit them over an unreliable,
possibly unreliable medium, right?
(laughter).
And then they all arrive, maybe.
Maybe they arrive.
Maybe they don't arrive.
At some point, we try to cut and paste and stitch them back
together to get the packet.
And on the other end of the pipe, we get a pixel perfect exact replicate
sent through the Internet of the cat we started with.
There you go.
Yeah, Internet.
Internet's great.
(applause).
So what's the problem?
I mean, the Internet's great.
We can look at cat pictures.
It brings us all a lot of love and joy.
Like, who would ever want to try to stop this?
Well, robots.
(laughter).
Since the beginning of time, there's been a war
between cats and robots.
No one knows why.
All we know is that robots have been programmed
to hate cats.
Okay?
So here's out binary classifiers work, okay?
Robot looks at something.
It looks at the packets and it says: Is that a cat?
Yes or no.
Those are all the options we have.
That's why it is called a binary classifier.
That's the decision it is trying to make, cat, not a cat.
Now, because they hate cats, if it is a cat, they replace it
with a sad Panda.
All cats are replaced by sad Pandas.
Now, if it is not a cat, don't care.
Don't care.
Just pass it through, just exactly as it was.
Bananas, whatever.
Doesn't even know what bananas are.
It just knows what are cats because of binary classifiers.
Pass it on.
Okay.
The question is how do we fool a robot so we can transmit pictures
of cats over the Internet without having them replaced
by sad Pandas.
That's the yes.
How do we fool robots?
If you have been paying attention I said pay attention
the first five minutes you already know the answer, right?
Right?
(laughter).
You got to make cats look like bananas and then robots don't
care, all right?
So here's the secret code to my talk.
Don't take a picture of this slide.
This slide is not on the Internet version of the talk.
This talk is only about cats and bananas.
Kittens are free speech.
Sad Pandas are censorship of free speech.
Robots are filtering hardware made in America and sold to companies
all over the world to make it so that people can't access
the Internet and find out things about news, what's going
on in their own country during elections and other critical times
like that.
Bananas are just messages that filtering don't care about.
Cats are bananas reencoded to get past the filtering hardware.
(applause).
We are talking about deep stuff here.
This is really important sort of stuff because the Internet needs
to be free.
But, you know, I just wanted to segue into this.
I hope we are all at the same level, we all are on the same page
and understand the code, right?
You know the code.
I can tell you about my project.
Dust makes cats into bananas in order to fool robots so we don't have
any more sad Pandas.
(laughter).
That's the intro.
Now let's go into some details.
Robots can't see cats the way you and I see cats.
Hey, it is a cat.
They only see the packets.
They see the grid of excuse me.
They see the grid of numbers and then they have to use some kind
of statistical or rule based because they're robots,
they only know logic.
So here's one mechanism, right, which is you look at the lengths
of the packets.
It is grouped into these randomly sized packets.
You kind of count the first one is 38 numbers in it and you say,
you know, if things are in this kind of configuration, then it must be a cat.
Now, this probably sounds really dumb.
You think, that's not going to work.
That has nothing to do with whether or not it is a cat.
We are going to do a little audience participation test
to see if you guys can classify traffic based on packet lengths, okay?
Are you ready?
Here we go.
This is a graph of 8TCP packet lengths.
That's not a border.
That's a giant spike in the graph.
If you know about TCP that's because of the algorithm that takes
little packets and then just hopefully for you it bundles them
into big packets.
Since that's not turned off in HTTP, you have kind of this spike
in the largest possible size packets.
Okay.
Now this is HTTPS.
HTTPS disables the algorithm by setting the delay option and,
therefore, it has the totally different statistical
like it still has a lot of fairly big packets.
It doesn't have that spike on the end.
And it has this other spike kind of around 400 or so.
I don't really know why.
I just look at the graphs.
Okay.
So I have just showed you two different graphs.
Now I will show you a chart.
I will ask you if you can guess which one it is.
Okay.
So raise your hand if you think this is a chart of HTTP?
Raise your hand if you think this is a chart of HTTPS?
Okay.
Congratulations, you are all robots.
(laughter).
It was neither.
It was Dust, my project, pretending to be HTTPS.
So yeah.
Did a pretty good job, right?
(applause).
I kind of tricked you, though, because I didn't have that option
is this something pretending to be HTTPS.
You might have picked that because that's the obvious choice
since that's what we are talking about.
So, yeah, so packet lengths work as a way to determine if something
is one protocol or another protocol.
And the reason we care about this is because these days the way
they block the Internet is they don't say, hey, you are looking
at this thing that we don't want you to look at so we are going to block it.
They say, hey, you are using BitTorrent, blocked.
Hey, you are using Tor, blocked.
You are using SSL.
Blocked.
You are using a VPN, blocked.
That's crazy because you could be doing
all kinds of things.
If they can't look at what you are doing to determine
if they don't like it, they will block it by default.
For instance, there are circumstances where SSL has
been blocked and you can use unencrypted HTTPS.
That's okay if you can make your protocol look like.
Dust removes packet length information.
It doesn't just randomize it.
It randomizes it according to a target distribution
of whatever you want.
You pick a protocol and Dust will make your packet lengths look
like that protocol, any protocol, doesn't matter,
just give me some sample traffic.
I will sample it and make a profile and then I will make it look like that.
These are one of the tools I have made looking
at deep packet hardware and trying to figure out how it
is doing classification so we can, you know,
circumvent that classification.
I made this tool called Shaper.
You give it a model of a protocol, statistical model.
For instance, like a model of what packet lengths.
It then does the trick before and makes traffic that looks
like that, infinite traffic that looks like whatever you want it to look like.
We pass it through and we say, hey, is this such and such or not?
And then we get the answers back and then we can tell well
the different hardware is at classifying protocols.
And then once we can do that, we can get better
at making encodings that hide sufficient from classifiers.
If you have some hardware, you can throw traffic at it and test it
and see how it's doing classification.
Okay.
Second type is just looks and says, hey, there is some statistical properties
of this traffic.
Like, for instance, I see a whole bunch of 6s.
If there is a bunch of 6s, it means it must be whatever,
some particular type of traffic.
So here's some examples of that.
This is an English dictionary and I looked at the probability
of different bytes to occur in that dictionary.
The one on the far left is just Nulam because it
is a list of words.
Don't pay attention to that.
I didn't clean the data because real data is dirty.
So I'm showing you the dirty data.
So this is the main thing.
This is lowercase letters of the alphabet, right?
So you can see there is definitely a spike.
To the left is a little spike that's uppercase letters.
There is a lot of uppercase letters in the dictionary, a lot
more than you would think but less than lowercase letters.
Clearly there is statistical sort of stuff.
If you look at an U.K.
English dictionary, it is a slightly different sort of thing.
This is HTTP.
Oh, my gosh, it is the same spike.
Why is that?
Because HTTP traffic actually has a lot of ASCII letters in it, HTML
is lowercase letters, a little bit of a spike in uppercase letters.
You can see this bleeds three.
We know that this was English HTTP traffic or at least HTML HTTP traffic.
I feel like a lot of people think if you wrap your traffic
in something it hides it but a lot of stuff actually bleeds three.
Here is HTTPS.
Oh, my gosh, it has the same spike.
Why does HTTPS which is encrypted with the same spike
in those letters?
It is because SSL is encrypted but the header is not encrypted and
the header has a bunch of information that uses normal English
letters, like the name of the Web site and sufficient like that,
the SSL common name as they call it.
And that's how they they how they get you with the SSL,
that's how they get you with the encrypted traffic.
They look at the unencrypted header and it
is easy to tell you which protocol you are using.
So I think people say, just encrypt everything with SSL.
That doesn't work because you can tell it is SSL
and people block SSL.
So Dust fixes that, too.
Dust removes the statistical content information.
I use this thing called reverse Hoffman encoding where I encrypt everything
to make it random and then I reverse encode it to make it not random.
If you say the only bytes you can use are F and A,
I will give you a stream of just Fs and As that encodes your traffic,
whatever you want.
Whatever hardware distribution you want, I will make it look like that.
And then final I know you will be like that's stupid.
No one does that.
But, yeah, this is the most popular way
of classifying traffic.
You look for a sequence of bytes at a particular offset in the file
and then that's it.
You see this, for instance, HTTP traffic, you know, it starts with HTTP get,
HTTP post.
They just look at the first four bytes.
If it is HTTP, they classify it as HTTP traffic.
That's it.
And that is like 90% of all DPI classification that's, like,
actually deployed and used for censorship is just doing that.
Yeah, so we remove that, right, because that's not going to work.
So along those lines, I have this other tool that I made that
is part of the Dust suite of tools, which is for looking to figure
out what these byte sequences are because these signatures
they call them signatures are not public.
Like, they don't want to tell you what bytes they're looking
for because it would make it easy to obfuscate your traffic.
I have a tool that will take sample traffic and replay it
with all different variations where it blanks out certain bytes
and you can find the exact string they're looking for.
Again, you can do that for any protocol.
Okay.
So to break it down for you, what Dust does is if you were
to find a set of properties that deep packet
inspection hardware is looking at to filter and you define, you know,
which things go in which category based on those rules,
then for whatever property that is, Dust will randomize that property
to remove all information and it randomizes it
according to a probability distribution to force a classification
into whatever category.
So you tell me what categories your hardware has and I can make arbitrary
traffic get put into any of those categories.
The reason you want to do this is because you want to get
into the category that's not being blocked, whatever that is, right?
Like, there was a recent instance of an adversary blocking everything
except for HTTP and HTTP connections could only be 60 seconds long
and then they were automatically closed.
A lot of protocols had trouble with that.
Dust says, fine, 60 second HTTP connections,
let's do it.
It encodes all the traffic you have over that protocol.
Basically, if you left any messages
through then you have to let all messages through because we
will encode to all the messages it allows.
The point of all of this, I had this message server that you give
it arbitrary messages, it encodes them to look like bananas.
They are passed through and then people are reunited
with the cats that they love.
And that's really what it's all about is just letting people get
to the content they want to get to, post what they want to post,
read what they want to read and just have free speech
on the Internet.
Cool.
That's the end of my linear part of my talk.
And now I have several bonus slides depending on how much time we have.
And I think yeah, I think I ran through this pretty quick.
So I'm going to go yeah, let's go through them and then we
will do Q&A, maybe some of the questions will be related
to these slides.
Okay.
So sometimes people ask me about various other projects
and how Dust is different from these other projects.
I don't really think of them as competitors.
Like, I mean, people are going to choose they will use one kind
of encoding or another for their traffic to get it
past this filtering hardware.
Just use whatever works.
I mean, all you want to do is get past the filtering hardware.
If something works, do it.
If it stops working, then switch to something else.
I worked with Tor on their pyobfsproxy.
That's an example of a protocol where it just obfuscates.
It makes everything look totally random.
That's pretty good.
That will get you past a lot of things.
Some of the hardware will now flag stuff as random looking
at which point you can make a custom rule that says, hey, if it
is random looking, block it.
If you can't classify it, that's okay.
Just block everything that has high entropy.
If you have heard about the entropy attacks,
those are awesome attacks that work really well.
They are not widely deployed but you can custom configure them
into some of the hardware.
That's the issue with just obfuscating stuff.
You need the second layer where you shape it
to look like stuff that's whitelisted.
A lot of people are doing a lot of research
on mimicking specific protocols, especially HTTP.
People are just trying to make stuff that hides information
in HTTP.
So the problem with that approach is that people always choose
the most common protocols, the ones that they think like no one
will ever block this protocol because it is too important.
People used to say that about SSL and now it has totally been blocked.
People are really focusing on HTTP.
The problem with that is that the DPI hardware has
the most visibility into HTTP of any protocol.
There are actually whole boxes that just do HTTP interception and do, like,
semantic parsing of all of the headers and
all of that kind of stuff.
So you have to do a lot of work to look like HTTP.
In fact, there was this paper recently called "The Parrot Is Dead"
in which they talk about that they're pretty sure given any
kind of traffic that mimics some other kind of traffic they can make
a test exist where they can differentiate two
because there will be a difference
between your HTTP implementation a real HTTP implementation.
People are trying to do this crazy stuff and get
an actual browser.
They are trying to make FireFox load pages
and then they encode information in the way, like,
which pages you choose and the timing and stuff.
That's fine.
It is just like a very slow protocol.
You don't need to do any of that because like I said
before the DPI hardware is just most of the time saying are
the first four bytes HTTP?
And then that's all you need to do.
A lot of the hardware only looks at the first packet
because they're trying to scale and so they're basically cheating
in their design, right?
Instead of looking at all the packets because they want
to be able to push more thruput and tell people buying it,
we can handle your whole country's traffic, you don't need any boxes,
they look at the first packet and classify it and they say, forget it,
they stick with that classification.
I was talking to a DPI vendor and said they have to look
at 20 packets, oh, no, 20 packets before they can classify it.
It is just a lot easier than trying to be exactly like this protocol.
And then there is a really cooled project called Format
Transforming Encryption that you give it a grammar for a protocol,
if you say HTTP or FTP or SMTP and then it
will generate random messages that conform to that grammar.
That's a pretty cool project, so I would check that one out.
So the differences in what I'm doing, I'm not writing a protocol.
Like, obfs3 is the BitTorrent protocol
for obfuscation.
Most people are just thinking let's make one protocol that can never be blocked.
And I got to tell you, that doesn't exist.
There is no one protocol that cannot ever be blocked by anybody.
It just depends on your settings.
Like, your attacker, your adversary is going to have some configuration
on their hardware for block this, don't block this, and it is going
to be different for everybody.
There is no one protocol.
So instead, I wrote a protocol engine where
instead of updating it with each revision when it gets blocked,
you just change the settings.
Like, you say, okay, before we were making traffic look
at HTTP.
Now let's make it look let's do some UDP based crazy.
Let's make it look like Skype, whatever.
And then if they block that, then again just switch it up.
Switch it up every day.
In fact, don't even just mimic protocols.
I have this thing that I can't really convince anyone
is a good idea that I think is awesome which I call kymeric
(phonetic) protocols where you take, I don't know, like SMTP and, like,
NTP and then you just kind of smoosh them together
and you get this protocol that people are like, I don't know what that is.
Right?
And just keep them busy.
They got guys (laughter).
They got to configure this hardware.
They first have to notice your anomalous traffic.
Then they have to figure out what your doing and it splits
out your traffic from the legit traffic.
So, you know, just keep it rolling.
In fact, you could even with Dust just use
a as a private institution, you could make
up random distributions.
In this protocol, everybody will be five bytes long
or 1400 bytes long.
I don't think there is any protocols like that., You know?
So yeah.
My thing is purely statistical because that's how they look
at per packet is how the classifiers work.
So my stuff is per packet.
In the "Parrot Is Dead" paper, they use my work.
They say stuff like Dust will never work.
And it is like, right, it is not going to work against a bunch
of CS professors and all of their grad students in a lab, sure.
But against the actual deployed hardware,
it works awesome.
I know because I have the hardware and I pass it
through and it works awesome.
I think that's kind of one of the differences there.
(applause).
Thank you.
Another difference is with FTE, Format Transforming Encryption, it
is a great project.
You need a protocol specification so that you can
follow that grammar.
With Dust, you just give me some sample traffic
and I will just build a model from that.
In fact, the best thing is you give me some sample traffic
of traffic that was blocked and traffic that wasn't blocked
and I can from that make you a protocol that will be guaranteed
to not be blocked not guaranteed, but it won't be blocked
without even I don't even need to know what protocol.
You give me the PCAP files and I process them and we're done.
So a lot of people that are doing these specific protocols like HTTP modeling,
they model the protocol and they say, what does a protocol look like?
Let's look exactly like this.
What I do is I model the filtering hardware and I say: What
does the filter think that HTTP looks like?
Let's look like that and not do any more work necessary and get maximum
efficiency while definitely getting past that hardware.
You give me different hardware, I might come
up with a different protocol.
I think this all come downs to I'm aiming
for a realistic threat model.
I want to base my threat model on what's deployed and what's being
used to censor countries.
One more thing I just added right before the talk is that there
is no shared secrets.
Everything is totally public.
The source code is out there.
You can get it.
Even the protocol doesn't have any kind of shared secrets or anything.
So you can know that people are running Dust.
It doesn't help you figure out who is running Dust because the traffic
by definition looks like the traffic that you don't care
about, right?
So even if you downloaded you run your own
experiments, unless you know what settings people are using, it won't help.
If you know what settings, the battle is you have to make a better rule
for your filter that can tell between the mimic traffic and
the real traffic.
It is no longer like a war of technology, it is a war of who has
the better information, the better models.
So talking about threat models, so in the academic world,
the threat model hierarchy of threats is if someone just published
a paper and it won a best paper award, that's the adversary that you need
to attack was the adversary in that paper.
And then otherwise, if there is a recently published attack,
you should defend against that.
Otherwise, if there was an attack published before 2003,
no one cares.
No one is working on that in academic research at all.
Cool.
So that's kind of my issue with academic stuff,
is they are really cool at classifying traffic in the lab.
But, I mean, who cares because until it makes it
to hardware and deployed and being used for censorship,
it doesn't really matter.
I have a slowed about open source threat.
And I just want to say I don't mean to offend anybody.
This is my experience working on Freenet is the number one threat
is the number one threat you can think of.
Oh, that's what I have to defend against and I thought about it so it
is probably a serious attack.
Secondly, if someone on the mailing list comes up with it,
then it is pretty bad.
If somebody attacks your system in a Reddit threat, I know
because your system stucks because I broke it,
then that's what people defend against.
And then they add plausibility.
I have been there.
We did it at Freenet.
Everybody thinks you have to add plausible deniability.
This is a bad road to go down.
My fair model is based on is this attack actually being done
in the wild to censor traffic.
A lot.
That would be an example of the static packet,
the byte sequence trafficking, that's the number one thing.
If you don't defend against that, then we don't even need to talk
about there is obfuscating protocols that begin
with magic number in the handshake.
So if you just put that magic number to the filter, then the protocol is gone.
If you see it occasionally, that's good, too.
We'll do that.
Finally, if the capability is in hardware
but just hasn't been used, that's lowest priority but I
will still do that.
There are some really awesome hardware.
I met a lot of people actually this weekend that
were dealing me about some DPI hardware that sounded
totally sweet.
No one is using it.
But if anybody ever buys it so one of the things about DPI hardware,
it is old.
Really old, no one ever upgrades.
A lot of these countries that are filtering,
they are using 10 year old hardware.
That's the first thing.
10 year old hardware is the first thing to defend against.
You would be surprised at the protocols that fall instantly when
thrown against 10 year old hardware because they are reading the papers
or going on the mailing lists rather than looking at the actual hardware.
Let me see if I have more slides here.
Let's see.
(speaker off microphone.)    BRANDON WILEY:
Yeah, okay.
That's a good question.
So, yeah, so you have to have a client and you have to have a server.
And they both need to be speaking to protocol.
You need the public key of the server.
You need that because I need to have to be able to do
a handshake where we don't have to communicate anything that's not
purely random.
Let me see.
I won't really get into the key exchange.
I don't have time.
But the key exchange and everything is all purely random.
You need to have the public key ahead of time.
When you find out the address of the server, you need to find
out its I.P., its port, its public key and then also the configuration
for what specific protocol you are going to be speaking.
That all needs to be out of band in the invitation, right?
And so I know that's kind of not the way that people usually do it.
People like to do these you connect and handshake everything right there.
That's kind of like a more popular way to do it.
I just feel like that way doesn't work.
You need to have a little bit of information transmitted
out of band beforehand in order to have all of the properties that we
want to have.
Let's see.
Yeah, okay.
Let's do questions.
And if slides there are slides that are referenced by questions, that's fine.
Anybody got any questions?
We got a mic.
That's good because this is a big room.
I'm Jimmy.
I don't have a long cord.
And shockingly no wireless here.
What, at DEF CON?
So how do we run a Dust server to help out?
Is there a community setup or such?
Or EC2 instances or anything like that?
How can we make those end points that people can connect to?
BRANDON WILEY: Right.
That's a good point.
So Dust right now is not actually a service.
It's a protocol and it is like an implementation
of that protocol which is designed for other people to use.
So, like, for instance, with Tor, I worked with them
on obfs3 proxy which is part of their transport system where
anybody can make a new transport for Tor.
That's kind of one of the targets, like a Tor wrapper that uses this.
And then also I'm trying to make it into a library where you can use it
in your own kind of protocol.
There is currently no system for just doing open proxies that are
based on Dust.
I think that's not really the model that I want to go
with just because I know from knowing the Tor guys
from way back when how much work it is to run a community
of volunteer nodes.
Freenet we had that issue as well, although Freenet was low maintenance.
There wasn't a lot of coordination.
Yeah, right now this is let me go to the slide
on whether or not you should put real traffic on it which is no,
don't put real traffic on it, because this is a purely,
purely experimental sort of thing.
Yeah.
So, yeah, I don't have a good answer for that yet.
But that's a good question.
I'm going to work on that.
Okay.
I guess this is more of a general question
for all obfuscating protocols.
But couldn't the attacker just notice that you're own communicating
with one machine all the time and it's always HTTP and you never get
anything blocked?
And then just block all access that way to that machine?
BRANDON WILEY: I see what you are saying.
You are talking about your connection patterns being
anomalous you are making long lived connections to a single machine.
That's one of the things I'm going in the next version I'm working
on is being able to split your traffic over multiple connections
to multiple machines, one conversation.
I have already got it where like, some protocols actually use
different ports.
VPN uses 443 and 1194.
80% use 443.
A 20% use 1194.
You can take that to host, too.
You can say split your traffic among this set of hosts
with this probability distribution.
Use these ports with this probability distribution.
So, yeah, I'm totally working on that.
Also, I'm working on a thing where you can split your
traffic over simultaneous TCP and UDP conversations using different
profiles, different protocols with different hosts.
And it all just kind of gets funneled back together
into one stream on the other hand.
That's a lot of work, though, so it hasn't come together yet.
It is just a lot of bookkeeping and stuff.
Next step though.
BRANDON WILEY: Yeah, next step.
It seems like the obviously escalation
for the hardware manufacturers is to just move up the chain
and start classifying distributions of trigrams, bigrams and hashes
of tokens in HTTP.
Have you seen any evidence they are moving that way?
Or are you sort of banking on the fact that's
a lab CS world theoretical attack and not likely
to be deployed in practice?
BRANDON WILEY: To come back to the basic principle of Dust,
if you define a property of connections, I will randomize over that property.
So if you move from a first order probability model
for content where you are just looking at individual bytes to looking
at bigrams or trigrams and that's deployed and I see that, I
will simply randomize on the bigram and trigram level
and I can do that a lot faster than the hardware people who need
to test it and get people to buy it and roll it out.
I can could do that today.
The only reason I haven't done it is because it's not deployed
and also today specifically I'm really busy doing some
of the DEF CON contests.
(laughter).
(applause).
We're not done yet.
Stop clapping.
So how do you specify what's allowed through?
Do you have the client email out of band some PCAP data
for things they were able to do and what they weren't able to do?
What's the actual details of how that gets specified?
BRANDON WILEY: There is two parts there.
There is how do I make a model of a protocol?
And then how do we communicate that model to the client so
they can connect to the server?
In terms of modeling the protocol, I have some tools that take PCAP files
and boil then down into a statistical like, it takes
out all of the individual packets and gives you the statistical model
and takes into a tiny little file that you can email to somebody.
And they bundle that up into an invite packet which has
the I.P.
and the port and the protocol configuration information
all in one thing.
All you need to do is tell Dust here's my invitation
and then it will connect to the server and do everything right.
So in terms of how you make those, what I do
is I have deep packet inspection hardware, and I look
at what gets through and what doesn't get through.
Now, obviously it depends on how you configure it,
like what kind of traffic you, like, are against.
So what I do is I look at instances of filtering, find out what they are using,
get the hardware and configure it to reproduce
the property's behavior and that's how I try to make
a realistic model which brings me to something I want
to say about contribution.
Here is a bunch of ways you can contribute.
My Haskell sucks.
So if anyone knows Haskell to C, I could really use some help.
If anybody has any DPI hardware, that would be cool
because I have some but I don't have it all.
In particular, I need some Huawei gear.
If you want to send some packets through,
you can help save the Internet from being censored.
It is on the DL.
You are saying Huawei may be a security problem there?
BRANDON WILEY: For my project?
No, in general.
BRANDON WILEY: In general, I wouldn't say in general.
They have good stuff.
They are really good at filtering stuff.
I don't know if my stuff works against Huawei
because I don't have a Huawei box.
Yeah, anyway, more questions?
Do you think it's possible to put all deobfuscated in the cloud so
the message be decrypted automatically?
Yeah, we can use a key exchange there but the protocol,
I mean, it is more recalcitrant than that.
So if we reverse engineer the protocol, I mean    BRANDON WILEY: Reverse
engineer my protocol?
Uh huh.
BRANDON WILEY: Oh, you don't need
to reverse engineer it so you can download the source code.
It is right there.
I was thinking just to put trying a defense mechanism
in the filter.
It will be automatically decrypted yeah, just put a (inaudible)
in the filter so you can put clients in the filter so we can (inaudible)
meaning of what has been passed through.
BRANDON WILEY: I don't totally understand your question so let's talk
after and then I will get it.
You mentioned some academic core which sort of questioned
whether in the long, long run your protocol can
fundamentally work because eventually they can adapt
to your protocol.
Can you please give more details about it?
BRANDON WILEY: Yeah.
So that was the "Parrot Is Dead" paper
in which they say packet based protocols
to obfuscation won't work because they have stuff where
they look at the whole connection and then they're able
to classify stuff a lot better which makes sense, right?
If you are not looking at one packet, if you are looking at all of the packets,
you have a lot more information that you can use
to classify.
So, yeah, sure, that's true.
Here's the thing, though, if you are looking
at the whole sequence of all of the packets,
unless you delay well, not even then.
That means you pass them, that means you pass the packets
onto the server and you got responses and you record
the whole conversation and then you classified it.
I won in that case, right?
The message got through.
Maybe you had to burn that I.P., that I.P.
is blocked now and you have to go to a new I.P.
because they said you are doing crazy stuff so we will block it.
That's already a problem.
That's already a problem that Tor deals
with all the time, you have to churn through new I.P.s all the time.
I consider victory any time I get the message through.
I don't care about anything else.
I don't care about people reading the messages.
I don't care about them decrypting the messages if it is afterwards
and they couldn't use that information to block the packets.
We just have different, I think, goals.
Blackhat people are like can we classify traffic, yes or no.
And my question is can they block the traffic which
they do through classification.
This will be the last question.
If anybody else wants to talk to our man, we will take him
over to the Chillout Cafe.
Only one more so I will make it count.
Can you multiplex traffic across multiple protocols
and multiple end points?
Is the first part.
And the second part is are you IPv6 ready?
BRANDON WILEY: So good questions.
The first part, that is in the next version I'm working
on is multiplexing over multiple protocols, multiple I.P.s,
multiple ports and also between TCP and UDP.
Nobody is doing that.
I think that's cool.
Most people don't like UDP.
I don't know why.
It is rad.
And IPv6 ready?
It is funny you say that.
The first version of Dust was IPv6 only and people had
to talk me down from that.
They had to be like, look, you guys look, Brandon, like,
people don't have IPv6.
I'm like, well they better get it.
(laughter).
So the new version thank you, yes.
IPv6 is cool.
So the new version I actually have just done IPv4, but I am going to add
the IPv6 obviously because one of the best ways
to avoid deep packet inspection is use IPv6
because they haven't gotten around to implementing most
of the stuff for IPv6.
Yeah, another great thing you can do is there
is a thing called Torito (phonetic) which is IPv6 over IPv4 UDP with built
in hole punching and stuff.
It is really sweet.
It is actually built into Windows 7.
If you are Windows 7, you already have it.
You can go to IPv6 addresses.
That's another thing where they don't know what that traffic is.
So you just use that and then everything is fine.
There is a lot of cool little shortcuts to getting your traffic past the filters
by using a weird protocol.
Stuff like that.
All right.
Thank you.
So, yeah, I will be happy to talk to everybody.
See you guys at the Q&A room or just see me around.
Let's hang out.
Let's get a beer.
Invite me to some parties.
Cool.
Thank you.
(applause).