All right.
All right, hey, everybody.
Welcome.
You have made it.
We made it.
Today we are going to talk about man in the middle attacks on doing it
on an IPv4 network using five.
I'm Scott Behrens.
I work at Neohapsis and I'm an adjunct professor
at DePaul University.
BRENT BANDELGAR: And I'm Brent Bandelgar, I also work with Neohapsis.
We have to give the hats off to the principal at Neohapsis.
SCOTT BEHRENS: Well, we are going to touch
on something that came out a few years ago, which is known
as a SLAAC attack.
We have systems like Windows vista and Windows 7.
Alec Walters developed a guide to exploit this fact.
It's called a SLAAC attack.
One of the observations we made when we were playing around in the lab,
it was difficult to follow the steps he outlined.
We ran into a lot of issues.
What we did is how we updated the attack to make it easier to use
and a one click install sort of approach.
BRENT BANDELGAR: Right and here we have our Blain vanilla
legacy network.
It does only IPv4, it has DVP, and there's no IPv6.
We have Windows Host and Windows 7.
What Alec Waters put together the evil router in the red.
There's two nodes, the evil router and the evil DNS are intercepting traffic.
They are doing they are running an IP version 6 network which
is in the blue and then passing it through their packages and their DNS.
Again, this is their own host and then it's resending that
out over the IP version 4 network.
SCOTT BEHRENS: This takes advantage
of is those advertised as IPv6.
Yes, I want to route over IPv6 and we take advantage of the fact
and run them through our interface, for example.
BRENT BANDELGAR: And then back out to IPv4.
Completely transparent to the user.
Here's the guide presented by Alec Waters.
It's not affected because it doesn't have an IPv6.
We just got a copy on Windows 8.
We couldn't get it to work properly.
SCOTT BEHRENS: It might be difficult to see in the next screen shot.
BRENT BANDELGAR: We have some IPv6, routers
but the Windows 8 no longer sends the DNS service setting
through SLAAC alone.
SCOTT BEHRENS: It tries to make
a request and doesn't get a DNS and then falls back to IPv4, which
is known as happy eyeballs and we will touch on that presentation later on.
BRENT BANDELGAR: There are some other issues.
First off, there's a lot of configuration files that you have
to go through and edit.
So these steps were very detailed but there's still a lot of things
to go through.
A lot of IP addresses and ranges to keep track of, lots of flags
SCOTT BEHRENS: And it used a lot of old and deprecated packages.
They said it was held together with string and sticky tape
and that's pretty parallel to what we experienced when we were
playing with this in the lab.
And, you know, because of that, we went back to the blog post
and we are like, are we the only ones having problems getting
this working?
And we were reading through the forums Duncan couldn't get
it to work and Vox couldn't get it to compile.
It was something that we thought could be an awesome weapon
for penetration tests or things like that.
BRENT BANDELGAR: All right.
To make that feasible    SCOTT BEHRENS: Yeah so what we decided
we needed was ...
BRENT BANDELGAR: It's up.
SCOTT BEHRENS: Check that out.
I got that from freebanners.net.
Automation domination, right?
BRENT BANDELGAR: Yeah.
Oops.
SCOTT BEHRENS: And really what this does is it's one Bash script
to rule them all.
Coming up with the defaults for the configurations, moving
all the old deprecated packages, we came up with the one click install
that takes care of all the dependencies and configures
your host and we made some adjustments so it does work
on Windows 8.
And it's been currently tested on LTS and we have tested
on a variety of the Kali flavors and you should be able to run
the script and run all the man in the middle things.
Before you get started, you will need to know the interface
of your attacker host that you want to run it on.
And you will also need an extra IPv4 on the network you are attacking
to do translation.
SCOTT BEHRENS: You want to test in your own isolated lab first.
It's a relatively aggressive attack.
You are basically going to route everything through your host.
If you imagine doing this on a relatively flat network where you
have 100, or 200 or n number of hosts, you will routing a lot of traffic
through your host.
You have to be careful.
We suggest you test it on a couple of hosts first.
And another thing I wanted to mention, that might not have been totally clear
in the slides is that this attack only works
on a local network.
You know, you need to be on the same subnet
as the victims that you are targeting.
BRENT BANDELGAR: All right.
Let's go ahead and see how the installation looks.
The reason we are showing you this is just because of how little time you
actually how little time you actually need to get it running.
Literally we invoked the command.
And within a couple of minutes or less than a minute, it's going
to pull down a number of packages, such as taking it to do the standard
by nine, the server, the standard DOHV server
and that's pretty much everything you need to start setting
up your IPv6 overlay network.
SCOTT BEHRENS: When we originally set this up, and before,
you know, RTFM done bind here, I ended up writing a DNS revolver
to do a super hack job and at the end of the day it was one line of work and
in a bind, so just a lesson to everybody.
Please read your manuals.
(Laughter).
BRENT BANDELGAR: Yeah.
So it's ready.
SCOTT BEHRENS: Right.
And so although it went relatively quick.
One of the other things that the script really does it prompts you
for two points of input and it has to be the interface that you are going
to run the attack on.
So here although it scrolled pretty fast, the attacker specified 0 and you need
to identify a free IP address on the network that you are targeting.
BRENT BANDELGAR: Right and at the end it starts
up all the relevant services and the kernel modules that you need.
SCOTT BEHRENS: It's not persistent.
So, you know, once you have actually set this up,
you will need to the run the script again
if you reboost your host or switch networks
or something like that.
BRENT BANDELGAR: It's two line fixes to make it persistent.
If anybody is interested, we can talk later.
SCOTT BEHRENS: Yep.
BRENT BANDELGAR: So now we see what this looks
like on the client side.
On our own Windows 8 host.
First off, we see that the it's received our IP version
6 addresses and the IPv6 didn't.
That's paused.
Unpause.
We will fire up our Wireshark and load up Google in another window.
We see it will be going over IPv6 on our configured prefix.
SCOTT BEHRENS: Right.
BRENT BANDELGAR: And then we pull up the flow to verify that that
is our HTTP request.
SCOTT BEHRENS: Right.
Cool.
BRENT BANDELGAR: All right.
SCOTT BEHRENS: So, yeah, we can see that the traffic, you know,
transparent to the victim, all the traffic is running over IPv6.
BRENT BANDELGAR: And this is what it looks like on the attacker side.
SCOTT BEHRENS: We have the attacker.
He's run the one click install and on Kali waiting
for that request to happen.
We see the request come in and at this point, now we are kind
of seeing a combination of the IPv6 traffic and we're also seeing
us do the translation back to IPv4 so we can actually get
out of the network, right?
We are taking advantage of the fact that we don't have
a full IPv6 tunnel out to the Internet here.
BRENT BANDELGAR: That was the IPv6 request coming
in from the client.
SCOTT BEHRENS: And now we can see that the victim's traffic, we have
the header's there and some of the cookies and the data as well.
BRENT BANDELGAR: And that's being retransmitted out over IPv4.
SCOTT BEHRENS: So basically in the ban of very quick, you are man
in the middling your victim's traffic over clear text.
(Applause)    BRENT BANDELGAR: Thank you.
Yeah.
SCOTT BEHRENS: So, yeah, we really think the main focus
is to improve the efficiency and, you know, it went
from spending quite a of time in the lab
to work and now it's two variables and about a minute
of configuration time.
(Applause)    BRENT BANDELGAR: All right.
Unfortunately not all is rosy in IPv6 land.
We do have a couple of issues with the attack as it is.
SCOTT BEHRENS: Yeah, and the hugest one
is disabling IPv6 by policy.
So if, you know, you are in an organization that has it turned
off this attack just simply is not going to work and in general,
you know, one of the things that's kind of nice
about this attack.
Any time you set up a new Windows host that it has this
turned on.
So unless it's explicitly turned off, you will have
a good chance that have hosts that have IPv6 enables.
One of the other things that we have to be on the lookout
for are IPv6 network defenses.
And these are specifies in RFC6105.
There's also a guide that Cisco put out that talks about how to find
of protect against first hop sort of attacks and they have
a technology called RA guide, router advertisement guard.
That basically stops when, we send out that router advertisement packet,
that guard basically blocks that packet from hitting the other ports
on the switch.
BRENT BANDELGAR: And some of the other issues we have run
into in the lab is different operating systems
will implement RFC6555 differently, which specified that there's here six
if it rolls back to IPv4, if the IPv6 is not coming back fast enough.
SCOTT BEHRENS: It's interesting.
The happy eyeball effect on ubuntu is different
on Linux and there's room to figure out what those conditions are that
actually trigger that fallback and unfortunately when
the fallback happens it seems to then just prefer IPv4.
If you are on a relatively latent network or your routing is latent
for whatever reason and the hosts drop back to IPv4,
there's a good chance that they will not actually route
through your host again.
So once again, we kind of suggest if you are going to run this attack
on a production network or something, that you have some pretty you know,
have a good network connectivity.
Don't be doing this over a latent wireless network
or something like that.
BRENT BANDELGAR: Yep.
Another issue that we are getting into is different operating systems
will prefer will query their DNS servers in different orders.
Sometimes they queries the IPv4 servers first, so we miss
out on translating the IPv6 through our server.
SCOTT BEHRENS: Yeah, there's room for improvement.
We think one of the biggest things is to actually specify the target scope.
Right now, it snags the whole subnet, and that's a little noisy.
If you are on a pen test and you are just targeting a specific server,
you really don't want to route everything,
and so that's definitely something that we are going to try to work out here.
We will also automate some basic network recognizance.
That's just one left step that someone could either mess
up or make it easier for everybody.
BRENT BANDELGAR: We like to figure
out if there's IPv6 countermeasures implemented on a network.
For example, if being able to send out a router advertisement
and then just waiting to specify a time and nothing comes back,
we can probably assume that there's nothing that our stuff is being blocked.
SCOTT BEHRENS: Yeah, that they have a protection enabled, correct.
BRENT BANDELGAR: We would like to be able
to automatically configure IP version 6 to look at v6 connectivity and
the reason for that is sometimes clients will receive
a quad A a legitimate quad A IPv6 address
and they will not be able to connect back to that site.
And so they will the happy eyeballs will kick in and they fall back.
So we would like for that to be as easy as possible as well.
SCOTT BEHRENS: Right, exactly.
BRENT BANDELGAR: Another thing we would like to automate,
is leveraging, the IPv6 hacker tools.
There are a number of tools in there.
There's a tool that will listen for the router advertisement responses
and they will just this basically will display the list
of IPv6 addresses getting handed out and MAC addresses
and you can see which clients are being added on to the overlay network.
SCOTT BEHRENS: It gives you a little bit more metrics
and give you a better clue on actually what's going
on with the attack.
And we would also like to see this expanded
to more platforms.
We looked at the mobile stuff but IPv6 didn't seem to be there, right,
on Android.
BRENT BANDELGAR: No, Android is there.
And IOS, they are in linear order and so their DNS servers
will always go first.
SCOTT BEHRENS: And so we ran into some issues with that.
I think there's more search that could be done to figure
out how do we get this across a broader array
of operating systems.
BRENT BANDELGAR: And, of course, we would
like to get this ported to other attackers as well
to unite people's needs and preferences.
SCOTT BEHRENS: Right.
BRENT BANDELGAR: All right.
So here's how you can help.
SCOTT BEHRENS: Go ahead and pull it off of here.
There's one other we love people to help.
So if you have ideas or have been working with similar stuff,
feel free to forward the project and submit a pull request.
We will be happy to add whatever you guys come
up with.
And one other note, be careful on running this
on production networks.
It's a pretty kind of aggressive attack.
Test it out in your lab first before you totally blow it
out of the water on somebody's network, right?
BRENT BANDELGAR: All right.
With that    SCOTT BEHRENS: Well, thank you, guys.