(Music Playing.)    JAVIER: Hello!
How are you, DEF CON?
(Applause.)    ALBERTO: How are you DEF CON?
Okay.
So, you know, this is our presentation, we are speaking about car hacking.
Later about how to do a forensic job into a car after a crash,
after an accident, to retrieve all the speed, the RPM,
the brake position and this kind of things, okay.
Let's start.
You know it's called "Dude, Where the Fuck in My Car?"
I'm Alberto, he's Javier, I'm going to introduce him and he's
a hardware specialist.
He loves breaking toys.
Every time I meet with him, he is always with some staff
with the hands completely dirty, dirty in the sense of the hand, only, okay?
So he's freelance, okay?
He's working alone.
He's from we are from Spain, okay, this is important to understand
the jokes and this kind of things (Laughter.) Sometimes we are
different kind of jokes, but I think the Spanish jokes are cool.
Have you ever been top Spain?
He is from a city in the part of Spain that is in the very south,
close to Morocco and that's him, okay?
I am this guy.
On the left.
The youngest one!
The other guy is my Grandpa!
(Laughter.) This is my second time here in DEF CON,
last year I was speaking here about other stuff.
The thing is (Applause.) Thank you!
The thing is I don't want to introduce myself
like the typical times, like, I'm doing the shit or whatever, blah, blah, blah,
so the thing is I'm going to use a video of the last year, yeah?
It's a piece of the total of last year here at DEF CON.
So I think it will be enough to introduce myself.
You see, I reuse the slides, I am lazy!
I am from a city 200 kill meters to the north of Madrid,
and I am 24 years old, I'm single, if anyone wants to (Laughter.) Okay?
No, I'm only like girls, sorry!
(Laughter.) (Applause.) I am only 25 years old now, and all the rest
is the same so only girls, please!
(Applause.) Okay, let's go.
Okay, like I told you at the beginning we are speaking
about hacking the car, hacking the ECU, like the brain of the car.
There are different brains around the car but we are trying
to get the control to interact with the ECU, the main one, the ECU
is where the configuration of the car is stored.
So this is the first part of the talk and like I told you, we are going
to do the forensic job, okay?
So we can know what happened in an accident and if someone
is guilty or not or whatever, yeah.
So for now I'm going to give the am I correct phone to my friend,
my partner, and he's going to start.
JAVIER: Okay, so as Alberto said I'm Javier I'm
from Cardiff and all that stuff.
Why did this happen, the car hacking thing?
Well, I had a friend well, I used to do this stuff with my laptop,
like everyone does and he kept on bugging me, you want a factory,
I want it cheap and I thought, man, I make one piece hardware so you stop
bugging me, and that's how it started, I wanted him to not keep on calling me.
At first I use this, it didn't work (Laughter.) I needed
a plan.
I had to sort it out.
At first I needed some information, of course, I needed to see how
the car did work so I realized that there were different electronic control units
that they were all networked in the same bus, so
they were address huddled, they had some security,
I didn't know that much, I was playing a little while,
and I knew that data was stored in them, and it's interesting data.
There are some communication protocols, these are widely spread.
They are not the only once but they are most common, this
is the one that is being used the most, Com Bus.
AUDIENCE MEMBER: (Away from microphone.)    JAVIER: One
of the most important things when I started with this thing was the price.
When i was going to develop the tool, my friend wanted it cheap,
and K Line was $10 cheaper.
I am not cheap I just we want for the interface, K Line.
Why did I choose it?
As I said, it is cheaper.
For Comm Bus we need ICs, and ECUs that work
for K Line are cheaper.
ALBERTO: (Away from microphone.)    JAVIER: It's $10,
$8, but that's something.
Then the question, if I say different, to implement it?
The difference between K Line and Comm Bus is protocol layers,
so it's layer 1 and layer 2.
All the encryption is the same so if you wanted to move from K Line
to Comm Bus it would take no time, it would be changing the hardware
and changing the structure, Comm Bus works on SPI
but not really a big deal.
What did we know about ECU?
We know they are in cars, and once I decided to start
with it I had two options.
One was to do some research and navigate
through the technical information, or hook the logic analyzer.
We decided to go 50/50 to make it not too interesting
either way.
So that's what we found.
After a little bit of research they are responsible
for the engine management engine is ECU, not all, we have locks ECUs,
many others, but this is the engine ones.
This is stored and they hold mobilizer routine and
they contain and determine the way the car behaves.
So the hardware which is the ECU itself the physical thing
is composed of internal and external flash.
Internal flash is most of the times OTP, it's not accessible, normally,
from the outside.
It has internal external most of the times as well and it's
like something when you try to hope it you start to hate it, it sucks.
You have to deal with it anyway, so.
As I said we attached the logic analyzer and we saw this stuff.
This is exactly from an EDC15, this is one of the first ones we
will talk about, the first part is the weak up pattern, the address
for the control module which is 01.
Then we request the speed to support the bus,
and then we change the speed to higher, because you start at 10,400,
you do authentication, you set address actually, you have
to send EDC15 you have to send a loader,
on 16 you don't have to do that, but I will talk about 245 later.
The fourth part is sending the loader plus operations.
Of course I was ignorant about this, I said "man this is easy" it didn't work.
It wasn't that easy.
So after research what did I found?
Actually we just noticed that there was an authentication that was not static.
That's why it didn't work.
So it's called a algorithm.
The ECU acts as a server so you request
authorization, the ECU will send you a seat, you will have
to do some maps, it will send the result and that's called
the "key" and there you go.
That's it.
It has checks to check the integrity of the data that you are uploading.
When you download it already hats checks so you don't need
to check anything, so on EDC15 it requires a loader
as I was saying.
For the operations it's usually an assembler, and it has internal flash.
On we have this algorithm, as well, but it is just one level, you send
the loader and do the operations with that loader.
Here we have level 3, which is pretty easy, the challenge is just
to a number, and we have level 2 can, which is operations and level 1
is to write the flash of the device which
is a little more complicated but it's like EDC 15 they didn't change at all,
you know, just small things.
We have RSA encryption, when you want to download
from an EDC 16 it's plain, it's binary, you can put it
into IDA or your favorite tool no problem, easy.
Bullet when you want to upload it of course you need to have
the check zones, like you did earlier but it RSA encrypted and it needs
to be in blocks of 256 kilobytes, in this case, whatever you want
to upload it must be encrypted in blocks of 256 kilobytes.
Well, how did we do it?
My wife helped me a little bit!
Why is this interesting?
Well, I think we all want to save a few bucks so if you want your car
to have more mileage per gallon, that's good.
The difference between most cars, like for example my own cars,
I have a Cooper 1 which is 167 horse power, I modified
and now it's 210 horse power.
It's easy, free, that's good!
It's cool, inexpensive to do it.
At first, I started with EDC 15 was the ECU in my car and my friend's car
and I developed the whole thing it was 1,800 lines
of code, and then I wanted to start reversing
for EDC16 and I had to start from scratch so I go
to different binaries, one for EDC16 which
is the same even though the processor is different.
This is the first point I had to be really careful code it go due
the two limitations of the NCU itself.
We're actually working now on externalizing.
For example, I coded it and we thought it would be
better to externalize it and bring the binary out and by making it
with modules, the processors, we can make
a universal firmware so we don't need to update every time we want
to support new ECUs and that's what we are working on now.
This is how an EDC15 board looks like, as I said, it has an external, and
the external flash and the ECUs.
This is a little bit of code from the EDC15 app they not indication,
the key.
The algorithm is static but, for example, here I have an EDC15P.
This has one set of keys.
Even though the algorithm is the same for all the EDC15 family.
If we get an EDC15V, the keys change and the VM
the keys have different so we would need to construct the keys
for every single ECU.
But that's not a hard task, it can be done with bruit force
and some power tricks.
Because at times you have done a wrong log in,
but you can glitch it to forget about it or, you know,
try something else.
This is the EDC16, in this case it's internal and there are
variants which have an external apron.
The ECU is stored internally, this is the algorithm,
we have external flash and a port which is BDM,
bench diagnostics mode.
Here we have part of the code for the level 1 authentication
for EDC16 as well.
Just like it happened on EDC15 for example, we have an EDC CP34,
it's a different model, the 16, the algorithm will be the same
the key will be different and we can do this exactly the same way to create
the keys for it.
This is level 3 authentication, that's, as I said, the ECU, since you challenge,
you add that I don't remember what number is it?
2FC9X, you assemble that number and you got it.
That's how much they brainstormed for this.
Here we can see an example of our encryption, in EDC16.
On the first part the top is the binary so I just brought
out this red square, so you can see the read out.
The next one the data is the same, it has no encryption, nothing,
then part 3 is the write out, what you are writing this data
down here even though it's completely different it's
the same it's just encrypted.
So that's how it looks.
It looks different.
How did we handle it?
RSA encryption in the tool.
Well, same instructions, we didn't really want to the you
will see it.
It takes approximately 10 seconds to code 512 kilobytes the map
for chip tuning, that's the size and we do it before the ECU
in it because it takes 10 seconds and that was a time
out in communication with the ECU if we first check if it's there
and we cannot afford to lose communication due
to the speed.
Of course the check is calculated at the same time and it is calculated
for the nonencrypted file not for the encrypted one so we do things
at the same time, encryption and check.
This is small part it was for four pages, showing the first one
for the EDC16 encryption algorithm.
So we can see that's the kind of operations    ALBERTO: Yeah,
like he told you, his wife helped him to do that so that's, you know,
you know his wife is a bitch!
With everyone!
Sorry!
JAVIER: This is assembler.
This is not a new thing, chip tuning, you can get tool for that.
These are the prices.
I consider that expensive, I don't know about you.
This is what our tool costs.
It's cheaper.
(Applause.) Thanks.
This is how it looks, it's fancy, it has mustaches,
and it's portable you don't need the laptop at all.
It doesn't work so don't worry!
(Laughter.) I will be releasing the code soon, the schematics,
so this is Open Source you can do whatever
you want on it.
You are paying $26 for the stuff you will be able to tweak.
So I think it's worth, I'm paying like $500 for a closed tool.
These are the features for our tool.
It is not locked to a single vehicle, there are other stand alone tools there
that require no computer but you are paying like $1,000
to be able to use it on your own car.
I don't believe in that.
It doesn't store encrypted files, I don't want you to need to use my tool,
you can use whatever you want.
Download it with my tool or with any other tool.
It does not use a master slave, which is encrypted, and as I said,
Open Source so you can add support for whatever you want.
Any other models, diagnostics, there will be some cool stuff coming.
This is the lower interface.
We can see they are doing a Mini Pro that is his on the left,
on the bottom level is the shifter.
Sorry.
This is just a regulator and a 7805 to get the 5 bolts out of the 12
and this is an SD car, this is the LCD 2IC and I think you can see
it's homemade.
This is a very cute eagle interface board, just the same hardware.
This part is on RG45 connector so you can get
the thought of how tiny it is and it has FTDI already imbedded
in and you can update it whatever, straight off.
ALBERTO: The thing is that is homemade,
the thing that you saw before this is homemade.
If you want to do it better with this board it's much
more than this, okay, this is just a case to haul all the things that
he told you, okay?
But this thing maybe just maybe like a    JAVIER: A quarter size of this.
ALBERTO: So smaller and the thing of the smaller side
is interesting because we are speaking later
about what evil things we can do with this thing, okay?
So that's not okay.
JAVIER: We're so evil!
Here is an example of how to make it wireless.
This is just the same thing but with it is the serial console
but without the blue tooth it's $1 and we can control it
with our Android phone so it's wireless and it's cheap.
Some examples of this, like I was saying, we can mold it
to have less more mileage per gallon, how to bypass immobilizer,
is just a process, it's 2 bytes.
The loader is embedded for reading and writing, so you click a button
and it's done and of course you can later enable it.
This car is fun, you connect to the tool and when it's in the middle
of the writing process you pull the cable, so it's fucked up, no check,
no anything (Laughter.) You've got an expensive piece of metal,
but later on you can still recover it, not everything is lost.
There are recovery processes for it, by the diagnostics part you don't need
to pull the off the car and it will eventually work again.
ALBERTO: But it's funny for a joke!
JAVIER: When he finds out his car isn't working it's so funny!
Yeah!
(Laughter.) An example well, you know, we can have any interface, 3G, wifi,
blue tooth as we saw with the phone and, well,
we can disable a car, we could eventually it
is not yet implemented that is completely different,
we could control a car with this device as well
with other firmware, we could disable or start modules, funks, like turn
on the air conditioner and make whoever get
a really bad cold, you know?
(Laughter.) He couldn't be able to disable, it would be terrible.
Now, we're going to do a demo on the EDC16.
It will be console but we will be able to see the process.
I'm going to show because you cannot see it
from there but I'm going to explain what we have here.
We have an EDC16 connected and a mega 2,560 and we have normal
$10 diagnostics cable.
So what did they do here?
Wired up the level shifter up to the ECU so we are going
to is send comments to read the information and read the flash
and to write we're actually going to kill the ECU, revive it again
and read the info after that.
So let's get to it.
ALBERTO: Yeah.
JAVIER: Okay.
So let's see if it works!
We're going to read the info first.
We can see that's fast.
It doesn't take too much time.
Here we have the information, the software version, the engine this
is for a Volkswagen Passat, where it is not connected to a chassis,
but the inside is all around the K Line bus, so we can get the number,
the chassis number and now we're going to read the external flash, it
will take a while.
Meanwhile, what can I say about this?
It's fancy, I like flashing here, it's a pity you cannot see it flashing.
(Laughter.) Well, actually, when it was reversing the protocol,
I noticed that there were huge time gaps, you know, this
is based on packets.
So between each packet is bytes, of course, and
between byte there was time I don't know how to explain a delay.
After testing I realized it wasn't necessary so I speed it up.
We changed protocol, made it faster, works 25% faster than
the original tool on EDC16 and it works 400 times
percent faster, on EDC15 so they didn't brainstorm too much
about that, anyway.
I will not show that at this time because we are running low
on time so now we are going to kill the ECU.
Now it's processing the RSA.
ALBERTO: You have to believe that, but we are going to show
the logical analyzer after that, okay, a capture of the analyzer.
JAVIER: We will show another logic analyzer
capture so you can see what is going on.
ALBERTO: Obviously we are running out of time.
JAVIER: So we got to be faster now.
So what we are going to do to kill since we have no cable
to plug we're going to start writing, we're going to send just one packet
of data, then we are going to stop communicating with the ECU.
So now it's deactivated.
I need to power cycle it once again.
Now we are going to try to read the information.
Of course since it's disabled it won't be replying.
So we got no response it's disabled, just a piece of junk right now.
But now we are going to make it work again!
Should be fast!
Things so slow, it's an AB processor.
With two kilobytes of RAM, it takes a while.
Now actual you will to revive it since we screwed up the flash,
we erased the flash, we started to right, so checks and swearing, correct,
so now to fix it we need to write the whole flash again.
We are writing what we read out the first time.
As I said, RSA encryption here is provided in blocks of 256 kilobytes,
this is the first block, now we're starting
with the second block.
Since we are running out of time we will go now on with the other things.
If there is enough time we will show the logic analyzer, it will be fast.
Showing out maybe while it's writing we can show okay, I'll show this is the key,
this buckets this is so small, the address, the target address,
the source address, this is our request, now 27 means we want
to have security access.
We are send this gone packet, now this is the level, level 01 which
is to write, so the ECU will reply.
With a 6701 means okay I will send you the challenge.
So here we have, for example, 86, 58, 86, that will be the seed.
For the challenge.
Now we will process this and we should send okay, 2702 we must add 1
to the security level we requested and these are just 4 bytes,
this one here.
Then if we succeed it will reply with 67.
If we fail it will reply 7F.
Which means "denied."
When writing we can see this is a huge block here, then we stop
with the letter second block, we write the second block
and then we are done, that's the writing response.
One second I need to power cycle it.
We are going to read info again to see it works.
So, again, it's alive!
After killing it!
(Laughter.) So now it works!
ALBERTO: Wait.
It's not connected.
It's fast as light but it's not connected so you didn't see
the joke!
JAVIER: Windows.
ALBERTO: It was a joke, Spanish.
Anyway.
So I have only like 10 minutes so I'm going to go fast.
What happens in an accident, the police usually look at the marks
in the floor with the accident happens and
they look at the condition of the car to figure out the speed and things that
happen but the IT guys we have a cooler way
to know exactly the parameter of the accident.
In all the cars, our cars, we have a black box, same as in a plane.
The only difference is it doesn't record sound so don't
worry if you speak dirty things or whatever, it's not storing that.
So it stores information before and after the crash, it is interesting
because even after the crash there is memory that stores information.
So we can have more information about the accident itself.
So that's information like I told you at the beginning this is related
with the speed, the most important, the RPM, brake, and depends
on the plan, the plan that have made in the ECU but there
is other information stored in the ECU.
This information is stored in the A block ECU, okay, most
of the time.
So we have to take this part of the car, this ECU is similar, it's just
a little smaller than.
Okay?
It's stored in the apron memory, it's nonvolatile, so we can get access
to the data after the crash, okay?
It's great for that.
There is hardware and software that is outside and you can use it
but the thing is this talk is about how to make
a thing that cost only $25 instead of $1,000 and
in that case even the tools used to get information are more expensive
than to mod fry the ECUs.
So the cool thing is we did something to the poor people.
Yeah, we are speaking all the time about 5 minutes okay.
We are speaking all the time about the ECUs, okay?
There are different ways to track information
from an ECU after crash.
The first of all is to connect into the ODB, it is the port
behind the wheel in the car
and we can access information.
Not all the time because in some crashes, the car
is completely fucked, so what?
So there is the the connection is lost so we can't retrieve information.
The other way is to connect directly to the ECU and get information so
for that we need authentication, maybe it's not a strong authentication,
but it is an authentication anyway.
Finally we have the fancy way, directly with the apron memory.
I said all the information is in the apron so we can read it, okay?
Yes, it's hardware more than software, I'm a software guy maybe it's more
difficult but for these people hardware is like eating ice cream.
This is the first one, behind the wheel, so this is the first way, this
is the other way, connecting directly to the ECU to get information and
the last way is this is from the apron memory this
is the size of the apron you can see it in the fingers, it's very small
but we can do it, we can do it.
This is the hardware I told you before, hardware and software, okay,
the hardware is like no hardware
because it doesn't do almost anything but, anyway, and the software,
the real important part of this kit.
The premium tool our kit costs almost $9,000, yeah, I'm not going
to pay for that!
What about the poor guys?
What about people like me that have just ended school
and University and these kinds of things and we don't have money.
The software that is for me, the important part is you can access
to it for free, okay?
Free software.
The code of the data, because this is important information and we have
to parse this information to know, okay, from the bytes 11 to 40 is the speed
and from bytes whatever to whatever is whatever.
So we have to parse it.
So, yeah, we can his wife is I sleep with his wife once too.
(Laughter.) Sorry, man!
Okay.
Other thing, this tool this are supported, okay,
so there are very cool brands that are supported to do this.
Did you miss something?
It's not interlaced, so what happened?
One time a client contacted us to do a forensic job on a car and
the car was a Mercedes, so we said one, maybe two okay, one.
We said what are we going to do?
So what do we do?
First of all we read the apron, okay, soldering, to the apron, and we read
the parts of the binary, so we erased one copy
of this binary and make a okay?
So when you parse will modify after the crash so it's a good point
of start, okay?
So the next step was already filter it, the information, we only have
the information, only have the parts of the ECU, okay, I'm going.
One minute.
Half!
(Laughter.) Okay.
We just it's the software to bring the graphics to bring the difference
in the graphics between the crescent and the crescent,
okay, so the speed will be in the crash, the crescent, right,
if you crash you stop yeah, the speed is the crescent.
So we found this.
Okay?
You can see.
After looking at it a lot we found this graphic that gives us
information in our research so we had anyway,
so we are running out of time.
We want to say thank you to you!
(Applause.) Like always, to our family and friends, and
all those who want to understand how and why things
work, thank you very much!