well
places
you know
so
so this is a natural this particular box
or no other place for rehearsal to
encrypted
steps to go beyond the strength that is
necessary just online attack or severe
bruising not scenario where there's
going to be an offline it is not this is
that people here are some of the recent
the reasons for bridges and walk through
of course they do johnny was so they
don't listen only true God for ever
consulted so that often getting beyond
race was actually both necessary words
most of the breaches that we've seen you
know the passwords just in plain text
without resorting to any of this drama
and things that way
sensible
online
so well
there's just published increased rate
but you're not getting what
but there's a box grater administrative
network like 20 percent of employees not
at all like they were here is my terms
of you know is it comprehensively beaten
by 11.1%
potentials rapidly dollars to get away
he already have my credentials
just like 11 Israeli troops got more and
more just finished their set of things
start to shrink wrap or look at it from
the other end respect your privacy
got all wondered why the sad thing
essentially boxes or boxes do the work
was so without having access to build
cases you know you get to see your part
to the claim that place is that came
with the beach
internally his
precisely at precise point of view no
matter what I will say is happier or the
or one-liners decided that is denied so
nothing is not here yet
necessarily you know much much much much
faster than 1% 2% but I'm gonna call and
it was sooo man has this kind of market
reform we will ensure about you know
where the New York Corp it all out this
fall which he's control effectively /
445 very small group Relations website
you know then let's say and its price
2011 taxes 2010 and was just online
offline increasing strength and guests
will will buy this is the fraction of
compromise that are already compromised
well as your 2013
so well is that all of us tonight that's
also part of the day that's also please
we're increasing past the regional it
does not succeeded is how we no longer
have pretty much scott is a test to see
which one you can do whatever you know
down please
he does not influence is not controlled
saying that increasing the strength but
also wants out disasters which ones he
has had over potential additional
strength distribution
believe this distribution box below
where most or all on like six student
population population choosing ran in
four days and still better than it had
exceeded your online social just kind of
old harry said groundswell for spare
parts and generally you know this is the
fraction of credentials from up top half
of the population that all you know
she's got here is also generally well
you know strength is good
more is here that the small fraction
facials will be home might get slowed
down at the green car
well the creek or appear to be far
better than in the sense that what we
have here it's indoors difference
between the cracks in the credentials
she one point where you know get here
posted by Softline
well on the Greek or he's going to get
20% off your day
4444 doesn't make any difference at all
when you're when you're close to that
degree weather was 22% for 400 words
from the same purpose far gone so you
have this will cost your hostages for
last year all this bike so the
distribution
like that you know this varies so
there's this is what we want to go back
taxes 2012 95 I asked as to what what
what what are the dangers and then
there's a password distributions without
beside the point at which
well the network that is truly
impressive things like these privileged
access compartmentalization it's not
really something that's under control
you shouldn't have to set up a network
where every user has access to a network
where only had somehow things always
managed to creep noise at the match
started making sure that online that
your guesses guess what do you want to
be resource but not what they have to do
to improve your so that I can do to try
to pull and that I can try to control
distribution using usual so you know
before he thought was reasonably well
the source like 30 we're just good now
can we chill let's say you know I can
call that all the way down to six or so
so that that's actually things are
looking at you and show you can do just
the twelve gases in Sao Paulo without
exposing all but one of the reasons to
stop talking about people with
says his things that we should not
receive your order is hard to get the
number 12 or higher are are far more
realistic because you don't want people
out there and change the distribution
region just don't you try to the
audience
italy's passport distributions to his
remarkably
direct focus no words to redirect users
please do this here and here was not me
right now focused in the areas where the
guy is well suppose I have some
population increase their march 9
percent that just wish it straight away
because 90% of the population light of
all about 90% of rappers just wanted
when she's on the particular cases there
were just a critical cases all gaining
access with with the fewest education so
that is where it is direct and the $1.42
that just for the record the harmful
actions so focused only two people
people hurting the people who is left
alone
blacklisted for protection against are
essentially is first rate for 90
position to buy as much to say really
directly address their whole population
by definition
population is so we mention what we want
the distribution go out but we're so
contributions