so I falls public
are really good I'll
or calling on all so yes he
of to something I'll
call do it he yeah
has to enjoying all that sounds
all I'm throwing up as the song house
you not like you last ballers
a all start
I i'm no you
Paul on use also lot
always he walruses
me no I don't called
yeah I'll yeah a
you the his on
his the house saw
no you Bay I'm are
this movies you
show for
are said so
this is his but
mike is a my name is up there arm I work
for a company called ace Metrix
on Norwegian company we specialize in
you know computer networks data centers
security icon stuff I'm sick senior
consultant
a in the security field that's why
professional email if you wanna
you know do anything professionally
related if you just wanna shoot the
breeze
this my Twitter handle my email address
link to you know find me goes up
rights I so this whole thing starts back
in the noughties
may impair was doing
well he was doing password
auditing for rather large company and I
was happening
him out with the analysis was about 2500
Active Directory gas he was analyzing he
attracts about
93 a for senator and
arm so this is a precursor to was going
late
later I have to explain the backs back
story here
up the used I think it was a fairly
standard password policy
minimum eight characters uppercase
lowercase digits
and for this
the speech the important thing is there
was a change every three months
speak up please I presume this was a
standard-setting
and I guess I don't know icarly recall
I but what's
what was interesting was that they had a
fairly substantial password
history available sort
with I was looking at these past
histories and and
I discovered these long sequences a
password the
look like this starting
well basically the same password
when with numbers change and I was again
and again and again and it was the same
thing and
o'hare so is the Lord of the Rings fan
on
but sometimes these chains were
Michael Bradley broken they were just
suddenly there was a pass for this
didn't follow this trend at all and I
was curious
as do why sorry
jazz you're from I might be yeah are
wall
the there was a lot of a my chances for
burgeoning other winter know there were
two apparent reasons
are for these changes a YS
rather obvious on
and anyone care to guess by the way
what was the reason the purchase
suddenly changing this radical
good and no that's not a radical change
might be not an answer said
I'm
football or it has been long of
holiday you he said pair
give them a chocolate that exactly what
happened
a well we sold yeah
and I'll I'm
because it turns out week we actually
recognizes
whenever they're people forget their
past where they would call help desk and
helped us with
reset the password to super predictable
password
and that's how we respond to that now
there's a second thing that was going on
which I would
like to I think I read just called
circular house for changes
and a since anecdotal evidence is the
best on evidence
like pair to related a story about this
up
horrible also yours
I'm I'll
calling I so go
halls dataset
whose up
some sort
called
house polls password change
every days lol
for you greater Laura
look all users Hall
for day is same while
Walmart boss house for
all up
since the
that there's for
recall this up
well well
all are
him for his Ron
safe all
all in fun
this all people him
house for which Haas
yeah and go back say always
and its Manuel
Holly is house Rep
at all are homeless or
to a lawyer always up
all life %uh that's
here you'll well
ago us or back so I was the second
second main reason for sequences
of course all the other ones are valid
as well you change your girlfriend or
your dog dies in the mirror
a well
are oh yeah I was told by someone I
previous countrymen it was Marcus you
needed quotes
in a presentation for to be valid as I
found on here that might
actually match you you guys have
probably heard this
before you probably have never heard
that name before
but is actually the guy the road in a
book
they went by then George really but you
can imagine
I think he liked imagine having book
signings with that name
and the you get through maybe three
books before lunch
well anyway this doesn't really work
with password is because it's the
opposite
if you remember the past you will repeat
it
because you great impassable looks
almost identical
so yeah the other item I need to
include in the presentation was kittens
so it has on
when I'm missing stuff here
a don't work
now
that doesn't mean anything to do with
drummer remembered
it's the path of least resistance I
think
so anyway as I was looking at this II I
I kept wondering
is there a way to measure the quality
I'll
password history a so this is just
a you know thought stage at that point
so I decided maybe I should try to
calculate the difference between each
generation passwords and
I would like to about that and
maybe the average dis difference would
be a good measurement for
for for this
so that's about as far as I thought
because I'm lazy
like everybody else and I went and
implemented as I looked around for
for I kinda algorithm for this and abuse
Levenstein
distance metrics which is like it is a
is an
nearly fifty or year old algorithm
invented by a guy called
blood in your the ensign it basin
calculates the minimum number
%uh single character added operations
that you need the to change or transform
one string into another
the operations are INSERT DELETE and
substitute
a so
I tried this implement it was a fairly
interesting baskin's it's a
it's a nice little outward is it's based
computer science 101 so
as it's been a while since houses I did
that so it's nice to
go back to the roots the so I
I had a look at the various now
the various password I found and back to
our Star Trek fan
the difference between obi-wan awaits
and 09
is just one single substitution
the difference between 09 and 10 is
actually to
substitution you have to substitute
0-for-1 9 per 0
and then on to 11 that's another
single substitution and just for good
measure has had looks if you
substitute a lot more replace subsidy
I don't know it's a big matrix or what
it does so it's it finds the shorts path
thats no a distance have nine editing
this the same as markers
talking about right other
so the average distance turn out to be
just over one
on are mainly because at this thing here
in because going from oh nine to 10
perhaps be dozens to said one
now so okay I thought but
this there might be mmm more interesting
ways to
joke you know this site so I thought
about it a bit more
om and I figure that well maybe I should
try to county is a
the difference patterns instead of
passwords
so I did basically what they're doing
and
hashed out in the other tracking after
they make you know
patterns for for hybrid hikes
so I transformed all uppercase
characters the
do it up because you largest now
digits an special characters to s
and this is how you can predict the
future
cuz what happened then is that om
only 108 became that pattern I can read
it is on silly
are 09 became that
10 became that 11-game that
and the average Palin's distances 0
which means that for patterns this user
is using exactly the same pattern for
every password arm
incidentally this is the this was the
third most popular Palin
overpasses in this on it the most power
popular one had
an extra couple bands at the end some
assuming that was the
year with Ford
alright arm
let's do some jumping to conclusions
here this is my favorite sport
this parents are uses responses to
password policies
clearly I mean now users are bloody lazy
they'll find the easiest way just path
of least resistance
they've the minimum effort they can do
to
to create a pattern that is hers to the
policy and they'll
for use it and use it in a user uses the
changes
little as possible each time you'll see
in this is no surprise right
are and this leads obviously to
very predictable sequence this
he cracked a single password you can
pretty much
guess all future passers unless they
break up with a girlfriend or they
forget the password
are really was it seem that they forgot
the original sequence
headed reset and then fell back into the
original
'em so yeah so I was thinking this
this is a bit silly weekend we can't do
this
this is just the what is the point of
having passed for security if this if
it's that easy to predict
so I tried fix it I try to find a way to
to improve this
up the question then is how to actually
prevent user from forming patterns based
on the policy
a is there anything we can do and i was
thinkin thinking house
and then suddenly I don't know when but
at some point I
there was this one is eureka moments
changeable see everybody time in
and is quite obvious that this is house
has to be done so I'm gonna deter a bit
into
a into the were the cartoons for a bit
you probably always already saying this
I mean
this is old stuff this is 1998 its
fifteen years ago
this password policy is nothing compared
to work using today
correct
well we squeal like a pig users will be
cheering if we had %uh this simple
possibles
so fast forward about seven years
this shows up now I was missing
something
Knauer an hour more closer to what we
are actually using today
I am we do we're doing doodles
Android business pattern thing that's
due
basically sign language I don't know as
a
we doing that kinetics passwords maybe
gonna
lead this from sup
it's a stretch okay let's go realizes
that's clearly voice recognition right
so sorry here but with
this is just simplistic stuff compared
to what I
think is necessary so is business going
to be in New World Order
we're going to generate a new password
policy on every password change
on so this means
we need to I'll generate we need to have
a cell rules
on how these generate how these
individual policies are to be generated
so there has to be like a policia about
the policies or a
a mess policy the so
enter the matter pass for medical see
which is
basically a blog post I wrote three
years ago
back then it was just thinking out loud
I've got a bit further this time
so to explain the matter policy the way
I envisioned it could be done
differently
but you know this is one one approach I
set up to carries a rules
one category is and are the non-volatile
rules there are the rules that affects
their
always going to be in the generated
policy
and their is something you will set
on at I very any apps trying to
implement this
than to have the both our rules these
are customized
for each individual policy
so here some examples %uh non-volatile
I'll the new general policy must deviate
from the previously generally
policy on at least three points okay
that means we have to store this policy
for each time
user changes password thats that's
doable
it's impractical but sure we can do that
arm
the other thing is that I think most
everything
agree that most passwords suck anyway
so it's just rejects I
why seventy-three percent init I just
picked
mom you can probably a price that number
more closely with some statistics
but then you would have to actually
implement a password
quality metric which as far as I know
nobody is done properly
there are billion different tense
none of them work probably think so arm
right cars
just you wait yeah
so I'm also each now the ball is I'll
policy rules well as a 73 percent chance
be included so sometimes there's a min
and password sometimes there won't be a
minute
on time in length et cetera
a.m. there could be other rules this is
just
you know we continue our discussion
later so the balls are rules
the which are serve the
the interesting part so the possibles in
and keep in mind I'm just talking about
a single policy
for a single user for a single pass for
change
now minimum personal lines
randomly chosen between one and 73
someone pointed out that well I would
love a password
that had a minimum length of up one
character
well that's going to be addressed as
well
duties at the Max or password length why
you would do that I don't know
pictures its not necessarily going to be
included in any way so
yeah next on I'll password must or
maybe must not contain a projector
characters the same thing with lower
case
digits and special characters
now keep in mind that
only 73 percent of these are going to be
included or other
there's only a 73 percent chance that
each one of these are going to be
included in any given
policy so it's gone Chen around a bit
I continued arm well as another
suggestion
some percentage balls I mean obviously I
I was only thinkin
the Western languages where you have
balls and
I don't know what you got in Chinese
won't but no I wasn't I have no idea why
I ended up with 73 but 75 was too
obvious
incidently I was born in 75
yep a.m. while
and the opposite password must contain
at least this as integer constants
on well okay so already now if you're
paying close attention which I hope you
are you can spot
a little niggle what if that random
number turns out to be 51 and 51
tough luck you won't be changed the
password
well actually reaches regenerate
generate a new
we didn't generate a new password policy
or we could
implement code that makes sure these
paradoxes or
are mutually exclusive rules don't occur
the right another on
and different characters so even if you
have a minimum length and one
if this room kitchen as 18 then
obviously the minimum length is going to
be a team anyway
are yeah
right is one that this is a simple
version on it
it must not much are word
or words found in and some kinda
dictionary which you predefined
your list addition issue that one look
into that
it might be you know rock you passwords
might be
a Oxford
unabridged something which but make
re tough okay am
also if you have other you other kinds
of information I mean
if if you all you have is just
you going to do change the password and
the these are rules that work but if you
have more information about user like
user name
you know the password history you know
the username email address you can of
course reference this
and create rules that that
well based off a bomb II have no idea
what age would be with you
real name other personal information you
can do you sound a similar phone
matching
I'll words that sound like other words
are not allowed no sounds this pastor
sounds like previous password
she talked about you talk the password
Janice you talk about passwords that
sounded like others or
right to this prevents that are you can
use rhyming dictionary is
around you can reference world events
you are not allowed to have
a password that contains ukraine
Thailand here that kinda stuff
these are just you know thoughts and
ideas of a mistake there's
stock in this house a I'm running out of
ideas here
these are things that can can base these
rules of
okay so you think this is ridiculous
right
well I prefer concert here and is going
to be a bit of those
a bit %uh audience participation I think
and let's see if we can actually
make this work in some way
are you basing this most of its
its do
he home alright
so you're seeing here is an example over
this is an example a a policy its policy
has an idea
and just for reference I guess
I am what you're looking at now
is one password policy and its
its up it what I'm doing is checking a
blank password so
there so obviously password must have a
maximum I'm for
63 characters that's that works provide
pressure
but a minimum like this 53 I am
not and I'll are cast on season we don't
have any characters are all
numbers and balls 21 per cent counts and
should be doable
forty different actors he well
okay so not lower case
are second
all that easy let's just start typing
what up but
I i dial blood testing this and what I
found works best is just mashing the
keyword
see what happens the
yeah attack pretty
im I think cats work better
they don't destroy the keyword I as if
you can do this
arcade 53 character the Hindu thats the
no
lower case so we can will things like
this
must contain digits a 40 different
characters
mom and second offer yeah
are just rude X thirty-three percent up
we have more is there anything else we
can answer
i jus should
up are you can fix up
ok area
so I am up for delivery geysers
his meh now we can start
typing good idea her you
well
an I should probably do this oh there
you are
I was your impression
gotta what
was back you
Korea now fitted
who said anything about memorizing about
you read by us so well
that memorizing the password isn't
really my
my something I've considered here a
mainly because there are password
managers the main thing I wanted to
avoid was
predictability a password so if we
going generate a new password policy
let's see what happens
to this one so this is a new password
policy
it's only the minimum life has changed
maximum length change
a now it has again Taylor case and over
I it must not contain special characters
are you have to remove these
mmm of
and I must not much words found in the
Rocky password list was the most popular
iraqi 123 456
well see
that's actually there
home well I noticed
12 is not a password in want
I
well is I
wells RAM need nineteen tags are some
teams are going to the party's old
sorry on 119 right must to not kiss the
19 purse problems and concerns so
but
order and I need to do this
the law so
even if so even if this
this seems impossible it is actually
possibly passwords
match this you will need the live
feedback
otherwise urs lost on
as is yeah of
year paint
sure now
you make a password manager generate
sequences
well I want to avoid I is this it is bad
for
not
I'm ignore the human aspect is this
something you would crack
with you run this through our to
bus its long here this
okay sir
so it appears that I've I managed two
things one thing is
actually three things the first thing is
to avoid patterns
usually are no longer able to create
predictable pattern second one is no
I all this this all depends on how you
set up your medical
of course but it appears that is very
easy to achieve
passwords that are very hard to guess
and the third thing I've managed to do
is alienate my users
severely but I'm hoping there'll be some
girl you know Stockholm Syndrome
thing going on here so after a while
diffused
alright to China long
are you get there I just
delete this one and as a No few rules
this time
any suggestions how to start
us
well will just continue with mister so
it's too short
did me a digit
six different him well that's just help
but twice
for lower there is racism
americanism I'd be
lost per
rising
in them
be whether
page I JK L okay as it is in past one
and no special factors need for that
only one digit you can remember
this is is it was the most filling in
your nap
II I
so party go back to the presentation
hey right so abuse them
this is the practical and approach to
anything
but this is unfortunately the way we
seem to be heading
less we find it difference method
handling
which circus nicely around you
peco or any other kind of password
manager
the things that pastors aren't bad their
cheese and if we just ignore the fact
that we need to remember them
we can generate passwords that are huge
and random and they would be great but
for the fact that we need to remember
them so that's about it
for me if anybody's interested in
actually implementing our
real version this I can surely help
but I don't think you make an
appointment questions
yes
on
Genesis failing to get my conversion is
well I don't have that much of a
conclusion
more it's more a you know writing on the
wall
thing the writing on the wall is that
this is where we're heading with
current password policy reviewed
I suggesting work like heck to find
different solution first
yes which is what I said if you have
been answered
and Russ yet
would you mind picking up a bit yeah
our your cat okay
so the question is is how how does it
work from usability
love you doesn't you should ignore it
but you do tend to get a bit
emotionally invested in the past year or
you're creating might actually be easier
to remember because you worked so hard
created yep good
yes up WAP
was related
us he said
up all
use also
us or basis
much up
you saw said
no you need up all
up well up
aren't
hope law
should pops
lost house
made usual yes up
halls on is
also said
ass for map
you you
min
also mass up
where run
much
yep
people
now this will be the policy did
all for you up
he
up
there was a question of here first
I'm sorry speaker please
did put into this know I did
or up
see is the problem is the password
managers are
are rather limited I mean you can say
the
food by is a including exclude yet maybe
you could you could maybe
managed yeah
I'm said
than or percent while
up
I'll up
he
people use
soap
up in
anything
the question is how
how far away are we from Boise
recognition as a login or
indication method group
way in the future
I
the technology is already here its
was not that expensive either is
but its yet
obviously has his phone its it's being
implemented as we speak
and on various platforms so secured
that's a different story that the most
I mean that the most practically secure
biometric is
what beam pattern recognition or
something the other ones are good
armistead I iris scanners is
low on their no
you're correct and also the attack
vector would be trying to replicate
the vein pattern it would be attacking
the chain between
so it's largely irrelevant that's
matter now has the problem we don't
really have a good
the passwords right now maybe when
speakers down or good
yet up
I'm not saying happy
old I'm not saying that a multilingual
policies are the questions
a yeah always
said
law if you want to try out this
particular version
a later tonight if necessary yeah
not at all i mean
people memorize thousands of digits of
pi
or any other towns so there's gonna be
some what
people very special people here
a only know a they're not necessarily
Mensa members
they were biology call cell phones or
something them
Billiton she could probably love this
but the ability to
memorize stuff is not pulling IQ
right yet
crosstalk now my I'm done any other
cousins
%um
I use
companies that into them much good
I allow on good well you have a
different
a indications are obviously deploying
matter past policies as well
are you're talking about the termination
trust
thing where where the the box topper
something yeah
that'll be a nice another time no
the use pies
are yeah we've seen that we see
the din digits of pi
bull up
actually what this is anecdotal evidence
again but I've heard people
are just
moving out one step further into the the
small
for each hydration so that's predictable
up
me well I'll
me that's what they can remember yes
this it
there was a couple there are some a a
memory rules for remembering digits of
pi
years or something like that I guess
some other stuff 12:30 is there
yeah
we're pretty good at remembering years
four-digit years
because we don't remember the difference
remember
here so you can split it up like that
ca
and I can only remember on sixties
and wanna miss group
up