foreign
good afternoon thank you all for having
me my name is Ian haken I'm a security
software engineer at Netflix and I've
spent about six and a half years they
are mostly working on the platform and
infrastructure security team and today I
want to talk about some adventures in
authentication and authorization and to
kick it off I want to talk about one of
the first times I got admin credentials
to our Cloud ecosystem so this was
during a red team exercise it wasn't
just while I was walking down the
hallway so I was acting as malicious
Insider and the target of my attack was
this Keys key service we have running in
our Cloud environment the idea behind
this key service is that it sort of
hands out different flavors of
credentials to developers like building
code at their desk that's later going to
run in the cloud but the thing that
makes the attack interesting is that
it's not something I can talk to
directly it lives up there in our cloud
in our VPC something with you know
firewalls around it all those good
things so the way you actually interact
with this system is through our internet
gateway service so this is the thing
that I actually log into with my SSO
credentials and that's going to proxy
the request on my behalf up to this key
service and the key service is going to
turn around and say okay well is Ian
actually allowed to get the key he's
asking for so it's going to call out to
our authorization service that's going
to give a yes no answer
and this is sort of all fine the way
I've drawn it the challenge with this
diagram is that there's a hop between
the thing that I logged into and the
thing that needs to know who I am in
order to do that check that I'm allowed
to get the key so the way this was
initially solved during the course of
this exercise is the internet gateway
throws in this little header says who is
the user and passes that up to the key
service
and that's a little bit problematic for
probably a handful of reasons but the
the big problem is that anything else
that's sort of in this ecosystem can put
whatever they want to in that header so
if I get control over something else
that's able to talk directly to the key
service then I can pretend to be anyone
and fortunately for me pretending to be
an attacker here there's a convenience
service already running in the
environment that lets you run whatever
code you want we've got this python
notebook system lets you run data run
queries against our Big Data Warehouse
schedule those things to run later but
importantly it literally lets me run
whatever code I want so I was able to
ask it to go talk to this key service
put admin in a header and give me some
credentials back so
that's the picture that I kind of want
to talk about for roughly the next 20
minutes uh the and talk about the
various iterations we went through
trying to make improvements to this
ecosystem and importantly talk about a
lot of the things that didn't quite work
that still had problems had different
threat models we hadn't considered and
if you're working in a similar space
thinking about problems like this or
really just trying to solve
authentication authorization your
ecosystem I'm hoping to just save you
some time and kind of fast forward to
this last step that we were finally
happy with
so all right talking about
authentication authorization and so
before I get too far into it I'm just
going to spend one minute to find those
terms make sure we're all talking about
the same thing so authentication AKA op
n is establishing your identity usually
there's some form of credential involved
there's a bunch of different ways you
can do authentication a lot of different
Technologies but at the end of the day
it's proving who you are to the remote
system and then authorization is the
other piece of it once we've established
who you are we want to know are you
allowed to do the thing so the thing can
vary a lot depending on the context
usually there's some resource you're
acting on some type of action you might
be doing a read versus a write they can
be a lot of other Dynamic factors pulled
in what sort of roles you have whether
you did MFA when you logged in what IP
you're coming from lots of things can
feed into that but authorization output
is basically a yes or no answer
and one of the things that we've been
seeing at kind of industry trend for is
a sort of centralization of a reusable
optimized authorization system and
that's kind of the what I'm alluding to
with this picture over here where my key
service is calling out to something it's
calling to something that has a rich
expressible policy language a lot of
information about roles and attributes
on the user and there's some links here
that you can look up about with some
examples of some of these sort of uh
optimized authorization services
but going back to our picture
uh the first fix that we wanted to lean
into is using affordable Bearer
credentials and so Bearer credentials
are basically just something that proves
who you are that can be passed along
kind of regardless of the context of the
specific request and this is a great
blog post I really like that does a
really good survey uh it truly is
tedious it goes through a lot of
different Technologies but regardless of
the specific to that the relevant bit
here is that it's something that can be
passed along the Hop so I do my SSO
login here I authenticate I get some
kind of like oidc access token or jaw to
prosetto or macaroon or biscuit
whichever whichever is your favorite and
that can be pass along when my internet
gateway makes a call to the key service
so the key service is able to validate
that this is actually an authentic
credential unpack the username from it
make the same authorization check as
before and now this sort of solves the
initial problem if there's some sort of
remote code execution in the service it
can't pretend to be anyone it has to use
a real credential that can be verified
by the key service
so this resolved the initial problem we
had
but we ran into a different problem with
this picture and the different problem
here is because of a completely
different service so in this case we had
a travel service this was an
off-the-shelf piece of software that
does sort of hotel and travel bookings
for us and this was part of the same
ecosystem so my bear credentials have
passed in there whenever I want to go
book a flight with our internal booking
system
but the problem is uh we had a really
good vulnerability scanner set up
discovered that there was a
unauthenticated rce in this service and
uh it turns out it was because it was
pulling in some super old version of
Open Source Library had rce in it uh
lots of goods Red teams that I work with
and the question came up during the
incident review what's the worst case
scenario if a malicious actor had gone
into the system well they have to have
real credentials in order to make use of
these calls to other systems but the
problem is that this is a service that
was used by basically every employee at
the company so when Joe admin went and
booked his flight his credentials flowed
into that service and those credentials
could have been forwarded by malicious
actor back up to this key service so
this is another way of getting admin
credentials from a single point of
compromise completely unrelated to the
security of that system so sort of the
lesson in walking through that incident
review is that using Bearer credentials
specifically in this way introduces a
high risk of compromise from any single
point of failure because any individual
service in the whole ecosystem that gets
compromised any user that has gone to it
can now have their credentials harvested
and reused in this way
so one potential fix for that uh that
people have asked me about a lot is what
about using credential Scopes so
credential Scopes is a bit of an
overloaded term it can kind of be
implemented a few different ways
depending on exactly which
authentication technology we're talking
about so like jots uh have an audience
in them oidc tokens have Scopes but the
idea is that your credential instead of
just being the same credential you use
everywhere has something embedded in it
that says what it's meant to be used for
so when I go to the key service I use
one flavor of credential or something
with my username in it that says this is
for getting keys out of the key service
and when I go and talk to that Travel
Service I have a different flavor of
credential a different audience or scope
embedded in it that says this is usable
for the travel service so this solves
the problem somewhat because then these
credentials I'm sending down there can't
be replayed against the key service but
the problem is that this only works in
sort of a static unchanging microservice
ecosystem so one enhancement that came
along down the road is that account
calendaring service wanted to get users
calendar data sorry the Travel Service
wanted to get users calendar data in
order to find like empty blocks in your
calendar go booked flights during that
period but those credentials that we're
sending down to the Travel Service can't
be used against the calendaring service
because they don't have the appropriate
scope instead the credentials that I get
sent down have to have scopes for both
services in them
but you can't just magically change the
Scopes down here that would sort of
defeat the whole point instead that has
to be configuration that's propagated
all the way back of this call chain the
Travel Service needs to use multi-scope
credentials and so your initial
authentication needs to embed both
Scopes in it
and that kind of cascade maybe isn't
that big of a problem in the picture
that I've drawn but Netflix is a really
big microservice ecosystem we have
literally thousands of microservice
applications and any given API call
based on some traces I pulled up uh
preparing this talk has on average
around seven 10 different microservices
it ends up talking to so when you look
at a given API call having any idea
about exactly what Scopes you would need
to embed to include all of those
different microservices it talks to is
really hard to figure out just a priori
and even if you do a really good job of
that you get a snapshot of your
ecosystem find out everything that every
call is going to talk to you have the
same problem I just mentioned before
where as soon as a new dependency gets
added that has a cascading effect where
whatever configuration enumerates the
Scopes that are needed has to go back up
every single micro service and
ultimately affects dozens if not
hundreds of Engineers
so in trying to think through how we
would roll this out our takeaway was
that using finely grains Scopes like
this at least in the context of like
trying to map them to a single micro
service and keeping up with that was
just intractable at a system as uh sort
of agile and dynamic as the one we were
working in so we basically gave up on
that effort
instead what we did was lean into
Services service or S2s access control
so the idea here is that in addition to
the user having credentials each
individual micro service has its own
credentials that uses whenever it talks
to the next hop in the chain
so in this case our internet gateway is
going to authenticate down to this
compromise Travel Service the travel
service has to authenticate up to the
key service and importantly on each hop
along the way there's an access check
and here the key service would check is
the travel service allowed to talk to
the key service and the answer should be
no there's no reason that should be
talking to me so that blocks this
particular attack where a user's
credentials can be replayed against that
so I think this is what at least in my
experience people mean when they talk
about sort of zero trust microservice
design where every hop along the way you
don't take for granted that that service
should be talking to you you want to
know who they are and are they in some
kind of Access Control list so enrolling
this out we kind of ran into a couple of
gotchas that are worth pointing out the
first is just I mentioned that each
service should authenticate to the next
hop but exactly how do you do that if
you're using the same type of
authentication technology as I said we
should be using for users so that it can
be passed along then you basically end
up eroding everything you're trying to
build because in this case the internet
gateway authenticates down to the travel
service and that service could just
Harvest that credential replay it
against the key service and now you've
kind of gained nothing in this whole
design so the lesson there is that
whatever authentication technology you
use it needs to be something
non-forwardable in contrast to what
we've been talking about for the user
credentials and exactly how you do that
you time we've got a lot of choices you
can either use finely Scopes Bearer
credentials or mtls certificates that's
what we ended up leaning into but the
point is it should be something that you
can't just sort of verbatim replay
and the other Pitfall sort of alludes
back to that previous Slide the fact
that we've got this really big ecosystem
with really deep call graphs and in each
step of that call I'm now suggesting
that we add an authorization check where
we say is Hop N minus one allowed to
call Hop N and that means that for any
given API request we're going to end up
having about 10 authorization checks and
if you're doing an RPC to some
centralized authorization service then
that's adding 10 times one two
milliseconds and that adds up that's
like 20 milliseconds for every API call
and if you've got a very rich home page
that does dozens of API calls just to
load it just adding up to now hundreds
of milliseconds which is just a
non-starter for basically everyone we
talked to about this so the way you
implement this is really important and
the thing that we learned in talking to
our partners is that we really have to
come up with a solution where the
authentication and authorization can
people can be performed locally so
there's a old talk we gave you can look
that up later uh that's still very
relevant that really goes into the
details of how we built in this
authorization story to be zero round
trip and it's basically just pushing
down Ackles and evaluating those locally
but you really want to design that into
how you actually Implement these
features
so all right that's 2s and that does
block the uh last attack I was talking
about because now our compromise service
can no longer go and talk to the key
service but there is one more attack in
this picture that in hindsight was kind
of obvious but actually sort of took us
to this level of iteration to really
consider and defend against which is
we've got our credentials being
harvested by this compromised service
and it can't go talk to the key service
directly
but there's nothing stopping it from
Just replaying that credential back
against our front door back against the
internet gateway because that sort of
looks just like a genuine user and that
can be played directly against the key
service so whether this compromise
service is exfil trading these
credentials or actually literally
calling the internet gateway itself the
fact that we've forwarded the actual
user credentials along every call inside
our ecosystem now means we actually
still have the same problem as before
any individually compromised service can
have those credentials exfiltrated and
reused
so the lesson there is that we don't
actually want to forward the actual end
user credentials internally because that
has the same problem as before any
single point of compromise uh leads to
Badness
so our fix for that was to use something
that I'll call end user context ticket
so I lifted that term from uh Google's
Beyond prod white paper we actually
developed this technology independently
called it something different but we
don't have a public write-up about it so
I'll use that term and the idea is
fairly straightforward you still forward
the end user credential off to this
ticketing system but what that does is
verify these credentials bundle them
into a new form of credential called an
end user context ticket has the same
data inside it but it's a different form
of Bearer credential that's meant to be
forwarded around internally
so that ticket is what gets passed
around instead of the actual user
credentials
and now if there's a compromised service
that gets a hold of that ticket well
it's sort of useless it can't be passed
back to the front door because that only
accepts the actual user credentials and
because of our implementation of S2s
access controls the compromise service
can't talk to the key service directly
even though it has a good ticket but the
services service Access Control prevents
that so this is sort of the final
picture of the state that we ended up
being pretty happy with that sort of
blocked all these different styles of
attacks and compromise that we were
worried about
but this has a different problem and
it's no longer really a technical one
instead it's a human one
everything I've just described now has
several different flavors of
authentication Technologies has several
different ways of doing RC and it's a
lot to wrap your head around so we've
got not just different types of
authentication Technologies we've
actually got different flavors of Bearer
tokens we've got mtls certificates in
the mix we've got multiple authorization
tools one for doing the local S2s Access
Control one that has a centralized
robust policy engine and in practice
we've actually got several flavors of
remote policy services that have been
sort of optimized for different
verticals and use cases and reverse
indexing and all sorts of things and to
operate in this system to actually sort
of be secure you have to be able to use
all those Technologies otherwise there's
not really a good way for this
authenticated RPC call to reach you so
how do we allow our developers to
operate in this ecosystem when we have
all these requirements for what they
have to do and the answer to that is
probably not too surprising is the
answer to everything in computer science
it's add a layer of attraction
but how we did that I think is sort of
just useful to illustrate so we've got
all these different flavors of
authentication we've got the bear tokens
when you come into the internet gateway
we've got mtls for the services service
authentication we've got these end user
context tickets
but regardless of how a request comes in
regardless of which combination of
things get used for any particular hop
in this call graph our platform packages
this all up and creates an authorizable
context and this is just an opaque
object that our developers are able to
work with and basically the only thing
you can do with this totally opaque
object is to pass it into our other
abstraction piece which is the
authorization client and this is a thing
which is configured under the hood to go
talk to whichever flavor of
authorization makes sense for the
application being developed
so when a developer actually wants to
write some code like this key service
where they're implementing this RPC now
they can inject this authorizable
context which is some kind of opaque
thing that they can just take for
granted will be there through magic
in any given request they can wire up
whichever authorization client they want
configured and you just pass that
authorization contact directly into it
and it's going to give you a yes no
answer and it's part of a platform
provider we also give you other useful
utilities like being able to log that
authorization context a bunch of things
that know how to unpack it under the
hood so that our developers don't need
to try and introspect this thing because
that's sort of the abstraction barrier
we want to keep
so that's basically everything I wanted
to talk about today but I think there's
sort of three takeaways that really sort
of summarize everything I just said and
the first is really what I've been
talking about since that very first
slide which is that you want your end
user identity propagated throughout your
ecosystem in order to actually have
useful fine-grained authorization at the
back of your call graph
and so uh if you're going to do that you
need to actually have verifiable and
forwardable identity otherwise you have
that problem that we had on the first
slide where anyone can pretend to be
anyone
but you want to avoid passing the actual
user credentials in order to solve that
and that's where the end user context
tickets are for
Services service authen and Aussie on
the other hand
can that limits any single point of
compromise again that sort of zero trust
that's why everyone's been talking about
it for the last however many years
but that needs to use a different
technology it shouldn't be something
affordable because that sort of erodes
everything you're trying to build with
that and there's some unique
requirements in particular for our use
case at our scale that says we can't use
the same centralized authorization
service that we want to use for other
use cases
and so the last takeaway is just if you
believe these first two points then
you're not going to use a single authen
or Aussie technology in your ecosystem
and so you really want to plan
accordingly as you go out on this
journey and for us that meant be nice to
our developers provide a good layer of
distraction means they don't have to
think about these problems but the nice
thing about abstractions is that they're
useful for you too because it allows you
to be agile in exactly which bits and
pieces of authen Technology you pull in
because if you're anything like me it's
going to take you more than one try to
get this right you're going to try some
new authen and I'll see you Technologies
and that abstraction layer kind of
defends you against having to uh tell
your developers to update their code yet
again so that's it
thank you all for coming and I think
we've got some yeah about seven minutes
for questions