foreign
if you're watching this video no it
doesn't mean I'm dead just means I'm
still coming up positive on my covet
tests
I hope you enjoy my talk lies and myths
in infosec
here we go
so why are myths and lies even a thing
infosec is challenging enough
we're in a huge growing industry sure
it's still a young industry but uh
growing lots of money in it if you have
any kind of cyber security experience
you're guaranteed a job for for life as
far as I can tell
VCS private Equity firms pouring tons of
money into it and in general in the last
couple decades we got the budget we
asked for we got the people we asked for
so why would we make up myths and lies
why would that even be a thing
so that's what we're going to explore
today
and dive into a little bit deeper
yep damages and losses are huge why
pretend that things are even worse and
one of those things is Comfort which
might sound like a weird way to say that
but because a lot of people in this
industry are very Mission oriented
they tend to latch on to things that fit
that narrative that make them feel proud
of doing what they do in cyber security
and uh you know things they would want
to share and so a lot of myths take that
form and then the more nefarious lies
maybe prey on that
another reason definitely more nefarious
is the fake it till you make it you know
we live in a culture now where this is
entertainment even you know docudrama
series on uh theranos and on wework uh
I've been popping out left and right
fire Festival I think there were two
docudramas on those that came out at the
same time on different streaming
networks and you know this is just part
of startup culture uh that's almost a
joke at this point but it's it's a very
real thing and a lot of cyber security
companies are startups there's over uh I
think 3 000 cyber security companies
I've seen from people who track lists of
those things
and uh and a lot of them just want to
meet those investor goals you know they
want to land that next customer and some
of these myths and lies help them to do
that
and finally reason three
proving uh you know some of these myths
and lies uh doing the due diligence due
diligence on them can be very difficult
and I think nutrition is an interesting
uh industry that we can draw parallels
to where
sure I feel great after drinking that
shake uh just after I wake up but is
that because I got two two more hours of
sleep last night or is it because I
drink the shake it's really hard to
separate the two out at least for an
individual
so see if you can spot a pattern as we
go through the talk here today this one
I've got Cloud9 card systems and blue
security
confirmation bias is probably the better
way to say Comfort when I was talking
about uh you know things that fit the
narrative before and it's it's a very
dangerous one because again being very
Mission oriented if we don't prepare
ourselves to do that due diligence to
check on stats you know to think twice
about the things that people are telling
us we can be very vulnerable and
susceptible to confirmation bias into
accepting and repeating those lies and
myths and I think the way that
yourbias.is puts it here is very useful
think of your ideas and beliefs as
software you're actively trying to find
problems with rather than things to be
defended and it's a very unnatural uh
way to do that we tend to get very
defensive very emotional about our our
beliefs and
it's just dangerous when myths and lies
come to form some of those beliefs and
uh
that's a healthier way of looking at it
I think
uh sunk cost fallacy I think is behind
uh some of the reason that we see myths
turn into lies so I think starting out
uh there are a lot of myths that are
um unintentional that are accidental you
know perhaps somebody just says it and
it catches on or somebody misinterprets
a stat or a graph and at some point the
people using this information find out
that it's a myth it's debunked sometimes
directly to them and at that moment when
they decide whether or not they're going
to continue using that bad stat I think
that's where it becomes the myth the
myth becomes lie
and uh I I would like to think that at
least in some of these cases uh you know
these companies aren't entirely frauds
from the beginning like theranos for
example you know I've I've dived deeply
into that story and I I would like to
think at some point that she really did
want to innovate really did want to
change the world but at that point where
experts said no this can't be done or at
least it can't be done uh in the near
future
you know I I think uh
you know there's that sunk cost that
we've already raised so much investment
I've already promised so many people
that we can do this you know some
people's egos don't allow them to turn
around and go back or to say sorry we
can't do it and return the investors
money
and of course lies travel much faster
than the truth uh because it takes time
to do due diligence and to discover the
truth
varus spiky pickle restaurants HB Gary
Federal distribute.it digit notar at
this point some folks should definitely
start seeing a pattern
and let's take one of these bad stats
cyber crime costs 2.9 billion dollars
per minute
just let that let that sit let that
marinate in your brain especially those
of you with
statistics or who have
taken classes and statistics or have
math or
Science degrees
2.9 billion dollars per minute
okay so sure you know maybe they meant
to say million and they said billion but
this you know once this tweet is up for
half a day for 24 hours it can do a lot
of damage it can spread quite a bit to
their credit they pulled it down but
in a lot of cases that damage is already
done it's amazing how long myths and
lies can live given just a few hours of
life before corrected
so why challenge infosec myths and lies
there are a few practical reasons one of
them is credibility for our industry as
a whole like I mentioned before we're
still a very young industry you know so
we want to make sure that we maintain
this credibility you know we've got a
lot of attention from media we're not
professionalized we do manage a lot of
people in budget inside of a lot of
companies now so credibility is
something to protect you know our
reputation is something to protect
uh also some of these myths and lies can
misdirect uh our efforts to solve some
problems you know uh especially if if
these are being repeated by vendors by
thought leaders people who are trusted
within the industry uh a lot of damage
can be done in terms of you know
problems not getting solved because
resources are pointed in the wrong
direction
and finally you know I I think the truth
is worth tracking down because we often
get more than just the truth when we do
that we learn more along the way and
um and it's it's almost always more
interesting uh than the myth or the LIE
only honest code spaces you should
definitely see where this is going by
now
so there's one company behind most of
the fake stats in infosec this was
something I was fairly shocked to learn
and
um you might recognize some of their
stats one of them is the infamous uh
trillions of dollars uh in cyber crime
damages every year uh 10.5 trillion is
now the estimate for 2025 6 trillion was
the estimate in 2021 and if you're like
me I mean these are staggering numbers I
don't use these numbers at this scale on
a regular basis so I need context
you know I'm thinking what's Germany's
GDP is it is it less than 6 trillion is
it more than 6 trillion uh how much in
Ransom payments were paid last year how
much is global fraud every year
and um and the answer to those to those
questions does kind of help uh Germany's
GDP is indeed less than six trillion and
Global fraud numbers are less than 6
trillion you know so already I'm
thinking yeah this is this does not
track
um on top of that one of the biggest
issues in our field right now one of the
biggest cyber uh certainly one of the
most uh
um in the headlines for cyber crime is
ransomware and ransomware never hit a
billion dollars before it started going
back down yes it went down 40 percent
last year ransomware payments did
so
you know for ransomware payments are a
fraction of a sixth of a percent of six
trillion dollars I have no idea where
that
the rest of that is coming in you know
it definitely doesn't make sense and
when you try to research it there's no
data behind it there's no methodology
behind it there's there's nothing behind
it except
this number stated over and over and
over again by this company and everyone
that listens to them
they're also behind most of the job
numbers that you've seen which also have
no data behind them I don't think these
are as quite as egregious
I don't think they're off by orders of
magnitude but I do think they're off
and also they spend a lot of time
touting this old 60 percent of small
businesses go out of business within six
months of a data breach number which is
a crazy stat we'll talk about a little
bit later
and there's a tried and true process
behind this make up a stat repeat it as
much as possible in as many places as
possible there are plenty of media
Outlets that will let you pay or just
let you contribute uh content to them
that makes you know whatever you
contribute look very official on those
domain names
and then once you've gotten it posted in
enough places
you can cite it as if it's real research
as if there's some you know real data
behind it when in fact it's circular
it's recursive and there actually is no
source for that data there is no
methodology but at first glance you see
a footnote it looks uh like it's been
properly cited until you try and track
it down and find it it goes nowhere
and there's a lot of money to be made in
this this this company does very well
and it is featured and quoted uh
everywhere government Academia
uh industry experts uh
you I and you have probably seen these
stats uh at least a couple times this
year alone in 2023.
and to quote James McCormick Who Sold 50
million dollars 50 million pounds of
fake bomb detectors it does exactly what
it's designed to it makes money
a few more here
my biz homepage precedent Communications
Colorado Timberline vastemol
so back to the 60 stat this is one of
the most prolific and Long Live fake
stats and actually inspired me to do uh
a bit of research some of my favorite
research in fact
and again this is a weird stat when I
first saw this I thought
you know six months within six months of
a breach like that's a really long time
like small businesses going under within
six months of a breach
they could be going under for any number
of a reason of reasons they could be
going under because they're the 11th
cupcake shop in the neighborhood they
could be going under because they just
didn't manage money well you know it's
just uh it didn't sit well so I started
to look into it started to try and find
a source for this data but where's the
evidence behind this data it didn't
exist
so I started researching I thought
how many companies do actually go under
because of a breach or do any at all
and so after five years of doing that
research I found 23 companies not 23
companies last year but 23 companies in
the last 20 years in all time I can only
find 23 companies who have gone under
because
as a direct effect of a cyber security
incident or breach and you can you can
find that data there it's open to the
public in fact hundreds of people have
have helped me curate it over the years
and have submitted possible candidates
for this data set and I go through I
investigate each one and uh and yeah
only only 23. so now I've got some data
to counter this 60 of small businesses
stat
but where did it originally come from
so
National cyber security Alliance and
Symantec did a a joint report and a
quote made it into that report they
published it uh for for only a couple
months as far as I can tell before
taking it down and putting up a uh
retraction basically saying that you
know there's no data behind that stat
they don't know where it came from so
they're taking it out of the report
and because it sticks around because it
won't go away every year or maybe every
other year uh they uh publish yet
another retraction basically saying the
stats incorrect don't use it we're sorry
in fact a journalist named Joseph marks
from nexgov Tracked Down The Source and
actually interviewed the individual that
this quote came from that this bad stack
came from and he says I don't know I
heard it from a cyber security expert at
some point yeah I don't remember who or
when or what any of the details
and so there you know we finally Tracked
Down The Source but then how do you kill
it it's still getting used in fact the
source who came up who originated the
fake stat is still using it as of two
months ago on his own websites so he's
still pushing this bad stat even though
he knows uh there's no truth behind it
um it has been interviewed to that
effect by by an investigative journalist
and this has been quoted by the SEC it
led to a bill passing in the small
business cyber Security Act uh vendors
are using it thought leaders use it we
see it everywhere still
and now you know what this mystery
timeline is this is the list of 23
companies who have gone out of business
due to a uh cyber security incident or
breach
and yes there were a lot in 2019 and yes
I think at least four of those were due
to ransomware
so that's the most prolific year we've
ever seen is six companies not the 150
plus you would expect to see if that
stat were true
foreign
motivational myths and maxims so sayings
maxims whatever you want to call them uh
there's a few of these that wrinkle me a
bit and and
they perhaps help to sell products and
services but I I think they need to be
replaced you know first of all this one
particularly you've probably heard a lot
attackers only need to get it right once
Defenders have to get it right every
time
uh first off it's it's
you know very demotivational second of
all it's not true you know maybe this is
true for the very first hold the
attacker gets into the defender's
environment but from that point the math
flips and now the defender
um
only needs to catch the attacker once
the attacker has to evade them every
single time and the saying completely
flips once they're on the defender's
Turf the defender can have deception
traps you know there's all kinds of uh
preparation they can do to catch that
attacker now
mm-hmm
it's not if you get hacked it's when is
another one here
um
this is just numerically impossible
there aren't enough cyber security
uh or cyber criminals out there to
attack every business or every
individual in fact we've seen many cases
where attackers have had access to
thousands of networks and only chose to
attack one or two because that's all
they had the resources for so again this
is just uh Incorrect and not useful uh
unless I guess you're trying to sell
products and services
and then humans are the weakest link in
security this is another one that
bothers me because humans are humans and
of course humans are going to do human
things uh to quote uh Lisa plagomire
here humans are reliably unreliable
so
I would argue the weakest link is
anybody designing systems without humans
in mind for systems to be used by humans
without humans in mind
foreign
things up here I have my conclusion
cassowary who I will call Paul Paul will
help me wrap things up here uh have some
healthy skepticism uh take a little time
to look up stats find data that provides
that context like we did around the the
six trillion dollar number
um do do a few sanity checks a lot of
this stuff doesn't take a whole lot of
effort to check on
and a lot of these reports that there's
no footnotes there's no methodology
listed at the bottom of the report you
know there are no appendices why would
you trust it
if there's no scientific rigor why why
would you bother why would you bother
with it
um
also with the maxims I think it would be
great if we could come up with some
positive versions of these some
motivational ones rather than
demotivational that would be great to
replace the uh these tired stereotypes
and
going looking for data is a bit of an
art but it's easier than you'd think
you'd be surprised how much data is out
there
um data scientists tend to be very open
and sharing uh there's a lot of open
data sets out there the Verizon dbir
folks have made their Veris data set
available on their GitHub page and are
also very accommodating if you have any
questions or want them to do some custom
queries or you know tease out some some
insights you know that maybe you have
some ideas related to
um they're great about that stuff
and then failing that like I did you
know and start to gather the data
yourself again a lot of people jumped in
and helped me out with that
if you see a bad stat don't just accuse
your marketing team you know don't don't
you know just tell them to take down
that bad stat help them out you know
some marketing folks you know they're
not uh wired to go do due diligence on
every single stat maybe you know find
something they can replace it with you
know help them out a little bit don't
just uh don't just jump at them
um also encourage encourage them or if
it's you that's using some of these
stats uh you know include important
context like the number of uh uh
respondents to a survey for example
and also
I think statistics should be used to
carry
the story to further the story somewhat
a statistic should be the tip of the
iceberg of the conversation that you're
going to have not a blunt weapon like
that six trillion dollar number you know
like these maxims that are just made to
to strike fear and things like that uh
you know and assume that when you use
statistics you know that it's uh the
beginning of a conversation somebody's
gonna ask you about that statistic want
to dive deeper into it and have a
conversation about it
and again uh like I've done with my
research if you put together your own
data consider sharing it
finally I think it's worth uh pulling
out the truth because the truth is just
more interesting
um add more time to your presentations
uh so
well to your prep time for putting
together presentations so that you can
check your facts at figures or maybe if
you have somebody working for you that
can do that for you or maybe go hire
somebody on Fiverr that can check your
facts and figures
um I'm not sure if people on Fiverr do
that but it would be great if they did
and uh and if you spot a bad stat nicely
tell somebody you know that they might
want to replace that
thanks for listening to my talk