foreign
so if you don't know these folks you're
going to in a couple of minutes but
these are some of the best
um security and privacy related
journalists that I have worked with
um in my career and I invited them to
um to Enigma this year because we wanted
to have a conversation about how cyber
crime and other types of
um like security incidents and things
get covered kind of like the behind the
scenes of like how does this happen from
like The Newsroom perspective how do
reporters think about how to cover
certain things
um and so I'm also like a this is
terrible but I am a uh True Crime
Podcast Addict so I was like how can I
bring True Crime to Enigma
um and so this is the the incantation of
that so
um I'm gonna ask each of them to
introduce themselves
um and then uh we will start the
discussion um please post questions in
slack if you have them
um we'll ask those at the end or of
course you can use the mics in the room
as well
um but very rarely will you get the
opportunity to ask these folks questions
because you all work for companies with
PR teams
um except for Leah who's at fun employed
at the moment
um
so please please make use of this
opportunity so we'll start uh on my left
and then uh move to the end cool hi I'm
Alfred uh I'm a privacy reporter at
Politico prior to that I was also a
privacy reporter at the markup and uh I
covered cyber security and privacy for
uh CNET from 2016 to 2020 before we were
replaced by AI so
or you are AI right now in front of us
um I'm Lily Hayne Newman I'm a security
and privacy reporter at wired and I used
to be a general interest Tech reporter
at slate uh and yeah I have not yet been
replaced by AI to my knowledge
I'm Joe Mann
um I started covering tech security in
and I'm now at the Washington Post I
extends at the LA Times and the
financial times and then Reuters
and you know sometimes I write books so
I did one about
the Russian government uh being in
cahoots with organized cyber crime
called fatal system error
um and then more recently I wrote a book
called uh called the dead cow
so I want to start just with a little
bit of context for everybody because
you've all kind of covered cyber crime
in a little bit of a different way in
terms of the different players and
perspectives and the lens that you even
if you're covering the same incident
you were looking at it from different
Vantage points because you're focusing
on different like stakeholders within
that scenario so I want to ask how do
you decide which perspective to cover
right whether it's like victims the the
attackers the investigators and can you
actually can you ever cover them all
within the same story
yeah
um so a lot of my coverage was very much
focused on victims of cyber crime so
ransomware was a big deal I think it
still is but
um it was you know really creeping up
around the time that I was covering
cyber security so I was reaching out to
school as I was reaching out to you know
Folks at hospitals about how is this
impacting you um I think for me that was
just more important and I think it
mattered a lot more for our audiences
um because CNET was like a very like
General news Tech website so it made a
lot more sense for me to show the the
harms of cyber crime more than you know
what the how did this this like attack
happen or what vulnerability did they
get in on I think it was more valuable
for our readers to show you know here
here's the impact of like these kinds of
attacks
yeah I think it's a really interesting
question especially like can you do it
all in one story I I would say similarly
um wired we often
attempt to really focus on victims but
it can be really hard right like victims
all right this is you know something we
know about uh cyber crime and just sort
of uh security incidents in general or
security findings in general uh
vulnerability findings all types of
disclosure like people don't want to
talk about it and come forward and they
don't want to be on the record so
anytime they can avoid that they do so
that actually
makes it challenging I think sometimes
it can feel like well the perspective of
victims and the real human toll of some
of these things isn't being told enough
or isn't being heard enough but there is
a tension there where it can be really
hard to get that stuff on the record but
yeah we we that's a huge Focus for us
and but then I think a lot of other
perspectives like wired is always trying
to cover are kind of the the interesting
technical nuances as well of how things
happen and the sequence of events so
maybe that brings in a bunch of the
different perspectives but it's pretty
hard to hit everything in one story
especially like a tight news story
um
my hidden agenda is to try to educate
people about important complicated stuff
and write it in plain words that regular
folks would actually care about and see
why it's important and by regular folks
I'm including members of Congress most
of whom do not have engineering degrees
though that's improving the Holy Grail
though is a story where you can do the
whole chain from uh you know some dude
working in Russia
through his pay masters
to the infection to the victim but that
almost never happens last time I found
that perfect chain where you could
humanize the victims and tell say
explain what was happening the day they
got hit and the guy who's I wrote a book
about it so that was that was fatal
System error
um it is it is super rare I'm so I'm
agnostic about which pieces of the
puzzle I use to write a good story that
will bring attention to important policy
stuff that we have to figure out except
that I try not to I don't want to
arrowize the um the bad guys and I also
don't find most of them very interesting
I find the good guys more interesting
and generally the victims you know they
didn't do anything hideously wrong and
and you know the wrong place wrong time
and so I tend not to Spotlight them
either so I guess if I was gonna more
often than not I am focusing on the
investigation
and uh and talking about high
highlighting policy issues in play when
relevant
awesome what was the uh the your
favorite cyber crime story that you've
covered so far in your career
um so this is going to be a bit out of
left field I guess but it is I promise
it's really fun
um so I had uh read about
um
if you remember Jared Fogle his
situation uh he he got for those who
don't remember okay so he was a former
Subway uh spokesperson turned uh oh God
like child predator
um so his situation
um part of the bus they had these dogs
like sniff out like this hidden hard
drive that he had which I thought was
kind of insane
um and then I found out that there was a
canine training academy like two hours
away from where I work so I went to this
Academy and like I followed around this
dog like training procedure that they
have for dogs like to sniff out
Electronics specifically
um which is pretty cool I I got to spend
like the whole day with like a bunch of
dogs and it
cyber crime adjacent so
wow that rules
[Laughter]
um mine isn't fun at all okay
um I was just gonna say we have been
talking about this question and like I
think favorite is maybe not the word I
would use because this story is it's
hard to think of one
um I mean maybe like you were saying you
know one where you have the whole chain
and you can make it into an amazing
narrative in a book would be like a
favorite but typically these are stories
that are really painful to report or
like you know really sucks to see the
toll and just see the sort of moral
bankruptcy of the actors and
um but I I was just going to say that in
general like the the story line that I
feel like strongly about covering is
business email compromise where actors
sometimes through email compromise but
sometimes essentially just through like
extended phishing and social engineering
attacks trick companies into sending
money to pay like a a contractor that
doesn't really exist or you know put
someone on their payroll who doesn't
exist or something like that I'm
and this is like the the biggest type of
cyber crime in terms of losses you know
at least according to the complaints
that the FBI gets
um but it just doesn't get a lot of
coverage for I think the general
audience because it's uh that's kind of
it like that's what happens and none of
the companies ever want to talk about it
and I I think the the sort of numbers
that you know are reported to the far
way way under because companies don't
even want to talk about it with law
enforcement or anyone
um but it's huge and it and the same
concepts are used to in or it's sort of
enmeshed with other types of crime like
romance scams and now you know Pig
butchering which is same type of thing
where you're like
it's sort of bringing someone into this
web that is totally fictionalized where
they think they're corresponding with a
different person than they really are
and end up you know sending all their
money and these are all kind of on a
Continuum so anyway business email
compromise is I guess a favorite
uh I like
crimes that illustrate a new thing or an
important systemic problem
um so uh if you know fatal System error
was super useful for me in part because
the crimes themselves were dumb it was
just DDOS and it was extortion behind
the DDOS uh and it's and it's maybe
really boring technologically but the
beauty part is my grandmother can
understand you know we're going to knock
over your business until you pay us
money which is what they were doing
the the great thing about fatal System
error is that the first people that were
doing DDOS for higher or DDOS for money
uh were going after offshore gambling
companies serving U.S Bettors and that's
sort of a weird you know why would you
attack another mob well it's because
they're you know their infrastructure
was in Costa Rica or wherever not
terrifically uh deep it's because
there's no heck and way to go into the
FBI for help and it's because if they're
down on Super Bowl Sunday they are
completely screwed also they have a ton
of cash on hand
um so I was able to tell the story of
basically mob versus mob and one guy who
sort of accidentally infiltrated the you
know American like Gambino Mobsters uh
by after protecting them and then
deliberately infiltrated the Russian mob
um and and wound up with three names you
know names of three real people who
eventually got sent to jail in Russia
and you know the point of the story
wasn't like you know Kumbaya we can all
do this together and get Russian baddies
it's it's it's the outrageous effort it
took including like the British foreign
secretary uh attempts on the British
detectives life uh in Russia all this
stuff to get three basically mid-level
people before the Russian government
said okay you can stop investigating now
rather than go Upstream thank you very
much time to go
um so it was just it was a terrific
window on everything and it just because
that's a heavy one I'll tell you my in a
way like a perfect encapsulation of a
similar era was the theft of sex.com
um you know it was registered by Gary
kremen when it was free to register
Network Solutions it just seemed like it
might be a good idea to have some time
and then um Network Solutions was like
run by five people in a monkey and
um this this uh you know Small Time
Hustler from jail wrote you know forged
Gary's signature in a letter Network
Solutions and wound up with the the
domain Maine I was raking in millions
and millions of dollars and living it
high off the hog in Mexico and basically
getting away with it and to me he's the
real hero of the story because is there
anything encapsulates the.com Smash and
grab era that that's it
so have any of you been approached by
somebody who's claiming to be
responsible for an attacker or some kind
of incident I'm curious for those of you
who have how do you verify them as as
sources and does the fact that they are
potential criminals impact the way that
you interpret the information that they
give you
um that's actually never happened to me
so I'm gonna pass it over
um first I just want to say you said you
weren't going to glorify the actors but
that's that that's 1999 in a nutshell
um I
yeah so I I'm curious to hear your
thoughts on this too but I definitely
have uh like corresponded with entities
you know claiming to be the actor behind
particularly data breaches
um and you know some sometimes like
ransomware gangs and stuff are often
have like a a PR account or sort of a
public-facing account you know on uh
criminal forums where they're like
available to talk so that was something
that I was just going to say about this
is that I have uh done those types of
correspondences but I never really felt
like I was the only one they were
talking to
um it always just kind of feels like
yeah they're probably talking to a bunch
of researchers or researchers who are
sort of posing as being members of that
cyber criminal community and then
they're trying to like uh get the the
word out probably with other reporters
as well and so uh yeah I have had those
situations but I I haven't really had
the experience of being like
oh like this person's only talking
to me and they're claiming that they did
you know what I mean so but I don't know
have you had other experiences yeah so
there are other reporters
um that do it more than I do I don't
make a big habit out of it in part
because you know in part it's a matter
of vetting but the real part is I don't
want to there are many cases where they
want publicity you know they're
publishing confidential information and
they want everyone to see that
confidential information and that's why
you go to the media because that puts
the most pressure on the company and I
don't want to be a part of that I don't
have like there's no hard and fast rule
but I have kind of personally a sliding
scale
um and you know the least likely I am
if it's like a nation-state activity and
they're trying to hurt you know
government X by leaking stuff my bar is
super high I want to see you know clear
public benefit from publishing the
information so I didn't do much
rummaging in the Sony hack
um because they're you know there was I
guess there's some mild racism and
there's some other like corruption
things but I didn't want to help out
North Korea
um so it you know the Whistleblower I'm
most most likely to publish something a
criminal group is in the middle
um but I haven't I haven't done a lot of
chatting with them as one of my more
memorable ones was I did chat with
guccifer too
um and he was saying you know hey I can
get you you know stuff on this stuff on
that
um and the FBI has already read this so
I'm not really revealing very much
um and you know I chatted him a while
and looked at what was available and
decided it wasn't it wasn't worth it to
me and so I passed
um and I I you know I later interviewed
FBI people were like yo I read that and
uh that was good that you did that not
everybody did best
well if they reach out to you on jabber
they must be legit say what if they
reach out to you on jabber they must
feel I feel like all of this happens
like that's why I never got anything
it's always
it's always funny to me when I see
stories where
um it's like somebody said this on like
Pace bin and was like okay I got that
like the company statement may not be
the most credible source of information
but why is that less credible than what
people are saying actually on these
forums well so so to me like a much more
common case for me is a security Reacher
researcher who's gone a little bit too
far maybe
um and gotten into some stuff saw some
bad things but shouldn't have been there
in the first place and so they're trying
to launder legitimate information about
avone or exposure through me and then
I'm you know often willing to play ball
along
um you know depending and sometimes I
know those researchers names and protect
them and sometimes I don't even know who
they are I just have to verify the
information somewhere else
uh what's the standard for you for
reporting on like the contents of emails
or data or information that
um that you receive through like a a
league or an attack of some kind like
um you know there's a lot of
conversation I think between security
practitioners and
um journalists unfortunately on Twitter
where it's not productive
um but you know just how do you decide
like
um because some of this information is
sensitive and some of it ends up being
personal some of it ends up being
identifiable for specific individuals
how do you decide like the contents
um that you will or won't publish
um I think part of it comes down to
newsworthiness and a lot of it like the
sensitive information that you're
talking about I I really don't find that
as newsworthy
um I think if the person involved in it
like wants this information like out
there then that's a little bit different
like sometimes when I report on a
warrant or something like that I will
like reach out to the person involved in
the warrant
um and if they're saying no like I want
like this out I want people to know that
I've been sent a warrant by you know
they didn't get Google didn't send them
the war but like you know they sent the
one to Google and then Google sends them
the alert
um then I will like pop if they want the
information out there and I I think it's
important to show like this is a real
person that this is affecting
um then yeah I I think part of it is
like consent and then the other part is
like very much newsworthiness and I
think personal information a lot of
times is just not doesn't rise to that
level for me
I feel like I already answered it you
know sliding sliding scale you know
you're weighing public benefit
um versus you know who what's the
probable motive who's the probable actor
and how much are you helping them by
doing this but there's almost no reason
to publish to publish anybody's private
information uh unless you know unless
you know it's a U.S senator like trying
to do business you know with the foreign
government or something yeah well you
remember uh Joe you were the one that
mentioned in our in our conversation
says we're preparing for this the the
possibility that like somebody may be
trying to get you to publish something
as a way to Blackmail someone or another
company and so I think being astute and
sensitive to what is this person's
motive
um I mean I'm in a position of luxury in
many ways and one of them is I am you
know I'm not paid per click and I'm not
desperate for traffic and so if I don't
want to help somebody out I don't I
don't have to and I think they're you
know there are other you know more
desperate you know Publications and
journalists who really need in order to
feed their families need to get some of
that stuff out there
um and I'm glad I don't have to do that
well and I was thinking about how like
one thing that's interesting is we all
sometimes end up like security beat
reporters sometimes end up playing like
a sort of gatekeeper role within The
Newsroom because if the leaked
information is coming through us or
coming to us like the the stories that
are on our beat might be not about the
information itself or what it contains
but about uh what happened like what's
the incident or who's the actor or
what's you know what's the situation
that's like what's relevant to our beat
but if there's something in the material
that's like potentially newsworthy on a
different beat I mean I completely agree
like personal information of sort of
like private citizens without public
significance like that should never be
reported on there's no reason but you
know if there's something that's
potentially gonna affect or sort of be
interesting to colleagues on another
beat or something like that I think
that's where some of our expertise needs
to come in of like you're saying
attempting to kind of apply a sliding
scale because we all have just kind of
thought about this stuff a bit more than
people on other beats and just trying to
I don't know I feel some amount of
responsibility to like help triage that
rather than being like I don't know
someone sent me this weird thing I'm
only covering this part you do whatever
you know and like thinking about uh what
you're saying Melanie about the the
potential motivations of how this came
to be so I was just gonna say hunter
Biden's laptop is a really interesting
case study because there you have insane
competitive media pressure and you know
you're always going to be accused of
everything by all sides uh you're
suppressing the story or whatever but it
was it was hinky the way it came to
light and what we eventually did at the
Washington Post months later is we had
some top Security Experts verify part of
the stuff as having been legit email
but most of the contents laptop they
could not verify and so we didn't get
into it we didn't report it I think it's
also just like a matter of discretion
too so around the time of uh you know
Elon dumpster fire
um there were a lot of people were
reporting on the the attorneys like
message on slack like saying hey you
know if you want to talk to a
whistleblower here's like the contact
information I'm pretty sure I hadn't
seen any Outlet like publish that
attorney is like name but like people
who who did report on it I I mean I had
seen the name but like I also made the
conscious decision like well that's not
really relevant to the article like the
point of it is that people at Twitter
are concerned
um so yeah I mean I'm glad that every
other reporter had reached the same
conclusion
yeah that actually reminds me of
something that I think is important for
us to know is that you're all
um
uh like print journalists
um or like Words journals text well text
text words yeah typed words
um whereas you know particularly you
know and I'll stick to the United States
so I don't end up sticking my foot in my
mouth but the the media landscape in the
United States
um varies depending on the medium that
we're talking about so print journalists
in general tend to be less politically
polarizing on on those types of stories
compared to say like our broadcast media
where there are certain Outlets that
really are specifically leaning
um intentionally
um on both sides
um and so you know it's it's for me it's
always interesting to see how different
types of outlets cover the same story
um and it just at least in my experience
the the print journalists tend to be
less political and less polarizing in
the way that um that they report it and
so I just wanted to to note that for the
folks here
um because this level-headedness that
you're hearing right now does not exist
in all newsrooms
and so I want to ask
um whether or not you think there's
something that those of us in this room
may not know
um about you know cyber crime journalism
um I actually think that covering cyber
crime is not all that different from
covering like just crime in general so I
before I I was even like a tech reporter
I covered the NYPD pretty extensively
and a lot of those skills like really
translated over to covering like cyber
crime a lot of it was like understanding
how to read court documents and um you
know police statements and things like
that and that really helped out with a
lot of the doj like pressures that they
that they do when they do like these
like big busts
um because they usually release like
their affidavit along with it and it's
like I feel like I've developed like
some pretty good skills of just like
reading through and through them like
very quickly and understanding what like
the key parts were so if you if you
understand how to do crime reporting I
think it translates very easily into
like cyber crime reporting I mean I'm
calling it cyber crime because I think
there's people in the back playing a
drinking game
um but
but yeah I think that's a really good
point
yeah I'm trying to think what
what like might be surprising about it
um
I don't know maybe just the thing we've
been talking about that there are so
many stakeholders and sort of into sorry
I hate that word like stakeholders but
you know that there's there's so many I
think you mean cyber stakeholders
okay drink
that you know there's so many there's
just so many sort of uh interests
involved in these situations I I guess I
I hadn't really thought about it but it
is sort of a specific reporting uh
challenge or just sort of sub-discipline
to like manage because you're trying to
it's like victims or like often trying
to cover up or obfuscate what happened
especially if they feel like the way
that and there's this sort of victim
shaming that is really problematic but
sometimes it's like well why was that
organization like so poorly protected or
why was that government age why hadn't
that government agency implemented like
the uh cyber security improvements that
were mandated 10 years ago that they
wrote right you know that they wrote
exactly so you know it's like there is
this very complicated interplay
um to try to uh get to just a story that
is straightforward and digestible and in
plain language and and one other thing I
was going to say when I called it words
journalism and everyone laughed because
like everything's words like makes sense
I get that but I I call it that because
it's like the different mediums have a
different amount of like composition
time like you know uh like news that is
like uh Network news that's like a
conversation or something people are
like speaking extemporaneously in real
time it's different from the medium
being that people are going to read or
like you know hear the words that you
composed like that it's they're just
different mediums and uh you put
together stories in different ways you
know depending
um and there there is like an
intentionality and uh it's there's a
friction to composing words that then
people are gonna you know read or hear
back
that can be helpful for thoughtfulness
on these things can you imagine if every
white paper had to have like a video
component with it as well yeah they've
already done branding you know this is
Heartbleed I guess that was the first
one it's not a real phone unless it has
a logo right so um I you know I think
security is an incredibly important
thing I've been covering security for 23
years now
um and I'm going to keep on covering it
um and I think of cybercrime as a subset
of that uh the reason I think it's
fascinating is that it's
interdisciplinary it's like a criminal
justice story and a geopolitical story
and a market failure story and a market
capture story there's lots of different
things going on that you don't get to by
writing most tech stuff
um security is really at the heart of it
but you're going to get more readers
when there's an you know Somebody's
knocking over a hospital than you do
when you talk about you know bad patch
management practices
um so I I think I think it's useful in
in that way but it's um you know I don't
care about a specific crime you know I
care about why uh why we haven't really
done very much about ransomware like why
is why are we as a government as a
society unable to get our act together
and beat this and so crime is a way to
talk about those things to me and I want
to build on that a bit Joe and ask what
is the difference I mean I mean I know a
lot of reporters who once they have an
idea for a story they then have to go
pitch an editor right so each individual
reporter may not actually get to choose
exactly which story or which angle they
go with and so I'm curious from your
perspective what is the process for you
know choosing to focus on something you
know that's more systemic like that of
why have we not figured out ransomware
um versus
um you know like covering like you know
those spot crimes like you said like is
there a different process for the
journalist and how you formulate that
story and how you get buy-in
um you know from the editorial folks
um I think we're expected to do both uh
like you are expected to do like this
spot news coverage like day-to-day
things but I think when you're when
you're steeped in all of this like all
the time you do start to notice patterns
you do start to notice Trends and then
that's kind of when I bring it up with
my editor of you know I I keep hearing
this I keep hearing about it let's like
dig deeper into this and give it more of
a focus
um like like as you said like with
ransomware for example yeah we were
writing about these like spot ransomware
attacks obviously like I don't think
wannacry was a a spot news kind of story
but
um then it became you know uh the city
of like Atlanta has been hit by it and
then some other City gets it and then
you notice oh a lot of these like cities
are being targeted now and what are they
doing about it they all have like
different responses and things like that
and then I think all of those questions
just naturally like coalesce into like
its own story
um and my editors have always been
pretty receptive of that so it has not
been an uphill battle for me to get them
on board with these kinds of stories
I'm curious what you think I'm just like
watching this panel too so
um
it's it's changed depending on where
where I where is working at the time so
the post fortunately has like a high bar
you know they care about the most
impactful biggest thing so Colonial
pipeline you're going to write wannacry
you're going to write and then maybe
you'll come back with an explainer
analysis or something in a little bit or
maybe you'll get a cool investigative
piece down the road but you know the
breach of the day is is not their thing
which is great and I don't want to write
the breach of the day and I'll read all
the cool like vone research but it's
unless I see it an important what I
think is an important pattern and
something that's really novel you know
and has wider impact I'm not going to do
that so
there are many stories from the before
times when nobody was covering this and
editors didn't understand it where it
was really Bleak and like the one that
comes to my mind is when I was working
for the financial times which is you
know on August publication but very top
down and in a really bad time zone for
me and I got woken up as I often did at
like 5 30 or 6 in the morning by some
guy in London saying look you know the
editor-in-chief you know
hackers have broken into the CIA and you
know we want it on page you know you
know theater in Chief wants it on page
one in in two hours and you know I'm
just you know I'm out of a cold sleep
and so it takes me five minutes to find
out it's a DDOS on their public facing
website and you know anybody could do
that
um and then they're like you know and I
tried to explain it and they got mad at
me you know like you're I'm
contradicting 90 minutes Steve yeah I'm
contradictoring the the editor-in-chief
and I'm like trying to get out of work
and so like there I had this desperate
struggle to come up with some story that
is that is true and you know is is
interesting enough to get them off my
backs and keep this off of page one
um and it's it was a frustrating process
and I think as a whole the journalism on
the stuff has gotten so much better than
it used to be
yeah the one thing I would add is like
that maybe also ties into things people
don't know or something I but a lot of
people probably know this in this room
it's just like that you know the the
main thing we can contend with is like
the difference between a topic and a
story you know you can't just like do a
report on a topic so even if you're like
okay this I have you know seen this uh
pattern in ransomware stuff and I sort
of have this thesis about it like it
needs to be reported and it needs to be
timely or have sort of a new element in
some way so wired is also very
supportive about kind of doing both
types of stories like the news coverage
and the more steps back news analysis uh
type thing but that is just an important
um like Baseline quality issue with
journalism you know when you're when
you're pitching is like it can't just be
because something is like abstractly
interesting it needs to be grounded
awesome
um well I could continue this with the
three review all day long thank you so
much uh for participating and sharing
your expertise with us today
um can we give a round of applause to
our panelists