foreign
hi everyone
um today I'll be talking about
technology abuse clinics which are
places where survivors of intimate
partner violence can come to receive
help when they are being harmed by
technology and in this talk I'll also be
introducing a toolkit for people who
might be interested in starting a clinic
like the ones that I'm going to be
talking about today
but before I talk about the clinics I
wanted to give some context and
background on intimate partner violence
and what it is as a problem
in the United States intimate partner
violence or ipv is considered a public
health problem with the CDC estimating
that one in four women and one in ten
men experience severe violence from an
intimate partner in their lifetimes
as often happens it is even more
pronounced in communities that are
already marginalized or already
vulnerable with over half of indigenous
black and bisexual women reporting that
they experience severe intimate partner
violence as well as over half of trans
and non-binary people
so what is intimate partner violence and
how do we Define it
it turns out that this is a little bit
more complicated a little bit less
straightforward and a lot more political
than you might think it is
and to explain what I mean by that I
wanted to take everyone on a detour
through how one United States Federal
agency has changed its definition
over the past five years so this is a
federal agency that's job is to respond
to intimate partner violence and five
years ago it would have to find an
intimate partner violence as a pattern
of abusive Behavior used by one partner
to maintain power and control over
another using means that can be physical
and sexual but also emotional economic
or psychological
and this is what experts call coercive
control it's a definition that Advocates
and experts stand behind because it
understands ipv as not just a single
event or an isolated incident but a
whole complex set of behaviors that are
underpinned by the threat of violence
and this is really important for
survivors because it means that we can
understand forms of abuse and coercion
that aren't just physical or sexual
and we can also respond to it and help
them holistically outside of those
moments
but a year later this definition would
have appeared if you went to the same
website and why this change happened
really had more to do with who happened
to be in office it happened to do more
with who's in charge of this Federal
agency and you can make your own
assumptions about who that was or why it
happened but ultimately what the change
was was that it defined ipv as felony or
misdemeanor crimes of violence
and this definition gets wrong what all
of the things that the previous
definition got right it is defining it
as crimes as an incident or an event and
it's in doing so it's stripping away all
of the context and narrative that comes
behind that
what that means is that if someone is
experiencing forms of coercion like
their partner is monitoring them 24 7
tracking their location without their
knowledge preventing them from talking
to their friends or family or even
draining their shared bank accounts none
of that would be considered part of a
pattern of domestic abuse or intimate
partner violence
that wasn't the end of this change
though because
um now at as of the time of writing of
this talk if you go back to the same
Federal agency you'll find a new
definition and it's a lot closer to the
first one which was a lot better in my
opinion but one big change that happened
was that it now recognized that coercive
control can be technological
and that was a big win for people who
were working in advocacy for survivors
for anyone who studied technology abuse
because ever since caller ID and GPS
became part of our Lives we've known
that digital Technologies can be used by
abusers to harm or track their victims
and that's only become more complicated
and more prevalent as technology has
so why am I telling you all of this why
not just start with that definition that
was pretty good and went straight to
technology
and the reason why I wanted to talk
about this is because definitions can
change over time yes but they don't
always change for the better and they
have real consequences for survivors
because how we Define something tells us
how we understand it and how we
understand it changes how we respond to
it
and that means that since these
definitions have outsized impacts on
survivors that they should be based in
their lived experiences and good
Evolutions change in the definitions
reflect changes in their lived
experiences in the reality that they
live in and bad definitions ignore those
narratives or don't seek them out
and I think that this is the real value
of Technology abuse clinics and what's
so powerful for about them
technology abuse clinics in one sense
they create places where survivors can
share their narratives of Technology
abuse and not with just anyone but with
people who have the power or a best
positioned to actually change those
platforms for better long-term change or
help create public policy
and we're not just doing it in a way
where we helicopter in and then leave or
just interview them and and walk away we
can actually offer them short-term help
with the problems that they're currently
facing while we learn those narratives
and I think that this makes us better
Engineers better designers better
privacy and Security Experts when we can
do this
so what kind of help do we actually give
to clients who come into the technology
abuse clinics that we run
um I currently run one in New York City
called The Clinic to end Tech abuse and
I've been doing this for a couple years
I've worked with
um over 100 survivors I can say that
most of the help that we give is not
very sophisticated
it's often things that are considered
relatively mundane like reviewing
account settings or changing passwords
looking at login histories it's a lot
less of the spyware that people tend to
imagine
and when I tell people this
I often hear the same question
and that question is
is helping people reset their passwords
really the best use of your time
and I think that when people ask me this
they mean well what they mean is why
don't you have someone else do this with
them and they can tell you about it
later or or give you a report of what
happened and then you as someone with an
advanced degree in computer science or
someone with specialized skills you can
go change the platforms and make this
bigger impact change
and my answer to this question is always
yes
um I do think that this is the best use
of my time and I think that it makes me
a better engineer and a better designer
for doing it
um
much like trying to understand intimate
partner violence as an isolated incident
or a single event we can't capture
technology abuse with a series of
reported incidents or help tickets and
we would make the same mistake if we did
because we need to be able to understand
what is happening within its larger
narrative
one example of this is this snippet of
an interview with a Survivor who said
I wrote down things that were happening
altercations and I had evidence
he told me that he needed to update the
device
he took the phone forced the password
out of me and he deleted my journal
what is striking to me about this is
that if you just viewed this as a
technical event it's nothing remarkable
it's someone's phone got taken from them
and some information got deleted
um if you just look at it at the actions
that we would take with them it's also
not that interesting we are really just
helping someone secure their device
better or trying to look for a backup
but when you hear the whole story we can
start to ask more interesting questions
like how can we as people who design
technology platforms
help survivors navigate the twin needs
that they have to both gather the
evidence that they need to pursue legal
protections while still keeping
themselves safe from the people who are
harming them
and doing this we can also start to do
things like build threat models for
intimate partner violence like we can
see coercive access as part of the
threat model that might not happen in
other situations we can also identify
other needs like preserving evidence
and
ultimately I think that understanding
this narrative the stakes the
motivations that are at play they help
us think about tech platforms as
something that interacts with people
with legal systems and with complicated
relational Dynamics
So to that end there's been some
research that has done a systematic
analysis of how technology abuse happens
and has come up with a taxonomy of what
that looks like
but in the spirit of honoring narratives
I wanted to just talk about what I have
seen in the past couple years working
with clients
I have worked with clients who came to
me
um saying that they had taken their car
to a mechanic and tried had it basically
searched all over torn the car apart
because they got an alert that there was
an air tag following them but they were
never able to find it
I've worked with clients who wanted to
exit a phone contract that was owned by
their abuser but they were too afraid to
do that because the first time that they
called the phone company the phone
company's three-way dialed in the abuser
without telling them
just as they had um finally left this
person
I've also spoken with multiple clients
who came to us asking if we could help
them find a single shred of evidence a
text message a photograph a call log
that showed that they had ever
electronically communicated with someone
that they had been in a relationship
with for over a decade and we were
unable to find anything because the
amount of coercive control of their
abuser had over their technology was so
complete that they were able to remove
all of it
one client that I worked with was still
living with her abuser and she told us
that her abuser was using Bluetooth
devices to harass her while they he was
at work so during the summer in New York
he would turn on and off the air
conditioning turn on and off the
internet turn on and off the lights when
she entered and exited a room just to
let her know that he could see that that
was happening
I've also spoken with multiple clients
who had lost the accounts that they
needed for public housing applications
for health care to run their personal
businesses
and I wanted to go through all of these
stories because I wanted everyone to
understand something
there are real Stakes here for people
and those Stakes include physical danger
that can mean death when it comes to
intimate partner violence
it can also be financially and
economically devastating you can lose
your job because of this harassment you
can lose your housing you can lose your
entire identity financially
but people tend to underestimate the
psychological and emotional Devastation
that technology abuse can happen and
this is something that I hear time and
time again when I'm working with clients
is that technology is so ubiquitous and
sometimes so unexpected in the places
you find it that they say that it feels
like it's coming from everywhere
and because technology is capable of
giving us this digital record that looks
so factual and real but is also so easy
to manipulate it starts to cause people
to question their own sanity
and these are people who are
experiencing a real attack in real
danger it's not just something that is
it's not like they are um
it's not like they don't have a reason
to fare for their own safety or to fair
that these things are happening because
they have proof that it actually is they
know that it is there is someone who's
actually out to get them
the good news is that working with
survivors and Clinics we've been able to
do entry and exit interviews and what
we've found is that these are actually
really positive corrective experiences
for the clients that we see and that we
work with
so a lot of the clients that we work
with report saying that they now have a
better understanding of how technology
can be used to harm them how they can
keep themselves safe
um and I would say that our biggest
problem as a technology abuse Clinic is
that we can't meet the demand for
everyone who wants our services
in fact these are the only three
technology abuse clinics that I know of
that exists and we can barely meet the
demand in our local communities let
alone the entire country or the world
and so I would say that what we need
more than anything is a network of
Technology abuse clinics that can help
people in their local communities but
that can work together to share
resources share experiences advocate for
Public Policy together
and doing that is something that I think
is really hard for one reason which is
that technology abuse clinics are hard
to run and I do know this from
experience and they are also really a
hard or daunting to figure out how to
get them started or off the ground and
so this was why we created this
technology abuse Clinic toolkit
now what is actually in this toolkit is
a lot of practical advice Collective
advice from what we have learned over
the past few years at our existing
clinics
um and that goes through a lot of
um all of the moving parts that we work
with on a day-to-day basis from
recruiting and training staff to how to
actually run a session with clients
um
but I think what's more interesting is
what's not in this toolkit which is the
best or the only way to run a technology
abuse Clinic
intimate partner violence isn't the only
relational Dynamic that can make people
vulnerable and so other clinics can
explore those Dynamics there's also a
lot of other possible service models and
funding structures that we haven't tried
or um
or even thought of and so I think that
being able to have Innovation is really
important
in fact I would say that almost every
aspect of the technology abuse clinics
is Up For Debate you're welcome to try
and innovate on every single on pretty
much every single way that we operate
which kind of begs the question of what
makes something actually a technology
abuse Clinic what is it about them that
actually lets us get these stories in
this exchange with people while
providing help in a way that's safe for
both them and for us
and what I've landed on is that there's
three features that really make this
that make a technology abuse Clinic what
it is and that is that they are trauma
informed and community-based services
and that they're delivered in a clinical
setting
and I wanted to run through what each of
those pieces mean
um briefly
and the first being trauma-informed care
so people who are in vulnerable
situations they have often experienced
events that might be that might be
traumatic and we want to create a place
where they can get care from us in a way
that is safe and respectful of what they
have experienced
um the main thing of what that means is
to work with Advocates and experts who
already do this work to work with social
workers to work with all of the people
who are already on the front lines with
vulnerable populations and meet them
where they are
um it takes training to really
understand how to do this properly and
nothing can replace
um hiring someone to train you in this
it also means from a technical expected
perspective that we want to you know
recognize the client's individual
situation so there's a risk of violence
from an abuser and what we want to do is
be able to acknowledge when any change
that we make might alert the abuser send
them a notification and work with them
to maintain their safety we want to
educate them and meet them where they're
at to not just tell them to use signal
if it's going to if that's not going to
meaningfully enhance their protection
from their abuser
and really just let clients Drive the
sessions of what they're trying to
accomplish and help them along the way
the second thing is that they are
Community Based and this is also
something that ties in with being
trauma-informed because being Community
Based or embedded in a community means
that you can work with the local
agencies that are already doing this
work there
it's also really important because it
helps us understand political and
cultural geographies that are specific
to and shape the ways that people might
experience Tech abuse
so in New York City where people rely on
public transit we might not have the
best idea of how people track vehicles
in ipv which would be more obvious
somewhere where people use cars uh you
need to understand in a local community
what technology people use how they use
it what help is available to them how
they travel to get to that help what
languages they have if there are
specific laws that protect them and
whether there are certain communities
who have a bad relationship with law
enforcement
and that's something that you can only
really understand by living in and
working with that population
and then the last bit is that it is a
clinical setting and so this is very
similar to things like legal clinics
where legal experts can work with
vulnerable populations who are under
resourced and give them expert legal
advice pro bono and this means that
survivors gain access to experts which
is really helpful because there's a lot
of misinformation and lies out there and
just being able to clear that up with
them is something that is helpful in and
of itself
it also means that it can create a place
where experts can do this for medium to
low commitment most of our volunteers do
have full-time jobs and we ask them to
commit about 10 to 15 hours a month
working with survivors
um which means that this is something
that people can do in tandem with their
job with their existing jobs working on
platforms and all of the other things
that people think of when they think of
making broad systemic changes
so on that note
um I was just wanted to end by repeating
what I've been trying to say which is
that clinics help us really understand
the narratives of Technology abuse in a
way that helps us shape public policy
and build better technology platforms
and if this is something that you think
that is you are interested in and that
you might want to learn more about
starting we desperately need people to
do that
um and I wanted to leave everyone with a
couple of resource links one of them is
that you can find the toolkit at the
cedo website and also if you are someone
that you know is experiencing intimate
partner violence then there are a lot of
resources available to talk about safety
and possible resources at the
hotline.org
thanks
[Applause]