foreign
Defender metamorphizing security
decision making by incorporating
opportunity cost
cyber security is a business of
decisions about balancing costs that
influence defensive outcomes where do we
focus resources what threats pose the
most critical impact what mitigations
must be deployed before another
in cyber security decision making today
we may determine the value of a
particular choice but we often ignore
what might have been
when we expend resources on X we
inherently can't spend those same
resources on why
so we are very hungry Defenders
hopefully you all know The Very Hungry
Caterpillar we're like that caterpillar
we want to spend our you know money time
and cognitive effort our attention on
outmaneuvering attackers but alas the
world only offers us finite scarce
resources
and in this reality we miss
opportunities and better outcomes when
we fail to consider alternative options
when making decisions
this is the very definition of
opportunity cost the Lost of potential
gain from other Alternatives when one
alternative is chosen the money spent on
data backups can't also be used for
endpoint detection to defend against
duransomware other Alternatives by
necessity are not pursued
this leads us to the critical question
we'll be exploring here today how can we
apply opportunity cost considering what
might have been demetomorphize our
defensive strategy and improve our
security outcomes
to start will introduce the concept of
opportunity cost then we'll explore the
spectrum of costs because it's not just
about money and finally we'll explore
how this applies to a particular problem
area application security
so let's start our delving into this
with opportunity cost
first coined by Frederick Von viser
opportunity costs is the loss of
potential gain from other Alternatives
when one alternative is chosen in cyber
security decision making today we often
fail to consider those alternatives
time pressure tunnel vision and
information biased a rail critical
thinking during crisis and our
exploration of alternative suffers
humans rarely think about opportunity
costs even the midst of calm collected
situations which I think for the most
part security is not one of those
the opportunity cost is actually a
problem or is a concept that applies
across problem domains and even everyday
life
so I think we should extract all those
lessons learned from these other domains
to improve cyber security
imagine if opportunity cost was
considered in every cyber security
decision after all real life rarely
matches you know the hot takes on
Twitter and the infosec folk wisdom and
cyber security theory in textbooks to
consider a few common decisions
should we buy a commercial solution or
should we expend time and effort on
building our own
do we need expensive software at all or
should that money be invested in
preparation on things like chaos
engineering and automated recovery
should we create new procedures or
should we ensure that the existing ones
are standardized and well documented so
teams can better self-serve
even consider a simple example if
resources are spent defending against
supply chain attacks which are so hot
right now but it's social engineering
that actually results in the most impact
to the business and the most frequent
losses than the business suffers
allocating resources to security can
even be detrimental to the bottom line
which imposes quite the cost
incorporating opportunity costs and
cyber security decision making helps us
minimize the impact of external threats
maximize company productivity and in
general helps us more optimally achieve
our goals
the cost of our choices that were not
just money and they're not just first
order effects how do these variegated
costs manifest in practice how do we
calculate the expected outcome of a
choice such questions are relevant to
nearly every decision cyber security or
otherwise
for instance what's the value of
spending two hours on reading a new book
is that more or less than the value you
would get from practicing the violin for
two hours or whatever your hobby of
choice is
these actually aren't impossible
questions to answer even if they feel a
little unnatural to us we can actually
answer these questions even if we don't
have precise absolute dollar values for
these activities
we can metamorphose our our decision
making for the better by simply
prompting ourselves to think about
Alternatives at all to make those
alternative salients we need to think
about the spectrum of costs that are
present in our cyber security decisions
this brings us to the costs and effects
in infosec
so the bigger picture question is how do
we elucidate the bigger picture of the
decision
mapping out the potential costs and
effects of security Investments
including of not implementing those
Investments can elucidate this bigger
picture of the decision at hand
no one's reading this slide right now
please don't try uh it's impossible this
is very much a leave behind for for the
world uh covering covering the numerous
costs and effects and security but
mostly what we see today is on the left
side in costs and the red but if we
consider opportunity costs perhaps we
can start producing more of the positive
effects on the right as well
so what are some of these first there
are tangible costs the ones with direct
monetary expenditure I think wages
Hardware overhead Outsourcing and so
forth
they're also intangible costs like
employees investing time and security
interventions the cognitive overhead of
task squishing interruptions to flow
that you know precious resource for
developers and even increased conflicts
at the organization level they can also
experience delayed time to Market due to
security interventions like slower
software release cycles and that can
erode their competitive advantage
then from a societal perspective
thinking really big when we thrust
security responsibilities onto consumers
we increase their anxiety
and on the effects side productivity
effects are numerous I recommend reading
Dr forsgren's space of developer
productivity which was an acmq for more
here but highly relevant ones for our
discussion today at the employee level
are usually perception of work efficacy
reduced burnout improved collaboration
and reduced toil and so much more
organization productivity effects can
include product quality gains it can
include faster time to Market incident
reduction speed of change Integrations
and also a lot more
then there are tangible benefits those
are also monetary like Revenue growth
customer renewals more software releases
profitability and uptime
despite being so tangible uh security
teams often don't consider the erosion
of these as part of the cost when
they're thinking about the return of
their security Investments
they're also intangible benefits like
emotional experiences which we'll talk
about in a bit like reducing anxiety we
also want employees who are energized
not drained and who are dedicated not
cynical organizations also care a lot
about competitive advantage and things
like brand perception
then finally there are tangible savings
and that helps with profitability like
reduced head count
reduced Tech cost savings things like
lower compliance fines
but how often do we think about how to
reduce what we spend on security and
find Opportunities to consolidate across
security and software engineering
infrastructure engineering or site
reliability engineering
how do we start understanding the
outcomes of a security decision like
purchasing a solution through this lens
of costs and effects can be especially
helpful to consider something we call
the null Baseline especially with an eye
to the benefits on that right side of
the graphic the null Baseline in a
nutshell is basically what do you gain
by not implementing a security solution
would developers be more productive
would employees be less stressed
it's important to stay honest about what
is lost when we Implement security which
can also elucidate a broader set of
options that might still uphold benefits
like software velocity that would
otherwise remain unexplored when we make
a decision
we cannot just think about ourselves as
stakeholders
this is precisely why negative
externalities are relevant in cyber
security decision making we are very
hungry Defenders like these little
caterpillars gobbling up leaves if
you've ever had a garden you know they
can be a total Scourge we may devour the
leaves of productivity for our
organizations in the pursuit of
protection and we might cause more harm
than good
what are externalities they are the
costs and benefits imposed on other
entities by a choice in cyber security
decision making as elsewhere the
monetary costs and monetary benefits of
a particular choice are often considered
in isolation rather than considering its
externalities
a classic example of a negative
externality is pollution a firm can
perform cost-benefit analysis to
consider the cost incurred by producing
a widget they can think about the
benefits that they get from selling the
widget but it won't consider the costs
imposed on the local community by
lowering the quality of drinking water
nor on the costs imposed to society by
increased carbon emissions
in cyber security the implementation of
say an application security tool may
have a positive return for the security
team
but it might result in a negative
externality of slower or fewer software
releases which impacts the organization
the organization's teams and even its
customers
we should always consider what costs we
are imposing elsewhere especially in the
realm of those intangible costs like
burnout conflict disruption of flow
productivity loss and so forth
some domains like healthcare actually
refer to the true cost of a choice as
the shadow price the shadow price
reflects the prices of goods services
and resources that are proportional to
the true opportunity cost for the
economy taking account of any
externalities
similar to healthcare cyber security is
complex in its network of stakeholders
the benefits and costs from the
perspective of a security team the
organization the teams within it the
organization's users and customers and
the society around them all those
perspectives are likely to be quite
different so benefits for one
stakeholder May beget a cost for another
a worthy question to bring back to your
work or research is what is the shadow
price of each security mitigation in
your organization
when we're thinking about costs and
Shadow prices we need to think Beyond
money
the root cost is often narrowly
considered in terms of monetary cost or
monetary value
certainly one important aspect when
we're making decisions because Financial
Resources spent on one opportunity means
that those resources can't be spent now
or later on something else that money is
spent but what else must we consider
time is a very common consideration and
opportunity cost but is often neglected
in practice
and security Investments can be
especially profligate with time
for instance time is required to answer
help desk calls it also takes time to
develop new security policies and it
definitely takes developers a lot of
time to fix those you know thousand list
of critical or super urgent
vulnerabilities right
cognition is another resource we have to
consider so cognitive resources such as
attention affect and productivity are
relevant in any domains when humans
expend cognitive effort to solve some
sort of problem
emotion is actually another resource we
should consider we often Overlook it so
emotional experience like anxiety
frustration and confusion is often
overlooked as a cost when we're
evaluating options despite its
well-documented salience during human
decision making
in cyber security studies actually show
that the stress of time pressure can
exacerbate users frustrations with the
very poor usability of a security tool
which makes them more likely to bypass
that tool or the security requirement
consider the example of securing the
software supply chain everybody's
favorite Boogeyman right now so business
is thinking about moving from an
Internet connected development
environment to a standalone disconnected
development environment to Shield it
from external threats
what are the costs of moving to this
disconnected development environment the
example might seem ridiculous it has
been proposed officially within the past
year so there are direct costs to this
change such as perhaps the need for new
hardware or increased I.T support but
even more substantial are the costs to
productivity and employee satisfaction
developers can't smoothly query the
internet you know copy and paste from
stack Overflow because that's what
developers do new Time Investments will
be required because of the network
disconnect and productivity will go down
as a result
so many variables influence cost and the
principle of opportunity costs invites
organizations to consider how else costs
might be used and which option maximizes
their success
think about opportunity cost in terms of
the laws of thermodynamics can actually
be an Illuminating analogy
so it's well understood that energy
within a system including a system made
up of other systems can't be created or
destroyed however energy with assist
within a system can be interchangeable
like a human hand winding expanding
energy to wind a clock which transfers
energy into its spring and then it
catalyzes the motion
Security Programs are a component of
organizations and they can expend energy
or absorb it
for instance a requirement for
organizational users to be vigilant to
phishing threats requires them to expend
energy on solving a security program
which the security team can absorb
because these user efforts allow the
security team to expend energy elsewhere
requiring software Engineers to triage
bugs discovered by vulnerability
scanners is another example developers
expend energy combing through the
findings and fixing them and the
security team can absorb that energy
thinking of where energy is expended and
absorbed and by whom can help excavate
opportunity costs in any sort of cyber
security decision
this brings us to our case study in
application security starting with the
challenge of the focal point
an opportunity cost framing exposes
situations when the problem definition
is overly prescriptive which dismisses
Alternatives that might be superior in
solving the problem this zoomed in
perspective that I'm describing is
called the focal point
for instance what static application
security tool is best SAS tool that but
gets a very narrow focal point because
it only prescribes SAS tools it's worth
asking why we want sast at all
the answer likely leads to the question
okay how can we minimize the number of
security bugs developers introduce into
code this is a little better it's less
tool specific and it might introduce the
focal option of say security awareness
training for developers nevertheless it
is still anchored to a relatively narrow
focal point we can ask why do we want to
minimize the number of bugs that
developers introduce into code
the answer is likely because we don't
want them to be exploited in production
and cause problems
with this better understanding of why we
can form an even better question which
is how do we minimize the impact of
security bugs in code running in
production this question allows a much
more expansive list of potential
opportunities and potential Solutions
which helps us consider a variety of
Alternatives from a more zoomed out
focal point
this allows us to allocate our finite
pool of resources to a variety of
alternatives
for instance if we brainstorm with other
teams we can maybe think of a broader
list potential Solutions and best
prioritize how we allocate our Capital
this broader list could include SAS
tools and developer training but also
ephemeral or immutable infrastructure or
standardizing libraries and patterns so
developers are less likely to make
mistakes it could include architecting
the system with strong isolation
properties talked about that on Tuesday
or you could run security chaos
experiments to uncover how the system
behaves when it encounters some sort of
adverse condition like an attacker
exploiting a bug
the point is we can allocate our finite
pool of resources to one alternative or
another we invest in standardized
libraries and patterns then we can't
invest those same exact resources in
those SAS tools perhaps we solve the
problem even better this way
the focal point is about the true
outcome we seek in our decision problem
so it's not about generalized or
specialized tools it's very much that we
need to understand the real Target
benefit digging into a few layers of why
if we want to investigate what benefits
we are giving up by doing X instead of Y
to approximate opportunity cost
unfortunately our default tendency as
humans is to remain very zoomed in on a
problem so for instance consumers will
consider which Resort is best for my
vacation rather than thinking about the
true Target benefit which might be to
reduce stress or maybe generate a sense
of wonder and that would expand the
possible set of options to Beyond just a
resort for a vacation
to find the true Target benefit we have
to consider our organization's kind of
fundamental purpose
most businesses do have a defined
purpose to fulfill and their primary
organizational missions are not to
secure their endpoints or their networks
otherwise they would probably go out of
business
so through this lens any work that
doesn't directly support the
organization's fundamental purpose Bears
the opportunity cost of taking time
cognition attention budget away from
work that more directly fulfills that
purpose
so for retail Corporation wants a
resilient online store let's say for you
know their e-commerce application
they likely don't have the internal
skill set or the expertise needed that's
expertise think like databases ad
delivery ad placement and content
delivery as well
but instead they could Outsource the
problem to some sort of platform service
provider an ad Tech firm or a Content
delivery Network whose employees are
skilled at such tasks because it's part
of their organizational Mission like in
this picture the hummingbird wants
sustins from nectar but an outsourced
provider of it will do just fine
the opportunity cost of trying to
successfully create and operate that
online store is time and cognitive
effort that could have been better spent
dedicated to the retail business logic
that would deliver more value to
customers
and this is a considerable cost to pay
but it's a cost that organizations all
over the world pay every day
so let's summarize
opportunity costs can be considered in
every cyber security decision because it
is always relevant whether we are aware
of it or not
we incorporate opportunity costs we're
more likely to derive the best security
outcomes we can balance our
organization's multifaceted goals
nurturing business operations that are
resilient to attacks and other adverse
scenarios
cyber security decision makers would
really benefit from recognizing the many
types of costs Beyond just money
and we think opportunity costs can be
understood by anyone given the right
introduction and Framing and one way to
ease into the consideration of
opportunity cost is to consider that
null Baseline heuristic to consider the
option of doing nothing rather than the
choice at hand this can only elucidate
the true problem to that true Target
benefit the one that really needs
solving
through the lens of the spectrum of
costs and effects especially when
considering the option of not
implementing a security measure
incorporating opportunity costs can
become natural and accessible in our
decision making
so The Parting question for you all
today is I'm very excited to see because
there are many Brilliant Minds in here
is how can we nurture the widespread
inclusion of opportunity cost in
research and practice so we can
metamorphize our security decision
making for the better
if you enjoyed that swathi said book is
available for pre-order should be out
this spring very exciting with that
thank you very much for your time and
attention which as we discussed is
finite and precious