foreign
so two years ago I have been here at
Enigma to talk about my experience as a
Maori analyst investigating Brazilian
mower samples by that time Brazilian
more symbols were not well described in
the literature which motivated me to
claim the need for an increased number
of region specific observational studies
but this is not the only challenge that
one entering the secured field would
face while entering our field
today I present five view other aspects
to change to make our research field
stronger so come with me
every search is potentially limited or
flawed my impression however is that
this complaint is much more frequent and
bigger in the secured field maybe
because the impacts of secured flaws are
huge anyway everybody has its own
concerns about the current state of our
field
if we're here to the industry and the
practitioners we will hear complaints
about how slow paced the research
developments are about how hard is to
transition to practice the research
outcomes that you have and also how we
are failing to educate our students
if we listen to the Academia it also has
its own complaints it's also aware of
its own limitations the pioneers of the
science of security movement already
pointed out that the field has severe
limitations reporting experimental
results and making experiments
reproducible my question here is what's
the actual size of this problem
and more importantly how do we move
forward how they solve these problems
and try to find Solutions
my point here is that you should
acknowledge some problems so we can go
towards a solution so let's adapt them
to The Logical position here that our
research security research is broken
I mean I do not fully agree with that I
believe that research contributions from
the past has led us to a better world
nowadays than in the past so these
research contributions were very
important but let act as a scientist
here so let's put this hypothesis and
let's see what are its implications so
maybe you can find some ways to move
forward
my cleanser you rely upon a paper that I
published that is the challenge that
pitfalls in our research it's a paper in
which I review more than 400 papers
published in the last days in the last
20 years in the top security venues
pointing out toward the challenge and
pitfalls that we and other researchers
face while developing security research
and here I talk more about malware
because this is my background this is
the research field I work on so I feel
more comfortable to make some cleanse
about it but in fact most of the
outcomes that I represent apply to any
secure domain
and that's important to highlight here
that what I'm proposing here it's a
reflection exercise not a pointy finger
exercise even because my own research
has many of these flaws that I represent
so what I'm trying to do here is to
pointing out to what are the most common
Challenge and pitfalls that we have to
face there could be 20 as the paper but
I chose to talk about the five most
concerning ones in My Views starting
right now
so the first one is that uh first
practice to change is to stop focusing
on the same research types because there
are multiple research types right they
have engineering Solutions there are
typically the defenses that we propose
but also have offensive work and they
also have observational studies so how
are these types of work distributed
among our fields
according to our literature review we
have a prevalence of our years of these
engineering Solutions more than that we
have more engineering Solutions than any
other type of research combined
typically offensive work and
observational studies are in a limited
number in the literature so is this a
good thing
um to claim something as good or bad you
need to have a model of what we consider
the ideal which in our case is the merge
of the scientific method and Engineering
method because you know security field
is integrated and very complex
so we expect people first to observe the
phenomenon in practice to identify that
it's something undesired secured
violation on their problems
and then to propose hypothesis to handle
that it's basically the explanation of
the scientific method right
but you put this hypothesis to test we
need to develop sometimes very ingenious
very complex Solutions proof of Concepts
there are the engineering Solutions so
you have to merge these two methods and
according this to Method it was
plausible to report a size that would
have a lot of observational studies
because these are the works that are
proposing the hypothesis right so these
are informed informing the development
of future engineering Solutions
but this is not what happens in practice
right so you have much more engineering
Solutions why it happens
um at first hypothesis could be that
engineering Solutions or defensive
Solutions are intrinsically harder to be
implemented so researchers need more
attempts so they end up publishing more
papers but this hypothesis is a bit weak
another hypothesis maybe researchers are
not following this expected way of
conducting research so they are
developed more independent way of taking
project decisions they are not based on
their decision on previous observational
studies and they adapt with solutions
that do not perfectly match the
operational scenario so they have to
refine and to refactor the solutions
which also end up in more papers being
published
and what I discover is that that this is
exactly the scenario the majority of the
papers published in the literature uh
are basically ad dock decisions from the
reviewers in the sense that previous
observational studies are not used to
inform project decisions to define the
engineering Solutions parameters or to
define the populations of the
experimental settings and why it happens
well one of the hypothesis is that there
is a scarce number of observational
studies to support this engineering
solution but this creates a cycle right
so to move this field forward a first
thing is to break the cycle and to have
more observationals from the field more
observational papers and most
importantly make the information in
these papers useful to inform the
project decisions of the engineering
solutions that will develop
but this is just a first challenge there
are more challenges to come
a second challenge is to look more to
the market into the industry When
developing these Solutions
because you know sometimes we especially
in Academia Technologies sometimes lives
in a two Ideal World but the problems
happens next in the practice natural
world so you need to look more to that
when it's needed the challenge here is
of course you didn't fight when it's
needed I represent you two scenarios to
try to help this identification the
first one are the target platforms right
now most of you like 99 are carrying a
mood core system on your pockets but
less than one percent of The Works
published in the literature are covering
mood core system right now
so this creates an understanding Gap
about this type of solution and I know
that's completely acceptable to develop
single core solution as proof of
Concepts that will be transitioned to
practice as smooth core implementations
in the future but I'm talking here about
understanding gap of specific phenomena
what about moot core malware what about
distributed threats how much examples of
that investigations of these phenomenons
can you find in the literature well here
I can point you to two right
another example
of a mismatch between industry research
and academics research is the use of
signatures by antiviruses because the
antivirus industry largely relies on
signatures not only on signatures it's
important to highlight but largely rely
on signatures because they are very
effective for many tests they are
compacted to be stored faster to match
it fast to be developed although they
have some drawbacks but academics seems
to prefer to work more with other
approach typically machine learning
approach that are more flexible are
capable of detecting zero days but they
also have drawbacks like the performance
and we can see in the literature tour
this practical divide we can see that in
the recent years basically all papers
are proposing machine learn based
detections and not signature detections
so my point here is how we academics
want to cause impact in the real world
if we are not studying the solutions
that are actually used in the real world
and by that point you might be thinking
okay so the point is uh we should look
to the markets in the industry this is
the solution for everything right but
it's not the case because the problem is
complex so in some cases we should stop
and look into the industry into the
market because in some case the industry
cannot provide a better answer than
Academia sometimes relying too much in
the market might even cause a harm into
our experiments for example consider
that we are Implement an experiment
perform an experiment typical one to
detect if something is malware or not or
if something is unpacked or not we are
training a machine learning plus fire
that's the typical approach that is used
and we need to collect the positive case
like goodware data where does this
goodware data came from well in most
experiments according to our literature
to review this data came from The
Crawling of Internet repositories and
also from marketplaces what's the
rationale about that researchers are
basically trying to reproduce the real
world they are ranking these repost
towards and trying to collect the most
popular applications with the
expectation that this reflects the
applications that are actually used by
the majority of users
this is a good intention
but as they got the intention you know
the paved to the to the road to the
house paved with good intentions right
so there are also drawbacks here uh a
problem is there's no guarantee that
these repositors are free from malware
there is no guarantee that the
applications are not crucialized there
is no guarantee this applications are
not bundled with the spyware and
unwanted software in general so you
might be end up biasing your classifier
and to learn these lots of unintended
Behavior as benign
and one might say okay but the solution
for that is to rely on antivirus to
pre-scan all files to ensure that they
are clear right
well it happens that once again rely on
antivirus is complex researchers rely on
antivirus Forge a lot of desks more
specifically researchers Reliant
antivirus labels to train machine
learning models and also to perform
comparisons we are always comparison
comparing if our results of our
development tools are better or worse
than an antivirus but as you can see in
the figure antivirus labels are not
homogeneous antivirus labels in fact are
very different depending on solution to
solution so far the same sample as you
can see here different labels are
generated even though we try to use some
approach to make them homogeneous it's
problematic because the meaning of the
label is different for each solution
worse than that the antivirus labels
often do not provide very useful
information research-wise for instance
antivirus do not disclose what are they
um engines that generated that label so
it's hard to perform fair comparison how
can you compare Your solution against
antivirus label in the case that if you
are proposing a signature based
detection you are comparing Your
solution with label generated by
antivirus using machine learning engine
or on the opposite if you are proposing
a machine learning detection solution
you are comparing a result against
labels generated by antivirus that use
signature matching so you might be
understating or overstating the results
of your experiment because of that so
the solution here is clearly not to
blindly rely on antivirus not blind rely
on any software any industry solution
but to have stronger methodology to have
standards to have guidelines to perform
these experiments and academics are
supposed to be good at developing
guidelines and standards and I say
suppose because the scenario is not so
simple
once again let's talk about an
experiment we are trying to classify
something as malicious or not and we
have to define a data set size for this
experiment what's the ideal data set
size well in fact we do not know right
so you can see here there is no pattern
in the works published in the literature
to have a data set size of all size in
the literature authors trying to prove
multiple claims using different data set
size
even worse sometimes there are
contradictory results there are words
saying that one million hour samples is
enough to present a landscape of them
our scenarios Wireless others say that
one million samples is the bare minimum
number of samples should train a machine
learning classifier
once again as I presented before
researchers seem to be taking sometimes
adult decisions the only pattern that we
can see here is that the average the
median average of the data set is
growing and this is because an effect
that we call Anchor bias that is in the
absence of a guideline what it what
happens is that a previous study in that
particular field becomes a reference for
future developments it establishes an
anchor for future developments so we
start to want data sets bigger and
bigger because of that but you know
bigger is not necessary the better
because in the end you do not want a
bigger data set size we want a
representative data set size but as I
told you two years ago for the case of
Brazilian hour samples they were not
represented in the literature and many
of these words do not represent many
populations that are still vulnerable
this lack of guidelines also creates
another problem that is the
reproducibility crisis and I know by
that time every scientific field has a
reproducibility crisis to call yours I
know but I would like to talk about the
security one because it's a little bit
different
there are human factors and
technological factors so the human
factors are related to our practice so
they are subject to change
once again you are developing
experiments we want to collect now
malware samples or attack samples and
where do they come from
according to our literature to review
they came from The Crawling of internet
repositors now malicious one and also
from companies partner companies that
share their repositors but since most of
these companies are not research
entities they don't want to disclose how
they were breached about which secrets
were breached so the data sets are often
not available and even though if they
are secured companies that actually
worry about doing research they do not
want to disclose their commercial
secrets so how they collected these
samples so what happens in that is that
in most case researchers are under NADA
non-disclosure agreements so for the
majority of the works in the literature
you're recording our literature to
review the data sets are not available
so it's impossible to immediately
reproduce the experiments as they are
but even though if we have access to all
the samples you still have problems
because there are also the technological
problems related to the nature of the
problem that is if we have access to all
the samples there is no guarantee that
you're running Mr experiment in the
future you lead to the same result as in
the present because there is no
guarantee that the mower sample will not
download a different payload that
servers will be reachable or that
command and controls will not have been
sink hold so there is still not a widely
established way to perform this kind of
experiment so there's not a very widely
established and accepted manner to
reproduce malware and many other types
of experiments that require this kind of
reproduce reproducibility aspect
so considering that this is very
important and we matter about that these
are really problems that you should
solve uh how to move forward
it's very complicated but I have a few
ideas first of all for us as researchers
we should try to diversify more the
types of work that we present so
basically we should perform more
longitudinal studies more observational
studies to provide useful data we need
data from The Real World from actual
infections from the prevalence of the
affected populations so we can better
inform the development of the
engineering Solutions
and when we are wearing the Hat of
reviewers program program committees or
any other position of power we should
worry about more about developing these
guidelines this best practice this is
standards we as a community should have
a clear message what is considered
secured for us what are the best
practices in our view what do you want
to achieve with our experiments so
what's our goal in detecting some type
of attack this should be clear for us as
a community and it's not clear at the
moment
and also for the field as a whole I
think we should start stop worrying a
lot about data set size and start
worrying more about reproducibility
because in the end we do not study files
we study phenomena we're studying
effective we study people right so if
you want to solve the data set size
problem let's establish as a guideline
that the good data set is the
representative data set if you want to
solve the reproducibility problem let's
state that the solution is to study
population do not matter the files if we
study in the same population we are
observing the same phenomena so they
will be reproducible right and of course
for our venues let's be clear for the
authors for the presenters that these
types of different populations instead
is observational studies are welcome in
very nice place like here at Enigma this
is just the tip of an iceberg this
beginning of a discussion there's a lot
to be talked about but what I'd like to
do here is to foster a discussion so
I'll be open here to discuss with you
thanks a lot
[Applause]