[Music]
all right hello everybody thank you for
coming to my talk about breaking Tizen a
little bit about myself
my name is Sam Hyneman I'm a security
researcher from Israel I mostly do for
an ability research
my day job is looking for
vulnerabilities in iOS and Android
phones and my hobby is looking for
vulnerabilities basically in anything
that has Wi-Fi in it or what people now
they call IOT I just call it boxes I
like finding vulnerabilities in
different boxes you get a chance to see
a lot of different technologies so it's
fun I like doing it now before we start
talking about what Tizen is one talked
about its history now the history of
Tizen is a bit too long for a
twenty-minute stock that you can see
here by this graph so I made this graph
instead which is a bit simpler
it's on a hard for city accurate but you
can trust me it's good enough now for a
long time Samsung want to have their own
operation system and they started in
2010 with something called SLP the
Samsung Linux platform it didn't work
very well and then it started making
something called bada it didn't catch up
like you guess I think it only ran on
some digital cameras so in 2013 they
merge the code bases from the two
operation system in something called
Tizen now Tyson's supposed to be the
operation system of everything and when
samsung say everything they actually
mean everything it's supposed to run on
smartphones tablets in vehicle to
payment Smart TVs smart cameras wearable
computing blu-ray players printers smart
home appliances refrigerator lining
washing machines air conditioners oven
microwave and even robotic vacuum
cleaners now most of you might not be
aware but
there is a great chance that Soundview
already own a Tizen device a device
running Tizen OS on it may be the most
notable one is the gear s2
which actually started as an Android
device but then Samsung moved it to
Tizen in 2014 we're not actually telling
anybody about it another really common
Tizen device is this month
Samsung Smart TVs the new versions are
running with Tizen there are about 21
million Tizen TVs worldwide and not so
recently Samsung started producing and
selling smartphones we Tizen on them
there are all labels with the letter Z
and they are not part of the galaxy
family even though you can see some
galaxy strings in the framework even
here in this picture you can see the
galaxy and the Tizen look and feel in
the mobile world is very much like
Android and it makes sense because
Samsung really helped to shape the the
Android user experience and I guess
those want to have something that will
be similar to what Android user would
expect so you can see the same tile
layouts as we know from Android now this
January
Samsung announcement CES they unveiled
the newest product line and most of them
are running Tizen they have Tizen
washing machine Tizen refrigerators
vacuum cleaner and even talked about
Tizen phones so it looked like Samsung
is planning something big for Tizen
maybe even making it their main
operation system instead of Android all
people are claiming that in the last few
years now over the last decade or so
Samsung has been using Google's Android
as its primary operation system and for
a while the two companies Google and
Samsung had up gain from this
partnership
because Samsung manufacturer of quality
phones like the s2b x6 the note 7 and
and they were controlling the control
about 60% of the smartphone market
worldwide and Google got accessibility
to millions of users worldwide this way
but today Google have their Android OS
they have their pixel phones so they're
not that depended on Samsung anymore to
create to manufacture quality phones
Apple have their iOS and they have their
iPhone now comes in red and it only
makes sense that something we want their
own operation system that we run on
their own hardware
just like the big ones do like Google
and iPhone where they could do whatever
they want whenever they want without
anybody telling them what to do because
when Samsung used Android OS it came
with a lot of of stuff that Google want
them to do they want them to put the
Google store in there the Google search
engine the Android pay and the doom let
Samsung do whatever they want on this
device so it makes sense that they want
to have your own operation system now
let's talk a little bit about Tizen
under the hood now Tizen is essentially
just Linux the core is open-source
most of it is open-source there are only
small part of the ecosystem that are
maintained by Samsung and our clothes
source the awards they wrote some parts
of the networking and messaging and just
like Android and iOS they also have a
concept of application and you could
develop applications in two different
ways you could either use the web
framework which is pretty cool you can
just write your app in HTML and
JavaScript or you can write it in native
code in C or C++ which is pretty cool
and in terms of security they've decided
to use smack instead of s Linux probably
to separate themselves from Android but
as you'll see as the toggles on Tizen is
very much like Android in some aspects
the first one I know this was in Android
we have the ADB the Android debug bridge
and in Tizen we have STD which stands
for that's right smart debug bridge so
that's the first thing I noticed but
anyway now we know everything we need to
know about Tizen for this talk
we know that Samsung is gambling a lot
on the success of Tizen in next few
years but when I started looking at
Tizen in the first place they only sold
it in place in the mobile world in two
places in India and Bangladesh and it
brings me to the question of why I
actually started researching Tizen in
the first place if they only sold it in
those two places so I was looking at
some Android cream wars as I often do
because that's what I do and I noticed
those free strings strings that I'd
never seen before
install WGP install WGP in apk and is GG
installed now I've never heard this WGP
file format and when I searched for it
online somebody mentioned it's the new
file format for application to the new
Tizen OS I said all right I've never
heard of it and I don't really care
about it and I just moved on but a few
days later I went about myself a new
smart TV and it said on the box that it
comes with Tizen T in with Tizen OS so I
got interested because I remember this
Pisan from a few days ago and I started
researching online about Tizen and I
came across this website Tizen store
calm which is an official Samsung site
it's basically just like Google Play or
the App Store and when I got to decide
it's just like browsing to the Google
Place or through your browser on your PC
and you can see here that they translate
these sites into two languages English
and some kind of Hindu language and it
supported the only two countries India
and Bangladesh a few days later when I
got to decide again I started I added an
extra country Nepal now the interesting
part was that there weren't even selling
any phones in a pal only about a week or
two weeks later they published a rumor
that they're gonna start selling Tizen
phones in Nepal so I thought well that's
pretty cool this site is a cool way to
predict where they're going to sell next
and in the course of the next few months
they added support to more languages and
more countries they added Sri Lanka
South Africa Nigeria and Nepal Kenya
Indonesia Ghana and there are even some
countries that they are not selling
Tizen phones to this day in this list so
it looked like Samsung are laying the
groundwork for a greater expansion of
Thailand to new markets and you could
see the exact same thing if you look at
their framework if you unpack their
femur you can see that they added
support in 2014 they had support in only
one country India they only add India
and MC season em and spindle config
files that mean that you could only
connect to Indian networks by default it
only supports several Hindu languages
and English and like you expect from any
Indian primer they had this fantastic
cricket app and apparently cricket is a
big thing in India I didn't know that
before that so they added this if we
look at the framework from 2015 then we
can see first signs of new countries
being added so you can see signs of
Bangladesh Nepal Sri Lanka and the
so added a movement times barracks and
they also had a bunch of new languages
formed for SwiftKey they added support
for let's see
they have Bangladesh India and Nepal Sri
Lanka China Korea and even Pakistan so
what I've been trying to tell in the
past ten minutes or so is that Samsung
is planning something big for Tizen it's
trying to spread around the world and we
should open it should pay attention to
its explicitly security researcher like
I did now samsung has been trying over
the last few months to learn more and
more programmers to develop it for Tizen
and there is something most people don't
know but some some like developers to
try their apps on physical phones before
they listen to the public and the way to
do it is that they give you this remote
test lab you could connect to this
remote test lab you get this you get a
connection to a physical phone and you
can test everything you want you just
apply for timeslot of between 30 minutes
to two hours they ask you nicely to log
out from Facebook afterwards because
people could use this phone later on and
over gradually over time they started
with only Indian servers and Korean
servers but then they added support in
Poland and in the u.s. probably trying
to approach developers in Eastern Europe
and North America and they also
aggressively start convincing developers
to port their apps to Tizen by giving
away about 10k a month to the App Store
in the top 100 apps in the Tizen store
and maybe their biggest move so far was
joining the dotnet foundation not too
recently they're trying to make c-sharp
what Java is for Android and by by this
way bringing all those dotnet developers
into Tizen
but for me the reason I actually wanted
to start researching tizen is when you
go to CV details calm
there are currently 0 cv is for Tizen
and I want to be one of the first to do
it and basically when I decide to do it
Samsung announced that they invested
about 10 million dollars it in security
solution for Tizen and I want to see
where this money has gone to so I went
ahead and but to Tizen phones think
doors are the only Tizen phones to have
been in Israel I or them from eBay from
India if Sonia wants see a ties for
later on you can come see it and I
bought them and I start researching them
and before we talk about what I found
which is the heart of this talk I
compiled the list of rules that I think
most of Samsung Tizen developers follow
in their during their production that's
my impression from looking at the code
so let's just start I call it being a
Tizen developer the untold rules well
the first rule is a string should never
be longer than 256 bytes there's no
reason for a string to be lager the data
right I'm men in the water think if
you're not sure you need as a cell don't
use it and I trust everything that
claims it came from Samsung you tell me
when to stop reading data which one
chicka by the RAM Malik could never fail
and no code review is needed ever so
this is the list I compiled the first
Apple looked at was the Tizen store it's
basically just like Google Play maybe
it's the reason for making Tizen because
Samsung for a long time pursue this
dream of having their own
application store and now they can it's
installed on every Tizen device and it's
very highly privileged because supposed
to install apps update apps and do a lot
of system maintenance now the weight
works a bit on technical side they have
a simple server client protocol between
the client is sold on the phone and the
server located somewhere in the internet
it's simple textual protocol over HTTP
there are about a hundred different
messages and most of them follow rule
number three of users lesser self
possible and the way it works we can see
it in this piece of code they have a
function called insecure connection
needed for every message coming out
there checking if this message is need
to be sent over a secure connection or
not now I'm not sure why that it is but
for every message every message type
they have a list of all the messages
that are supposed to be sent on secure
connection and not all of them are being
sent on secure connections an example
for one message is this it's the send
image download and what we can see here
it's just a message being sent to the
server asking to download an image from
a URL that the server send it before and
if you look closely we can see something
from way way back that we don't see
anymore they're taking this string this
image URL that we send it as the server
because it was send in plain HTTP and
they're copying it into a buffer of a
picture length of 512 so this is a
really basic heap overflow we also have
this just an example of bad coding we
have this Kellog it is being cold and
nobody checks its return value so what
we have in this function is using
obsolete and say a function not checking
for array bounds and some know the rest
but most of what we see is that nobody
even tried doing this
a proper code review to this code if any
was done this code has it all and here's
a really good example you might be
wondering by the way why I have this
really neat looking functions with a
function names and variable names and
everything somebody in samsung part is
going to be a really good idea to
compile everything with the bug symbols
making my life way easier so thank you
Samsung so here we see a function called
parse response error and what it does
sometimes their app server has a problem
and it can decide either to send some a
list of error codes to the clients or
sending a custom string if you'd send a
custom string an error string what it
does is it checks for to see if the
length of the string is longer than 1
and again copying it to a buffer of a
fixed length of 256 leading to a heap
overflow so we have the same thing here
we have using absolute unsafe function
not checking for a bounce and checking
there is enough data for Ebola flow and
then overflowing the hip I actually
explored this function this
vulnerability this is the one I chose to
exploit because it was fun and the list
of Pern ability just goes on we have not
checking for a bounds no proper stop
conditions not validating return values
PAP traversal and they actually did a
pretty good job defending against SQL
injection wherever I looked so good for
you Samsung you can have this one and if
you play pokemon go then most of the
referring to those vulnerabilities are
like gratata they're pretty crappy and
you can find them anywhere so it's the
same thing
another nice app I was looking at was
the Samsung cloud Samsung really want to
have their own cloud service and here we
can see on our great example of good
coding practices like allocating a
buffer or thousand hex
and then men setting about 1001 byte
doing an off by one always I'm not sure
why they did it you can read data from
the socket into this variable and then
allocating as much data as I tell it and
then copying data to this buffer that
you just allocated so you can just send
allocate 0 bytes and cause another heap
overflow so just think anybody if you
decide how they want to attack this
function now before we run out of time I
don't think this pup would be complete
without a browser burn ability that's
what people like these days that's what
people talk about in our talks in pwned
to own that's what people like so for
the sake of this talk I for the first
time alive open a browser code some of
it was open source I had to reverse
engineer and started looking and I found
a burn ability and about 3 hours before
my talk my flight story somebody from
Samsung contact me and we're start
talking about this burn ability and when
I try to send him a link to the burn
ability from their open source site I
saw that one of those developers J
quickly or John's oubli close the burn
ability they actually changed the code
around it and now the code with the
permeability is gone I don't think they
intentionally tried to close it but I
was already talking with this guy from
Samsung and I promised him burn ability
so on my way to the airport I was
actually sitting in the terminal
I found this vulnerability because I
promised them something
I think it's exploitable I asked them to
check it they haven't returned any of my
email ever since but I send them it the
different ability
yeah it's locally I think you can
exploit its I have a few years to do it
I've done stuff like that
now let's do a quick summary I found
around 40 different bugs
most of them look exploitable it felt
like 2005 in terms of the burn abilities
I found out of mem copies and here are
copies everything that you'll open the
fruit you open a book about her
inability research and it might be the
first example that you'll see for a heap
or floor second floor or just for a
buffer of though I exploited one
function the one I showed you before I
had one mini heart attack
when I tried the browser vulnerability
on my TV and my TV crashed and I was
really afraid that it won't come back
but human setter is a got back so I was
pretty happy about that and to maybe the
most important thing I want you to take
from this talk is that there is a great
chance that we're going to see the
Galaxy S nine from Samsung coming out
which ties in OS honest and right now
Tizen isn't mature enough isn't ready
enough to be sent to the public like
this if those are the variabilities I
found in a few hours of research then
somebody's really going to dedicate
himself in to via Tizen researcher will
find way more vulnerabilities and well
you can have a phone like the Galaxy S
named ship to the public like that now
currently Tizen is aimed to developing
countries if there's somebody from
Samsung here then I want to tell you
that I think they deserve security too
even if they come from India and all
those developing countries I don't think
you can just send stuff like that to
them because they don't matter to you
and I invite you all my fellow security
researcher to join Tizen ecosystem it
might be a new business opportunity for
you there
millions of TVs smartphones smartwatches
refrigerators everybody wants to hack a
refrigerator right somebody just found a
pet reversal in a dishwasher exciting
exciting times to be living in so I
encourage you all to join me into
researching Tizen thank you very much
[Applause]