[Music]
hello everyone thank you for having us
and thank you for joining the
conversation our session is South Korea
a PTO decades and we really show some
intelligence reports about this South
Korea apt attack before moving on
let us introduce ourselves briefly my
name is Hans Park and I work in the
class particular crate and as a senior
security researcher and my main duty is
researching about the threat landscape
in APEC region mainly of south korean
and hi my name is Tony and I walk that
walk that 4fk input leg escape Patel is
the courier company and I'm going to
move I'm going to work for IBM coming 17
and I worked I worked there as an aria
analyst and instant response at SK
InfoSec okay this is our story with
first hour we just share the South
Korean landscape and we picked 180 a
decade last year the South Korea
ministry national defenses breach so we
show that case and we will explain the
what is the connection with the previous
operation and Amanda breach case and
what is the what is the connection with
the emerging operation and finally then
flees the behind the discotheques
okay you know the Korea is the only one
divided country in the world
we divided North Korea in South Korea
and the Korean War is not and we just
see the fire so anytime the Korean War
can start our game and sub not created
keep attacking the South Korea not only
the ethical attack such as fires the
missile nuclear bomb exercise but they
usually doing the cyberattack against
South Korea and this is the we choose a
targeted altercation on the only the
2015 I just add other big issues in a
periodic case but so you can see the
only favor is the Korea local security
software vendors co.design is breaching
so and the slit actually using this code
signing to make it from custom Marvel
and on March the some selector using the
South Korea local software PSE local PLC
using the TSA they try to spray it on
malware and if there's more important
because we mentioned this operation
several time in this session so on June
June the Korean national policies
publish about the operation cost less to
big enterprises are compromised by the
same actor and they compromised on
140,000 and point and they still more
than forty thousand statements and that
uh cannot include some military
intelligence for example the f50 air
combat playing blueprints and the gravy
blueprint so it's very big issue in
South Korea and also on June July's the
Korean number one ecommerce company
called inter partes breaching
and more than 10 million customer
information is late and queer national
police the investigation this instant
and they publish the North Korea s top
behind the disa tech and finally on
December is a recent case of Ministry of
National Defense East bridge and we will
describe detail details about this case
so let's see the Korea Amanda peaches
Korea Mandy for public they were hacked
it on December 2016 and they found that
author was going from August 2016 and to
pieces in lots of DB division of Korea
means military were in packaging so some
computer data was stolen by a hacker
so let's see the incident flow so that
we could see the drone were surprised to
the inter internet and Eastern in
intranet but the troll was connected to
same ad management server and there were
two legs to that occurred the world's
two in solving git server Emily said to
later on maintenance company installed
visible measurement so hacker to
advantage or will give server to spread
malware to pieces internet and Internet
Emily that 2500 watt to were impacted in
Internet and 700 watts were in activity
in Internet we don't know whether
whether the information in the database
will
tolerance will not but but we think it
would be possible
so let's little timeline of daughter
Emily pounds suspicious evidence from
the rock pile on a lot of food and they
can't recognize the connector sentence
holstered attack on December 2 27 so
they organized the organized this
investigation came through 32 and right
this instant
then they well that to netacad were
installed in a be management server on
October 6 and they they found that
allowable pieces in Internet were
impacted on October 12 okay then I will
explain the tool of the we found robot
relate to the Amenti for each case at
the initial intervention phase we don't
have exact idea which method is used for
the initial intuition but and commit the
control place then using the full
feature the back door which is the
unknown back door
any every vendor is categorized this
back door
we just categorize the type ABC in this
time and the privilege escalation place
they using the mimic cut very famous
login credential something tool but they
packed with automata so they easily
evade the Avery detection and they may
using the custom network camera they
developed by themselves by this kind of
tool this tool can scan the whole IP
range and when
hoster can connect the copy copy the
more rare and executed by this tool and
at the data if you see is filtration
based a using the SSH tunneling tools
you can see the command the full if the
medicine enter make some connections
from internal network to the Internet
network you can see the port number put
numbers on one for three three is the
famous one ms SQL database puts so the
that actor try to make some connection
from the internet and Esther internet
data we suspected that the that actual
can access the internet database and
about the back door they're using the
three type of a backdoor type ABC and
this factor is a whole is a
full-featured spectral when the display
goes to implant to the PC the selector
easily can control the whole system but
it has a little different thing so for
example it has another pic on signals
type a backdoor using the prefix to the
two byte header and the generate one
bite Lendl xwiki
and using the lambda max one key it
encrypts the comforter name and the
username and send it to the city server
and start to start to communicate each
others and the B type be back wall using
the hard-coded in one bite actual value
and just to increase and appended a
predefined the strings on only most
question mark and IP address and send it
to the C&C server and type feedback door
also using the some kind of beacon
signal is a little different effortless
it standard four bytes
predefined key value values you can see
the
seven eight three two one zero and when
the C to e to the C - 7 4 by 2 this
value 10 start to communicate each other
so they're using the another kind of
activity but when we compare the
decryption routine that this is type a
backdoor encryption routine is a type C
vector it's almost the same using the
almost same encryption of team and but
this routine is using the another
purpose for example type egg a vector
using this declaration looking for that
equipped comment from the CNC server but
the cueball key rewards are using the
same encryption routine but okay in key
over using the disk encryption routine
when they increase the users kin
strongly so they share the some code for
many kind of more layers and it is the
attribution of the Malheur the when we
look into the filename is a very if many
I think the following people is not
familiar with this kind of finally but
it's very very long violin in South
Korean for example the hn3
update study FC is the Korea local water
process process name and the max Amy is
the query local software vendor TRX of
training and briefly logo dot exe is a
cool local antivirus software name so
selector may be so that can well all
about the South Korea host environment
and when we look into the language
many of the sample has a Korean
resource language so we suspect that so
that after using the Korean OS
environment and were they familiar with
the Queen
with so let's see the connection
readable the old operation as prophet IP
has the mother has passed 80 of
application and the routine was the to
post - static - character world still
asleep
they will stay with us through
characters kettles
Ethne job applications was was open to
that original date the stream so this
catalyst he was shooting operation esta
and operational mission this operation
was the step through the purple tack so
low tech and Taipei and taxi has a
similar description routine the routine
work has had operations like add and
shift and actual with with static number
the capitalistic world was showed in
operation plan Mac and operation cost
red and taxable IOT operation plan mine
was the worst operation saga for South
Korea organization if it was published
by a nerd and operational state was
already splendid and tax owed alliance
worlds was spread by watering hole all
july 2014
so let's conclusion disease and the
murderer used in MND MND breeches don't
matter had similar decryption routine
with taxol valiant and operation good
threat and operation playing mind also
the mario had stable opacification good
method with operation one mission and
president star this operation will let
you through tax or tax because Jesse IP
and Mario structure and in crystal
method will overlap with the tax all of
cybertek axle cyberattack world
the bankers and media in Korea will have
acted by large group so we take all the
diesel engine operation world hacky or
later later through the next is the
connection with the emerging operation
recent case recently the South Korea ATM
is compromised by threat actor if the
first time the ATM is attacked in South
Korea the same model from the same one
vendor is ATM machine isn't compromised
adjust more than 60 ATM is affected by
same malware and 2500 credit card
information is leaked by the thread
actress when I look into this more real
briefly it is not a memory scraping
style more real it's just an search
specific file at the hard-coded paths
and Italy if the moral
founded is fine it just compress it and
send it to the C&C server by the FTP so
when I asked about this file to the
viral security Institute again he said
with this ATM machines called the whole
credit card info
in this file so so that I already know
how this ATM machine is excused and he
just he or she protector just collected
his file and descended to the CN cover
very simple and but very efficient when
we compare this ATM ATM compromise
mother and the other operation the same
city server is using the ATM compromise
case and the operation cost less and
when I compare the amount which case a
the ATM compromise case it has many
called the similarity for example it has
it also has the same custom decoration
routine but as you can see the
encryption machines are almost the same
and when I compare the backup function
it's a almost identical as you can see
that this is the external function to
get this key information like the disk
number and available disk space but as
you can see they're almost the same
it means the same memories using both of
the operation and even some we found one
key local both of the operation ATM
compromised and Amanda bridge case whole
operation using the same controller file
even the same hash is also same it means
the same Java file so let's put them
together for operations we believe the
this operation is that could be by doing
by the one apt group but we won we
weekly sure 100% sure but it has many
connections
many overlap about these these whole
operations before that solo test the
operation one mission and the
operational once and
what's going on and the 2014 the
operation bling mine and operation post
let is the started and the last year the
MND is breaches and recently the ATM
machine is infected by the using by the
same mobile
so we believe these operations that have
so many connections and they share the
many code or mobile for these operations
then who is them who is behind the
discotheque so we believe many evidences
point out the larger cease to be hind
the discotheque larger say cyber and
phrenology cyber sabotage group but when
we compare the target at and the
intention of a whole operations
operation goes less is talking for the
big enterprise in South Korea and the
Terr main intention is military
intelligence they steal the blueprints
of UAV or f15 air combat plane and amend
in which case they target for the
military and still the military
intelligence but listen to ATM which
case they not target for them any
intelligence they target for ordinary
people just for the credit card so their
main intention is the financial profit
and as we publish the yesterday Rogers
has a intention photo an attack for
global bank so they're very active 880
group and they expand their target
horrible natural photo South Korea they
attacked our global bank and recently
they attacked a make a motion for the
financial profit so we believe they
their intention is a little changes
recently okay that's all from our
silence thank you for listening thank
you