[Music]
hello dear colleagues I had a bad news
someone will die till the talk till the
end of the talk but I hope northern is
audience but anyway he will die
why because 300 people died annually in
US states only 300,000 people is a third
reason of death in the United States and
this numbers always increasing and the
local education of doctors is not a
problem it's not a main problem the main
problem is the wrong diagnostic
procedures the second problem is the
trunk drop the theoretical and tactical
procedures that the reason of wrong
diagnostic my name is Dennis mcruiz and
I want to increase your attention to the
problems of smart medicine and probably
I hope the talk will save the couple of
lives in the future
and just imagine the conversation
between two guys in medical facility doc
are you sure that we need to cut my leg
yes our diagnostic equipment show us
that it has no life or another thought
doc are you sure that I need a read
instead of pills here you need a vide so
it happens because our medicine becomes
connected what I mean connected a huge
devices like MRI laxity or another big
machines like cardio grafts connected to
the packs servers back servers it's
something like NASA for medical proposes
picture archiving system and if this
device is not connected directly to
connected to PCs that connect it to the
back servers and of course
all of those devices connected to the
Internet - if you try to open the show
them or senses and make some requests
like Dai comport the icon with a special
protocol for communication between two
devices
- medical devices so if you try to
google it you will receive a lot of
interesting information about medical
devices that available online the DICOM
servers DICOM clients and probably
equipment like diagnostic equipment so
you will receive about 1000 results that
a potential medical equipment but some
of them is a honeypot of course but you
can diversify that easily using the show
line on using core system like honeypot
or not - Adam calm so the most of them
is the medical equipment or you can also
google it using special keywords like
medical clinical cardiograph cardiac etc
cetera with openness and be poor and you
will receive the infrastructure for
medical facilities like this one and if
you are adversary you can bring your
laptop to the medical facility and you
can hack it because you can extract the
sensitive information for these
computers or another example its back
viewers you don't need to bring your
laptop you can compromise the classic
web application for doctors proper for
doctors proposes because this
application contains the DICOM image the
image from the passion or another
example medical intelligence portal it's
a classic web application that has the
classic vulnerabilities so for example
you can find something like our series
web portal or serious medical portal and
you can extract a lot of information
because it has no identification just
tap on login form and you become the
doctor so you can upload something
arbitrary data you can download
something arbitrary data to something so
I think here is the best it's worth key
but it is it's available online and for
example what can adversary to do with
that
he could easily get access to medical
information to fashion information he
could bypass it I mean not a bypass but
spoofing so the center b3 DICOM image
and as a result someone died Agnes will
be wrong and this is example what about
available online from everyone
I think mr. Rodrigo will be disappointed
when he will see his data online but you
know this is still open it question what
about security of medical devices
because this is a classic web
application it's with the classic
vulnerabilities we have checked few type
of devices it's expensive devices and
very expensive devices
I mean house connected the just the
equipment is that could be a host in the
network an equipment that connects to
the computer using PC or USB port or
something like that and if you are
compromised the classic network medical
network you can extract the computers
that have connections to those devices
those medical devices like this one then
you can either compromise it because it
contains the classic vulnerabilities
classic services and even the house life
changing you in the medical equipment
and medical facility so if you are
adversary' what you can do with that of
course you can steal the information
about patients you can spoof the
information so that's why you will get
read instead of pills and then you can
write some ransomware for those devices
what we can do what we can do to save
the world to save the medical facilities
first of all if you are developer please
use the something like vulnerability
assessment approach if you administer
ATAR please
isolate tooth devices this computer with
medical data from the network in
separate segments and separate networks
if you are doctor please check twice
your results if you are user be healthy
thank you fantastic yes
[Applause]