[Music]
now good afternoon everybody and that
was simply an incredible talk involving
some digital archaeology that I could be
taking us right there way back into the
90s from Tom and Danny and Costin and
unwind just mind-blowing stuff and I'm
going to stick with a little bit of a
same sort of historical theme and but
focused on something that takes us back
into the slightly more recent past and
so the right 2016 and we got cold to
deal with some apt intrusions which had
a slightly more interesting twist than
we first expected whenever our incident
response team got holding and we lit up
a few instances of plug X and the
networks that we were looking at and our
Intel team map goes back pretty quickly
into a very large set of c2
infrastructure that overlapped in dozens
of locations with a very well-documented
set of historical activity and the very
first instance of that historical
activity was back in 2009 and with a
malware sample but contained what would
turn out to be actually a pretty
well-known phrase that phrase menu pack
was the poison ivy password used by the
malware sample to communicate with its
c2 server and with the first of more
than 30 samples containing that password
used by this actor over the next four
years a long way to about 90 other
samples using seven or so other
passwords and so that actor known as TV
NX based on some of their very early
subdomains potentially even going as far
back to 2007 and was also known as Tim
Honda bike ride strike and apt 10 by
fire I and actually a lot of that
historical activity from 2009 through to
2013 was thoroughly documented by fire I
and their 2013 report titled assessing
damage and extracting intelligence so
this is kind of a little bit of the
background on where this activity links
to and a lot of people thought actually
following that report the group had gone
to growing because they're poison ivy
usage killed off pretty dramatically so
I've got about 20 minutes to Philly
on some of the stuff that the group has
been up to since then so as we continue
our investigations and we kept mapping
out some of the infrastructure we find
plug X and we find more plug X and we
find more plug X and a lot of what we
find was effectively delivered using
load order hijacking with side loading
and a lot of the samples from 2014-2015
and we're all wrapped using security
products we've got Microsoft Security
Essentials McAfee Antivirus Enterprise
VBA 30 to 90 rootkit G data antivirus
kit and a whole lot of similar kind of
security products and for the most part
the file names of the included blobs
that contained to plug X payload
actually were generally blended in with
the nature of the application that was
being hijacked but as we got toward the
end of 2015 and into 2016 there was a
bit of a shift away from that into more
arbitrary applications and actually the
names have been coded payloads seem to
be completely random as well almost as
if they were being picked from sort of
some sort of English language word list
and for awhile they really loved the
Brazilian language version of the
PokerStars binary I don't quite know
what the connection is with that but
they really liked that for a while and
we saw that shift and two kind of
arbitrary word lists and some other
aspects of their operation as well which
I'll come back to in a bit so in total
we find something in the reason of like
30 plug X and site loaded variants of
these guys and we're using some of those
have been used by other apt groups as
well like apt 26 and some of them we
think are pretty exclusive to this group
we also saw them taking some open source
tools like peter be jumpin mini katz and
actually site loading those as well and
so there was a particular version of
minicamp that we find a couple of
instances of which had some very curious
error messages that the developer had
put into the source code and a few other
kind of sassy notes into this that I
couldn't actually get away with putting
on the slide and the interesting bit
about this for me it's a language and
the dev has used so the fact that they
don't view themselves as an A Team
hacker yet but it seemed to feel
fortunate they're giving that sort of
opportunity is quite interesting and the
fact that they have bosses and seems
like
in some sort of formal working
environment or some sort of on-the-job
training is available so it's quite
interesting to see them deliver some of
this stuff with that with side loading
as well so the plug acts usage brings us
up to 2016 which actually marks a very
significant shift in the group's
operational skill and the capability
prior to that they're using mostly
poison ivy and then plug acts and they
didn't really demonstrate any end-to-end
development capability themselves but in
mid to late 2016 APD can began a
parallel espionage operation focused
almost exclusively on Japanese targets
and potentially some Korean targets as
well and the amount we're at the center
of that campaign was called cheech's by
JP search the root of bloggers by the in
January this year and was actually named
after the fact that some of the malware
samples contain icons from Chinese chess
set most of them continue icons from
Microsoft Word and some other things and
are fairly common but it's actually a
fairly straightforward backdoor
relatively limited functionality kind of
fingerprinting and a kind of basic old
functionality and but it can and has
been used to pull down other commands as
well particularly PowerShell commands
and most of the kind of 70 odd samples
that we looked at were signed by the
team certificate from that 2015 breach
which this stage is a pretty good
indication of something that's bad and
some of the samples linked to two other
projects I will put it into them in any
depth of the report bypass AV which is a
wrapper that seems to be designed to do
what it says on the tin and black DLL
which is a loader named after some of
the DLL exports and that was used in a
couple of instances to launch that she
chose malware and but has also been used
to launch another kind of bundle of
malware that we call Nettie's X and that
we've only seen use the target Chinese
speaking individuals through social
engineering accounts we actually don't
know if that's apt 10 or not the
targeting using teacher seems to be
extremely narrow and very much focused
on kind of politics and diplomatic side
of things like foreign relations between
Japan US China etc as well as policy and
research
things against some particular
organizations focused in health etc and
some of that targeting is pretty obvious
based on the names of the file names
which we've translated here from
Japanese I had to be pretty selective
about which ones we put up here because
some of the file names are almost too
long to fit on screen they're almost
like an executive summary of the actual
lure itself which was a bit of an
interesting technique in it in its own
right there are loads of other examples
of this and a lot of them can be linked
to stuff that was quite topical at the
time and in particularly in the kind of
geopolitical sense there's plenty of
ammo for that sort of stuff at the
minute so you've got things like with
disputed ownership as it's in kaki
Islands you've got president Trump's
meeting with Prime Minister Abe in Japan
and things like flowing during
trans-pacific partnership just to kind
of give three examples of that that sort
of thing the developers were also a
little bit or kind of inadvertently
helpful and in this and they actually
left a bunch of printf debug statements
and some of the malware and so whenever
you ran it from a console mode you
actually got a pretty good narrative of
what it was doing behind the scenes
which turns out to be quite helpful in
some cases so thank you apt ten guys for
for that but despite their shiny new
implant and a lot of the delivery vector
that was reminiscent of some of their
2009 to 2013 activity where actually
they were just spearfishing
people and with the XE directly attached
to the email or either or inside a zip
file of the same name so obviously
wasn't having the degree of success that
they wanted so they added another layer
into this and in January 2017
they began spearfishing with link
attachment so this was actually a link
file that kicked off some PowerShell
which then got redirected through a
Google URL shortener to the c2 server
where it grabbed some more power
shelters and launched the church as
malware into memory and they seem to
have a little bit more success with it
but because of the regional targeting of
this JP shirt again have pretty good
visibility of it and blogged about it in
early February and this year one of the
obvious targets of this was the Japanese
Ministry of Foreign Affairs for which
apt 10 registered a couple of pretty
similar demands and one of those was
actually used to host a scam box
profiler as well on the Amgen
good JP dot-com address we don't
actually have the telemetry of which
sites were compromised the hosts that so
if anybody happens to know that please
come and talk to me afterwards we'd be
really interested in figuring that stuff
I'm just another data point on the
targeting and Google helpfully makes the
public stance and a mix with status of
the redirects public and so we took a
look at one of them just a few days
after it was set up by the attackers and
at this stage has fonts pretty small and
but Japan is responsible for close on
50% of all the clicks to it today at the
rest at Western Europe Nordics US and
Canada which is probably quite heavily
focused on security researchers like us
that we're doing a bit of investigation
into this their 2016 also brought a new
malware family very helpfully JCAP syrup
just published a new blog on this this
morning it was quite timely and like
most of the plug X activity this was
read leaves which is actually named
after one of the included strings in the
payload for default XE is delivered
through side loading but in contrast to
the chairs now where we're back
non-western and targeting and read
leaves itself is actually a pretty slick
piece of care it's a really nice
foothold and very comprehensive
fingerprinting of the user and the
operating system credential theft file
operations proxy tunneling shell section
enumeration screen capture and all it
sort of good stuff and that an operator
might need they also the developer
actually seems to know what they're
doing as well so quite a lot of the
functionality is actually multi-threaded
and one of the decoded mutex strings at
the bottom redly CMD simulator mutex is
what's actually used synchronized
activity across those threads as well
and 2017 january we also saw a PT 10
trying out the open source net quiz our
rat and then actually built a really
nice loader for this and so what they've
actually done and they kick off the
loader with the legit install util file
and but they have a heavily obfuscated
net binary which
that looks for effectively it has a
hard-coded directory and recursively
enumerate every file in that directory
over 300k attempt to AES decoder and
then launch it at the dotnet assembly
and obviously the exception handling
around that will prevent any errors so
you've got the loader which it can be
dropped anywhere completely independent
of where they typically see the payloads
we've also seen looters that are several
months older than the payloads that
they're using so it shows that you can
actually swap this stuff right or swap
like the payloads very easily and keep
the load of the same and we've seen the
actors actually do that on three
occasions within a 24 hour period to fix
some of the OPSEC mistakes that they've
made in the context Isles of the quiz
our rank which is actually included in
the in the DAT file so that's a
rapid-fire overview of some of the
malware families they've been using
there's a little bit of evil grabbed
usage in there as well and we haven't
gone into that and any dent but just to
give a walkthrough of this october 2013
and it's effectively the first set of
plug examples that we can link to this
group that continues all the way through
2014 2015 and 2016 and then we have the
chair's malware appearing in September
2016 through until the end of the year
as a standalone version it's not being
launched using PowerShell and from
January 2017 but sort of this year we
also saw them using the red leads
implant and quiz our malware as well
although we've got some indications the
red leaves might have actually been in
use a little bit before that too so if
we take a look at some of the compiled
times of this malware so focused on plug
exquis are in red leaf so far this is
all UTC plus it you generally get a
standard kind of working day and there's
a few exceptions on it but generally
it's a standard kind of China standard
time working day
the reason I've left churches' out of
this is if you look at the compile time
for that she was a very different
picture so we've either got an out of
hours project we've got time stamps that
are being tinkered or we've got
development happening somewhere else all
of the c2 infrastructure associated with
this campaign we'll come back to in a
sec
is again within China Standard Time so
actually let's take a quick look at some
of the the infrastructure these are a
few of the demands they registered in
the back half of 2016 and some pretty
common themes coming out a bit of
religious things a bit of political
themes a bit of international stuff as
well and you can see that Ministry of
Foreign Affairs stuff there that I was
talking about earlier if we look at the
subdomain to hang off these and we also
get some really interesting themes there
are a lot of sub demands that are
Japanese cities a lot of them are
land-based things to flee lizards
scorpion Lions falls ever etc some sea
beasts up shrimp type will and then a
whole lot of people's names as well and
actually a lot of other things here that
are either can originally focus or a
topic focused again on some things like
health and there's a remarkably
consistent naming structure with the
dynamic DNS to means that these guys
were using as well which increased
exponentially throughout 2016 and 2017
whoever was setting those up in hundreds
of instances use very similar terms all
to do this or IT management so it's
things like m/s update Windows Update
download ipv4 ipv6 etc so they've
obviously got somebody that's following
a pretty pretty standard routine for
this stuff and again looking at the
domain registrations as I mentioned
there's a pretty consistent working
pattern this is UTC so you can see
there's a first than a brick and another
burst and but if we swing this run to
you TC plus it and look at it in a
slightly different way we've got very
clear picture that between 8 a.m. in the
morning and 12 p.m. there's most of the
activity then a brick for two hours and
then starting from 1400 to 1800 again
and there's another burst of activity
and notably none of this happened on a
Saturday or Sunday so here these guys
actually been targeting and well for the
most part and all the usual suspects
we've got a lot of energy and mining
engineering construction metals
industrial manufacturing a bit of
business and professional services that
are on telcos particularly in Asia and
retail and consumer and pharma and life
sciences a little bit more recently and
obviously then the chairs stuff we've
already talked about that was targeting
Japan and they've actually been doing
this in a pretty broad skill so we've
got the USA Canada Brazil on one side
we've got South Korea Japan and
Australia on another and there's been
quite a lot of activity in Europe and
particularly the Nordics as well so for
a group that a lot of people thought it
disappeared in 2013 I have these guys
actually been staying under the radar
this is where we think it actually gets
quite interesting so during 2016 and
potentially as early as 2014 apt can
were heavily targeting IT managed
services providers these folks obviously
have hot boxes on the client networks
that they manage they have legit demand
admin access to the client networks and
we've observed multiple MSPs being used
as both an entry route to those customer
networks as well as part of the exfil
path an apt Ken has actually crafted a
really quite interesting web of exfil
paths to be able to move data around the
world and the compromise of some of
these MSPs potentially would have given
APD can access to thousands of victim
networks and the fact that they were
able to move data between MSP customers
and across MSPs themselves it could
probably be pretty instrumental in
helping them avoid a lot of public
reporting over the last few years so to
give a very quick example of this we've
got the actor using plug X directly over
the internet into a compromised MSP
client network using that to push data
out of the client network back into the
MSP that manages that client transferred
from that MSP over to another client of
a different MSP then back into that MSPs
network and then back tied to a location
of the actor is able to get it so that's
just one example but on a much larger
scale this actually becomes quite
complex because you've got webs of MSPs
that have inter connections with each
other you have victims that are being
used to push data back and forward and
actually you end up with quite a complex
kind of picture to piece together
whenever you're dealing with multiple
intrusions of this nature
laughter as well seem to keep a quite
tight eye on what's being said about
them and so quick kind of walk through
some of that stuff August 2013 have
already talked about fire eyes
assessing damage and extracting Intel
report a couple of months later in
August 2013 we saw the first instances
of plug X that we can cite of this group
26th of January I mentioned JP cert
published a teacher's vlog 2nd of
February apd 10 registers JP sir org and
I'd be quite interested if anybody has
seen that used and we don't have the
telemetry on it yet 10th of February was
the JP cert blog about PowerShell and
she says and within a couple of weeks a
new sample of the PowerShell script hit
virustotal
they showed a whole lot of evasion
techniques built into it on the same day
a silence published a blog of what they
called snake wine which is exactly the
same stuff they detailed quite a lot
about the demand registration habits of
the actor and which was primarily to use
India comm and Yandex chrome email
addresses and then the i-th name servers
and a few days after that who saw a
wholesale shift away from that
registration pattern which had they
stopped to consistently for a month over
to using privacy Guardians org
registration with children's TOCOM which
was the first t2 of it so it'll be
interesting to see what happens in April
2017 because as I mentioned JP sort of
just couldn't you blog up on it in a few
minutes we are releasing a joint
publication with BAE Systems and some of
this activity and the national
cybersecurity center excuse me in the UK
has been helping us coordinate outreach
to some of the affected organisations
and victims that we're expecting and
quite a significant uptick and some of
the public reporting on these guys as
well so just to wrap up and this on way
more than I can fit in a 25-minute talk
we have extremely high confidence that
the activity from 2014 to 2017 using
plug exquis our red leaves and she says
is being conducted by the same actor as
was responsible for the 2009 to 2013
menu past activities nearly apt 10 a
couple of other things that are quite
interesting around their ability to or
they seem to have quite ready access
native language linguists particularly
in Japanese English and potentially
Korean as well the skill of their
retooling and development through 2016
and shows that they've got multiple
in-house developers or access to a
digital quartermaster that's helping
them and their ability to manage
multiple campaigns and the skill of
victims that have been collecting stuff
from in 2016 as well is remarkably
different than their previous activity
and so we actually think they probably
absorbed some teams are familiar with
see any operations and we think that
that's pretty likely to continue so just
to wrap up I guess we've gone from in
2009 with a p10 APC 10 or menu has to
give them their original name being
little more than I guess a pimple on the
hairy arse of commercial espionage
through to a major player who's
compromised multiple networks giving
them access to potentially thousands of
high-value targets which is also a
pretty stark reminder for all of us that
we really need to be looking at our
supply chains not just those that are
responsible for our own kind of
corporate networks but also the folks
that are managing have hybrid cloud and
public cloud environments on our
behalves
as well and given that's exactly where
John Lambert is going to pick up in the
next talk that's exactly where I'm going
to finish thank
[Applause]
you