[Music]
all right so Who am I
this is me I know that I no longer look
anywhere close to what this is so I've
put on weight last year and most
importantly I no longer smile you never
know what ICS and cyber security can do
to you
I had no intent of including this slide
until in a couple of other conferences
I've had people walk up to me and ask
her rather tell that they thought
Schneider Electric was in the business
of manufacturing elevators and
escalators and then I had to remind him
that it was a Schindler and not
Schneider and then one other person in
the u.s. he said that on the morning
that we met he said I saw a truck saying
Schneider so are you into logistics so I
had to tell him that it was a Schneider
National which is a logistics company
and got nothing to do with Schneider of
course we are a French company with a
German sounding name but that's about it
so the main intent of my presentation is
to highlight the fact or the importance
of crate controls for companies
especially in the ICS world small and
medium-sized enterprises and of course
for other companies such as like
suppliers vendors and things like that
so it just sighs breeze through IOT ni
IOT so we have seen numbers different
numbers from multiple sources from
Gartner from Cisco conducting their own
surveys and here
Gartner says that 8.4 billion connected
things will be news in 2017 which is an
increase of 30 percent from the previous
year the other important point is that
there are they say or they forecast that
20 billion connected things will be news
by 2020 so three years from now
and another important point here is that
Greater China North America and Western
Europe constitute for two-thirds of the
install base this year so anything and
everything is getting connected to the
Internet these days
refrigerator smart TVs like who doesn't
have a smart DVD space and even though I
do not know as to why we need a smart
refrigerator
hopefully someone needs it and providing
ubiquitous connectivity so as far as a
IOT is concerned so we are mainly into
the industrial we are talking about the
industrial releve right so manufacturing
critical manufacturing utilities power
grids water wastewater military
complexes data centers healthcare things
like that so what we see here is a mix
of the traditional IT companies such as
Cisco hibm Accenture and the traditional
ot companies such as hydro Honeywell
Johnson Controls so everyone is jumping
on the I IOT bandwagon so I was looking
for a definition for a IOT and so
industrial internet consortium last
September published a document called
the industrial internet security
framework in which the define I IOT as a
system that connects and integrates
industrial control systems with
enterprise systems and that enables
significant advances in optimizing
decision making so what we see here is
that the traditional industrial control
systems which were isolated and not
connected to the Internet are being
connected extensively so we can probably
classify the a IOT devices into three
types low medium and high sophistication
devices so the low sophistication
devices are the ones that have minimal
to no HMI and which are a kind of binary
in nature so it's either an honor of yes
or no sensors things like that they are
actually deep down the line behind
multiple layers and there's like no
direct communication to the Internet and
then we have the medium sophistication
devices which along with the things that
I said for the low sophistication
devices also let you change parameters
so for example data aggregators are
devices which have which sound an alarm
if something goes beyond a certain
threshold and these devices may have
only a couple of layers of separation
from the internet the important device
that we are concerned about here are the
high sophistication devices the ones
that let you control and configure so
here we are talking about like smart
meters relay strip units breakers like
for example smart meters these days
allows you to send emails push data to
the cloud among multiple of other things
and these devices use only are only one
or two layers separated from the
internet and they tend to use encryption
or cryptography in one form or the other
so earlier we saw a prediction for IOT
from Gartner and so someone took the
pain of conducting a survey for a IOT as
well and this is what they found out so
in about 5 years from now
so the IOT market is expected to reach
150 billion US dollars an
ever-increasing attack surface of course
hackers like them so what has this got
to do with trade controls so originally
trade controls is is actually nothing
but export import licenses for items
which was primarily used for military
purposes so over time the scope has
expanded and now they are into
commercial products as well so the main
focus of this talk would be on products
which use cryptographic algorithms that
enable encryption functionality in a
product so why is it important that we
look at these things over here I will
get back to this slide but so why do we
care because of this so Wind River for
example was fined 750 thousand dollars
for exporting to these countries without
proper licenses and that is after the
fact that they self-reported this issue
so the point would have been much larger
and so previously as I put here our
self-reporting resulted in a warning
only
and now looks like fines are the new
alarm so blood sales should take a
direct hit on the revenue potential
liability so people can sue you no
matter what and the opportunity for new
or recurring business might be difficult
so probably so countries can blacklist
you a certain product it's possible in
secular product so sometimes and I'll
probably talk about this later
this can result in actually taking step
backwards so we're in we are going back
security-wise
and producing a more in secular product
and since ICS systems are into the
critical infrastructure facilities it
might have an impact on the safety as
well so all countries have certain
regimes for trade controls review and
here I'll be just focusing on us so in
the u.s. it's mainly dealt with a ITAR
and ei R so here we are not making a
recommendation of how strong the
cryptography has to be in a product but
what we are saying is if you are using
anything if you are using a key length
greater than anything mentioned over
here then it probably has to go through
a trade control review so 64 bit for
systems symmetric algorithm 768 for
asymmetric and 128 bits for elliptic
curve algorithms and also not to mention
that in the u.s. they have another I
think what is known as de minimis which
is so if there is a minimum of say 10
percent content u.s. content in your
product you still need to go through the
trade controls review so what's in our
arrangement I won't be talking about
that because earlier today we had
another session from Katie who is expert
on what's in our arrangement and she's
also one of the advisors to the US
government on what's in our arrangement
so what I'll be talking about is so the
way it is organized in the US and why
it's important so in the u.s. it is
handled mainly by ITAR
DoD oversees that and for civilian
purposes we use ei R which is overseen
by the Department of Commerce via bis
and what we want or if it's a global
product containing encryption what we
typically want is we need to shoot for
mass-market license which is e AR 99 and
ECC n is just a u.s. term so this is how
complex it can get and this is just for
the US I won't be going through that but
this is just to show us so this is
really a complex topic so having said
that what is the set of recommendations
that I want to give to all these SMEs
there are three recommendations so the
first one is to evaluate the product or
the offer to ensure it is properly
classified so we have to understand as
to what is the product capable of and
what is in the product so it's very
important that we understand these
things properly before answering the
questions or completing the forms for
trade controls determine where the
product will be developed source and
manufactured so it's very important that
we understand this because I'll give you
an example so there was a product which
was designed in France manufactured in
Germany with components from Romania and
Indonesia
so three months before the sell date
somebody in the French team realized
that probably we need to go through
trade controls and they went to NSS I
fancy and as a DB you who are
responsible for issuing licenses for
France and what the license that they
issued was you can sell this product to
EU plus seven other countries but that
was a bummer because they expected the
majority of the revenues outside the
Europe European Union so what they did
is they reached out to the team in the
US and the team in the US then went to
the Department of Commerce bis and the
BIS said it looks pretty straightforward
it has to be a mass-market product so
when we conveyed the message to the
French team they were excited so they
said that so problem has been solved
leadership all the products to
to us and then you can ship it all
around the world well it doesn't work
that way because it depends on the
country of origin so we have to go by
the rules of the country of origin so we
had to give them the letter that
Department of Commerce issued and then
they went back to a and SSI and so
finally they got the mass market from
the French authorities so by doing all
this we sprint close to around eight to
nine months and so we were way past the
seller date so that is the reason it's
very important so the other point is to
determine the geographic market the
product is intended to serve so another
example so in this product which is
actually a data aggregator so the
majority of the revenues from this
product was supposed to be from China
and so everything was on time on
schedule and we went to the US
Department of Commerce
you got the ear99 mass market and we
were ready to ship the product to China
however so we got a stop sign from China
saying they were not willing to import
the product and the reason being that we
were using HTTPS and so the Chinese
government suspects that NSA has a
backdoor in HTTPS so the solution that
they offered was either we strip out
HTTPS shipped them plain HTTP or work
with the Chinese company under the
auspices of the Chinese government and
integrate HTTPS so so these are the
things things that we encounter and this
is not rocket science especially our
peers in the IT world have been doing a
phenomenal job so this is just like an
example of Apple Microsoft has done a
great job Cisco I mean I can keep on
giving you names but so this is what we
are basically looking at so what is the
and this is available on the website of
your respective company so what is the
export control classification number do
we have a mass market or things like
that
step 2 so contact your trade controls or
tax and customs or
whatever team that you have or call
within your organization because it is
better left to the experts it's a very
complex complicated topic if you don't
have if you're a small company you don't
have tax or trade control team within
your organization you're better off
consulting an expert and this again is
for France so just to show you the lead
time so it can take one to five or six
so close to eight months whatever right
so you have to make sure that we have
these time considered into the posit
timelines and step three
so confirm that the export regulation
classification supports the offer
strategy so if an organization is
following the Microsoft STL or its
variant what we recommend is to start
early so go for a preliminary
classification during the required stage
and then if you add more countries
remove countries to do whatever you can
always refine it during the design stage
so in summary what we are saying is
trade controls in peyote is an immature
discipline so mainly in the OD part as I
said so mainly for ICS and that - for
small and medium-sized industries
because what happens is whenever we are
like say for example we are using a
crypto library in one of our product the
crypto library would have classification
and when we are using that in our
product the classification entirely
changes so we need to go for
reclassifying the product understand the
product components sub components
including its origin so it's very
important as I said earlier that we
understand not just the components but
even the sub components where is it
coming from do they have a
classification already conducted on that
component so that we can reuse that
start early consider time and cost so
it's very important that you consider
the time and cost for your project
planning and budgeting purposes do not
expect all your key went
worse or suppliers or contractors to be
complained today so we just need to be
realistic you need to work with them
it's a painful process we understand but
this has to be done the the reason that
you're not seeing much news on this is
because that it is not being enforced
properly so once government I don't know
when but with the latest US government
you never know when they start enforcing
things so probably once they start
expecting you can see more traction on
this topic
and lastly embed freight controls into
your organization's supply chain process
so it is always better to have this
embedded into a process so that you
never miss this and this is what we
recommend so that was a quick
presentation thank you all and life is
on
[Applause]