my name is Mumtaz lagarith I'm from the
University of Luxembourg and today I
will be speaking about Bitcoin anonymity
when I was flying to this conference I
watched a movie Horrible Bosses 2 and
Jamie Foxx was given a gun to three main
characters and he told that he was he
bought this gun completely anonymously
using bitcoins so I have an impression
that people think that bitcoin is
anonymous however recent research
disproves it and even Bitcoin developers
do not claim that bitcoin is anonymous
this encourages people to use tor why
one of the reason is that Bitcoin does
not increase its transactions so
everybody who is in between the user and
the Bitcoin network I can reveal the IP
address of the user it involves Internet
service providers or malicious peers
which the user wasn't lucky to connect
or if it can even be done with good
enough probability by a remote lower
resource attacker so today I'll be
speaking about issues which arrives
which arise when a user decides to use
Bitcoin over tor I will start with a
brief background and motivation I will
then this explain how to isolate a user
from the rest of the Bitcoin network
then I will describe a technique about a
fingerprint or set a cookie on a user's
computer and finally I will show to a
low resource Sibyl attacks so what is
Bitcoin
initially it was perceived as a p2p
Network however right now there is a
core of Bitcoin servers which accept
connections and there are users which
occasionally connect to this core
network to send and receive transactions
and this is what we will be concerned
about
the anonymity of transactions which he
Ellis sends to Bob so to increase the
anonymity of the Bitcoin system users
are recommended to store and to generate
as many Bitcoin pseudonyms which are
efficiently public keys right now Bob is
connected through Tor network which is
briefly is big set of proxies which Bob
can chain and send his transactions
through to the Bitcoin network usually
bit conscious three tour relays which
are called guard middle and exit and he
sends the transaction which travels all
the path through the changes of relays
and finally she arrives to the Bitcoin
network so let's start with the first
part how to isolate isolate the user
from the rest of the Bitcoin network
lady is a very simple there is built-in
ante dos protection in Bitcoin according
to which if you are a Bitcoin peer and
ascend the amount forint message you
will increase a penalty score of my IP
address and if I sound and send you more
foreign messages the usual increasing
and increase this score and finally it
it will reach 100 which means you burn
my IP address so let's see what happens
when a mall adversary tries to send a
mall mall front message to the Bitcoin
network over tor so he chooses
toreally say r5 and he sends it to a
chosen bitcoin server in this case the
bitcoin server will see the malformed
message coming from the IP address of
our fight so bit conserver
will effectively ban r5 next say other
day the same day Bob decides to connect
to the same Bitcoin server
over the same tour relay or a fight but
he will not be able to do this because
mitko already burned our five this
implies a very simple strategy the
attacker just burns all go all good
tor exit relays and he burns all would
be squad peers then he injects his own
Bitcoin peers and his own Tor relays
this results in that one Bob tries to
connect to the Bitcoin network over tor
he will be only he will only be able to
do this when he uses attacker a story
lace or attackers Bitcoin peers so let's
see how it looks like for example client
one chose some good tour relay in this
case he will not be able to connect to a
good to good bitcoin peer because an
attacker older already burned this
connection so for a client one the only
option to connects to the Bitcoin
network would be to choose a malicious
Bitcoin Bitcoin peer on the other hand
if client to connect to malicious tor
exit node there is no authentication in
the Bitcoin protocol so the malicious
tor exit node can impersonate whatever
beacon peer client you wanted to connect
to so what are the results
yep so the results are that an attacker
can delay or drop blocks or transactions
which increases the probability for
double spending attacks in Bitcoin also
an attacker can use classical traffic
confirmation attacks to the anonymous
the user or reveal his guard nodes and
also during the very same session since
all these transactions go through a
terrorist nodes he can link different we
consider name
of the user the problem is that when a
attacker burns all good
Tory lace and good Bitcoin peers and a
user will try to connect again and again
and if he chooses bond connections bond
Bitcoin peers he might spend some quite
some time and finally he might decide
that the whole system will be Co and
overturn it doesn't work properly so
this graph shows a delay and how much
between Pierce and tor exit capacity and
I take our suit half which is like
reasonable this is the first part so
what we have right now is that all the
connections of clients who decided to
use bitcoin of our tour goes through
attackers nodes let's see how we can
fingerprint those clients and the idea
again is very simple and it is based on
Bitcoin pure discovery protocol there
are just two rules which we should take
into account is and they are role one I
can send you an address message to find
out what IP address of other peers you
know and if I send sufficiently enough
messages you will tell me everything all
the IP addresses you know which are
stored in your database and they're all
do they're all - when I get a request to
tell what IP addresses I know to another
Bitcoin peer I'm ready to tell
everything yeah it is to tell everything
I know and when they receive an address
message back I will store all addresses
messages which are contained in this
their vision rules which includes any
garbage in any garbage
ap addresses this distress message can
help what it means it means basically
why send in addresses
I can fingerprint users or use it is an
address cookie and it will work it
doesn't matter if a client is connected
to the Bitcoin network overt or BK v pn
or alec proxy systems and we can use
different combinations of IP addresses
for different clients let's see how it
works
so we now I selected the client from the
rest of the Bitcoin network so whenever
he sends sends a suspicious transaction
we also send him back address cookin
next when he decides to connect to the
Bitcoin network without tor just to send
some benign transaction we check this
user for a cookie and this allows us to
reveal his IP address and if it's
effectively D anonymize the user the
respond problem is that for me as a
Bitcoin peer my database of IP addresses
is limited and I can store approximately
20,000 IP addresses at the same time
excuse me at the same time whenever I
make a connection to the Bitcoin network
I connect to 8-bit Co and peers and they
will send me the addresses they know so
with each new session which is which
with each new connection to the Bitcoin
network I will get about 20,000 non
unique IP addresses which looks like
with every new session within a couple
of session the fingerprint which already
set will be overwritten however actually
it is just an apparent problem and in
reality the IP addresses which are
receive will almost never override the
fingerprint the the cookie which has
said before
and it is based on that each first of
all me as a Bitcoin pier I only store IP
addresses about which I don't know and
our experiments show that about only 6%
of IP addresses which I received are
unique or new and this second thing is
that each IP address has a timestamp and
whenever I can see there if I should
store whenever I decide to store an IP
address I need to replace it with some
other I need to put it into some some
slot which occupied by somebody some
other IP address so how I do this I just
choose randomly 4 IP addresses which are
already in my database and I choose to
all this one again our experiments show
that for 45 percent of IP addresses in a
client's database there are older than
10 hours which tells us that with the
very high probability the cookie is set
recently will not be over overwritten
this table shows our experiments and in
a nutshell within 10 sessions we were
able to preserve 36% of our fingerprint
which with very high probability allows
us to see anonymized a uniquely D
anonymize the user so the bottom line is
that our finger printing technique
survives survives restarts it is
preserved for many hours and so for
example within 24 hours half of the
fingerprint is preserved which again
allows us to anonymize the user the but
well the bad thing for an attacker it is
this ticking will be fixed soon
we also concerned the fingerprint not
only when a user connects to through the
Tor network but we can also do this
other way around we can fingerprint the
users when they
connected to the Bitcoin network without
tour and then when we see a suspicious
transaction coming from the from the Tor
network we can we can request a cookie
from the user which means that we want
all Bitcoin users to connect from time
to time to our militia spears the
problem is that right now I need one IP
address for Bitcoin Pierre I will
describe two techniques right now so the
first technique is well known in the
Bitcoin community and is also very
simple by default a Bitcoin Pierre
accept 117 connections this suggests
strategy just get the whole this whole
list of Bitcoin P different peers and
occupy the connections open collection
slots then whenever a client decides to
connect to the network he will not be
able to connect him legitimate Bitcoin
appears so he will finally end up
connected to malicious peers and we can
update or set any fingerprint to the era
computers the second attack is based on
the fact that if I already store an
address of Bitcoin P R I don't consider
it worth number when I is you I decide
to store it or not so this allows this
has suggest the phone strategy I
broadcasting the Bitcoin network IP
addresses of legitimate peers but with
their own port numbers then clients try
to connect to those around port numbers
and well which obviously fails at the
same time when they receive an update of
this IP address will they even restore
those new IP address in the database
because they already have they P but the
course number are different so
their own port number girl feigning data
database and the collide will not be
multi connected to the network so is in
conclusion we force all Bitcoin over
torque lines to connect through bit
peers or relays we can set the
fingerprint on there are computers which
allows us to deal analyze them and we
also know how to increase the chances
that the client connects to malicious
Bitcoin peers so which allows us to
refresh the fingerprint or request the
long fingerprints from the from the meet
compliance yeah this concludes my
presentation
thank you thanks very much for that talk
I'll take the first question the middle
Mike hi um you don't mention any
solutions for this attack I mean an
obvious idea would be for one of the
Queen for each one for the first attack
I'll get mostest exits to be blacklisted
for bending over for Benny Bitcoin over
tor right so if some peers were to want
to enable anonymous access by tor that
could run a tor hidden service but then
I mean they still have an idealist
problem right they've got malicious
sorry again but so if they ran a hit the
service hit a service then they could at
least know those guys coming over tor
and they could they could apply some
other mechanism other than IP banning I
don't know what that mechanism that
would be do you have any suggestions so
with hidden services there is the first
problem yeah the first problem is that
you can make a denial of service of tor
hidden services this is first second
right now we checked it and I don't
remember the exact number sitting in the
in the paper right now there are about
only 30 hidden services to which a user
can connect to the Bitcoin network and
the third problem is that for hidden
services civil attacks just work
perfectly because you don't need
additional IP address to run a Bitcoin
Bitcoin peer so you can run as many
hidden services as you want
so my suggestion would be if you know a
hidden service fee which you can trust
you need to connect to that hidden
service and just choosing random random
hidden service will not solve this
problem so heinous service should be
trusted you know Thanks did you me say
that there are some people in tears who
are running in service are there some
Bitcoin peers who are running in
services is that what you said sorry
are there some Bitcoin peers that are
running tor hidden services yes yes
there are like about 13 oh yeah
so in there is own Bitcoin wiki there is
a list we found some some others like
making queries to the mythical appears
thank you take the questions right Mike
I was gonna ask really similar things to
Aaron but just you know ask the other
side of that what would be it seems like
this hinges on the fact that bitcoins
main denial of service prevention is
banning IPS that do something bad so I
mean it seems like a necessary
alternative would be some alternative to
that so have you looked at any other
ways that you would be able to yeah
probably so I think the the reason why
they have hunted Bitcoin until those
protection is to prevent basically those
into the whole network so what can be
done is that half of the network and
like with probability 1/2 your Bitcoin
peer disables and DDoS protection and
half of the network like with
probability 1/2 is still preserve this
anteaters protection so basically this
will result is that you cannot isolate
all all Bitcoin clients from the network
so but if by default you have 8
connections to the network half of them
will go through and half of them will
choose a malicious fear if you thought
about anything like having clients have
to pay in Bitcoin appear that they're
gonna connect to for bitcoins - oh yes I
was thinking there is there is one paper
which was presented at financial crypto
actually about paying
but immediately I kind of think how it
can help to solve this problem I think
it's it requires some some more thinking
yeah thank you one last question
okay so what if we can modify the tor
network so that the toe entry node we've
been over the bat user who broadcasts a
bad message
so without make a bit koibito a good
practice oh sorry I'm sorry I didn't so
worried we modified the Tor network so
that the gardener we check it a user is
broadcasting a bad message so that
they've got note we regard oh yes the
gardeners rejects you rejects what the
bad the god node we we banned the bat
user so that the thought exists no we
still work sorry the guard note is the
first note in the in the Bitcoin change
in the Tor network yeah yeah so what so
um the garden cannot do anything because
he just sees an encryption something he
sees an encryption connection so he
cannot distinguish if it is I am saying
I am saying that but if we can modify
the Tor network so that the GAR node can
bind the the bad user right so we that
might go over to a good practice and
it's a really good question for the
toward the April community it's the
fundamental motivation of Tor there you
have it okay okay thank you but we can
discuss it offline but yeah let's thank
you speaker one more time