Thanks this is joint work between toss
and horse group and go home and another
thing is open and after that actually
just rooted in my second talk
unfortunately I were to make it in time
for the vc3 cloud-computing talk on
Monday yeah funny story
okay and today I'm going to talk about a
novel code we use attack and let me give
you a brief introduction to two code
reuse attacks in general so code reuse
attacks are roughly well composed of two
steps and first is the initial control
for hijacking because the attacker
exploits buffer overflow vulnerability
or reviews of the precondition to take
control of the instruction pointer and
because today we have things like data
execution prevention attackers can
really jump to their to the share code
directly but they need to employ a
second step which is a code reuse step
and the purple of the choreo step is to
bypass data execution prevention mainly
and well probably the most widely used
technique years will turn them into
oriented programming and in the curio
step the attacker reuse existing pieces
of code that are available in
applications at webspace and peels them
together such that some alysha's
computation is performed for example in
Rob the attacking objects a fake effects
deck and then private the stack pointer
to the stack and such that short short
chunks of code are are chained together
and Ingrid turns such that some
malicious computation is performed of
course for Coby at attack the attacker
needs to know the locations of the code
chunks he wants to reuse so usually
there's also an initial step the
information leak where the attacker
needs someone ability to infer the base
address of executable modules and
application gray space
all right and in this talk I'm going to
concentrate on step two and all our
contributions just concerned step two we
are preventing another proper use attack
yes you may know if defense against
designing defenses against koreas
attacks is a
it's a busy field post in academia and
the industry and I think you can roughly
categorize defenses against code reuse
using this table they are first memory
safety approaches which try to invent
the initial control for hijacking then
they are control for integrity
approaches which try to not to prevent
the initial control high braking but
rather to to mitigate the following code
reuse
step they try to prevent an attacker
from from branching to the funny total
occasions essentially then they are code
shuffling and rewriting hiding
techniques but try to to make the code
to hide the code from the attacker or
make it unusable for for reuse and then
finally there are heuristics based
systems which try to detect code reuse
attacks at one time using different
heuristics and last year this
comprehensive was the out of control
paper by a good test and others and they
urgently essentially showed that
different control for integrity
mechanisms relied on certain assumptions
that are not necessarily correct in
practice and they were they were able to
demonstrate an attack set by past some
of these Avaya systems additionally
there have been four papers last year
two from our groups which saw that
certain heuristics based system are not
sufficient in practice all right and in
our well in this talk I'm going to
pretend count of counterfeit are
optically or in the programming and we
essentially show that all of these
defenses or that defenses from all these
categories have rely on certain
assumptions that aren't necessarily true
in practice ok the autumn for the rest
of this talk is as follows I already
gave introduction next is a background
slide on on c++ then i will prevent the
basic idea of our copious attack then I
will walk you through a simple example I
will talk about our example exploits and
there will be a discussion illusion and
the conclusion of course ok but very
click quick background slide on C++
and it also understand our tech it is
essential to to at least have a very
broad picture of what she prefers
objects look like in memory so if you
consider Class A plus I has two fields
index and sharp point a Y and an object
of Class A essentially looks like like
it is shown over there in memory is just
composed of the fields x and y if you
now look at Class B we see Class B is
essentially the same as Class A but time
zero is virtual so whenever we have a
virtual function in the class object of
the class get a hidden field called the
DPR and the VPT our points to to a table
of virtual function of pointers to
virtual functions and this this V table
contains pointers to all virtual
functions of the class so what and
whenever a virtual function is to be
involved at the runtime it isn't this
the address of this virtual function is
looked up dynamically from this table
so what attackers usually do when they
attack c+ replications they they hijack
this v PG are in order to get control
over the control flow and then to mount
the extra copy of the tag and this is
also what we do and please also keep in
mind that because of this V tables they
exist pointers to all virtual functions
in the sequence elliptic application and
so there are many address setting
functions in a C++ application okay now
all the basics of our our tech and the
motivation for our tech was the
following of the observation and
existing code to use a text such as Rob
all exhibit one of these five five
characteristics first they branch to
funny code locations then the us return
instructions out of order and the inject
inject or manipulate existing code
pointers they executed successively many
indirect branches all they pirates a
stack pointer and many defenses rely on
these characteristics and in essence it
is sufficient to maintain a shape to
maintain and enforce a shadow calls take
in order to fend off our base attacks
and our initial question was to Kobe use
the technique necessarily exceeded these
five characteristics so the the ideas
for our tag if we only hijack and inject
C++ vpg ours and the only reuse existing
see plaster virtual functions on our own
injected counterfeit objects and we call
these virtual functions only from
existing virtual function calling site
then a we don't exhibit these five
characteristics and be the defender
needs to be aware of C++ semantics now
the question is can we create a mean
attack using only using whole virtual
functions and turns out we can and
here's an excerpt from our paper and we
figured that we would need virtual
function of different types in order to
provide the attacker with
turing-complete
semantics and earn some extra semantics
and these are essentially all the
different types of need in order to
create a meaningful attack on x86 32-bit
and 64-bit and I'm not going to explain
awesome but I'm going to explain the
main loop gated which is the most
important one and two simple ones okay
and we refer to to these virtual
functions that we use in the coop attack
as react gadgets so the control phone
incorpo Tech looks looks like this first
we have the entire control V call
because they take a overrode thing the
VPT alpha C++ object and the attacker
then branches to a main loop gadget and
from this main loop gadget we invoke the
actual DF gadgets that we want to to
execute in order to program our or
Twitter or ballistics computation will
execute it okay as I say the main loop
gadget is most important we have a
gadget in the koba tag and it's defined
as follows let me read this for you a
virtual function that iterates over
container for example a C++ that array
or vector of object pointers that
involves a virtual function on each
object and here's an example it's a
simple container class which has an area
of object pointers and it iterates over
object pointers and it works it works a
virtual function on each of these
objects okay and here's an example of a
main loop from video studio 18 store age
just to give you an idea looks pretty
similar to the for my example here's an
example from from Chrome and here's an
example from Internet Explorer ok so
there are plenty of main loop graduates
available and now what kind of data that
the attacker inject in order to to know
the coop attack and as I said in and Rob
the attacker injects a fake snake and
manipul manipulates VPT R such that the
stack pointer is private suit to this
fake stack in the coop we inject a bunch
of fake C of counterfeit C++ objects we
have a well imagine we have object here
we can overflow into this object then
the attacker rewrites the B PTR of this
object such that the main loop gadget is
executed next the next time virtual
functions involving that object and we
also inject other counter feed objects
the kind of hit objects that correspond
to the actual to the actual VF gadget
that we want to to execute to induce all
malicious computation ok this is this
was a main loop gadget and now comes how
can you and you can you actually come
actually compute this coop so as I said
we have this main loop gadget and this
made-up gadget invokes different virtual
functions virtual functions that we want
to execute and I'm going to show you how
we can do some some meaningful
computation but we using virtual
functions on our own injected
counterfeit objects and well I'm going
to present two very very simple VF
carrots I'm going to show you how how we
can combine them ok first let's say we
want to to add values in our attack we
want to dynamically calculate the sum of
something so consider the classroom
and the class result has at least four
fields well you're able to be well you
see and and well you and the virtual
function update value adds value ABC and
write the result to the field value so
if we invoke this virtual function on a
counterfeit object that we inject it of
which we control all the data fields
then obviously if we invoke this virtual
function on this counterfeit object then
we have a simple simple summation that
we could be controllable right we have a
data flow from ABC - well you okay so
this is an example of a virtual
functions we can use to do some
arithmetic and now let's say you want to
write some memory and consider the class
simple string and the virtual function
set just as a string copy right and if
we invoke the virtual function set on
the counter feed object that we injected
then we of course control buffer and we
can control length so we can control the
destination and the amount of data
that's written but of course in the
meaningful Korea's attack you would
probably want to control the destination
address you would probably want to
dynamically calculate this nation
address right so you need an you need a
data flow from 1vf gate that you execute
to the next one all right you want to
dynamically calculate the address for
buffer and you want to do this using the
first we advocated I showed you and you
want them to write some data to that
address that you've calculated and
here's how we do this we have over there
we have the concept of overlapping
counterfeit objects in coop so see we
have the a blue object which corresponds
to the first we F get it I showed you
this calculate the sum of ABC and write
this two to the field down below because
these counterfeit objects overlap the
next we F gadget interprets this value
that we wrote as a destination pointer
for this mem copy operation of the
stream copy operation of course you
would also want
to control the the sewers pointer
probably in a career attack but well
this is explained in the paper
how how how you could control all this
okay so and we created different two of
content exploits for co-op for example
for in to explore 64-bit we created
where we used existing vulnerability for
for step one and we created a co-op
attack that dynamically calculated the
address of winner of the Winx API and
read the current account and if the
current account was even then chi-x II
was launched if the current account was
odd that Emma's pain taxi was launched
all in all we needed to inject 21
counter feed objects for that of which
eight overlapped like I showed you and
we used eight different V educators from
its HTML the DLL and we also did some
two of contact sports winter exploring
to bid and for Firefox 64-bit on Linux
and we implemented a core programming
framework that relies on zip three
theorems solver and submit for arranging
objects in a given buffer and we use
Amazon doesn't the metallic tool to to
look for useful VF gadgets in a given
binary ok now comes the discussion of
our co-op attack and first applicability
of course I mean you can design great
careers attacks on paper but of course
this needs to be applicable all to be
relevant and yeah we essentially we
found we we created we brought the text
for x86 x64 and we also discussed in the
paper why Corp is probably applicable to
RISC architectures in general and of
course the question is how many useful
virtual functions are there usually and
we found that in reasonably sized
programs there are lots of virtual
function that you can be used to build a
cool co-op attack and well as I said the
main loop is probably the most essential
we have gadget that we have
and it's unfortunately also the rarest
one but we discovered that main loop we
applicators are also very relatively
common for example we found useful
specimen in standard libraries of with
the studio which are linked to very many
dynamically linked to very many
applications and windows so you're like
you are likely to find all the Gators
you need in most processors and windows
ok now the properties of coop and hope
does not inject all pointers cop who
lies does not rely on
doneita semantics of code does not
execute rock returns of strange
instruction sequences and it does not
pipe the stack pointer and as such scope
does not exhibit the aforementioned five
code reuse characteristics and Cobus
immune against the protection of code
pointers semantics preserving rewriting
shuffling of code detection rule six
existing heuristics and general generic
see if I or shadow crawl sex how to
prevent co-op and of course you can
protect z plateau v PG arse you can
apply c pathos aware control for
integrity or you can randomize c plaster
structure so there's probably more you
can do and the inside is but we think
that in order to design strong even
seeing hope you need to have access to
source code because you need to consider
high level c++ semantics as such
preventing corpus our access to source
code is very challenging
they're always challenging this is what
we claim and in fact we don't know of
any effective by the way only defense
against co-op so here's the table from
from before and i colored some some
defenses that are vulnerable to corbin
red and even those that are that are not
wandering green and we can see that
basically all the binary or most of the
binary only stuff is vulnerable
alright that's it conclusion I presented
the novel coleus attack that shares
common assumptions that many defenses
are built on and we make a strong
argument for suus k z-- defenses that
consider
high level programming languages
semantics Thanks well time for a couple
quick questions can you come and our
other Oh languages like C sharp
any and we thought about that and I
think and cope could be very believable
to Objective C Objective C and because
there also there's also this object to
see if there's even more metadata than
then in C++ and there's there's even
more dynamic binding going on and we are
kind of looking into court that you've
seen yes
Matti aspire Purdue I love the technique
but I don't necessarily buy that you
need source code semantics for that
imagine if you like the gadgets will be
less likely and you will need to find
gadgets in sieve in several different
libraries and even on the binary level
you can observe control flow transfers
between the individual libraries if you
abstract to this library granularity
level and this would be a clear
indication of some cope attack going on
yes and yes it's true okay it's true you
can probably construct something that
does not require source code and B it's
what about some things especially if you
monitor application at one time and I
think it's hard to construct something
that's just aesthetic and yeah but if
you run it if you have some additional
runtime analysis I think well our
exports went to expose they just rely on
gadgets from ms HTML dll so maybe that's
not it's not too revealing but of course
you cannot come up with can't come up
with something that's binary only but I
think our point is that you well then
you can maybe again construct something
that misses you design another
programming language features yeah we
could discuss moral yes thanks
I was wondering if you have any more
thoughts on defenses so for instance
just just throw one out there what if we
had something like stack Canaries
Canaries after the V PTR or or can you
suggest other defenses that you think
might be effective and I think what
would be a cool defense is if you could
randomize object layouts right oh you
could insert canneries I mean this like
like I said can be as I said I think
there are many defenses but the question
is can you well can you maybe just find
a simple way around that we can take
these guys
obvious thanks again