well first of all thanks for the kind
introduction and thanks to all of you
for showing up this early in the morning
I know it's always a bit over there to
give a talk right after the closing
remarks so I really appreciate your
coming here um I'm going to present a
set work on back search in binary
software which works cross architecture
and I'm going to wait for the first
slide show up before I actually start
the talk
okay that works um asset I'm going to
present my work it's of course not my
work all alone um I've done it with some
colleagues of mine namely be hard kimani
robot garlic Christian also and my
professor toss notes unfortunately
Christian also is not at the rural
university anymore he switched to sis
Bowens island which I forgot to mention
on the side so I should really mention
it here but all of them are actually in
the audience so if you happen to like
this little piece of work please make
sure to tell them about it too i'd
really appreciate that so asshat cross
architecture back search um if you ever
feel a little bit lost in this talk just
remember that the key ingredient of it
is a code similarity metric which
happens to work across CPU architectures
so if you ask yourself well why are we
doing all this pre-processing stuff it's
to set up this a key ingredient they are
slightly out of sync
we can probably get that fixed right
okay here we go key ingredient called
similarity metric asset if you are
asking yourself why are doing all this
pre-processing is it to set up this
constantly are geometric if you don't
know how we are looking for bugs again
it's with that code similarity metric
the basic workflow all over what we are
doing is you shall is a binary in either
x86 or MIPS or arm and obfuscate it that
is you pinpoint us to the exact back
location and then you give us another
binary and we try we will try to refined
the same or very similar back in that
binary which may be compiled for another
architecture so and the basic assumption
with finding bugs with Col similarity is
that we know what a specific buck
instance looks like we try to find a
piece of code which looks pretty similar
to that and well then it is likely to
contain the same bug and the reason for
that is mainly because the reason for
the code pieces being similar is that
programs are lazy they will copy and
paste code and that means they will also
copy and paste bucks they may adapt them
slide into the situation which is why we
not only find the same box but actually
sometimes similar backs so i'll start
with not all work but actually with
somebody else's work and that's for two
reasons first of all because it really
inspired what we did second of all
because i really like that overview
graphic that they have and that allows
me to include in my talk so I'm talking
about generalized vulnerability
extrapolation using abstract syntax
trees it's worked by 5am Iguchi at all
who is also in the in this room as far
as I know and what they do is they
analyze some source code and the
resulting abstracts industry abstract
syntax tree is embedded into a vector
space and then they use the metric of
this vector space to find similar code
vectors and if one of them happens to
happens to be known to be a bug it's
likely that the other ones may also be
bugging so um what do we actually want
to do it's um so that worked for me
mostly means that they abstract from
back classes which may sometimes be hard
to use are in practice actually so what
they do instead is um they and we focus
on single bug instances
second of all we want to focus on
something like nearest neighbor search
actually we don't do any fancy
clustering or something like that
because what we actually just want to do
is to find out if two pieces of code are
similar to each other third we want to
do it not on source code or non-binary
and all that we do actually has
sub-function granularity because that is
very important for back search if you
think about it if you know what a piece
of code that as a bug looks like it
would be really cool to find that not
only in the function that it's in but
actually also in another function and
that requires sub-function granularity
and last of all we would like to focus
more on the semantics and the structure
of the code than on any symbolic or
syntax information so and no it really
starts with what we actually did so we
start off with an intermediate
representation as set you give us an
office skating binary be it x86 or are
more moves that's the architectures
which support so far and then we use the
VEX intermediate representation most
known for the wall grind memory checking
framework and that's IR is usually used
for dynamic analysis and we kind of
missed use it for static analysis which
gives an onset of problems but we also
had to modify it heavily to abstract
from some architecture specific let's
call it idioms so to say and what we
then do is we use basic blocks as our
let's say single building block and for
each basic block we try to accumulate
the effect this our basic block has on a
specific register or memory location so
we accumulate all the little of XIR
instructions that have that specific
register as target and we got a big big
expression that explains what happens to
this register or memory location in that
basic block when you execute it we pipe
all that into z3 and that is only to get
a nice simple as expression out of it
and to simplify it a little bit so as
you can see on the bottom we start off
with some assembly code in this case our
it's just something that reads of a
memory location and incremental calendar
and you can see that the assembly
instructions are kind of different they
differ in the number of registers in
there actually x86 only has one
instruction for doing both of those
tasks and the intermediate residents
have representation already looks kind
of similar so um but these are complex
assignment formulas as we call them a
kind of hard to compare to each other
what you can usually do is you can use
some unifying approach or something
which will tell you if they are equal or
not but that is really not what we want
we want some kind of scaling gradual
similarity measurement so what we did
was we sampled which means that we
generate a random input vector execute
the basic block on that input vector
which gives us an output vector so and
we do that for a lot of inputs and that
really gives us some kind of point wise
semantics of this basic block and now
the reason the reason while we do that
is that similar basic blocks are kind of
exposed to share in these input output
vectors these input-output pairs and the
more they share the more similar they
are now from those assignment formulas
we have got a big big set of I au pairs
basically and that isn't optimal either
um because to compare them you have to
do something like whatever the jack our
index or something like that which is
pretty pretty costly actually so we came
up with another step which is to use
locally sensitive hashes and those
little things have a nice little
property which means that the similarity
of the hashed object is actually
represented by the hash which is not
similar to cryptographic heathers hashes
for example and that allows us to save
one hash per basic block instead of all
the big big list of input-output pairs
so that's in the end we can compare two
basic blocks actually find out how
similar they are just by comparing this
one little hash so and now or that we've
done that we can actually go to how to
find it back with that we start off with
a bug signature in an hour case back
signature which is just a catchy label
we need it
just a piece of code it is not as
abstracted as for example arm in network
intrusion detection systems or something
where it's a glorified reg ex or
something it's just a piece of code
that's it and back signature in a sense
should contain the back and a little bit
of discriminatory context but as set
it's just a piece of code it's not
structurally different from the target
program we look for we look in for the
back signature so the next step is to
find some starting points we start off
with a single basic block in the
signature and try to find a good basic
block level match in the target program
just to know where we have to like start
searching for a full signature spanning
match and that asset gives us some
starting points and a starting point is
somewhat of a misleading term because
it's actually a pair of points one in
the signature and one in the target
program you can see that in the big big
picture at the bottom asset we start
with the signature and the target
program try to find some starting points
and the second part of that picture is
actually done on this slide so now we do
have these starting points and what we
then do is some what we call in the
paper bastid broadening and it just
means that we explore the neighborhood
around these two already matched blocks
and broaden the match with the next best
candidate we can find so I try to
explain it with the picture at the
bottom on the left you always see the
source program the bug signature on the
right you see the target program and big
black arrow represents that two basic
blocks are already matched now at first
only the starting point Paris matched
and what I should mention next is that
the similarity in that picture is
represented by the number of edges so
the more similar the number of edges is
the more similar the basic blocks in
that example should be so as you can
maybe see there's two triangular blocks
in the immediate neighborhood of the
already matched block and that is the
next best mesh so we fix that one and in
the picture in the middle we get that
next big black arrow and we do that
incrementally until we have got a full
signature spanning match in the target
program this bassett broadening is a
greedy method but it's locally optimal
so with all the neighboring nodes we
have we actually look for a arm for a
full matching that spans all of them and
try to find the optimum of that at each
local point there we go so next we did
some sanity checks and what we did was
we try to match functions now a big big
big disclaimer function matching is not
our basic use case a set we want some
sub function granularity but for that
you have to come up with some sub
function or signatures and we really
don't have an automated way to do that
so the only way to convince you that
it's not our clever choice of a
signature that makes the match work is
well just to use the whole function so
please keep that in mind function
machine is not our full use case we did
not optimized for that and actually
there would be some very simple
improvements to increase alarm function
matching or scorn so to say and a set
our framework supports x86 and mips an
arm so it's quite natural that you can
compare x86 code to x86 code which would
be armed comparing code for multiple
architectures but it actually turns out
that we can do a little bit more we can
compare a code similarity from x86 to
let say nips so we can do it cross cpr
cpu architecture and it still works
pretty well it also works reasonably
well for different compilers or
different optimization levels and as you
might imagine the less similar the code
gets the moralists transformed like by
let's say switching the OS switching the
compiler switch in the optimization
level or switching the cpu architecture
the less simulate will be so naturally
the quality decreases somewhat but it
doesn't decrease as much as you maybe
will think and it doesn't decrease as
much as to make the whole technique
pointless well on the bottom you can see
a little bit of that cross architecture
matching where we plotted the rank of
the true positive in like the ranking we
computed before we
the sound up differences of the best
match we had we just sort them by the
similarity basically and on the same
architecture and even on cross
architecture we can achieve pretty good
matching rates at that point on the
bottom right you can well maybe not see
but retrace with what i'm going to say
our experiments regarding different
compiler optimization levels we took
three compilers compile a piece of code
with four different optimization levels
and the darker a pixel is the batter the
match is and you can probably see that
four different compilers the old zero
optimization level looks pretty similar
working on the same compiler works a bit
a little bit better than switching it
GCC on GCC works still pretty reasonable
and stuff like that all in that one to
the picture none of that we've done the
sanity stuff let's go back to back
finding not that that's not sane or
anything but so we go back to it so
these are just some examples we have a
few more in the paper but first of all
um we took our the openssl the heartbeat
in famous one and try to find it cross
architecture so you let me remind you
again you show us the piece of buggy
code in an x86 binary and we are able to
find it in an arm binary or even in the
mips router firmware as you can see on
the bottom left where we always search
from arm to another architecture or from
mips to another architecture x86 didn't
fit on the slide as you may or may not
know there's actually too vulnerable
functions to heartbleed vulnerable
functions at least there may be more
other vulnerabilities and open SSL and
those are the cases for TLS and dtls we
use both both of them as signatures and
so we also get like 22 matches to match
rankings for the two vulnerable
functions and as you can see in the
table they are ranked pretty much
perfectly even across architectures we
also like did us the same examples on
busybox vulnerabilities and on the
circum back door which we found in
closed source router firmware which is
pretty cool but the question that
remains is since all
our algorithms do is give you a ranking
ranked by similarity whether most
similar matches are at the very top even
if you find a pretty good match like the
similarity of values of pre far apart
from the next base hit is it actually a
true positive and the set answer is we
can't tell because all we do is find
some local similarity to find out if the
piece of code is actually vulnerable you
have to do a lot more than that you have
to find out how to get to that position
and how to fulfill all the necessary
preconditions that the path conditions
to get to that point and to actually
trigger the vulnerability we can do that
at that point and let me give you a nice
example for that it's patch code a lot
of patch code is actually just a piece
of vulnerable code surrounded by a guard
statement and the guard statement
basically says the path condition can
never be mad but still a localized code
similarity metric that finds this piece
in the middle as being similar is
perfectly fine right that's its purpose
still this back can never be vulnerable
which is a little bit problematic but a
sad for that special case of patch code
um I try to make a little improvement to
that you can just give them that you
already know that the code can be patch
and that you know the patch use two
signatures so you once try to find a
match for the patch signature and if the
functioning question is more similar to
the patched back signature than to the
unpatch one it's likely that it's also
patched if it's the other way around
well you're in luck maybe you find a
vulnerability but that is something that
is really up for an expert to decide
it's just a hint in the right direction
at this point you go so arm in summary
um we work on binaries no source code
also moves required we have a very
fine-grained a sub function granularity
code similarity metric and by using that
code similarity metric with the bug
signature as input we can actually use
that for back search and maybe the
coolest thing which is why it's at the
top we can do so across architectures so
from X
62 maps of from x86 or MIPS or arm to
any of the other architectures that
still works reasonably well so in the
end we come up with cross architecture
back search in binary software and that
concludes my talk and I'd be delighted
to answer all your questions Thanks
doesn't have to be about this I'll
answer hey Alex am from Qualcomm so it
seems like sort of your work you have to
have a bug that you're looking for so
it's a targeted match have you looked at
sort of more open-ended basically then
diff kind of a thing here are two
binaries you know in different
architecture shown me similarities
between the asset function etching is
not our thing which is what Ben if
usually does and we really try to focus
on box we already know about but which
aren't fixed yet so we try to forget
about all the new ones who don't know
about yet it would be cool to have those
that we know about actually fixed our
back extrapolation capabilities are
unfortunately less good than what you
can achieve in source code so we are
more likely to find actually this the
same bug in another situation then
actually find a different box so the
same thanks you're welcome hi oh this is
fish from UCSB and I think your work is
very interesting and the thing that is
you can you can arm compare functions
across architectures are pretty
promising one thing I want to ask is
that forearm especially forearm they
have a lot of like conditional operation
operations basically means like a lot of
the instructions are conditional like
they sometimes there are executed
sometimes are not based on context and
our experiment we see actually a lot of
those on but I mean arm you see you see
many more basic blocks and other
architectures because because of those
conditional condition operations and how
are you going to deal with that if you
are comparing
them like based on basic blocks and
another question is that oh I'm sorry
another concern is that I think a rather
paper and then you talk about how to
pick on the range of the values for
sampling and is from minus one thousand
two one thousand is there any special
meanings of that and if not what what is
a good way to pick the arm sampling
ranges for relatives thank you okay I'll
start with the second question which
concerns the range of the values we put
into it um we experimented a little bit
about it we wanted to get like a pretty
dance field so we didn't want to have a
lot of sparse values in it but apart
from that we simply chose the number and
went with it and acid worked reasonably
well we kept it that's basically if
there's no special meaning to it to the
first answer we actually found out that
MIPS has by far the most basic blocks
and that actually x86 and arm are more
similar than x86 to MIPS or arm to move
Scott so if you ever asked yourself as
arm is still the risk environment most
likely not concerning the conditional
instructions on arm we can just sample
so we can see a sampling value as an
input to that binary condition so if you
just sample it a little bit that
conditionality will reflect in the
output values I hope that answers your
questions awesome thanks welcome hey I'm
yawn from UC Santa Barbara um from your
paper I gather that part of your
accuracy drop aside from compiler
optimizations so forth is the cross
architecture part yeah and did you look
into maybe grabbing samples of different
source code for example compiling it for
different architectures and doing an
inner architecture bug search just just
single architecture but since you have
so I'll give you a partial answer and
then ask it to rephrase what what came
after that because um so in all our
experiments except the one for different
optimization levels we actually took
code we found in the wild as it is I
don't know what compiler so they used
right if they happen to use a similar
one
the better for us but I really don't
know we haven't checked that that given
please answer please refresh a question
regarding the inner architecture thing I
didn't quite get that so yes if you look
at code in the wild and you look at MIPS
router code right and you know some is
vulnerable and then you look at other
MIPS routers to check against them right
instead of looking for arm routers
because there's plenty of you know arm
code to check on code against ok yeah so
I guess the question is do you feel that
the cross architecture part is needed or
so in theory what let's say you have the
source code right and you have it for
usually compiled for x86 and you want to
see if that specific back in the source
code is also in some MIPS road or
whatever code right what you could do is
just compile the source code to myths
and then check mips to get snips but you
don't always have the sauce go do you so
that simply doesn't work cool