hello everybody my name is Brian Pardo
and this is joint work with my
colleagues at Microsoft Research along
with two interns who joined us from the
University of Virginia so in our work we
consider scenario where Alice is a
scientist and unfortunately she hasn't
been very lucky with her grants and so
she can't afford the cluster for dreams
and instead she's going to outsource her
research to the cloud and get a response
back from the cloud based on that
response she might send the computation
and run it with some new data hoping to
get a new answer of course from Alice's
perspective it's very important to know
whether the clouds doing what she asked
it to or if it's doing something a
little bit simpler and probably cheaper
from the clouds perspective even from
the perspective of an non-malicious
provider we like to think that places
like Azure and Amazon are not in fact
malicious it can be desirable to be able
to prove that you did the correct
computation both to instill confidence
in your customers and potentially to
help shed liability so if a customer is
upset with the outputs he's getting from
the cloud it'd be nice to be able to
prove that those outputs came from the
inputs that he provided and not a
mistake on the providers part so to
formalize this setting we define a
notion of verifiable computation
protocols and what this means is that
Alice can take the function that she
wants to outsource and convert it into a
pair of keys a public evaluation key and
a public verification key she can then
send the input that she wants to compute
on to the cloud and the worker can
compute the correct answer and use the
public evaluation key to produce a proof
that this particular output is the
correct answer for the input that was
provided this proof is publicly
verifiable so you can think of it like a
digital signature except that it covers
the entire computation not just a
message and so we can send this proof
along with the output back to Alice and
she can use the public verification key
to check this is indeed the correct
output of course the key challenge here
is that we want the verification to be
cheaper than computing the function
itself or we haven't won a whole lot
from outsourcing now we can add a flavor
of zero knowledge to this entire setup
and here it's better to think of the
cloud as say another scientist and this
scientist has access to a private
database and he's willing to let Alice
compute over it but he doesn't want to
give her a direct access to that
database and so Alice can provide her
input to Bob and Bob can compute a
function both of his input and Alice's
input and he can send backup
that convinces Alice that the
computation was done correctly even
though Alice learns nothing about Bob's
input and so this has been a very
exciting area to work in lately when I
first started working in this area in
2007 if you took a state of the art
protocol and used it to verify a
computation it could take upwards of 72
trillion years to verify a computation
that would take about 15 milliseconds
locally fortunately we've seen dramatic
improvements in the area both for myself
and from many others in the community to
the point where two years ago at this
conference we presented the Pinocchio
protocol where we're finally able to
break past the point where verification
was cheaper than doing the computation
yourself and overall this represented a
fall and twenty three orders of
magnitude in the course cost of
verifying these computations and since
then there's been a ton of great work in
this area there's been work on
optimizing the Pinocchio protocol for
various operations on adding to the X
precipitate of the protocol as well as
using it for various applications
including Bitcoin and you'll hear about
a couple of these later in this session
however if you look back at the worker
and look at how much effort it takes to
produce one of these proofs there we've
seen a fall of 18 orders of magnitude
which is great and in many areas of
computer scientist science you could
just say all right we're done
but unfortunately here we're still four
to six orders of magnitude slower than
the original computation so you're doing
a ton of work to produce this proof way
above and beyond what you did to produce
the answer and so with Geppetto we've
tried to look at ways in which we can
reduce the cost of generating the proof
as well as increasing the flexibility of
the prover for various classes of
computation so we've developed a new
encoding we call multi cue APs to enable
computations over shared state we've
optimized the notion of bounded
bootstrapping for proofs about proofs
and I'll talk a minute in a minute about
why that's useful and finally we've
brought the cost of generating the proof
closer to the cost of the actual runtime
through something we call energy saving
circuits and to support this new
versatility we've built a new compiler
architecture that scales higher and
enables more flexibility than previous
compilers so to give you a little bit of
background before going into the details
the Pinocchio system took the C code
that you wanted to outsource to the
remote
cloud and compiled it to an intermediate
representation look like a circuit that
circuit was then compiled to an encoding
we call a multi queue API sorry that we
call a quadratic arithmetic program or
QAP and that encoding is designed to
lend itself to very efficient
cryptographic protocols such as the key
generation proof generation and
verification algorithms I told you about
earlier and so the important thing for
this talk is that the cost of generating
the proof as well as the key size grows
in proportion to this intermediate
circuit representation so that's where
we're going to focus our optimization
efforts so let's look at how pinocchio
would compile a stateful computation
such as a loop that's updating its state
on every iteration so the first thing we
would do is compile the body of the loop
to a circuit but then we would repeat
that body four more times as we unroll
the loop and so this is going to create
a very large circuit representation and
hence lead to a large evaluation key and
that's not going to be very performant
so how could we do better well we could
compile just the body and compile that
directly into an evaluation key but then
how do we produce a proof
well the worker can take the input that
the client provided and feed it through
the circuit to get some intermediate
state we can then take that intermediate
state and feed it through a circuit
again to get a new intermediate state
and of course we can repeat this over
and over and over again until we finally
get the output that the client was
expecting but that raises the question
of how does the client check that we did
this correctly well we obviously have to
send her the input and output but to
make sure that all of that state was
correctly routed from one output to the
next input we have to send all that back
to her as well and all of a sudden she's
not quite as efficient as she used to be
and we see a similar problem if you look
at sort of MapReduce style operations so
we have a whole lot of mappers that are
in a fetus set of reducers and in theory
we could turn all this into one giant
evaluation key representing the entire
computation but that's going to be
extremely inefficient instead we'd like
to produce an evaluation key that just
represents one map operation and
similarly one key that represents the
reduce operation but if you look at how
the computation proceeds we're gonna
have a whole lot of input data the
mappers are gonna produce a whole lot of
intermediate state before producing the
final output and we really don't want to
send all that back to the client to
check that the computations were done
correctly so with Geppetto we address
this in two ways first we generalized
the encoding scheme that we're using to
create
we call a multi QAP and we use that to
generalize the cryptographic protocols
to create a commit and prove scheme so
to give you a little bit more detail
about what that means we're still going
to have the same key generation
algorithm that we did before but now the
prover can commit to a series of inputs
and create a constant size commitment
representing a large set of data that
you can then use that commitment along
with other commitments to generate a
proof that the values that those
commitments correspond to are a correct
evaluation of the function and so
essentially the prover can commit to
different values and use those
commitments and many different proofs
and thereby save effort on computations
that share state across instantly
instantiations and similarly the
verifier can verify commitment once
check that it's correct and then verify
many proofs that make use of that
commitment so to go back to our
MapReduce example instead of sending all
this data back to the client the client
can specify all the inputs based on
commitments that she pre computes
similarly the worker as he's producing
this intermediate state can produce
commitments to those values and that's
all we're gonna send back to the client
so she's going to get a small collection
of commitments and she'll get a set of
proofs showing that those commitments
were used properly in the computations
and why is this a win well the
commitments are constant size regardless
of the data so only 256 bytes regardless
of how big the data is and the size of
the proofs is constant regardless of how
complex the computation it is and so
Alice is only going to receive a small
set of data that's easy to easy to
handle so to look at the impact this has
on performance we can compare against a
system from last year's SOS P called
pantry where they were also trying to
handle stateful MapReduce computations
however they were doing it by doing
hashing verified hashing at the
application layer rather than changing
the underlying cryptographic routines as
you can see how long it takes to
generate proofs for various benchmark
applications and the high order bit is
that Gepetto's improving by one two
three orders of magnitude on how long it
takes to generate these proofs now if we
look back at how much work Alice has to
do now for each of these commitments
that she receives she needs to verify
that the commitment is correct and then
for each of the proof she also has to
verify that those are correct given
those commitments
now this isn't too much work but it's
still a little bit less attractive than
the original Pinocchio protocol where
Alice only receives a single constant
size proof and did a constant amount of
work on that proof
so how can we get back to that world
well if we look at all this code that
she's gonna run to do the verification
we can think of that as one one big C
program and we can run Geppetto on it
again and generate a new evaluation key
for that verification step and we can
outsource that operation as well and
then we can similarly turn all these
commitments and proofs into a single
commitment and proof to the larger set
of data and so now Alice's back into a
world where she only looks at one
commitment and one proof to check the
entire computation was done correctly so
essentially if you look at our pipeline
what we've done is add a layer of
recursion so that we can run this
process over and over again
unfortunately if you do this naively the
time to take to verify a single
commitment or proof can take we're
upwards of five CPU days and so that's
not going to be great from a from from
the prover standpoint so how can we do
better
well in a paper last year at Krypto
Ben's the song at all developed a very
nice set of elliptic curve technology
that allowed them to do unbounded
recursion in this style so they can do
proofs about proofs about proofs sort of
ad infinitum and they also use this for
a general CPU interpreter so they can
support a very general class of
computations
unfortunately this led to fairly slow
performance so if you look at sort of a
standard benchmark application it can
take upwards of 29 years to run on this
framework so with Gepetto we explored a
different option we looked at different
elliptic curves that give better
performance but require a fixed bound a
head of time so you have to commit ahead
of time so how many proofs about proofs
you're going to do and we also choose a
approach based on compilation so you
have to specify the function that you
want to verify and we're going to
compile key specific to that function in
exchange however we get a result that
we're able to do these proofs about
proofs much more efficiently overall
we've improved by up to five orders of
magnitude for for some of these
computations and finally we looked at
how we can do better for various
programming constructs that show up
regularly how can we encode them in a
more efficient manner in particular if
you look at how a standard compiler like
Pinocchio or a lot of the compilers and
the secure multi-party computation
literature work if you have an if-else
branch you compile a circuit
representing the if portion you compile
a circuit representing else portion and
then you add a multiplexer at the end to
decide which of the two sets of values
are going to continue to the rest of the
circuit unfortunately if you look at how
this is
used in the cryptographic protocol
essentially we're going to do a giant
multi exponentiation where some of the
values are coming from the if branch and
some of the values are coming from the
else branch and so regardless of which
branch we take we're going to end up
doing cryptographic work for both
branches and so that seems rather
unattractive what we realized was that
if we instead move the multiplexer to
the inputs we can ensure that in the
branch that's not taken in this case the
else branch all the values are driven to
zero and so when we go to do the
exponentiation and the cryptographic
work all those go to zero and so it's
very easy to do those exponents and so
essentially now the computational work
for the PRU root to generate the proof
is proportional to the branch that we
actually take rather than all possible
branches if you look at the impact this
has if you look at the standard way of
compiling say we compile ahead of time
expecting to do five maintenance five
iterations of a loop and in practice we
only do one wellyou're the standard
approach you're still going to do effort
proportional to all five whereas with
the energy saving approach if we compile
for five but we end up only doing one we
do work that's much closer to the
computation we would have done if we'd
known ahead of time that we're only
going to do one iteration and so to
support all this flexibility that
Geppetto now offers we developed a new
compiler infrastructure so we designed
it to be a streaming architecture so we
skip the intermediate state entirely and
go directly to the multi cue IP
representation and from there onto the
crypto this allows us to scale better
and to make better use of the memory
resources that are available on the
platform on the front end we've
developed an a new fronting based on
clang and LLVM for consuming C code and
that allows us to take advantage of a
lot of the great optimization work
that's being done in that community on
the cryptographic side we use a single
symbolic interpretation engine to run
through the program and when we're
generating keys we have a very precise
range and semantics tracking for all the
unknown values that occur during key
generation and that allows us to create
the smallest most efficient keys
possible then when it comes time for
proof we use the same engine but we
instantiate the values in the program
with concrete values and use those to
generate the commitments and proofs and
finally from the perspective of the
verifier this integrates very nicely
with your existing code and so all you
have to do is label the function that
you want outsource and it behaves sort
of like an RPC your program can execute
reaches that point the values are out
sourced they come back the underlying
machinery checks it all the computation
was done correctly and then passes those
values back into your program which can
continue executing as normally and so
all together thanks to these
improvements Geppetto is able to scale
up to programs 40 times larger than
previous works such as Pinocchio was
able to handle so as we add all of this
complexity to the compiler it becomes
more and more important to look at
certification other words being able to
prove that the cryptographic material
that we're generating actually respects
the semantics of the original program
that we started with and that we haven't
made a mistake during the compilation
process we've also started looking at
various applications such as x.509
certificate validation as well as
electronic voting so just to summarize
with Geppetto we've been able to reduce
the cost of shared state computations
such as MapReduce and loops by up one to
three orders of magnitude we've been
able to reduce the cost of bootstrap
proofs by up to five orders of magnitude
and we're able to align proof or cost
with the actual runtime execution rather
than worst of case execution through
these energy saving circuits and all
this is supported by a new compiler
infrastructure that increases the scale
and flexibility of what we can support
so thank you
okay how how much does it cost to
generate the keys in the first place as
compared to like if Alice couldn't run
the cures cancer predicate could she
generate the keys necessary to run the
cancer predicates sure so the the cost
to generate the keys generally scales
proportionally to one execution of the
program and so you do need to be able to
have some computational to get that to
get that started
though interestingly there's a talk
later in the session on how you can
distribute that work and have multiple
people involved in the key generation
positions be applied independently of
each other like can you take advantage
of the energy-saving circuits without
needing to use bootstrapping or other
permutations yeah indeed all of these
are sort of independent optimizations
they happen to play nicely with each
other so when you're doing bootstrapping
you have several independent
computations like you're doing the same
verification algorithm to many different
proofs so that's nice and also with a
fixed bounded bootstrapping you have to
commit in advance - how many proofs you
want to verify mmm so having the energy
saving it's kind of nice if you wind up
verifying fewer proofs but yeah each one
can be applied sort of independently any
other questions so when are we gonna get
an S okay paper explaining all of that
it seems like the space of optimizations
is so complicated here now and like
Andrew was saying some you know it seems
like most of them play well together so
when are we gonna have the grand paper
explaining sort of all the points
someday when I find the right entry I
guess alright
yeah let's think Brian