hi I'm David kohlbrenner this is work
with Mark and risco Keaton Maori run G
Jolla Soren learner and Hohokam my
advisor all at UC San Diego and we're
gonna be talking about floating point
and side channels so not caches so
that's cash we've been talking a lot
about caches you've seen a lot of cache
attacks but we're gonna talk about a
slightly different part of your
processor today a little bit less
understood the floating-point unit of
your processor so let's run code on our
floating-point unit we have two programs
here both of them perform the same
multiplication a hundred million times
except one of them multiplies 1.0 times
1.0 and one of them multiplies 1.0 times
a rather suspiciously small value and if
we just run these two programs in user
land on linux and we time them using
unix time we said that one of them runs
in point two seconds the other one runs
in point four point three seconds which
is over twenty times slower so that's a
little bit disturbing who knew that if I
wrote these two programs they would run
20 times slower well numerical analysts
knew this and CPU designers obviously
had to build this game engine authors
have great blogs detailing how to avoid
this behavior but I would argue that a
lot of us didn't know it and we probably
should have because we all read what
every computer scientist should know
about floating-point arithmetic which
was written in 1991 and and as a kind of
an example here one of the systems that
we examined and we were able to find a
floating-point side channel in the
authors stated that they quote claims to
effectively closed all known remote
remotely exploitable channels
specifically referring to timing side
channels and we have a functional timing
side channel attack against their system
so let's learn a little bit about
floating-point and timing because
obviously they run rather strangely well
what just happened in the code I showed
you well there's this I Triple E
standard which was standardized in the
late 80s there's these subnormal
floating-point values let's actually
look at them for a second here so
there's these sub normal values but
first we're gonna talk about normal
values this is an I Triple E 754 64-bit
double via 52 bits of significand you
have an exponent you have a sign bit
this value that it represents is here
one thing to note is there's a bias
value applied to the exponent and this
lets you represent values a lot easier
and a normal value the exponent those
eleven bits are non all zero so you set
something there and this specifies then
that you have an implicit leading one
bit on your significant
now the adroitly standard also specifies
a sub normal floating point number and
these are an optional part of the
standard but most c or most CPUs
implement them and in the sub normal
case your exponent is all zero bits and
you have an implicit leading 0 bit on
your significant now if you're doing the
math you're going to say that is an
incredibly small number and yes it's an
incredibly small number this is your
range and I've included the plunk length
there for scale now why would you want
numbers that are so incredibly tiny and
these are just doubles well one thing is
it greatly extends the representable
range of floating-point values you've
got a much larger range of representable
values and kind of getting back to our
goldberg we have a graceful underflow
problem here if I were to perform this
check and math with integer arithmetic
you would agree with me that a minus B
is never going to be 0 and we would
never divide by 0
but with floating point this is not true
because we can end up with a situation
where we have values that are too close
to each other with sub normal values
enabled you are guaranteed that no
matter what a and B are you will never
result with zero in this case so there's
a kind of a safety and correctness
property that's that's nice to have here
so what happened let's get back to that
so we have these sub normal values I
just kind of explain to you though that
they're not the common case and the FPU
that you have the floating-point unit is
designed purely for speed that's your
goal so most of the time they're just
gonna kind of pretend that they don't
matter and there they end up being a
hardware slow path on all processors
today they're your commodity processors
notably for example as kind of a
motivation here the Alpha traps to
kernel every single time it results it
got a sub normal as the result of a
computation and that's a machine that
wanted to be cranked and also most GPUs
don't support
values some newer ones there's some
differences but the majority of them
will simply treat them as zero if they
encounter them now I'd like to argue
that floating point is a security issue
for several reasons but this is not the
first time the floating point has been
misunderstood there's a fantastic piece
of work by Ilya Morano on laplacian
noise generation there was a system that
was attempting to join to generate
uniform random noise and rather than end
up with a beautiful probability curve
that like you would expect they used a
naive way of generating this noise and
they got this Bowser's Castle of
probability distributions which I don't
need to explain to you before you'll
know that that's probably not what you
expected and there's also kind of this
issue of dependable results when you use
floating-point arithmetic recompiling
your program can result in not only
different running times but different
values out of your computations and this
is especially noticeable if you start
doing things like changing optimization
flags so they run in different amounts
of time how do we leverage this into an
attack we're gonna need to get two
timing attacks and not even even talked
about them yet
so on a timing attack you want something
that operates on secret data and
attacker data and you want it to have
some sort of difference so we've seen
instruction traces we see memory access
patterns caste utilization IO
utilization etc this work presents the
first practical instruction database
timing side-channel so our attacks have
identical code paths identical memory
access identical Oh IO access the only
difference is the value that's
represented in our floating-point
registers and this was proposed by coach
or twenty years ago in the original work
on floating-point but there hasn't been
anything since so this is some kind of
random data from from our paper on
unloading point on the top we have a
core i7 processor and on the bottom we
have an atom Intel processor and the
blue is SSE instructions these implement
your I Triple E 754 standard and on the
other side we have our orange which is
the x87 unit now you might not have been
aware of this but you're a cop in your
processor actually has to in
highly independent non compatible and
non-conforming floating-point stacks and
your compiler is deciding which of these
to use and you're going to get different
results from them so we have add and
division for SSE and we we have add and
multiply for x87 here and these are all
normalized graphs to how long
add normal value plus normal value takes
so on the i7 as you can see we have some
variation division where the
normalizable is nasty the x87 is worse
on both of these than the atom is
notably kind of all over the place
so these are just for normal and sub
normal but there's actually a wide
variety of timing differences with
special cases like zeros and ones and
extra large values and that sort of
thing and you can see the paper for
details on that
so these as I said though are our cycle
count differences so when I say that you
know oh this one's like twice as long
I'm talking about seven cycles versus
fourteen CPU cycles which on a loaded
system is gonna be a little bit
difficult to spot and if we go back to
that code I showed you at the very
beginning we're gonna need a way to
amplify this timing difference and I did
that in the sample code I just ran the
math one hundred million times so we
want code if we're going to use this as
a side channel as a timing side channel
we want a code that runs tight math
loops over a repetitive data so that we
can amplify our attack which means we
need to now take a detour I've been down
in the low level talking to you about FP
use I don't need to talk to you about
something that we can attack
specifically I'm going to talk to you
about Firefox and to do that I'm going
to talk about Firefox SVG filters and
summarize a previous attack that used
Firefox SVG filters because ours looks
pretty similar so what's a Firefox SVG
filter well if I fox SVG filter is a CSS
thing that lets you turn this a I framed
copy of Wikipedia into this which is a
blurred iframes copy of Wikipedia this
is very valuable as we all know it does
actually let you do other things and
then that you can apply it really to
pretty much any Dom element that you
would like notably iframes in this case
and you can run over a variety of
different functions you can run your
blurs your excuse gradients clipping etc
and very importantly these are stackable
filters so I can apply ten of these
filters in a row compose
and get back out a different result so
I'm gonna go over now a kind of a high
level version of pulse tones pixel
perfect timing attacks with html5 this
was an attack on Firefox privacy that
used SVG filters the purpose of it was
that an attacker webpage could I frame a
victim web page and then read pixel data
out of that web page effectively
violating the same-origin policy so
that's what we have right here we have a
attacker web page that is eye framing a
target web page we're gonna pick out
some pixel we're just gonna highlight it
as read let's pretend pixels are black
and white for now and we're going to
expand this pixel and we're gonna do
this with some filters we're going to
use some divs a couple of kind of silly
CSS elements and you're going to end up
with a div that contains that target
pixel as many times as you would like
and then in the Paul stone case we're
going to run an SVG filter over this
we're going to run he runs the FE
morphology filter over this and you
obtain the filtered rending rendering of
that div which we immediately throw away
because you don't care about it but you
time the rendering of that and you can
use JavaScript to do this you can use
JavaScript you can set callbacks for
animation frame timing and you can get a
high performance timing counters out and
you time this and in the the FeO
morphology case there was a fast path in
the code for the filter if it found an
image that looked very similar across
all of itself
the code ran quicker than in other cases
and this is actually an excerpt from
that specific code so there was this
fast path optimization and by utilizing
this fast path opposite optimization the
attack was able to read out pixel data
now the fix for this was to write
constant time code which is something
that should scare everyone and it took
around two years to land the patch for
this for various reasons there's an
enormous bug thread I highly recommend
reading it it's very interesting a lot
to say about Mozilla and and kind of it
boiled down to to them trying to
implement a couple key parts as constant
time things in C++ okay so I'm I'm gonna
now shift us back to the present let's
remember that we have our sub normal
floating point we have this SVP attack
and really firefox SVG filters weren't
fixed right the filters were just
written to be constant time but we still
get to compute over foreign in pixel
data and I have a brand new timing side
channel source for you but I told you
that well and I guess it should be no
surprise at this point but SVG filters
run floating point math so this looks
really good for us but I still need I
still need an amplifier remember cuz I
ran my code 100 million times thankfully
10 seconds ago I showed you an amplifier
which is that I take a target pixel and
I'm able to expand it to be as many
pixels as I want and then run a filter
over it so that's exactly what I'm
looking for now this is a simplified
version of the the convolution filter in
Firefox which is what we use to
implement our attack so this is run over
every pixel in the target div that
you're running it over and it's gonna
take a swatch of nearby pixels and it's
going to multiply it against a kernel
the kernel is what is controlled by the
attacker and then it's going to sum up
the result of that multiplication and
set that to the new pixel value so the
sorts patch in this case is the unknown
data of some sort and we as the attacker
I've set the kernel to be some
suspiciously small floating-point values
and so there's gonna be two kind of sets
of math that occur the first is this
multiplication and let's pretend that
our pixel data czar just one or zero for
this case you're either going to be
multiplying 1 times the subnormal value
a bunch of times or you're gonna be
multiplying 0 times a subnormal a bunch
of times now this does actually turn out
to have a timing difference but we don't
care about it very much what we care
about is that this fills temp up with
either sub normal values or zeros
because then at the bottom we're gonna
sum everything up and summing sub normal
plus sub normal versus 0 plus 0 is an
enormous timing side-channel and we do
this as many times as we want because we
simply expand our pixel as big as we
need in our case 200 by 200 pixels and
we're able to time the running of this
and we get out about a 20 millisecond on
most machines difference and that's
measured from JavaScript with a browser
running and all of the usual Gmail open
so this is again we're doing this attack
it's the same thing we just kind of
switched out the filter and switched out
the timing and it's all based on data
now rather than
on code paths so this is a not real time
but why would you want to do this well
maybe you want to read some internal
websites that you can't access
internally on an intranet and you'd like
to read some pixels from that web page
Firefox currently doesn't consider
running SVG filters over foreign pixels
a violation of the same-origin policy
and I think between Paul stones work and
ours that really should change here
cores or CSP or one of these standards
should be applied and computing over
foreign pixels just really should not be
allowed well what can you do with this
I'm not gonna talk a whole lot about
this but reading pixels is a little bit
boring if you're reading from other
origins you can do things like
reconstruct characters or other pages
lets you read user names and logins and
anything that you can I frame they can
read so you can't read Facebook but it
doesn't matter a little bit more subtly
though we can read pixels from our own
origin so there's an attack called
history sniffing which if you haven't
heard of it the idea is that in history
sniffing you read the link color on a
webpage so you as the attacker page make
a link to some other page and you're not
supposed to be able to read the link
color of that because that would tell
you whether or not the user has been
there before but we can just read the
link color of our own links using this
attack and then we know whether the user
has been there ok so how do I avoid
problems with floating point I've just
told you that it's kind of a disaster
there's a lot of timing problems and the
answer is don't use floating point if
you're writing security critical code
and the phrase timing side-channel has
ever occurred to anyone in development I
suggest not using floating point there's
undo predictable results you have these
enormous timing variations I don't even
show you all of the graphs for that and
it turns out to be extraordinarily
processor and build dependent you also
get a fingerprint out of it if you need
non integer math for some reason we
suggest using fixed point which entirely
coincidentally brings me to the final
contribution of our paper which is Lib F
TFP which is a fixed time fixed point
math library it's a sea library that
implements most math functions that you
would care about AD by transcendentals
etc it's variable width when you compile
the library you can decide how you want
to split up your fractional and integer
bits it's 64 bit it requires 2 bits for
flags and
probably constant time well I say
probably constant time we tried really
hard techniques we used no
data-dependent jumps this means avoiding
things like double ampersand it means
using a lot of preprocessor macros you
can't use instructions like div you get
to re-implement division yourself you
can't have look-up tables do the caching
and memory accesses but we can't be 100%
sure of the the constant nosov our code
and this is where I'd really love to
talk to Intel some more because they're
totally unwilling to release information
about the data dependency timing and
honestly the timing in general of many
of their instructions and we can't
exhaustively test this so our library
uses things that we think are constant
time and we spent a long time testing
but we can't be sure of it and really
any time you write constant time code in
this kind of a case you're battling
against every future processor and every
future compiler that your users are ever
going to use so here are some some brief
statistics on on Libya left EFP
comparing to us two hardware which is
the SSE column isn't exactly fair
because we're a software implementation
and comparing us to M PFR which is a
infinite precision representation in
software is also a little bit unfair
because we're fixed precision and we use
we use various approximations but we
feel that if you really need some fixed
point math you need non integer math
that Lib FTO P is worth checking out and
we'd love to talk to people who are
interested using it so takeaways here um
if you're writing security critical code
again I want to reiterate this don't use
floating-point if you can avoid it just
it's there's a lot of pitfalls there
there's a lot of problems and we all
haven't read Goldberg's paper writing
provably constant time code turned out
to be extraordinarily difficult I
recommend reading our paper for some
background on some of the things we had
to go through and again Intel some help
here would be great
and lastly browsers should really be
requiring cores or CSP for computing
over foreign data like pixels at this
point I think that's kind of a foregone
conclusion
so future work at Firefox light-attack I
showed you it doesn't work any more the
attacks stopped working on version 27
not because of an intentional patch to
fix it but because they switched to the
GPU and at that time GPUs did
support subnormal floating-point however
nvidia engineers have stated that they
do now supports a mobile floating-point
and great for us there's a slowdown on
computing subnormal floating-point but
only in some cases and we have not been
able to adapt the attack to that
additionally we only looked at
floating-point there's obviously a tons
of integer arithmetic instructions and
we would love to look at what we can
break with those because we know that a
large number of them are not constant
time and are used in real libraries with
that I'd love to take questions you can
email me there or contact any others and
Lib FTF P is available on github right
now so go for it questions no thanks
this is a great fascinating talk coming
from the usability of security viewpoint
one of the last things you said is okay
we have this lib fixed point yes all
these things but division actually is
variable time so if you we are not
including that if you need it just write
yourself division is in our library I
meant that we had to reimplementation
second we had to re-implement division
we couldn't use division instruction oh
you have implemented oh yeah we have
sorry if you are writing is you have to
rebuild it so you went in depth on this
one attack with pixels a bit of you guys
explored other places where you might
yes so we do have another attack we have
an attack on a differentially private
database which I didn't talk about right
in here today I'll talk about
differential privacy but we recommend
looking at that as well it's an
interesting attack um unfortunately
there aren't actually a huge number of
applications for floating-point because
there's not that many things that do
large amounts of floating-point
computation if people have other things
that do use floating point math that
they've spotted we recommend looking to
see whether this type of attack applies
all right oh one more question all right
Ruby Lee from Princeton I'm sorry to
this book disappointing overview but
most of hardware performance
optimization is based on a fast path in
a slow path if you think about it it's
really no easy way to optimize
performance except making the frequent
path fast and the infrequent path slow
so there's all over the place in
Hardware performance optimization is
feature so the issue is is extremely
easy for hardware vendors to make
constant time operations the question is
how much performance are you willing to
to suffer
for this and so one new line of research
that I've been trying to promote is to
do Hardware optimization through
randomization rather than this approach
of frequent operation fast and
infrequent operation slow ok so if there
are randomization security experts in
the room we would very much like to
develop this new theory of hardware
design that is completely different from
before but we if we're gonna use
randomization for Hardware optimization
it must not sacrifice performance and we
think that's entirely doable so please
do do you want to finish that off with a
question or no I wanted to make that
comment because I think there's no other
way to prevent a side channel covert
channel with any kind of power or
performance optimization I think so
there have been a number of processors
that I unfortunately cannot remember off
the top of my head that have allowed the
user to disable certain fast path
optimizations and just drop to constant
slow path and I think that for some
cases this would be actually pretty
valuable and again for example if the
Intel would you be willing to commit to
certain things being saying like for
example if you multiply a 32 by a 32
it's gonna be constant time that would
be really great for a lot of these
things all right all right well what
we're out of time so let's take it
offline sounds like a fascinating and
longer discussion than we have time for
did you run in the cloud we did not run
it in the cloud but we ran it on a very
loaded system
well with that why don't we thank all of
the speakers recession