thank you for the introduction and
welcome to my talk this is a joint work
with maverick
and David Bromley today I'm going to
talk about my research about mutational
fuzzy mutational fuzzing is an effective
software testing technique for finding
security browsing cost software such as
follows we often call this technique as
blackbox mutation or fuzzing because we
consider the program as the black box
which means we do not look at the
internals of the program the way it
works is to iteratively run this program
with a series of different inputs and
observe the outputs and if the program
crashes then we know that the
corresponding input is buggy input we
say mutational fuzzing because we
generate test inputs by mutating as
given C which is typically a
well-structured
input as we can imagine the
effectiveness effectiveness of fuzzing
largely depends on how we generate those
test inputs because some inputs may
trigger lots of software bugs whereas
some other bugs may not therefore in
this project our goal is to generate
test inputs from seed in such a way that
maximizes the number of bugs found for a
given limited resources for example one
of our previous works in this line of
research showed that selecting good
seeds matters by selecting a good seed
we can generate good set of test inputs
therefore that that triggers a lots of
software bugs and similarly selecting a
good mutation strategy also matters
given the same seed different mutation
strategies will result in different sets
of test inputs therefore it is a common
practice for mutation of others to
employ various different mutation
strategies based on their own heuristics
for example a FL which is the
state-of-the-art mutational fuzzer uses
20 different mutation strategies BFF and
these of which are also very popular
mutation or fuzzers they employ their
own mutation strategies however when you
if you notice that all these different
mutation officers use the exact same
common
pip strategy from Biff flipping the bit
flipping based mutations
is very simple yet popular technique the
idea is to take a seed and generate test
inputs by flipping several bit positions
from the seed although it looks very
simple it is surprisingly effective in
practice and therefore it is used by
many practical fuzzers as I mentioned
however there is one issue in using this
particular strategy namely we need to
know how many bit positions from from
the seed to foot this is important
because we will get totally different
sets of test inputs by flipping
different numbers of bits of the seed in
fact several mutational fuzzers even
employ an additional parameter called
mutation ratio to control this
particular number so in this in this
case the question becomes which mutation
ratio should we use to generate test
inputs there are several of previous
approaches to tackle this challenge the
first approach is to try several
different mutation ratios first to learn
which ratio works best but as you can
imagine this approach requires lots of
unnecessary trials and the selection of
different mutation ratios to try is
based on arbitrary decision the second
approach is to use a single mutation
ratio regardless of the program and the
test which may work for some programs
but this is not a general approach
because good mutation ratios differ for
different programs in this project we
propose a novel approach that tackles
both of these problems by directly
inferring a good mutation ratio for a
given program and a seat therefore our
approach does not require any learning
process and it is program adaptive at a
high level our system called sim first
arrives a mutation ratio from a white
box analysis and we use this mutation
ratio to run classic black box mutation
or fuzzing to find box so the key
challenge here is to infer a good
mutation ratio our from the white box
analysis in our system we perform
a three step approach to tackle this
challenge the first step is to construct
a formula representing the fuzzing
efficiency which is the probability of
seeing crashing impacts we start from
the following observation crashing
inputs derived from the same seed share
some common patterns the suppose we're
giving a PNG file as a seed
since synthesis is a well-structured
input this file consists of several data
fields as as you can see here and we're
going to use a red rectangle here to
represent a bit position that is flicked
from the seed and by flipping several B
positions of the seed we can generate
test inputs as follows and and out of
those four test cases that we generated
we assumed that only two of them are
crashing inputs and from these test
inputs we observed the following
patterns first the - crashing inputs
have the same flipped positions in fact
there is only one common the position
that is flipped in both crashing impacts
and if you look at the third test case
that we generated we can regenerate this
input by flipping just one Vectis which
means this particular bit position is
really critical to find out crashing
input however when you look at the last
test case that we generated this input
also has exactly the same flipped bit
position but this input does not crash
the program the reason is because there
are other with positions that must not
be flipped to trigger the crash for
example in this particular case we flip
a bit from the magic value of the PNG
and and since we modify the magic value
of the PNG file no matter what value you
have in this input this input will be
rejected from the program because the
program will think that this is not a
valid PNG file from these observations
we notice that there are two kinds of
critical bit positions there are bit
positions that must be flipped in order
to trigger the crash which we call
minimum buggy bits at and we use small B
to denote the cardinality of the size
the second kinds is the bits that must
not be flit and we are going to use
small e to denote the number of bits
that must not be flipped and since both
be bits and a bits are critical to
trigger the crash we are going to define
the number of crash critical bits D
which is essentially P plus e we also
use an to denote a total number of bit
positions of the seat and use R to
denote the mutation ratio and in our
model our mutation of buzzer will
generate test inputs by flipping and
times our different positions from the C
now using all these previous definitions
and model we can now define the fuzzing
efficiency which is the probability of
seeing crashing inputs from mutational
fuzzy
in fact this probability follows a
classic multivariate hypergeometric
distribution which essentially represent
the number of attainable crashing inputs
divided by the number of all possible
taste test cases now that we formulated
the fuzzing efficiency we need to
perform the second step which is to
represent an optimal mutation ratio with
respect to B and D in fact we can
achieve this by modeling the problem
with NLP non linear programming problem
where the goal is to maximize the
fuzzing efficiency subject to some
reality constraints and by solving this
NLP problem we can derive the following
formula representing an optimal mutation
ratio R with respect to B T and N and
since n is known from the seed we only
need to estimate the value of B and D
unfortunately though the values of B and
D are not known prior to fuzzing because
there are specific to a bug in a
specific program so we need to somehow
estimate these values from the program
under test which is the last step of our
approach we want to estimate these
values to infer a good mutation ratio
for a given program and a seat recall
from the previous example I showed you
that there are two
kinds of critical bit positions there
are bits that must be flipped and there
are bits that must not be flipped we
notice that there is a certain
relationship between these two kinds of
bits if we let the two kinds of bits as
x and y respectively then we know that
there must be a control flow that tracks
the value of x as follows and depending
on the values of x the program should
either crash or not and since the value
of Y also affects the program crash here
there must be another conditional that
checks the value of y we typically say
the second conditional statement here is
control dependent on the first
conditional statement and we and we
generalize this notion of control
dependence to represent the dependence
relationship between input bit positions
in this example X is dependent on the
position Y because the value of y
determines whether the value of x will
be read in the second condition we call
such a relationship as input bit
dependence and we formally define this
concept in our paper we can compute
input bit dependence of a program
execution using our white box analysis
as follows first we instrument a program
execution and for every program
expression in the execution we compute a
set of relevant input bits and finally
for every conditional branch that we
encounter during the execution we
statically expand a control flow graph
to compute the dependence between the
input bit positions input bit dependence
allows us to compute the number of
critical bits D of any bit aniseed which
led us to define the average value of
the over all possible subsets of input
bits and we are going to denote it as d
bar
and notice here that we can compute this
average d bar without even knowing the
actual minimum doggett bit sets so in
this paper we use the following
heuristics that estimates the value of
the
with the multiplication of average
average D bar and B this heuristic
assumes the value of D linearly depends
on the value of B and this allows us to
simplify the formula as follows and
therefore all we need to do here is to
compute the D bar from our white box
analysis and estimate a good mutation
ratio for a given program and a seat to
evaluate our system we obtained 8/8
applications from our one of our
previous works and we fuzz these
applications for 8,000 hours of CPU time
more specifically we use thousand
different mutation ratios ranging from
0.001 to 1 to collect grant ground check
ground truth data and in this paper we
report the number of bugs found after
triaging crashes with our technique
called safe stock cache which is similar
to the heuristic based on stack cache
technique for more details please refer
to our paper the collected ground truth
for the program ABC MTPs looks as
follows the ax axis here is thousand
different mutation ratios and y axis
here is the number of number of bugs
found for each different mutation ratio
and you can see that there is a clear
trend for fuzzing efficiency depending
on the value of mutation ratio so the
first question that we want to answer is
how close our mutation ratios obtained
from senses compared to empirically
optimal mutation ratios so these graphs
show the comparison the dashed line here
indicate the ratios derived from
synthesis and the blue lines here show
the ground truth for each of different
programs as you can see the prediction
and the empirical was close and this is
also the case for other programs and we
also observe the similar trend in this
case as a result the average difference
between ratios obtained by
sym first and empirical of the mole
ratio was just 0.017 now we're going to
compare our system against BFF and ziza
which are famous mutational fuzzers we
ran fuzzing for one hour each of the
programs and computed the number of bugs
found the red bar here represents sim
fuss and as you can see it prevails
other fuzzers in most cases in total
symphysis find 3 7.2 percent more bugs
than BFF and 55.3% more bugs than Ziza
finally we also applied our technique to
AFL again AFL is the state of the art
mutational fuzzer
and in order to do this experiment we
replaced bit flipping based mutation
algorithm of AFL with our own algorithm
with our synthesis all our own algorithm
and ran both original AFL and modified
al AFL for for 24 hours first we tested
the code coverage difference between
between the two so the red line here
shows represent the modified AFL and the
blue line shows the coverage code
coverage for unmodified AFF and as you
can see the code coverage of our
modified AFL was was improved compared
to the original AFL the second
comparison that we performed is the
number of bugs found for both cases and
as a result modified AFL found 18.5%
more balls than original AFL and we
conclude that our technique and also
improve the state-of-the-art mutation of
others there are many more details that
I could not discuss duties of time limit
so please refer to our paper if you are
interested and finally we also open our
source code to boost future researchers
so please refer to our paper for more
details
in conclusion we showed that selecting a
good mutation ratio is crucial and
mutational fussing and as a result we
devised an algorithm to leverage a white
box analysis to estimate a good
parameter which is mutation ratio for
black box mutation or fussing with that
thank you very much and I'm happy to
so thanks a kill we have time for a
couple questions hello Julia Vanek from
Bloomberg um I wonder if you try to
combine you work with tormented
exploitation my work with Oh automated
exploitation for example whether you you
know how many bugs you found were
actually exploitable how many were not
haunted references etc that's a very
good question so the question was can
the I apply our automatic explosive
generation technique for along with this
line of work actually we did not try it
but it's a very good idea and this is
going to be a very interesting future
work I think yes hi I'm Jonas from epfl
and there's one thing I didn't
understand it and it's you seem to kind
of throw away a lot of the data that you
find in that you identify all these bits
that the father should not change and
then you say okay Allah we don't use
that data we just like count the bits
but what would happen if you actually
sort of prevented the father from
changing all these data dependent bits
and only like so I think the question is
why why don't we try to find a specific
position of of a seed that we want to
modify and we don't want to modify yes
exactly right so I mean that's a very
very interesting question and it's a
very interesting direction as well and
actually if you think about it if you
think about grammar based buzzing
usually people came up with a template
that says hey we want to fast this
particular part and just the type of
this is integer and this is a string and
so on and so forth so automatically
finding those kind of template is also
very interesting research and
potentially we can extend this work to
handle this case but we currently we do
not handle that case our model only
consider the bits flipping based
mutation strategy okay thank you yeah
so juan caballero from in there so what
institute so following on that that you
just answer right I mean so very suit
years of research saying mutational
fasten it just doesn't get get deep
enough into the programs right so which
propose things like grammar based
fashion right and that's actually widely
used right we have things I can call it
fashion but here you're only comparing
light to the basic rotational fashion
that doesn't seem like a very fair
comparison tone sure so well you can say
that you know grammar based is grammar
based buzzing can find more deep bugs
than you know bit bit flipping based
fuzzy but actually if you look at the
the box the crashes that we found
actually we tried all you know regular
file parsers like you know mp3 file gif
file which doesn't make sense that you
know we have without grammar based
buzzing and by just flipping has some
bit positions how can you find crashes
but actually that's what happened in our
dataset and applying this technique to
you know more different data set or
large data set is going to be our future
work right what is not clear there is
that you are actually fast in any
program that has already been like
significantly fast right see you get a
new program you're always gonna find
bugs but the question is like whether
you get a program and the has already
been applied with other techniques and
something like mutational fashion is
still gonna be able to find bugs that
were them found before by other
techniques so I mean it's not clear that
the programs that you actually have in
your data set they've already been fast
with other non mutational
techniques right so that would actually
be very good you're actually able to
find that you can't find new bugs with a
simple technique on programs that
actually you've apply more complex the
next then that would definitely
demonstrate it but this programs is not
clear doc has been done I guess
okay so your cash
it's not so you're saying it's not clear
whether this program is representative
is that what you're asking right in some
sense yes
okay so sure so this program is actually
as I said we obtained this set of
programs from what from one of our
previous our work and the reason why we
selected this program is because we know
that we can crush this program and we
can collect the ground truth data and
that was a main reason why we chose this
program and for that for that reason we
actually opened our source code and data
set for further research so people can
you know use our data set and code to
apply this technique for other programs
as well okay thank you thanks uncle
again