yes my name is Henry Corrigan Gibbs and
I'm going to talk about some work I've
been doing it Stanford with Dan Binet
and David Morris about a system called
riposte which is an anonymous messaging
system handling millions of users so the
setting that we normally talk about when
we're talking about cryptographic
protocols is one in which we have Alice
and we have Bob and Alice has some
secret messages she wants to get to Bob
over an insecure Network and the way
that we usually do this is we have Bob
generated public and a private key for
some public key encryption system and
then he gets his public key to Alice
somehow Alice then just encrypts her
message with Bob's public key and sends
it over the network and the security
property that we usually demand of such
a scheme is that if there's an adversary
listening in on the connection between
Alice and Bob the adversary doesn't
learn anything useful about what alice
is saying so with encryption we can
actually do a very good job of hiding
the data hiding Alice's payload but I'm
gonna ask the question does that really
hide enough does that hide everything
that Alice wants to keep secret so in
particular if you look at what the
adversary learns by listening in on
Alice's network connection for a period
of time you see that the adversary can
build up the sort of table so he learns
who else is talking to the size of her
packets and the timings of those packets
and this doesn't necessarily look so bad
until you swap out one of these fake
names with the name of a real
organization so for example tax fraud at
Stanford that you'd use the email
address were supposed to contact if we
suspect there's some tax fraud going on
in our academic department so in this
case just by virtue of seeing that Alice
is communicating with tax fraud at
stanford.edu the adversary has learned
something very interesting about Alice's
message even though he doesn't get to
see her payload so the point here is
really that hiding the data is necessary
to get the sort of privacy that you want
but in many cases it's not sufficient
because this metadata leaks a lot of
information about what you're saying so
the goal of the system called or posts
that we've built is to allow a large
group of users to get together and I'll
call this the set of users the anonymity
set they run some protocol and at the
end of the protocol everyone has posted
a message to some public bulletin board
and the key security property is that no
one has no one knows who has said what
so there's sort of a non anonymity in
terms of what you're posting to this
this bulletin board so in practice we'll
implement the bulletin
with a set of servers and we'll make
some non-inclusion assumptions about
about the servers but I'll come back to
that later and basically the way it
works is that every user in the internet
MIDI set comes online over the course of
a day and interacts with the server's
somehow so exchanges some messages with
the servers and so by the end of the day
every user has come online
and then the servers once they've
gathered all these messages from all the
users can add up their shares of what
they've collected over the course of the
day and recover everyone's plaintext
messages so again the key security
property here is that the database
servers don't learn who wrote which
message so the set of users is public
the set of messages that comes out at
the end of the day is public but we're
hiding the association between users and
messages so that we keep secret who said
what this sort of protocol turns out to
be really useful for building systems
all sorts of systems related to hiding
the metadata so you can think of
anonymous Twitter is a direct
application of this anonymous survey
platforms private point-to-point
messaging systems systems that allow you
to sort of leak information to a news
organization and so on all can use this
as a building block or a primitive and
riposte is not the only way to do this
there's other systems you come to mind
when you think of this sort of messaging
so the first class are low latency
anonymity systems like tor which are
very good for browsing the internet
anonymously by design though they don't
protect against an adversary that sees
the whole network so they're just not
designed to protect against that sort of
adversary and if you are interested in
protecting against an adversary that
sees the whole network you shouldn't use
those systems so mixed nuts are another
way you could you could think of
achieving this but typically mixed
systems require pretty expensive zero
knowledge proof to protect against
certain sorts of active attacks by the
mixed servers and as the number of users
grows the complexity and cost of these
proofs grow too and it large scales
they're not so not so practical so
riposte is an anonymous messaging system
that tries to sort of solve both of
these problems at once so we're trying
to protect protect against an adversary
that sees the whole network that also
controls some of the servers and that
controls many of the clients so this is
a very strong adversary but we want to
handle millions or
users for this sort of anonymous Twitter
application so we really want to scale
to network sizes that are close to
internet scale even though we're still
defending against an adversary that's
quite strong so that's the rough
motivation for this work I'm now going
to talk about a straw man construction
our first attempt construction that
should give you a little bit of
intuition for how we build this and then
I'll go over a couple of the technical
challenges that we had to solve to make
this work before explaining how how it
works in practice
so the straw man scheme is is relatively
straightforward we're going to have two
servers server X and server Y and I'm
gonna make the assumption for now that
they don't collude and we can this
weekend this assumption later but really
these two servers are holding a shares
of the state of the bulletin board so
that the bulletin board starts out at
the beginning of the day of with all
zeros and you can think of this also as
like a database like these two servers
are holding shares of a database and the
users as they're posting to the bulletin
board are really writing into the
database without leaking to the servers
where they're writing so how does this
work
Alice comes online and she has some
message that she wants to write into the
database without leaking where she's
writing so she has some message to say
she wants to write it into the third
slot here what she'll do is she'll stick
her message into a big vector of all
zeros and this vector is going to be as
large as the databases so it's a big
vector and she generates a big vector of
random blinding values again as large as
the databases and then she just takes
the difference of these two vectors and
sends one vector to each server
okay now the server's having received
these vectors just add them into their
state and then do the same thing with
another user so some other user Bob
comes online he does the same thing
sends his vectors up to the servers and
they update their state so now at the
end of the day the two servers can come
together add up their shares of this
database state and what comes out is a
vector of all zeros except with Alice's
message at Row 3 and Bob's at row 5 so
we sort of accomplished what we wanted
to at least up to a first approximation
so why is this not sufficient well well
let me explain first what this does
achieve which is that you get
information through a theoretic
anonymity as long as the two servers
don't collude so as long as the two
servers don't don't share their
information with each other there's
secret information you get very strong
anonymity properties and you can
actually we can this assumption by
adding more servers so if you use K
servers you can get protection against K
minus 1 servers that collude the other
neat thing about this construction is
there's almost no heavy computation
involved this is just X ORS over over
strings and one other nice feature that
we take advantage of is that unlike a
mixed net the storage cost here is
constant in the size of the a nativity
set so the storage cost that the
server's is really proportional to the
size of the Bolton border the size of
the database which actually can be much
smaller than the anonymity set size if
you're working in application where
there's many more readers and writers
so like Twitter or WikiLeaks or
something like this but but we're not
quite done there's a bunch of reasons
why that the first scheme doesn't work
so here are a couple I'm not going to
talk about all of these but so the first
the first problem is if two users write
into the same row of the database
they'll corrupt corrupt that row so they
won't get you know neither message will
get through so we need to do with that
we need to deal with malicious clients
who send malformed vectors to the
servers to try to corrupt the state of
the database and we need to worry about
the bandwidth cost and the cost between
the servers and the clients so for the
first two things I'm just going to point
you to the paper we have solutions for
both of these problems and if you're
interested in how that works you can
check it out I'm gonna focus on the
third one just just to give you a taste
of this sort of problem that we had to
solve so the challenge sort of the core
challenges this issue of bandwidth
efficiency in the in the first attempt
solution I described each client needs
to send a database size vector to each
of the servers just to make a single
write request so if the database is
millions or billions of rows long that
means to write a single message you have
to send gigabytes of data to each of the
servers and if you have millions of
users this is not going to work so what
we do is we we use a cryptographic trick
to compress the vectors so instead of
sending database size vectors you send
much shorter vectors and these are this
this trick is based on private
information retrieval protocols so if
you've seen them before private
information retrieval protocols allow
you to read privately from a database
we're basically turning them on their
head so using them using a private
information retrieval protocol to write
into a database and really we can use
some of the same tools and take
advantage of the very nice literature on
private
formation retrieval to work on this very
different problem which is anonymous
communication so the the core the core
sort of cryptographic primitive we use
is called the distributed point function
to achieve this and these are also used
in private information retrieval
protocols so if you haven't seen them
before this is how they work there's a
key generation routine that takes in a
message and I'll enter Durell which is
like an index into a vector and it spits
out a bunch of keys so k1 up to KN and
you can think of these as like
short-short keys for a pseudo-random
number generator and the second
algorithm associated with the DPF is a
very much like a pseudo-random number
generator and that it takes a key and
stretches it out into a very big vector
but there's a couple special properties
of these algorithms the first of which
is that if you add up all the resulting
vectors you get a vector of all zeros
except with an M in location L so these
vectors have some very special structure
but even more than that if you look at
the keys if an adversary say gets ahold
of some subset of the keys she can't
learn anything about M or L so the keys
in some way hide the message m in the
location L unless you see all the keys
so how does this how can we take
advantage of this tool to reduce the
bandwidth between the clients and the
server's the basic idea is is to do this
so Alice now instead of generating two
big database size vectors to send to the
servers she just generates two DPF keys
then she just sends one DPF key to each
of the servers the servers on their own
can use this eval routine to stretch out
these short keys into very large vectors
again the size of the database and then
they add this vector into their state as
before and from there on the whole
protocol runs runs exactly as the
earlier scheme I showed and it turns out
that you can actually construct DPF that
have very nice both security property
properties and efficiency properties so
prior work has shown that you can you
can construct EPF where the key size is
like the square root of the length of
the database so if the database is
gigabytes long your DPF keys are going
to be something like kilobytes even
better than that though
the to server version of this protocol
just needs to use AES so there's no
public key crypto
in generating or evaluating the DPF keys
which turns out to be a huge performance
advantage but then if you want if you
want protection against many of the
supers colluding so you want a DPF
scheme with K keys such that if K minus
one of them get leaked to the adversary
we can build those too so we show a
construction using public key primitives
that is still efficient in terms of
space in terms of the key size but of
course since it's using you know
elliptic curve operations instead of X
doors it's going to be it's going to be
slower so the last thing I'd like to do
is just talk a little bit about the
evaluation results what what what this
looks like when you try to implement it
so we actually implemented the whole
thing and go we implemented the to super
version and the multiple server version
and the bottom-line results is that for
a database with something like 65,000
tweet length rows we can process 30
writes per second on a single server so
putting that in another in another way
we can process about a million writes
and eight hours on a single server and
this workload is completely
parallelizable and the reason for that
is just because what the server's are
doing is they're taking these DPF keys
stretching them out to the size of the
database and then adding them into their
state and you can do that operation in
parallel on as many cores as you have at
the same time so if you want to you know
triple these performance numbers you
just add add three servers is an easy
way to do that and to give you some
intuition on on why we get the numbers
that we do this is just a chart of how
the throughput in terms of the client
requests that a single server can handle
for a second varies with the size of the
database table so on the Left when the
database table size is very very small
you're basically limited by how fast the
server's can set up to us connections
with the clients and then as the
database table size gets huge the
servers are just spending all their time
doing AES to expand these DPF keys into
long vectors and at that point basically
the the dominating cost there is just
how fast the server can do AAS
operations so so to sort of come back to
where we started in the world we live in
today is one in which if there's an
adversary listening in on your network
connection the adversary not only sees
who you're talking to but how much
you're saying and when you're saying it
and with this sort of system we'd like
to move to a world in which if there's
an adversary listening in on your
network connection the adversary just
sees that you're talking to a riposte
server and you're saying fixed-length
things and the adversary doesn't really
learn much about what you're saying
right because it just learns that you're
talking to a riposte so I've tried to
argue that hiding the metadata is at
least in many contexts just as important
as hiding the data itself hiding the
payload and with the system called
repost we've shown that a combination of
cryptographic tools and systems design
principles can can let you create these
million user anonymity sets which I
should point out is something like two
orders of magnitude larger than you can
do with prior prior work that has the
same security properties and and of
course the next step is to try to make
this thing even faster handle even
larger messages with an even larger
number of users yep with that I'd like
to take your questions
yep we have about five minutes for
questions so so fascinating stuff I'm a
specific question about the fact that so
you mentioned you're writing into
database
how about Orem instead of PIR for that
could you say that one more time
Oh Rama Oh Ram yeah ah so the trick
about ORM is that you need to keep State
on the client typically so here we have
many clients that are not interacting
with each other so there's an issue of
how what do you do about the client
State and so one thing you could think
to do is to store the the client state
in the database but the problem there is
now you have to worry about malicious
clients so if a malicious client
corrupts the state of the database that
could cause some later users requests to
leak information say about where that
user is writing so at least we looked at
over m and we were not able to figure
out a way to do it more efficiently
where we'd have the property that both
the clients don't need to coordinate and
we can tolerate malicious clients that
might try to corrupt the state of the
database or caused an honest client to
do something incorrect by corrupting the
state
so even assuming honest clients if I'm
gonna send a message I need to wait
until a few other people also send
messages right before the anonymity is
secured the concern that I have is that
there there might be a bias because if
I'm sending you a message it is quite
likely that the responding person will
like the the responding set from the
anonymity set or the responding subset
from the anonymity set will include you
and therefore if the if the anonymity
said is not particularly active at this
particular point in time the unanimity
said will comprise of the people I have
instigated into an active state by
sending them a message right so you're
saying if the enemy said changes over
time for example you can use the fact
that it's changed to sort of intersect
intersect and enemy sets and figure out
or make some guesses about who's saying
what it seems that I mean it seems that
I'm inherently causing a bias in the in
the anomaly set by causing certain
people to be more active by sending them
a message and expecting a response so
say that this is sort of a private
messaging right and the anonymity right
now so say our servers based in San
Francisco and it's midnight and
everyone's asleep ok so not this unknown
reset is not particularly active at this
point in time I send a message to you
and three other people I am by sending
this message I'm causing a bias in the
anonymity set that which means that you
and the people I've sent the message to
are more likely to be active right now
and send the response yeah I get you so
I think I think the issue is is sort of
about the meta protocol that you design
around this this database that you can
write privately into and as you say it's
very important that you construct that
meta protocol in such a way that you
don't leak leak information by virtue of
the way that works so for example a
protocol that works by I check to see if
there's a message for me and if so I've
responds is not a not going to be a good
protocol to use because that obviously
leaks leaks information about it over
time about who I'm talking to and what
I'm doing so typically the way these
things work is if you really really want
security over time you have to make sure
that everyone is checking the system at
some fixed time interval or you know or
or do something out-of-band
but yeah typically the way the way you
protect against those attacks is making
sure
by making sure that the interview set is
sort of as constant as it possibly can
be
over time thank you oh it's one more
question so you said you want to get
better performance at scale than a
million people but I guess have you
thought about the application of the
anonymous messaging systems on college
campuses that students really like kind
of like yak yak and whisper because
those are usually less than a million
and I actually got like a lot of traffic
with kids writing snarky stuff about
each other and you could disrupt the
market and have you know actually good
security where they all rely on a
trusted server right now it sounds like
a startup idea Joe that's what happens
when you have a to Stanford people
chatting yeah I guess with that let's
think Henry