thank you to 30 months for the
introduction the title of my book is
tiny garble it's a tool for highly
compressed and sequential garble circuit
the main idea behind this tool is to use
the knowledge that we have in hardware
synthesis and hardware design to make
yours garble circuit more and more
practical okay let's look at the
motivation behind this work we want to
solve the problem of secure function
evaluation or sfe in sfe the goal is to
compute a function jointly between two
parties on their private data an example
is the O's millionaires problem where
two millionaires wants to want to
compare their world without letting each
other to know what was their amount of
money do you have in their bank account
there are a couple of solution one of
them is you always garbled circle
solution which seems to be the most
promising one we are focusing on to
party GC protocol or yours garble
circuit protocol let's see how it works
on the same problem of yours new
universe problem the first step is to
make a garble a boolean circuit out of
function f here is comparison so we need
a tree bit comparison here in this
example which is this circuit the next
step Allison needs to make a garbled
circuit which is the randomized and
encryption circuit the same as the
boolean circuit Alice also encrypt all
the truth table in this randomized
circuit and sends them to Bob Bob cannot
open them unless he has the input labels
or inputs randomized wires Alison's hair
inputs to Bob and through a protocol
called oblivious transfer or ot Bob
receives his input so bob has all the
input wires so we can go ahead and open
each of these encrypted truth table to
get the final output after this you can
share it with Alice to find out what was
the actual
to it so the question is can this
protocol be practical can be actually
implemented I use it thanks to lots of
people works in this world it is
practical it has been practical since
2004 for a decade and this is the
chronology of the work on the
implementation of garbled circuit and we
saw that many of this work try to
implement a compiler or library to solve
the problem in the first set of garble
circuit which is making a boolean search
out of a function description and still
there are some shortcoming in this step
for scalability many of these work as a
porous scalability and prevents user
from making a large circuit and some of
them asked user to manually optimize
their circuit suit they don't provide
any automatic tools for them also some
of them use online circuit generation
which doesn't provide any global
optimization for the function because we
don't have the circuit at a time so we
cannot optimize it also its waste of
time of garbling and some of them also
provide high level abstraction which
usually result in inefficient
optimization compared to manual
optimization ok what's your approach we
thought maybe we can use hardware
synthesis tools and techniques that have
been around for half a century and they
are used for the same purpose
translating a function description into
a boolean circuit but for different
objective for actual hardware and actual
device so we want to hack these tools to
make them able to generate an optimized
circuit for GC protocol instead of
actual hardware the next one is all is a
concept in hardware design a sequential
circuit which makes us in able to make
scalable circuit for the complex
functionality ok let's look at all
detailed contribution
the first one is the adaptation of these
a shield synthesis tools for generating
an optimized garbled circuit so we have
an offline circuit generation we don't
do it online also it's automatic user
does that need to do anything also we
create some new custom libraries and
objective to change the up to change the
purpose of these tools to hack them to
get an optimized circuit for DC protocol
instead of optimized circuit for actual
hardware I also we introduce sequential
circuit description for GC it makes us
unable to have a compact circuit
representation and limited memory
footprint during garbling and evaluation
also makes is enabled to use the
knowledge that we have in hardware
design for making function in gobble
circuit for example we provide a
scalable solution for private function
SF e or PFS fe ok based on this idea we
generated tool called tiny garble let's
see how it works this is the global flow
of tiny go a user can start from a high
level description of a function like C
or C++ our tools translated to a
hardware description language or HDL
very log or VHDL or alternatively user
canister from very low provision most of
the hardware design are done in these
languages then the next step is hardware
logic synthesis tools with our objective
and constraint which is hacked for
generating optimized garble circuit its
result in a netlist necklace is
essentially the answer it has all the
gates and it's connection so we want
this necklace be optimized for garbled
circuit the next step is a scheduling
which is a topological sort then we
store it in a portable format so we can
distribute it and use it during garbling
and evaluation so what about the
sequential
circuit what is sequential circuit
usually when we are thinking about
boolean circuiting corbel circuit we are
referring to type of circuit called
combinational circuit in hardware design
combinational circuit in combinational
circuit outputs are only function of
inputs so we have a directed acyclic
graph around inputs to the output there
is no loop while in sequential circuit
outputs are functional inputs and also
state of the circuit which are kept in
some memory elements like a flip flops
so we have a loop here it's not bad
anymore all the hardware design are done
in sequential circuit not the
combinational circuit because if we want
to design a computer holy on a
combinational circuit for a simple task
a computer would be the size of this
room it's not as scalable and also it's
not just unrolling the rupal having this
memory for the loop it can do many
exciting stuff that we cannot think it
think about it with the loops only for
example shift register or a counter if
we mix them together we cannot think it
about think about them as a loop they're
just a memory element for reusing them
later in the circuit okay let's look at
an example and see how it works this is
n bit adder for combinational circuit we
have n minus 1 full adders and one half
adder full adder has a carryin carryout
half adder doesn't have a carry so the
size of this circuit is open while in
sequential circuit we can have only one
full leather and reuse the carrying as a
care as carry out as a carry in for the
next cycle so we need to repeat these
circuit end times or n sequential types
to have the same functionality as a
combinational circuit number of gates is
here is all one we only have one full
adder no matter how arbitrary large n is
the circuit is this so it's very compact
it's a scalable as it's very easier to
optimize if you
want to optimize this the sequential
circuit is much much easier but there is
no free lunch unfortunately there is a
small overhead here if you remember her
father was a little bit simpler than
full adder in sequential circuit we need
to repeat a full adder end time so it
means we are doing the full adder minus
and half adder mode compare the
combinational circuit this is the
because of the asymmetry in the loops of
edition which in the first iteration we
have a half adder the rest is full adder
if you notice I ignore the flip-flop
because we don't need to actually
implement the flip-flop in an abstract
level in the gobble circle flip-flop is
just transferring a label from one wire
to another wiring garble circuit so it
doesn't have any over sequential circuit
makes us in able to solve many exciting
problem for example private function sfe
where a user has a function the other
user has a data I they want to jointly
compute f of X now the current solution
is to reduce this problem to sfe the
normal sofy using a universal circuit a
circuit that gets the circuit as an
input and a data and evaluate the
circuit unfortunately this is not is
scalable the size of this circuit
increases with the size of the function
f so we are looking for an alter a
scalable alternative for the universal
circuit without what about processor
they are implementation of universal
turing machine they receive a function f
as a binary coding their memory the
receiver x as an initial data in their
memory and they write something as an
outlet in your memory and the size of
the processor is independent of size of
f is 0 of 1 we have a laptop with the
limited area and we can do whatever we
want with it doesn't matter what is the
function and the time complex is very
straightforward is all of them which m
is no
of instruction in the function that we
have and the question is how to secure
evaluated with the gobble circuit the
good news is that processor are
sequential circuit if we can support
sequential circuit for global circuit we
can use this processor into garble
circuit and they have you can go ahead
and enter it and download them they have
available compiler so it's very
straightforward to implement them if we
can support sequential circuit okay
let's look at the evaluation at the
first step we want to see the effect of
hi love hardware synthesis tools so we
just compare or combinational circuit
with previous work so we don't have any
sequential circuit the next step is
comparing sequential circuit with what
we generate and also the previous book
we use to matrix the first one is memory
footprint efficiency which is comparison
between total number of gates in two
circuit why we call it memory footprint
because for every gate in a circuit we
have to a store a label during garbling
and evaluation in the memory so if we
can reduce number of gates in a circuit
we are reducing memory footprint of
garbling and evaluation higher MFE is
better mean meaning that the circuit and
the size of circuit is reduced compared
to the reference circuit the next one is
number of garble table that is generated
during garba which is number of non xor
times c which sees number of sequential
cycle for combinational circuits is one
why number of nanak sore this is due to
optimization called free XO that let us
to garble only nanak circuit and Xers
are freeing under this optimization and
it's a very very good estimation of the
a sub garbling and evaluation so we look
at the GT difference in a percentage to
see if the circuit is
optoma is more optimized or less the
most negative GTD means the circuit has
a less number of nanak source we compare
our combinational circuit with PCF PCF
at the time of writing was the best
automatic tools for generating garble
circuit so let's look at GTD compared to
PCF and also MFE for example for
multiplication 64-bit we have nine point
three times a smaller circuit compared
to what PCF can generate also at the
same time this eighty-four percent more
optimized meaning the cost of garbling
is reduced by eighty-four percent just
by using hardware synthesis tools and
hack them to optimize the circuit for
garble circuit ok let's look at
sequential circuit we compare them with
our combination circuit and also PCF
again multiplication 64 we can reduce
the size of circuit by 20 times compared
to a combinational circuit by sequential
circuit and 200 times compared to what
PCF can do so it's much more compact GTD
number of non x you're compared to PCF
is negative eighty percent so the number
of non XOR is reduced by eighty percent
but when we are looking at GTD compared
to our combinational logic we see a
positive number twenty-eight percent
more number of knowledge so this is due
to the overhead of sequential circuit
because multiplication 64 it doesn't
have a symmetric loop so here's the deal
we can use a combinational circuit and
have a very optimized circuit but it's
not scalable we cannot do it for example
for multiplication 1024 it's not
practical we have to make a sequential
circuit to be able to optimize it using
these tools because they are designed to
optimize small circuits for the actual
hardware they are not designed to do
combinational circuit force
huge circuit but still you can see the
GTD the comparison between onyx or is
still better than previous four because
these tools are designer for making
optimized circuit okay in conclusion GC
we look at GC boolean circuit generation
as a typical logic synthesis task where
we change the objective of hardware
synthesis tools for generating an
optimized circuit for garble circuit
meaning reducing number of non exploring
these circuits we also introduce
sequential circuit description which
beside reducing the size of circuit it
makes us an able to do many exciting
circuit that are available in hardware
design for example chain nearest
neighbor using sequential circuit is
pretty easy to think of boiled with
combinational circuit is very hard to
design also a scalable private function
is to be using a processor circuit which
the circuit size is independent of the
number of instruction that we have so we
can see using those knowledge that we
had in the hardware design and hardware
synthesis makes us an able to do many
exciting things for garble circuit thank
you in Christian
thanks for the talk so use you surely
and it said on the slide you have to
have a separate garbling table and
separate wire labels for each time
around oh the thing you said you
actually replace the garble table and
wire labels each time on the same
circuit so we'd only need to store them
in a memory you just replace them
because we don't need them okay so you
you are still generating yeah it's still
the time and everything is saying okay
with sequential circuit you're just
throwing you can yeah just repeating the
circuit and send the garble table for
example to the other user but the thing
is the memory footprint is much smaller
because we know how much why we have in
this circuit right so some previous work
also could figure out that okay I'm
never going to use these wires again and
dump it out of memory yeah but the thing
is here is very simpler we exactly know
before starting to garbling or
evaluation we know exactly how much
memory we have to and we have to
allocate for this circuit because we
have the surface at a time thank you so
I yes one question sir just someone who
doesn't work with these Hardware
synthesis tools it seems like they're
these these magic super powerful tools
people in working on for 40 years yeah
that you put a circuit put logics
description in and get circuits out so
the questions can you you found this
trade-off between the garbling cost and
the the memory footprint could that be
part of the input to the synthesis tools
if you didn't want to you want actually
it doesn't we sweep the number of
folding the circuit or the number of
sequential circuit we need to evaluate a
sequential circuit we sweep it from one
to the maximum and we find out which one
is better actually the number of the
size of the circuit will reduce
definitely and also the number of Nanak
soul will be increased because of the
asymmetry if it doesn't have a
asymmetric in its loop it will be static
so it actually depends on the function
we cannot ask those tools to do it for
us we need to do it manually thank you