so hello good morning everyone
so I'll be presenting we see three
trustworthy light analytics in the cloud
using SGX and this is joint work with
Felix Schuster Cedric moon a Christian
series Marcos panade reason in micros in
of each
silly Felix should be doing the talk but
but he lost his plane so the problem we
are addressing here with this work is
that cloud computing introduces privacy
risks so if a user wants to do cloud
analytics today they prepare some data
and some code then they upload the code
to the cloud the clouds the untrusted
cloud runs the codes over the data
produces some results and the results
are shipped back to the user so what can
go wrong well a lot of things the cloud
may leak confidential data encoded my
temper with the code in the data for
instance privileged cloud operators may
leak the data intruders in the data
centers may also leak the data and we
know that governments may ask for access
to the beta so encrypting data on disk
is obviously not enough for this because
users want to perform general-purpose
computations on the data and fully
homomorphic encryption is great but it's
still inefficient for general-purpose
computation
although partial homomorphic encryption
schemes have been shown to be applicable
to restricted cases so people have
looked at using trusted Hardware to
protect these workloads from from
attacks from the cloud but previous work
doesn't guarantee confidentiality and
integrity for all code and data or it
has a very large tcv in previous systems
don't guarantee integrity of the fool
that distributed data and all these
computations so in vc3 we are addressing
this problem for MapReduce computation
protects MapReduce computations from the
untrusted cloud it ensures
confidentiality of analytics code and
data and we use trusted SGX processors
and compiler enforced invariants to
achieve this we also ensure integrity of
distributed MapReduce computations and
we do this with a small software TCB and
lower
so I'm going to give you a quick
background on MapReduce and Intel SGX
then I'll do an overview of the vc3
design I'll explain some details about
our lightweight protocols and our
compiling enforced invariance and I'll
conclude with some numbers so MapReduce
is this very popular data analytics
programming model and the idea is very
simple if very simple so the users
specify inputs as a set of inputs pool
splits and they write map and reduce
functions the data analytics framework
then runs the map functions in parallel
over the input splits and this can be
very large datasets think terabytes plus
and the map functions output
intermediate key value pairs the system
then does a group by on the keys of the
inter intermediate key value pairs and
calls the reduced functions in in
reducer nodes and the reducer nodes
output results so it's a very simple
programming model but it is very popular
and it is very useful to do data
analytics the other piece of background
is Intel SGX so SGX is a set of
extensions to the Intel instruction set
architecture that Intel has defined and
what is these instructions allowed me to
do is to it they allow a user mode
process to define a region of a virtual
memory and say that that region of
virtual memory is isolated from the rest
of the system and these regions are
called enclaves and SGX supports TPM
like features like sealing sealing and
attestation and it also does encryption
when cache lines are evicted from the
CPU and are written back to RAM and
finally SGX
allows the enclosure to do fast il
through shared memory so the code that
he is running inside of these enclaves
can read and write freely from the full
address space and this can be used to do
fast idea so we are going to secure
these MapReduce data analytics
computations and we are going to use as
Jack's and waves so so at a very high
level what we're going to do is we're
going to encrypt data and code and we're
going to keep that data encodes
cryptid except when it is inside these
SGX enclaves and when it is inside the
enclaves and inside the CPU the data
will be in plaintext and the code will
be in plaintext and it can run
efficiently inside the CPU so is this it
are we done now there are lots of
challenges that we need to address here
to make a practical system that works
for data analytics computations one of
the challenges is how to partition the
system to achieve a small TCB what is
exactly this code that we trust to get
access to the data we would like to keep
that as small as possible the other
challenge is to guarantee integrity of
the whole distributed computation the
CPUs protect these regions inside the
single machine but to build a full
distributed system we are going to be
using many machines and at some point
data needs to come out of these regions
and it is handed over to the operating
system the operating system can do them
many bad things it can corrupt the data
duplicate it drop it and if we don't do
anything we wouldn't be able to
guarantee integrity of the full
computation the final challenge that we
need to address is that the code that is
running inside of these regions my
heavens safe memory accesses and we
would like to prevent leaks due to this
unsafe memory accesses and finally I
will just add as a bonus we would like
to integrate our design with existing
cloud frameworks so that we can easily
deploy this on existing data analytics
frameworks ok so the first challenge is
to partition the system to minimize the
TCB so what we did there was we we we
defined a simple programming model the
traditional MapReduce programming model
and users write code in C++ they write
map and reduce functions we link that
user rate Analytics code with a small
library that includes in our prototype
mathematical and string functions so
this would be typically you know they
turn out six libraries
we encrypt this secret code and we we
bind it to a small amount of public code
that implements our public protocols and
we put all of this in a dll where the
secret code is encrypted so oh this is
going to be the the code that we're
going to trust and give access to the
data and overall we are talking about a
few thousand lines of code so it's it's
a very very small amount of trusted code
outside so this code then has a very
narrow interface with the rest of the
system the code just reads and writes
key value pairs from the rest of the
data analytic system and outside the the
trusted boundary the the code that runs
in the the untrusted area those things
like creating these SGX enclaves talking
with the operating system binding to and
modify the loop installations but all of
that code which is if you include the
operating system and the hypervisor is a
lot of code but all of that code is
untrusted so what we we achieve here
with this design is that the TCB is
essentially the code that we put inside
of this DLL the secret date Analytics
code that the user writes and the
hardware TCB is the SGX processor so the
software tcv is three orders of
magnitude smaller then the operating
system hypervisor and a dupe so we have
this very small TC v so so this is how
we package the code to do the data index
computations then we ship it to the
cloud we then run a key exchange and
remote or at a session protocol to share
secret keys with the code I'll refer you
to the paper due to the paper for
details on that and once the key
exchange protocol completes the code is
ready to run and we can run the data
analytics job so the date and the the
the the our job execution protocol is
going to do the normal sort of data
processing that you'd expect from a
MapReduce job but it's going to do a few
additional things
so the compute nodes are going to output
some secure summaries of the work they
did and the and these secure summaries
are going to be aggregated conceptually
at a verifier node and a verifier now is
going to check the consistency of all of
these summaries and detect any tampering
with the computation and both the key
exchange protocol and the job execution
protocol integrate with and modify that
loop we can run this on and modify the
ado per installations and the the
protocols tolerate filing now straggling
nodes the usual things that you expect
from these data analytics frameworks so
let me give you a little bit of more
details on the job execution protocol so
during the normal data analytics
computation the mappers will be
producing these intermediate key value
pairs to send to the reducers so we
change this and we we have a different
format for this intermediate key value
pairs so in we're going to put the
original key value pair encode it inside
a new key value pair and we encrypt that
with the AES GCM and for the key we're
going to replace the key with a
pseudo-random function over the original
key and in the value we have some extra
information like job identifier and
identify for the mapper a sequence
number to allow reducers to detect
duplicates so this still allows the
system to do the aggregation on the
inter in on the intermediate keys so
that precedes as usual but the user also
writes the tools that user uses write a
job specification that includes the set
of input splits that the job is supposed
to process and the code that is supposed
to process those input splits and this
is sent to logically to this verifier
node and the mappers also sent to the
verifier node information information
such as what input splits were processed
by each mapper how many intermediate key
value pairs were sent from each mapper
to each reducer likewise the reducers
send summaries to the verifier including
what was the set of mappers they
received information
how many key value pairs they received
from each each mapper for instance this
allows the very fired into to answer
these questions did mappers process all
the input data was an input data
duplicated or dropped do the reducers
agree on the set of mappers that process
the data did the reducers process all
the intermediate key value pairs that am
a percent and if the verifier can answer
positively to all of these questions and
it can certify the output of the
computation and in the paper we also
show that the verifier can be modeled as
a normal MapReduce job and can be ran on
the normal MapReduce framework I'll not
hear that our encoding of the
intermediate key value the intermediate
key leaks some information about the
distribution of keys and we don't
address this in this paper but we in
follow follow on work we have addressed
this problem so the the other challenge
that I wanted to address here is that
the disk this data analytics code that
the users right in in C++ may have
low-level coding defects and so if you
have a defect like a right through an
initialized pointer you can easily
corrupt memory or simply leak data by
writing outside of the enclaves and
likewise if you read through an
uninitialized pointer you may be reading
a not authenticated data supplied by an
attacker in the cloud so to deal with
these problems we allow sorry to deal
with these problems we allow users to
optionally use a compiler that enforces
two security invariants so if users are
worried about these problems they
compile the code automatically with with
with our compiler in the end they get
these security guarantees the one of the
guarantees is region what we call region
write integrity which guarantees that
writes true pointers can only go to
a drastic and variables inside the
Enclave or hip allocations in the
enclave and so in this current for
instance guarantees that any right to a
pointer can never corrupt known as s
address taken data inside the Enclave
and can ever write data outside of the
enclaves
so that's the first invariant and the
second one is augmenting region right
integrity with all with the guarantee
that reads cannot go outside the Enclave
so its users can choose not to use any
of these or or either add either one of
them and just to give you an idea of how
we enforce them to check the region
right integrity property we keep a
bitmap that maps every eight bytes of
ankov memory to one bit in the bitmap so
when one means that the memory slot is
writable so this is a compact
representation of the memory protections
inside of the Enclave so if the compiler
cannot check that a rat is safe it's
going to check the bit in the bitmap to
see if it's one and we update the the
bitmap on heap allocations and stack
allocations and deallocations
we also check control flow transitions
to make sure that the the read checks
and the write checks cannot be bypassed
and we use a similar bitmap to check
control flow transition so that is a
form of course control flow inside
integrity that we enforce and finally
the read checks are a simple range check
that we enforce with with a simple bit
mass mid mask and I'm not going to go
into details here but in the paper we
show how we have efficient code
sequences to to implement the checks so
to evaluate this we implemented vc3 for
Windows Server 2012 we tested the
implementation on an emulator provided
by by Intel but because that emulator is
not performance accurate we measured
the properties of the system using our
own emulator and we implemented the
region self integrity properties as a
modification to the microsoft c++
compiler we tested seven seven
applications a mix of i/o intensive and
computer intensive applications and we
run experiments on a Hadoop cluster with
eight workstations so the the graph here
on the slide shows the numbers the
runtime numbers for all of the
applications and the runtimes are
normalized to the case where the
application runs on I do but is not
protected by our mechanisms so what we
see there is that for VC 3 we see over
the sort of device properties of VC 3 we
see overheads below 1% for VC 3 with the
right integrity checks we see over
overheads on average 4.5 percent and
with a read/write integrity of an
average of 8 percent now we whe when
when we ran this on a dupe there are
lots of things that are happening in the
system that mask the real overheads of
this III and these things are scheduling
a dupe jobs
shuffling data around launching
processes those types of things so to
have a better understanding of the
overhead we also ran the map in reduce
tasks in isolation without a dupe so on
a single machine just executing you know
for instance a map function over an
input split in there we see some higher
overheads so for VC 3 we see an average
of 4% for VC 3 3 with region right
integrity an average of 15% and with the
read/write integrity and an average of
about 25% so I'll conclude here inside
that VC 3 protects Map Reduce that
analytics computations from the
untrusted cloud we ensure
confidentiality of code and data for
these applications and we're showing to
ensure integrity of the full distributed
computations and our experimental
results show good performance
so thank you and I'll take questions
thanks a lot Manuel any questions
Rupali Princeton University it's very
interesting I was wondering when you
talk about the TCB and given that the
cloud can migrate virtual machines and
there's a lot of SSL may be involved in
talking to different nodes within the
whole cloud scheduler and you know
network stack protocol and so forth
wouldn't that have to be in the TCP so
so no so we we do rely on all of these
components to run the full system so if
the if the cloud can for instance do
denial of service attacks on our system
by for instance not migrating or
scheduling jobs but those components
they can never they never have access to
the plain text data that we are
processing and and so they can never you
know read or or temper with the data
without being detected and then we would
our integrity protocol which is based on
having the the nodes that have access to
the data producing some summary
information of what they did what they
did they processed for instance those
sort of our integrity protocol then
aggregates all of that information and
verifies that for instance the scheduler
did not temper with the computation a
schedule might for instance strike when
a typical attack would be as the
schedule might for instance not schedule
a map function on us on a particular
input split but we would always detect
it might be clearer to see your threat
model doesn't defend against
availability attacks but it's failsafe
for confidentiality that's exactly right
there's another problem if I kind of
understood your restrictions you can
write from the Enclave outside with your
right restriction or something so then
how do you release the encrypted code
from your Enclave to the outside if you
can't write or we you know you get the
encrypted code into the arm so the that
the item if if we use our compiler
extensions the data analytics code
cannot write outside even by mistake and
that's our sort of our threat model
there that that code is not malicious
but it it may have bugs so you are
writing that code cannot but the our
implementation of the the protocols so I
had this slide with the sort of the data
analytics code in the small amount of
crypto protocols so our implementation
of the the crypto protocols implements
the communication primitives in that
code can write the messages out but that
code first
when writing out first in cribs and when
reading data checks the the
authentication codes on the data that is
coming in from the outside