I'm boy young who a PhD student from
Joseon University China and today it is
a great honor for me here to present our
work slinked a two-way implemented to
automatically verify as a self API usage
in applications by static analysis and a
report in one ear abilities whenever
this verification fails this work is
conducted with the joint lab of Internet
and security technology at Georgia
University and in northwestern
university supervised the pipe advisory
engine and also collaborated with our
alumina injured hall from Columbia
University and professor venkata krishna
from university of illinois of chicago
and as we know SSL and TLS protocol have
become the security backbones of
Internet today as a transport layer
protocol SSL you're a year's TCPS at the
learning protocol and the many
application layer protocols are built on
top of it and the SSL provide an
end-to-end encrypted communication
security over Internet as a result many
software including mobile in excuse me
and desktop applications are protected
by SS of particles and SSL is based on
the model of public key infrastructure
and x509certificate and is designed to
guarantee the confidentiality
authenticity and integrity for
communication against the man in the
middle attacks however recent study
shows that some SSL applications are
still vulnerable to my enemy attacks
because of implementation flaws in many
cases as a library api's are not well
designed so the developers to fail to
understand them correctly and they also
fail to use them correctly so previous
work has already mentioned that this in
cracker usage problem especially in the
server certificate certificate
validation on the client side showing
that that many applications are affected
by this problem and making all of them
vulnerable to many enemy attack so
motivated by this SSL API uses
vulnerabilities we wonder that since SSL
is so important and why they use to how
many such unknown vulnerability that
still there and whether it is possible
to automatically detect such as a
vulnerability in a large scale and in a
more general way with the high
efficiency and accuracy to answer this
question we propose an approach as well
as a tool called slimmed a scalable
static analysis framework which is into
automatically identifying incorrect
usage of SSL ap is in client-side
applications so our work has foramen
contributions and the number one is we
designed a systematic approach to
automatically detect incorrectly use
assess our API usage vulnerabilities and
the second one we implemented SSS linked
a scalable automated a tool to verify
SSL usage in applications the third one
in order to find those other
applications using SSL library ap is as
our candidates with leveraging on the
existing package managers which existing
existing in many linux distributions for
automatically comparison and analysis
and then acquire all the application
target applications with ssl library as
their building dependences in the end we
did a large scale merriment and analyzed
more than 22 million lines of code and
discover 27 previous unknown SSL
vulnerabilities in the software packages
from the ubuntu 1204 and we confirm all
of them and the so far for have being
four have been fixed sorry here comes
the agenda for the rest of my
presentation today we start from some
background knowledge of the SSL
vulnerabilities and show how many in the
media tech had happened and my enemy
turcica happened due to the incorrect
API usage then we present our slink
design and implementation including code
representation we use in a stack nasus
and the signature design
at the end of presentation we gave a
summary of our fundings we start from
some background knowledge sterling how
ssl protocol works and as a transport
layer protocol SSL is built on top of
TCP so after a successful story we TCP
handshake and SSL handshake is
established from the client side and
then the server presented a certificate
for the client to verify and such this
is authentication face for the SSL and
you're related clients a certificate is
optional according to the RFC's so in
fact the one we all syndication is a
common practice in many SSL applications
as shown in this example and after a
successful authentication the keys and
staffers will be exchanged between a
carnist server before the handshake is
down and in the end a secure
communication channel is established and
encrypted application data can be
transferred over this channel as
mentioned earlier SSL is designed to
secure an end to end this channel
between a carnist server to avoid a
man-in-the-middle attacks however it may
still be possible if we still be
vulnerable to such attacks if ssl
protocols are not implemented
incorrectly incorrectly usage of SS
api's make it possible for attackers to
bypass certificate validation and in
this way attackers can easily intercept
on decrypt or tamper all the information
instead ssl channel in other words the
sss completely broken and there is such
attacks so we will present a demo video
of such attacks against the one
vulnerable email app we found at the end
of the presentation in order to show the
details of the vulnerabilities and the
idea of our system design now present a
motivating example from a real
vulnerable app we found this application
use openssl as its SSN implementation
and the first api ssl ctx new as you can
see the first line is called to create a
ssl contacts which is for as the
configuration and then the second one
the ssl new is called to create SSS
session using this context for next
as a handshake is lunch using the SSR
conducted API after all this this
successful its establishment of the
connection the another API SS ok the
very fair result is called here to see
if the certificate validation is
successful and it's terminate the
connection if necessary this is one of
the common practice or corrupt a usage
when developing the and open an app
using the openssl library and we've
referred to as checking after handshake
however opening SSL API is not a well
designed as most of you know we know and
the well-documented so the SSL get a
very fun without the function will still
return a successful flag if no
certificate is presented by the server
so in this way this app is vulnerable to
fix this vulnerable app another epi I
sense they'll get peer certificate it
should be called when checking
certificate validation results so in
this way the app will terminate the
connection with no certificate is
presented by the server so in order to
automatically detect such ssl
vulnerabilities including those shown in
the motive in examples we first model
the correct usage of the API SSL API as
a signatures with under Zen with his
ends linked which takes the source of
the app as input and then transform the
source code into a certain kind of code
representation in a static analyzer and
then match the match the match the
signatures to detect let vulnerabilities
remember that it is a correct logic that
we model so in a signature so the
vulnerabilities will only be reported
whenever the signature measure fails in
order to show the ideas of a signature
design here again we use our motivating
examples this is a fixed version
representing the correct logic of the
open ssab is when buried in a
certificate the model is correct logic
first our signature needs to track the
data flow between all of this AP is so
starting from the ssl ctx new you
can see at the land one on the left here
at all the data flows we need a track
including all the ssl in critical assets
AP is and also there are some if
conditions in this state of law in
addition to this develop the country
flows relates to the ssl api's usage
also needs to be modeled in a signature
for example the ssl read an ssl right
aps which adds the line eight on the
left too many aps used for developer to
send and receive data over as a channel
so these two aps should be called only
after the successful a certificate
validation as a result in this example
we also need to track this country flow
from the two if condition to the ssl
read and as a ride as you can see that
dots the arrow in this flow graph yeah
in our solution we use program
dependence graph as code representation
as well as signature representation in
this way we successfully capture both
the country follow and the data flow in
our signature and here we show our
signature for the openssl AP is and
which is very similar to the flowchart
as shown in the last page and you may
already noticed that there were two
parts in this signature and that's
because the openssl has to correct API
usage when managing the certificate the
one is already shown in our motivating
example as check after the handshake and
the other is the checking during the
handshake which i will not go into the
details because the limited time here
and so we model the correct AP i use
that you for the post cases and if these
are often two parts is matched warning
will be triggered in our system our
slinked implementation has the following
technique challenges the first one is
the given and SSN library we need to
understand the precise conditions for
the correct and the correct usage and
then model them in our signature the
second one is the given a signature we
need to identify a preliminary
conditions to decide if a signature
master match for example in our open SSL
signature shown in the last
the data flow from the SSN new API to
the SSN read or write API it must be
captured before the PDG paste the
signature is matched so the last one
from nan OS dibs distribution we need to
identify that is the selected candidate
apps using SSL libraries and
successfully compile this apps for now
analysis er implement our implementation
slinked ex act as a certificate
validation a vulnerability scanner we
use code suffer with a static analyzer
provided by Crom attack for static
analysis and the generating pd GS and
the slint is implemented in c++ and it
is about to sound and your lines of code
and our signature expression design is
motivated from cipher a graph query
language used in popular graph graph
database name for Jay and we also design
a custom algorithm to perform this
signature matching in our evaluation we
invest in well investigated apps
leveraging on the most popular to SSL
libraries on C++ cns C++ platform the
one is opening exercises guru TRS with
designing signatures for both the
libraries automatically scan over 22
million lines of code and detect a 27
progress unknown vulnerability
vulnerable apps on a 485 Ubuntu Linux
apps we have reported all of our
findings to developers or maintainer and
got 14 confirmations from developers and
so far for have been already fixed our
results shows that the vulnerable apps
from the various categories as you can
see here we have email apps we have web
apps and the even database apps and
tools for administration and performance
testing and these vulnerabilities can
lead to serious consequences such as
privacy leakage and privilege escalation
and make us great trouble for users and
they hear the table are the our
measurement result in detail as you can
see the size of each code for each
vulnerable app is between a few thousand
lines to more than one
hundred thousand our lunch 14 of the
vulnerabilities are either conformed of
fixed by developers for this photos we
have not heard from the maintainers or
developers we successfully launched the
main enemy attacks are all of them so we
confirmed that they are really
vulnerable we refer to this part of job
as dynamic auditing as listed in this
table another thing another interesting
finding we found in our evaluation is
that ubuntu developers are only
responsible for maintaining a small
number of apps in this software
repository the other apps are maintained
by the community the our evaluation we
found that the both the Linux
distributions and the community
developer linux distribution maintenance
and the community developers feel no
application to fix bugs or
vulnerabilities in Linux distributions
so we even found that examples which has
already been got fixed in the community
up streams but it's still vulnerable in
the latest Linux distributions and it is
also true for the other Linux
distributions besides 12 we sing such a
security problem yeah the open-source
software must be soft properly to avoid
more vulnerabilities in the future to
conclude our work we started from the
motivating examples there there a lot of
misuse of the ssl api's in application
and the design and implement is linked a
system to verify the ssl API usage in a
large scale and the way these discovered
27 previous unknown vulnerable
vulnerable in the womanhood software and
most of which are also sharing other
linux distributions and 3 is our first
step to verify API usage based analysis
battle we believe that this approach is
not a strictly in in SSL so currently
we're focusing on the following ongoing
works that and first one we are building
generic system to verify API usage in
application of different programs
languages such as Java Java apps and the
second one we are trying to fix those
filled applications in our analysis due
to the memory explosions and the other
arrows by automatically identifying as a
rather bland code in the application and
only focus on that part of the code to
reduce the workload out our static
analysis
in n I'd like to show to show you a tech
demo video against the one of the
vulnerable email app we found and
meanwhile I'd like to take your
questions and that's in number of my
presentation today thank you thank you
so sorry hello Cammie vanier Indiana
University I'm curious how much of the
signature is you able to create just
from the documentation and how many of
them you then had to later create based
on looking at the examples were finding
so were you able to actually just create
figure out with the correct one it was
upfront or how much did you have to go
back in and create new signatures after
looking examples ok so am I understand
what a question is so how many
signatures do it do it do it made and
yes we made the signatures for kabuki OS
we have actually we have two and we have
openssl actually we have that one and
all of them the front example so some of
them up from the document button you as
you know the open desolation is always
poorly documented so many of them from
the examples from the developers yes oh
sorry from the video 100 seconds ok so
i'm mike from the united states military
academy I just wondered if you had
synthesized any lessons based on looking
at the api's and looking at your results
that you could kind of make some
recommendations and all these api's
could be better I mean I know George
Evan fall and others have shown that
they're bad but anything anything like
opinions on that you'd like to share ok
so I asking me for opinions or okay
first we recommend it all of the
available now to use openssl that's true
that's a really poor design and oh poor
document today that's true and I noticed
that many of the vendors have already
open you can start their own project
down that's libraries so
something like the labor at liberal SSL
or other libraries and I think for now
many developers has known this fact that
the openness are now safe so that's cool
thing I think yeah thank you very much
okay one other question I had did you
have any false positives when you're
running these applications first
positive of course as you don't know I
prepare for slides but this video is not
over so okay it's false positive view of
course because developers can do some
customizations to the openssl libraries
so in that case they can write a
callback functions inside the openssl so
in that way we cannot capture this for
static static analysis by the way and we
i'm pretty sure that we can do that in
data analysis as we have some previous
work has already done that yeah all
right let's thanks billion and all the
other speakers in the session thank you