developed a viet code for federated and
delegated identity several open source
product projects as here's Tom with the
weather on github prior Tom develop
network and security code for companies
including V extreme Microsoft yoli full
security and biometric access okay good
afternoon and I hope everyone had a good
lunch and I hope everybody's in the
right room i'm excited that so many
people showed up because it's kind of
like the wild card session i think i'm
not a security expert or why they hacked
or anything i'm just stabbed a ruby
developer who participates and identity
workshops that are twice a year in the
mountain view and we talk about user
centric identity which is instead of
letting companies dictate what the terms
are with identity systems we focus on
user rights and letting the user keep
control of the data and things like that
so if there's identity work that that
isn't aim for that kind of goal then it
doesn't fit in at identity workshop so
let's get started I'm Tom here's Tom
with the weather is my kind of moniker
and a run-through well be talking about
today I'm gonna kind of start out with
the motivation it's ok I'll speak a
little bit sputtering or maybe actually
over bring this down a bit
there we go that better okay the first
thing we'll do is just talk about the
motivations why do we want to read redo
payments on the web and then to kick us
off I'll do a quick code sample just to
show how easy it is to make a web
payment using OAuth today in dollars so
we'll all actually be moving my money
from a a big bank into my local credit
union using OAuth and then then we'll
take a step back and look at a walk one
versus oauth2 we'll talk about a merging
protocol called open transact which we
did our first draft at the identity
workshop last week and then its
relationship to open ID connect open
transact doesn't require open ID connect
but open ID connect is a very good fit
for it as an extension and then talk
about kind of future things that we're
working on or would like to work on
okay the motivation is articulated
really well in a book called beautiful
security there's a chapter by a dulles
called rethinking ecommerce and he said
you know the way we do payments on the
web today is totally insane why are we
using these shared secret credit card
numbers they're so vulnerable because
you know in the lifetime of a credit
card number it passes through a thousand
people's hands and you know you have no
idea who's got your credit card number
and you know every day you have a
conversation with somebody who had to
you know they got a email from their
bank so you know we have suspicious
activity on your account and it's kind
of a real pain and a lot of my favorite
restaurants only take cash because it's
for compliance they don't want to go
through all the hassle credit cards and
stuff and so credit cards or real pain
in the butt so I'm sure its secrets are
bad and people who are trying to do
business get the wrong in the deal
because the banking darknet imposes
unnecessary responsibilities on them
that they don't really need to do so one
a kind of bright spot of hope and I'm
not affiliated with Dwolla in any way
although they're the first ones that i
saw that support OAuth 44 payments they
my under saying is that they do like a
million dollars of transactions a day
they're very new growing I think half of
their transfers are Bitcoin exchanges so
for as far as their volume in a walk we
have kind of like this mantra that's
emerged somehow to like make it simpler
to digest for newcomers which is there's
two steps that we talked about getting a
token which is the authorization process
and then using a token and in the slide
person dictation it's very heavily
linked ified so all these blue text you
can link to and that these particular
ones are links to dois documentation so
when you actually before I do the Dwolla
thing just kind of like a raise of hands
is there anyone who has no idea what o.o
fizz and and would like me to just go
through an example okay so let's do this
just to get our settings here Twitter
was the company that gave oh off the
credibility it has with OAuth version 1
because they deployed it in 2009 and for
for third-party applications to do kind
of this authentication kind of thing but
lets them use the Twitter API and so for
instances you can see here I've used
other web applications that have asked
me for my Twitter stuff so these are all
the applications that I've trusted and
at any time I can revoke the token that
Twitter gave them when I when I asked
for it so what like one of my favorite
is a the earthquake command line client
for Twitter it's a it's a ruby gem and
so like here it is right here let me see
if I can so that's the beauty of oooff
is that it lets these ecosystems emerge
where if the main website Twitter
website isn't solving a problem then
another third-party application can do
stuff like threaded conversations or in
this case you know if somebody gets
chatty and I don't want to hear from
them anymore I can just say Marcus
exclude you know Charlie Sheen and I'll
no longer get tweets from Charlie Sheen
so that's the beautiful thing about
OAuth is all this new innovation that
occurs around a website
so that to the ebb there's my station so
similarly Dwolla has this authorization
of get a token step as you go through
and and there's this notion of scopes
and oh off and I think it's
unfortunately named term a better term
would be capabilities because scopes
kind of makes you think of only like
read-only access you know is am I
accessing you know Google YouTube vs
google calendar that kind of thing I
think capability is a better term than
scope and especially in banking because
you're doing active stuff like you're
making a payment so when when Dwolla or
any other banking Oh auth application
asks for permissions or you know to get
a token and this would be this would be
a third party application using Dwolla
so this is a third-party application
asking Dualla for these I'll call them
capabilities instead of scopes and you
can see the last one there's send money
and so when it asks for the token it
specifies exactly what scopes or
capabilities so I've already a clio to
token with a send money scope for Dwolla
and so now what I'm going to do is run a
little ruby program to make a payment to
show that it works
this up this set sample code is in that
github link i had at the front that this
presentation is at lap con oo oo oo oo
KU calm and that link to the github
where you can find this sample code okay
and it's a guess I'll just go actually
you know what how's that hey okay that
sounds like we good idea that i'll just
talk about okay um so anyway I think ok
so these are the steps just a document
them that I'm going to do I'm going to
fetch the ruby program I this you know
the first step is get a token this is
the token I got and I'm going to make it
an environment variable so that it's not
gonna go and also just right off of you
okay that's good idea