[Music]
i expected my first address at this
conference
to take place under different
circumstances the kovit 19 pandemics
seems to be affecting everything it's
impressive
that you're able to do it because i mean
everyone is very afraid of taking the
step
but we all know this is very important
and that you can't just do everything
online because
particularly politics foreign policy and
the intellectual world you need to meet
the people you need to exchange ideas
you have to
keep these networks alive even during
the pandemic
to think through what sort of europe is
going to emerge from the pandemic
who we are as europeans what do we
identify as common threats what sort of
common destiny
do we perceive for ourselves since this
crisis is associated
with many other issues this is not only
the health issue this is also social
and also the security so therefore i
welcome this topic at globsec conference
the good thing about globestack is that
the range is very wide i'm very
interested in 5g
in technology but also geopolitics for
someone like me who is interested in
many different things glove sec is ideal
we have to now focus more on our
freedoms and
liberty and democracy and rule of law
because even though
we we have things working online it
becomes even more
essential i mean the freedom of speech
but at the same time there is so much
this and misinformation going on so
these are
very very important aspect i think
we are all on the same page in saying
that climate change
matters to our security and that we all
need to do our part to mitigate its
impact and we all need to do our part to
adapt and be prepared for the changes
that are coming
so yes i think based on the conversation
you can see that the defense sector the
policy sector the private sector
we are all thinking about how do we do
this now
clearly european foreign policy is in a
bit of a mess at the moment because
we've seen
a lot of differences recently on how to
manage challenges from belarus to russia
to turkey the eastern mediterranean
even if one can steal your physical
freedom he can't steal freedom of
thoughts
and freedom of conscience
this year belarusians understood what
freedom means after this year
belarusians
will never forget the value of freedom
european union is not trying to compete
or to substitute for the defense our
connoisseur of defense is still nato
but we are missing some capabilities and
we are looking for those which are
actually not on the both sides of the
atlantic or which are missing
desperately in europe and we cannot just
simply buy it
my favorite panel has been the one on
hybrid threat to me this is the fight of
the future
is looking at ways in which adverse
actors are trying to undermine our
democracies
or change our values or do things which
go against our interests