be mmm be okay
this is my good friend Steve Thomas I
he's gonna talk about
defending with you back for syndication
I am
that's it agency %ah
so
a s as the reset I'm Steve he may know
me escapes
so a
he different types a a
you factor authentication inside time
base
topky I it's usually just like six digit
and that dongle tells you or
smartphone I usually it's a quite
96 pets private key some for
then there's a challenge response I this
is
usually more secure because our there's
it's usually like a large G with handy
responses just like six digits its
hash output from like up age Mac
had there's counter mode
I bike hockey which is
somewhere to you talkie %uh in that it
has security summer
paid six bucks and it's a six digit PIN
pay taking I'll there's unit G
which is basically I
ATS in cryptid China Road replace mother
deals your which is fairly scare out
he only thing with that is that its
most is starting I'll
authentication as a service so %uh
it but my everyone usually leaves
ya Depot GN which but only works with
UGG they have the her
out basically cher je where pagers have
HSR has
an encrypted version of it well cue
transit thanks %uh so anyone that
gets answer anti 29 just say
yes its some hair
but its probably K
arm than SMS so self-harm
but yeah sheen go
yet
scientists it's like quote like are a
sec
0 or Parker 0
I no but well this
on not eating all but much more I was
ask I
so the threats a stone tasered
from basically than
it relies and so we on the second factor
so for top he or I
hockey %uh those with sixty Japan
%uh your password is done basically
bout to get in you happy break a sixty
arm so lost or stolen
of storing second factor bennett's
normal just passer arm
so he won so workflow on the earlier
are much Marvo euros battle per
but ISO the next you I online guessing
from that its I'll mmm
from a then there's timing
tax such a mile I've
pressure and I'll the
so there's I'll her online cussing
you wanna rate limit I
you know per user per IP its separate
ipv6
other China doesn't matter anymore
because she's
he's and you can actually get like a
32-bit
I'll network address you
that eat me cycle for so a
but for the time being and even at you
so you still showed rate limit ot
yeah checker %uh
so you wanna check both from
make sure that you don't say which one
fails
because than a it's basically be
security 0
pass written to strengthen your password
times strength
he to tractor or your password
plus de facto so if your password is
like you take
a billion gases Andy two factors knowing
gases
he I'll a million up
one point so 001
billion gases for plus order
%uh say doing all I don't yet
so one hard drilling it should be I'll
lot harder gene very
timing text but so you don't wanna say
which one felt before
this about so what you don't want to
happen
is let's say you have a really strong
password hashing
over them that takes you know a decent
time
if you check the second factor first and
then just return
that and you'll know that the second
factor is problem
about also I'll
about timing text don't really work
Chigwell because
he thing that you're trying to get keeps
changing
for the second factor but
it's still I'll important to check
stop second factor possibly hair
in constant time so there's out for like
at the time
base once I usually check
to be foreign to you after so 8 covers
like
five minutes in case times you
so it even if you do actually about find
the code correctly
you should check all five just in case
yards
yeah they're very close to you so that
they can actually tell
arm
but obviously you wanna check both yes
on
help home so this is basically so that
you can have
yup password strength: times
June factor I'll if you do you check
he second factors first and then check
the password
but that is almost equivalent you
a multiplication because you have to
keep guessing
ya she factor which keeps changing texts
replay
I'm us there are replay you know you can
just keep sending saying
up gas over and over just keep saying
yes up and less the second factor
she cites for about its small
there is actually a case where a company
thought they're using
96 bits but they're using forty-eight so
after I'll to correct guesses
you then have up basically 40 thats
so that only the its last that you don't
know
well you for force the
whole entire range to see which ones
actually workout
then you have basically 256 gases you
have to make
then you would have not know if he was
I'll it was including air
being coated out there's the
private key Cherokee that was then and
tax
than base 32
yeah harm
hurty a sorry I
so a yeah you want you check out
ir so hardcover
sacked so you
money cue track coach everything in the
last %uh time span
so that about you can't just keep
guessing those
her
oh yeah
also you don't wanna update so did you
get the
but for talkie if you get
about the about
second factor cracked than up
usually I with the so does is
it just for times you I
you don't wanna Justin so after you
also verify password: because
be database update will take sometime
busty might be able I'll whether you got
the
hazard reg for I'm arm
me so you should have
archie factor upon occasion optional 0
I also has amassed that is
one that is horny is hair here
hey yes so
for Twitter a had problems as
always started so right um
so login process I so you have to
repeals
username/password second factor which is
are optional if it is and Mabel so what
you do is you look up there using
its naval than you than ask for the
second factor
and you check %uh both
the password said factor otherwise you
just
hassles home so
I yeah II extractor
tell company about this so well I told
them
Brian Thomas gonna do talking shop sets
so
up star star star star company home
this is up what they do all ok
well what they do is they do
quiet side crypto that so
all the encryption is done right side
and
the only thing on the servers encrypt
the data so
yeah huh so
up they had a similar misunderstanding
has crept on
home so they have occurred on
a their always saying zero-knowledge
arm they don't want anything to know
about your password
but to do this day use Searcy
but the server has well decides the fact
that you do any
encryption Bay stop password it some
public gee or I indicating corruption
both does happen I'll you know
information to say whether you got
passer correct or not so those are
password hash reports I'll
so butt whipped up past a
SRP um basically
about its password hash up for what in
the Davis
use or authenticating with circuit which
is are I so bad in order lecture
her so I in AR
well this has nothing to do it guys up
talk about
he circle so I scouts
home so in an audit or a
tripped on they're told to do a elliptic
curve asserting
but you non-existence
or something um there is a you but
they're major problems
I'll so %ah roads Roman
a be GTG 11 hacker
he was trying to do arm well
hey here but
I she was trying to do I'll
incur SRP and about you're going back
and forth and wanna
things a him up with was using
a P&Q but
which are two points on her up
but such he was unable to actually get
anything that works
but %uh so I came up with this
up so minor things but might
he weird-looking is the
%uh he division the facts but
basically since I looked occurs are
on a single group that has a hate crime
um
you can do and basically what you doings
up multiplying their inside just support
group so we can do is
up so she being the prime
number her the said sequel herd size
%uh you can view
acts race to you she -2 Maki
and that gives you the I'll
modular inverse there
so unwanted greatness others shrink
username on
your billion
god's your so are
so the worst I've ever seen I'm so good
talk about said
I had more up and yes so the login
process
is get username and six digit I
site factor 10 I'll it pronger sale
are than 0
a so if they get it right I'll you
reached that the server gives you a
challenge
which is a message in cryptid with your
public G
and your crib did cry Vicky so
what but so this is a real password
hasher quite what that but is being
protected by six digit K
arm than FB
response is cracked and 11 so
the attack I you guessed the
sixty Japan and so you get a rate
assuming that there is
to you you know awesome -2 us that spot
original you I'm here are her time you
um they originally had no women
for guessing but a so I just what we're
quite
10 dozens psyching so going on yo how
the pen yes sixty-two per over
I'm our new tomorrow
%uh this is the second factor there's a
password and
he's sector
so sick how a better passer
than its ir use
I think it's up this property are
best um an arrest so
this is just guessing the six digit PIN
I'll take on average three hours but
since I told them this they changed it
to you a
ten-second up rate so you can only do
one every 10 seconds
so %uh now on average
its 12 dates so after 12 days yet a
has a passcode what they can do %uh a
heart attack
and are
um there is a problem with this
%uh he since you're guessing every 10
seconds
the legitimate user when they try and go
they're not going to be able to login
he chose out its gonna say wait 10
seconds
and that'll keep saying that for so
dates so you can you go like of ours are
like
up thirty seconds away so that you know
there's
20 seconds where they can actually
jumping so
now that you have the pasa ask for what
you do %uh
our crime cracking than once its
%uh once you have the passer I'll
than you up to you
get back and say up to do another 12
days I'll
getting past the factor than
once you're an I you can actually
request or
he I'll second factor G
yes sixty 96 bit up
he and I'm you are
lynching up are
quest be
yes
all
yet
that's you yet
all I had
nada anymore
0 I'll up
well there are some that are its okay
you plus like I'll with Yuki
%uh I believe it's like 6496
thats I'll letter I'll
you actually have to you right so
there's only way
any 128 some noms on a cake with up the
128 thats
you sometimes are gonna get site 30 to
you
sexy purpose he
thank you little basically secrets
to something that's our 0
for are 0 her
for xx a star star star I
a well some I was looking when
a yes a I guess you could
tech your but you have to actually know
everyone's its email address sir
a reference to mention I'll with sources
are
help me the key factor obviously is
required
she's I know someone in this room
is like required to obey screw that
they know who they are
yes but
so Cheryl password sexy
is it multiplied or 0 so
attacker your you well would you like to
%uh
topky the protocol up or
up the home
Cooper but the ones that
burger per your your
so they check a second bag records
up yeah as long as there's
arm well I must say doc morrow
if they have rate-limiting than
its probably find like if they walk you
out for a long period of time
early you guess in some no because I
usually with
the six digit I'll and goats site 5
piping a million chance its yet your
ski but a
yeah if you can a server
white hundred thousand times yes your
after in
well
up your
more you
where
there was a problem
1 %uh just recently are I don't remember
his name
or he was a journalist use like this is
my real
Twitter password and that he just gots
have
by all these text messages trying to get
their Institute factors like
yeah it did not work because then you
might turn it off
and he was like whatever heads show
area I'll are
I A
well go
whole
all all are
go
all
or
all all
go
are all
all
all all all
affecting but
all go
go
go all
go your
or and okay
now
all I'll
look auto
all
you
I'll
your
all
mom
Hall
am
I have no idea I just might star star
star star star star
in oh no I was selected to the did
your and
if the
your me
well or I tried it I didn't want to like
running for better the heart your
yeah a I then ran it for a little bit
then I was like
pup seems to be working but I'm like
that could be giving me back
you well fake nose but %uh so what I did
was
I generated by and then had that yet the
and look like
a hundred up so that it went through
them all
that hit it and I got in I was like
that's bad yeah
yeah
your yeah be
I had yes
Beverly other things I miss her longer
their a helpful
I'm more hell
go
all
her bro
me
bull the legitimate user
have a on that wouldn't work anymore and
there would be no so basically you would
see I am i phone doesn't work anymore
than they would actually go to the store
and the like why would you think that
might on stone
you can watch that's cool all
more
on attack would-be I'll had a hacker con
jus you know I Britain US are few years
from
yeah
her cost your up
you'll
but you know there's also
the top he Joe side
factor Shapps your be um
up wall
us well I
now her order
well a source confirmed
about huh yeah no
I just over to Parker early remember
skills its daughter yeah
up McChrystal's Rep
house