is actually unable to physically be in
Vegas right now so we have them on a
Google hangout
on there also decide not i really good
speaker setup here cuz it's just gonna
this is going to be talking from my
laptop through this microphone
I was just gonna be awful but away so
are if you wanna hear his part of the
talk which is oxygen the really good
part you should please
move up towards the front um because
song goes I was like one over our cube
or something and
adults ok want are to be small what's up
are you can see me so the cameras one at
me you
yeah there's a lot of details here kinda
complicated
girl
ok whose for from I'll
here my hollow
I don't know if I'm this Michaels on
taken can you hear me right away
ok cool I'm gonna turn your volume up so
we can hear you
other your
our from
I don't think that's my cue
um yet type speaking a couldn't pick up
alright ARDS can you hear me over there
yeah well we have
we have victory small victory I'll
as Theron and treasure to start talking
in
ok bout yep from
welcome everybody are now we have I G
Jake apartment Andrews he is the talking
head
and yang Xu from BFF here to talk about
how
if f is making start a less resistant to
active attacks
or stalk title I've ever written by the
way
I'm really impressed there that there's
people here arm
okay so %uh Spiga how to present in
Google
docs there we go cool
ho okay cell I my name is John
US Army okay sounds a little here and
there cuts I'm yelling
and and Jacob Hoffman and reservoir is
that the somebody had to use a son Peter
Eckersley a soda somebody that he is not
here
I'm but we all look at the Electronic
Frontier Foundation how many of you have
heard a bf
of some so I'm not gonna so what it is
but we're here
you should learn more about as a beacon
our booth on StubHub she gave a great
talk earlier today
about start your last says the psych
awesome
of thing that everyone should implement
but and reality are
SMTP e-mail transmission is mostly in
secure
how many people knew that ISO
doubts many slides are going to be
things in you also this is what parent
says hi Hannah said earlier
but if you have you know if you have
some mail servers like
I like I could be on your network doing
this and looking up passwords
if you're not using stock deal a speaker
has things are just Sun uninterrupted
I am and also guess what I'm doing that
Ali NSA
sonya is aside from excuse cool and I
shows
on emit aside a tougher email sessions
and Facebook's oceans and so forth being
collected and text
and so you know could end up like this
and then I say they are pissed
and from mom prism sides we see that
they're doing the subscale
um which means they're using me a
passive surveillance
a more abundant a pic of it public so
here is our job
here's what my colleague peter sellers
are 0240
kinds of threats we think about when we
say like you know you well as in secure
possible hacker such as the NSA and
Paris um
in your office possible hikers with a
special power of key compromise
up there with hackers and especially
supposed to get up to the hacks and
we'll get into what those mean
so earlier today how many people out the
talk
okay so I today all possible hackers
we all know you know you turn on start
your last year good and Bihar doing on
that
so I I want winners this um
July is so tight June 2013
right after snowed in a happened %uh huh
we are doing so that's a gmail Carlos I
listened to have start your ass but
they're so it wasn't actually Ballard
and none of these other three big mail
providers
on were doing %uh and your New Year's as
good as Gmail
a nearby actually all kinda formally to
the survey
with that we call encrypt the way we %ah
service providers ahh
what which for which of these things are
you doing an are so we have things like
supports HTTPS
arm supports its best foot forward
secrecy support starting us
lol we started there was a lot of red
and gray like people weren't encrypting
armelle you know but then we kept
bothering them bothering them and
finally by like May 2014 we see a lot
more green so
all at sea like Dropbox Yahoo Arlington
um sonic already had a Twitter
well well what we're doing good I am and
I gmail recently released the state data
shows that you know on corruption on
average
what's not tell us has been rising Aug
30 32 fifty-eight percent depending on
how you look at it
sense the summer last year
also but all were really interested in
pulling this crap
further back in time in which to split
don't billing no how
on things like encrypt the weapons no
don't have affected star tell us
and that's where you come in so we have
some scripts that you can run
on your math history to see percentage a
bomb
sucio assumption and so forth so I'm
but you know there is also possible
talks with sophisticated as
assistance which is key facts in this
case um
you know what's easiest way for hackers
to I have a lot of the mailbox is a set
a
cuba not somalian tric up these
long-term session keys I'm sure
all-out sorry long time cues I'm sure
you all know this um
just over prime acute something like
harpley it or just by compromising the
server
you get all the mail but if he is
perfect for its secrecy on the damage
isn't as bad cuz you can we compromise
from that point forward
up to 100 on perfect for its secrecy for
SMTP a bit so important
his party lost 1.2 but
you know how do we spend as a Service
said I only want to use tools 1.2
but and North also the Tigers active
network attacks
which are really easy what started us in
case you missed it too and earlier talk
because the way star tell us what's very
opportunistic
one side says I want sir tell us and the
other says I also want start to us and
then
you know you have this negotiation I'll
but you know what
as a one-off Paris followers points out
you can just see if you're on the
networking industry about that start to
us
and we just fall out two in secure SMTP
and we're back where we started
you can also do a at Yas man in the
middle
um so are a lot of SMTP its service that
you start your lust don't have valid
certificates
and that is barely enforced so you can
see our meanest
weapon Facebook on the far left I love
this
servers that support 30 us only about
how
%uh demonstrated about latella
certificate
I so what do you do for these other
three nom I guess other
up two things gonna it knowing the third
one for second
'em so under what are we have something
called
HST us which is a way for server to say
arm when you see
no I'm not and get clone
and all that Jacob do the second part of
this talk if I can figure out how to
%uh get to this so we're gonna have them
do a screen share on Google Hangouts
she's pretty nu for having on
I take up so you're near faces now on
the screen I
so a %uh so
everyone I'll I'll make sure you can
forget about it clear
so politicized arms at all US
everywhere nicest RTLS use the
30 a.m. after RJ got I think people are
like
not wanting to sit on a front as much as
I wanted them to do so if you'd like
part really loudly not be great and I'll
try to dues a microphone work to
the action a know you have a
what happened to her assist doubt most
intractable
if you oppose fixer and moderately
I'll so she a
I'll it's one that's informed with I
a Internet experience with it it just
yes sir
it just yes water and also by that
yes experience what HTTPS
everywhere I'll so a
probably similar mister transfer
security data
now and past this first is it
problem first time you visit her website
it
how do you know that it supports
a is to yeps your follow first time you
visit
so quick Firefox take the approach
a for the day a number but its
into that as well say okay we are having
just
a this I which seems a that what scale
but
those I'll order some groups sites
getting a chest yes for you this a.m
o'connor
a significant fraction that similar
a yeah as the school doesn't accept
HTTPS Everywhere which is
a scoreless tie sites support
just yes a and
as it actually help scale supposedly
well just simple worst
a we about a
300,000 users to the same who this
30 a and
said no they with stocks last there's a
potential to improve security for
millions of users
with a this report this
up so will I'll a
central reconciliation case of I'll
that lists rules are the
well-disciplined events
you know supports to us and
labeled useful stuff with us
yeah our what's up
said um noite think
there wasn't it up to a distance
if you are trying to send mail to Gmail
you cannot to all the food as well so
those we should just know it's
what's that yes and if you connected
gmail elsa and it doesn't then you will
to a study of us a statement say
at s this temperature then
years ago possibilities whatever it is
some sort of glitch in that war or
a service configuration that situation
what did she do that at all rather than
78 a tax
and try again later wants the no all
other
there she fell those all I
in the case that severe let also
their loss and especially they want said
the Val attacks
I so again what you there and
it actually a you can't it without
lol all-star mister
I'll so all-star civilized if you have a
mission this fall
up of hope all system of spacious
I'll so before we get too much into the
hotel all-star
with that name alright will a last fall
all say those this fall wats a
the some on the alright because we'll
with him he's doing for SMTP
and seven th is if you've been in the
Sun
you can use to less all to provide and
stick your nation that states so
this that last night a man and
a here is that so that's that's that's
membership starts at us
nasa so it's a bit sad and
it seems a bit suspects today Paul
all for first then a in
additional all I because a
what we found is many of the large
of the white house I I'm all
warming up the mess a say childhoods
to the fall hands Wakeman
years down the line for still G that
I'll call ya
without arm this aside so
well and sale another
all list and checking it now
we'll talk about stuff later is
St Apt or send also are up
that they're actually not trying to
apply
also the all to
who a the sender side so we're so it
lowers
also falls in love for the pie say a
word you see more
what about all you look at what rules
s yeah to sing what all citiship what
I this is the s would actually what's a
who send their a halt
I on because of the on my
I bill as much control say to the
allergy to assess
so a with the St Lucia wall-to-wall
a within all threatened wall
you know every for a the plane into the
all sides types
the to more well us consolidate
it's a good yeah and we also
let me that everybody who the poison
pill
a do it with 74 malval day a
the confetti so that
it say something good relations of Star
Plus
for for that Apple a know of that effect
mail delivered it exploding also this
product
is to not have a detrimental impact on
the
I'm so that's why I would but yeah up
its
I'll mention nothing that wasn't too
a the that new balls this I could say
this install we all it yeah
I'll and then a and some large-scale
productions Morris
a we know certainly know how that
access to the Internet access I
a I wont s I'll
so you can also fetch okay on a
machine would hope that your whatever
machine who
always fall and pasta a
all so gazans lol also Davis
of what's on wall yeah I think so
I'll so the
they've been here this use it was a busy
day in the fall
it's in there because its hot stuff yes
but
a baseline and everything else
supposedly I use for yesterday
wheelchairs
up by a this that's handled the hots for
him
I so you expect to us
on to Melissa we get to know us all
I who intense to and bid with walter
separate sexually I'll the
still challenges mmm doing
stalled corrupted that he would set the
last
a it's that what continues to be rather
than
to Forza so and here
you moss and that too why would a on
I yet to say daley and that's not me
that
I'll and he gets a and its launch a
yeah that's tough and in the absence of
goodness
I its scare
well so
similar search 2 I still
you yes look at all
www cool I'll I'll
that could be 15 schools I a
hit an impasse was kinda on the farthest
I get to all the TAS
the exploded onto it served
I you know about hip-hop that's a
I'll says some way this service
killing it moved to the trouble of
getting science at that
I mean if style almost anything
an excess leads and why I a
know that make it here about it its
I'll so I'll that the know it was
actually
him um which yelster ship what happens
to avoid and
your lipstick balms yeah from night
them out I'm sorry does allowed for
Stockton
on boots on YouTube sweet
um so idk again gonna be Jacob talking
so that it or not
volume machines
a top at send sheehan
down the yeah a
is people postfix all as
the gayborhood surfers
the the whole a the post pics
the senate version
0 yeah that's important
yeah here for SEC
were looking for is a I said TP
t'as you person
which means send the no
tense t'as to severe a
of the law yeah yes
you know 17 his now
yes over people can hear there's two big
win instances it all and one of the
mists under one of them's the receiver
somebody fall are you don't have to
start looks security laws policies
so take a piss sending some stuff you
can't
see the to other a
a not so that the headers
question
headers missy is see said a
I music curtain
I think Adobe crashed the middle that
oh man thanks for them our
whoever a as great I am
on group think running all over YouTube
video through a Google hangout is gonna
be worse
all right here we go we're looking for
here
is yes and a for so
all to %um the
start TLS configurator should provide us
with the ball
situation and send box good
Asia the
the result to pester
see you
yeah
person this and
then this isn't more but really that was
mad
so that means we connect Tunisia
as sportster yes
the user Brett such a cup dispenser
some come out and say fuck yeah are some
pics good and I suppose in clinical
are still up always say for this list
you should always use stepdad
okay suspect that
Allston then because this is a
test harness I just don't want those all
that the recipient to and the policy is
to always impressed
UK a know this up
tell you this
a some a
complete
so you can see here the receives
male and December now except wasn't
dollar headers
and symptoms a
cool yes
palm said you see the H
yes a six-shot my sister
losses what happens in the mail
a someone is
for that day about it and basically a
advertising star yes
for Center all super late to
soon a just back from the all-star a
dollar deficit yeah this
the pics here ball
and this the no its SMTP
do used to us service controls it
force yes absolutely setback yeah
and his truck service
now Sunday
okay okay cool a
solvent
you follow okay in the center
and then the disconnect
male Wimbledon wow that is amazing
%uh we just boy to a man in the middle
talk because we changed our kiosk
policies
arm I'm gonna and the demo there cuz I
think those
the course by %uh how do I stop this you
too
always cross Adobe again okay sweet um
jaco Keystone hear us yes I as the
dominoes kinda not loud
arm but we'll send out a video link if
you really want to check out basically
we r we
did the whole start a lasting and set up
the laws policies
Bay I am so
I so again where FF are so tell us
everywhere would love to get feedback on
it and have people look at it and
I have an eye on your mail servers on
set up a date
I would also like to take this moment to
announce that we are hiring for the
technology to stop a DFF
and if you join you won't have to do
annoying things like
do presentations over Google Hangouts
with us I turn to YouTube video
ninety-nine percent of the time um
yeah so I can make a few quick questions
but we gotta get out of here in like two
minutes
yeah down I him
act I'm drifting through this to buy
max domains up
how I noticed there to you're talking
about the slide what do people can see
right now right to asylum adjacent I
things are listed by MX domains
now maybe these big huge organizations
have everything together
but most email administrators
will fess up that they've got some MX
backup
bed is Jess not up to date with
everything else right to you
right so to repeat the question for gay
couple can't hear you are so the
question was so we list a max demands in
the states on config file
but large are you know companies will
have like backup
.mx demands arm that on on a server up
to date and whatever
on so how do you deal with the the
backups on
take up the 1i think this question share
said the question great it's actually
the other way around a
yeah on sys admins are more likely to
have
she moved back to accept that sir well
and that's true a you know you do
double-checking
is before we had anything seven-fold and
unless all the rednecks goodness II have
school
I was 34 for instance owns a class II
about sweat
with them %uh and so if you specifically
want to be a part
start til it's over a get your house and
all
and you know us and so in other words
but we don't want to miss it if it means
that
have I and that's what does that mean
alright
thats picture plus because think that
this is how to IM
call a thanks can we take one more
question are we
well thank and a thanks thanks everyone
thanks take up