yeah
am over body this is Robert Graham on
network password hashes hashes
ash it
so out today to talk about um
a for small about me
moment I do stuff I'm that make you have
account so the slide presentation will
be at get have a Cal
leader weapons to their um
when talking about today is a so we all
know if this is right
this is be out we were crashing
we get password um like some on the
Internet like
hacks into big website and dumps
a million passwords and they're like may
be insulted md5 or something like that
so we go into all still have scattered
on the river
on we going to crack
we like to look at this algorithm is all
25 so that's the store and we use
reported that so we're not talking about
today is
what with your network we eavesdrop on
the network and we get stuff
and it often looks like this it's the
same algorithm actually
and actually you could in some cases you
can just go in there
sniffed packets pull out the fields and
pretend that they're assaulted md5
password
but back to sexy challenge response and
then
what your look you foresee it the a
child response matches
the what you see in the packet so
most what we talked about for password
hacking is
password ups up you hack into download
passions run and three keep you crack
rock has cat
and we're talking about is we tap into
the network
we don't pack it's a desk or something
abstract password hashes
and then run through the Jeep you pass a
cracker um
and this part though is part that Sony's
be done is that we don't have a lot of
out rhythms
in like oh still have scattered on the
river that can
deal with the pass rehash that with your
network and go through that show you
with those with those
I'll algorithms look like um
were talking about some tonight wall she
is
who does not know while she so while a
sheep is this thing they do every year
at Def Con
where they eased up a network and they
disclose
clear text passwords so when people log
on like pop to your FTP or Telnet
and disclose in the clear without
encryption whatsoever the password
the pop them up on the screen at that
cut and Israel are fun because you see
oftentimes see people there that are
very well known in the community
who have done something really stupid
disclose the password so what i'm
talking about here though it's over
walls to 2.0
I'll wear something similar might go on
where we look at the encrypt it passed
through exchanges
where the pass was not clear text but
which we can run through a
a password cracker and quickly get the
original password
so you might find someone famous in the
community very well known for security
but whose password turns out to be a
very weak password easley crackle
up
so when I log onto a computer like Mike
gmail or I a website
or might chat session
um how does that actually work and
there's four ways
one which is the first one which at the
cleartext one
where just the senate you using a pastor
in clear text you when he's dropping on
the network and then discover it
which is the wall she play doing things
another one is where you put the
connection
with SSL that's how we mostly log on
today I logged on to Twitter
is clear Texas the occasion but it goes
over SSL connection so that
no one can use drop on that unless they
have course happy eso connection with
that
look really not what the stock is about
on acting as a cell
the third way is crypto where I do those
count response is where I
where the machine where use crypto to
hide the passwords don't see it without
having
crockett national the stock is about
is also a fourth way a doing it which
on the talk about the N I'll their ways
exchange you pass without using SSL but
in a way that
can't be cracked either
so here's a typical password
authentication audrey has been around
for decades
I was called tap in Chap means challenge
response protocol
and that's weird me connect to a server
get sent to a string
you then hash that string with your
passwords in the back the route response
back to the missing
and simply that mp5 a child what's the
password
and the server that does the same
calculation South
compare whether those two are the same
and then
a lets you login and by hash
it off I often mean more than just md5
like this the H Matt algorithm which
took more
passes in the complicated way to make
cryptanalysis more difficult
but we're talking about propel password
cracking
which is brute force a dictionary tax we
real hear about the exact details above
the
a protocol are a mean the hashing
algorithm
the weather is using H Mac which is much
more secure descriptor now says
techniques milk extract it we're never
doing for noel says
do reports that were cracking
up so here's an example here's the
cleartext way for small spot three
which protocol that's older than many of
us you guys
and here's how I might log on I might
wildlife user Rob
okay password are is a strong password
there random here
and then it says okay you're logged on
you got one message waiting
so pop 3 supports a more secure method
called a pop
um and is the server supports that the
first okay message I get when I connect
be the the TCP connection in those
a rap get sick with a random string
and most the time that string consisting
a timestamp followed by
like the domain is is the standard
technique
and the timestamps always increasing so
that a
yet replicate the same hash over and
over
and I log on now I take by a logo for
use him again a Papa Rob
then I md5 past
that sounds during lost my password and
then the last logon
so that's how pop 3 solve that problem
but for love early Internet Protocol we
didn't really have any good solution for
in a cryptid
I'll connection away one
maginnis less osaka is about as I can I
could take that string
that child responds to parse terrible
um and put those into a password cracker
I can pretend that one is the salt
what is the password Iran perhaps get
and ask that can actually
her
I am so I am
support that help up three they add that
that a public sent into it
but for La early Internet Protocol they
don't really have any solution
SMTP didn't have any
login because back when it with SMTP was
graded there was no need to authenticate
user
because you works change the email on
was get your user that cared about
because
all the emails going to its final
destination and then spammer started
exporting servers that would forward the
email that people say well now we need
user authentication to make sure you're
allowed to use the mail server
so what they came up with was a solution
for all these particles
and that's called saddle as yes it's
simple application security layer
but it's just the pluggable cryptosystem
that plug into all these particles so
whether you're using pop three-year I
mapper
SM ppl that or Irish senior Jaber
we might be in CES yen a
UNC's protocol for remote screen grab
this the end
does a version control source code
jabar's a chat protocol
a all these particles now have Sasa was
one other options
they also might have their own
authentication techniques but saddled
not
what's havel gives you is knowledge is a
plugin dollars protocols
allows trip to our girls reply again
so one algorithm is called anonymous
which just means
not indication another algorithm were to
alter the plane and login
which are both just clear text passwords
one puts both
using a password on the same a
together and the other one with what
separate lines those really did this
both plain text
loggins and then
the other algorithms the next line are
all these child response things like the
MT 51
a digestion defies the same one like a
pop
NTLM as Microsoft specific child
response protocol
which read: talk about a lot more
because everywhere Microsoft world
up Graham md5 s Graham char1 are
variations on the same sort of theme
tell boss with additional things
the reason we need to have this is
because these different algorithms
impose different requirements on the
server
so with I just md5 it I'm doing the
calculation other challenge plus the
password
that means the server needs to store the
cleartext password that's a bad thing
as we all know no passer crack in world
is Sir Richard store passwords with
assaulted
addition they shoulda have to pass
through the server store with assault
and use an hour with Mike PKD up to
which a will rehash it Mike a thousand
times
and that's the secure way we know the
password should be storage servers
left with this s Graham saw one s Graham
a
md5 does is it's just the same
a child response password algorithm but
with the fact that you now are doing
recognized with that the storm passes
directly on the server
and there's also a bunch other things
that we can't crack
um at one time passers that we have a
security token or something held
current password is that allowed to log
on you can log on with that
and that I can grab you the network
packets but yet
crockett you ending useful with it
savell floods in the many protocols and
then there's this
GSS API also clubs in saddle
and the whole GSS API thing we're gonna
see that and
in protocols has his own plugin
architecture
so those are the main things we talk
about settles night say hey I'm doing
I met for about doing this as cramps are
one login or I'm doing
DNC I'm doing digestive 5 login
for me St and Bob do not miss thats
house all
all these things a plugin to each other
so here's pop three again where I'm
doing
of grand md5 over business adult
and its a base64 encoded grain
that server that what means research
and a town 3 that
or and I my house with everything
that the bases before go to string
with industry by the way is the username
plus the response to the
to challenge
or might do of Graham Shaw 17 of Graham
md5 and again it's the same thing
so I want longer so the screen
a or about your going to look he
Microsoft Exchange Server using popular
at work Microsoft user
and he'll am which has a more
complicated thing going back
or doing luck is all creepy is all
Cody here in base64 because and he loves
a binary
a thing but a
upward tech base protocol all that the
for were in C&D line I'll
in other protocols so we're gonna I'm
not really is too much time on exactly
is happening right here
if our to base64 decode that that one
mystery
look like like the slogans during
old what user I was before Cup the first
challenge back
a to here's your Gmail login
so i connect to tell netted yesterday
SMTP here two years ago SMTP gmail dot
com
report by the G-seven so as we all know
SMTP normally runs report
25 but there are these other ports open
design for things like this users too
many
email the the system
and so I tell it to the sport and we see
some interesting things here
um so I say hello who and
help to come back no yes get abilities
and so do things as also tells me all
the authentication technique that
supports and settle
it tells me I can do this log in a plane
to clear thats
or um also sports is own custom
extensions
cells on plugin: protocol a algorithms
just using 00 or what to do
in and I have no idea what way right ok
these are all supported by the way
because Google does this outsourced
email system gmail years
at who uses the outsource Google Gmail
Corp other
corporate headquarters
a Google s yeah so I am
yes the whole system to lapse never on
authentication is all plugs in
that although out quite quite up
for from
so why did was okay was promptly
the love
argues that login and told me that no I
could use that
because I had to do the star you less
for
so it's got the plaintext log in clear
text login
available the only if by do
US first star SSL connection
are ya who does the same thing those
interesting it didn't advertise would
soften
basement start just I'll you start
you let first and the reason for that is
is that once you start you start he'll
that
your cell next you
your restarted rock so
Yahoo only tells you which
authentication techniques that supports
only after that you done the SSL
and then a ghetto issue this case is yet
yeah I'd
like that or
so here's another example miss cases I'm
that poor know the way to grab
email the server I'm again the server
tells us hey
I don't get Billy command it'll be okay
your
bill I Rob for
you
%uh and those are the three
authentication techniques it supports
and here's an example up doing is the
other case plane and Bennett
help when okay I love login
so let's talk Mon but the SCRAM a
technique
which is one the ones that plugs into a
lot these protocols
so as I said before up just doing the
the brought challenge response mp5 means
server has to know the password
with gramm the it the server doesn't
serrano's the password hashes hashed
thousand times
with PKD up to and I'll
has a saw and so what's Graham does the
reports that
the client nets and it says 'em
the user name is user in this case
calabash
Rob hear something and use a random
string
and the circles back and says okay I
think the industry has more RAM
here I'll and by the way this all
that all by
generation four thousand times rehashing
the password
um so that's why I've that's what I've
done to the password
and but why waste so
so now service call me how house toward
after database the population using the
hashed passwords like you first as I
take the password
hasher was so i won and then
I do the replica populations in order to
improve the server that I don't password
now with this transaction I now can
store the pastors
Requiem the server and a
not little the way way with with them 5
arm and here's how it might appear so
let's say I'm I'm doing XO
you gather for chap protocol
I am here's why start the client %uh
start the connection
a again lead to the strains
in one cell
usually million are that
their basic were coated yet that's
because it usually might have a
utf8 pass for carrot this binary
the protocols can support just been a
basic one code again
so he basically for peco's history
have a protocol I'm a little match
the Spurs here
so a village Abers XML protocol so you
can see how things like this plugin
the saddle plug in system works no
matter what kinda protocol you have this
case is XML
and just loved writing yeah
I had this twice your don't know why
okay so this heart
my screen to so this is an held that
message
and this is held up log in
and what we see here actually is hoop
who your nose for Brause
okay so her Ross is
was developed in long time ago by MIT
and the ideas for us is the only login
wants to login server
and then from then on with an
organization a
that server controls your login
everything else
so that's class why has a thing here out
message esse guys I'm or battle system
is that a her boss plugged into that but
instead
up the pass through the exchanges you
get this ticket
from the login server that allows you to
log and everything else
so you arrive at work in the morning you
log on for Microsoft
Active Directory domain um NASCAR rush
exchange
and then when you log into your email to
the corporate website to also this up
within the corporation you're not
actually ever given your password ever
again
he's other servers they never know your
password they just are
record tickets so here's nelda
exchange up where I see it
here with wires are her were that
that her brother exchange driving ticket
and then here's the %uh that protocol
and just that were
go cool said
yet and yet
so in this login up here crack
but in other cases or exchanges what's
going on there something that I can
crack into
so a lot of people know that curb ross
is a sticky granting system
that a you log in once the tickets are
sent back and forth to
login every servant corporation well I
have doc risks or to skip how the
herb ross authentication works in the
first place your that first login
you log in her bra server
and the way it's done is it's not a pass
for caching system
instead the first FBS someone into the
server
and the service is ok and look up Robin
in the database
heroes password is blah or maybe rose
password hash and that's fine too
I'm I can feel them pass
and then I'm going to use that password
to encrypt the message back to rob
that has all that ticket information
so it's used pork ribs
and the and this is that message now if
I don't know the password or the server
doesn't know the password
I can't jump that message de que
continue on with with with herb ross
and this prize mutual authentication
technique does it proved to me that the
server knows my password
without me having to disclose the server
password is so while server as you set
them up
where wherever password exchange to use
and servicers is OK
does action password does not actually
rude serving what's up to
like hostile WiFi access points
so that sucker rod work and
because this message that sent back has
a well-known format
it should be pretty easy to actually
crack
and there's lotsa different herb ross
course plugins again
always for all these things or plug-ins
so the courage to think Asian supports
for example
using md5 hash password and then Dez
to diplomat or you saw 12 hash the
password and use
a yes to get the message or use mp4 to
hatch the password
to a Microsoft you sorry to have to pass
word up and then you'd like RC
for in order to curb message so
arrest had about 20 audible algorithms
but the upside is that well we can't
grab all the things like this
that just passed tickets around and
crack those passwords
from was if we see the initial corrupt
chains we can
is that for cracking system
up use the same sort of thing with perot
up
is plugging into a different protocol
here this is Microsoft SMB protocol
file-sharing protocol that me micro
article
or 5 here we were log into a file server
and again we're seeing how S&P
or and held up are completely different
protocols
but once we get done well Ruby Apple
yeah I that point is all the same format
and this is some it's really useful for
from forgetting the slings
if I want to write a program the
automatic rebel this hashing information
I don't actually have to do as much work
as I originally thought
because I want to park what or
this 1 and yup
parser or my oh that parser or
my jabber parser and so on
um but as much before for the
her bra stuff were skipping the login
stuff that was a seagram's
but here's the same thing where message
in the log in
Microsoft primary login portal actually
that's used most time isn't
herb ross 1 but is the end-to-end E
which has won this very well known its
decades-old by now
um again it is plugged going your
the work
around and
Haseeno password plus
blue challenge on this case are hatching
the password hash because
when the store is a mess a that's rude
as int4 hash
so that's a good discussion ok what's
going on for like protocols
but there's a lot other stuff doesn't
quite fit
that mall a who hear her to the no I P
incident
a few weeks ago so Microsoft hijacked
this company this company is providing
dynamic dns which means that your laptop
a car on the network right now my laptop
go to know why PNC
a my current IP address for this domain
name is this
yes by laptop was around people on the
internet
still access my laptop via that the main
even that my IP address changes
than empty nest is used for home people
whose providers change your IP address
on a constant basis
and for things like mobile device
so a is also used by botnets so
Microsoft hijacked that the main
went to court got a court order saying
give us that the main
and then which is a a million a
don't be a million customers and now
suddenly went no I P sorry
being an Microsoft you all this dynamic
dns
and Microsoft server still down about
%uh surgery BN's
had a bad thing but
so I looked into how they do their
authentication how they do that dynamic
a how my laptop would register a dynamic
name
and I originally thought it was going to
be via DNS DNS has that dynamic DNS
functionality built into it
and the way it works is on the DNS query
and that query the campaign to record
when
heart you
K
your up
and again it's very simple md5
straightforward authentication
I'll that's how I thought that know what
you would work in S
posed a problem because um Microsoft
doesn't have any look past took
ever validate what those patrons are the
hassle accepts
that ended up this rainy one
so up by the way in that DNS thing
again as possible crypto so even that
was 25 in that example
you can use all 10 me was when you got
this
yes thing as 0 which can then be all
these other possible things like
again T-lam or Ross
so whenever it is password field job we
which costs the same pattern over and
over
but there's this huggable curves are
possible authentication system that
matter something else I've already done
so that's why I thought that no I P was
using and as it turns out was
when used although I P H on your on your
laptop
I'll its end clarissa when you change
your IP address
said or like that or
here yet yo
long work
watson et Bay 64 Coast ring
clear text so
again we're back to like the stock is
supposed to be about cracking password
hashes and and robust script up
authentication but no one week we look
into things off we just seen it was
worker so yes this was a real
got great Rob
agree with the Y P and
that's my real museum in past where they
chose
because the course is a demo
it should be a thing was celebration Yes
No
it
so it's another case to study this is
kinda interesting a
Vic Kohring nope their windows becoming
so
one other ways that the cooling system
works but that point might
that's how a transactions are verified
how do because agreed
so if I'm a big boy minor I'm gonna have
a lot to working machines
their office furiously a money back ones
arm and I need to post by latest results
back to up my nipple
these days people don't mind the clothes
themselves instead they work with the
pool
that takes the collective effort if they
went together and then presents that as
because money
that's because of your mind by yourself
it would take a thousand years to get
one day going so instead you
you work with 12,000 people and that
it's only a month
to get a partial but going
so here's a minor might look like
subtotal money
how might be using homered
or your he said
as custom chip working away generating
0 a third have a billion I
hashes per second because of the basin
hatching it's like password hashing but
its a different
so you still see working away money
going my generate
0 now brower
which that very much actually its
affiliates who aren't going to go to
pick one per hour
I'm anti-slip disconnection so how does
he authenticate
and again we see a.m.
a pick up
the wrong string year yeah
so those a stir in a similar transaction
if
if I had the right thing here i decoded
it
and eat it too so it might work with
woodworker one and the password
cortex a 64 encoded again the same sort
of thing but their text
these big win money support two
different versions the protocol
that was the first verse the second
version 10
a j-son document and just again so
you me clear one thing about this
though is that that's not actually in
secure because what
these big point mining pools do is they
have one using password:
for a for your
your main account and then assigns
another using a password for each
worker so if a workers comp my eyes it
doesn't compromise your entire cow
and if workers compromised there's not
much they can do with your account other
than summit bad workshops
yeah
and most fools don't even care yeah all
they care about who I do I get credit
so so he must clear taxes actually kinda
works
your no one knows my main account name
was
I'll it the only other worker counting
and mention this because that
Chris Paul can actually apply to a lot
of protocols an example is set
Sep is the simple session repeated
had his truck the book which is the ice
get more
we have a gun %uh the wrong direction
yes which it says Initiation Protocol
I'll and it did for making phone calls
across the unit was the right people
call me and all our phones come with
ship so
for Android and iPhone some good as a
SIP account we can actually start dying
without actually any
special software wells a
the Super the protocols are this session
and anarchy p
is the real time protocol I think I'm
that carries the day the voice so simple
only about started phone call
other stuff panel that will draft which
invoice its
often issues a done deal over you TP but
uses HTP like Oracle
so how does that but then again it so
and yes that's minutes into a plugin
stuff as the other particles do
%uh HTTP doesn't use as a lot south but
it
it effectively does use a lot same
algorithm
so here we're seeing the standard-issue
protocol does again the md5 exchange
where they send
up town go
works in
the hatch the town what's the password
so thing is with said
if you're making a phone call or his
public network here conference
I can grab your Session Initiation
well you register year your
yeah minute spitting out
a packet to the SIP server so if you're
running a sip on your phone
your costly talk in the network giving
up
password hash that in another cracker
and
that readings I bring this up that big
point example
because set sorus really should have
that that worker concept
aware I've got one account but
Sep information that would in here %uh
should be like per phone
so the only thing you can do pick up my
eyes this cup might just my phones
connection to my September
not mine parce pick out so yeah so
phone require something simple like I
log onto maybe a account
answers okay your phone were actually a
QR code
then you take a picture that and that's
your thing case information for your
phone
and by the way as me completely
randomized password so that when these
are cracking this
cracking happens because you doing
dictionary tax that by sign a random
tolley long random stranger phone
will never be trackable and the sleeper
say so suddenly
ATP for a moment a HTTP support
suffocation within the header
most the time these days we log on to
the server
were logging on via stuff going within
the
the you are I R host information this
then
up to the SSL just look beyond normal
form
we'll ever use actual HTTP
authentication
when we get those annoying pop-up box a
with the realm is that
it that thats this other caisson
as usual mentioning this because a
there was the case with we've was a
the notorious internet troll broken AT&T
as they broke into because AT&T it
published the information
a bunch of all love all the early iPad
account holders
policy all the IP addresses on the
internet and North axis that you need
you need to set your script have the use
registering
say it was an iPad and and and looking
at is all that confirmation
I'm so that's not the case I
my repeat that because Europe lawyers in
the
the judges and the juries think that
well here changes
is I just moved his iPad use rate
history
network must be some sort of
authentication technique but it's not
to ATP define is his better
the way it works to connect to web site
the URL
misses you have access to it and by the
way I support
up I yet
up year-round well
there
up so 0
so they said okay you here
well
out that 0
your
so again is very credible stuff
um and here's the exact algorithm oh
please
how is it that way using row
and then that value yeah
other value here met year 0
all
loss
so a that we're trained md5
digest a version here's the same sort of
thing
yes really small sorry about that
this you
here Europe or I wasn't held Apple
SMB although Microsoft particles
a yet here to blow it up you can see the
cell
up your E
and all the other information
um again a
we see it there's the end-to-end
directly but there's also Jesus API
work and do things like herb ross there
as well
was interesting about this by the way is
I'll
for the prevailing Microsoft techniques
%uh Dante Lam
and Microsoft's version herb ross
because it supported now Internet
Explorer expect also chrome
and Mozilla and support a back-end
like on a patchy plugins stuff so
this Microsoft way above indicate things
is pervasive it's everywhere
even in unit system that you think are
hostile a Microsoft
having people here's organization up
Microsoft Active Directory domain
is the settled authentication for the
whole networks
so fun ought because alive universities
are very
unit centric but when you log on to your
sole heiress machine with your account
is actually going to acted directly to
Microsoft server
II I find that really amusing because
allow the students really hate Microsoft
in love you next but they still haven't
your Microsoft
just talk about Microsoft more so
Microsoft has this
RPC this remote communication technique
also
wesun messages back in force the
XML messages
um and so you support saddle
and their own authentication mechanisms
all that plug in stuff I talked about
before all supplies
this here's a SOAP request dust-up
for all I'll year
yeah all
so
we've seen so away so when year-long of
your Xboxes
them this is the sort of thing haitians
happen your list love you like your game
and sex was going across is this or to
request
though these days it's all been SSL
encrypt it now so you can see the more
but I'm imperious crackles only happens
with the
the SSL who here uses BNC
so and of you might be using
not really be aware because I you've got
Mac books and stuff use VNC for your
home screen grabbing
so the NC has Israel
its almost two decades old um
and over the years has had various
authentication schemes
and eventually got down to a
number twenty there which is just that
yes that
so yes he supports as well as well
it also has its own and father Asian
out on I'll have to resort vacation any
was really lame thing a
where was just it was a username was
just
just passer login and again you
connected
the see password on the login
in
and so is no protocol OSPF
OSPF is the protocol that riders use
talk to each other I is using md5
any five passer plus all the contents I
am
year is BGP et/pt cheaper also
its how all the the backbone routers
know about each other Nova
rouse matter-of-fact me great each other
there's no feature in BGP provocation
so what they did was the add a feature
the
you sport the five up
he should be today trip all TCP packets
pretty much just for BGP I'm let's talk
about radius
reduces the server when I log on where
way it and enterprise for register
that what's up a
Esparza budget any we miller won when
you easily hackable a
up mocks the most part now that'll
happen says
just friends the but eat with plugins
here's how it works I'm at my hotel I
said that with our
log on to the east net there I have tea
you a 02
11x authentication to the Ethernet and
it works I seventy
I seventy happy that for way wrong
yet no your and with me
that go
with md5 again but here's what the
switch
sends to the RADIUS server
it takes you rate protocol
you right though
go one
from switch to the RADIUS server
'em
so PPP is a all protocol that went over
modems
and it has the same md5 charge response
the side but PPP over TCP nasa VPN
technique
or or PPP over Ethernet which is now you
might log on to your ISP
it has all the same tell
I'm E what them I'm
so VPN are often very hackable so if
you're if you're
look at conference here um eavesdropping
on people's protocols
you might find it people are so sleepy
PPTP
and the using a cell response hack
easily
me crack or in which is especially easy
crack see also but
World of Warcraft how do they do I think
Asian with a great people are playing
World of Warcraft
conference I get back into their
accounts will use this lesser known for
a call call secure remote
ago and really kinda cool it does the
same
diffie-hellman our essay exchange where
you generate primes
and then you change the prize by math
but mixes in the password and this those
addition to the six changes
that in technically it's all in the
clear nothing's being
purpose I can see what's going on but
yet because
is that it's that public-private key
exchange thing
I'm I can't crockett so it's not as a
song corruption
those using similar algorithm yellow
but a the clear yeah racket katmandu
missus actual people everywhere should
be using something like this
and now all that crack a pollster
a by the way if you've got a large
capture files you want to extract them
you can use these are go get
presentation for the exact details on
how to do that
also by the way this is perking up there
for Windows call Cain Abel
and it has a point wrapping up for them
report budget particles
so about 30 per also my presentation it
supports
and what he's up on the on the network
rebels hashes and that has
will sup is really slow because now I G
you but it's preschool
so that was it that was what that was
about was
it's not about up we're no
for that RP were crap about
always production house everywhere
particle use
eased up on this network here yet a
little wall sheathing going with got so
many people's asses
run through a cracker they're using weak
passwords will get the password
any questions
here's our sample question about what
MySQL use late
general use plain text sample question
see things
question
at universal plugin
thanks certainly is you get this sim
universal shame likes asl
how do you avoid in order to provide
that universality
how do you avoid having to store
password in the clear on your server
last choice you have to make is often
done with the configuration option
where you configure your back in Surrey
say
I'm restore these hashed passwords so
therefore use Graham
and not md5 authentication so
mostly services had aspiration option
if you say I want twenty-five indication
that is that okay now all your passing
records
get I guess that's it I guess it's time
for lunch