the manager security engineering at
control scan and
up to talk his password security in the
PCI DSS
mickey on afternoon
I'm my name is JR white
today I will be talking about passwords
as they relate to the
PCI DSS okay nobody
bolted for the door so on as you guys
know PCI DSS is an extremely
exciting topic some I I'll do my best to
make it
as interesting as possible um primarily
wanna talk about sorted with PCI ID SS I
has been and where it's going in terms
that passwords 'em
reading that
for oh yeah I will begin at 3
for sure sure I cannot
change slide yet word
did you know what is changing in
presenter mode for some reason
not from I'm
writer and like evicted
winston at area
awesome thank you outage took
wrote brief background I sell up I
didn't see reengineering
insulting or look for ten years I merely
office
your icarly he a your users
me actual yet I'll just small lab base
compliance security are and a
specialized administration testing
application testing session jeering
thats I'll and and I your
couple things like he's in my spare i've
seen or I'll
sir asians up and I'm originally from
louisiana is extremely important if
anyone has any one early and the only
area
yet they are back yet send your
child-rearing
showed up so PCI DSS
face or failure well parts a
outlet frameworks guidance frameworks
it's really
yet while better not as I
saying that see in re
up on seizures process smaller
businesses
said him I'll loss
Martin's unit use
partner at of his
adheres yell arms
reporting requirements have or in Sri
I'll what that means you you know lot
the has and security and robot hacker
our ap helmets yours this of it
Ross where the smaller or a and our
your process I'll despite its
implementation there is no slowing
reaches im I'll probably never really on
interestingly enough homie you're not a
lot
and isn't are here
up you hear a lot about your
are right so I me I'll heart
of the ignore recently heard years yeah
I
yes on years yep I'll
loading EC service latter home
army by criminals of course there is
this whole section titles
yes who is service
row your service provider you her I
service your organization apply
any impacts true he
chain all yessir prior not mister
cry %uh once laureate
you're using was manage solution
something like that
that with me sir writer up and all that
party that has for me way to attack Iran
research provider at all access in part
network I'm not seeing it that
permission myself so
is speculated I that says
low that's how I her I'll and is
something I L
your lead I really hard yeah
are half what is it he said password
I'm which we all know is extremely
secure in
okay up yeah
in UK not just go out but you can't you
sad red require all
hackers elder well
up but but anyway I thought this is
really aching
I har you see a lot as up attributes
here's at work at
are at work be up US ally I think I
row and users he a
of password have at white are
head all yeah here
with that that here
that it's your neck hasher alright
health follow all you so as you can see
all but and well
but it does lol gay I me
every a me all lets our
drop Mar so or me lady
back I'll he's are every
acting I'll years
%uh my interest poblano
another up pls are all so it
name your class ahranat or
or product I'll there's ball at
or the I don't my horse all this I'll
yes what we see each be had me in
Hackney
are com so
and is Outback all US
new for a scraper now where out there
and weighs going is there yet
gainful server it I'll password list
they cost about it a lot harder it
are you East life came back after
years Aloha iris my Etsy a lot less
I'll up and I levi's all out below all
up research that's all late exploits
crack passwords and that I had wat
network I'll of that up
while I heard might rights are
huge small you are rights away
and Midwest region you know they were
all
Leslie are 8 work
right here army were quite you see
yes RGR small rate
I'll shop ru Heather months
were I'll and so what of that
you know they sound like he is a beast
mad I'll yeah for our
already I S he
happens or easy that Monday
I'll all your on hand you know that
shit but wasn't don't have her are
already
so this is a the SL contenders elite
world your you last that route
I'll there are also a variety it for at
least a
we rare see a slower practices
saying across holiday the chamber
after class work yeah attorney I
way this horse shit it an exaggeration
but
on yeah it really of an issue you that
me managing saying they're Nazis
nah process well or me slow
an Islamist year
ups here on C that
on and so now they're for raising a hand
network at wrong wat
or and with that equally
here eating their
I'll more your job sir in
ball of my they had here they have
a yet with you NOP
alone well mercenaries jury
dollars %uh you know each year
our yet access I'll of March
searchable greatness who I'll know about
how it
lower of or here at
or energy our prime Road yell
right back up people your I'll so
you know I eat that a lot or even lesser
acquired
are he pardoned over you %uh
greasy for it I'll just because I'm
always there
so many things that yes
does for all Asian works up and
as her yes know all yes but explicitly
specify a half hour
rather or as on synergies
that here %uh equine your
yes nah on consumer
users jeans consumers
all of us everyone who uses her
hack crack passwords I okay well in hand
stay and at ask %uh
radiation release choir which
Marshall me all right now I'm her on
track on cheney officials
on home at all hit
outside are are head
me lay yes or me yet
I'm really released and irri's grass
court
transitional an operator wire soaring
ever are hour recess
sir as let you know yes
work on this signal up process
we're implementing controls of testing
as her little bit
shopper parts that had your
I only eat pro yes but on
hey and issue were all and
her 10 I am
weird arm all he record hero
yes so so was com- pared
happy way he said say he
Irene I'm USA II at
I'll just pay the bills I okay
hand side hand yes
yes nah I'll
is not witnesses here I this
%uh and solvency helms
yes so you know here
mike got home that like race yes
learn to love on you never hey wait
way up
through being in what way or the
in their all over it
at it at all at
what about that hey law at
yes here Mar
well II yes AI
and red read more class %uh at
track say some other I I want to get on
that bus ride ever had
EA fundamentals me way you'll
you are wat r use out
so holiday other changes from yeah
car yes are you at
shoot New York sleep well and
overall me there's of changes
I'll II most Mr
superficial up but here are some good
in the right direction also others holes
lifeguards yea yes rate I am NOT super
well
worse yet year here
yes army that
said there's Jersey are yes late
are the ally holiday us this
seller universal 10 are
everybody does this Ichi all at work or
way action %uh style
and the wondered what happened years yes
up
%uh all hashed is going to get worse
yes I S as on this one a
he had like the seriously up so I
me this is Angie that really well
out what this what all all at wasn't you
are at had asked is or
is or using you portion %uh you got one
are release he did not say light all
or your your in USA World
outside he which I have not been years
me yourself this I a and that horny
hey you got any hi it
slight change your password this change
all
hearing fire up