[Music]
you
so
[Music]
uh
so
[Music]
me
foreign
[Music]
you
wow
[Music]
hmm
mmm
thank you
so
[Music]
bye
two
so
[Applause]
[Music]
my
so
[Music]
um
ah
[Music]
so
[Applause]
hmm
[Music]
hey
do
[Music]
my
[Applause]
[Music]
do
so
[Music]
uh
so
[Music]
do
my
so
[Music]
[Applause]
uh
[Music]
you
um
[Music]
so
uh
[Music]
and
welcome back
this is airtocon 2021 uh this is the
second day
of the conference i hope that everyone
enjoyed yesterday it was a training day
uh but this time we have
so many presentations
and we'll begin the day
speaking with murphy so
welcome alex suleim he will be talking
about the art of freedom
making some
demos and examples showing how to use
mainly for ios and android application
analysis
so
hope you enjoy
morphe that's your tire turn
and i will present you uh an
interference
workshop
uh it's it's more like a talk but the
idea is just to make it practical so
just to understand different use cases
uh using nato friday in mobile
environments in ios and
and in android
so
enjoy
so just a brief
uh overview about who i am my name is
alex i'm a security researcher at the
tagaquil
and i'm considered a mobile enthusiastic
especially in ios but as well in android
and
i'm
at the friday trainer as well
uh
we we did some
some
trainers related to it to friday in pass
air2cons
this year as well
and just you have your my twitter handle
and my github if you want to
just
get more information so this talk
deviates just to to know more about that
to freedom
uh just uh
explaining what is around different
commands uh all commands and
and new commands related to it to friday
so we are going to show as well uh
the new things that that we have
and we are going to explain as well how
to develop and to automate processes
using it to frida are
using
the plugins and how to develop the
plugins uh from from scratch so it's
just an introductory
presentation and they as well just to
see different practical examples uh how
to use that to friday in different
environments and we are going to show
different examples in ios and
others as well in android
and just at the end we have some
surprise to to show that we will see
so
what is it to frida
for those that
already
don't know it already one side radar too
that
all
uh all people here we already know what
it is
and we have in the other side frida that
you know that it's just
the two walls the with the radar we have
the the more the static wall world just
analyzing binaries analyzing data
structures
and so on and then we have the more
dynamic wall using frida
in different environments in ios android
windows
linux and well you know that you can
automate a lot of processes using 3d
commands and as you already know or
should already know
freelance space mainly in
javascript
so
why not to put the two walls together
having the power of the static
analysis that we have in brother and the
all the poorness that frida has in the
dynamic world
and this is quite powerful especially in
the in mobile environments
because frida works pretty well in
android and ios
and allows us to just
analyze
all the information all the applications
into the memory
and just
get it all the information
from memory and just get it into our
radar 2 session
and just
get all the features that we have in
brother as all the analysis
[Music]
algorithms all the flags
and how to for example print
all the disassembly or for
a good example as well it's how to use
l2 frida
uh to bring the disassembly from memory
using ether grid
given as well so it's a it's just a
powerful tool as it in our radar wall in
that case
so how it's implemented is just we have
a one-sided radar that is installed
locally
and it's written in c uh if
you
didn't do it just watch the
the total yesterday that pancake did
related to how to develop plugins in in
radar 2 and you will see how
it looks like and then
uh we have the i o plugin that it
communicates with a free agent that is
written in javascript and that's the
code that is then injected into the
applications
through the frida server and that's the
way
uh how it works and how it's implemented
and the idea is just just to invoke from
radar
the rather air to free the plugin the
idea is just to use the handler frida
dot dot slash slash and that kind of url
it's just what we use to invoke there to
free the commands from the
arrival session
so
just from living how to how to install
the frida
quite easy so just if we use r2pm
uh just r2pm
minus sc it's just to clean previous
installations you will want just to
upgrade the
the installation using a new a newer
version of it to frida and then with
minus
i
we install the
plugin and just compile the age as well
and
this is if we want to use it from a user
perspective however if we want to
develop
new features in edufrida and we want to
contribute to the
um
to the project the best uh way to
install it is just using
a make and make user install what it
does is just create a sim link to the
project installation
and then
we can just modify the project and just
executing make we are going to use the
updated version
in that case
so
just uh
how it works it's just
uh
in that case it's mainly oriented to
mobile environments
and the only thing that we
we need now is just
we have different mobile environments an
android and an ios environment with
frida installed inside the devices
and then we have connected
the devices into computers using a usb
and then we are going to invoke etofrida
using through the usb
in that case
just to identify the different devices
that we have connected in our laptop
uh we are going to use the r2r2 frida
and with the with the usb and
two slashes
it's just going to print the different
devices that we already have
and then if we want to connect on a
specific device we are going to put the
device into the two slashes as we can
see in the second dot
we have different ways to interact with
an application with that to freedom
we have
we can
attach to a running process
to uh uh that it's just
we can
we can use to attach to the process the
piv or the application name
or
we we can just
run the application again and just we
can expand the application or we can
launch the application what's the
difference between them it's quite easy
the difference is that if we spawn the
application the application is going to
be paused
at the beginning of the application
allow us to introduce all the frida
hooks that we want at the beginning of
the
running the application running and then
continue the execution of the
application that is what we get with the
spawn
however with launch what we get is just
automatically
continues the application so it's just
running an application and application
is just continuing the
to run in that case
uh
so here
we have different examples
and just uh with the
command with the two dots dc command is
just
as explained before just what we need to
execute to continue the execution of the
of the application in
in that case just just to resume the
application
so
something new that we need we have to
consider from previous years is that
the
[Music]
the contour slash
command it's been deprecated
and now we have to use the
the column a command or the equal and
exclamation mark
command
as a
air-to-frida handlers in that case
and just a
a quick way to identify all the commands
that we have in there to free the wall
is just with the colon and the
um
question mark
we are going to get all the commands and
the help and how how to execute them and
in this talk we are going to see some of
them
so
just to begin the first thing that we we
should do in an application is just
to get
basic information
from the application so in that case
this is an ios application
and
what we get with the
command i in that case
it's just uh for
the the vandal application that
we
we are executing that case is demo
objective c app
and as well we have the home directory
the temp directory and the back dell
directory that are the directories that
the application is using
inside the ios device
and this is a good way
just to start to have for example
what architecture where we are analyzing
the if we are working in 52 bits or in
64 bits
and this kind of information
that
can help us to understand the
environment in that case one
new thing that we have as well is just
with this command we can detect if the
application have been compiled using
shrift or only objective c in that case
it's using the objective-c environment
so uh
we have some basics commands here to to
understand
the first thing is just to to send an
alert to
the application
it's just with the with the first
command just with the e command
in uppercase
and just and then the the title and then
the message and this is going to create
a new alert in in our ios application
this is
supported in ios only
for the moment
and this is just a
good beginning to understand at least
how it works and just to check that it's
working as expected
then
uh we have different air-to-free
commands native air to three commands
that we are going to see
right now
however with eto frida we can work as
well with frida scripts or with frida
snippets even
so we can
just
create our frida scripts or our friday
code snippet and using edufrida
this code can be executed
using the eval command if it's just a
free snippet or
just the
with the
colon dot and just the
path to the script we are going to
execute this this friday script in that
case
and something to
to have into account to take into
account for
for that to fit a wall as well it's just
we are getting the powerness of radar as
well and
all the commands that ends with a
j
are getting the output with json
or
if it's ending with an asterisk at the
end
it's returning the output as r2 commands
and this is quite useful if we want to
for example update our auto session
with
the new information get from frida and
this is quite useful we we're going to
see
in a couple of minutes
and it's as you see just at the bottom
of the
of the slide
it's just
printing
the commands and this with this dot it's
just
quite useful
so
now we are going to get more information
from
from the
application and we can get our
information the import information or
the exports all the symbols and the
difference is just with
changing the the second character with
an l an i an s or an e an uppercase e in
that case and this is quite useful
because we are going what we are going
to do is just get this information load
it into an
into the earth session and then just use
it for our analysis
our deeper analysis
this is quite uh helpful if we want to
do this like
uh
automatically that is the
with the init command
we can just uh
any analysis
so
just getting deeper
we are
talking
we er
about how we analyze applications
but it's working as well for
for android applications but it's quite
simple
uh in that case
uh
what we want is just get the
if the classes information
and
this this information can be imported
into the
uh the r2 session
we are going to see this uh
in data linear example right now
uh so i'm going to just explain maybe
maybe better in the example
and this is quite useful
because it's a good way to access to the
file system of our devices
it's only we we only have super for the
moment for ios but it's quite useful to
mount
the remote file system in that case for
our ios in our edit session and we can
navigate through it and even we can just
download
files from our ios device
without using in that case sched so it's
just our using only using airto frida we
are able to access to the file system of
the application and get the files from
it so we can just get the info info
please file to which is analyzed
information for the application or
all the information the sensitive
information that any application can
generate into
their container can be downloaded only
using uh
this command that is just
initializing the session within it and
then just with ms
you are going to have like a shell where
you can just navigate through all the
folders and then just with get we can do
you can download all the files that you
want
so we are going to see
uh an example about how to analyze an
ios method using ato freedom
and we are going to put in practice all
the commands that i
just explained
so
what we have here
is just i have a
an iphone with an application it's a
custom application that is developed for
for demo process and then we have a
shell
that we are going to
uh
launch the application
as i told you
we are going to use in that case launch
top voice to resume the application i
had to free that's going to resume
application automatically we are going
to connect to the device using the usb
we can put
a device
here
if we want
a device id
a device id or if we cannot if we
don't put any device it's just getting
the one connected by default
and
if we don't know the name of the
application
just
with two slashes
head to three that's going to print all
the applications that we have installed
in our device
so
just
i'm going to
execute the application
as you saw the application just rerun it
and then
we are going to
change
some options
but it's quite useful to improve the
analysis of in that case for for ios
and then just
we are going to execute init
so
just automatically is sticking to the
entry point
the libraries are having already loaded
and
if i just execute
this command we are going to see all the
boards from the application
and if
i put
the star at the end
are printed as i said
as
air two commands
so
i got way to import this information
into our session as flux
you just put it a dot the beginning
and we can do the same for
the exports
so
now
the next step
now we we we have uh
the earth session with the imports and
the export information loaded into into
session to current session and now we
are going to see
the different classes that we have in
in the application
as you can see we have a lot of classes
because we are
printing the classes the classes uh
implemented by the application and all
the classes imported by the application
as well
so a good way to just check
the classes implemented by the
application is just using this command
that is i see the video at the end
and just
filtering by the num the name of the
application
so
we can see
here are the classes implemented
by this application
so now
we are going to see
the methods
implemented by
this this class
that are are these ones in that case
and another useful command is just if
you use the star at the end of the of
this command
you're going to see
the information as flux so
this information can be as well imported
into our
earth session and this is quite useful
if now we want to just
use
the
the sick command
using the flux to move around the
application and then run the methods
using the the names instead of just just
pointers
so we are going to move to to the easier
rookie method
analyze the function
and with pvg we are going to print the
disassembly
uh
using air to github
this is
quite powerful because what we are doing
right now is just getting the
disassembly from memory
and
just
decompiling the information directly
from memory
this is quite useful in ios because as
you know ios applications has a drm
implemented that if we want to analyze
the binary
we need to decrypt the binary first
however if we are using it to free that
we are working very directly in memory
so it's not needed to decrypt the
process because
everything is already
memory so
here we have the
the method
that it just
it's just here
ah however
okay
here in that case we can see that we
have two different functions
as we don't know what it is
however if we print this pointer we can
see
that this is
uh an string referencing to apt that is
just a path typically used for
generate detections
so
we are going to check
what are these functions
and how to analyze it so
we are going to
just analyze the function using the
sl command
just let me check
ah here
okay
i forgot to
just
this command is just
to improve the analysis and just
executing
ac
[Music]
exactly
so we are going to use seal
just different analyzing the decals
analyzing the function and if we print
it again
yeah
here we go
we have
we have resolved the the goals to this
function so we already know that these
functions that default
so this access function is using
this pointer
that if we print what is this pointing
it's just a string to see the
application
we what we have here is just a
very simple way to check if a device is
still broken
checking if this file exists using
access
and
if not
if not exist it's just creating another
checking using dlc
the dlc image as a function for
ios
used to resolve
to resolve functions
and what we are resolving
is
the string stored in that address that
is the the l stat
so
what we are doing is just executing else
that
as we can see here
related to
what it's
stored here that is there
so we are using elstat to check if this
file exists into the system and if it
exists it's just showing that the
devices are working and if not
so it's just checking checking that it
so
just to
some
different things that we can do as well
this is from
the air tool because we are analyzing
the function using radar and getting
information using using frida
uh
but we can do more
things from in the dynamic world
using it to freedom so one example is
just we can call methods
so
as we saw
we have
the main controller
and we have different methods and
here we have a method that is changing
the
background of the old application or at
least it seems to
so
something that we can do is just
execute
kfs
sorry because
i forgot to put the class name
just to
check what is the
the method
signature
we can see that we have a pointer
another pointer and an integer this
integer is referenced
to the
to the first parameter of the method
and these ones are referenced to this is
referencing the class name and this is
referencing the the method name this is
how it works in india as well but
always the first two arguments the first
the first one is a reference to the
class and the second one is a reference
to the method name
so
just
executing dxo like this is a method to
call objectivity methods
we can see
how
we can get this method
and call it
and just
check the background
as you can see
right now
just sending a
an integer we are updating the
application color
so it's a good way and an easy way to
interact with application methods only
knowing
the class name
and the method name and just to
understand the parameters we can use the
efs
retrofit command to just get the
function signature and just interact
from it
cool
let's continue with the
with the slides
so lights uh this is the dxo command
that we
have already used
uh
to just interact with the application
and the efs command that the function
signature and just understand how her
application is
implemented so
from the dynamic wall
we can now
call so we can call a function we can
interact with the functions
however we need as well to understand
and to monitor the applications itself
so a good way to
to understand
when
a specific function is called
[Music]
a specific class is it's been used or
not
a good way just to tracing the code and
with etofrida
we have dtf that with etf we can trace a
function calls
and as well if we can define as an
argument
uh different parameters to just uh
depending on the function signature just
to print not only when the function is
called
uh but to print as well um
the arguments that the
method call is
is using in that case
uh so we can use dtf if we want to
interact directly with pointers and and
with the arguments or we can use dtr
if what we want is just to print the
the registers just
when the function call it's called and
this is quite useful when the you are we
are interacting with
with system calls on with
low level functions
that it's just passing all the
information in in the registers and
it's a good way to just
quickly understand how
all the information is passed and what
kind of information is passed
here we have
the
dtf and the ddr
example of the same function
as you can see the difference is that
the you
with etf you are seeing the output as an
argument
and with etr you are seeing the output
as as registers as x0 x1 x2 and so on
however uh because of using arm
architectures you are passing parameters
using the registers you can see this
exactly the same information as
as you can see in the slide and for ios
[Music]
i mean
to just
use dtf or ttr or any
tracing command
you need to use or a symbol name or
a pointer to
to to the function
however in ios it's implemented like a
helper
that is the object dc helper
that can allow us to resolve this
information automatically so we can
trace object dc functions using
objective c
a column and then the class name and
then the method name
so we are going to see
[Music]
an easy example
when to use
dtf
as we already know some information some
applications
are implementing a
[Music]
certificate pinning to avoid to
intercept the traffic
of the application
and just to understand what kind of
information it's just
sent between the application and the
servers
and
there are a lot of different ways to
just bypass the certificate printing
checks
however an easy way is just instead of
having a proxy between
the the device and
and the server to get the the
communications http requests and
and so on
uh instead of that
uh
we can get directly the information of
all the http
requests generated by the application
directly from the
from the method names and the method
calls that it's been used
so
[Music]
yeah i'm going to show you a quick
example how to
intercept
communications of an application that in
that case is an application that i know
that it's implementing certificate
pinning so it's not
easy to put a
proxy like a burp or another
proxy
because it's just detecting the
it's just detecting that the
communication it's been tempered and
analyzed and it's just blocking all the
communications so uh a good way
and an easy way is just
to
monitor directly the
functions in that case the object is
functions that the application may use
to communicate with the servers and
print all the information stored in the
in the arguments and with that
we can monitor the urls used to
in the different communications of the
applications and even the content of the
body
of the request sent to the server
this is the how it's been done it's just
using the dtf
and the objective c
handler
and then this is the class name and this
is the method name
i'm using
just these characters
just to
[Music]
to just narrow the search and to avoid
having conflicts with with method names
that can can happen
and with the with these commands what we
are
doing is just configuring the
parameters is just a configuration of
the
agent
so we have different parameters that we
can we are going to show just right now
and with that we
we
we get the information with
json in json format and we are not going
to print the back trace because if not
it's just too much verbose the output
so
i'm just going to execute
the
script
as it is
application needs trigger it's launched
and now it's just printing all the
requests done by the application as you
can see the application is still working
so it's just getting the information
itself
and
we have
all the urls
just here
for example here we have another url
and it's a good way to get as well uh
bonald is in a quick way in that case
it seems like an api key that maybe you
just use for this application
and just
we can
get it only just executing the script
and just analyzing all the
communications just
choose it
from it
cool
getting back to the presentation
so
now we now we know how to
interact with the methods into an
application we know how to monitor the
method calls so we know when a method
it's
it's been called or not
now
what we are going to do just
we are going to modify
the behavior of the methods how how so
here we have different methods to modify
the return value of the methods and when
this is useful this is quite useful when
we are working with
security checks like antifreedo checks
with anti-routing checks
or a digital reject checks that
are just functions
making different checks into the system
and then just returning true or false
depending on
if the application is it's just broken
if the devices are working or not
so with these methods we
we can just modify the return value of
the of the functions quite quite easy as
you are going to see right now
and returning what we want
so we have
a
if we are using a 0 or a 1 into the
method we are returning zero or one or
as it's the same true or false
if we are using
the df
with the f at the end it's calling the
original method
without the f it's not calling the
original method so so what we are doing
is just
substituting the function called just
returning the value without calling the
original code
and with the f we are
actually executing the original code
and we can bring to nanite an arbitrary
integer or even a string before one
so
let's see a
practical case using the ai
just to bypass uh
routing checks
so now
i'm going to use an android device
i'm just connecting the
render device
and
yeah
you should see the already the android
device
and
here i'm going to
spot the
application
this application is just
for for testing purposes it's just
to check if the device
it's root or not it's different doing
different checks
and it's a good way to identify
which kind of checks uh your device it's
failing for typical
anti-rooting checks
so
um
here i have different checks that i'm
failing even
some native checks
so just
let's
finalize the application and see how
how
to bypass all the checks
so in android we have
the command ic as well
just to analyze the the classes
implemented
and just to narrow the search
we are going to
filter the results for root build
within the package name of the
application
so we have different classes
uh
this is the main class
so
we are going to copy and just print
the methods implemented into this class
so we can see
how
our different checks already implemented
checks so exists so binary
read write paths
magic's binary so there are different
checks
implemented in using java
and we are going to just bypass this
this checks using the di command
so
we are failing
in those four because this one as we can
see in the name it's native so
we
i'm pretty sure that it's not
implemented in java
and
for example
the
so exists referencing the the sub binary
[Music]
or
we have
the
the read write paths
just right here that it's failing as
well
so we need
to
just modify the written value of
different functions
that as you have seen
are written
returning boolean
mainly all of them
so
the only thing that we just need is just
executing the di command with zero at
the end just returning false
always it doesn't matter the device
doesn't matter the checks and we
remember that if we are executing with
the f we are calling the original
methods however now we don't want that
so just
return false and that's it
for android we have a handler
that is
java it's not implemented in all the
commands but it's implemented in this
one
and you can just have
the
package
name the class name
and
the method name
just
do the same for
all of them
just let me
copy this
just to be quicker
check
for
um
[Music]
and now we are going just to trigger
again
the checks we can see that automatically
when we are using the java handler is
let to frida is having java traces into
application just two
notifiers but the
the method it's been called
and then it's been modified
with with you
and as you can see all the java checks
have been easily bypassed and quickly
bypassed
so
we are going to just bypass the the
native checks
how how to do that so the first thing is
just we need to identify
where the native checks are implemented
normally
how
in android is it's it's working with gni
it's just
we have like a stop implemented in java
and then this is a stab it's loading a
library and this library is implementing
the the code itself
so we are going to check
the libraries and just to narrow the the
search
we are going to filter by check and here
we have
uh
the library that
is implementing all the logic
of the native checks
so
as you remember
with the star
we are going to load the libraries
information into the r2 session
with the dot idea at the beginning
and now we can just
jump
to the library code
once we are inside the
library code
we can
get all the imports and the export
information from from the library put it
into there to session
and we are going
to see
which exports has the library so because
the
the java the java is calling
the function the native function using
an export so
we have different exports
and this is maybe
suspicious because of the name
and
uh
we are going to jump to this code
okay
so
so now
what
i forgot
yeah
now okay
so now we are going to analyze the
function
using guessing as well to analyze the
function and just
using a together to print into this to
the
the compiler function
so it's triggering a little bit
and there we go so we have the czech
route
it's doing different things
and
as you can see there are different
function calls
so
we can see
for example
[Music]
let me check
this function
to see
what is implementing
we are analyzing the function as well
and we are going to print the
the function
[Music]
i don't know why
it's not
so i don't know why it's not
just
praying for the democrats
but
should have
uh
we should see a reference to this method
that it has a
like a reference
i don't know why
the grid is not printed as expected
but we are going to move to this
function and
to analyze the function as well
using gasil and we have our command
and we are going to print this assembly
okay
so this is another
function that is is doing something with
this function
storing in this variable and depending
of the value of this variable it's just
doing one thing or
the other
so
just to
autoname the functions
after an analysis this is a useful
command with its ain
so
if we execute again there to free the
either to give
the compiling
we are
renaming the function so now it's quite
easier to understand what the method is
doing so in that case it's just
calling the
open
of an argument
that it's just
calling the open method of this argument
and depending of
the
the value of the open just
what it does it's doing is just checking
if some file is existing into the system
or not
uh
it's just
printing a lock
or
printing another lock so what it's
printing
it's just
we can
just print
the the values
stored in the pointers
so we can see that
what it's doing is just checking
it's an anti-rooting checking and it's
just checking
if a specific file is present to the
system and depending on if it's present
or not just
returning a value or not and printing a
specific log for it
so just to bypass this
we can just
get this method and
and bypass it
so
here we have
a script
and i'm going to show you
that it's just
tracing the function just to check that
it's wrinkled
and then
modifying the the value what is doing
this method it's just getting the
exports and filtering by the exist
and then just getting the address in
that way
so
just
double check
this is the method that i'm just
actually modifying and tracing and if we
call again
the
application we can see
all the different arguments that did so
the different parts
verified by the application so so in
that case
another two binary different locations
of the sub binary
as you can see fail safe
so all the different memories
are
printed in the screen so we can see the
different paths
check by the application and then
how it's been bypassed just with the dig
recommend
put it into the the export function that
it's a
the one
checking the
the files using the open cisco
cool
so
this is what we already explained
we are going to talk
about r2 plugins so how to
the
all what we
did was just manually for analysis
purposes and using the smallest small
list pre scripts however if we want to
do something more complex
we need to do it
as a nerd to frida plugin
so
how it's working is just
uh
you
the plugin is implemented in javascript
the only thing that you have to consider
is just to
call the plugin register api to load the
the plugin to the to freedom
and then you can load the plugins using
the
dot
at the beginning
with the file name
and
it's just
[Music]
loading the plugins and you can list all
the plugins so
in in this
image you can see an example of how to
implement the typical hello world using
a net to frida
plugging
here we have the code
it's quite simple and can be used even
as a template
because
you
you have at the beginning and
an array and then uh is where your hash
where
where the
commands are defined then we are calling
the plugin register
api called
using as a parameter the commands
structure
to register the plugin
and what we are and then
we have all the functions
that are
uh
called when the command is used in that
case we have a function called hello
that is being used by a command called
hello as well
and as well we have the plugin
name that is used inside the plugin
register api that is called hello as
well
so just with this simple structure we
have a typical hello you need to freedom
uh
just to
[Music]
well
to
have it as a good template
to create your more complex uh plugins
for
freedom
this is a
a simple example just using the api
reserver for objective-c that is
implemented in the friday api for ios
and what we are doing here is just
implementing the command find inside to
fiddle just to look for
different
class names or method names depending on
how the expression is it's used as an
argument
we have another example that it's a
michael parser micro is the the
format of the ios
binaries
or or
mac it's the upper wall in the case
and uh
what we are doing is just
loading the
the plugin and then with the star we are
getting the output as
um
[Music]
as rather
commands
and these commands can be implemented as
flags in into the session so it's a good
way to
have
all the mac parts and having all the
flags updated
into your two session to finish session
quite easily
and here you have
the code it's bigger however you have
the snippet to
how to convert the output of the
of a of a function to earth of radar
commands that is just returning
the string as
as it did stating just here
so more complex examples of our two
plugins
we can
here we have
uh
is an example for for ios it's just uh
our url schema fuzzer
uh
it's just uh
it's it's nothing new it's something
that it's been
already implemented in frida and what i
did is just
get the code and import and just
update it to head to frida
as an example
let me show
a video of a demo executing this
this is here to freedom
script
okay
here i'm attaching to the springboard
and i'm just
importing the the plugin and fuzzing
the e-code
url schema
and just with the contact name 666 and
then in the message it's what i'm
putting as a fuzzing
string
and then i'm just calling the
application continuously the url schema
and just what i have to do is just wait
to
identify if the application
crash and if it crashes just check what
string describes application and just
analyze just a nice deeper
from it
and
and this is a
simple but useful example of a specific
use case to use a net to freedom command
a neutrophil plugin sorry
to implement something useful to
automate a complex
process for your
mobile apps analysis and this is an
example for ios but can be done for for
android as well using deep links
so
this is another example
that is a
[Music]
the surprise of the of this talk
that i just
deserve it from the end
uh and this is
uh
an ios uh application decrypter
that
as i told you before you know that ios
applications are improving the drm
to avoid
to be analyzed and you need to decrypt
the application before
put it into your
radar session to analyze it statically
to do that
there are a lot and of different tools
however i decided to implement the mind
using
uh
as a neto frida plugin
and it's just a small tool composed by a
network plugin
and a
python
[Music]
a python script that is using air to to
interact with
with the device
and it's only supporting 64bit
for
and
something good for for this that other
tools maybe have not is you don't need
ssh to put your ssh credentials
to download
the the bundle
so it's everything is done using frida
and using the
as i told you before it's using all the
i o
features to download all the content
from the application
and
what you can do is just downloading only
the binary
or if you want to generate the ipad file
you are using the whole app bundle you
can do it as well with miners i
so just to get it
the requirements it's quite easy it's
just a working device an ios your
working device rather to install it in
your local machine and free installing
the device
and then to install it you can just use
pip
we've installed r2 flash
or l2pm
minus ci air to flash
and with minus l you're listing all
applications of the device and just
putting the the app bundle
afterwards
you are
getting the
the application bundle
and downloading the content as well from
from memory in that case uh the autofill
plugin what it's doing is just
analyzing the application analyzing the
structures and applications and just
getting the decrypted part portion of
the code and just patching the binary
in in local
so just i have a
video just to
to end just a quick demonstration about
how it works
so
okay
just
like sorry
check
[Music]
okay
i don't know if
you can see
well the video
however
it's just
uh what you can see it's just how whole
application is being downloaded
and
the the ipad is created
i'm going to upload the videos so
you can check it afterwards
so just to finish
well this is how it looks like
and just to finish just say thanks to
all the people
that it's just helping to all these
projects to
to continue
all the references especially for the
source code of the orthoflex tools for
the plugins and examples that
i used
during this talk and different
references and videos
to learn more
to
there to free the world so
yeah now that's it thank you
sorry for for the video
and well
hope you enjoyed
now it's yours pancake
thanks alex
we're gonna make a
quick transition to the waiting scene
and then we'll start with a presentation
from captain banana
[Music]
m
so
[Music]
hey yo what's up it's bananaman i hope
you all had a great trip to barcelona
today i'm talking about the intersection
of r2 frida mobile security and dildos
so i came across this pretty interesting
product it's called satisfier
and it's a dildo but with an app so you
can
connect to it using bluetooth and
control it
and there are quite a few people using
this app
it's mainly sold across europe
and a main feature is that you can add
friends in the app
and allow them to control your satisfier
remotely
and i wanted to see if i can pose as any
other user on the app and trick people
into allowing me to
control their devices
so i did all sorts of analysis on this
app i've decompiled it using cfr and did
some static analysis
and i've used burp to view the traffic
of this app
in combination with freida and the
universe the third pinning bypass to
actually see the traffic
authentication is handled using jwts in
this app
and upon starting the app it generates a
jwt and that's used to authenticate at
the server as an anonymous user before
logging in
and what's interesting is that
this jwt
actually has to be signed in order to be
accepted by the server
and the key used
during signing
is hard coded in a native library
so as you can see there's a function
called get release key
it's originating from this from this
library and
the key is being used in this call to
sign with
and that's basically the initial
authentication
now if you look at authentication you
see
quite some difference
the first one being the subject being
set to satisfier for unauthenticated
users
and the subject
being the username for authenticated
users
another difference is that the off
role
is set to anonymous client for anonymous
users and upon logging in you receive
the role user
and authenticated users also have
another attribute in their jwts called
user id
so i wanted to extract this signing key
and use it to make my own jwts for any
other user
and there are quite a few
ways to extract this key
the simplest one being just using r2
opening the shared library
and
disassembling the
get release key function
and as you can see
the key is embedded as a string constant
another way would be to use frida
a simple technique is just creating a
new instance of this jwt token builder
class
and just calling get release key and
printing the result
and another option is to
actually find the the exported functions
in the native library
and adding an on leaf hook to just print
the return value of the specific
function and of course you can just use
r2 freeda
here i'm attaching to a running android
app
and
i'm using the available modules the
shared library that i'm interested in is
called lib native lip
so i'm adding a trace point at a
specific location for the register x1
and i'm triggering jwt creation
and as you can see the
secret is being printed
so to actually use this key to forge our
jwt
you could use your own code
but i've decided to just let the android
app do the heavy lifting for me
so i've used reader to overload two
specific functions
the first one being claim
which is being used to add the
information which user is holding this
jwt
and
i'm changing it in a way that allows me
to
add a specific user id to this jwt
and another one being the set subject
that allows me to set the subject as the
specific username that i want to be
so then
if we want to pose as any user
we need
the user id
and luckily there's an api call you can
use
to
just search for a specific user using
the username
and the endpoint just returns the id
so the id is public and it's not secret
and then we can use the generated jwt
to for example change the account
description
which is like as the status you can set
and here i'm using the put request
my generator jwt
and i'm setting the description to
hacked and the api says okay that's fine
and then i've effectively changed the
description of another user
that i don't even have a password for
so which means
it is a server side issue
that has to be mitigated on the server
side so jwts for authenticated users
should be validated using another key
that's secret
and the app doesn't have to be changed
but it's always a strange thing to do
to add the signing key
to
to the app that's accessible for any
user
so what did we actually learn there are
many ways to use r2 and 3d to analyze
apps
and i found r2 frida 2 work really well
when reversing complex applications
so yeah that's it
i've also
published a blog post for this if you
want to read it
and i guess the issue was patched by the
vendor
after some back and forth
so yeah that's it
thanks for having me
hmm
[Music]
mmm
thank you
so
[Music]
bye
wow
[Music]
two
[Applause]
[Music]
do
my
this
them
[Music]
my
so
[Music]
hmm
my
[Music]
ah
[Applause]
hmm
[Music]
i'd like to talk about how chao chin
free more inter integrate with r2
and mostly i will focus on the details i
didn't cover in my last hi tv talk if
you
if you if you didn't didn't watch that
talk normal i will do a fast recap
so first of all the recap the in in the
last tv ams to 2021
i i did i did the talk on on when chile
meets right there too and and how how we
implement our symbolic execution based
on radar 2 and the cheating framework
and today i'd like to focus on some
interesting details and mostly you know
the black magic behind the whole thing
so fast recap of cheating framework
cheating provides almost the best
dynamic instrumentation experience for
example is system infumination and you
have flexible hook and snapshot and a
full control of the sandbox and so
what's next
so we thought we think for a long time
what what's the next of cheating
framework and our answer is we we have
to expand the ability to to analyze that
both dynamic analysis and static
analysis and the best and the the best
solution is to r2 since it's free you
know the free software is open source
and it's the best alternative not not at
the person
so also our first demo is symbolic
execution
so about r2 you know r2 is the swiss map
of the engine reverse engineering and
it's and but it also has almost the
steepest learning curve you have to
learn different command and
and and sometimes the source is your
best friends often or as often the case
i have to read the puzzle to know which
command i need
and i but you could find almost
everything yes everything you need for
security analysis for example you want
to design both instructions you want to
show the control flow and you could
debug and it also has tons of utilities
for example the question market method
rate and what we cheat what we cheating
team really focus on is the esl the
available streams intermediate language
and it uses reverse polish notation
designed for interpretation and suitable
physical execution
so first of all in unit you know r2 is
written in say in c language and the and
the cheating it is written in past
number so there needs a bridge
and and the existing solutions are to
pipe and r are long arctop was only
available passing binary at that time
but it required rather to be installed
in system-wide and we hope to minimize
the cheating installation to pip install
so we don't want user to to execute
various very commands to just to install
a dependency
so
so the archive not suitable for for the
direct use along with the other way is
running a passive interpreter in r2 and
it seems good but it backs to wrong
standalone and it's still system-wide r2
installation is required so i decided to
to reinvent the view
so i wrote a brand new bathroom binding
for r2 r2d 2d bar so how it works r2
headers is clean enough to do auto
generation for
almost every api is marked with our api
and the bindings are generally
automatically set up and the github ci
so in this talk i would cover
the the detail of this part
so connect so actually how it works we
have the header from red r2 and we
expect patency type bindings and the two
is c type slip two it's a bank and by
deploy and and it pass this the c hider
and the up to the ast and and produce
the passing script from the ast but it's
not actually maintained it has it has it
has many bugs and for example there are
many issues at risk to to fix some bugs
which we avoid which
which prevent the generation
and and and the that's all so so
uh with the box fixed and we could
generate the generate the python
bindings similarly no no so let's see
the real black magic first of off ru2
unlike other r2 modules it is managed by
multiple headers there there are no r2
api in in the hydra file as you can see
it is include ru2 i even are as a
sub headers but so c types we won't
generate symbols in included headers or
or for example
if if it did if you do generate symbols
indicator headers the headers like
like stdio and st will be also generated
so c types won't generate symbols in
included
headers so what's ours what's my
solution i do the do the expansion
manually like the standard c
preprocessor preprocessor and i applies
it at the unexpected header for example
here as you can see i generated a brand
new header are you two gin dot h
it is composed of all all these headers
just copy their content to this head
these headers by the by the cycles and
you can get this big file and generate
all symbols from this file
so so that that's do enough we still
have more black magic so after we
generate generate the bindings we have
to put everything together unfortunately
statistically designed to output a
single screen for example you have a you
have a header you have a source file it
just generate that that that script and
and you can only use with that script
you you but we would like a library you
know we want just the frequent you
import the bar and and you get
everything so we have to try to put
everything together so my solution is to
mangle output by
regular expression yeah it's 30 i know
it's 30 indeed but it's really it works
basically this is the only way i could
think about that that could solve the
problem and it gives each r module a
separate name space and and and i remove
the local parts generated for example
my my local path is generated and and
make it relative and i read the wrapper
to use the relative parts to load all
our lips
so the last blend match you know it's
messing well you you
you may you mean you may not imagine
what's the problem with method
so first of all we would like to cross
platform so i choose messen but it has
very quickly bug on mac os then here i
give it i give a link but basically in
summary you can't use relative paths to
refer dynamically on my um mess and
build libraries
so it's really frustrating you know i
tried many many times and finally i
found it's a backup medicine
so what's my solution and then not and
another black magic i pass the libraries
you know it's it's microphone it's a
macro files and they rewrite the
downloader path so it's the last blank
magic and put all this black met
together what you get in a working
artery bar a passive bindings
so that's our 2d bar and next i will
cover some details about how the simple
execution
implemented
so
i asked excuse the concept and ask the
concept and demo if if you uh if you are
from unfamiliar with this part you could
go to the hitbe uh hide youtube channel
and and understand my so my demo and and
some concept introduction so for for
today's talk i just start from the
difficulty so i could introduce the
details
so first of all the implementation is
much complex than expected artw itself
doesn't have memory
implemented so we have to do it our own
and also we can use r2 registers
implementation due to we have to store
symbolic values and as a result we did
the full re-implementation of esl no not
all the r2 is still responsible for the
design resemblance but the interpreter
is implemented by ro and it may become
another mullah engine to replace unicorn
i will discuss this later and the
symbolic execution is never suitably you
know sometimes really really slow since
you have to keep every state immutable
also i know there are many there are
many things optimized but but but in
theory you have to keep each state and
the state would be exploded for complex
function and make it acceptable slow
so let's see so some details first of
the memory
so why why would i like to re implement
memory
since we had so we would like the memory
that holds symbolic values and it should
support full clones since we since the
memory you know a memory object or the
memory of the stage should be immutable
and it also
it should support a memory map and a map
and the under under the implementation
so the um the memory itself is managed
by segments
so every time ever
i mean you couldn't just allocate a very
long array and and and allow user to
read values you have to you have to use
segments every time user writes a
rest to a
address you you allocate a new segment
just like the page tables but but i
implement a simpler version so it's
managed by segments every time user
writes to energize you
you create a segment and insert to
current segment array and
you know it's really complex that
expected for example when i insert the
segment i have to
have to check the overlap segment and
the merge emerge or merge segment or
delete some existing segment and replace
it with a new one so it's really really
complex
and the second implementation is the
register information again the reason is
that we would like the register to hold
the symbolic values and it also should
support fulcrum since we we need we need
an immutable copy for each state but but
but fortunately it's much simpler than
memory
and the most importantly we do a full
representation of the esl interpreter
so first first of all since we have
implemented the memory and registers so
it's impossible to use r2 implementation
and in orientation the the most
important part is how we handle symbolic
values when we encounter a branch
uh when we uh here here is a code
snippet when we we
encounter a branch for example if here
we
we ate the cut with the conditions to
the
conditions for example here source
source that equal to zero and
and then after we we we interpret
this macro code we we
searched the possible the possible pc
for example we just
we just ate the condition of the true in
this function we could search whether it
could be false or or other branch
so
in in this case yes also really a nest
reference and and i indeed i i learned
many symbolic execution knowledge from
esl so and still wait to our unique
automation on our side
so for future you may ask why you you
gave the talk uh simple education three
months ago why students don't you still
don't
make it public or open the store open
source
so basically the the symbol execution is
still in heavy development and what and
what uh and i was doing is unicorn two
yes so uh so
so
in order in order to
to release the symbolic execution we are
waiting for the unicor 2 to be released
and and then we may have the engine
module and we can introduce esl as a new
engine and and then we can implement the
symbolic execution based on the esl and
then we we have uh the better a better
collection of the
extension
and and you could and and for the for
the first
for the future steps sorry i have a
table here this is your future steps
firstly we would we just released the
evm and and the and i
and i'm i'm working on unicorn 2. yeah
it's a brand it's a brand new version of
unicorn 2. now not only i ate some
not only it is bumped to cumula a higher
qmi5 you know you know unicorn it uh
originally is based on cumin 2 which is
quite old and unicorn 2 is is based on
cumin phi and and also i ate
very uh
a lot of a lot of exciting features and
and also also yeah our cheating team uh
recently what is working on some some
sacred projects based on uc 2 and its
new features
and and then after after we release
usually two and they release this
security this secret project and we are
going to introduce esl as an alternative
engine to to unicorn i mean and and
after that after that we we could we
could introduce the the rest of our two
components uh to
to for example implement symbolic
execution and the various stack analysis
so so that's all the all the future
steps
and last for credits so first off the
rather rather two for the next project
and certainly for our truly bar
implementation is also for the reference
an anchor for the design reference these
these three for the excellent silver and
pancake for the timely health
so that's all thank you
[Music]
me
um
[Music]
so
foreign
[Music]
hey
so
[Music]
[Applause]
foreign
[Music]
oh
my
[Music]
so
uh
you