One of the major points that is created here is the networking
I have pupils from the last year that still writes me
and I keep the contact with them
To exchange opinions, share information about threats and
well, is very interesting in this respect.
It is an initiative that in my opinion is a success.
I have several years of international experience
and I believe that there is no other country
as far as I know, using this format.
To make different countries, cultures
and different ways of working come together.
It´s almost two very intense weeks
in which there is much talk
a lot of collaboration and information exchanging
and I think it is something very positive.