well welcome back ladies and gentlemen
trust you enjoyed your afternoon tea saw
a couple of people wandering in with the
schooners out of the combi keg situation
we've got set up for you there so we're
enjoying afternoon tea hope you really
enjoyed the parallel streams as well
don't forget if you are missed something
during the course of the day or if
there's two things you would rather go
to at the same time obviously you can't
etc
all of the content generated in the
conference exists on the on air platform
for i think it's three months after the
conference then goes to youtube as well
so if you miss something or want to take
in it again make sure you do use that
facility we've got three short sharp
keynotes for you this afternoon before
we wrap up and start to prepare for our
gala dinner we're about to hear from the
director of information security program
at anu with over 15 years experience
in program management public sector
governance and senior leadership roles
have previous roles include the cyber
engagement manager at the anu national
security college program manager at the
cyber institute and executive director
of the academy of social sciences in
australia suffice to say when i clicked
on her page at the onu staff website
this is what i got
alleged phone number alleged email and
that profile and that's all so to put a
face to the silhouette to talk to us on
the topic of beyond the bridge from
legacy to zero trust a woman of mystery
please welcome liz west
[Applause]
good afternoon uh that is me the lovely
photo of me taking a little while ago
it's fine
uh so firstly thank you to oscert and
the conference partners for welcoming to
speak to me to speak to you today my
name is liz west and i'm the director of
uh information security program at the
australian national university
sothogracy ratnam anu's iso was
scheduled to attend but was
unfortunately unable to make it and he
sends his apologies
like it says on the tin
i am here to talk about the anu data
breach specifically what came next and
the generational shift on our horizon
the anu was established in 1946 we're
ranked 20th in size for australian
universities but number one in the world
university rankings
a major focus of our mission as a
university is to conduct research which
transforms society and creates national
capability
we're also a commonwealth government
authority we seek to be that bridge
between research academia governance and
policy
this designation also means that we are
subject to additional scrutiny and
regulation
and the entire higher education sector
has just been made critical
infrastructure which is fun
the anu has an annual turnover of 1.3
billion dollars 4 500 staff and roughly
20 000 students
and we are a target
every day every second every click just
like many of you
in november 2018 a spearfishing email
kicked off a campaign that would lead to
a breach of the anu's administrative
systems
as our vice chancellor put it this
wasn't a smash and grab it was a diamond
heist it's likely they spent months
gathering intel on anu and planning the
attack
they used custom-built malware and
zero-day hacks to exploit unknown
vulnerabilities in our systems
and they dismantled their operations as
they went to cover their tracks
the breach comprised of three main
elements the attackers used multiple
spear phishing campaigns to try and gain
credentials targeting elevated
privileges in particular
once they got on the network they
started stiffing for more
the attackers built a shadow
ecosystem of compromised anu machines
tools and network connections and from
this they built their mapping and attack
stations
and finally
the attackers used a variety of methods
to extract
stolen data and credentials via email
and other compromised anu systems
if you want to know more about the how
of the data breach you can find it in
the public report that anu published the
report is the culmination of months of
investigation into the hack it outlines
the incredible level of sophistication
behind it as well as a detailed timeline
of what happened and when
in fact it was during this investigation
that we found a second attack and
disrupted it
the report was made public for a number
of important reasons
to offer transparency to our community
to take ownership of our weaknesses and
to make a public promise to do better to
not let this happen again
and importantly to encourage disclosure
of these types of attacks more broadly
as our vc put it i want my pain to be
your gain so that we know what we are up
against
we wanted to encourage the practice of
an early warning system
we've had we've carried this theme into
the selection criteria of the tools that
we implement tools that feed threat
intelligence detected in one environment
back into the machine learning to
protect the rest of the environment are
going to have a greater protection long
term
as an aside the breach report has been
translated into four languages including
russian and mandarin and is on the dark
web as a training tool it is important
to note because i have been asked before
this wasn't done by us
the two attacks were an act of
organizational trauma a violation that
robbed us of the trust that we had in
our systems and our processes and in our
people
but it was also a singular point of
clarity
the university had to take a sharp right
turn overnight into a new security
posture and start the rapid uphill climb
to get anu secure
this was the new normal
the focus and the risk of the breaches
also gave us an opportunity to surge
resources to gain control and had
decision makers listening when we called
for change
after the first breach a ciso was
appointed who reports directly to the
vice-chancellor once he was installed he
started gathering anyone at the anu who
knew the systems and how to protect them
into a task force
where we had gaps and we had many we had
found industry partners to assist
from that the information security
office was born
as an entity we have one goal to keep
amu safe and credible the focus of our
efforts is entirely on the anu community
we don't have all the answers we haven't
even finished asking ourselves all of
the questions but we've learned a few
things that might be of interest to you
today
a couple of slides back i mentioned the
attackers leveraged unknown
vulnerabilities in our systems
the vulnerabilities were unknown because
our systems weren't well documented well
controlled or well understood
this was not the result of malice more a
lack of prioritization high workloads
focused on user needs
and a situation where the small gains
weren't keeping up with the evolving
threat
and we're not alone in this companies
around the world have reported that a
lack of visibility
of what is in their environment is a can
of worms they're too afraid to open
much like the theme of this conference
we needed to rethink reskill and reboot
the university needed to rethink its
priorities our assumptions about what
was on our network and how it was being
used the current and future environments
and the functions we actually needed to
serve
we also needed to better understand what
normal looked like so that we could
detect suspicious behavior
we needed to re-skill to uplift
capabilities not just of our support
staff but of all of our users
and our processes and our tools and
technology
while establishing career clear
priorities is critical that was the easy
part we're in the uplift phase now
laying the groundwork for the
future-proof next phase
for us the reboot phase is a
generational shift to zero trust
principles in our environment
this includes a new network an overhaul
of identity management and the removal
of passwords on our core systems
and while considering what normal looks
like we had some cleanup to do as well
my apologies if that triggers anyone
those those are bad
so our new capability model centers on
the intersection
sorry i've gone too far on the
intersection of assets vulnerabilities
and threats pretty common language to
most of the people here but this is the
core of our approach
to understand our attack surface how we
will be attacked we need to know what we
have as assets and how they're
vulnerable
to understand the attacker's motivations
we need to know the value of those
assets and who may want to harm us
and to understand how we will be
attacked we need to know the threats
against us and our own vulnerabilities
where they all meet is our business risk
just like finance and hr
cyber is a risk to the business and
should be treated as such
moving to reskill
immediately after the breach we had to
tackle the unknown unknowns blind spots
and question marks
and the known unknowns answering the
question what is on our network and
should it be
the university was carrying a lot of
legacy infrastructure and a lot of
bespoke research and technical equipment
this meant a lot of tech debt leading to
a lot of security debt
we simply didn't know where we were
vulnerable and the state of our systems
further we had to untangle who owned
what and was responsible for maintenance
the anu is like its own city with all
the diversity and complexity that you
might expect
at any given time we have in the order
of 74 000 devices on our network
including workstations and servers
running windows linux apple hpe cisco
apc android unix among others
while some machines were centrally
managed by the university's i t
department some colleges run their own
some researchers would buy or build
their own kit and plug it in
and they're around twenty thousand
students with an average of three
devices each on the network
but the network is that one commonality
between all of these environments so the
majority of our early focus was in focus
there
we introduced technical safeguards
including firewall zoning mfa encryption
data de-risking and macro blocking
we partnered with industry to deploy a
network visibility tool across the
entire network we lit every door
dark corner and started ingesting
real-time data
we linked our npb to patch vulnerability
and privileged access tools
and where we had integrations and
improving automation to provide scale
and defense in depth
and when i say we lit all the dark
corners on the network this is what that
looked like
every dot represents a device but it
also represents a scientific or academic
aspiration
something we need to protect and in most
cases enable
in addition to the devices you'd expect
we have a lot of byod iot medical iot
operational tech and scientific
instrumentation
things that were purchased in 1970 and
cannot be upgraded
those clusters you see around the edges
are private networks within the anu
where someone clever decided to buy
something clever and plug it in
i'll talk about culture in a moment but
academics as a general rule have a
strong sense of personal ownership over
technology and data and we have to work
with that
the chaotic cluster at the bottom right
is the residential halls anu is also an
isp
we have to protect everything from a
student connecting to the network on the
cheapest gray market smartphone they can
find to a plasma fusion reactor with an
i p address
which is basically a sun
moving on
following the breach and the no holds
barred executive support for our remit
we rapidly introduced or upgraded a lot
of technology solutions in our
environment
some of this was just actioning upgrades
that had been on the back burner
others were whole scale reforms we
introduced new tools took ownership of
tools that needed to be fixed or worked
hand-in-hand with the area responsible
for a tool to uplift it
our approach to technology and tools is
modular
the backbone of our environment is the
network and the tools plug into this
spine
we are not beholden to one stack or
technology partner we look for
functionality integration automation and
importantly alignment with the
university's values
some of these tools already form the
core conceptual framing for xero trust
the same modularity can be said for the
frameworks we follow while we're guided
by ism and we're building our compliance
model against essential 8 and top 37
we also draw insights from nist and
other international standards
the university's environment is unique
and as such there's no one rule book to
follow
with the right funding and authority and
the right tools we were able to up
achieve a significant security uplift in
the first 12 months
we have continued to strengthen our
protection again and processes to keep
pace with the expanding threat against
us
in april this year we blocked over 14
million malicious attacks and intrusion
attempts we blocked 307 000 phishing
attempts
due to the tuning of our mail filtering
and education for our staff the success
rate of phishing campaigns that is
getting to the point where a user clicks
a link
is now down to 0.12 percent
we're also actively black blocking
around 20 000 malicious ip ranges and
domains per day
as we modernize our tools and clarified
our understanding of our environment we
needed to change the way we do business
we started using the data feeds from our
new tools to profile the network
specifically we looked at device
identification the characteristics of
those devices communication channels
protocol analysis
building a complete asset inventory
linked to criticality
and revisiting current policies and
procedures to see if they align to best
practice or even current practice
now that we knew what we had we shifted
to threats we focused on ingesting
intelligence and understanding tactics
techniques and procedures
improving our capability to detect
external and internal reconnaissance
activity
our openness to lateral movement
the motivation of threat actors and what
they might target
and an alert system for exfiltration
attempts
while analysis analyzing threats we also
undertook to better understand our
weaknesses and vulnerable abilities by
linking network data to device profiles
undertaking continual health checks and
monitoring introducing and auditing
technical controls like patching
improving hardening and auditing admin
controls improving perimeter controls
and putting everything through a risk
management framework
and that's the last simpsons gif
probably
everything that i've just outlined every
effort we undertake has a particular and
intentional focus
we view information security as a human
centric challenge one which frames our
behavior and decisions at the
intersection of people process and
technology within our environment
behind every data breach behind the
technical detail is a human-centric
story full of emotion
the biggest threat to security is at the
end of the keyboard but they are also
our greatest protection if they know how
to be vigilant and what is and isn't
right behavior
this leads us nicely into the final
section of reskill our people
for us this is the anu community
students professional staff academic
staff researchers partners and alumni
re-skilling the environment affecting
real change means changing the behavior
of our users
teaching them how to operate in a more
secure manner and how to be vigilant to
threats
this means changing both our approach
and their mindset
changing the mindset is multifaceted and
subtle hackers don't just hack systems
they hack people
the cyber threat actors hack your
culture all the time why can't the
defenders do it too
successful cyber programs have in their
dna a strong change management component
so we needed to borrow from behavioral
psychology and organizational change
management among others
in our case we were fortunate enough to
have the psychologists just across
campus
they helped us design a human-centric
program based on reinforcing personal
accountability using empathy and
understanding ensuring a positive
security experience and obvious value
communicating the benefits before the
risks and defending our values and our
purpose
this we needed to do at every level of
the organization and we're still hard at
it
our cultural change program is called
cybersense it aims to use the skills and
understanding that we give to these
participants to apply scrutiny and
common sense to the environment we give
them the confidence to scrutinize
this program which kicked off in 2021
comprises online and bespoke training
videos road shows resource libraries and
tools that researchers and staff can use
to help make them be safer
with upwards of 2500 users that is 2500
opportunities for error but it's also
2500 opportunities for cyber champions
already we're seeing a significant
increase in disclosures from staff who
think they have clicked a dodgy link who
noticed suspicious activity in their
email account or just want us to check
something that feels wrong
even our own legitimate emails usually
mine
get reported and pinged for being overly
opaque or for encouraging urgent action
so we're learning from that too we need
to change our language and we need to
understand our audience
for cyber sense as you can see we've
leaned hard into the quirky side of the
university we use humor to affect change
to make messages that cut through and
are memorable
you might recognize some of the faces up
on the slide right now there are
chancellor julie bishop former foreign
minister
vice chancellor brian schmidt
nobel prize winner and comedian chris
ryan
the former let us animate them because
of how much they believe in our body of
work
the latter did because we paid her and
it was funny
so we did a rethink of who what and why
we are we started a body of work to
reskill our technology our processes and
our people
the next phase of our journey is the
reboot retiring the old and starting
anew on a platform that will be able to
support and secure the university's
growth a zero trust environment based on
infrastructure as code
it's important to understand what zero
trust is and is not
zero trust is an architectural principle
based on the removal of implicit
automatic trust and the introduction of
explicit constantly verified trust or
adaptive trust
this principle can form the basis of
identity and authorization on more than
just networks and it can should be
linked to business intent
we're applying zero trust as a lens
through which we build our modern
infrastructure
but zero trust is not an off-the-shelf
product one technology tool that you can
plug in or firewall rule that you can
set
the paradigm of zero trust as a
foundational principle of infrastructure
replaces what we currently have
insecure disparate and high maintenance
processes
with a modern system that is secured by
design the new network will bring
together multiple activities systems and
functions into one
system with less tooling and
inconsistency
zero trust for amu means infrastructure
that is resilient adaptive and enabling
zero trust takes a more granular
approach than traditional castle and
moat network security
every application every person every
device must prove its identity and
authority before every session and once
authentication has occurred they only
get least privileged once they're in
there
xerotrust is also software defined so ie
infrastructure is code
software defined means utilizing
programming for interfaces source code
to manage configure and reconfigure the
network this means the network is highly
customizable very quickly and distinct
from traditional networks which rely on
hardware reconfiguration to make changes
sometimes this is also called
programmable infrastructure it also
allows for the creation of repeated
patterns and automation which makes
configuration and reconfiguration even
easier still
implementing xero trust involves
building the right systems from the
ground up which means it needs funding
support and engagement
so what why have you all come to listen
to me speak today
does the anu's journey from breached to
more secure create a roadmap for others
to follow
i think it does
our hard learned lessons can act as a
guide like the man said our pain can be
your game
keep in mind that your unique strengths
and problems will form a unique solution
so a couple of bits of advice
first have compassion for your starting
point it's the place to build from it's
the place to learn from
if you don't know what you have you
don't know what you can leverage and
what you have to protect
map your environment map with realistic
capability map your behavior
know your assets your vulnerabilities
and your threats
and apply empathy when looking inward
it's not us versus them it's just us
understand the norms of your
organization and their relationship with
the technology
understand the behavior that needs to
change at every level
build a plan around that behavioral
change a plan that's well defined and is
easy to
support a plan that removes fake
friction and adds value
set realistic but slightly ambitious
goals
work the problem in a logical order
linked to risk
build borrow and buy the skills and
tools required if you buy and borrow
make a plan to build so you have
internal capability
choose partners that align to your
values and will be there alongside you
when things go right and wrong
because they will
if you underpin infrastructure change
with behavioral change you'll achieve a
more sustainable outcome
build for your future needs
build a solution not a fix
and finally add value and earn the right
to optimize
thank you
[Applause]
thank you very much please please enjoy
the gift as well the taka gin made by
some indigenous female distillers here
in australia wonderful stuff i do know
also the chancellor i'm sorry the vice
chancellor at anu brian schmidt of
course who won the nobel prize for
physics a few years back for his team
showing the universe was continuing to
expand and explain increasing rate was
going to collapse on itself while it's
not his specialty area he would just
totally geek down on this sort of stuff
wouldn't he he would have absolutely
loved to give liz another round of
applause thank you what a great great
presentation very honest very open not
unlike brett's one this morning our next
speaker is a specialist in threat
intelligence and threat hunting he works
in the virus total team in google as a
threat intelligence strategist he's been
a crime manager in s21 sec for five
years he was deputy director for eu and
kaspersky's global research analysis
team for almost 10 years he's here to
take us on an adventure from threat
hunting to actionable threat intel from
virustotal this is vicente diaz
[Applause]
oops
so i was attending i was paying
attention
to the previous talk
and i realized i was very hungry and i
was like why is that it's because for me
it's breakfast i'm from barcelona spain
so
apologies if if i look like a little bit
confused at some point but yet lucky as
well
so i've been
home for the last two years because of
kovit like everybody else
and so this is my first business trip
since then
and i chose like
the opposite side of the world basically
to travel
and i don't know if that was the best
idea but i'm really thankful for
inviting me for this conference and i'm
really enjoying so far
um okay so let's go back to our
presentation today my name is kitten tv
and thank you very much once again for
inviting me for this conference and
for the last 10 years before joining by
aristotle
i was in kaspersky and we were
investigating apt attacks basically
so
from my experience there i wanted today
to share some of the ideas lessons
learned and how how i think that things
have changed
during all this time
because these days we're all talking
about threat intel but it's not so clear
how to use it and
now in barista i have the opportunity to
see how many of our customers are
dealing with all these threat intel
and
sometimes well
i would like to share a little bit where
is my vision maybe you appear or not but
i think it's interesting to discuss
so
the first question when i was preparing
this presentation is why we do threat
hunting what is the reason behind and
basically the answer is to get some
context we want to know hey i have these
indicators of compromise i saw this
happening in my company in my computer
and i want to get more context i want to
know a little bit more this is basically
the main reason we are doing this handy
but also we want sometimes to detect
something new we do this paleontology we
discovered these big campaigns in the
past and we are creating like a better
understanding of how attackers are using
different tools and techniques in order
to infect us right
um
and this changed a lot in the la during
the last years basically i would say the
difference the main difference is that
now
we have much more data to share
and this is not necessarily something
good because by having that much data um
it's computationally difficult sometimes
to understand things
and also we've been basically building
as we were encountering things as we
were understanding how to deal with all
that
and at some point
this created a lot of noise
that keeps stacking is making this a
snowball effect and at the end
something small like somebody
intelligence from the very beginning
keeps growing and today we are making
maybe some bad attribution based on some
report that was published eight years
ago uh where there was some
misunderstanding about this group this
sector et cetera et cetera so this is a
danger that we are having so much intel
so much data
and the data that we are having for
threat intel it was not
well it was not designed to be sure in
the the best efficient way for instance
if i share with you
uh this ip
this is some random publication i i got
it from otx
alimbold
and i was taking a look this is from a
publication from asset and they are
talking a thing is about set net
so
this ap if i share with you today and i
say hey this ip is malicious
you will be asking yourselves okay why
well in this case it's a domain sorry
but you will be asking yourselves why is
malicious
what is behind
and since when this is malicious
in reality
i was checking the report
and what they said is that this was
compromised and was serving some malware
so my question here for you is should we
block it
or not
well it's it depends right depends what
is your purpose with this but what i'm
saying is that
basically what we do is we get any
publication we get all the iocs we put
the text yes set need malicious
and we throw it into some thread into
the system
and from here if we don't read the
original report
then we don't know why
when how et cetera et cetera we will
simply say hey this is segment activity
maybe it's not
so it's just a silly example what is
reflecting what i want to say here that
this noise keeps growing
to make things a little bit more
complicated in the past we had like all
these attacks uh
different groups creating their own
malware we have like different
signatures we have
uh like good understanding what kind of
tool sets different actors were using
this is not the case anymore
where most of the attackers are using
more or less the same stuff if i say
i don't know
cobalt strike
mimikats
all this kind of stuff is what attackers
are using
over and over
in many cases like we saw this morning
uh lapsus group
what are they using basically they're
stealing credentials and from here they
are able to get whatever they want so
it's not about sometimes the complexity
of the malware
and there is not such a thing like a
signature for the groups we started
creating ttps
which is
it sounds good on paper but later it's
very difficult to characterize a group
by ttps without any technical further
details
because eventually all the groups are
like fulfilling
all the boxes in the
enterprise attack metrics
but still i think that
if we are conscious of all these
difficulties there is a value in threat
hunting
and in my opinion
i would say there are like three main
things we can do when we do threat
hunting or
three main benefits of doing threat
hunting the first one
is having the knowledge
uh
to shape our security strategy so
sometimes we don't know how to start
sometimes we are making decisions based
on we don't know what
but this data exists today and with this
data we can shape what and we can
prioritize how should build our security
strategy let's say one simple example
ideally we want to have all the
vulnerabilities patch in our environment
but we don't know where to start we
don't know which ones are more critical
yes there are like cvss score so from
here we can say this is more critical
than that
but which one is being used today right
now by attackers
the most do you have an answer for this
the thing is that you can get an answer
for this and from here you can decide
like
i'm worried or not i should prioritize
this or another one
um
maybe in these campaigns for a more
comprehensive vision of the attacks this
is like the second goal and i think this
is extremely important because many
times
our conception of
our idea of the attacks
when they come from osint is like
publication iocs
end of the story may we have sanjar
rules that's it but it takes some effort
to actually follow the campaign and to
understand how it evolves
is some effort not much
but many people or many companies
in my experience they don't do this
extra step and the value is here
because the publication is at some point
in time
but the campaign goes on
so you need to see how it evolves and
you need to readjust a little bit just
to make sure that you are having a good
understanding how it's evolving
and finally for discovering new
malicious activity in this case
depends if you want i don't know to
discover something to make a
presentation here for instance or you
want to well
to check for anomalies that could be
related to your main activity to your
main infrastructure technologies etc etc
so i have some examples for all of these
the first thing is as we discussed about
this campaign tracking and monitoring
one of the things that i see many times
is that
yara rules for instance are not updated
they are taking like they are in some
cases
many of these are rules these days are
created automatically which is a good
thing is saving us a lot of time
but when these rules are created
many times they are overfitting
the samples that are used for the
research
meaning that they are detecting very
well these samples but maybe they don't
escalate so well
so sometimes we need to keep
working on them as they move on
sometimes we also see that the yard
rules are created from different malware
families which results in
uh
the rules are not so good and well what
i want to say is that just making this
effort to make sure that we are on top
of the campaigns and monitoring how they
evolve is bringing us a much complete
vision of how attackers are
creating their campaigns and what kind
of malware they're using
uh the second thing is the discovery new
activity actually yesterday we were
doing uh some worship here
um
and in the in the meantime we were doing
some exercises i just started taking a
look into this so i would like to share
with you if you don't mind
and
why i'm sharing this is just an example
um looks like the connection is not
great but happily i have it here open
already so this is just an example of
the
of the kind of things that we can do
these days
and
and this is saving a lot of time and
this is giving us a very good idea of
what's happening so i found this
document
this is a document that
for real i found yesterday i never seen
before
and this document
was related to
to some activity pretending to be
related to the war in the ukraine
here is called u.s analyze provide
chemical weapons to ukraine's military
and actually i found that from the same
domain
here
we found all these different documents
all of them
were served um
that all of them were submitted to
aristotle by one submitter
different submitters but only one which
means it's pretty targeted all of them
came from different countries
if you see the countries hungary italy
ireland great britain
czech republic
denmark lithuania
and iceland
and all of them
were related to the same topic the
chemical the kremlin's allegation of
chemical and biological weapons
putin face claims or whatever
so all of them also were first in two
days ago in barista for the first time
so i started taking a look and from here
i discovered well
that this is related to some emoted and
again
this took like a few minutes just for me
to understand at least the context
and these days we can do things like
that
we can go into any of these documents
and we can search for similarities
like similar files
and
immediately we will get some results as
you can see here so all these files are
similar to this one
and if we take a look to these ones
nato's general who were hiding in the
underground bunker whatever
saying
name list of nato generals so they are
all slightly different chemical weapons
but they are all part of the same
cluster so this kind of technologies is
something that 10 years ago when we were
doing this apt research we didn't have
and today we do
and this is thanks first for having a
big database that we've been growing all
the community together
and second by incorporating new
techniques that allow us to do this
in a very agile way so thanks to these
things
these days
you can use thread hunting for
discovering new activity and get the
context pretty immediately which is
great in case we find something
suspicious
finally we were talking about monitoring
trends for this knowledge-based security
strategy and here i wanted to share some
of the discoveries we did during last
year when we were monitoring
changes
in malware trends between 2020 and 2021
uh just based on very subtle data
so with those in these two years of
malware
we got some interesting ideas
the first one
was regarding the use of exploits
so we found not only that there was a 37
percent increase in the number of
samples that were implementing some
exploitation
they were using things like a power
shell for instance much more than before
exploiting at least nine different
vulnerabilities with power shell
but the average of the most popular
exploits being deployed in the wild
dropped
crazily
in reality from 93 days to zero days it
doesn't mean that every single
vulnerability was the same day that it
was published already in barista it
doesn't mean that but this is the
average meaning that some of them were
significantly before at least for the
most popular ones
and we also found
57 zero days
vulnerabilities that were deployed in
the wild so it means that
attackers they have resources in this
case for zero days and
well i wouldn't say this is something
that revolutionary to find anymore they
simply have access to them
the second thing is how they were
moving to new formats this is also
interesting
like moving from docx files infected to
excel files
infected in the in reality it's the same
there are simply macros behind
but in
our perception is that maybe this has to
do with social engineering like you know
that documents are malicious but maybe
you are not sure about excel files and
you are opening them we saw some big
campaigns for instance deploying dry
decks
using this
there was a huge increase in the number
of l files that we saw in various hotel
and the reason for this was also
log4j
obviously which was implementing this
for some mirai tsunami
and some coin miners this vulnerability
in order to spread the malware as fast
as possible so this was one of these
events that
somehow it could it has the potential to
change everything this kind of
vulnerabilities
we also saw
how they are switching their tool set
from some rats from some different
backdoors to new ones or even to all
ones that they were
reshaped
for instance things like drydex we saw
an increase of almost 1 000 well not
almost one thousand three hundred
percent
uh a cigarette also
an increase of one hundred and thirty
percent
while other rats basically disappear
from byrosotta like this gravity rat or
dorkbot here you can see for instance
in this chart the number of loot caps
for cobalt strike
and well what is funny is that if you
see the other part of the chart which as
you have included here
you see first the submissions and then
you see the lookups so basically first
they are submitted to various total they
are being exploited later and people is
searching for them like what is that
but basically you can keep an eye
first in what kind of malware attackers
are using and make sure that you are
good protected against that and second
in many cases we don't pay attention to
all these generic backdoors and rats
just because they are all and we are
like
who cares about this rat if it is
detected or not
but this is the first step in the kill
chain of the attackers to deploy
whatever it is in this case drydex i was
super surprised but still
we also saw sea loader
being used by attackers to deploy
a lot of ransomware so it's interesting
because still this malware has uh an
important role by attackers
so just to finish my presentation
um
just to to double down on these ideas i
think that this constant evolution for
threat hunting
is something that
if we are conscious of the limitations
is a good thing uh because we can use it
in a much more efficient way but we need
to define the goals that we want to
accomplish
i think
that just simply accumulating iocs and
accumulating data without any purpose at
the end of the day is a problem
we need to put a little bit of effort
just to do this monitoring as i said and
to make sure that all the data that we
are ingesting
is is valid is solid um because this at
the end of the day we don't do that
this snowball effect is created and then
we can make big errors uh when assessing
our intelligence
but still i think that the potential is
is tremendous i think that this is
something
that
we are all exploring together we are all
growing this is a new set of techniques
that is changing uh with time as well as
the tools that we are using
so
still i think is a vital element for any
security strategy and thanks
to the new technologies we can start
using this but
again the most important thing is to
define the goals how we want to use it
so we can make something out of this
so that will be everything thank you
very much and i will be around if you
have any questions just let me know
thank you
am i the only person who's going to miss
dork bot
probably that's the way it goes thank
you very much for sending you can watch
for sunday tonight at the gala dinner
wrestling with his jet laggers he
alternates between complete fatigue and
a thousand percent energy give him
another round of applause that was a
wonderful chat mate real interesting
stuff
descending of course from virus total
one of our wonderful sponsors on the
topic of sponsors going to thank again
the platinum sponsors octa we heard from
brett this morning emt gigamon and
netscope did someone say netscope that
brings us to our final speaker for day
one of ulcer 2022 and experienced a cso
saiso strategic advisory investor and
coach he's currently the aipac cso for
netskope helping customers manage their
digital and cyber risk programs in
addition to working across the industry
with the owner making the digital
economy a safer place to do business to
talk about the integrated security model
security beyond just cyber brier
applause policemen david fairman
hello um welcome everyone i realize that
i think i'm the last session and you
hear this every sec every conference the
last session we
everybody's waiting for their drinks
i'll try and keep this quick
um but hopefully you'll learn a little
bit of something from my presentation so
look i'm just talking about my
experience
for those of you who don't know me i've
had a long career in banking finance
at the cso cso level
i've built two fusion centers one for
for nab
when i repatriated back to australia in
and i built one for rbc as well and and
i'm going to talk about the fusion
center and the integrated security model
and i i guess
maybe i think about it a little bit
differently to how other people sort of
view fusion centers uh
and i'll i'll explore that i'll explore
you know a couple of the techniques you
can use to think about
venturing into this space and more of
the point the outcomes we can achieve
so
what we'll discuss
i sort of covered that already so
complex environment we know that
you know the
i don't have to explain the threat
landscape and and the the rise in
sophistication and velocity and
sophistication of attacks here
but i think what's really interesting is
the
what we've seen as an evolution
over i would say
i'm actually going to say sort of 12
years
is
the expanding role of the cso or the
security officer
and i'll give you a little bit of a
history of my history my experience
so i think if we go back and we talk
about fusion centers where did the term
fusion center come from after 9 11 it
was really about how the intelligence
agencies came together to really share
intelligence in a lot better way because
we knew we found out
that they weren't communicating they
weren't sharing they didn't have the
situational awareness and there were
silos
and that actually led to exposures or or
lack of understanding of what was
happening in the threat environment
so that sort of started to drive through
government
and you found that
industry started to take on that process
as well or take on that concept and it
became very
um
i think the leaders in this space
personally was the european banks i'll
give you an example
i started at royal bank of scotland in
i worked in a division called security
and fraud so we had an integrating in
what i call the enterprise or the
integrated security model back in 2005.
you know i was part of the information
security function we reported into a
director of security and fraud
and that director of security and fraud
covered multiple functions information
security business continuity crisis
management
intelligence
physical security
fraud investigations
uh financial crime it was
and
if you look at rbs if you look at
barclays if you look at lloyds they were
operating in that space and they were
really starting to break down silos
between all these
uh you know front to back security
functions of the bank and we started to
realize that there was a lot better
situational awareness and
insights that we could
you know collaborate on and actually
make faster decisions around what was
happening
uh in terms of financial crime fraud and
even cyber threat back in the day
and i think if you you know if you
you think about that evolution that's
back in 2005 2007 through to 2010 the
u.s banks i think started to pick that
up obviously when i came to nab in 2018
nab was the first bank in australia and
a couple of these the uh you know other
australian organizations i want to call
that iag and nbn you know they had
brought fraud and cyber security
together that's great that's sort of one
part of it you look at iag today they've
really started to move through that
process where they're bringing fraud
investigation cyber physical together
but nab was the first bank to do that
here cba have just done that underneath
brendan good who's the new chief
security officer there at cba
but i think you know that those cso or
cso roles
are now expected we're expected now
these days to have a much broader
understanding of what's happening in the
business
understanding
what impacts are happening to our
customers
and
you know making much smarter faster
defense decisions
and i'm going to talk about that in a
little uh
in a second
so the journey to fusion i sort of
spoken about that evolution from an
operating model perspective
which is really breaking down the silos
of those functions
figuring out that end-to-end operating
when i talk about that end-to-end
operating model what are the handoffs
between these different functions and
it's not just i'm not just talking about
cyber fusion here i think we all talk
about cyber fusion we talk about
you know breaking down the silos between
our i don't know our pen testing teams
and our sock teams and our grc teams
that's sort of just running a cyber
function in my opinion
you know you need to make sure your your
core team is is communicating and you've
got clear handoffs but let's make this
bigger this must be much bigger than
just a cyber conversation it needs to be
an operational resilience conversation
and that's where you start to bring in
these other functions the fraud
functions the investigations functions
physical security business continuity et
cetera
and there's different sort of processes
you can you can take and you know
journeys in terms of for different
organizations but
you know what we start to see there is
really we start to see
a data driven approach
to how we start to solve and digitally
transform our own security function
and that's where i think fusion
has been really successful for
security functions we talk about digital
transformation
in our own business right we know that
our organizations are steaming down this
digital transformer all this
digitization or this digital strategy
they're doing that for a couple of
reasons one they don't want to take cost
out of the environment
and they want to create you know
productivity benefit but two they want
to
reap value
from that data they want to get greater
insights from that data they want to be
able to
understand their customer better they
want to be able to
understand what what products and
markets they want to enter into they
want to make smarter business decisions
the organization the business itself is
becoming this data driven organization
the fusion center in my view
is the security team's own digital
transformation or digital strategy
because we want to get greater insights
from that data we want to change and
transform the way that we've operated in
the past we want to take cost out
we want to simplify
but we want to reap value from that data
from my perspective
how do you start thinking about a
fusion center how do you define it how
do you put some shape around it it's a
great term
but i think there's a couple of things
that you need to i like to use to frame
what fusion actually means
creating a brain which is a new
the brain or or the the the core of how
we're going to start to make decisions
but we wouldn't understand what we want
to start making decisions about so what
are those shared goals and those shared
outcomes across all those various
functions
right clearly there's in a digital world
there's a massive and a clear
crossover between
our cyber security teams and our fraud
teams and when we talk about online
banking and we talk about mobile banking
digital payments
we can think about inside a threat
there's clear crossover there from an
insider threat or cyber perspective
physical security uh function
perspective
i think we want to
understand that there's a
big data play to be had here which is
the correlation of that data so bringing
together
not just the data sets but actually the
unification of activities so coming back
to that cross-function
front to back operating model
conversation i was just having
making sure that all those inputs coming
back to that 911
sample or example making sure that all
these inputs come into one control
center where you can add traffic control
and create better situational awareness
and integrated action so much better
detection and response capabilities the
idea of fusion is to be able to move
from this reactive state
to a more proactive and predictive state
and i actually do see a fusion center in
my experience being separate to a sock
you have your sock which is sitting
there looking at all the alerts and
monitoring doing the threat hunting
identifying actual
incidents or intrusions in your
environment responding to that solving
for that the fusion center is trying to
be predictive
it's trying to help you anticipate an
attack before that attack happens
whether or anticipate a fraud before a
fraud happens and we'll talk about some
success cases that i've seen before
so the converged
security model
you heard me talk about the various
functions
that you might want to bring together
there's a lot of value in those
disparate data sets
and actually bringing them back together
bringing them together and analyzing
that enriching that data with each other
and external threat data external
criminal related data
you can really start to drive proactive
uh
models and and
approaches to how you
you know increase that situational
awareness and
uh you know really
you know we talked about meantime detect
mean time to contain that same process
that same
you know metric applies across all of
those functions it's not just a cyber
measure
think about the co-location elements and
i think this is really tough in today's
world actually and
you know i haven't run it off a fusion
center in a remote working
environment but in my experience it was
about co-location getting these teams to
sit together
mixing those teams together so that
the digital for the the digital
forensics and incident response teams
would hear what the fraud teams were
talking about or would you know the
threat teams would hear what the
physical security teams were talking
about and i'll talk about threat i don't
mean just cyber threat i mean all threat
so physical threats geopolitical threat
you know social
social economic risk and bringing all
that in together because those
conversations that they have in one
fusion center where they're sitting side
by side
it spawns thinking it helps you join the
dots i actually really think that today
in that remote working world
we'd lose a little bit of that
cross-pollination of skill sets i think
that's really important that's a great
outcome that's a great benefit we know
that we're fighting
for talent today we know that there's
this skill shortage so how do we start
to
you know
understand some of those
duplications that we might have across
those functions as an example we have
investigations team and we have incident
response or digital forensics teams they
have some very transferable skills that
we can tap into and we can help create
some efficiencies in our operating model
but also we can start to
engage our teams better because now
actually a cyber person becomes a fraud
person a physical security person
becomes a threat person
and our teams are being stretched
they're learning more and they're
starting to be engaged a little bit more
i think that's a really great outcome
because that's one way of
maintaining and managing and engaging
your team and retaining your
i spoke about the reducing uh reducing
duplication and inefficiencies that's
great because we'll identify that
there's common elements across those
functions and we can streamline that we
can take cost out
and i think a real important thing and
this is really key i can't underestimate
how important this is is the battle
rhythm and the coordination so making
sure that you have a morning stand up in
that fusion center what are we seeing
across the environment
and it could be not just
uh you know like think broadly
what's happening from a bad weather
perspective do we expect bad weather to
increase you know in in a certain area
we're going to have to start thinking
about closing branches if you start
thinking about closing branches what
does that mean from a physical security
perspective is there activity we need to
take there right so really increasing
that situational awareness having those
battle rhythms having a morning stand up
having an afternoon stand up making sure
the teams are communicating effectively
then understanding how we synthesize
some of that information and enrich the
various functions
so what's right for your organization
i've spoken about my experience in
banking
in two organizations where we pulled
those elements together but no one size
fits all you know i spoke about nbn who
pulled i think actually they've got
fraud together now um iag recently just
pulled in their fraud function but they
just had the
the you know their start in this process
was uh physical and cyber
but i think you need to figure out
what's right for your organizations to
do that you want to think about
what your capabilities how mature are
those capabilities
and the key thing which i you know
you've heard me talk about is that
underlying data set
bringing those data sets together
understanding what data you do have
because there's no point really starting
on a journey
where the underlying data sets aren't
really going to help you then it just
becomes a
process element and it's more than just
for me the the
the
the completeness of the fusion center is
both the process and the data-driven uh
capability
understand what your biggest pain points
are that's a great way to start that'll
help you think about where do you need
to start first what are those areas that
make sense to bring together first
what data does your organization have
spoken about that more to the point what
further do you what further data do you
need do you know what your gaps are what
would make you so as you're thinking
about this journey in this roadmap what
are the data sets that are going to give
you biggest impact when i talk about
biggest impact
really it's about risk reduction
so risk buy down
data platform can't under can't i can't
underscore this enough
i spoke about digital transformation and
why our organization's going down this
path
fusion for me is a digital
transformation for security environments
or security teams security functions
it's about us
getting greater insights from the data
that we use all that data that we have
making much better
security decisions
faster security decisions
ideally becoming proactive
anticipating things before they happen
becoming
predictive and i'll talk about some of
those things in a minute so how do you
do that
data science plays a big part that comes
back to the operating model as well so
my two experiences
i owned the data science team i built a
data science team at rbc
and they were joined at the hip with my
threat and uh threat management team
i owned that which was fantastic because
i could really prioritize that in an at
nab i didn't own the data science team
but ultimately you want to use data
science big data analytics we know about
this we've spoken about this we talk
about how data is driving our decisions
and driving the way that we operate
today this is no different
use techniques like clustering analysis
neural networking it'll provide better
insights and predictive analytics i'll
give i'll give you some of those
success stories in a minute
so use cases and success stories
a couple of things i've seen is
preventative fraud indicators
think about it in a digital world
digital banking online banking mobile
banking
when you bring all these data sets
together and these functions together
we can see the entire data stream or the
entire click stream
from the endpoint the the laptop or the
pc or the mobile device
all the way through to the actual
transactions of the customer these
things you have that whole entire
lineage you can see all and when you're
continually monitoring that entire click
stream you'll start to identify outliers
variances
threats
which will allow you to be a lot you
know a lot more predictive in that
downstream impact which could result in
a fraud
being able to
predict that fraud
and reduce the impact on the customers
what we want to do right that's the goal
and actually what what you'll find is
and you know we had the success at rbc
where we actually
you know we lodged four patents when i
was there for predictive fraud
indicators which was fantastic outcome
for us and significantly reduced our
fraud losses as a result of the
analytics and the insights that we're
getting through this process or this
capability threat modelling enrich your
own threat modelling process because
you're going to have all this data
available and you're going to see
patterns you're going to see new use
cases
you're going to identify unknowns things
that we haven't seen before your threat
modeling from a security
and risk perspective and process
perspective gets much better so you feed
that back into your your your project
process
and your bau risk management process
so now you're you know you're having
this this complete cycle of these
unknowns that you probably wouldn't have
seen before
and this this this
now you have this path this gradual
maturity of uplift as that as those as
that modeling and those insights grow so
it really does start to ramp uh your
overall security posture
insider threat i think that's a actually
for me that's a quick win right so
bringing together the physical security
logs the logical logs and you'll start
to see anomalies really quickly i'm sure
a lot of us sort of do some of that
stuff today if you bring your physical
logs in together
opportunities and challenges
so
why should you do it so improve
visibility
efficiencies
move from a reactive detective and
reactive state to a more proactive state
actually what you probably find is like
i mentioned you're going to still have
your socks who are there to
detect and respond absolutely but you're
going to have this analytics
data driven capability that's going to
be allow you to
be more predictive be more controlled
optimizing value of existing systems
right between those various functions
that we spoke about this duplication and
types of systems a really good example
is case management
right having one case management system
across those functions enables a lot
better
handoff and visibility of
information in an in an investigation or
an incident
it also reduces cost of your operating
environment because now actually you're
not running two different systems two
different disparate systems you can say
you know there's a cost out
benefit there to be had
improved organizational resilience
ultimately that's what we're here for
right
cyber security is great but cyber
security is
i think
us as a profession have realized now
that we're never going to protect
everything that there is always going to
be an impact
you know the mindset now is around
resilience
and i think it's an operational
resilience it's just not a cyber
resilience element for me when i talk
about bringing together that enterprise
that integrated enterprise
integrated model
uh expect challenges along the way and i
can't underestimate i can't underscore
this enough
this is a massive change to how
organizations work and like
any change in any organization it
requires strong leadership it requires
taking people on that journey and
managing that organizational change the
technology is sort of the easy part i
think technology is getting easier
change is getting harder and actually
how do you get your organization to
change the way that they operate it
takes strong leadership and take strong
leadership not just from a security
leader but also from across the
organization because we're going to have
to
you know people are going to lose some
ground people are going to lose their
five times that they've built
but we you know that's when it comes
back to really having those shared goals
and making sure that we're all brought
in and we understand what we're trying
to achieve
it requires so some of the challenges is
new ways on how you're going to start to
connect these dots so maybe introducing
new technologies new capabilities like
that data science learning function
where to start
so i think you know
having done this a couple of times i
think there's a couple of quick ones you
can do that you can build on to take
this forward one is
identify those goals
that'll be most relevant to your
business not this not necessarily the
security function get out and talk to
your business leaders what are their
biggest challenges what are their
biggest concern about how do you
demonstrate value to your business
leaders
identify three or four of those
top goals that these various functions
need to work together to achieve
and that's going to start a process
in that you know that that human change
process that i spoke about or that that
organizational change process
is going to start people thinking about
and get them bought into that they'll
start to see success and they'll start
to see benefit
start function start somewhere so in rbc
as an example my peer who was the head
of fraud uh
we came up with fusion friday so
every friday we'd get part of the cyber
team and part of the fraud team and our
data science team to sit together and
you know we built that uh sort of
organically over time it's getting those
teams because those teams sat in
different buildings they didn't really
talk too much didn't overly communicate
actually what they found when they were
sitting together and they were talking
of us you know in one place with this
the shared goals that they're trying to
achieve it really built a esprit of core
in the team
and it really started to
demonstrate benefit and learnings
prioritize two or three key processes it
could be an insider threat piece it
could be a
you know
account takeover on online banking as a
use case
think about the handoffs between those
use cases so what's the handoff between
the digital
forensics and incident response team to
the fraud team and the investigations
team how do you streamline some of that
demonstrate value
co-locate teams physically or virtually
like i said i think it's a little bit
difficult these days with the virtual
environments
but i'm sure there's you know good
collaboration tools that we can use to
solve for that
actively manage the change of people
like i say the key thing here is not so
much the technology change we can get
through that it's actually changing
people
i'll talk from experience you know some
of the investigators and physical
security team and even the cyber teams
they all have their own opinions and
their challenges and they think that
they know better than the other team you
need to break that stuff down right and
that takes strong leadership
celebrate success regularly
right tell war stories
you know motivate the team make sure the
team understands the value of what we've
done and where we're being successful
so that's it for me hopefully that was
semi interesting uh you know the key
point for me is around i really see this
as
our own digital transformation and how
do we get more value out of data
just as our organizations are trying to
do that to grow
and create better you know create
revenue and grow their business
we should be doing the same we should be
thinking about our own digital
transformation i think this is a great
way to enable that thank you
thank you
and he finished with 21 seconds still on
the clock that's the sort of accuracy i
like from netscope as they say mate
thank god it is fusion
friday now we are done for the day in
order for the starting to prepare for
tonight's gala didn't we ask you leave
as quickly as possible once we're done
in about 30 seconds carrying any
conversations outside if you want to
hear a fascinating conversation in the
exhibition hall by the combi keg alex
tilley and shannon darling going to have
a fireside chat talking through
solutions issues that have been touched
on today more broadly across your
industry see you back at 6 30 6 30 is
when the drinks start out in the gardens
for the gala dinner you can only enter
through the glass draw the event center
you can't come through the garden
kitchen and it's only at all certain
that i get to say this
i can't imagine any other gala dinner
house coming right say don't forget to
bring your lego kit
for the speed build challenge that will
take place during the gala dinner this
evening how about one final round of
applause for all our speakers today
thank you for being stoned to the end of
the day see most of you at the dinner in
just over an hour