we can make it right
imma need my background to help me sing
Who
well good morning ladies and gentlemen
how are we up and at it on Friday the
13th there you go of May
welcome welcome I know for many of you
it's your first time back on the
conference scene
for a while maybe even a year or so so
for many of you also now it's just that
first time in a while you've felt that
feeling of the morning after a Gala
dinner of what the hell was I thinking
last night it's great to see you all
here actually
in some ways pleasantly surprised the
size of the crowd morning after a Gala
dinner but not at all surprised given
the keynote speaker we've got to kick us
off today we'd also are so excited to
have her here this is in fact her first
visit to Australia she's cuddled a koala
she's done it all she's ticked
everything off the list and she's here
in her capacity as the Director of
incident response for North America at
the industrial cyber security company
dragos Inc leading the response to and
proactively hunting for threats in
customers ICS environments I've always
hoped that dragos was actually
pronounced Drago's
it is dragos oh my apologize and after
Ivan Drago
the Russian heavyweight champ from Rocky
IV
oh I was hoping to the dude who killed
Apollo Creed before succumbing to
Sylvester Stallone in a brutal slugfest
anyway
she's not a boxer but when not working
Leslie enjoys being a youth martial arts
in structure so it's a little bit more
Cobra Kai than Rocky IV but it's a start
you may also know her via her iconic
Twitter feed hacks for pancakes she
manages a team of incident response and
digital forensic professionals across
North America and she's here to share
her stories from the field on the topic
of uncovering the invisible world of ICS
cyber security how about a massive Round
of Applause for Leslie Carhart
thank you sir
wow look at all those hungover faces out
there kudos to the five of you I saw at
the gym at 6 30 this morning near tears
so good job everybody it's nice to see
you all thank you for having me here at
Oxford and thank you for having me in
your wonderful continent and country
this is also very exciting for me as
mentioned I did in fact oh can I have my
slides
um
I did in fact get to hold a koala and it
was very exciting so um I'm Leslie I
drink and I know things and I'm going to
try to convey some of that knowledge
about useless facts to you all hopefully
useful facts for a few of you
about what I do and I have a really
weird job
um as mentioned I do specifically
incident response for industrial control
systems
and this is a weird Niche because I'm
one of the few people in the world who
when there is say a cyber security
compromise of a power plant or a train
my team gets called in to do response to
that so these weird non-standard
computer systems but they're really not
that uncommon okay you probably have
industrial control systems in your
environments and I have like 40 minutes
here
to tell you everything I possibly can
about what you should do about that
because it's really really important
we're going to talk about what these
systems are where they live what they
look like and how to understand them
we're going to learn some basic
terminology so you can talk to the
people who work on those systems
next we're going to talk about the
threats they face and why I'm even here
why I even do what I do other than take
glamorous trips to other continents
which happens to me all the time
definitely
um not really anyway
and then finally we're going to end with
building your own industrial cyber
security program from the ground up so
if you've got nothing there or you're
just starting I'm going to give you all
the tips in a short period of time that
I can possibly give you just start
building that program it's really really
really important so let's get rolling
okay
so ICS fundamentals industrial control
systems
I have a lot of words in some of these
slides so you can take out your phone
and you can take a little picture and
take it home with you have some homework
you know have a nice picture to post on
Twitter whatever
um this is this is for your reference
but let's let's talk about some terms
I'm going to use in this talk so the
first one is operational technology or
OT
now this is a fake made up word
sorry to everybody here who uses that
word frequently in their marketing
material it is a term that we've made up
as I T people to describe stuff that is
the other that wonderful anthropological
concept of the other
um so when we're talking about OT it's
us using it as a differentiator to talk
about this industrial stuff this
non-typical computer stuff that's doing
process things in our environments and
you don't really see like industrial
engineers and operators using those
terms so who are these industrial
engineers and operators
um so operators are the people who
kind of make the industrial process run
so they watched little screens and they
see how the process is running they make
sure it's safe they adjust levels things
like that they're sitting in the control
center
and then we have the more technical
Engineers whether the mechanical
engineers electrical engineers chemical
Engineers who are doing the detailed
management and Analysis of the process
so you have your operators and your
engineers who are working on these
Industrial Systems but finally let's
talk about what an ICS actually is an
industrial control system
a lot of you are imagining a PLC right
now like a little ruggedized computer
but there have been industrial control
systems for ages and ages and ages and
ages
um they can be gears and pulleys they
can be mechanical
they are simply a a thing that takes
input and makes decisions somehow about
a kinetic process so it could be again
gears and pulleys something simple like
that industrial Control Systems have
existed since like early water clocks so
you can do this mechanically you can do
it with analog control so for a long
time industrial control systems were
simple electronic systems that that made
decisions and now they're more
computerized and digital but there's
still plenty of mechanical industrial
Control Systems out there there's still
plenty of analog industrial Control
Systems out there so that's why I'm
going to tell you right now the terms
ICS and scada are not interchangeable we
hear people use them interchangeably all
the time I'll tell you in a little bit
what a scada system is
but an industrial control system doesn't
necessarily contain scada it can again
be gears you know making something
happen mechanically
but what's this process that I'm talking
about or process if I say it properly um
the conflict of world verbiage there
so a process is a series of discrete
things that make something kinetic
happen so it could be all kinds of
different stuff right it could be
something as complex as electrical power
generation so you're generating
electricity a kinetic thing or it could
be something as simple as a door opening
and closing so it's a decision-making
process whether that's gears and pulleys
or a computer system making a physical
kinetic thing happening and processes
can have lots of sub processes I mean
think about like canning tuna I always
use this example I use it around the
world I've now used it in like three
continents so canning tuna you have your
conveyor belt that has you know your
cans you have to fill the cans you have
to put the labels on the cans each one
of those things that's a sub process it
makes one big process that is sticking
tuna in cans that have a label on them
and they're sealed and things it's very
exciting
all right
processes are made up of process Loops
okay and a process Loop has three parts
okay everybody it has a sensor a
controller and an actuator
and let's talk about what each one of
those things is so first of all you have
to have an actuator that's the thing
that makes the physical thing happen so
that could be making a motor run it
could be changing a temperature opening
a valve making a conveyor belt move
etc etc et cetera so something physical
in the world
something has to make decisions about
what that's going to do so there's some
kind of control device and again that
could be digital which we're mostly
going to talk about in the cyber world
but it could be a mechanical thing as
well that makes decisions about when
that actuator does something but it has
to have some input right there has to be
something that helps it know when to do
things so you also have to have some
kind of sensor in your process control
loops
so let's let's look at a pretty simple
familiar example here that I really
really like um we actually don't have
one of these in the hotel I'm very
disappointed I put this in my slides and
this ritzy Hotel doesn't have a
automatic revolving door but raise your
hand if you have seen an automatic
revolving door just checking okay
everybody's seen an automatic revolving
door has anybody walked into one
a few times I I've walked into an
automatic revolving dark
um so this has the a process control
Loop and it has these three things think
about it for a moment okay so what
happens when you walk into the door it
starts turning right so that's the
actuator getting to work but it had to
make a decision about when to start
turning so there's also a sensor right
there's a sensor to tell if you're in
the door and then a controller takes the
input from that sensor and says there's
somebody in the door and I need to start
turning around okay so that's the basics
of the control Loop but there's more
things right because if you get too
close to the door and you impede it
it'll stop right there's a safety
control so that the uh the actuator is
actually providing feedback to the
controller as well and it says I can't
turn stop it's not safe
so there's there's like a bi-directional
feedback going on in that control loop
as well
so there's safety built into these doors
as well and I always use this example um
to understand how these process Loops
can potentially fail so what can go
wrong there are only four failure States
for any process Loop okay so the first
one is
the actuator fails to start when it's
supposed to so think about your door
what happens then you walk under the
door and it doesn't turn and you're like
I would like to go now
um no so not not too bad in that case in
that example fails to stop when it's
supposed to so you walk into the door
and it keeps trying to turn your face
that's rather unpleasant right
the third one is it starts too early or
too late
so you wait for a little while or it
keeps turning into your back while
you're getting out of the door very
unpleasant but probably not
life-threatening and finally it goes on
for the wrong period of time which in
that case has similar results
every process loop on Earth can have
those four failure States and they can
get much more severe than a revolving
door although Mia culpa there are
apparently a great deal of injuries
caused by revolving doors over time
across the world so they actually can be
dangerous for those reasons in those
failure States
but real industrial processes
um they are much more complex than a
single process Loop usually they have a
multitude of different things going on I
talked about canning tuna earlier you
have the conveyor belt going you have
the stuff filling the tuna and
everything has to be synchronized
together because like if it's not then
you have tune on your conveyor belt and
it's disgusting and somebody has to
clean it up like so these process Loops
have to work together they have to have
feedback between one another so you have
to have some big computer that's making
decisions about all the little computers
and when they do things so they're
coordinating them all and for a long
time in the digital world that was
distributed control systems or dcs's
now we're seeing those which are smaller
scale and more elaborate scada systems
to integrate a bunch of parts of a
process together sub processes into a
bigger process and that's where we pull
in scada systems we're talking about
this picture up here which is
controlling a bunch of process Loops
getting feedback from them and
coordinating their efforts perhaps over
a very large geographic area
so there's your scada
process control is super complex there's
a lot of things going on in these
processes there's a bunch of
sub-processes with different devices
different sensors different actuators
and they have to work together right so
that means a bunch of protocols and
things so I'm going to introduce you
here to the Purdue model
this is a model that is educational it's
academic it's not always representative
of everything that's really going on in
industrial control but you can see we
have a layer cake here okay so at the
very very bottom we have our very simple
analog digital devices so our things
like our sensors and our actuators
and as we move upward we get into more
familiar devices so at level one you
start to see your PLC see your
ruggedized computers your control
devices simple computers that have you
know simple ladder logic program getting
into them
and at your second level you start to
see things like maybe some familiar
Windows computers like hmis so you might
have a Windows XP XP embedded system
there that is your control interface and
that talks to the lower levels but it
might also talk to the upper levels too
because as you go up further you start
getting to like workstations where the
systems are programmed so actual Windows
workstations or Linux workstations
then you hopefully hopefully have some
kind of DMZ which separates you from the
rest of your corporate environment your
normal familiar Enterprise environment
so that's the Purdue model so the
low-level devices are less familiar the
higher level devices before you reach
the DMZ are
more familiar so potentially Linux
Windows Etc
now why is this important to all of you
well I'm here to tell you that you do
probably have industrial control systems
in your environment they're all over the
place so not just in manufacturing not
just in transportation we do a lot of
ICS research on trains and aircraft but
also things like You're Building
Automation and control
we respond to a lot of incidents and
data centers around the world where
there's been an intrusion on say the
fire suppression system or the heating
and cooling what happens if you're in a
very very hot place and all your air
conditioners suddenly get infected and
fail that has a big impact to how you do
business even if you're only working in
the computer World typically right
so you really need to think about these
control devices and has anybody is
anybody else staying in the hotel with
the little button on the wall that has
the controller for your blinds and
everything so mine crashed while I was
here the electrician had to come up to
my room and reset the controller that
makes the light switches work in the
room it took 20 minutes to reset so we
are surrounded by industrial control and
Internet of Things devices that control
these process Loops we're surrounded by
them all the time and they do important
things that we often don't notice until
they fail
now there's a concept that I need to
introduce you talk to called itot
convergence an itot convergence means
simply it's cheaper to use commercial
off-the-shelf thing to build these
process Loops then go build your own
roll your own it's also safer to
typically use something commercial and
instead of rolling your own protocol or
something
so we are in the industrial space seeing
more and more familiar Network
infrastructure devices like Cisco and
Juniper and Windows computers doing a
lot of these control tasks especially at
the mid levels of the Purdue model but
also at the lower levels because they're
cheaper and easier to replace and
Implement and build so of course people
are using more of them they aren't
building their own network protocols
like they used to things are running
over CAT5 Cat6 between the industrial
devices they're running through typical
switches and routers like we see in our
Enterprise environments and that means
they're vulnerable to all of those
things that those devices are typically
vulnerable to in the cyber security
world
so this has changed a lot of the
vulnerability landscape of industrial
Networks
so I want you to think for a moment I've
told you you probably have an industrial
control device in your environment
think about this this is why you might
be missing them if you aren't aware of
them right now they're oftentimes on
different subnets or vlans so like
you're building Automation and control
your backup power your heating and
cooling systems your elevator
controllers or even the things that do
your shipping and Logistics like your
your RFID tracking systems etc for
shipping
they perform key tasks that are not
considered because you're not
necessarily thinking about your
processes you think about cyber security
in a vacuum which is okay in Enterprise
but
now we need to think about these
processes right these control loops
these things that are happening to
accomplish our mission
and we oftentimes get the message that
these systems are too sensitive to touch
or look at as cyber security people so
we're told to ignore them we're told to
write them off or check them off in our
risk assessments
because there's something that's foreign
and unusual they're low-level devices
and we're scared to break them for good
reason we don't want to bring down our
process and we'll talk about that
and there's oftentimes an unhealthy
culture relationship between the
operators and engineers and I.T and
cyber security because there's been
misunderstandings and miscommunications
for so very very very long
all right so let's talk about why we
care okay so incident response I do
incident response in these systems right
um I respond to three types of cyber
security incidents in ICS typically okay
the first one is Insider threats
now um one of the first industrial cyber
security accidents actually
happened very close to here it was a
sewage plant
um a uh this happened back around 2000 a
fellow working at the plant found out
that he didn't get hired on he was a
contractor and he wanted a job there
and he got so mad that he went and he
dumped a bunch of sewage into a nearby
water body
um and it's a horrible mess but this was
a great example this was long before
stock snap and anything like that um
this is a great example of the the
people who work on these systems 95 of
them are great people 99 of them are not
going to do anything bad
um but there's always that one or two
people who are know how to break the
system and they have a bad day or they
get pissed off at their boss and they
decide to break something so that
actually does happen we do respond to
incidents that are Insider threats in
these environments
but they're normally sententional
sometimes the operator who's working at
two in the morning just wants to watch
Netflix like yeah okay
um and they plug something in and they
infect the system
um commodity ransomware can have huge
impacts on those mid levels of the
Purdue model if you suddenly can't see
your control screens because they've got
a ransomware screen on them and they're
running Windows XP you got to shut down
your process because you can no longer
operate it safely you don't know if it's
on fire you have to shut things down so
ransomware can be very impactful same
with crypto miners Etc
things that bring down these low
resource systems older systems and
finally there's targeted and at dragos
we track a bunch of different
adversaries that are trying their hand
at poking at Industrial Systems and a
lot of what they're doing is foothold
building and reconnaissance so so that's
changing over time you know they're
staging for future attacks they don't
want to waste all these resources and
making something explode right now they
want to build a foothold and they want
to understand the system because they're
the processes are complex and they're
hard to break in a specific way so
they're taking their time now and
learning how they work very quietly and
slowly in these environments so that
when they need to in a geopolitical
context they can make something explode
all right so I've told you all this I've
told you you've got ICS oh my God and
I've told you that you probably need to
do something about it and that there are
people out there who are getting better
and better and better at breaking it for
a multitude of reasons whether it's the
ransomware actors just wanting money or
the advanced adversaries learning about
and staging for future attacks
by the way you are not too small for
that to be you they use a lot of small
operators as test beds for their attacks
on bigger stuff
so that's that's not great right so I'm
going to give you a little crash course
in building an industrial cyber security
program for your organization and this
can be little it can be just for your
building Automation and your HVAC
systems if you need to if they could
impact your operations this is an
important thing to do
so I've got my top seven misconceptions
I want to start with this these are my
top seven misconceptions I hear from
everybody about industrial Control
Systems so let's get this out of the way
the first one is that it's an edge case
that it only applies to same
manufacturers or power companies no it's
all over the place we already went
through that
it has to be out of scope for scans pen
tests and assessments no we just have to
do them differently because these
systems are older Legacy sensitive doing
critical health and safety life life
safety things
it's our Arcane no we looked at the
Purdue model the low-level devices might
be less familiar but the mid-level
systems we're talking Windows XP
embedded think Linux things that you are
familiar with there's still Cisco
devices there now Ito OT convergence is
seen to that in a lot of cases you can
learn this stuff
it's protected by air gapping data
diodes and segmentation air gapping is a
lie um I see one to two networks in my
fully ICS career that are actually air
gapped in a year
a lot of organizations will say they're
air gapped and I'll actually go in there
and take a peek and there's like modems
connected to them and there is a DMZ and
there's pass-through in the DMZ
um people have Odd Ideas about what air
gapping actually means and even the
environments where they are air-gapped
they have to do updates right they have
to do software programming so somebody
comes in and plugs in a transient laptop
and they they bridge to the network or
they they bring in a USB drive something
has to bridge even if it's sneakernet
even it has it has to be a human being
walking in with a USB drive so air
gapping is not
common and it's not necessarily a
reliable defense I don't see a lot of
data diodes they're a nice idea but
they're expensive
so really we have to think about other
more traditional defense in depth in
this in terms of cyber security
um purposefully neglected it is not
purposeful neglected these systems are
Legacy for a reason because the life
cycles are different in industrial
control when you go out and you buy the
equipment for a power plant you are
buying that whole setup that whole
system and support contracts for 20
years maybe and you're buying a really
big expensive package and you can't just
tamper with that it all works together
all those bits all those process Loops
all those parts of the Purdue model they
all work together all those different
protocols that are used at various
levels of the Purdue model they all have
to function together and if you start
replacing operating systems or adding
EDR or something you're going to make
something fail you have to work with the
vendor and the engineers on that and it
can take a very long time you might only
have a maintenance window in these
environments once or twice a year
um is it easy to secure with next-gen no
we can't install EDR on our XP embedded
hm hmis I'm sorry we've got to go back
in our time machine to 2002 and we've
got to do good security and depth and
we've got to adapt to the fact that
we're dealing with a lot of Legacy
systems and a lot of very sensitive
systems that we can't tack things onto
um and that it's vulnerable simply
because individual devices are insecure
these protocols and devices are made to
be simple so that when you hit the giant
red button on the wall to stop somebody
from being chewed up by a machine the
connection happens really fast and the
machine shuts down if you add encryption
to that an overhead to that protocol
that could be another precious couple
seconds perhaps or something could fail
you need these protocols to work
reliably reliability is number one in
these environments so that these systems
can function safely
so real talk here are some real facts
about industrial control systems for you
so the first one is I already mentioned
industrial cyber attacks are increasing
I have more incidents every year it's
really happening and adversaries are
getting better at attacking them
as I mentioned these industrial Control
Systems they often use Legacy stuff on
purpose longer life spans that's how
they work they have to function they
have to function reliably without a
bunch of downtime
familiarity stuff as we mentioned itot
convergence is happening you will see
more I.T stuff in these environments as
time goes on it's happening more and
more and that means I.T vulnerabilities
air gaping is a lie I'm sorry it sounds
really great if you hear that word
double check everything don't don't take
that term at face value anywhere
protocols rarely have authentication or
encryption as I mentioned when you hit
that giant red emergency button on the
wall the system needs to stop
these Protocols are simple for a reason
they are unencrypted for a reason
because the number one thing here in the
CIA Triad is that the the unity you need
to have reliable protocol going to the
devices so that they do what they're
supposed to do at the right time
um ICS can be sensitive to scanning and
exploitation absolutely these are simple
devices with simple protocol stacks but
there are still ways to do cyber
security whether it's testing the
systems during their maintenance windows
or using a sometimes we have a digital
twin system where somebody has a little
lab where they test the systems maybe we
can do some testing in there there are
ways to work around this but we have to
be adaptable and communicative
and ICS is comprehensible this is
something you can learn you just have to
focus on an area and you have to
understand the process that you're
dealing with so the very beginning of
this is identify what processes you have
to secure what process environments are
in your purview as a cyber security
Personnel even if it's just something
like building automation
and you need to have healthy
conversations healthy conversations with
your engineers and your operators these
people might not trust you at all you're
the people who let don't let them go to
websites you're the people who say they
can't watch Netflix when they're bored
at 2 A.M
um so I do suggest pastries that's a
really good really good tactic bring in
a box of something and sit down and say
teach me about your process they are
much more educated and informed about
their process than you will ever be so
let them educate you learn about the
processes you have to secure learn about
how they're maintained what their
concerns are they already do business
continuity planning they know what
they're concerned about they know what
could go horribly wrong you should be
asking these people these questions and
listening and being humble
so we have the cyber security maturity
model here so the basics are the thing
you have to get out of the way out of
the way in any cyber security you need
to start at the very beginning you need
to start with
understanding your environment and the
architecture and what you actually have
to secure so what are we even securing
and how are we going to find it in our
Network so let's talk about
architectural understanding of these
environments this is where you should
start after you understand the processes
that exist okay what's the what's the
process
and who's involved in it
what are they concerned about what is
their worst day ever do they have
business continuity planning
what vendors are in place and what types
of cyber security tools are already
deployed there might be some simple
antivirus there might be some logging
that could be useful to you so again
you've got to listen and have those
conversations with your engineers with
the OT staff they knows these things and
if you don't push them and try to push
modern cyber security onto them in an
inflexible way they will be willing to
educate you on what's there
asset inventories this is tough in I.T
it's really tough in OT a lot of you
probably have some idea where your
systems are and what they're named in
your it environments but these different
vlans and subnets and segments that your
um that your Industrial Equipment live
on are probably unknown or barely known
to you and this means that you have to
start from scratch with this whole asset
inventory process so you're going to
need to find ways that work with your
sensitive industrial environments to get
acid inventories there are tools out
there typically they do this passively
so they collect Network traffic office
fan port or a tap and they build an
asset inventory you can install agents
on everything you can't go out there and
do active scanning on everything
the best tactic is to do things
passively and carefully and again work
with your operators and engineers
you need Network Maps
you need up to date and routinely
updated Network Maps again these are not
the same as your it Network Maps they're
going to involve every level of the
Purdue model
and you need to understand from a
process perspective how the network is
laid out and what's sensitive so that
means again you've got to work with
those operators and Engineers to start
understanding the layout of your
environment
now we need to understand what actually
Matters from a cyber security
perspective so we need to do some Crown
Jewel analysis and really this is
something we should be doing in it but
we're really bad at it
OT people are really good at the
thinking about their worst day ever they
do that from a safety perspective all
the time it's part of business
continuity planning thinking about hey
from a very high level what does my
worst day look like is it somebody dying
is it the facility catching on fire is
it my multi-million dollar piece of
equipment grinding to a halt and
destroying itself
they already have an idea of what those
consequences are and what you're going
to need to do is start at the top with
the mission and those consequences of
concern and understand mapping down
where
what parts of the process what devices
what sub processes could cause these
consequences to happen
this is actually kind of a tricky thing
and a long-term thing that you need to
do and we should do this in it too but
it's very very critical life and safety
to do it in OT
so as I mentioned we start at the top
what is the worst day ever
and then what parts of the process could
cause that worst day ever
are there mitigations in place that
could prevent those terrible things from
happening are there human safety
controls physical safety controls that
prevent things from exploding or
catching on fire
how reliable are those what could cause
those to fail and we map downwards and
downwards and downwards until we have a
really good list of very specific things
like software things or Hardware things
that could cause those terrible
consequences to happen those are the
things we actually care about do we care
if configures on every Windows computer
system I don't know we might not care if
every computer in our industrial
environment has configure on it because
it does not cause a consequence of
concern this is a different way of
thinking for cyber security people we
care about exploits we care about
malware we care about there's being
infections on stuff you have one day of
downtime in these networks a year
you're probably not going to shut down
your entire process at millions and
millions of dollars
just to go remove configure from some
engineering workstations they're working
okay you can make a risk assessment and
say it's probably not going to get worse
it's a headless worm now
and keep things running you need to make
those types of risk decisions about the
consequences that you actually care
about in your industrial environment
this will help you prioritize what you
do in incident response it'll help you
run threat hunts
um so this Crown Jewel analysis is a
really critical thing to do early on and
it's a heavy lift but it'll really help
you understand what could go
catastrophically wrong and why
so we move on from architectural
understanding to build passive and
active defense for our OT environments
so let's move on a little bit immaturity
so now we have five recommendations from
our last year in year in review report
at dragos and I agree with them all so
I'm just going to read them to you
um so the first one is Build defensible
architecture so we've kind of talked
about that already we want to make sure
that we have things properly segmented
we understand our environment
etc etc so properly segment properly
control access from one part to another
as best we can inside our industrial
environment
we also want to start implementing
network monitoring so
a lot of these environments have no
monitoring in place already but that's
okay we can start building some passive
monitoring we that's not an intrusive
thing we can start building some
monitoring off a span board or a tap and
understanding our asset inventory
understanding threat detection things
like that
establish remote access Authentication
these are a squishy Center okay so we
talked about the Purdue model and
hopefully you've got some kind of DMZ
between your internet facing Enterprise
environment and your industrial
environment hopefully you have some kind
of DMC between the two and it's
relatively secure and this means having
something like jump hosts and
multi-factor authentication to get
across that DMZ into the industrial
environment because I mentioned these
Protocols are insecure these devices are
insecure once you get into the
industrial environment segment things
are kind of squishy in the center you
have the hard candy outside and the
squishy middle you don't want people
getting in there if you can prevent it
vulnerability management again you're
going to need a separate vulnerability
Management program for your industrial
devices because the needs are so much
different when you can shut things down
when they can actually be updated and
what that means for your security
posture
and finally creating an incident
response plan for your OT environment
what are you going to do if something
goes catastrophically wrong there what
do you do if you detect something
malicious or there's a potential Cyber
attack
I'm an into the responder I come into a
lot of incidents where this plan hasn't
been made and what I do for the first
day of incident response is figure all
this stuff out because nobody's ever
done it it slows down into the response
in a crisis it costs more it's much more
expensive to have me do that than you do
it right now
so here's some basic questions your
incident response plan at OT should
answer
when's an OT incident declare it so what
are your declaration thresholds they
should be related to those consequences
we talked about
who will do what when how do you involve
both your cyber security people and your
OT people they both have to be part of
this response effort
how will they contact one another have
you established that in advance out of
band Communications document sharing
resource sharing Etc how are you going
to do that and how are you going to call
one another in a call tree Etc if
something goes wrong I see some people
like laughing at each other right there
obviously this is gone catastrophically
wrong for you I've seen it go
catastrophically wrong a ton of
different times
how do you even do OT forensics we're
talking about plcs and things what are
you going to do if you have a
potentially compromised PLC and you need
to know if the firmware has been
tampered with
who are you going to call is it a cert
is it a vendor do you have somebody
internally you can work with that
it's a different world of forensics do
you have forensic stuff that can do
forensics on Windows NT if that exists
in your OT environment you need to work
this stuff out in advance
where's the big red button or X how are
you going to cut things off in an
emergency so what how are you going to
hit the big red button or chop off
Network segmentation if say ransomware
is spreading through your ICS
environment that's a really tough
question and safety concerns and
requirements you're talking about
hazardous environments do you need PPE
do you need to be wearing a hard hat do
you have that can you buy one quickly
there's a bunch of different concerns
that go into OT incident response
planning
collection management this is really
really important as well you need to
know what data you have available to do
analysis and monitoring and incident
response in your OT environment
how long is it retained you might know
this well for your Enterprise
environment but again we're talking
about an entirely different environment
with entirely different concerns so you
really need to you don't necessarily
have a Splunk index list that you can
use you need to build an Excel
spreadsheet of what data sources are
available in your ICS environment
and finally let's talk about moving on
into the Future Okay so as you're
talking about moving on to higher levels
of maturity an important thing that I
can tell you is find out how mature you
really are right now not based on your
own negative or positive biases
so you really need to rate your maturity
in your industrial control Network in
terms of cyber security and understand
where you stand compared to everyone
else that's going to tell you whether
you should move to more advanced things
like threat Intel Etc
so a tool I will suggest to you that you
can take home today and do something
with is the US Department of Energy's
c2m2 bottle it's a self-survey that
rates you in three levels of maturity
from one two and three level one is just
basic fundamental maturity the things
we've been talking about today moving
into maturity level three where you're a
little bit more advanced and maturity
level three is the most sophisticated
modern cyber security programs with the
correct Staffing and everything complete
um and what you're going to do is rate
yourself across a number of categories
in cyber security and then you'll take a
look at these graphs and it'll show you
whether you've completed all of maturity
level one and you don't want to move to
maturity level two until you've
completed all the things at maturity
level one
this takes a couple days to do the whole
thing sit in a room with your operators
your engineers your network people go
through all the questions be honest this
will help eliminate that bias about
where you really stand and where you
should go next because again if you see
that you're jumping ahead to the
maturity level three stuff and you
haven't done the maturity level one
stuff
you need to start with the fundamentals
in your uh in your ICS cyber security
program this is a really important tool
now if this is all too much for you I
understand
I understand I've thrown a lot at you
right now we've gone through the entire
world this is normally a five-day class
at Sans and I've dumped it all on you in
40 minutes
start with the basics anything that you
can do here matters at least understand
what you need to secure start with the
fundamentals try doing a tabletop
exercise that involves your processes
and your industrial control devices
humble when you're relating to your
operators and Engineers those bad
relationships are probably there and you
need to start from scratch bring your
pastries
be humble ask them questions learn about
your process it's probably really
interesting and they want to help they
want to educate everybody wants to talk
about their job right
project ties the longer term things if
it's really hard to start building out
passive monitoring in your industrial
Network take your time build a project
around it
start with the fundamentals first but
anything that you can do today will save
you time and money if you have to call
in a person like me I want to save you
money I'm a terrible salesperson
yes you should have a plan for instant
responses in your ICS environment that's
a must-have but it's very very important
to have as much prepared in advance as
you can because you don't want to pay me
at incident response rates to do that
for you at the beginning of an incident
and leverage outside resources when
needed we're here but all of our major
competitors in the ICS cyber security
landscape are also in the vendor hall
right now
I am a terrible salesperson I don't care
who you find to help you do this find
somebody to help you do this
it's very very critical from a health
and safety and cost-saving perspective
to secure your industrial environments
whatever those might be go out and find
help and begin to do this today it's
really really important
thank you everybody for having me I'm so
grateful to be here
[Applause]
Leslie that was wonderful we're so
excited to have you here we're slightly
there but I want to ask a couple of
quick questions naive idiot outside of
all of this but I assume as we move into
this genuine world of Internet of things
and
hundreds of millions or billions of more
devices all start getting connected this
area only grows in importance and
complexity is that right are we just at
the beginning of this sort of taking off
the um ICS world has been a Harbinger
for what's happened in smart devices and
iot
um everything that is new and horrible
about smart and iot has happened before
in ICS so the connecting everything to
the internet and the devices without
security built in and things becoming
more and more commercial
all of that happened already in ICS and
yes it's only continuing to get worse
with iiot and iot so this problem is not
going away it's only increasing and
you're going to see more and more of
these
digital devices that are connected to
the internet connected to Bluetooth
connected to one another out there in
your environments fantastic lift this
lid up because I want this in the photo
I'm getting the guy to type oh oh
final question if you talk to a hundred
organizations about this you've got 100
organizations in the room first question
how many of those hundred are anywhere
near across this issue enough for your
liking on average in business
um
you know we did a survey of how many
people have incident response plans in
general and that number through the
whole company both it and OT and that
number was relatively low it was
certainly not 80 percent and then when
you look at people who have specifically
OT incident response plans and some kind
of security program around OT it's even
even lower so I had an opportunity today
to reach out to all of you and try to
convince a few more percent to start
building this program it's really
important I get called out for some
really catastrophic things you'll never
see in the news Okay so busy people lots
of things I know there's all these
things they should get to if this is
reaching out to them what's the single
idiot simple takeaway thing they can do
right now to significantly bolster their
strength in this area of all the things
you talked about go to the bakery pick
up a box of pastries take that take it
into your process environment watch the
safety concern signs so you don't go in
there and look like an idiot and meet
your engineers and your operators and
understand what they do start with that
start with a conversation hi my name is
Leslie it's very nice to meet you can
you tell me a little bit about what you
do I brought you some donuts you know
whatever works do that today fantastic
and now you just set the small for this
camera because I want a photo with you
give Leslie a massive Round of Applause
that was tremendous I'm so glad you
liked it you can see why we were so
excited about having her here what a
fascinating fascinating conversation
we're not far away from morning tea you
may well be able to grab her and deep
dive into the subject for a few minutes
during that as well our final speaker
for this morning is currently a senior
sales engineer for airlock digital which
you know is an Australian company that
provides solutions for organization to
implement allow listing one of the
essential ladies itself professed Splunk
Fanboy who isn't formerly a computer
security analyst and focus on All Things
Blue Team especially dfir and CM when
he's not a computer you'll probably find
him organizing SEC talks in Adelaide
enjoying all that Adelaide restaurant
scene has to offer pre-covered and he
likes to attend something here that says
Levain music
Levi Michigan
oh sorry live music
get a bang tough crowd had a move on
okay here to bust out some rocking cyber
busting beats on the topic of finishing
your essential eight program being
successful with a loud listing this is
DJ Josh Schwartz from airlock digital
[Applause]
excellent thank you Adam
so hopefully my slides will come up soon
um my name is Josh Schwartz as mentioned
I'm a senior sales engineer with airlock
digital we'll come back to those guys at
the end I've got a history in a range of
different Technologies I've done
everything defensive security but
basically summarized I love preventative
security controls and that's how I've
ended up here at airlock digital I'm a
huge fan of purple taming so come find
me on the booth if you want to have a
conversation and yeah as I said
self-professed blunt fanboy
so
I don't want to sound like a broken
record but I really just want to make
sure we're all on the same page here so
I'm going to be talking about the
essential eight today
um I'm sure everyone's heard it you've
heard it a million times it's been you
know smashed into your brains but just
in case you haven't come across it this
is a list of eight controls that the
Australian cyber security centers put
together
they put them together because they
actually work you know these guys are
the ones out there doing instant
response every day and so these are the
eight controls that if you've got them
all in place massively reduce the risk
of cyber security attacks against your
organization
um so hopefully you're doing a lot of
these already you know some stuff's
really simple
um patching machines turn on two Factor
some of them have a reputation for being
a little bit harder
um I want to challenge that and we'll
get to that but the reason we always
bang on about it is because it actually
works so if you look in the top left
hand corner there you'll see number one
on the list is application control
so let's talk about app control what
actually is it and what are we trying to
achieve here so application control is
the act of explicitly stating what is
and is not allowed to run on the
endpoint and making sure we actually
enforce that so we did a final list of
what's trusted in our environment and
then we run that and interestingly it
blocks by default so unlike antivirus or
EDR which blocks no and bad application
control only allows non-good so it
massive reduces our attack surface in
our organization and it can even cover
attacks such as you know low bins or
living off the land binaries and we can
again lock those down and really control
those in a way that you know Solutions
like EDR and Antivirus can't do
so there's this perception that this is
hard to implement I've heard a range of
reasons speculation there's always
horror stories flying around you know
they deployed it and it it broke
something or users got mad
um you know I've heard all sorts so you
know cyber security team doesn't have
capacity
um service desk is going to get swamped
by tickets and we can't do it I don't
know what to trust you know these are
all really common conversations
um
but I want to challenge these today
um you know
um we've rolled this out in millions of
not Millions thousands of customers
right and and there's people doing this
every day
um so it's definitely achievable
so the trick here is we need to plan to
be successful
so a lot of people fail because they
just grab a tool off the shelf for one
that they've already got or they buy the
add-on for a solution they already have
and they just start enforcing and they
just start trusting
um and making exemptions and making
rules and this often leads to you know a
bad outcome and these horror stories
that we've heard
so it's really important that we start
with the why you know we need to
understand what are we actually trying
to achieve and just saying we're trying
to achieve essentially maturity is not a
good enough answer we need to understand
are we trying to control executables you
know we just want to stop that phishing
attack and the user double clicking on a
binary or are we trying to control
drivers dlls system files Powershell
scripts on the endpoint these are really
important things to consider
you know things like admin users
excluded do you want to control just for
the user or do we want to actually
restrict what the administrator is
allowed to do on those same machines
um so basically it boils down to you
know are we trying to do anti-malware
protection or are you trying to stop you
know the non-marketing team from running
Adobe software
so to help us understand this why or
choose our why
um the essentially maturity model can be
a really good approach
um and and help us kind of Target what
our end state looks like
so hopefully everyone's familiar with
the essential 8 material levels but
basically it's broken down into four
levels so it's all about risk mitigation
and intent so you know we can sit there
and and you know do a risk analysis of
your organization you know are you guys
actively being targeted by apts then
highly recommend you target level three
are you a small medium business with not
many employees not much I.T not much IP
then maybe level one is more than
appropriate for you
um so if we break these down level zero
is obviously doing nothing level ones
you're proactively blocking executables
so the intent of level one is again
dealing with that drive by type attack
the phishing attack that the user gets
an email and double clicks on the file
as we Step Up level two we're now
expanding that to you know the scripts
the libraries the installers
and on to level three where we're now
including bypasses as well those living
off the land binaries so this is where
we get into the really complex
complicated uh mature stuff
um so now we've picked our maturity
level and we understand what we're
trying to achieve here how do we
actually kind of start making this
practical
you've probably heard this a million
times but it's really important with
application control to build a
cross-functional team
so one thing that a lot of people seem
surprised by when I come and have this
conversation with them is that the most
mature organizations that are doing
application control the cyber security
team doesn't actually run the platform
they write some policy and say here's
what we want to allow in our
organization but from that point on
their hands off
um so because of that reason we need to
make sure that when when you're rolling
this out you've got a cross-functional
team
um it's got representation from server
admins desktop admins
developers support team and of course
the Cyber and risk team as well
cool so once we've got the team we need
to start thinking about our use cases
so we really need to understand how our
users work so as Leslie just mentioned
you know it's all about sitting down
with your users and understanding kind
of you know what are they doing and how
they're doing it
so if we talk about some of the
traditionally more difficult or
perceived difficult Solutions you know
we've got our developers so you know
these guys are generating code running
weird code compiling they're doing all
sorts of interesting behaviors so we
need to sit down with them and ask them
questions like what tools are they using
what languages are they writing do they
have a build server do they have a
pipeline
um you know so the intent here is that
we sit down with them and understand how
can we control them and give them a safe
environment but not interrupt their
day-to-day workflow so you know can can
they sign their code if they can sign
that code we can do trust the publisher
and Away you go can we give them a
specified file path you know hey you
guys have your developing development
tools into C developers and Away you go
so we can definitely find that middle
ground and keep everyone happy
remote workers who've seen over the last
two three years now it feels like a blur
but remote works you know becoming more
popular so we really need to understand
you know what's the intent of the
control when a user goes home off VPN
takes their device you know off off site
somewhere we want to make sure that you
know is this security control meant to
be enforced when they go home uh is it
not what happens if you can't talk back
to the the server or group policy or
whatever it is so we need to consider
that and make sure we understand and
what we want to achieve there
another really common one is the
executives so we know they're always uh
interesting people and their demands are
never come through with you know five
days notice
um so we need to make sure that we're in
a position where the world's not going
to explode if the executive you know is
five minutes away from a WebEx meeting
and we've forgotten to trust that in in
our policy so we need to make sure we've
got them considered in our use case
another big one is it so I.T unlike a
lot of users they're doing quite
interesting things you know you have to
think about what a day in the life of it
looks like not so much what they're
doing on their machines that's pretty
easy to Define but you know they're
making remote connections so you know we
our security control might say we don't
want users using RDP but now how do we
make sure that it is able to remotely
access those machines to provide support
so when we have these conversations with
our users these help us Define and
understand the test cases so that when
it comes time to test tools we can jump
in there and know what we have to test
to make sure we're not going to upset
our users
cool so once we've thought about all
this it's time to get into the boring
stuff the documentation writing ask
yourself lots of why questions so the
best place to start is asking yourself
about the roles and responsibilities so
there's a lot to this so you need to
really unpack it so you know you need to
be asking yourself questions like who's
going to be responsible for the policy
who's going to do the day-to-day
administration of the tool you know the
updates and the maintenance
um who do the tickets get logged to
what's support going to be responsible
for what's going to be a ticket to cyber
security risk team so as I mentioned
before you know it's often not the cyber
security team that's going to be living
this day to day so make sure you've
really got clear definitions of who's
responsible for what
this is a huge one so we really need to
understand the workflow and the
day-to-day of what and how we're going
to trust
so what is going to be the source of
Truth do you have you know an acceptable
use policy that says we're only allowed
to run this sort of software in our
environment does cyber security have a
rule about you know if it pops up as
malicious in the AV it's not allowed to
run in the environment so we really need
to think about what is the actual
definition of what we trust
and from that how do you add and remove
trust who's going to be able to say that
this program is now trusted to run in
our environment
and who's going to be responsible for
saying removing
um trust so what happens if you know
there's a supply chain attack and you
need to rip it out you know is that
something that support's able to do
because the users
um you know going to complain when that
stops working so we need to make sure
this is really locked down
another important one to flag here is
know what external resources you're
going to consult and make sure this is
documented before you get into the
database operation you don't want to be
waiting and looking at files and then
going oh I'll just check virustotal just
have virus total say it's perfectly fine
but it doesn't match your policy you
know make sure it's really codified
um and if you're struggling to know
where to start I highly recommend just
trust everything that's in your
organization you know most people are
walking around assuming they're devices
and their environments aren't
compromised so that's a really good
place to start you can always go broad
trust everything and reduce trust over
time
cool so exception policy is a huge one
as well I mentioned the executive users
before so we need to make sure we
understand and pre-plan who's going to
be eligible for exceptions and who's
going to be able to you know add the
users to the exception group and handle
them you know again we see a lot of
people that do this successfully will
have their support team able to generate
the exceptions and then we'll have the
audit gets sent on to the cyber security
and risk team
so that's a really good approach to take
another interesting point here is what's
an exemption policy versus what's an
actual policy change you know where's
the Line in the Sand of you get a pass
to run this once versus this is going to
be allowed for my whole organization we
need to make sure that's clearly defined
kind of before we get into actually
deploying the software
another really really critical piece is
you need to have a mature software
deployment a software maintenance
program before you even consider doing
application control
we see in our experience that the people
that do this successfully have a really
you know locked down standard you know
we're deploy using InTune and here's our
sewing image that makes the world a lot
easier easier place to work in so yeah
the more uniform it is the easier it's
going to be to roll out and worth noting
here you know a lot of people seem to
think that the allow listing or
application control project is going to
be difficult because I've got a huge
organization it's actually just going to
be difficult depending on how many
different applications and how many
different use cases you have in your
organization so you can imagine if you
everyone in your organization has local
admin and they've all got Spotify and
Netflix on their machines this is going
to be a much harder conversation to have
um in a similar vein the software
development process so I talked about
talking to your developers as I'm
understanding how they work but actually
also knowing you know how their
pipelines work how does the new code get
introduced you know if you've got
application developers and the apps
getting pushed onto a web server you
know how does that process happen and
how can we inject ourselves into that
pipeline we need to make sure we really
understand this because this is going to
be the sort of stuff that really trips
us up early on
and annoyingly uh or at least annoying
for me I'm sure there's some GRC people
out there that love it but make sure
this is really documented well you know
make sure it's all codified there's not
going to be any questions once we get
into the rollout phase we know who's
going to be responsible for everything
what's going to be trusted and so on
cool so now we know where to start
um a real Pro tip for once you actually
get into the deployment phase is make
sure you're doing your people change
management
um we've got to make sure we're working
with our users and not against them
especially if you're going to come along
and start telling them they're not
allowed to do something so again make
sure you've got a plan to work with
users to understand their their
workflows and their needs and make sure
they understand why you're putting this
control in place
and along those lines make sure you've
got an off-ramp you know if you're about
to come in and say you're only allowed
to use Edge you're not allowed to use
Google Chrome anymore make sure they
understand why but also make sure you
know their bookmarks and their favorites
have copied across and same goes if you
drop if you're blocking something like a
Dropbox make sure that you've told them
they've got time to copy the files out
and shove them into OneDrive you'd be
surprised how often people end up
forgetting this step and then you're
just fighting users the whole time and
users are trying to find workarounds
because I've got to get their file or
they need this program to do their job
so we can make that really easy by
working with them as we go through
when we come to the tech in our
experience there's four key technical
requirements that any software product
needs to be able to do application
control properly to those kind of level
two level three maturity controls so we
need centralized visibility so this is
really crucial to see what's going on in
our organization you know I just
mentioned you know it's easier if you've
got a soe but even with a soe we all
live in the real world we know that
that's not what the environment looks
like so if we build an application
control policy based off our soe we then
roll that out we're going to be again in
this situation where we've missed stuff
so we need to make sure we're not
working off one machine we're working
off every machine so make sure that's
coming back
um you need the context at the point
you're making the decision you know
you're going to be fighting the process
if you're always having to you know grab
the hash from there or a truck into
virus total and take the results and put
them over there so you know make sure
that you've got it all in one place
whether that's the tool itself whether
that's pumped into a seam make sure
you've got your kind of the dashboard
that you live in
really importantly you need to be able
to push update out rapidly and
frequently so you need to be able to get
those changes out to users near
instantaneously or at least very quickly
otherwise again they're going to have a
bad time you know if something gets
updated you've push new software up to
your environment and missed something
you know we need to make sure we can fix
those problems quickly
um and along the same lines we need to
make sure we've got methods for
temporary exemption
um so again you never know when an
unexpected update is going to head out
you never know when an exec's going to
need to jump on some weird wacky
wonderful WebEx or something so we need
to make sure you've got that in there
so bring this all back together we need
to understand our why and our what as
step one so again deciding your Central
State maturity model understand what
you're trying to achieve work with your
cross-functional team and understand
your users workflows to Define your
technical requirements
we jump into step two then we can now
evaluate our technology against those
technical requirements and those use
cases understand the limitations and
keep our users day-to-day in mind so we
need to find the right technology for
our workflow for our users and our
environment
step three is the plan plan some more
plan again and develop your business
process so make sure that edge cases are
documented make sure we know how we're
going to handle them make sure we know
how trust is defined and understand the
roles and responsibilities across the
teams
and hopefully at that point you should
be able to deploy successfully with a
solution that's not going to disrupt our
users it's going to enforce the exact
policy we want and will massively reduce
the risk to your environment
so again don't forget application
controls there to help you reduce your
attack surface in your environment so
feel free to start with a broad
definition of trust and cut it down you
know five percent of machines with a
good application control policy is still
five percent machines that aren't going
to get ransomware
cool so I just want to say a huge thanks
to AMT distribution for dealing with
slot to jump up on stage and talk to you
so EMT is a crayon company and they're
focused on delivering proven effective
and Innovative cyber Security Solutions
so they've got a booth out in the vendor
Hall so please go check them out and
have a chat to them
I just want to finish off by mentioning
airlock digital the company I work for
so we were founded by people that were
struggling with this stuff all day every
day in Canberra in federal government
you know doing it in the big leagues
they found themselves constantly
fighting so they decided to develop a
technology that has all these decisions
kind of baked into the product so if
you're Keen to have a look have a play
come past our booth and we can get you
set up with application control kind of
there and then if you want to have a
play thank you
thank you
thank you very much Josh wonderful
presentation you rightly thanked EMT all
the sponsors make this possible we're
about to break from morning T the best
thing you can do for the sponsors is get
down there go around the booths check in
with your app do the passport thing go
in the running for great prizes chat
with some of these people who've made
the entire event possible Josh thank you
so much mate wonderful presentation we
go to morning tea now then break into
our parallel streams if you're tossing
and telling me Oh do I want to come to
the speed debate you want to come to the
speed debate if you haven't seen it it
is the famous way that we finish off Oz
cert every year six Topics in an hour
best luminators in the industry tearing
strips off each other and having a bit
of a laugh too so after afternoon tea
we'll see you all back here for the
speed debate until then morning tea and
your parallel sessions enjoy
baby
[Music]