good afternoon and welcome to day one of
oscar 2022 my name is valdemar jacobson
from business aspect i'm your chair for
this session
um for this session we have jonathan
neal
talking about rethinking your identity
strategy and how to determine what
security is enough security or have you
got the controls right in your business
please welcome jonathan
thank you thank you very much indeed and
um and welcome
so yes i'm jonathan neal i'm the vice
president of solution engineering for
savian
i've now been saving for about five and
a half years but in total i've been
working in the identity and governance
arena
probably for about 22 years so i've seen
a lot of change
in that time a lot of evolution in terms
of application ecosystems and a lot of
evolution in terms of
security challenges cyber security
challenges and of course regulatory
compliance and how that impacts
our roles as security professionals and
how we address those types of challenges
so it's fantastic to be at all cert
it's also fantastic to be doing
in-person events again
i think if you're all like me i got
tired of doing webinars after the first
six months of the covered lockdown
so it's a refreshing change to be
actually
able to meet and talk to people in
person
okay so in this session what i'll be
talking about is some of the strategies
that you can employ to rethink your
identity governance strategies for the
modern enterprise
so before we do that we'll just take a
recap really on just looking back at
what are some of the aspects that are
causing those concerns or causing these
challenges so looking at how the
evolving cyber security landscape has
affected the roles that we have the role
we play and also the types of tools and
processes that we need to deploy in
order to
ensure that our customers or our
partners
are staying safe
once we've done that we'll then start to
look at some of the strategies to
rethink and redefine your iga strategy
how do we reskill
your environment
so that you can address some of these
new concerns and of course how do you
reboot
how do you start fresh how do you start
taking the new way of thinking the new
way of developing the skills and the
platforms that you have at your disposal
to reboot your iga strategy so it's fit
for the modern enterprise
their business is changing and i think
in the last few years um sometimes due
to covered business has actually changed
at a more rapid pace than we've ever
seen before
and we've seen a huge explosion in the
number of digital first or digital
transformation programs
and that's introduced a lot of new it
challenges and a lot of a lot of new
cyber security challenges
it's also had the knock-on effect that
what it's done is introduced a whole
another set of identities that we need
to manage and govern within the
enterprise
whether that's
employees contractors partners the
supply chain
rpa iot devices workloads identities are
everywhere
so now it really is the right time to
start looking at rethinking your ij
strategy
but what are some of the challenges
for me targeted attacks
often compromise
um you know mismanaged identity
scenarios now whether that is just poor
or weak password management or password
hygiene
whether that is ungoverned or unmanaged
supply chain user accounts
or whether it's of course privileged
identities that remain within your
systems with standing privileges that
are often excessive
at a great way for an attacker to enter
your network and move laterally across
and we've seen loads of examples where
privileged identity particularly has
been exploited
to cause not only business disruption
but also financial losses and maybe
we'll cover some of those as we go
through
so some interesting statistics there was
a recent survey
um
and the survey returned 79 of the
organizations within that survey
admitted that they'd had some kind of
identity related breach within the last
two years
now that's a pretty frightening prospect
79 of those organizations
but i also think what's more critical is
the fact that 99 of those organizations
believed that their identity related
breaches were absolutely preventable
but what's the impact of just doing
nothing
let's understand that
well we talked about breaches and
breaches are devastating to any
organization
whether it's in terms of audit findings
or audit failures
fighting financial impact or
reputational damage or of course
business disruption
but i actually think some of the root
causes the fact that the tools that are
currently deployed in a lot of
organizations
are either out of date
too expensive too costly to own and
operate properly and are effectively
wholly ineffective at dealing with a
modern set of threats
so if you stop for a moment and you
reflect on this huge explosion in the
numbers of different types of identities
that you manage
plus the risk
that you introduce to your organization
by not managing those identities
appropriately
you can
really see the size of both the
challenge and opportunity that lays
ahead
so how do we start to rethink our iga
strategy how do we start to sort of
remap what it is that's important to us
and how we can implement the proper
tooling and the proper controls to
ensure that we are governing and
managing our identities appropriately
so we need a new way we need a new way
to manage all of these different types
of identities within our environment and
we talked about our customers our
partners our employees our privileged
accounts and our workloads
but also the actual application
landscape or the platform landscape has
changed significantly over the last few
years as well
so you need a tool that's flexible
enough
and scalable enough to also be able to
onboard some of your
businesses most critical applications
and infrastructure
whether that is data infrastructure as a
service running in single cloud
multi-cloud
whether it's your core erp platforms
financial systems
or new sas applications and
collaboration tools these things
exploded over covid where you had to
start doing more collaboration with
people
through different tools like microsoft
teams for example
and of course if you're in the
healthcare space then it's really
important for you to be able to manage
who has access to some of those
electronic healthcare records
so looking at how do i
onboard more applications how do i
manage more applications how do i
onboard and manage
you know more identities is really key
to be able to drive a 360 degree view
across your organization in terms of who
has access to what
is that access being used appropriately
and what does that access really mean
putting someone in an ad group could
have implications beyond your wildest
dreams
it could give someone full control over
all of your ec2 instances running in
your aws cloud
right so it's a really important factor
to be able to
recognize that information and be able
to put the right security controls
around it
so you can manage your identities you
can secure your business critical
applications
and of course once we start doing this
we can also put in processes to start
automating some responses or automating
some processes
so i like to think about this
this diagram and
i kind of envision myself sitting in the
dark trying to complete a thousand piece
jigsaw puzzle
it's pretty impossible
but if you now think about this in terms
of all of these identities all of these
applications all these infrastructure
what we're now looking at is actually a
puzzle that's hundreds of thousands of
pieces
and the problem is you don't necessarily
have a good idea or understanding of
what that final picture is actually
going to look like
so you take that problem and you magnify
it many many times over
so what is it we can do to help
drive some
clarity from that chaos that we see
and the way that we do that today is by
using modern capabilities like machine
learning
intelligence analytical controls
which really does help an organization
implement better automation and whether
that is managing our user journey from a
life cycle management perspective
how can i give them
most of what they need day one
but also what happens if i need
my user to
request additional access discretionary
access how do i make that process
more streamlined how do i make it
predictive how do i tell the user what
it is based on their relationship with
my organization what it is they should
be requesting
and of course how do i make sure that
what that person is requesting isn't
actually going to introduce new risk
into my organization whether that is by
granting them access to critical
applications or creating segregation of
duties which could cause
financial
fraud or just audit findings
so we're managing the lifecycle of these
identities and obviously events is
something that naturally occurs through
the life cycle of an identity so how do
we make sure when that user changes
their role it could be going from a
contractor to an employee it could be
going from sales to marketing it could
be coming becoming from an individual
contributor to a manager how do we make
sure that we are
right sizing the access that they need
based on that new role
and we're not introducing additional
levels of risk
so this isn't
just something that can be done with
iga alone right we need to leverage
different
avenues or different facets to provide
some additional information as to how we
manage that journey
so thinking about intelligence and
analytics how can we leverage peer group
analytics
how can we look at what are other people
that have the same set of
characteristics as me
or the same sets of attributes as me
what do they have what does their access
look like what is the level of coherence
can i use that to make more predictive
experience on behalf of my user
absolutely
can i use things like historical trends
what have other people requested in the
past was it successful was it approved
was it rejected
so can i leverage those insights again
to help me make more informed decisions
as an approver as to whether i should
grant that access to those users or not
and as i mentioned
one of the key things here is not
introducing additional levels of risk so
what other things can i leverage within
my iga ecosystem to help make those
better decisions and better automation
whether it is
grc type integration segregation of duty
checks before i'm granting the access
whether it is leveraging information
that's coming from a user behavioral
analytics technology or a seam system to
provide more real-time more contextual
based risk
and of course one of the last pieces of
the puzzle is just to make sure that
when that user's journey within the
organization finishes that we've got to
make sure that we are removing those
accesses we're making sure that we are
staying clean from a governance
perspective we are not
um you know increasing the size of
our attack surface by leaving accounts
um
unmanaged ungoverned
when the user or the owning identity is
moved on from the organization
so again better automation
better life cycle management better risk
control better visibility
so
if you
think about that from an ij perspective
think about all the things that are
possible to do then it is possible to
start conquering some of these identity
challenges
and it could be all of the above it
could be just a subset of these maybe
you just want to
modernize a legacy iga or pam solution
maybe you've got a problem managing your
supply chain your third parties
or maybe it's achieving continuous
compliance controls
highly regulated financial systems
so these can all be done when you start
looking at iga
more holistically looking at your
applications more holistically and how
you manage those access the days of
having individual silos
of grc technologies of provisioning
technologies of pam technologies you
know are really a thing of the past and
they're the things that introduce risk
and latency
and
can cause identity mismanagement
so how do we
reskill we're rethinking our iga we
understand what the problem is the risk
is of having all these unmanaged and
ungoverned identities the risk of not
incorporating all of our applications
into our
new iga ecosystem
i always say re-skilling is about people
processing technology in that order
so certainly you've got to do an amount
of re-skilling
in terms of what is possible with a
modern iga technology what's changing in
terms of industry best practice what's
happening in terms of
the direction that the industry is going
let's get rid of that
so pick on a couple of things right um
and i mentioned um some
major high-profile attacks
um that caused untold damage and
business disruption to a number of
organizations in europe and in north
america particularly in the last couple
of years
and one of the things that they're
looking to
do as an outcome
of these types of challenges is to move
towards more of a zero trust identity
model
and if we think about that in the
context of pam it's quite
straightforward right
traditional pam vendors
they go off they scan all the privileged
identities in your
in your data center
and they put them in a vault and then
they put some services around which
allows you to check in check out and
rotate password
that's not actually solving the problem
it's just centralizing the problem
you haven't reduced your attack surface
so you haven't necessarily implemented
anything that's going to drive real
security benefits so a lot of our
customers are now looking at a new
approach how do we manage pam
differently how do we do this based on
more of a just in time
just enough
approach how do i request access to a
privileged resource
with privileges
would allow me to perform certain
functions
only when i need it
only as much as i need
and of course how do i make sure that
when i finish doing that activity that
that information is actually removed
and we'll talk about some of that in a
second
but if you think about identity you
think about governance privilege you've
got to be able to adapt to changes as
we've said we've seen unprecedented
changes in the last two years alone the
explosion of digital transformation the
explosion of the numbers of identities
the types of applications and systems
and platforms
so being agile with an ij program
you know is again paramount to
successful implementation not taking
uh you know two months to onboard a new
application by which time you know
there's maybe another application or
another release or something else that's
come on to take its place
and we talked a lot about automation um
you know automating additional decisions
um not just from uh should this person
have access to something
but what about if i'm doing something
that i believe is not necessarily within
the best interests of my organization
what about if it is something
that is outside the remit of what that
person subscribed to doing as they
executed a privileged session so how do
we make automated decisions in terms of
removing that access
shutting down that session automatically
based on certain risk signatures
and of course how do i bring more
context to risk
i think one of the things actually i'll
show this on the next slide because it's
probably easier to describe this so if
you think about this from
uh harnessing the power of identity
today and harnessing the power of
additional providers we're extending the
visibility we're extending the risk
profile
to different avenues yes we're managing
all of our identities
across the top right there
and we're feeding that into our risk
engine within our ij solution which
allows us to make intelligent decisions
based on access requests on
certification campaigns on risk
management and so on
but what about if i could tell you about
something
even more
powerful than making those types of
decisions
what if i'm a salesforce user um and i
have
because of my role as a vp of sales i
have the ability to export my customer
list
it's in my role right i have access to
the customer list what if i was able to
tell you that for the last two weeks
that person's been
on job sites
would you make a different decision as
to whether you allowed that operation to
happen
based on that additional risk context
right absolutely
what if i'm requesting access as a
devsecops guy right i own the
infrastructure that's running in my
cloud service
and my role is to
manage this i have privileged access to
a lot of my services
so for me accessing a particular service
isn't necessarily a risk in itself or it
wouldn't be an easy
easy to identify risk because the risk
doesn't actually exist with me as the
person
the risk doesn't actually exist with the
operation that i'm trying to undertake
the risk is actually what i'm trying to
access
so what if we can
tell you that the service that that
person is requesting access to
is compromised it hasn't been patched it
has open ssh ports open rdp ports
unencrypted disks attached to that
workload would you make a different
decision as to whether you allowed
access
to that endpoint given that information
absolutely you would
so when we talk about
leveraging different risk contexts
we think about a wider
risk
set of risk providers that are common in
your in your ecosystem again breaking
down some of those silos and being able
to drive more value
by getting in more contextual more
real-time risk analysis
so some of the pillars um of success for
a converged iga platform from my past my
perspective
i think first of all extensibility
looking for a platform that you can
start with a set of use cases
maybe it's on iga maybe it's automation
maybe it is third-party access
management
but as and when you mature
as and when you evolve that ij strategy
how do i
provide more services without disruption
without heavy lifting without more
coding without different integrations
so i'm looking for a platform that will
allow me to start and address my
immediate business goals but also to be
able to quickly adopt new modules new
features to address the business goals
or the it goals of the future
built in the cloud fast time to value
i mentioned in my introduction i've
spent 22 years doing iga so i've been
through the whole pain of
um
heritage legacy whatever you want to
call it in terms of iga on-prem where it
takes you six months to do the sizing of
the hardware work out which os
you need to run to be supported across
all these platforms building the
platform acquiring the technologies it
takes six months so what have you done
you've achieved nothing other than build
a platform
and in my time there were so many
different iga programs that reached the
18 month point and the only achievement
that actually happened
was the fact that they had onboarded a
handful of applications
for provisioning and they had
implemented password reset
fantastic right an i.t tool for an i.t
job
so again the whole business landscape
has completely changed it's a business
enablement tool it's an
agile tool that allows you to
immediately sorry allows you to move at
the speed of business
right rather than restricting the speed
of business and without compromise to
security or regulatory compliance
so built in the cloud fast time to value
configuration and not code all of these
things are high on my agenda when i'm
looking at
rebooting or rethinking my iga
best-in-class service engagement model
you know that's really important i need
experts people that have been there
people that have done this people that
have addressed these types of problems
in the past
because
this is not about having java developers
or net developers
right deployed for your iga program
this is about business and risk
consulting
so
you know the people that you need in
order to help build that center of
excellence within any enterprise you
know has really kind of shifted from
deep technology
to yes obviously you still have to have
that grasp of technology but you need to
be able to translate what the business
is requiring what internal audit
function is requiring
you know what the cfo is
needing
from
let's say an sod perspective
and operational excellence absolutely
being able to
have a platform that is
more scalable
more resilient more secure than anything
that you've built in your data center
you know how many data center people
have their own sock too type 2 iso
fedramp certifications
so the whole block is the whole
challenges of moving to the cloud oh
it's my data it's in the cloud it's not
secure i mean that's not that's not
correct
you're looking at these platforms now
that are
very very well secured very well
certified you know and this is an annual
process to maintain these certifications
and again that is everything from people
process technology
who are you hiring what is the
background check what are they going to
be doing for you
right all these things become really
really important and is that a headache
that you want to
maintain yourself running on-prem
running all these servers running all
this real estate keeping the lights
watered keeping upgrades done
right not focusing on how do i actually
work with the business to provide you
know a more efficient iga process
so we think about rebooting
so we now
understand what the problem landscape is
we know that we've got to rethink things
we've got to do things in a slightly
different way and we know that we've got
to be ready to re-skill
based on the way that we're going to
address some of these issues
so what about what's happening in terms
of
the industry so again
there are um
there's been a number of uh
surveys and things that that happen
frequently and gartner are a major
provider or source of these types of
things
so in a recent survey a year or so ago
people were asked what is the most
important thing in the future of a
converged iam or ij platform
52 that's the majority what a platform
that meets all of their requirements
they don't want to employ java
developers.net developers to do this
kind of stuff anymore they want
something that will give them outbox
exactly what it is they need
27 said
you know i'm happy to um have some
misses i'm happy not to cover everything
that i need but i actually want to what
i need is a tool a broader tool that's
going to allow me to do more with less
so whether that is converging
grc with iga or whether that's
converging pam with iga or third-party
access governance with iga
and 21 said the most important thing for
them is a sas delivered model
so these are just some insights that you
might want to take away
market
predictions uh 45
of respondents said
um you know that they were looking for a
converged platform that was one of the
most important things
for them uh incredibly eighty-four
percent
of people said that they were looking uh
first shifter cloud and whether that is
iga whether that is ig uh and pam
whether that's just pam standalone
so to meet the demands of cloud you've
got to be in the cloud you've got to be
born and architected in the cloud
and of course not everybody is at the
same level of maturity
so it's okay right
we all have a different starting point
we all have a different journey
with which to get to our end point so it
could just be that you know your main
priority is building in better
automation
using analytics to drive better decision
making so i can make sure i'm
provisioning my day one users with the
right access that they need to be
effective and efficient from day one
so
just to finish off
introducing
the market leading number one uh
converged identity platform
being able to onboard any application
any infrastructure any identity any
cloud
and being able to deliver services
across those identities
such as identity governance
administration
privileged access management
third cut third-party governance
application grc
and data protection
i forgot an end slide my apologies
so i really in summary i really hope
that you found some aspects of
that
interesting or at least informative and
of course if you want to come back and
learn anything more about savian
then obviously we're going to be in the
main expo area
so i'm happy to take any questions if
we've got any uh
couple of minutes left
or i can take some questions back at the
booth
they don't seem to be any questions from
the audience either locally or remote so
um
if everybody could uh please thank
the speaker on behalf of the conference
oh thank you very much
thanks everyone
so we've got a 14-minute break until the
next session the next one in here that
was i was looking at just a moment ago
there we go um what the bad guys are
looking for cloud misconfigurations
so that could be interesting so anyway
all right