there we go hi everyone you might want
to move close to the front and the
reason is the next guy is really good so
you're gonna want to be close to his
show and it's gonna fill in so if you'd
like to move close that'd be great
I'll give you a chance if not I'll get
started wherever you're comfortable I
would encourage you he's been known to
give away free things involve the
audience and light things on fire
so you might want to be close or further
away from the fire but that's your
choice
well you got it looks like everybody's
got their popcorn that's good let's get
started hi I'm Jeff I'm a senior
security engineer this presentation was
submitted by myself and malicious we
submitted it together but unfortunately
she's not able to make it today
she's a training specialist working with
organizations on inclusion volunteers
with targeted groups and we are both ex
teachers so this is I'm this classic
teacher turned hacker and she's a
teacher turned privacy advocate and we
submitted this talk on our largely our
opinion on some issues in the industry
right now so we regret that
Stella wasn't able to make it if you
follow her on Twitter she's pretty
active on Twitter you can probably
figure out why do please send her
support messages or regrets that she
wasn't able to make it make it here
you're also welcome to send her job
offers as well so feel free to do that
so when I'm talking today if I say I or
my or me I do mean we or our this is as
much our talk as it is hers or mine I
was getting notes from her this morning
saying say this say this so this is
something we did together in
collaboration it generally represents
our opinions this isn't a traditional
research based talk this is generally
our opinion that we're presenting and it
doesn't reflect the opinion of any
groups were associated with which may be
our employers or other groups that said
let's begin how do we become a hacker
you could say security professional or
whatever but that's probably for another
debate you might try learning to code
challenging yourself to think creatively
asking questions attending conferences
like you are now hopefully this is a
good path for you and you know you just
might go try hacking something and maybe
then you'll become a hacker there exists
in our industry however this notion that
to become a hacker the only way to do it
is to lock yourself in a room isolated
do nothing but write exploits and
reverse-engineer applications or scan
the internet and hack things and you're
just it's an isolated thing or to do by
yourself
come join the struggle like everyone
else and eventually you will become lead
when you need help just go figure it out
google it and try harder it's
practically our industry motto sure many
of you have heard it before
so our opinion though is that telling
someone new or even an experienced
person to try harder without providing
additional support is detrimental to
their education it discourages them from
continuing and has broader implications
on the diversity of skilled talent we
can bring into our industry and I'll be
addressing these points as part of the
presentation
most people don't learn something
they've never done before
by simply figuring it out some do and
that's great if that's if that's you
others when they are not succeeding
don't continuously beat their heads
against the wall until it just magically
works by very definition that's insanity
further still these methodologies are
quite possibly the most ineffective and
inefficient way for someone to learn
something just telling someone to go
figure it out there's got to be a
quicker better way to learn there are
also many types of learners depending
which theories subscribe to there might
be four seven or eight different
learning styles that you might fall
under one such style is the Vark model
which defines four learning styles
visual visual auditory reading writing
and kinesthetic
another is the Howard Gardner model and
depending on who you ask it's eight or
nine as a little bit of a bonus one
there defines eight modalities of
intelligence things like musical
rhythmic visual spatial verbal
linguistic logical mathematical bodily
kinesthetic interpersonal and
intrapersonal as well as naturalist
without going into too much detail on
each of these if you were to reflect
right now on your own learning styles
you could probably think of a few
categories that reflect your more
preferred or dominant way you like to
learn when we consider the population as
a whole we can accept that a diverse
population would be comprised of many
diverse types of learners not all areas
though are weighted equally across
various groups or roles when we're
talking about these different learning
styles this is referred to as
neurodiversity which also includes other
neurodiverse learners including things
like autism a DD ADHD among others and
it's actually said that info sack or
hacking attracts and a great percentage
or a higher percentage of neuro-diverse
learners which generally is good
certainly we need this variation of
thought in our workplace and we should
encourage it I believe however that our
actions are discouraging to people with
various learning styles and we need to
do a better we need to do better at
welcoming new learners and all types of
learners when you think of a typical
engineer you might be expected to
categorize them as a more logical
mathematical learner they might have
some visual or kinesthetic tendencies as
well you might think of an artist to be
more visually spatially inclined or
musicians to be more music and rhythm
ethically inclined go figure hey
it is true that people tend to gravitate
towards roles or careers that play to
their strengths
but many industries also benefit from
the inclusion of a diverse set of
learners from all categories and I
believe that InfoSec is one of them now
I'd like you to consider what happens
when you tell a new learner trying to
tell something and trying to enter
information security you're trying to
become a hacker to just google it try
harder and figure it out based on the
learning styles I just told you about
what learning styles and modalities are
you forcing on them definitely you're
forcing like a reading writing skill
you're requiring them to have that skill
or be successful in that learning
environment maybe if they're more visual
you could have said go to YouTube and
YouTube it's in that case you're
replacing google it with YouTube it you
are very quickly though excluding most
auditory learners and it was certainly
difficult for many kinesthetic learners
to get started without strong skills in
other areas on the modality side of
things you're pretty much forcing people
to be interpersonal go do it yourself
and that excludes a large percentage of
the population that interpersonal person
who just asked for your help immediately
has a much steeper barrier to overcome
some of the logical and visual learners
might thrive in this area but the rest
are facing a more uphill battle my point
in this section is when you tell someone
to go figure it out google it or try
harder you are forcing them to either
conform to a narrower set of learning
styles or place additional barriers in
place that may make it more difficult
for them to be successful it'd be
detrimental and maybe even prohibitive
there are many reasons why learners
struggle to the point where they are
unable to learn a concept or even give
up in short in order to get the best
chance of success you need to keep the
learner engaged and at a level they can
handle without getting bored or
frustrated and to teach to a method
where they have the best chance of
success for learning for their style
when it comes to keeping a learner
engaged we want to keep them in a bit of
a Goldilocks zone too easy they're gonna
get bored too hard frustrated just right
sweet spot super engaged hopefully when
someone comes to you with a question
they are very likely either super
excited about the concept they are
learning and looking to be challenged
further further so they're finding it
easy and they want to learn more they
want to be kept in that engaged zone or
they're getting to the point where
they're frustrated and could use some
extra help to keep them going their
kneading like a recalibration of their
learning what's your answer and if you
tell them to try harder you might as
well tell them to screw off it's pretty
much the effect you will have for either
person that comes up to you I hope my
hope is that you can see how this
mentality has a discouraging effect on
new learners it also makes you a bit of
an ass I believe that this mentality has
broader implications to our community
makeup the types of problems we are able
to solve and our ability to have a
positive impact on society the results
is our community is made up of a
narrower set of learning styles
it is hard for us to overcome the
stereotype of a loner hacker in a
basement in a hoodie that everyone is
afraid of because men and many of us do
resemble that stereotype self included
maybe if we had more interpersonal
learners I wouldn't have to tell people
that I'm an ethical hacker and not
someone who they should be afraid of I
haven't ever had to ask my doctor or
lawyer if they're an ethical doctor so I
would prefer to just be called a hacker
or security professional and not have to
tell somebody that I'm actually a good
guy you should just believe me but we
might be a long way off of that one but
maybe those interpersonal learners if we
welcomed more of them into our group
could help some inform Society of the
positive in positive ways we contribute
or maybe they could help educate the
public on our activities so that we
don't get arrested for doing things they
don't fully understand I mean we saw
this last week our limits on including
diverse learners from other groups
prevents us from solving problems that
we can't relate to as a simple example
how many of you have ever seen an
application and thought geez what idiot
engineer designed this it's completely
unusable
that's arcmap if you ever tried to use
it you might find it difficult you might
certainly find it overwhelming for most
people even visual learners look at all
those visuals on the more severe side
though our real-world complex security
problem and privacy problems it is
difficult for many of us to fully
understand the impact of security and
privacy decisions if we can't relate to
the threat model or the learning styles
of the users whose lives we are
impacting by these decisions
we are not encouraging empathy or
developing it through our personal
interactions and one of my notes this
morning I got from Stella was just
scream empathy at them all day and
hopefully that will translate into more
more caring in our industry the result
is we create a mob of people that think
and act the same in our in reality it is
the outliers we need to give her a
bigger voice to to help overcome our
weaknesses supporting other learners I
wanted to take a few minutes to cover
some counter points that we that often
come up when I when I try to argue why
we shouldn't be saying try harder there
may be more but I'd be happy to discuss
and refine my position later over a
beverage after this talk I'm more than
happy to speak with you further the
first counter point is if we don't make
hacking hard it will lead to unqualified
charlatans
selling snake oil and this if you're not
familiar this was a booth at RSA last
week where a company bought a booth to
legitimately try and sell snake oil and
I think the counter-argument was our
products not snake oil like everybody
else at this conference that was the
argument they're making regrettably I
don't think we'll ever squash the last
charlatan in our industry they'll always
exist in industries where the general
public have trouble understanding what's
going on and what the concepts are
whenever there's a clout of not with
confusion cryptocurrencies are full of
them right now and lots of scams are
existence reality is InfoSec needs a lot
more people there's a massive shortage
of skilled talent i believe that
bringing more people to the community
will make it harder for charlatans to
exist as there were more qualified
people to call to call and
discourage their behavior the second
argument is
InfoSec isn't an entry-level position I
hear this a lot you also see this in job
requirements and it can be discouraging
for new people to try and enter the
field did you know that there's almost
as many CISSP postings as there are CS
qualified CIS SPS this is based on 2015
study but it's continuing to grow in
that rate since I agree that security
director C so and many other positions
are not entry-level but if not enough
schools are teaching security and you
don't hire fresh grads anyway how else
will someone learn and how will they
learn from someone else it might be
better to try and structure your
organization in a way that allows for a
certain percentage of new learners of
various learning styles to participate
and it can work with your organization
if entry-level for entry-level roles as
they grow their skills I was doing a
security assessment a couple months ago
and one of the members on the security
team a few months earlier was actually
one of the bank tellers and now they're
on the security team through the
company's internal training system or
process the way they invest in people
and to do this we really need to value
training and professional development
within an organization
it takes investing in your employees for
long term growth it is my hope that in
the future you consider the implication
of the implications of the words you use
to encourage new learners I hope that
you consider the ways in which you
support all types of learners to the
InfoSec community and I'll be using the
remainder of this presentation to
provide you with ways you can do that
but first I thought it'd be fun if I
taught somebody something on stage do I
have a brave volunteer nobody's brave
enough come on up now that you
volunteered there's absolutely no
backing out
come on up have you ever been in
handcuffs before okay I don't make no
judgment the skill I'm gonna teach you
today is how to get out of handcuffs so
let's go book let's go maybe I don't
want to break your watch so we're I'll
just just remove it here you're
comfortable with me like touching you
okay
we'll just put it right here I think
yeah I won't do it to tighten by the way
my goal isn't to hurt you in any way so
if you're uncomfortable or you're gonna
get hurt or you're worried about it
don't worry I'll let you out okay so I'm
gonna teach you how to get out of
handcuffs you just go ahead and figure
it out I would tell you to google it I
go ahead you know figure it out whatever
the other than google it try harder
certainly if you're trying you can see
how it is quite difficult she has a very
literal obstacle in front of her to
prevent you from learning this skill and
you've sort of dived into it to try to
learn how to get into handcuffs and I'm
a bit of a jerk of a teacher in this
case now the first thing I would have
told you if I was going to teach you how
to get out of handcuffs I'm actually not
gonna teach you okay
afterwards I'll take the time and take
you through a full proper lesson we
probably don't have time for that right
now but the first thing I would have
taught you was it's probably a lot
easier to get a hand out of handcuffs if
you have them in front of you and it's
probably easier if your hands are in a
different position then they might be
right now you might want to know where
the tools available to you are maybe you
need a lockpick maybe you need a shim
maybe you need something else but
otherwise
you're stuck there so I hope you can
realize like just telling someone to try
harder if they don't have the skills and
tools available to them or it's not to
their learning style or they're not they
can't visualize it
some people can figure this out others
might be there for a while I'm not gonna
put you to that test but I wanted to
give the point that when you tell
someone to just try harder you're not
actually helping them there is a very
few number of people who that use that
as a motivating factor but most don't I
think I have it to somewhere well I've
got the actual key yeah dropped it I
think you're gonna be there a little bit
longer okay so it seems like you have a
little bit of experience and prior
knowledge on this that's like I said no
judgment I'll let you try if you'd like
to keep working on it and I can
afterwards I promise I will take you
full full through a full lesson if you
want there you go round of applause no
I'm gonna I've a challenge the next
speaker to a gentlemen's competition but
he hasn't accepted yet so we'll see if
he'll accept thank you I didn't get your
name thank you Mary oh and your watch
put these here case we need them later
I mentioned that Stella and I are both
ex teachers and we both share this
experience as a story so I thought I
would share it with you most new high
school teachers come to a really
interesting realization early on in
their careers for many of them they've
always been in high achieving academic
courses everyone around them was mostly
keen to learn read ahead if necessary do
extra credit and could generally pay
attention for more than 10 minutes
without getting too distracted I might
be the exception to that in university
we read textbooks stayin awake through
three our lectures most of the time
absorbing as much information as we
could we were able to work independently
on large essays or projects and we're
generally able to learn independently or
with limited additional support in
Teachers College we were surrounded by
other mostly high achieving academic
learners but something different started
to happen here we learned about all
different learning styles that I shared
with you and other teaching styles to
accommodate those learning styles ideas
like project-based learning
differentiated instruction where you
accommodate to a variety of learning
styles and developing what's called a
growth mindset along with many other
buzz words depending on the current
political regime and anyone who's worked
in education can probably relate to that
you mean we won't be lecturing for hours
at a time and the students won't just
hang off for every words and sit in
their seats for prolonged periods of
time in most areas where I'm from I'm
from Ontario if you finished Teachers
College and you're lucky enough to get a
job the first class is you will be
teaching will certainly be the
challenging ones the the ones that not
necessarily every other teacher wants to
teach surprise the realization that you
quickly come to early on is that there
are many obviously diverse learning
styles who don't learn anyway close to
how you learned to become a teacher
there are many who would not thrive in
the same environment you are accustomed
to and if you want to teach them you'll
have to quickly adapt to survive or
they'll eat you alive for me I'll always
remember that first grade 9 applied
French class I ever taught
at the time I'd been teaching for a
couple years and but I needed a job and
they needed a French teacher so there I
was and in Ontario every student from
about Grade three to nine needs to take
one French class a year so the sorry did
you interpret that or did I say that
okay one French class and this class is
mandatory for all grade nine students to
graduate so this is this represents the
last French class most of them will ever
take this to students who may choose to
continue to take French are usually in a
more academic class at a different level
and I do know some teachers who
absolutely love teaching this class this
one wasn't for me just to give you a
little bit of a picture I didn't quite
have that many students in the class but
at days it felt like that my lesson for
the day would often include no fewer
than ten short activities to work
through at different times because some
students would chew through them so fast
they'd be bored and need continuous work
in front of them others would barely
make it through one or two in a day
getting them to listen for more than
five minutes all at once in their seats
for two minutes even was hard enough
some students would finish I said to get
finished quick and get bored others need
support and help and extra one-on-one
time which is to challenge to do when
you have so many diverse learners no I
don't advise that my students try to get
drunk by licking hand sanitizer Tide
Pods weren't invented at the time there
was interesting story where a grade 12
student was absent from their class the
previous day and they had missed a test
so the teacher next door came over and
said so and so it needs a quiet place to
work can he write his test in your class
I laughed a little bit but said sure by
the end they never wanted to return to
that class again because it was that
seemed wide awakening that grade 12
academic student
never experienced a class like that
either I can probably go on for hours
about this class and I think if you talk
to most teachers they've got stories of
the the worst class they've ever had to
teach or the most challenging class in
order to survive though this is the
important point I want to make is you
have to quickly learn strategies to help
engage learners at their level you need
to connect with them and keep them
engaged to be successful I'm sure there
are many of you here today who didn't
come from a university setting into
information security many of the best
hackers I know barely finished high
school and have wild stories how they
got into the field I hope we can be more
accepting of new people who can join
through whatever means is most efficient
and comfortable for them and that's some
strategies now for the rest of the
presentation so my main thing I want to
get into your head never left you with
one thing today is if you could take try
harder out of your vocabulary that would
be excellent and instead of saying try
harder have you tried and asking the
learner have you tried doing this thing
have you tried doing it this way or try
harder is fine if it's something you say
to yourself to motivate it yourself you
try harder to understand why the learner
is asking that question try harder to
understand their challenges and try
harder to adapt to their learning styles
to help accommodate for them so that
they can be successful there's this
notion of metacognition and reflection
and there's different philosophies on it
but really you want to encourage a
learner to think about their learning
different education professionals have
different philosophies reflection is a
precursor to action you should be
reflecting on the things you've done and
the things you're doing as you're doing
so if you can encourage reflection on
action and reflected reflection in
action Scouts Canada uses a model called
plan du review or the youth are expected
to plan their activity do the activity
and then review on it and I think it's
important for accepting people for what
they know in our industry if you don't
have to prove you're the best that would
be a big one
everybody thinks through the best except
that everyone has a different
perspective and knows different things
try to that learner who's coming to you
you can probably learn a lot from them
as well if not you can learn about how
you will better teach them in the future
I guess it may be you can learn from
them there is a difference between
something being accessible because
anyone can google it versus a tutorial
that caters to diverse learners and
learning styles and meets their needs so
it's an important concept you can say oh
my course is acceptable accessible
because you can read it all online that
doesn't mean it's accessible to all
learners might be low if I were to leave
you with this I would say that try
harder should be something you say to
yourself if you really want to to
everyone else try helping try relating
to their preferred learning style and
demonstrate an idea in that format
accept them for what they know and ask
questions that encourage personal
reflection interesting my parting words
for it would be that hackers are
supposed to be those non-conforming
members of society we are the outliers
the people who call on
everything and hold society to account
when we say try harder it creates a
structure for people to conform to and
force them to
or to our ideas of what a hacker is so
maybe don't do that I want to thank you
for your time I promise you the next
speaker it's absolutely amazing I've
seen him before but thank you