everyone hear me okay I apologize in
advance I just kicked laryngitis from my
hectic travel schedule last week so if I
go on a coughing fit I've got some water
here I hope I don't lose my voice but
should be good so everyone having a good
time so far awesome
so welcome to decepticon basically these
are my deceptive techniques to derail
attempts at open source intelligence
ascent gathering before we get started
the thoughts and opinions I expressed
today are those are mine and mine alone
and do not represent those of IBM the
reason I say this I'm a senior security
architect at IBM I'm the 2017 der beek
on social engineering capture the flag
winner
I do blogs I do podcasts I have my own
blog and podcast advanced persistent
security and that's half out a lot in
Brazilian Jujitsu
they say you either win or you learn I
think I learn a lot because I don't
always tap but aside from that this is
the trophy from the social engine
capture the flag I'm a very vocal person
very outgoing and the picture there to
the right is that one time in my life
that I can actually think of I was
speechless so it's it's a rare
occurrence about decepticon basically I
want to talk about where we can find a
scent this is actually going to start
out as an offensive Oh scent talk
because I want you to understand where
and how I'm going to gather a scent on
you as a target
prior to arming you with some techniques
to make it harder for me to make it a
little bit more clear I don't implement
a lot of these things that I'm going to
tell you for myself I'm framing this
from the perspective of I'm a
practitioner these are things you can do
to make my life harder
so aside from that we'll talk about some
online deception maybe some decoy
accounts Canaries of course to some
degree encryption we can't talk oh sent
without mentioning social media that's
just a requirement we'll talk about
identity management not to be confused
with identity and access
management I'm talking about the
things.when small credit reporting
bureaus and Georgia get breached that
you have to worry about getting stolen
that kind of identity not hating on
anyone specifically to be honest so
where can we find a cent well most of
the time it's on the Internet there are
other methods as well newspapers
conference proceedings any time you deal
with like I Triple E or ACM they're
going to put they are going to publish
conference proceedings to some degree
the fact that this video is recorded and
will be published online that provides
OSINT about the speakers any anecdotes
that we tell about our well personal
lives could be used against us later it
gives people an idea of what we look
like what we sound like our hobbies our
interests anything of that nature of
course you have your academic journals
that's all with those you have to think
of it from the perspective of this is
what this college is interested in this
is what this researcher is interested in
and to some degree you might even get an
email address and a phone number so
there's a little bit of a scent to start
with photos 2016 at Derby con a
gentleman by the name of Josh Huff he's
on Twitter at BAE wolf 88 he
demonstrated gathering o sent off a
single photo the photo was bragging
about gas prices so the obvious route of
looking at photographic ascent would be
what does the metadata say is it an
iPhone is it an Android does it have GPS
which camera was used which direction
was the phone being held which version
of the phone was this photo taking on
taken on those are all things you can
get from the metadata but Josh went a
completely different way he looked at
the reflection of the glass of the gas
pump and he noticed there was a vehicle
in it so he started doing reverse image
searches for this and he enumerated that
it was a 2006 to 2011 Dodge Durango it
was in this one specific color and he
did a little bit more searching and he
found that there were only three
vehicles of that color registered within
a 50 mile radius of where it was taken
with a little
of further research he could have found
out exactly who the car belonged to and
then we have to talk about geospatial
stuff if you want to deal with that for
the most part you're going to look at
Google and Bing that's going to be your
starting point before I do any social
engineering on anyone I try to take a
what I call the drive and that's where I
will just go to one of their sites
virtually with Google Maps or Bing Maps
or something and I use them both you get
different perspectives from each but
I'll take a drive using this around the
building I'm looking for things like
dumpsters who's their dumpster company
is there a gate is there a visitor
center for this social engineering
capture-the-flag one of the flags is who
does deliveries I saw a big brown boxy
truck backed up to the building for my
target
that's UPS so flag down how about the
fence what's there what's the parking
situation these are all important things
you can find out where the dumpsters are
if you want to go dumpster diving it
gives you some context on how to sneak
in does anyone in here remember the the
shenanigans that happened a few months
ago with Strava the workout app where
some people in the US military we're
using it overseas and they had logged it
as base perimeter the thing is when you
looked it up on Google Maps there was
nothing so basically they outed a
classified base because they had labeled
that base perimeter and they went
running and they shared the data and by
sharing the data it became accessible to
anyone using the app that's just one
example so this this photo is more true
than we will ever know
so when we look at it we see that
someone ironically I was on submarines
in the Navy so the periscope of Facebook
just definitely is even more ironic and
then the fact that I think there still
may be a periscope app as well for
social media but Society wants to look
out the periscope of social media
into the world whereas if they would
just put the periscope down and open the
door they could be exposed to the world
as a whole we see things as they are
framed to us via social media and that
gets into a completely different
discussion for a completely different
type of disinformation that I'm just not
going down that rabbit hole but
nevertheless let's talk about some major
resources here so if you want to do it
from the web until technics comm is ran
by Michael basil o cent framework is ran
by Justin Nordine Oh said framework is
basically a link to it's a repository of
links to other o cent resources things
like public wrench record searches
business records like in the US SEC Form
10-k that lists executives persona
generators so whenever I'm doing those
fishing phone calls I can keep my lies
straight because I have my persona on
the screen right in front of me and if
you want to take a look at that that's
under the OPSEC option on the site but
you can also do things like IP IP
address searches DNS searches hashes all
of that Intel techniques that's Michael
Bezos personalized tools that he wrote
that allows you to interact with certain
things as well there's a very nifty
Facebook image or a Facebook live video
search function so you can go into
Facebook live you get the video ID you
can search on his website for that video
ID and get the latitude and longitude of
where that video is coming from so just
think about that when you're when you're
talking to your teenagers about their
makeup tutorials that they're doing
because I'll be honest when I do my
offensive social engineering at AU cent
talk that's my favorite target it's like
hey look here's a makeup tutorial in
terms of tools I'm a huge fan of recon
ng hands down that's my favorite tool it
doesn't do everything though so it has
integrations with things like show dan
LinkedIn Google it also has interactions
with have I been poned you can even
input user names and it will go scouring
to find out which other websites user
names on your list exist that's how I
found out that my sec TF target had an
account on pornhub that was a little bit
embarrassing didn't go into the report
but it was there data's point is another
good one it does a lot of what recon
Angie does but it's more from the
command line
where recon Angie ironically enough
feels a lot more like Metasploit with
data sploit the biggest thing I can tell
you out of that one is you can do
searches on WikiLeaks I was doing Oh
sent on a target in my previous position
leading up to a phishing campaign and I
used a display and I found that that
institution had 31,000 files on
WikiLeaks I don't know what they said
because they were all in Italian but
they were there and my security point of
contact had no clue
you also have onion scan that was
written by Sara Jamie Lewis and meant to
be a privacy tool so that when you're
operating on both the dark web and the
public web that you're not using the
same key and just like in map or just
like a hammer is it a tool or is it a
weapon you can use it the same way to
find people who are being sloppy about
running their onion sites when they have
a public-facing website as well the
harvester I don't have a whole lot of
experience with the harvester I've never
really warmed up to it
nor have I warmed up to date to spider
foot there used to be a tool called Foca
that works really well it's not been
updated in almost six years and when you
try to run it it crashes now so you
could find a few things out of that but
not a whole lot in terms of training if
you want to get into that micro basil is
the primary source that I would say to
get your ascent training from whether it
be offensive ascent or hiding from the
internet style privacy training Chris
had Negi has a two-day OSINT course and
in his social engineering courses they
cover ou scent as well Justin cites a
Canadian actually he has a Python course
that actually teaches you how to
interact with api's if you take the
Python course you actually learn how to
interact with the Twitter API and get
meaningful data
of it I highly recommend it and then
Micah Hoffman has his four-day sans
course and it's not on the slide but
actually starting in June I will have a
one-day social engineering a docent
course through ec-council that's
actually what this t-shirts for so if
you come to the class you get this cool
t-shirt if you want it and and I
seriously did lose my password so anyone
who wants to give me their password
after this presentation is over just
just meet me in the back corner I will
take them down it'll be purely secure I
promise I would never lead you wrong can
you help me and from a social
engineering perspective those are the
four most important words you can drop
but in terms of ascent where else can
you get ascent you get so you get a
little liquid courage in someone and
they're willing to tell you anything
think of it from the perspective of a
salesperson when you've interacted with
salespeople professionally one of their
first questions tell me about the
problems you face in your organization
tell me about your environment what was
your mom's name before she was married
see how I phrased that it's the same
concept so realistically you could do
the same thing in bars restaurants
there's a restaurant where I live in
Tennessee it's a Thai place I like to
sit in the bar area and there's these
little portholes that go into the dining
room you wouldn't believe the number of
a half-million dollar deals that I've
heard tanked because someone doesn't
know what they're doing from the social
engineering perspective just because I'm
sitting there listening to the whole
deal going down and I'm learning it
which which companies are going to grow
which are shrinking who's about to try
to by whom all sorts of things I was
walking around at Macy's Christmas
around I think 2015 or 2016 there's a
gentleman on the phone yes that number
is 4 8 6 7-5 3 0 9 9 0 3 5 7 6 8 4
expiration date October 20 20 of the
code on the back that's 1 2 3 in the
middle of Macy's Fiona gets that credit
card number have at it
it's not real I give it to scammers all
the time
if you hear the first eight digits the
other eight makes sense so it's 4 8 6
7-5 309 and just do it backwards family
and friends who in here does not have a
social media account whatsoever
ok siblings parents friends do they none
not a lot of friends or family hmm
that almost sounds like a challenge
because even if you don't have an
account someone you know does there's a
good chance Facebook already knows what
you look like they probably already know
your political affiliation just because
of pictures you've been in whether it's
your friends it could be venues you went
to it could be something to that nature
back windshields I can't count the
number of times I've nearly crashed my
car trying to take pictures of back
windshields with interesting stickers
and I don't even know what's going on
with this back windshield here in this
this I mean I really don't I it based on
the Halos I'm going to assume someone
died and I'm going to assume with those
three children I I don't know if those
are stepchildren or not but it's
probably a crazy cat lady involved I
don't know we can obviously tell that
it's Baltimore as well
additionally forums people typically use
the same username everywhere they use it
in forums they use it in email wherever
that's just one way that I can trace you
a lot of mailing lists actually end up
publishing everything as a forum later I
used that in the SE CTF my target
they had a former employee that had
posted for help about their storage
array yes he copied the configuration
file he did not sanitized anything
he gave explicit versions a lot of
information he really shouldn't have
where did he go wrong he didn't snip the
signature block so when I did the search
for the regular expression at company
Tia
there it was job boards
that's a double-edged sword indeed.com
is one of my favorites for two reasons I
find out who's hiring for what I might
find out what technologies they're using
might even find out the exact version
and then I can go searching through
resumes that people have uploaded and
find out even more that's how I found
out who the security company was at my
target because they worked at the target
company it said it in the resume and
then dialing it back a little bit
further
looking at the previous experience it
said I used to be a security guard for
allied Barton working the front gate for
company name it seems harmless it really
does until someone puts two and two
together
I can go bounce that off the careers
page of your of the target company
during the sec TF that my target company
was hiring someone that was an Oracle
ERP administrator they wanted explicit
experience with version 12.2.2 I be had
two entries for Oracle ERP version
12.2.2 : Jackson the other being a
server side to request forgery because
it's an ERP system there's a fairly
decent possibility that's going to be
public facing so just get that injection
there start your server cited request
forgery you can start pivoting from
there I didn't do a single port scan to
find that either Google Google foo if
you're going to do those things you've
got to have Google foo and then social
media which will kind of get into in a
bit so here's the Google foo you're
looking for things like phone number
syntax do they use parenthesis do they
use periods do they use hyphens do they
put a plus one at the beginning of it
how do they do it once you know that you
could search across Google and find it
if you know their phone number range
address the job boards in the forums
with that user that had posted to the
mailing list and not sanitized his
signature block actually found his
github account as well leading to that
github account
I found that he had scripts for Netflix
ice which is used to estimate your AWS
costs I found some scripts for nagios
availability monitoring which okay
arguably that could be used at home I
found a few scripts for max okay that
can be at home as well but then I found
a script to synchronize his Red Hat
satellite server and synchronized
updates the probability of him running
that much red hat at home is very slim
also here if he wrote in three different
languages up until about May of 2016
according to his LinkedIn he left the
company in June 2016 he resumed posting
to his github in September of 2016 in
three new languages so now I've
enumerated languages that that target
company uses Yelp TripAdvisor these are
all places where I can find out things
you like places you've been bad
experiences that you've had great
experiences that you've had it wasn't on
a review site which actually I'll
address their review site first for my
target my target company was in
Louisville Kentucky based on scouring
through employees on Yelp on TripAdvisor
and all of that I found out that there
were three things that they liked craft
beer bourbon and they were foodies so
when I got someone on the phone I
basically said happy Friday
I can't wait to get out of here I just
bought a new case of craft beer and I
had research to find out the exact brand
that I had purchased and the person on
the other end of the phone she said oh
craft beer I love craft beer I was like
what a coincidence I love Fridays too
and then at that point I had instant
rapport and I was able to say I'm
working under the direction of the C so
we have an external audit coming up I
have three to five I have a few
questions that should take three to five
minutes can you help me and from there I
got almost every single flag out of her
so that's one example another example on
social media I found out that a senior
vice president of this company had
tweeted to an airline complaining that
he had been delayed in one Airport and
missed a business meeting in Amsterdam
I'm just gonna make up an airline well
sort of hello this is Air Canada a
customer support I understand that you
had a problem with with your flight to
Amsterdam I would like to help you can
you please provide this information more
than likely he's going to provide that
information even if it's already been
resolved I can say that we reviewed the
actions and the resolution were not up
to it our corporate standards it doesn't
matter because it's a game of cat and
mouse
improv tiptoes that's what it really
boils down to
so with this anyone who knows Adrienne
Sanabria in the middle
his face was actually cropped out of a
larger picture a vendor at InfoSec world
had an owl and he had the owl on his
hand like this with but was doing his
impression but you know it's good
InfoSec people we can't show the owl we
have to crop it to be funny so he's
always watching though just keep that in
mind but within it wasn't we always here
the whole paradigm of her McGurk Olark
Toro the dirty guy rehearsed that sorry
but we also hear the paradigm of we have
to be like South Park's underpants
gnomes because you know with them it was
step one collect the underpants step two
step three profit with it o cent we have
the same problem step one collect all
the Oh set step two step three weaponize
it what we're missing a step two in step
four step to being parse and refined the
data so that you have data that you need
and then step four being disposed of the
data in a secure manner which we'll get
into in a moment so here's a little fun
it was that this is a back windshield
what can we infer about this family
mom's a teacher yep so let's think of it
from the perspective of we are a burglar
and we want to break into this family's
home mom's a teacher so federal holidays
summer break spring break fall break
probably not good times or maybe they
are if they go on vacation you never
know during school hours that's
definitely an ideal time John he plays
soccer
he's probably old enough to play
competitive soccer there's a good chance
that his team's schedule is going to be
on the Internet Neal he's a skater you
find out the local skate park show up
with a Thrasher shirt a pair of etnies
shoes introduce him to the exploited or
the casualties or some other awesome
punk band and he'll probably like you
for about 10 minutes and then he'll pull
his fidget spinner out and it'll be game
over Jessica she's the curve ball why
because you can't tell anything about
her is she old enough to stay by herself
does she have any hobbies we don't know
we'll go back to dad for a moment dad is
one or the other it's a very binary
thing here he's either legitimately
jacked or ripped or the only concept of
ripped he has is ripping his pants it's
one of the other but 5 a.m. or 5 p.m.
there's a good chance you're gonna find
him into gym it doesn't matter how hard
he's working out but he'll probably be
there now comes the dogs Ruby is a hound
hounds make noise in no way shape or
form do I advocate harming the animals
so here's what I recommend doing if
you're going to be a criminal and try to
be successful about it take some dog
bones just keep them busy if you feed a
dog the dog will love you for life just
don't harm them so with regards to the
collection
what can we start with company data if
you go to Bloomberg in search
bloomberg.com and you search for your
company your target company you're going
to find out things like the locations
the phone number the address maybe
in the email syntax you can find out the
managers names and any other
affiliations they have like are they on
a board of directors for something else
then we want to look at things like
vendors who's your antivirus company who
do you sell antivirus to because as an
attacker we're going to try to look at
it from the perspective of what do we
have to evade right and then
affiliations we can all think back to
target the HVAC company had some
security flaws and that allowed the
target or I'm sorry the attacker to
pivot into target that's just one thing
you can find out vo sent social media
I love chasing PR people but I'll tell
you it's secret about PR people too they
are boring they almost never post
anything of value
what exception though they follow the
people who do my target company their PR
people were absolutely boring they
posted pictures of hummingbirds and bird
baths I was like man this is life on the
edge here I should mail them some garden
gnomes but they followed all of senior
management that did post the fun stuff
they followed all of the sea levels all
the senior managers and then any of the
people within the organization that were
known to be public speakers come to
think of it I have a few people from my
PR department that follow me on social
media mm-hmm anyway but that's your key
employees if I want to get to the CEO
and I know the CEO is an avid runner
obviously I'm not an avid runner I mean
I run to the refrigerator from time to
time but that's about it
but if I were working with the team
there's a good chance someone on that
team could actually pose as an avid
runner get close build rapport ask the
questions find out what they need to
know they're an avid golfer so it's all
about context I use the phrase it's the
context for the contact
that's what you're looking for so for
Google you want to use innovative
thinking things like your company name
plus the phone number syntax you're
gonna find all the sales PR and
marketing people right there he maybe
even find legal okay now the next one
you're going to do an advanced Google
search against that company's website
company TLD file type PDF or docx or XLS
that's gonna find any PDFs any word Docs
any spreadsheets
that's out on the internet from that you
might find some sensitive stuff like
passwords alternatively you may find out
things like who created it what
operating system they have what they use
to open PDFs from the perspective of the
sec TF those are all flags from a real
life perspective of an attacker those
are all ways that someone could exploit
their way in if they know you're using
Foxit instead of Adobe they're not going
to waste their time trying to find an
exploit for Adobe when they're going to
look into exploit DB or through the CVS
to see if they can find anything for Fox
it and then they can send you the
malformed PDF and do what they want to
do again there's the same thing with the
phone numbers you're gonna find a little
bit more when you actually go searching
across the website as opposed to the
Internet as a whole and then there's
Bloomberg so I'm going to reiterate some
gold mines per se indeed resumes the
github repos customers they're gonna
post what they love and hate about your
company another thing I learned
employees are gonna give companies five
star reviews and then when they leave
they're gonna change it to one probably
maybe it depends on the terms but most
often employees give five star reviews
of course there's the targets that we're
looking for to get information the
technical staff executives
I love targeting targeting executives
because if I can get to them they assume
that someone's already vetted me and
they inherently trust me
if you spoof a call from legal to the
CFO I say this with experience you will
get domain admin on a bank without doing
a port scan it's happened before
potential vendors and then of course
LinkedIn where everyone is the director
or chief executive something right so as
we start the transition into the actual
decepticon let's talk about training the
people so we can do things like rate
limiting to slow my scraping of your
site down or my ability to use tools
like spider foot or Foca to get the
information from your site you can use
Canaries so if you get an email address
or an email at your canary address from
someone you immediately know that
they've scraped you and you should block
them just information we're going to
talk about segmentation and DLP we'll
talk about as well encryption kind of
works but not really yeah it's worth
mentioning but of course you've got to
train the people on policies and
procedures and incorporate it into your
policies and procedures train the people
train them about insider threat social
engineering open source intelligence
activities have recurring training yeah
you've got to have your annual 1-hour
check-the-box training great do it then
employee quarterly or monthly training
not to exceed about 30 minutes to keep
them abreast of threats and trends that
you are seeing things that are of
interest to them I'll give you a hint
if you teach them how to protect their
family they will do that and bring it
back even stronger role based training
HR accounting sales they are all
expected to open emails with attachments
and open the attachment train them on
what to look for executives the same
thing just as I stated before they think
of things from a different lens keep
that in mind when you're doing this
incorporate it with your incident
response plan people should know exactly
how to report it such as phone carrier
pigeon smoke signal
next message slack in person whatever I
don't recommend doing it via email
because if someone thinks they're
breached there's a good chance your
email has been compromised what actions
do you want them to perform what data do
you want them to give you do you want
them to unplug the yellow cable from the
back of the computer or the network
cable I think of things like this from
the perspective of if I were telling my
mom how to do this what would I tell her
she's not gonna know what the network
cable is but she's gonna know what color
yellow is so I recommend using the same
color networking cable if possible as
well if someone clicks a fish or falls
victim to this don't beat them over the
head give them give them something to
work with gamify it collection
considerations what is the endgame it's
what you're doing ethical is it legal
how do you protect the data so now we're
into decepticon who who is the adversary
what do they want what have you what are
their capabilities what have you done to
target them what vectors could they use
what happens when they find you here's
some here's some notes about OPSEC if
you want some if you want some blogs
here are some blogs I've kind of went a
little bit ahead of my time so I'm gonna
have to speed up just a little bit but
if you want to opt out here there's a
link to a Google Drive that will
actually give you links to opt out of
anything you could possibly want to opt
out of secure internet usage I'm not
saying don't use Google calculate the
risk use a VPN be careful of your
browser extensions in your add-ons they
may or may not be vetted vulnerability
management is low-hanging fruit cloud
storage leaking Amazon s3 buckets that's
something to keep in mind the file
metadata what can I pull from the file
if I if I download it there's a tool
called Streisand if you don't trust VPNs
that you want to pay for you can
actually stand it up that's a link to
the github you stay
upon your own cloud instance you'll have
your own VPN concentrator your own tour
bridge your own shadow SOGs proxy
everything at your fingertips you
control everything you're only at the
mercy of your cloud provider deception
we have disinformation and we have
deception so sock puppet accounts fake
email addresses social media you can do
phone and payment I mean the pseudo app
allows you to have an email address a
phone number and you can even do
payments through pseudo pay deception
you have honey things like honey pots
honey jobs
honey docks whatever and you have
Canaries let's talk about disinformation
briefly we're just trying to make it
hard we're not trying to make it
impossible we're trying to make it hard
for me to do the attribution create your
accounts use different browsers use do
from different locations to it from
mobile do it from Wireless so forth and
so on
if you're like me and you publish your
travel schedule don't do it on your
travel schedule do it at another time
put bad information out misspelled your
name you can use hush mail protonmail
pseudo Google Voice if you want Bitcoin
have have a plethora of social media
accounts I have at least seven accounts
right now so I'm having my picture some
don't some have my name some don't if
you want to go the route have a New
Mexico LLC it's tied to your name and
you can be anonymous to your registered
agent be cautious when you're doing
transactions that create public records
like home buying heavenly landline phone
something of that nature informations
going to be in data breaches credit
reporting if you work in a large company
SEC filings if you pay in cash you can
avoid this to a degree you probably
still need a bank account and then
adrian is not impressed with this advice
don't go if you're in the u.s. don't go
applying for a new social don't legally
change your name don't have social media
altogether it's just that's just the end
game of it
you can use your Canaries you can use
your interactive technologies you can
have your decoys
I recommend Canaries to float all
possible but I believe I'm running out
of time so I apologize for not finishing
the final few slides does anyone have
any questions in the interim okay in the
interest of time thank you for your time
I apologize I got a little slow on this
trying to kick the sinus infection and
laryngitis definitely played a role but
thank you for coming out and enjoy the
rest of the conference