okay hi now we're joined by Nicole
Schwartz so hello to go hey glad you
guys are still going I kind of shocked
it's been a very long time so how far
we're beer powered so Nicole welcome a
bear come one and as it would be very
nice of you if you wouldn't mind telling
us a bit about who you are and then what
what is it he do so I do a lot of things
and I'm a very weird person so I'll give
you the high level summary yeah I am now
a person working and get lab in the
secured team and I just moved to Canada
and I ended up here because way a long
time ago I convinced my mom that we
wanted to go to Vegas for DEFCON it
wasn't even 18 yet and then it all kind
of went from there so that's like the
really short summary of my life and
otherwise I was on the side I work on
the Diana initiative which happens
saying hacker con summer camp week and I
also help with the songs I've got an OS
n project that I'm trying to start work
on for that and I generally herd cats so
if there's any cat herding to be done oh
my god she's like a way better looking
female version of me that's crazy I
volunteer at Diana initiative a def con
was how I got started
oh my god we're like sisters okay so
it's gonna be interesting to have my mom
back because were you originally
Canadian no well there you go yeah
interesting so you mentioned you working
forget that but it does that mean you
involved in development or researching
what is it you do that
so I'm actually doing product management
for
secure testing sweet so ideally doesn't
know what good lab is it's software for
software developers to write software
which is only slightly recursive and so
while people are writing their software
would really like them to write it
better with less security holes and less
bugs because high quality code is
awesome and everyone wants to be proud
of their code so as of right now in our
paid tier and we're bringing it down
into our free tier as this free version
we have sassed dashed dependency
scanning container scanning and license
compliance and it lets you know oh there
see bees for this or you know the
possibility of a sequel injection here
and a lot of times that happens way
later in the process and so you don't
know what developer necessarily
introduced the bad thing into your code
whereas since we've run the skins for
free and we don't charge like per scan
or anything we're relying on open source
tools you can run it every single time
you add codes you know exactly when it
was introduced and bike home so that's
kind of my mission as I've always been
in software demo but now I'm trying to
make sell for dab a little bit better
for everyone
Wow it's just it was so impactful
because I know that was it was get labs
that introduced the idea of scanning the
repositories the repos for software
vulnerability right and we didn't start
with that about yeah a bit over a year
ago with gymnasium we purchased that
yeah yeah
and then Microsoft are throwing money at
the problem and acquiring people so also
does that now but we did it first
awesome that's that's such a powerful
way to impact security at like really a
developer friendly level you know
probably a lot more constructive than
posting your homework to Stack Overflow
I've heard that that isn't a pleasant
experience so at the software
development level then is there like a
obviously you have to pay attention to
what's happening in terms of disclosure
right what are some of the sort
inputs that you guys use is it like a
threat intelligence feed is it feedback
from the developer community like how do
you identify something bad in quotations
so as of right now a majority of our
scanners are looking for rather
simplistic things is this applicable to
cross-site scripting or whatever and
then they're also checking against a CBE
list and we're using an VM and a couple
other sources which are all listed if
you go to our public vulnerability
database project you can see exactly
what sources were aggregating from and
we do take community contributions and
so our vulnerability database anyone can
go look at it anyone can see what we've
got in there anyone could add something
obviously we need to approve it right
before it gets accepted but we do take
community contributions at this point
nobody in the community has done it
we've had you know obviously some
internal employees add some stuff but
we're hoping over time more people will
add it especially because fingers cross
we're discussing becoming a CNA so that
we can accept vulnerabilities related to
project hosted that's awesome so I mean
you've got all these two leading them
and that they're so what are sort of
some of the challenges that you see
teams or teams face today especially
around developing and security so the
talk that I've been giving for this
whole past year probably summarizes down
to two points we don't educate
developers well about security so even
if they want to care about it we don't
give them the tools to understand what
they can do to change anything and then
the second part is security teams and a
lot of cases and if you followed InfoSec
Sherpa on Twitter she shouts about this
a lot we don't have empathy for the rest
of the business units and what they're
expected to do and so I think if we can
get some empathy for the teams that are
having to do security and then get them
the education they need nobody wants to
be the person who gets the company
breach they just usually don't up the
tools to understand how do I stop it
like I
understand sequel injections bad but
what is sequel injection you know yeah
yeah I know it's bad but what is it and
how did I introduce it now do I fix it
and it's interesting because you know
that comes back and then the easiest
route that devs frequently take is to
add filters soon realizing that filters
don't work at scale and parameterised
input is the way to go but then you have
to rewrite the entire application that's
a very simplistic view and I'm using a
lot of words that I don't quite
understand but I just wanted to show off
a little bit because I'm good okay
so flipping that around it's all very
well saying hey you're gonna reach out
to teams and there that's only gonna
work if those teams are willing to
engage what what advice can you give
when you find that teams are just not
interested for whatever reason you just
effectively meet a brick wall how do you
break that wall down and you get them
invested and engaged and working with
the security teams I think unfortunately
if you've gotten somewhere where there's
already a bad relationship you need to
start really slow and I know that drives
some people crazy but just starting with
having coming over with bagels Donuts
fruit trays whatever some food and just
asking you know how exactly does
software development work in your
department just tell me about what your
normal workflow is and understanding how
they work as a starting point and then
bribing them with food because everyone
likes food at least most people like
food and just starting to get friendly
so they feel like they can you know tell
you about things so don't start trying
to force anything on them just find out
exactly how they work and what problems
they experience and find out if some of
the security controls you have in place
or places that they're getting caught up
and see if that gives you any win so for
example maybe right now they're trying
to login to a bunch of different places
and they have to remember all of those
passwords and then they're told we can't
write the past it's down yeah oh yeah
yeah that well what if I mean as a
security company
you loved it if everyone
using a class pass or okhta or you know
what a password or something anyway so
can you start being like oh well what if
we get the company on board with doing
this this would help you have less
logins or the day and just find things
where they have a pain point that you
can make more secure and better for them
because once they start seeing that
you're working with them you can start
being like okay and the other teams are
starting to do a ghast skin in their dev
environment I see that you already have
a test server up and you already run
some automated regression can I run some
tasks and I will make you do anything
with the results to start I just want to
see where we are and compare that to
production but are you talking then
about a big investment in things like
sonar Kiev and checkmarks or there are
tons of free scanners out there they're
not necessarily as fully featured or
robust but why start with the expensive
solution until you've gotta buy it it's
totally cool yeah that's that's that's
great advice so a personal plug yo cuz
chapter leader go look at all us they
are so many tools out there and some of
the tools are bringing out now are
fantastic oh yeah is great that there's
defect order that we even looked at that
looks absolutely amazing and then
they'll actually I mean you've got the
community edition do you want to maybe
give a bit more about that so our
community edition is free for everyone
to use and we try and rely on a lot of
open-source tools which is why I was
saying earlier that a lot of our
security skins are going to come down
into the community edition because they
are based on some of the OAuth tools and
some of the other open-source security
scanning tools that are out there and so
now that we've kind of worked at the
bugs and we've got it working and we
think it can scale there's no reason why
we can't take all the open-source tools
that we have and are using and put that
into Community Edition it just doesn't
make sense to not do that and so the
great thing this is the only company
I've worked at where people actually
come up to me when I'm working a booth
at an event and say like I love your
product you're amazing
that worked out usually they come up and
they're like either who are you or you
know oh I have this problem and no one's
responding to me but yeah generally the
community because it's open source
they're like oh I love you and listen
sometimes they get into a crew fluffle
with us but we try to listen
sorry it's good we're gonna have to wrap
oh okay the reason is that we are we've
got a little bit of a timing blip on our
channel so we we've got we've got Nicole
on it tenth and fourth of teff bus for
that we've got hockey fantastic on at
four okay yeah so apologies for that
but Nicole thank you very much for your
insights into application security it's
a subject that's very close to certainly
Shaun and my own half that's what we do
a lot of our place of work we really
appreciate you giving us each time and
thank you very much thank you and those
last few donations yes yes fingers
crossed thanks thanks so much thanks to
Co