power InfoSec couple yeah quite okay so
it gives me immense pleasure to welcome
really good friends of the bear farmers
people that we will sit around the set
circuit in the last year or two
incredibly popular bring on GS and FC
welcome good evening how you doing guys
good really nice to be listening into
the last hour or so fantastic it's a
pleasure having you on so we know each
other you and the bear farmers we've
kind of mingled it around the circuit in
the past year too I saw you at besides
Leeds I think last year and you did the
fu foot talk which was fascinating it
was kind of heart melting in certain
places then it really opened my eyes
personally to the sort of human aspects
of what it is we're all about what we do
that was just a little anecdote from
that point on that follow you guys ever
since so again it's great to have you on
what would you like to talk about soon
we could we can talk about anything
anything you want really to be honest we
yeah we remember meeting obviously at
besides Leeds that was fantastic that
was the first besides Leeds yeah did an
amazing job putting together and that
was a slightly different talk for us
where we talked about he from us all
personal perspective and then we talked
about fear in terms of how it's used or
misused to try and sell security to
people so we took it we felt like we
were taking a bit of a risk doing that
talk and but we were really pleased with
the response that we got and we still
get we still get people actually
messaging our oil coming up at
conferences and saying that that talk
sort of meant something to them so that
was really cool
so we will see kind of both sides of
what you guys do so generously the
business operation that you you put in
place I remember it when it was a
redacted firm by the way our IP
yeah but I guess Jess you kind of focus
on the the human aspects of what we do
the psychology of a second the behaviors
and what kind of stuff and actually you
I guess you deal more with the technical
is that is that a fair split or do you
kind of both split what you do both yeah
I'd say it's my size the technical and
the physical side and Jess is definitely
the more human sight and straying into
the technical in some areas yeah yeah I
think it's been a good mix of our skills
over the last few years yeah it's what
made us really start so gender as we're
now called because we sort of thought we
bring those different sides together and
we're able to offer something a little
bit different with that and yeah we felt
really really lucky you're really happy
with how the businesses taken off so
having watched you develop I guess your
business over the past year you seemed
to do things separately and then you see
we do things together know you do a lot
community work down on the southwest
around getting in for second technology
engendered in schooling and all that
kind of stuff which I think's wonderful
but could you each give us an example of
some of the stuff that you've been doing
over the past year yeah sure so we do a
lot of outreach and and that's something
we do kind of on the side of the
business to be honest but something
we're both really passionate about in
terms of the work we do with clients
it's it tends to be very mixed most of
our clients are very large
multinationals across all sorts of
different sectors I'd say the bulk are
in financial services but we have large
retailers health care education some
marketing companies law firms and so
it's quite a mix in terms of what I to
you it's as you said earlier all focused
on awareness behavior and culture so
I've been in the industry for nine but
nine years and I've always focused on
the human side so I work with clients on
their awareness raising everything from
helping their strategies through to kind
of do
during sessions for them and then I also
do cultural assessments so help clients
understand what their cybersecurity
culture is like you know in terms of
what they want from people and what's
actually happening where people are
finding workarounds when it comes to
security and why they might be doing
that and then we have a product called
seed app which also is very focused on
awareness raising and doing us
measurement of culture at the
organizational team and individual level
cool are you seeing behaviour change it
I work in an enterprise where it's a
constant battle to keep awareness high
and it's implement new controls and get
technology bought in and find funding
for stuff are you seeing
I guess when organizations look at
what's happening in the news and I'm
thinking date breaches and all the kind
of really high profile stuff that
happens you would like to think that
that's a wake-up call for organizations
to start getting the house in order ease
don't see that kind of thing happening
or are you finding it's still a bit of a
struggle well I think it's awareness
behavior culture you know it's like
security in general it's not something
that's ever just fixed like you're never
just there and it's done something
that's that's always a process and
always needs to be worked on and but
definitely you know compared to when I
started down nine years ago and over
that time there's been a there's being
like a huge shift I think in terms of
more and more organizations recognizing
that the human side is important
recognizing that they need to do
something around awareness that it can't
just be like tick box approach you know
once a year training for people or you
kind of borer and click through
computer-based training so it's I think
it's definitely changed I think the
amount that it hits the headlines does
make a difference but sometimes it's
about engaging the particular
organization or particular teams within
an organization as to how it's relevant
to them is sometimes people can find a
thing
well it's insecurities stuff that other
companies need to worry about what other
people need to worry about people can
have a bit of a tendency to think it's
never gonna happen to them sure I want
to jump in with something so two things
the first is just a huge compliment to
Jessica who I meet a lot on the more
corporate II circle where she's
frequently sought out facilitator and
guest speaker and it's always lovely to
run into you and you always have a kind
word and are just super upbeat so I want
to say that the then I want to bounce
over to freaky because I feel a little
bit of a kindred spirit with him because
both of us I think have done some some
time in some organizations the mileage
that we've put on our bodies and stuff
with that freaky is it getting harder or
is it getting easier yeah I was like the
the the saying that at some point you're
gonna have to start to do some running
and that's never more true in our
organizations and the stuff that we've
done is tough on the knees and as I'm
getting I'm running less do you find
though that it's that the physical side
of the security thing like when you're
when you're move it when you're trying
to get into a place or whatever do you
find like it is getting a bit tougher
like people are hardening their defenses
or you still find it's like a hot knife
rolling through butter so I've been
doing this for like you know coming up
to thirty years now yeah breaking into
all sorts of started when he was 10
years old people know I'm a lot older
than I look
yeah the paper gives it an air of
youngness and we have absolutely no idea
referencing whether you have any hair
yeah I'll share a photo in next couple
of weeks will show you what's under my
hat
but yeah have I seen an increase in
security as it got harder no in a word
no it hasn't
I've still got a hundred percent success
rate getting into everywhere it's never
going to change because of that's how
social engineering and physical
assessments always work is there's
always a way in there's always something
and if you've if you're trying to fix
everything you you're gonna fail you can
only sort of mitigate when it goes wrong
so how's it gonna know have you ever
have you ever been bounced from a client
where you were like I didn't think you
know they would have had the process of
procedures in place but then you go into
like a really high-security place
they're just like completely
laissez-faire
yeah it's kind of odd like you you think
that the more secure places are gonna be
better at it but they're generally not
it's it's a very odd world that they
live in I think sometimes
cool one thing I wanted to ask is um I
only see you two jetting off all over
the world placing some amazing photos
which I'm sure there's that lovely
aspect to it but is it they're all just
some sort of dance ads how do you guys
capable being away from home so much is
there any advice you can give anyone
yeah it's I mean it's it's great like we
are constantly aware of how privileged
we are and you know the fact that a hard
day for us is not like you know to me
we're still in an amazing industry doing
amazing work and and so we constantly
feel privileged by it we get to go to
great places see beautiful parts of the
world and we love what we do so you know
what that's like it's amazing when you
can do something you're passionate about
but of course it is tiring
laughing so we've both flown the
equivalent of over twice around the
world yeah just wow so it is tiring and
sometimes we get to do it together which
is amazing often when we're doing it
apart and so sometimes one of us is in
one part of the world and we come back
and the other ones just flown off
somewhere so we constantly have like a
suitcase packed and I think the most
important thing is actually being
organized knowing where you're going and
what you're doing and you know having
having stuff as organized as you can
it's really helpful we do have someone
to do that for us which is amazing but
but also kind of taking the downtime
when you can and anyone who is listening
that works freelance or runs a business
and probably you know especially if it's
in the early stages will know that you
don't really get time off you don't
really take weekends or holidays and
stuff but naturally this times the year
that are a bit quieter so over Christmas
obviously people don't really want much
awareness-raising or pen tests or an or
conference talks and stuff so it's
taking that downtime when
comes and looking after your health
really as much as possible I've been
traveling for work the whole time I've
been in the industry so after nine years
after seven years slip to disk and was
um was kind of coping with that for the
last couple of years and so yeah look
after your physical health you know and
your mental health because it does take
it out of you so you have to make sure
that you look after yourself first and
then you're able to do your job we
watched the Nightmare Before Christmas
last week and I said that I felt like if
she called Sammi the corpse pride I felt
like here sometimes like stitching
myself it does feel like that I mean
I've been I've been quite poorly for the
past couple of months and I think it's
just been a cold and I do I feel like
I'm coming out of it but it does take it
out of you and I think when you but we
don't
we've been nowhere near as busy as you
guys but we've kind of doing a
conference nearly every moment and then
we've got a lot of podcasts and all that
kind of stuff I think just the thinking
about it and the planning and getting
involved in it does wipe you out I found
it's wiped me out people talk about
conflict I've probably left every
conference this year two or three days
afterwards I've felt ill because of
being highly strung about it or you know
nervous about delivery of it and the
success of it that kind of stuff and I
think if that in itself isn't healthy
don't mind if you drinking or you're
eating crap food or all that kind of
thing I mean just the behavior of being
in the circuit can be quite tiresome and
have a profound impact on your health
yeah I was gonna say eight it's all of
the things that people don't really
think about like after a conference that
the hundreds of people that come up and
want photos or want to talk to you for a
while you can leave those feeling really
drained yeah it's a mental exhaustion
that you sort of come out really I'm not
godlike I thought I was gonna be easy
but actually I just need to sleep for a
couple
yeah I thought for me one of the things
that and I assume it's gonna be a even
worse we relaxed you guys were you guys
all around the globe given several talks
but let's also that lead up there's a
lot of preparation certainly from our
side I found like the amount that
actually goes into some of these things
there's pretty significant a lot of time
does the seems like you throw a bunch of
slides together you get my stage to give
a talking the talk then it's not quite
the case so how do you guys cope with
that I mean there must take a lot of
work to to give a lot of these talks in
that yeah I think that that sort of read
you've hit on what differentiates just
casual speakers and professional
speaking is you have to put in a lot of
work we got a lot of people that kind of
come ask us to do a free talk for this
or that or or just incredibly low price
and they go well you're only onstage for
half an hour right
yeah but it's actually 20 years of
experience and three days of time sort
of build up that the talk that you
require they don't see all with the work
that goes into it and it's it that can
be really tough if you don't plan for if
you're not if you saw just go okay I've
got a talk next week I'm just going to
do the slides at the last minute and
it's never going to be as good or as
polished as the client needs yeah and I
think when you're passionate about it
you want to do the best job that you can
and so obviously that means preparing as
much as possible and you know preparing
it so that it's it's right for the
people in the room and that they're
going to get the most value from it and
so that you can then really feel good
when you leave knowing that you gave it
your all which is is great and I think
it's the right way to approach it
of course that takes time and you have
to build that in and and be aware of
that I just think when when
they say oh I get really nervous before
a talking start like do you get nervous
like speaking in front of like hundreds
or thousands of people Jess and I have a
thing where we we don't really get
nervous about giving a talk but we're
more nervous about the client being so
it's like making peace yeah
but making sure that the client gets
what they wanted you know with that
we've delivered the best thing that we
can and I think if you're not planning
for that then it's never gonna be as
good as it could be yes so I have just
kind of a question is a bit personal but
I mean obviously you both have got a
huge profile in the information security
community how do you keep connected
between just the two of yourselves I
mean clearly the demands of the public
and the demands of the clients are huge
how do you carve out enough time for
yourselves
we just tweet each other liking and
sharing Oh Ryan Reynolds type of
relationship is that Wow yeah we like
like if says we try and take the time
out that we can whenever we can it if
the clients willing to pay for us to be
in a country for another day or two
we'll take it if if we get to a weekend
and there happens to be a it's more
about a work to be done then then we'll
get that down quickly and then just
chill out watch a movie just try and
make as much time as you can for each
other don't we I actually think working
together it's it's kind of demanding in
one way when you're a couple but I think
it's it works so well for us yeah and if
if just one of us was running the
business and the other one was kind of
doing a job somewhere else then it would
be harder probably for us to stay
connected like we're going in the same
direction we work on the business
together so that actually I think is
something that that's really beneficial
for us I agree I think that sorry FCI I
think the
section is that you are a an incredibly
strong unit and I think it's partly down
to the point I meant at the beginning
that you come a basis around what we're
trying to achieve you know we all do
kind of our own individual little things
to contribute to the the betterment of
the industry insecurity generally I
think you combine in such a way that
people probably just assume that you are
the package as it were that makes any
kind of sense some may even know that
we're married which is really weird well
that's a pretty good upset well listen
we've got one minute left and just a
quick one really what have you got
planned for next year what's coming up
[Music]
trying to finish that draft before
Christmas which I'm gonna do what what's
the the broad subject to the book yes
it's kind of it's an intro to
cybersecurity particularly for those who
are early on in my career in the
industry or wanting to get into the
industry fantastic it's not like these
books great for pen testers mine is kind
of it's kind of trying to take a broad
look at the industry from the human the
technical yeah will you cover the
importance of writing a good email we
can all benefit from that couldn't we
ever say what about you what you got
going on so my biggest thing is actually
gonna be promoting my wife which is
she's giving a keynote at RSA wow that's
huge one of only the few women that ever
get to be our keynote RFA's um
and one day I hope to strive to be as
good fantastic alright well thank you
both for sharing your time with us this
evening it's been a pleasure having you
mom
next up we've got Becky Pinkard yet all
the remains Jessie thanks ever so much
and we'll see you back in a couple of
minutes thank you cheers guys thank you
just lovely