and ready let's do it credit hey so yes
so welcome to beer com1 great to have
you great to hear another American
accent you are apparently a programmer
turned a recruiter oh yeah this is super
cool because we we wonder about the
world of a per sec recruitment oh yes we
do oh how cool the industry is or is it
really [ __ ] easy
tell us about what you do okay so yeah I
started
I'll age myself it was mmm early mid 90s
I did a little bit application
programming and then I I found myself
doing ite standing up and running it
helped us a little bit for startups and
then for local government and then I
realized that what I was really good I
was building those chains more than more
than the technical stuff love the
technology and I still get to be
involved in it and a part of it because
I'm surrounded by it but recruiting is
when I'm really super good at um so now
I run recruiting team I retain team at a
technology company so that's that's who
I am
I don't care if you call me Karen or
everybody at conferences either calls me
Crenna or car hacking person girl
whatever but my name is actually
pronounced Kirsten and people write but
that's who I am and and I'm a Saints fan
who dad what's up Bri alright Kirsten
cool great intro so you were a
programmer back in the day and you eat
it's a candy dude sack and you are a
techie person so how he found moving out
one realm and into another one and how
is the one thing helping me doing it I
think it's very important for recruiters
to to make themselves knowledgeable if
they didn't come in with any technology
and I trained my recruiters one of them
just went and got a double us-cert and
reinvent so it doesn't mean that I can
sit down and do all the things that you
guys can do right or the technical
people can do [ __ ] I was programming in
Visual Basic like a million years ago
but I think it's very important to
understand what you what you're
recruiting for at the end of the day
could I recruit in healthcare yes kind
of recruit in I don't know construction
probably but I want to do I want it to
be something that I'm passionate about
and as far as our community goes I've
been listening to each of the not all of
them but a few of the sessions up to
this point we're trying to slow down on
my drinking so I can stay awake for
[Music]
listening to what you're saying and
noticing you know I'm on Twitter all the
time and I want to tell you what I was
going to talk about and how Twitter
changed my mind at 3 o'clock this
morning my time the technology because
if you're not sleeping and who sleeps
right and and you're out of wine what do
you do on Twitter might you just get on
Twitter yeah you punch is you for waking
him up but I saw a post will be back up
what I was gonna talk about is I was
just gonna do like I talked to six or
seven recruiters I said hey tell me here
your best and worst candidate
experiences and this is gonna be very
entertaining right I'm gonna tell you
guys these great stories and then as I
started to collect those stories from
them I realized that's not helpful at
all right because if I tell the story
about you should never show up drunk or
you should matter
well you should only flip over the desk
if you're interviewing for the WWF but
that's not helpful it's it's trash right
it's like click so I said I'm gonna do
better than that and I hope I pronounce
her name correctly
Alyssa who's actually coming up here
after me here or tomorrow morning yes
yeah she's in that she's in the room and
I want to shout out one thing
besides that her tweet prompted what I'm
about to speak about and sorry I'm
Italian I just go off in a lot of
directions I hope you can follow them
okay
shout out she just did a article on
LinkedIn you should all look at it and
read it it's about leadership and it's
one of the most poignant things I've
ever read about leadership it really
struck me and I've been reflecting on it
trying to be a better leader based on
what she said someone see that real
quick but good thing last night and I
believe the original she wasn't the
original tweet I want to give credit to
the person who did it I wrote it down
but I can't find it it was about
horrible job descriptions it was a
screenshot of a job description that
listed I'm not kidding you 30 and
requirements they didn't say preferences
they didn't say was that was that the
Sony architecture one pick widely
lampooned by the entire community the
company redacted what I want to walk you
through is in my opinion and experience
how does this happen I have two theories
and what should you do about it
how should you respond so do you have
any any questions first before no lay it
on us okay I haven't heard any clicking
of beer cans tabs opening in the last
few minutes
it sounded like the French Revolution
I'm gonna take you to before I got into
info sack recruiting at about the year
2000 and it did have some examples that
that I thought maybe would be
interesting decides flipping over tables
from being drunk let me just say one
thing you shouldn't do and then I'll get
to the to the job postings the only
example I wanted to point out and I
don't think very many normal non
sociopathic humans would do this but you
can do variations of this there was a
person this was my very first Def Con
back oh my god mm it was 10 years ago or
more and I was brand new I was a baby I
didn't know anything I didn't I didn't
yeah I was like they threw me right in
the pool and I had my personal cell
phone number on my business cards you
know that's how much of a kid I was and
came home after after it was all over
started getting text messages from this
person who wanted to be a candidate to
one of the positions that I had posted
on my company's website at the time and
wanted I guess to impress me by talking
about and sending screenshots and
excerpts from domestic case files from
my personal past from a very dark time
in my past and that's pretty awful so
let me just say free pointer to the
universe if you're capable of doing dark
creepy things find a better way to let
people know so that was um I don't think
it ended up working out very well for
that individual but that was my worst
candidate story
mmm just shocked you know like that it's
just beyond like how do people really
work that I get if you're critical about
a job description I get if you're
critical about you know maybe the way
the company treated you or their process
but to then kind of go to that dark
place of like stalking or or you know
making a person feel very uncomfortable
or unsafe just what is the mental you
know process there you know what and
guess what person that doesn't even make
you a hacker no I know all the best
hackers in the world
that's not hacking that's super googling
that's cheap and gross right those types
of records if you really wanted to
figure out where I used to live and
they're all there are public records if
you really wait weird and bored um so
that didn't even it wasn't even
impressive it's just creepy I don't know
what I don't know how that happens I I
feel very badly when I see people having
bad experiences it's it's it's why I
volunteer it's why I speak at
conferences it's why I train people how
to interview and how to write their
resume so that they'll have a better
experience it's why I try to make my
recruiters better to close the gap in
this process and make it less awful hey
not every recruiter sucks for you
Kirsten
LinkedIn yeah okay so a lot of people in
industry general whatever the you know
the mission that we're in tends to be
approached by people in LinkedIn
recruitment companies and recruiters and
all that kind of stuff yeah and I get a
lot and I'm guessing a lot of other
people get the same thing I saw in a
database the word Salesforce
your name next to it me No No maybe so
so here's a job that you may be
interested in because it's got the word
Salesforce that was a database match and
all that kind of [ __ ] yeah or a very
formulated template approach that says
we have a job and your profile seems to
fit it perfectly yeah and then I look
and it's not even close to what I do
Executive believably any and then you
know the other weirdness is like a
recruiter hits you up for an
introduction to somebody else and I'm
just like I don't get it like geez I
should have prefaced with I want to make
a blanket apology it is not your fault
you're one of the good ones I'm sure I
did you know I reached out to a systems
engineer and said do you want a program
in Java or something stupid like that
that was Sean right Zach I've got the
best one I had a recruiter reach out to
me asking if I was interested in a job
fine
java web development fine I was doing
all of that except for was the same
company in the same role so these train
wreck stories but I wish we had ours I'm
ready to take the punches right I'm
ready to have people throw tomatoes at
me I would get up on the stage and every
graze her hand and complain and and I
feel horrible because I want to solve it
I really do I was you know that little
kid running around trying to fix things
yeah I guess that's called social
justice warrior now that's awesome
though no that is true and I do want
people to understand and I'm gonna
mention LinkedIn in my solution to this
wretched Job Description it had I think
43 requirements there's two different
reasons but right off the top of my head
I can think of why a Job Description
would be that awful so one of them is
gonna be because it was written
specifically for and my company doesn't
do this we are in legit shop but back in
the day when I did telecommunications
before as a sec a lot of the candidates
required a sponsorship for a visa right
so let's just say a person who's a
perfect fit who could do this this is
back in the day now work with me like 3G
ETL whatever whatever eyes this is could
climb towers in CDMA right so here
there's this candidate and they need an
h-1b and so I have to file for that so I
have to follow the rules and post the
general up and leave it open for
whatever this whatever the stated number
of days is let's just pretend it's 5:00
to have the job open so I'm gonna very
creatively write that Job Description in
such a way that it is sure fit for this
person and a lot of other people won't
necessarily apply to it because it's
awful and let's just say I'm going okay
he's posting this job I know exactly who
I want to hire but I have to post it I'm
gonna have to prove that I followed a
competitive process and was being fair
I wasn't discriminating against people
who aren't this person in case there are
some protective factor other than this
person and let's just face it that
person just statistically speaking is
probably a white guy
it isn't that right and I'm pleased
everyone who isn't a white guy don't get
mad at me it's just it's just statistics
so if you if you aren't that /
and I write the Job Description and I
say okay I want you to have my what can
I think of a cissp and a PhD and three
years of La Crosse Crossing college wink
wink he's gonna get the job and everyone
else is gonna be angry here's how and
there's another reason why some job
descriptions are terrible this is
probably way more likely the case in
fact when I looked at the one last night
on Twitter and you can look at Alyssa's
page my page and I'll find this other
guy's name originally posted it and I'm
gonna write this whole thing up and turn
it into a blog and post it for everyone
because pregnant amount of time but the
other reason is going to be straight-up
administrative errors my company's only
have thousand people we've got like
hundreds of jobs open so think of the
huge companies that have thousands of
jobs open they're really not paying
close attention and they could be an
administrative error it could be a
misunderstanding it could be I've seen
this happen before when the applicant
tracking system some horrible applicant
tracking system that was written in 1984
in takes the position descriptions and
reformats them and takes all of the
subtext makes them in bullets now it
looks like there's 50 requirements when
a lot of those were only preferences and
the job description is horrible and
nobody ever knows the manager would be
probably devastated if he knew why
nobody was applying to the horrible Job
Description
duplet knows it ariza and nobody ever
knows in that application I'm gonna show
you here's the steps you should take
when you see it you're like I love that
company I love company XYZ I would love
to work there but I can't do that job
description nobody can do that job
description right apply to I'm gonna
take you to LinkedIn here in a second
you're gonna go to LinkedIn I'm sorry
wait don't expect to get a reply from
your application almost always it's a
black hole I wish it wasn't but it is
and you're gonna look up
soozee company on linkedin and then
you're gonna do to the recruiters but
they do to you you're gonna look for
where the people are that work for that
company and you're gonna be like huh
bartholomew he's a recruiter i'm gonna
send him a direct message
hey bartholomew i applied for this job i
noticed um you know it had a lot of
requirements I'm hoping that there's
some flexibility there I don't really
have lacrosse experience I don't really
know a lot of people do and then you're
gonna give him one business day to reply
to you just one yeah one and if he
doesn't
you're gonna go back to LinkedIn and
you're gonna look for the director or
the VP of the solutions architecture
division where this job likely rests and
you're gonna say hi sorry to bother you
marry the director I I noticed this and
really excited and really interested in
maybe Bartholomew hasn't gotten around
to his messages yet and I understand but
I'm super eager and please take a look
at my profile and here's what I'm gonna
promise at the whole world however many
people are on right now
you can quote me if you don't get a
response I will buy you a beer wow this
is C at DEFCON do you think there's
another reason perhaps and that's just
simply that those placed in the job just
don't know what their wines or what they
even looking for I think it's very like
I said there could be a misunderstanding
but I feel like there couldn't there
isn't likely cash I hope there isn't
such a disconnect in between the person
who wants to fill the job and they know
what their customer wants don't get me
wrong
most of my end customers are the US
government and wash pick you're going to
say sometimes delete all that the end
customers
sometimes the end customer changes their
mind frequently so that happens it
really really does you're out there
you're there you're the recruiter or
you're the manager and you think you
know what they want and then they change
their mind or they completely change the
requirements they change the location
they change the tools that you need
everything so that happens and in those
cases maybe they're trying to cover all
the ground and that's why they put that
many things on there but they should all
the potential employers should clean up
the job descriptions they really should
and you have to get through all these
hurdles you have to get through these
awful job descriptions and resume the
application process the interview
process getting getting dropped on
accident you know going getting ghosted
there's so many girls you have to get
through the best way to do it is what
we're doing right now networking and
communicating being at conferences
communicating with each other on social
I have to say I appreciate what you said
about how we stand up to each other for
each other yeah there's been fighting
yeah there's issues this community has
been so there for me like I can't even
tell you oh yeah giving me opportunities
and it's something personal happened a
couple of weeks ago and everybody kind
of rallied together and raised money for
my family like it's amazing it's it's
mostly overall very good and because
it's good I can care about it so much
then I can sell it very well so
absolutely brilliant
well Kirsten thank you very much for
your testimony yeah but for sharing a
time with us really we really appreciate
it
it's perfect it's nice taking it taking
it on the chin for all the recruiters so
differently right yeah I was going to
say that you know we probably don't have
too many recruiters in the on the roster
for the evening yeah so yeah we really
appreciate your time so thank you very
much
you're very welcome thanks for doing
this yeah
and follow her @k r e and n ER go ahead
and fall give her a fall if you're good
- I will link this up and post it for
you guys I love it
just ahead
thank you and just a heads up so
everyone knows if you go to the beer con
one official site I don't know if
there's a link somewhere in the agenda
everyone's Twitter profiles there