uh you know what no I think we can
transition straight to Philip if I it
seems like if I'm pausing I coulda died
seven o'clock in the morning you're
allowed to die hey I've been going all
night we've got about an hour of sleep
it just kind of intermittent there and
who do we have to got Mike back no you
go Philip good morning folks well good
morning to you sir
and I think it's safe to say that you're
the only MBE that we have on the show so
I think for people to understand where
you're coming from which is not I would
say true info sack give us an
introduction okay yeah not to InfoSec is
a good one I'm sort of an interloper and
I think my background I'm ex-military I
was in the British Army for 26 years and
that's where I was very fortunate to
have collected enough cereal packet tops
to get them submitted and be given the
badge the awards I just very very
fortunate to be awarded the MBE which
for those who aren't from the UK it is a
member of the Order of the British
Empire that is an award that was
bestowed by Her Majesty the Queen for
having done something that makes you
stand out and heard the turn around and
decide that you get an award and for me
it was as part of NATO planning team
taking over from the United Nations
going into Bosnia and I was Minister
intelligence officer and here's where
the InfoSec link sort of comes in and
and part of my responsibility in that
was providing overall security and
security policy for different places
that I was in and part of that security
policy was the wire in through sex and
cyber security policy and policing that
as part of a wider threat piece and that
was out there so I do have a little bit
of intersect credibility from a
practitioners perspective but I wasn't
it was really just a policy Center and
had lots of people to do all that it
still works for me
we've understood great but I mean having
said that you are a favorite of Kate and
Davie winter for commentary and I think
you know you've really shown that you're
taking a view of the nation-state
activity out there and terrorism and
counterterrorism and commenting publicly
about it you know with with great
comments comes great responsibility are
you sort of seeing an evolution of the
threat actor I've got into that so it's
leaving the military of sort of fall
into journalism so I write and report
about it and yeah you're the intersect
threat I look at all threats equally and
the wider cyber threat and InfoSec
threat is out there and it's something I
monitor very very closely so if I can
comment on it is more thing it is
changing and they and I think we're
actually missing a lot of it the
lower-level threats are the same the
activists the script kids the criminals
that are out there there's this new ways
developing all the time of the time to
steal your money
the thing that concerns me and you've
mentioned it there most is the
development of the nation-state and the
levels that the nation-state
will go down to is something that I
don't think many people realize everyone
thinks that a nation-state is going to
focus on another nation state it's big
target see and it's for espionage it's
four spines for everything else a lot of
people don't realize that nation-states
will actually target individuals nation
states are developing capabilities that
are out there that they're getting kids
to use to spy on their behalf and nation
states are using proxies to use you to
carry out a lot of their activities so
that they've got an element of plausible
deniability and with the nation-state
factor
one of the big issues is in in warfare
terms there are sort of four
environments there's land air maritime
and space right
each of those four environments are
controlled by either the Geneva
protocols or the other Space Treaty of
1969 v environment is cyberspace right
there's no international regulation
whatsoever yeah and I mean it's been
controversial because the Tallinn manual
is in its second printing the
International Committee of the Red Cross
issued a paper on the use of cyber
weapons but you're absolutely correct in
that there is I think a lot of
governance and rhetoric I was really
concerned when you know a member of
parliament in the UK suggested that a
cyber attack could result in a kinetic
response but then I thought about that
and I went wait a second if cyber could
actually cause a mass casualty incident
then a kinetic response might be an
appropriate response what are your
thoughts on that
well we talked about cyber and we talked
about it as if it's something could be
different I'm holding up my index finger
on my right hand at the minute like
that's that's a digit that was the
biggest digital problem that the reason
that's right there because it has to
click something has to push a button and
you something that we talk about inside
where it starts in the physical world
and ends up with a reaction in the
physical world and that we actually
could be a kinetic effect coming back
against someone or it could be a kinetic
effect through
a control system and the dam being
interrupted and the floodgates being
opened and that's that that causes a bit
of a physical effect and therefore you
know it in cases it would be very
appropriate that there is a physical
response and I think it's only a matter
of time I'm rocking the
because i thinkand read an incident were
there was a physical response in syria
to a cyber cyber incident
well there was Hamas Hamas operatives
that were allegedly preparing a cyber
attack yep
I've got killed by the Israelis that's
right I love the building right that's
that's that's that's the one I was
thinking of it but also the so called
Isis had an organization called the
United cyber caliphate
yes Caliphate was out there cyberattacks
and other bits and pieces the head of
the United cyber Caliphate just after it
he was asking an individual who I
happened to know to try and help develop
some training material for what they
were doing and a couple of days after he
had put that request in and his
cybersecurity wasn't good enough and a
500-pound bomb ended up in this cyber
cafe that he was sitting in at that time
you know did you know if it disappeared
so at the moment we're seeing physical
effects on activity that's going on in
cyberspace and from an espionage
perspective you've always said that from
a policing perspective we've always had
that you know the script kiddie sitting
in his room hacking into the bank will
tend to result in a physical effect of
the police kicking his door down and
coming in way for a little bit of
questioning yeah oh yeah two worlds are
completely linked and it's wrong with
people to try and I think from a wider
security perspective to try and separate
cyberspace out as something completely
different we have to think of everything
holistically and the more the more times
we think of it holistically then you can
you can look at dealing with the
potential threats that are out there
against or threat actors and
understanding how it's going to impact
on you and your organization that those
are all really great points and I think
you're absolutely right that it that
it's interlinked and it is something
that is not easily deconstructed I want
to talk a little bit though about your
transition from
military service to civilian and and so
there are a lot of folks contemplating
making the move coming out of the
military and moving into civilian
practice what advice would you give them
what what did you discover on that
journey that they might benefit from
well I went through the journey in a
slightly painful way because I came out
of the military not realizing that I was
suffering quite badly from PTSD and it
took me a number of years before I got
to position and properly diagnose and
treated the transition it's not as
difficult people think it's it's trying
to understand that and all you're doing
is going into an environment were
there's two things people are talking a
different language generally in civilian
life
people don't care that sounds a little
cruel people are the military's a little
bit teamwork you don't work as a team
and you don't work as a team all
overtime and all of the training all of
the environment everything else is built
around you met looking after you people
doing things automatically to help you
because your that should be what's going
on that's that's the environment it
doesn't always happen but when what I
find I'm going into civilian business
and all the rest of it is that certainly
in business terms most people right for
number one and that's quite hard to get
used to and the motivation is not there
from a team perspective you get some
exceptional companies you get some
exceptional groups of people who buck
the trend and but you know I I got out
and went into the steel industry as a
sales marketing director and to learn
about business that nothing to do with
the military and certainly find that
that you know at every turn I was having
to watch my back you know I I almost had
the more body armor on
in business and in war zones and that
shop recycling however what I've also
found is that there are some exceptional
people out there and when I left the
steel industry and set up my own
security consulting and marketing
business before I fell into journalism
you know I came across some absolutely
except dedicated individuals who helped
me learn my new trade who helped me
develop who your help helped push me
forward so it's it's the biggest bit of
advices of that and just contradicted
myself and everything I've said in the
last couple of minutes is it's a
different environment go in your eyes
open it's exciting there's lots of
opportunities it's not the same as the
military and you have to realize that
within it you have to look after
yourself there's no one else looking out
for you as you go through things and
just just be who you are don't try and
pretend to be something and that you're
not I see a lot of military people that
come out and they tried to be something
different because they've done lots of
courses they've done lots of
qualifications they put a sailor etc
this next section of that and they've
got hundreds of certificates and letters
after the names and everything else but
the bit of practical experience so yeah
we don't know what they're doing and
that stands I very quickly indeed so the
other biggest tip is be humble and learn
from people and don't be afraid to to
learn from those that in the military
you would say are at a lower level than
you I've learned more from a large
number of my junior noncommissioned
officers and my my senior
non-commissioned officers than I have
done from anyone that was more at my
level or more senior than me when I was
in the military so I I didn't find it a
difficult transition but that's because
I was having other difficulties okay so
let's let's turn our intelligence lens
to the tragedy that just occurred on
yeah and what I found interesting is
this was the first time that the tragedy
had occurred that the rhetoric of we
need encryption backdoors wasn't rolled
out as you'll recall after Manchester
and after the previous London Bridge
there was some Member of Parliament that
continued to press for Christian
backdoors do you think the encryption
backdoor in the UK issue is is a dead
issue now or do you feel it's just a
quiet issue because of the current
election climate I don't think is quiet
because the current is actually climate
but I don't think it's a dead issue at
all I think it is something that was
good to come up more and more and more
and more because the government agencies
are having real difficulties and they
see this naively as a solution and for
some reason or other think that just cuz
they govern the agencies that get away
with it
of course you crypto backdoors exist in
Russia exist they exist in or you're all
of the oppressed it's that are out there
so got some governments come can't sit
and look at things but that doesn't make
it appropriate for us to do that
the the London Bridge attack you the
individual and it's early days and
subject still subject to police
investigation it looks as if the
individual was a lone wolf or
self-motivated and interestingly at the
time there's a couple of weeks
beforehand we had the so called Isis and
al Qaeda encrypted communications on
telegram taken down by July Europol yeah
I watched that with great interest well
the thing about that is that some Isis
and al Qaeda executed a perfect business
continuity plan and they and they have
reopened the communication sites on a
number of other different internal
encrypted platforms which are even
harder for the intelligence services to
penetrate so I think as that comes more
and more and if more attacks happen
an unfortunate thing that's an
inevitability not something that isn't
going to happen it as more attacks
happen then I think the cry to try and
force some form of backdoor is going to
grow more and more but I don't think any
Western governments gonna be powerful
enough to achieve that right but the
tournaments of thought in there you know
are they putting it out as a cried to
try and keep it in and the public domain
to cover the fact because they actually
have a genuine need to get in or are
they doing it to try and cover the fact
that the really got backdoors into
lovely system yes exactly are listening
away as it is we're going to ask for
something that we already have so that
people think we don't have it correct or
never everyone says you're accessing the
the dark web and all the rest of tours
the only way to get in those tor was
invented by u.s. naval intelligence
that's right you know you know you
nobody could convince me that an
organization that has developed
something has not got a method of having
a look at what goes on in the background
well when you do have the resources of
the United States certainly and you
understand a little bit about the the
architecture of tor the vulnerability
being in control of the end the exit
relays it's conceivable that a nation
may be able to establish enough exit
relays under their control to
essentially try and reassemble a session
so it needs theoretical I don't think
the attacks have actually taken place
but again if such capability existed why
would you want to reveal it to to the
bad actors correct and there's
capability being developed all the time
it was controversy at the moment in the
run-up to the UK general election
because they're saying that the
documents that were released by the
leader of the Opposition talking about
trade talks between the UK and the US
over the National Health Service right
those those been released for the
roofies and to the to the Labour Party
or Russian connectors to get to get them
out in the first place
Tizen real Russian hacking Russian
influence and all the electrics but it's
wider than that it's it's it's Russian
Chinese and other influence of those
around the world
a few years ago with a big Asami attack
yeah and Americans were very quick to
turn around and blame the North Koreans
their terrain I find it fascinating
North Korea when you look at it we've
got a country where they can't send they
don't send anyone overseas to study at
any of our universities about modern
technology and about how everything
works Internet doesn't exist could you
just don't exist routinely within the
society where are they getting people
with all of us technical knowledge to be
able to understand how modern scripts
are working from modern communications
networks are working and to provide you
to develop these hacking teams that can
get past anything that's our big
companies have got with very
sophisticated
protection mechanisms in place there's
one question you throw out there
the second question is how is North
Korea connected to the Internet and the
wider world
yeah I'm not most likely easy to answer
there are two internet pipes that go
into North Korea there's a relatively
small one that's been there for a number
of years that's provided by China
there's a second one three years ago the
second pipe was put into North Korea by
a company called trans telecom okay
trans telecom is a Russian
telecommunications company that is part
of the russian national railway
organization and and it's wholly owned
by the kremlin and you know they it's
quite normal that telecoms companies are
a part of railway companies because the
old traditional phone lines used to
break but you have to ask why the
Russians put such a big pipeline in and
if you look at the tie
it was also very interesting whenever
Kim jong-un's missile tests were failing
nine times out of ten in very
short-range missiles as they as they
blew up on the pad or yeah by very far
to within several months after that and
he had very long range missiles that
were being successful nine times out of
ten right and you didn't have to look at
what was a wider geopolitics that's
going on here you fought for so both
Russia and China controls the internet
pipe and control all the internet
traffic going in and out of North Korea
mmm okay and North Korea get blamed for
lots of these attacks that are out there
yeah we've got this naughty schoolboy
unfortunate nuclear weapons and Kim
jong-un but he's a very good possibly
deniable outlet for other nation-state
activity so if the Russians the Chinese
wanted to do something but blame blame
the boy in the naughty step they can
only get the blame North Korea easily
absolutely we have to recognize that and
it's a very strong possibility I mean
recently we saw a PT 28 Turla a subject
or hijack infrastructure attributed to
Iranian cyber algorithms so you know not
with our president of Philip I just want
to say it was my pleasure having you on
beer com1 any sort of last thoughts that
you want to leave our audience with I
think this is absolutely fantastic and
hats off to you guys that tinfoil hats
off to you guys for a put this together
and the charities that you are
supporting are phenomenal you know I
just actively encourage everyone to get
on urn and started contribute as much as
they possibly can I'm good thank you
thank you so much for that and yes we're
doing quite well we just had a donation
from Wendy Edwards a little while ago
and we're at four thousand two hundred
and eighty quid raised so we are quickly
approaching our five thousand quid goal
or five thousand would be the halfway
point we have a goal of ten thousand so
thank you so much counselling on my
favor
truly appreciate talking to you
fascinating as usual and look forward to
many more of your comments in in Forbes
and and following your work as a
journalist thank you cheers have a good
day folks all right