okay oh hi there we're back again and
next up we have ray redacted for you
Ray's been a really big supporter of
beer com1 good friend of the band and
they're very vocal and helped us get
well get to the where we are with the
money so good morning ray
good morning to everyone out there good
afternoon everyone
Asia we have just crossed the halfway
point our summer cast
our past fundraisers and we are
certainly hoping to reach the halfway
point on our goals as well very very
shortly that we are that we are so
you've told us that you've got quiet I
don't know an action-packed agender of
things you want to talk about we match
any donations of 133 thousand seventy
pence made that offer without realizing
that GoFundMe doesn't allow people to
donate seventy pence I will be in the
next hour I'll be matching any donations
whatsoever the Exide so if you are a
half asleep one twitch right now and you
want to just make a donation for two or
three pounds during this talk please do
so because we want to keep this momentum
up you could go into the second half so
but Mike gift you're right I did have a
few things I wanted to talk about
because I am very old I'm the old school
hacker and I call us the wargames
generation meaning that we were preteens
but we're the movie wargames came out in
1984 sure I was gonna give up a nice
little history of the history of freakin
and a lot of the people that were there
but I've been listening to the beer pong
podcast for about ten hours now and I've
heard a lot of things that kind of
trying to decided that I want to talk
about something else which I haven't
really heard that much about and that is
this you know we as a community as an
infoset community there are about three
million of us there's 2.8 million
workers in the cyber security field ok
and if we think in terms of how big
Twitter
those seconds even if it will be
extremely generous okay we're talking
about under three hundred thousand
people and then of those three hundred
thousand people there's probably maybe
five hundred that are particularly vocal
or particularly well-known and so when
we talk about community issues community
building and a lot of these things it's
really important to understand that what
we see on the surface even in the mini
heights of discord is the absolute small
percentage of the very very small
percentage of the entire community
period right so we're talking about you
know significantly less than 10 percent
of everyone who works in InfoSec will
ever attend a con at all okay
hopefully this this counts as the cons
that may be really be getting that
number up yeah and Twitter is not a
statistically significant reflection of
the community its what Twitter is a
representation of a very specific type
of member of the community right and I
think that that is I've heard several
folks talk about cybersecurity shortage
this how shortage certainly the need for
diverse viewpoints and things like that
that is the one of the biggest drivers
that I think is extremely important when
we talk about growing this industry from
3 million to 7 million people in the
next few years is we have to open it up
we have to get people with different
ability levels different different
different underrepresented communities
you know certainly increase the
diversity for people of color and LGBTQI
all of those types of things because
it's simply a matter of survival we
absolutely are better the more diverse
we are nice but I'm going to play that
in there any thoughts on that
I completely agree completely agree and
it's interesting isn't it Jenny thoughts
about the the UK community circuit being
pretty much the same people and it's
true you know what I've been practically
all these science conferences in the UK
this year and you do see the same people
every time okay
and I guess socials it speaks to your
point ray about it about the the actual
active community in four seconds a real
microcosm of the wider industry it's
just the same
people all the time that's not a bad
thing but I think again to your point is
it's high time we started seeing fresh
faces and getting new ideas and new
experiences involved yeah no just keep
in mind that the vast majority of people
will never actually necessarily tweet or
give a con talk or even be on a panel
right but they are reading some of those
things right you know when we get into
some of our our echo chamber type
discussions or our you know micro disk
arguments or whatever about password
policies etc I think we just need to be
very kind so the fact that there is a
entire community of probes out there
that are not necessarily speaking but
are definitely listening to us so that
was that was the kind of the that was
kind of my big my big plug based on that
and I have enjoyed a lot of the other
podcast we've got all I'm here today but
I actually really want to build that out
towards kind of something that I'm
extremely passionate about and what I'm
actually kind of involved in this
podcast for and that is you know when we
look at statistics I'm an American so
pardon me for using an American
statistics here but really would be more
applicable to use global ones but about
one in five people prettier than the
flip okay so one one about twenty
percent of the people in the world
suffer at some point from the flu and
because of that we have vaccines we have
hand-washing campaigns we have
sanitizers we have things on the tube
that advertise you know behaviors and
things like that but twenty eight
percent of the world population has
suffered a mental health issue in the
last twelve months so think about that
statistic okay and the vast majority of
those twenty eight percent of people did
not get any treatment at all they did
not go to a doctor they did not get a
medicine they did not even necessarily
talk to a priest or counselor at all
though that is and ultimately that
really kind of was what brought me to
this podcast was one of our two
charities that were fundraising for is
mental health hackers just an initiative
the demand of Berlin and some other
folks started in order to address this
and by the way I know
talk a lot about Amanda Berlin but we
can't talk about this without also
mentioning people like Jason Street
hockey and a lot of other folks that are
very very much at the forefront of
addressing mental issues in our industry
because our industry has a lot of
behaviors that are identified to self
harm something medication gas lighting
and posture snare drum toxicity all of
those things with a lot of the other
pipe coasters I've been talking about
but the one that really really really
kind of stings and I think it's the
elephant in the room if I can use an
American expression took off we've got
wedding yet again and that is that a lot
of the folks in our industry and the
shocking number of folks both publicly
and Muslim finally had been affected by
childhood sexual trauma so just to give
you kind of overall statistics we're
typically talking about one in five
males and one in three females have had
some type of sad childhood sexual trauma
in their lifetime at about ninety
percent of people that have a
developmental delay or disability
compensation assaulted so you can see
that those statistics first of all are
just absolutely shocking we're talking
about four million in the United Kingdom
about 50 million in the USA but when I
was getting ready to talk at the
first-ever mental health village it was
actually Derby time in 2018 I decided to
see what those statistics would look
like inside our community so I went out
and hired to research crimes and
interest of getting a little bit of a
scientific way of looking at the same
statistics and I asked him you know tell
me how many people in the hacker
community and the InfoSec community have
been affected by childhood sexual trauma
and the results were extremely
surprising because neither company was
able to give me those statistics neither
company was actually able to come up
with something that they considered to
be reliable metrics for that I marilee
because people don't necessarily answer
the survey it's you know artifis later
truthfully or whatever but what they did
tell me just
is that if we look at a career matrix
where you would put in prosthetic
professionals and hackers etc is
probably closest to police officers
psychiatrists and priests
right all of which have overwhelmingly
disproportionate representation of folks
that have been affected by childhood
sexual trauma at some point of their
life and so I think that it's safe to
say like that statistic about one in
five males at one of three females is
probably way way way low for our
industry and it is something that you
know folks like Dennis applies
foundation and mental health hackers etc
I'm really really been talking a lot
about and the reason I'm bringing that
up by the way is because I know that on
the the microcosm echo chamber Twitter
there are still some folks out there
that are anti COCs right codependents
like they're still opposed to that and I
think if you look at that in terms of
the statistics that escape you might
have a little bit of a different opinion
about that because the vast you think
about what's going on at a conference if
you realize that up to meme you know up
to half the folks there and affected by
assault or trauma in their life it kind
of changes the aura surrounds around
behaviors what do you do I think that's
fascinating I think it puts a hell of a
lot into perspective I also think you
should probably color the way people
think when they're dealing with other
people and I often think about this
generally in life that this is saying
that you know don't don't ever judge
people because you don't know what kind
of bad day they're having so when you
trolling people on the web Switzer or
whatever or being a dick generally and
you know you really could be the the
switch that finishes somebody off so I
think I think we all can learn from that
and even if we can't get inside the
understanding of how people feel we
should be sensitive to the fact that
they are necessarily they aren't
necessarily full of beans and everything
isn't necessarily going great for an
individual in their life and we
shouldn't compare that problem but I
think we should do everything within our
power to to try and sensitive to other
people's situations
yeah absolutely I mean I do see progress
being made and I would tell you again
I'm on fire so it's a long time I would
tell you I've seen eating in the last 24
months a lot of the efforts including
this podcast itself which they're
raising money for about a civil rights
organization as well as the mental
health trackers sitting there oh by the
way if you're listening to this you can
donate right now the link is right
directly in the Twitter meeting still
right now you see did you see yeah I do
see progress being made there and I
definitely see I know dear farmers does
a lot of stuff and he has to collect
ours as well I mean if you go to youtube
and you take them in fact that will help
they'll see tons of videos for people
talking about impostor syndrome and and
gaslighting and self-harm and very very
famous talk that everyone should watch
was Jason streets talk at sky dog sky
and sky khon sky don't come I don't know
the only thing that's gonna scare
against his rant about a lot of issues
of any quality than assault deception so
I don't mean to be necessarily a total
downer about these types of things but I
do think they need is something that we
don't discuss enough and I will tell you
that I think that it probably would
behoove us to be a little bit more aware
of that especially when we're talking
about using language that might trigger
people I know that there's a big joke to
say to a your warning this before you're
wanting that but certain words can
actually bring back memories and in a
way but you know you may actually intend
itself
ya know that's it that's that's sort of
my soapbox that's my soapbox are we
getting donations up so much that would
be
I'm sure think we're reaching for that
credit cards right now and if not we'll
come find them will tear their money one
way or another can I ask you a question
right sure
do you find that the information that
you provided arias is really really
interesting and quite scary actually
would you say that that is
representative of InfoSec as a thing or
would you say it's representative of
wider technology as an industry or would
you say that it's it's representative of
human life
is it something that work was seeing as
a problem in information security per se
or is it is it a general problem well I
mean and I'm not gonna necessarily
mention any of the previous podcasters
that have been on this podcast but I'll
just speak from my own experience sure
there's a certain generation of us in
InfoSec that started out black hats
right and when I say black hats I don't
mean working through the NSA on CNA and
then traveling the nation states I'm
talking about cracking Commodore 64
games and dialing BBS is that were in
Canada just by defeating copy protection
or doping gang suits or I guess in the
more current generation it might be
mining gold on boards or something like
that yeah so because of the fact that
nympho SEC has a gray hat or a black hat
roots that are out there
you're going to necessarily attract
certain people that have had criminal
deviances or criminal to the pass or
just this incredible and innate
curiosity right and in the last five or
six years we've managed to take that to
take back the term hacker right so that
you can think about books like Marcus
Carey's try the hackers and you think
about a lot of the conference's that now
use that in the positive way et cetera
we definitely turn the tide so to speak
at least inside of our history on that
particular term but I do think that it
is indicative of society overall it's
just it's a very narrow use case right
because it takes a special kind of a
person to want to be involved in this
industry it's you know right you have to
have a little bit of a um a little bit
of a I don't want to say malfunction but
there's certainly the characteristics
for there that are out there and that's
that's one of the reasons why you know
when in many many cases people talk
about the family the hyper family
immediately get to be have these
relations well in many cases and again
I'm not going to speak for other people
but in many cases some of our family
lives maybe weren't that great right
with a family of origin or a parents or
whatever else that is so there is a need
that can be met by this community and
that certainly does have two sides to it
one is the generosity and the
overwhelming support
and the other one is sort of the
infighting in the feuding typically does
along with the family yeah yeah sure so
we just want to be more of the first
unless it's a second I guess but you
know I will tell you I strive to always
try to meet people with completely
different backgrounds and it is amazing
to be you've had two people in the
podcast in the last 10 hours that were a
year or under or just around the year
and I've already amassed these massive
huge followings and passive networks of
people etc so I don't think it should be
intimidating to people based on your the
experience yeah I don't even think it
should be in two million people very so
whether you can code or whether you can
reverse engineer already good social
engineer all of those insecurities and
concerns I think kind of go to the
wayside when you understand you know the
community at whole and how much
diversity that's out there yeah
completely so really we were going to
talk about predictions no the original
would you guys saw me on this we were
going to talk about 2019 and review of
2020 looking forward we have a whole lot
of that to me other folks happily we
haven't really gotten any any really big
ones goals see somebody really truly put
a stake in that one because even just
today we were seeing you know Microsoft
announced 44 million passwords that were
being reused across data breach sites
etc so the credential stuffing is
absolutely positively going to work I
think that we will continuously see
progress made make it maybe a
multi-factor American banks over the
last ones to embrace it
but I think with some regulars and
regulations and some laws changing I
think we will probably see a lot more of
that I very much think that we will
start to see and I'm hoping that we will
start to see a much more diverse
representation than keynotes and I will
call RSA up right now because RSA
been criticized very very much for not
having women to be notes this year there
this year their keynotes are absolutely
amazing
female lineup and they've gone the key
note aside and okay D mysterious is one
of those there's a few others really
good mine up so I think that they have
responded to that type of activity in
that criticism and I think the mini ads
Club is probably gonna cost ten thousand
number just at some point in the year
reasonable to me
and I think and there will be more of
the same
yeah I think it'll be there'll be more
breaches that we more nation state
badness happening there were more people
falling out and more drama I think
probably on social media I don't think
it's something we're ever going to
really get rid of in the world but we're
on the right side of it so I think as
long as we keep doing what we're doing
keep fighting the government will get
that how much do you think elected
security is gonna be in the news for the
next year 2020 do you think it'll be a
lot a little probably a lot we haven't
seen a lot of progress being made there
you know I don't know if you follow that
blaze or Rachel toe back on Twitter etc
but I've seen a lot of discussions but
yeah and obviously you know when we talk
about the influence campaigns and
Facebook and some of those other folks
it's it's it's it's rather dicey whether
anything is really being done to to stop
that aspect of its you yeah no I
completely agree okay well we're we're
out of time right really really best
please please please donate if you're
listening to this even if realistic so
don't replay please get out your credit
cards and donate at least a few pounds
and let's really get this over 10,000
pounds I have to also just jump in here
real quick and say really really big
thanks to the entire AV crew that has
been working for 14 hours straight and
for 48 hours before that this is that
I'm very well done well done show and I
really do appreciate you guys absolutely
and and you you wishes come true right
because every I would certain is just
donate 50 pounds so we've got another 50
pounds in the bear called a camel in any
room I done that's that one right away
there you go that's absolutely brilliant
so thank you Emily
and thank you reg for you insight your
energy and
you're involved in what trying to do
much appreciated so thanks very much