so thank you for joining me this morning
well testing restful restful web
applications I'll try to both keep it
interactive so let you ask questions in
the middle but do keep the pace of the
presentation so if at one point I tell
you you know we're running out of time
sort of let me go through keep your
questions I'll answer them either at the
end or personally later on so a word
about myself the picture is for the
slides that are online later on you can
see me here
of course the picture would always be
look better than I I I'm sort of a
person that I'd never know what I am i I
do product management today which means
I'm a bit more on a business side but my
heart and soul is research mostly around
application security today I work at HP
arcsight division until the year ago I
ran research at 45 still HP so I'm I
sort of come here my reason to come from
coming here is keeping in touch with
research with the community talking
about community I I'm in or very active
interest but I started is really chapter
I ran a few open source projects they're
all listed here a fun fact about myself
is that the airport closes to where I
live is Damascus I've never been there I
mean you read in the papers what's going
on there so did I read in the papers
what's going on there
I live on the other side of a steel
border in the first world and 40 miles
from me the third world starts and I
Drive to tell him because it's a 80
miles per hour freeway even though it's
a 120 miles drive the second process by
the way would be Beirut so
no no I went out with work I never tried
I write TLV which is our airport I never
tried nearby the fun
okay what about are we going to talk
about it today so we're talking today
restful web services are becoming a
major part of web development and are
very challenging for pen testing and I
broke the presentation in two parts
because I think many people don't know
what web services are and if they know
they know just about what they used is
restful Web Services so I'll try to
portray a picture of what really it is
and what it isn't then I'll discuss us
in a very small number of slides you
know how widely they are used whether
you stuff like that and then I'll get
into pen testing I'll first discuss many
open testing so challenges associated
with is actually getting after restful
web applications and then I'll move into
what I did at 45 time which is trying to
solve essentially the same issues but
from an automated scanner point of view
so this is interesting but it's a bit
more for if you write tools rather than
if you do pen testing yourself but all
for script our way around so might be
useful anyway okay so restful Web
Services so what our web service is to
start with we hear the terms so much
it's worth spending a minute
understanding what it is so we all use
the web daily web service is usually a
term which refers to interpretation
communications so when you want to use
the web technology to connect to
applications so it's not any more
interaction human interaction with the
web with web servers which matters it's
an application to application tracking
which matters one thing to note of
course when I'm using an application to
control my presentation is today the
client is also an application it's sure
to throw
but it's true also to reach real
applications whether it's rich as in
flash technologies or reaches in HTML
moving to html5 essentially the
difference is now so html5 applications
are pretty complex application so those
technologies even though they are
client-side and I used by end-user
are very pickett --iv and use web
services to communicate with the web
server example it's not the most common
anymore I used to say it's the most
common but it's not a flavor of web
services is something called soap thinks
s stands for simple however everything
in these that is just getting a stock
quote so a single stock code so soap is
a very very highly document formalized
way to use web services to interact
between applications it's based on XML
payload and XML results and there's tons
of standards around that and on the
other hand it makes it hard to use also
it's not a very efficient because
there's just a lot of XML there all I
wanted to do here was I sent the IBM
value and on top of that I write all
there just to send essentially one free
letter part meter so suburb web services
are giving way sorry that's previous
enough next application UI not so so
we're web services are pretty common die
usable inside organizations when they
try to do their sort of messaging buzz
between internal applications but
they're hard to use one thing worth
mentioning I won't go into details here
is that they are considered by the
industry as secure there's a tons of
security standardization around them
something usually called WS star because
it stands for number of WS
web-services standard around single
sign-on and session management and
authentication authorization and now to
sign the traffic and all that stuff
there is a good argument left to a
different presentation that this does
not really bring a lot of security to
software services it's sort of it never
gets to ask you an injection of course
which can go through that just as it can
go for any other input mechanism and
it's so complex it's so complex that
people are just not using that so off we
go with soap here we go with rest so
rest is an interesting concept because
essentially restful is a design pattern
it's a way to look at things when we get
in the next slide to restful Web
Services will try to understand what it
means to the same use case of connecting
applications to each other
however restful design is essentially a
design pattern is a philosophy of how to
do things right around essentially the
api's and essentially the restful design
pattern is the basic building block or
design pattern for the most pervasive
technology out there which is just the
web so web one so to speak is a restful
implementation it's not a web service
because it's not for interacting between
two applications it's usually used for
interacting between a user and an
application now I won't go into details
here they'll be very boring that's why I
sort of I don't want you to look like
the guys behind the slider but if you
think about what you do in the web
that's essentially our rest it's using
URLs to access the functionality you are
looking for its stateless no session
which is one of the most horrible things
about the web security wise but it's
still part of the design problem because
it makes everything much more simple
and it's supposed to be uniform some way
let's get into details which will be
much more sort of easy to understand as
to how this design pattern is actually
used for interacting between
applications so for restful Web Services
so one thing that I need to mention is
that restful Web Services are not a
well-defined protocol there's unlike
soap which is highly defined restful Web
Services are different ways to use the
design pattern that's called rest in
order to do interrupt occasion
communication so I can't really share
with you the spec for restful Web
Services what I can share with you is
common practices for restful Web
Services of course this makes it quite a
challenge to test them because you don't
even know they're there and we'll touch
about on that in the following slides so
essentially the simplest restful web
service you can have is taking
everything in this soap message and
putting it in a URL so apart from
changing IBM to HP which depending on
the day is not a good idea if you own
stocks you do save on character though
you can see that this is a much simpler
method for doing essentially the same
thing and that's why it's very
compelling that's why it's used a lot in
mobile applications in in web 2
applications it's just so much simpler I
mean think about programmers they want
this they don't want that
however dart applications not all the
information is as easily sent and we'll
see it about both security pen testing
in future so a few sort of con practices
one thing which falls very very directly
on the design pattern is using methods
to determine the actual action you would
want
with regard to the URI so the or I
specify sort of the resource you want to
access the metal specify what you want
to do with the resource a very commonly
used term is crude which stands for CR
UD create read update and delete which
are for functions you want to do over
essentially object so those translate is
very well into file management and
you'll see rest used very widely around
anything that has to do with closing
files so Amazon Web Services box.net all
of them Dropbox all the views are
restful Web Services that are very very
focused on the crude design pattern
providing access to their to the file
system from the road however a lot of
you want to do is a file access and many
times delete for example is not
meaningful there are other sort of
practices that are used a lot around
restful web services and one of them is
where do I put the parameters so there's
no standard around that that's probably
the matter of the major pain point of
understanding restful Web Services
dealing with them quality wise and
security wise you'll find that
parameters are passed in many different
ways so we've seen the example where
parameters part of your L this is a
pretty common one many times it's
implemented in practice in web server by
something called URL rewrite which means
that the error looks to you like it's a
file but essentially it actually is a
set of parameters and Apache has all
actually is as well these days every
role model around actually actually take
it before application gets it and
translate it into normal parameters but
it doesn't stop there
headers are used a lot for as parameters
so now the headers are also part meters
and that leads us into pen testing
because most of us will pass parameters
if they look like request parameters or
parameters but we rarely fuzz heather's
I mean we read a lot didn't research
about your abilities in headers but in
practice that's not where we'll go first
to search for a screen injection but
those are just regular prot meters so
why not another thing we want to look
into our composite power meters so a lot
of times usually Jason at times XML is
used as a container for power meters in
in restful Web Services of course XML
getting asked back to the soap era just
without the complexity and an overall
structure Jason be much more sort of
shorter and therefore loved by
programmers the issue there is that now
when the application gets it it treats
each of the values separately so just
injecting injecting the JSON itself
would usually break the first minute
because the json parser would just throw
it away
however if you inject and of the part or
any of them better parameters the risk
for vulnerability is to do very much
there okay keep in mind that the result
might also be a JSON payload the only
thing I've seen around that which is
security related is that in many cases
Jason is Jason's actual JavaScript so
this is just directly executed by the
application to derived values and if
it's not valid J's if it's not very data
but valid JavaScript it might be run as
code very own application which opens an
opportunity for different types of
cross-site scripting attacks lastly I
think that there is a challenge which is
always a challenge for web applications
which is the relation session management
there is no common way in the a web
world to actually do that
which by the way is major challenge for
pentesting always it's a huge challenge
for ultimate pentesting any of you
you've tried anyone here using is using
scanner I'll grab the kitchen scanner
which one
burp same any commercial one and burpees
commercial actually with any commercial
one apps can reming's back so many apps
can okay so in all those and actually
the way you can tell amateur we
replicating scanner from just a an early
stage one is how it does it handle login
how do you go over the log interface and
steal and scan all the activity that
exists after logging because there is no
standard way to do that it might be a
complex application oriented process
just think about the CAPTCHA and the
scanner makes it hard so just like with
interactive web usage restful web
services are very very not standard
around how they handle also education
and session management few common
practices to be aware of or the
authentication is many times done using
basic HTTP authentication so essentially
it's sending a username and password in
the header therefore many times HTTP it
sorry restful web services rely on SSL
for security because the only thing that
actually protects these those
credentials is as a cell you know many
times find that restful web services
security is nearly equated with SSL for
that reason as we all know as a cell has
its limitations not because I am afraid
of somebody breaking into a server
because of gateways proxies just bet
implementation that leaves some of the
site out of their cell range and some
within the cell range
the next phase
how do we do in session management in
most cases this nearly most restful api
s would provide you with some kind of
token that so you send your credentials
get a token back it has a lifetime in
essence this is an alternative to
cookies it just a managed eternity
cookie so it's not sorting because it's
an application calling running the
browser there's no need to use the
cookies mechanism which is sort of a
token automatically maintained by the
browser for the user an application can
receive the token and no word to use it
so actually it's more secure than
cookies because it's under the control
of the application but it's not that
different and it might have many of the
challenges you are aware of with cookies
I mean you could steal those tokens just
the same an interesting point to note is
that the design pattern itself due to
purity reasons calls for including the
session ID in the URL not in a million
header some implementations do that it's
very insecure because URLs are often
logged that are easier to steal a most
more major mature implementations of
restful api would have this token in and
header nearly 100% actually these days
another thing to keep in mind is that
since it's an application to application
interface there's a major s is so aspect
to it that's so being single sign-on so
I have a client application it's got a
token from a specific service when you
start to build your entire sort of
infrastructure education likewise you
want this token to be valid also on a
different service that's associated with
it and this is very challenging there is
no standard around that usually to
evolve some back-end communication that
the first server would tell the second
server this is an OK token but I've seen
areas
sort of the client gets to get the
information that allows you to get to
the second server it might be well
encrypted that's not a bad design
pattern it might be our weakness now one
last aspect I want to discuss about
restful Web Services is their
documentation restful Web Services so
software's web services are often nearly
universally actually described as
something called a wisdom WSDL which is
web services description language so and
since it's very highly structured it's
easy to define in a very OB fancy
numbers in a very formal way with with
restful web services since there's so
many variants essentially no standard
and the parameter can be in one of
dozens of different ways it's hard to
define there is something called waddle
web application description language
which is an attempt actually technically
it can describe any variant of restful
web services I've seen today it's not a
standard it's just a proposal and it's
not widely used the numbers you can see
here are my Google searches for both for
actually files available on the internet
which have wisdom files or Waddle files
and this is around I know two hundred
thousand which by the way is a security
issue if you think about it I mean we
still exposed sometimes intentionally
attacks is not intentional and for
bridled around two thousand so one
percent of those and my guess is that
it's not because when you write the rest
web service you know your security and
you put the waddle out there it's just
that it's not widely used and we will
see you later
it doesn't imply that restful web
services are less widely used it just
implies they're less well documented and
that's a big challenge when we go to
test something we need to know
as much as we can about it and we'll see
that even though normal applications are
not documented well we have our ways to
find the attack surface for Web Services
there really isn't way to do the partial
documentation and if there's no
documentation we have a big big
challenge okay
so that was sort of an a prime primer to
restful Web Services I hope you get out
of here knowing a bit more about restful
Web Services sort of getting it from a
buzzword level to something which is
tangible but the bottom line is that
it's the web as you know it apply to be
inter-app location communication so a
few slides about work can you find in
the world so I promised another Google
search on the technologies so I needed
the Google search on restful web
services and software services and you
see that soap is declining crust is on
the rise and actually since I was
stopped at Barcelona about this subject
and I did update the slide we were even
and now we see the Tres restful web
services are actually gaining momentum
over so probe services everybody is
using that I did not update this like I
didn't go out and look for additional
logos to put here essentially every a
major web site aggregator whatever you
call it that expose an API today does it
using restful web services it's becoming
very common so it's sort of the factor
that's the way things are done that's
good that way one thing to keep in mind
is that you will find especially in the
mobile application world all restful web
services that their program are never
knew the name so the implement is
something that's restful web services
but they didn't call it this way it does
exhibit a lot of the characteristics
that we've seen before but it usually
has a lot less security because if we
talk I talked about having a header as
the token used for session management
if you write the RESTful API
intentionally you work it out if it's
just an app doing an API for itself
there are many cases where it's not done
the correct way so two slides about the
security of restful web services because
I said quite a bit about that but and I
think that the security itself is no
different it's the the testing which is
different which is get to in the phones
like so first of all rest is just the
web so if you know rest security and if
you are old and wisest this guy you know
restful web security and a lot of things
that you already know are there I mean
it's a way to provide far Minister
application and the same attacks work I
don't think there's any major change me
in the next I'll show a bit of sort of
things to keep in mind one thing to keep
in mind is that that there is a notion
of security by obscurity that does not
happen on web applications nobody really
sees this this API because it's been to
applications and therefore we test it
class which is what we will talk about
today and the programmers tend to give
less you know those programmers that we
all only protect and check
well the login page because of the
famous SQL injection around or one
equals one so they will do nothing
around restful web services few things
to do keep in mind would be that there's
no standard mechanism to do security and
therefore I'm talking about penetration
testing I do believe that you need to
start and the rest test with an
architecture overview there's a lot of
four key issues there they have to build
there is no standard you can't just
expect you know login cookies as you
would in a web application or W a star
as you would expect in where in so for
services worth looking rather people
have done there it's sort of a black and
white picture usually if somebody gave
any thought to that it would be okay if
not I hope you got earlier
because I was it would go live without
your without changing because it's hard
to change architecture I measure
proprietor of the education session
management and lastly some smaller
issues I mentioned that people usually
say I have ssmi restful web services are
ok the reason for that is because you
need to protect the attend occasion key
for sure and the username password if
it's basic HTTP authentication it's
certainly not enough but people will
tell you that everything else are
probably covered ok a bit of a long
introduction but I think it's important
because it's nearly half of the
presentation or because restful web
services are not well understood
let's get into actual pen testing ok
so I'll mention three or four challenges
that are facing us regarding testing web
application best web services then I'll
I'll show a few solutions what you
should do then we move to the automated
part of it so the first one is the
application surface keep in mind that
now you don't the paradigm of you see a
page you know the parameters you know
the you that the links doesn't work
anymore
there are a few reasons for that first
of all it's generally generated by an
application so it that might not be easy
to view HTML in the first place it might
be still HTML but done by using a lot of
JavaScript so only after tons of
JavaScript execution the actual restful
call is done and lastly but not less
important once is there any PII there is
no one to one correlation between what's
implemented on the server and what's
actually used by the coin so just look
in the client would never give you a
full insight in the API it might be 30
percent it might be 70 percent because
it's now two teams an application
exposing an API client application using
just by looking at the client you won't
know what's the entire surface so those
were sort of the URLs
the second part is about the parameters
so assuming you know at least resource
wise URL wise what is the extent of the
application it's pretty hard to know
what the parameters are I've mentioned
two aspects of that one of them wiii be
to death before was about what is a
parameter the second one is that
especially for unused api's or those
it's hard for you to see the real
requests it's hard to know what's the
base values if you think about it when
you do fuzzing you do one of two things
you either send sort of an own attack
vectors or known vectors to solicit
response that would indicate an attack
single quote okay
for that matter or you files over the
existing values so you take the current
values and and look for the red herring
for the value which is out of range and
the second one is very hard to do when
you don't have a base value basically is
critical for that part and it's hard
when you don't have any example of the
actual core the result of that is that
you need a lot more requests or more
attempts which is not scalable when you
do many old testing and also pretty bird
building some for automated testing okay
as I mentioned the customer education is
something that's a challenge relatively
easy to solve one usually you can't
analyze that but you should analyze that
so you need in order to actually do
testing you have to understand the
authentication mechanism what is the
actual session ID and B have a tool that
knows how to help you with doing that so
for example if you have a standard proxy
which has a cookie jar that you can
store a cookie there in order to
preserve your session doesn't help
anymore you either need to manually
update the header for each request or
you need to find a tool that
to keep an header an ongoing basis which
is less common so that's more of a
practical issue in the first two and
after I mentioned challenges let's look
a bit at solutions so first and foremost
probably the first thing to start with
and be and I mentioned the for restful
Web Services you may want to note dive
directly into the application but
looking at architecture before you may
want to do gather as much documentation
upfront as you can now when I send the
commentation it might not be just a
formal documentations waddle because
there aren't that many of them there are
few other places to look for that so I
have here an example of a documentation
program you guide an example of
something interesting you may look into
the configuration of the web server or
whatever framework you are using because
in some cases the the configuration
let's call it the pirate code something
comes before the code includes a lot of
information about how the requests are
translated into parameters what is used
as a parameter because the programming
language has a very concrete notion of a
parameter the interface you're using
doesn't have it so something in the
middle would include this this
translation one thing worth mention
specifically would be configuration for
your rewrite model on the web server as
I mentioned in some cases of this the
translation from one uniform URL to URL
plus parameters is done on application
on the web server level and then the mod
rewrite configuration would disclose to
you what is the actual parameter so in
this example essentially anything
anything which is you think of as a URL
is essentially passed as a parameter to
index dot PHP so the rewrite rule checks
for any URL and put the parameter
department of foreign expiry so that's a
simple one can be much more accomplished
than that
let's do key there are two examples of
potential sources I mentioned waddle of
course lastly the application source is
a good way to go and in many cases you
don't get need to get into the sources
in to dive into C code in both a dotnet
and Java there are sort of frameworks to
build restful Web Services which implies
there is some configuration file this is
the net example that an able to define
for the code your restful Web API and
essentially you have it pretty World
Translation very similar to the rewrite
example of how you translate the request
into code for meters I won't get into
the details here but essentially you see
here the patterns for the URL and then
how they translate into a method call
with the Parmenter used as a parameter
so you have names from parameters and
how they are reflected in the URL all
those examples are for URLs you will
find especially in documentation I
didn't see it in frameworks also of
course documenting when headers are used
as parameters or JSON is used for meters
so go to the documentation I know it's
harder it's usually something we don't
do as pen testers then we just hit the
application and it creates a problem
with the reach the interaction with the
customer because they're not used to
providing that I think it's important so
another another thing you should use you
may use it today it's important since
web to its are critical would be proxies
of course I mentioned two things about
that first of all you use a proxy
because you can't get all the URLs today
in the only request in the first place
so once we start doing web to Ajax you
don't see all requests on the page you
use
Prague's in order to get the request
understand what to send yourself or
store the cookie ready for that matter
so that's for sure and for restful Web
Services that's nearly a must one thing
to remember it's also a source for
understanding request that they request
structure and we'll see later on to use
that especially in automated tools so to
sort of map the attack surface what your
URLs are especially used a point in
question will of course be that for
application point to remember is for
applications for mobile applications
there's literally no other way you have
to put that middle and files here rather
than files on the client or on your own
Python script okay the third one I want
to share with you before we get to
automation if April well would be how to
identify in a request for meters by
looking them so directly addressing
manual pen testing so of course anything
which is an understanding that none
stunt header would be something you want
to fast some you want to inject it so
that's sort of easy luke into the URL
try to assess whether anything there
looks like a par meter know that easy to
said why would it look like a power
meter so one thing would be if it has a
pattern of a par meter if it doesn't
look like finally a directory name a
date you have a date in the middle good
chance it's a par meter a long term
vertical value by itself directories are
not often called by long numerical names
or anything which is just garbage
forever if it's just letters or numbers
it's usually a session ID by the way so
you can attack it as a session ID or as
a parameter for that matter thirdly of
course look for structured inputs they
are visible you can see them if it's
looks like Jason by the way it doesn't
have to be JSON or XML if you have a
power
that has sort of the limiters inside
keep in mind there's a good chance that
each you want to inject or test fast
each part between the delimiter so
you'll have a value which is a semicolon
offers semicolon ID number semicolon
Dave that's a compound value you may
find more abilities if you try to inject
or fast each one of the parts and if you
try to just replace everything by by an
injection string because if you just try
an injection string it will be sort of
found a zero is an error by the parser
itself that breaks it while if you try
each value by itself you'll get the
actual code that processes this value
which will prove more efficient to find
our abilities lastly somewhat
interesting look for your role there is
no extension usually it's not always but
if there is no extension there's a good
reason to think it might be part of in
restful api because it's not the file it
can be a file there's no reason wouldn't
be a file but these are just heuristics
nothing here is you know pure science
forever so we've talked about testing
restful Web Services I mentioned the tax
surface is a major issue both finding
the actual URLs and secondly knowing
what a parameter is and the session
management is somewhat challenging then
I went into solutions and I mentioned
that to find the attack surface you
should really go into documentation it's
now important sorry for not being a real
native technical idea but it has to be
done you need to use a proxy and then
there are some heuristics that would
allow you to test it to think about
whether something is might be a
parameter so you don't have to pass
every aspect of the request but can
focus on some things that might be more
valuable now going from here let's spend
the last few minutes of the
talk about automated pen testing so what
is automated pen testing about for in
the first place not a lot of you are
using that you should by the way it's
not replacement for many old pen testing
but it saves all of the hustling is
going to start from manual pen testing
and I want to share with you what
actually automated weapon testing does
because people run apps can run bear run
this parrot and I want to get somewhat
into the under the hood so ultimately
pen testing has two parts the first part
is usually called crawling crawling is
detecting the essentially the touch
surface and essentially historically it
was based on links so you would follow
the links open source early on scanners
still do only that today it doesn't work
anymore because there's so much web to
an HX there the links are just not
enough also just parsing JavaScript
findings would not work either so a
modern scanner has to run JavaScript
internally and do break points on the
actual Ajax call so essentially
something like a smarter version of
proxy in order to detect those calls and
this is sort of the complexity that
works kind of has two days it's a pretty
new technology it's not easy to do not a
lot of scanners out there do that I
actually know just of two but maybe
they're fearful the second phase will be
attacking and attacking falls into sort
of two different aspect it's much closer
this time to what you do as a pen tester
it just automated it has the fuzzy part
which is trying to send abnormal values
into parameters but this is a bit too
simplistic there are a second group or
family of tests I would call session
based where you try to create a workflow
that would cheat the application into
something I'll give you a good example
of that
you'll login automatically as
administrator you'll do you crawl and
get the surface and then you'll try to
go directly to everything as a user and
if you get to everything the
administrator you can get to as a user
something might be wrong so that's a
good example of that attempting to do
testing for cross-site request forgery
for example ok might be a session based
thing so again a lot of comparing
different credentials different users
that's essentially what the ultimate
pentesting machine does
so essentially you need to understand
request generation which was either
links or past or running JavaScript
understand what parameters are which is
tough if there are no standard another
session management again for an
automated - it's pretty tough if it's
not standard so all those are pretty big
challenges for automated websites web
testing of web applications I remove
that from the table because as I
mentioned before this is something that
even if you have to tell it to the
scanner is still worthwhile because you
just have to teaching something you what
you do have to make sure is that your
scanner actually supports more well
non-standard methods for session
management so they know it knows I
mentioned that the test about compared
logging is a user as an administrator
and keeping a session if you do it for
normal web using session it would be a
cookie if you do it for a restful api
probably a header a different header so
the scanner we are using has to know to
keep a session in the header for a
matter even if you need to teach him
that the specific header is a specific
name received by the login still it is
the the technical capability the two
other issues are way more complex so I
think we beat the challenges for that I
mentioned them more than once what can
we do what would be the solution so so
this is sort of the idea that actually
came up with when we started looking
into that for women's back the first
thing you need to do is what I call
defined rules so define how to explain
to the scanner the RESTful API why not
just waddle so it can be waddle but why
do is very complex for the pen tester so
the rules are usually more and that's
very small and the trajectory is not
very good so sorry for that it would be
available online of course and if you
want before that send me an email
it's ofr at hp.com thats too short to
forget I went to HP just to have the
shortest you are in the world that's the
only reason so essentially what we have
here is a bit similar to the today what
the rewrite rules I showed before it
takes a URL and have a regular part way
that breaks into one of the parameters
here so this is the simple part where
it's about URLs if you want to go into
headers into actually breaking JSON and
stuff like that you need something which
is not a one-liner
it's sort of our request territory in
which you take a sample request and
point to what would be the parameters in
it so that's sort of a method that's
sort of easier for pen testers then
model to model how the application the
RESTful API works now how would you
populate that so you can define it
manually you can import from
Waddle or from a new crewman tation from
actual source as I mentioned before the
trick we tried to do was to do it in an
automated manner so while it is easy
because it's a standard from
configuration we can support a certain
number of known configuration I showed
net1 mod rewrite stuff like that and the
nice part and we are looking into that
would be to take it to guess it from
documentation from textual documentation
because you know it's looks like a URL
it is curly brackets and it's a
parameter so and it actually works
it's a you'll do it by examining the
invitation
a smart to can try to do it also and
again
only suggest the rules and then you can
mark if it's included or not why what
would you use those rule for so the
first one would be of course fuzzing
you'd fast using those rules so you have
a much wider fastened the other thing is
pretty interestingly pretty interesting
would be to actually when you run the
scanner not that tach part of both
passing the scanner to actually detect
you get a URL or a request in the
scanning process and to understand that
you will deploy those rules to it to
understand if it's part of an API okay
so the rules should be more generic than
just to point to specific API entries
they might point throughout when API
looks in this specific design pattern so
and then you catch the specific API call
and you can facet once you find it in
the crawling phase saying that I want to
get smarter I don't want to stop here
that's just a methodology the second
thing we do and actually we do that is
to ask the server when I said
configuration when I said the
application source if you think about
files if it's actually file based so the
file attack surface all these are known
to the server that are just not known to
this client
so what we have we have a piece running
on the application which can disclose to
the scanner all this information so this
kind of communicate through the runtime
piece on the application server and it
gets actually the application attack
surface by the way this technology is
good for many other things with dynamic
scanning with vacations coming because
for example it can tell you the dispatch
specific input actually gets to a sequel
call rather than just being an input so
it can actually validate the sequel call
or that something that cross-site
scripting is actually persistent because
it's get to the database stuff like that
so it's a pretty new technologies that
I've been coming to acknowledging a
application scanning we do that apps can
do this as well a few others do it it's
so again there's a mature scanner and
some
to look into lastly we want to actually
get smart about how we determine you
remember the slide about you trying to
assess if something is a parameter or
not we try to do it on an automated way
do you have something automated guess if
it's a parameter or not so some of the
things I showed before are can be done
by a machine as well so an OnStar header
would be a good example I can fast nice
alright non-starter headed by a scanner
as well other things are sort of less
straightforward so two things that are
really neat and sort of we like them one
of them is the four-four method so
essentially usually if you issue a
request for a folder you will get a you
get either a four-four if the folder for
four is they should be message for not
phone if there is not nothing like that
and you'll get a message saying you
can't browse it or you succeed in
browsing it if it's a real folder now
that's a good way to determine if
something is a folder or a parameter if
something so cut the URL short somewhere
anywhere call it and if you get the
phone for okay it's a middle thing of
something you know it means it was a
parameter one thing to keep in mind
though
just keep it might be a 4/4 it might be
your standard not found message both
sides today don't have a 4/4 message
anymore they have somewhat technique to
tell you that it wasn't found which is
not a lousy message it would usually be
a redirection to a specific URL but it's
still a method to tell you it's not
found so it still works the same here
the second way is to look for highly
varying Ural segments and I'll try to
explain that in the last two minutes I
have here a serial thing about the
session ID within the URL in the middle
of URL so you have X slash something
very long / y dot
aspx for that matter it's pretty obvious
to you that the very long thing in the
middle that there are fairly different
values for while the X and the Y's keep
the same there's a good chance they're a
parameter so if it might be also the
type of value because it's very long but
if it's just a word it might be hard to
understand oh that from the text so what
we can do is we can do statistical
analysis about the frequency in which a
middle section of a URL changes while
the rest does not change and if those if
there's something that changes a lot in
the middle there's a good chance that
there is a parameter luckily enough we
can verify it using this method for
formatting neither of them is foolproof
that's why both of them are suggested
keep in mind that we don't need the
higher percent success factor as pen
testers know we need to get to as much
as we can to see if there are
vulnerabilities and we when we create a
scanner I want to minimize the number of
requests we send for the matching my
maximum value we get because it takes
time so so give me me to sum up no
because we are in two questions so so
essentially I want to summarize in a
minute we talked today about restful web
services it might be for some the the
most important part you got out of today
because we really tend to talk about it
but it's hard to know what it is because
it's not something very specific
so the message it's not very specific
and refer to my presentation from a few
characteristics which are common to it
when you get to it
second we did try to discuss a bit about
it security which is just like web and
then the challenges and solutions for
how to pan test it which is mostly about
the attack surface how do we determine
the attack surface to solve that I send
it first and foremost to the
documentation but then offer a few more
practical solutions as to how to look
into the web application requests you
have and determine if something leads to
additional URLs is a parameter etc
lastly I talked a bit about automation
and point out if things can be also done
in an automated manner which is harder
in this case to detect the attack
surface for a restful api so now for
questions and I was asked just to give
you the microphone so that's the reason
I sort of how often do parameters show
up in the middle of a URL as opposed to
usually at least in my experience they
tend to be at the end at some point they
stop and it becomes file structure but
so it's not in both cases it's not as
something is just 99% and the rest is 1%
it's sort of in somewhere in the middle
my experience is the those at the end
are the mod rewrite stuff so Drupal
WordPress so those you see a lot while a
lot of enterprise applications which are
more of interest to us in many cases
because they've a lot more ability in
the first place and we are called in and
paid to test them
unlike open source in many cases do have
primaries in the middle as well
especially if you especially it's in
hebrews api there is a good chance that
the last part is deus ex parte is paging
the parameter stuck so last questions I
think I was so anyone thank you for
participation feel free to contact me
email now for more questions I hope you
enjoyed thank you
[Applause]