money perfecto
bueno bueno dias a todos good morning
everyone and thank you very much for
coming one more day thanks coming my
name is Erika Saarinen here's the web
site and co-founder of Armando raquel
something that we fund 10 years ago
there were five or six of us working in
an office from 7 p.m. to 10 p.m. every
day so we we've been doing a lot of work
in order to we spent many hours doing
things and we ended up hacking TV
walking around the streets with a hidden
camera and this is what made us arriving
here the way we are and we're very much
involved in this world of cybersecurity
I'm also within security IBM F for Spain
Portugal Israel in Greece and when I
started was I've been working for IBM
for five years now I used to do
fantastic projects ethical hacking and
they started also doing product demos
after which I went into the vending
sector logo meant ostomy Kasturi gusta
mucho la parte de entrenamiento de I
also started working the area
entrepreneurship and innovation and I'll
be giving you some tips in case you
wanna set up your own business and so
always I've always worked in an area
related to technology
because technology is wonderful for many
things that people don't even imagine so
thank you very much for coming I know
that there are families here with us a
people who are no practitioners in this
area children we've got engineers all
sorts of profiles all sorts of people
and also professionals in their world
and there have been some wonderful
presentations and first of all I'm gonna
be telling you what I do outside IBM
because in the end the IBM is my core
work and some time ago I gave a
conference in Madrid this show on TV I
don't have you soil but that program we
were showing how to use technology in
order to chase bad guys and so we were
able to help many people and we felt
very good with the program and that we
also help people to get problems with
technology so this is very important as
well as the whole awareness process the
technological gap has made it to
everybody even grandparents have a cell
phone and they go in the web analyst and
welcome anybody is trying to pay me what
I didn't do anything to you
I'm how come I'm being attacked so you
were helping our people know the
technology some people don't use
technology properly because they don't
know how to do it and they run into
trouble so what you can see here on the
slide this little box that I'm going to
show you later on I'm going to give you
the details this is a company for health
food take away health food the
technological part of the company orders
and many things it's a different
I don't know where technology has a very
important role to play since I've
technical background and take care of
Android and iPhone applications this is
a something that I published a some time
ago and then here the feathers it's a
brand clothing brand that I've had with
friends for a long time you know camisa
he hit me Niq Niq sa la surfing mis
amigos P and this business also entails
a technological part and the feathers
we've done something that's really
important that is then when an order
comes to our website this order is
linked to the warehouse that gets in
touch where the delivery people on
motorbikes are so it's something that
works the operator that runs on its own
it works automatically so one of the
keys for entrepreneurship is to devote
time to it so this something that can we
send orders all over the country all
over Spain and this use of technology is
not just for cybersecurity but also for
entrepreneurs because one can always
think differently out of the box and
give the whole thing a twist
and this is well you can see on this
line are different projects different
businesses as we can see seem recommend
on important data per la camera there's
also this company that sells covers for
you
machines cameras that is for you
computers cell phones so you can cover
your camera be able not to be seen so
what I do or 24 IBM I brought you an
example we do some very nice settings
right now we're working in artificial
intelligence and cognitive systems
because it's not just interesting to
detect a threat but we have some
cognitive tools that go step knowing
that somebody's in your system when you
go into many important banks around the
world there's a solution is the
following for instance at the beginning
the session says in blue this is what
people normally do once
you learn how to use the mouse whenever
you log in username and and then tab and
then we move the mouse to go to log in
log in and the normal thing is to use
the blue thing so one of your valid
session starts you got a little red tab
the abnormal user behavior here we need
to be what's happening and then there's
the known first behavior when you go to
this a black apart this generates an
alert and you're telling banks with 90%
of probabilities this user is who he or
she says it is some if you do weird
things with your mouse a bank may call
you and say is that you same thing with
mobile applications everybody has a
different way to move your hand every
time you click on a key in here we know
whether it's you or not users name
password and for instance you change
hands
so these behaviors according to which
you'd tell the bank well this is the
right user so he is the one who is
supposed to be so this is just a little
example and it's not just to do
publicity but just to tell you that's
the whole world uh behind with cognitive
fool our tools and there's a whole bunch
of open source online tools for instance
video analyses face recognition there's
a whole bunch of our tools that are very
easy to use with a great potential
so what are we concerned with in
cybersecurity this is something that I
always tell when I go and see a client
this is the next Secretary of Defense of
the US Donald Rumsfeld there are known
knowns as these are things we know that
we know there are known unknowns that is
to say there are things that we don't
know we don't know and there are some
things that I don't know about and this
is something that was done or said in a
non technological scenario now we speak
about cyber war etc but like being like
to scare you or anything just to give
you some figures not just to tell you
something and ask you to believe me this
is a report we bring every year in IBM
every year there are security analyst
creatures to research and investigations
but this is research this is these other
types of our threats we've seen in the
last few years this is from March 2014
15 16 like green these are access as
attacks in yellow as a key well hi
attacks and also fishing as you can see
there's color that predominant color
this is the one 2016
that's everywhere and it says unknown
means that most attacks are gonna be
classified so and I think that this is
very interesting for those of you who
want to work in the area of cyber
security this is the right time to do so
as curious you see that most of the dots
are undisclosed we see that more and
more we know less there's more money
invested and we realized that we still
need to invest much more let's go beyond
this these are the attacks when new
vulnerability is detected in the last
few years since 2010 in 2010 there were
thousands 9,000 now there's about 10,000
vulnerabilities or detected such are
easy from 2010 to 2016 so before this we
don't know the minister said that there
are things and attacks that are taking
place and that we don't know of that
could be happening right now for
instance
cryptid communications whoever knew
about this could be spying on them who
knows 2017 maybe we were being listened
through the mic or maybe they're seeing
it through the cameras and nobody can
make sure or ensure tellers that were
not being spied on so just to tell you
that from the point of view of
professional standpoint there's a huge
niche some people are saying technology
is going to take jobs away from OSHA and
the end is not going to be we won't be
able to find a job I believe that
society will keep evolving new work
opportunities will come up and we are
not taking jobs away from security
analysts people are going to be able to
specialize more like I was saying at the
beginning this is an area the main a
sector that we love yesterday I was
talking to people and to the winners and
you can tell they enjoy doing what they
do I'm sure that when they get home they
keep on doing research and investigating
this kid you can see here you may say
well he doesn't seem to be having a ball
just by looking at the stickers on his
computer I can tell you that he is
having a great time maybe he looks tired
because he hasn't slept for the last
three days because he's been doing
something he loves doing so when there
is passion you'll make it I know
cause you need to devote time the
training is important me you need to go
to college you need to have a degree you
need vocational training people in high
positions analyzing people they want to
hire and then privately they tell me I'm
not asking degrees from them
I want people will really even know what
they do take afine allocated of course
training is needed it's true that there
are very brilliant people sitting there
come very good in cybersecurity and they
have opportunities but I always invite I
always say that it's important to have
something basic degrees something
because people don't know you and they
need to know that there's something
behind there are so many different
profiles you know is something because
in the end of the training when you go
to a company not just showing that you
know started you're interested in what
you're doing and really interesting is
true that teamwork for instance in
Bologna they encouraging teamwork and
Ivan an actor please raise your hand
who's ever come across this situation
you work in a team with ten people
there's always somebody who works very
little or doesn't work at all and that
one person is never you is that happen
to you
yes I like to know there's a one
is lazy I'd like to interview this a
person and no these are just an Arduino
a second to me is a buddy common PSL
many people tell me well okay and how do
I begin
how do I get started how do I get to
work for IBM what do I need to do well
the first thing and by the way I'd also
like to thank cyber companies
institutions of having invited me here
because these companies these
institutions public institutions I think
that it's extremely important for
countries not just been it's really
important you see that there's a lot of
public investment in cyber security not
just our security but also technology
the Internet of Things many other things
we specialize in something the
opportunities there's something I always
tell competitions like the one yesterday
is very good because areas that allow
you to learn and this is a very complex
thing and I'm sure you've thought about
this how are we going to train hackers
doesn't allow you to hack it's wrong in
Spain these people that would play chess
since they are little somebody's hacking
the police will knock on the door
tomorrow so what do we do do we learn
these things so CTFs very important you
capture the floor
city s very important thing is the work
all games used them for especially in
English there's a couple in Spanish I
guess and when you be more games these
are websites where you have several
challenges divided in broken County
specialities working so there's a
different ten different levels and you
one by one the first ones are super
super easy and then you keep on
advancing and then they start getting
more difficult the good thing is that
when you cross a certain level they let
you mentor those who come in behind you
come after you so collaborative way you
can learn we can train people and I
recommend people to go in here and then
finally whatever saying on
yeah well mundo say sorry cape I didn't
even sent arrows so people with hackers
in Ravello know there's a whole bunch of
regulations make it compulsory to hire
people jobs in the field of
cybersecurity whole bunch of
opportunities and we if we specialized
will probably become leaders in ten
years
so speaking about career plans what am i
doing reckoning what am i studying what
am i studying this for and one day I
want to see results
companies you can go to your boss and
say what's so going on why am I sitting
here will end up being head of pen
testers or hackers and so let's not
waste time doing things so we don't know
what we're doing them for to a company
and no job and somebody says sit here in
the table and do you in five years later
you're still there well we need to
complain and and say well I'm doing this
I don't like much why am i gonna spend
so much time here why do we do things
why do we do the things we do typical
interview in an interview where do you
see yourself in ten years time I would
ask what do you see yourselves in five
years time and remember everything that
I'm telling you today comes from my
personal opinion have been working for
IBM for five years now and I started
working the world of cyber security
since I was 21 22 and there were 300
people who showed up for the interview
so there was this girl sitting to my
right I think she came from Russia she
spoke like five or six languages her the
list of languages she spoke was longer
than my entire CV so I thought oh my god
I have nothing to do here I'm totally
lost this is the important part you do
have a CV and a vital CV I didn't have
work experience but I had worked for
no hacker for seven years I had
researched I had created Apple apps etc
so that gave proof of the fact that I
wanted to work for that company that I
liked what I did and that I had a
passion for it and they told me that in
the end that was the reason why they
selected me rather than having a lot of
decrees and speaking a lot of languages
if you like it and you love it they will
hire you actually in the world of
computing there are a lot of intruders I
mean physicians chemistry engineers and
many other professionals that are also
trying to find a place and a job in our
field anyway when I recommend when you
go to a job interview you have to prove
that you know the company when they ask
you why this company and not another one
you have do you have a clear response
well a relative of mine was hired by a
company that she didn't know anything of
because well she just gave out thousands
of CVS and well she found her job the
job of her life and she wasn't quite
aware of the company she was she was
applying for it but don't desperate
sometimes you are not hired and not
because you're not good enough maybe the
russian girl who is sitting next to me
wasn't hired because she had two degrees
in seven languages maybe she was looking
for something else and see the example
of my relative I mean she just gave away
and gave out thousands of CPAs until she
found the company where she really fit
so this is what happens in the end
an IBM and in the world in general there
are people who get paid and they are
angry and the world they're just sitting
at their desk watching the time go by
and they do much about it
so I think during the interview we have
to give proof that we know the company
then we can add value to the company
we're not going to be just one more
sitting there we have a CV and we are
different innovation and disruptive
thinking is what companies are currently
demanding young people now are listened
to of the companies I had the luck of
being a trainee and I didn't have to
copy anything or do paperwork because
they were interested in me they were
interested in my opinion they are
interested in the technology Bri that is
coming and not just in the field of
video games when it comes to computer
security where can we work well I have
split it like this first consultancy
this part is a little bit apart from it
because I like to tell or make a
difference between the commercial world
and the technical world in terms of
consultancy there are many issues
regarding cyber security if you go to
the checklist standardization etc as
some people like this world people who
are highly technical are not so fond of
it but there is also the option of
technical consultancy some clients
actually asked me to help them because
they've bought very expensive software
item they don't know how to do with it
so we help them make things work that is
a nice job as well it is very rewarding
because the client is very satisfied
that someone who knows about this is
able to help them so being a
troubleshooter is also important and
interesting then technical world
technical sphere and commercial sphere
in the technical sphere there are many
job opportunities are
sitio iBM is a technician a practitioner
she started programming as everybody
else then I I will talk a little bit
more about the commercial side but maybe
there is a way of combining those the
technical world is the one that is
providing value to the company because
it's you actually who are who is
performing the ethical hacking for
example but you need a commercial part
in the entire operation in some
countries people from the commercial
departments get higher salaries and vice
versa
that depends on the country so you have
to think about what is more important
someone who knows about how to do things
or someone who knows about how to sell
things we will discuss it more at the
end now a question you have to ask
yourself is what happens if you are
fired at tomorrow
are you irreplaceable am I the only
person who knows the passwords Forex
people companies avoid this more and
more they cannot have the company
paralyzed if the only person who knows
the passwords falls ill for example a
great problem for the company that's why
they prevent this kind of situations of
course specialization is very important
but be careful because being too
specialized is sometimes dangerous if
you want to be the best hacker in the
world hacker but not a cyber criminal
let's underline this so if you want to
be the best hacker in the world you have
to spend your whole life doing intrusion
test but there are many different and
cool pen tests here we have people
specialized in networks in Wi-Fi
networks people who are ultra
specialized because they love what they
do and what they do is
spectacular but be careful because if
you are too specialized in one
department in the company you will never
be promoted or changed or you won't have
any different job opportunities that's
something you have to consider so as I
was saying what is more important being
a practitioner or being a seller sales
rep well in the technical part we have
the product development the development
of existing products to adapt them to
clients needs then there is also a part
of investigation at Google HP IBM etc we
have research centers in San Francisco
San Jose New York Switzerland there are
many places you can work so there are
many cool places you can go and develop
and research research teams are really
fun teams they were jeans to work they
have a lot of fun at work they it says
while they are working and if you take a
closer look at the IBM research team on
LinkedIn they don't have the real names
they have their hacker nicknames so it's
interesting they know a lot of things
and they add a lot of value to the
company then the integration if you are
in the technical field you can integrate
already bought end products for example
as I was saying before some clients
don't know how to use a software they
are interested in having so we make
things work and we put that into to be
up and running and then we have the
services professional services that is
bring me somebody tomorrow who can
perform a pen test in my company this is
the value that is provided by somebody
and somebody's knowledge rather than a
product well on the other hand we have
these sales worlds and it's all about
selling of course it's interesting as
well because it is measurable it's
interesting to ask this to your boss how
do you measure me how do I know what my
goals are what are my milestones what
goals do I need to achieve in order to
be promoted this is difficult in the
technical field but it's very easy in
the sales world if you need to sell a
hundred and you sell a hundred and
twenty you are uploaded and you only
sell 30 you are fired so they say there
are more career options in sales because
it's a very measurable area so what
happens if I'm not sure about what to do
well thanks to all these new
opportunities are coming up there is a
little bit of everything and here's when
we come to these new profiles for
example pre-sales
you can be a sales rep and a technician
as well here you may have a fixed salary
and then a varietal salary depending on
the amount you sell this is interesting
because there are many practitioners who
have a varietal salary and they have to
go to the clients and sell them things
then there is this very new position
this very new job called CSM and I
encouraged you to know more about it
because there are more and more
opportunities and this is called client
success manager it sounds a little bit
like nothing really important but it is
indeed have you ever heard of yes
IAS cell software as a service
this is a sales option where clients
software-as-a-service so instead of
buying a big equipment they pay you a
rent because they don't want to make
that upfront investment so they rent it
from you and you just provide a service
for example the company connects to our
sock and we notify the clients whenever
there's an alert so this SaaS thing is
very important and so is c sm c sm is
the manager that makes sure that the
client doesn't leave at the end of the
month because saas it is interesting but
it is a bit tricky because at the end of
the agreed period clients may just go
away and leave you don't have to go to
their place and get the equipment back
to your office etc in this case i don't
have to do anything like that they just
have to click a button so this is when
this profile comes into play this is
somebody with the technical profile but
who goes to the client and asked the
client why they want to leave they ask
about what their needs are and the
salesman this rep needs to be
specialized because if the client starts
asking technical questions they want to
be able to answer them CSM is a very
nice position is a very interesting
position because it combines sales and
development so if you are a CSM you
become a bridge between the client and
the developers for example if your
machines are in Israel if the clients
machines are in Israel you can tell the
developers
to change the parameters say that the
customer receives a pop-up box if you're
interested in a certain things to come
up with so I encourage you to to learn
more about this position and of course
the city oh I mean why not the chief
technology officer is the highest
position in the technology field and now
it's very interesting to decide where a
company is going in terms of technology
so this is the role the profile there's
guy reading the paper with the moustache
so this is how I started I started with
the development research integration and
service and then I worked as a CSM for
some time now I do all the time every
time I go to a customer I just told them
about what their vulnerabilities are and
I told them well if I were a hacker
I would attack you here and here so
that's how I can actively send them I
sell them products that may be
interesting for them so let's assume we
are at work now and here we face a lot
of dilemmas a lot of people work at
companies and they don't know what that
means what that in for example there are
many multinational corporations such as
IBM that give you a lot of money every
year to receive training in whatever
field you want 3d animations go ahead
for it these are very good benefits that
large corporations provide you this is
something that you need to ask for
example this is very common in
California in California this is the
other way around
if you go to California they
you come to my company because I'm going
to pay social insurance dentistry
insurance I'm going to invite you to
many events they have very different and
very many benefits for you and this is a
different mentality in California
coaching also in many large corporations
you can get a coach if you ask for one
at IBM for example we have technical
coaches and career coaches the first one
is someone you meet whenever you want
once a month or once every two weeks etc
and the one is about asking okay I want
to know more about IPS or about security
ticketing tools ever so there's
technical coach tells you what I've been
doing this for 30 years and this is how
you have to do it you meet with that
person that person takes care that you
learn more about that and they always
recommend that it is someone from a
different department than the one you
work and your boss cannot be your coach
because the car which is going to tell
you tell your boss it is time that you
promote or it's time that you get a pay
rise so the coach the the higher
position he or she has the better
because this person has a broader vision
of the company if it is the CEO for
example you can understand the pathway
that person followed in order to become
a city--a so it is very interesting this
is from my own experience when you're
talking to people who are at the very
top or who are close to retiring
they are usually nicer to you and they
are very eager to help youngsters so
don't hesitate to go to them and ask
them I want to be with you in the future
what do you have to do
then mentality and challenges there are
many in vase this is something that
needs to come from you you need to learn
all the time if you spent one or two
months without looking at Twitter or
keeping yourself updated there are
thousands of new products and
vulnerabilities every day therefore you
need to keep updated all the time and do
different things regarding events and
communities there are many events like
this one communities such as mundo haka
there are many options that I encourage
you to attend and the last part I would
like to tell you about is the
Entrepreneurship I'm going to tell you
about stuff that has happened to me in
my seven years as an entrepreneur and
things I would have liked to know when I
started first of all it is good to have
an idea
and develop it when you're at home and
you realize you have a good idea and you
want to develop that's great but you
need to set milestones and set fun dates
because I've seen people who've spent 10
years programming at tool well maybe the
tool is out of date or maybe it's time
to do something else and they go well
yeah maybe you're right because yeah now
it's time to do something different
because 10 years after that tool is not
going to be as as interesting as it was
10 years ago this is the the the case of
a friend of mine who started seven years
ago and who didn't realize that websites
were totally different now he knows that
he won't be able to sell his solution in
20 years time so be an entrepreneur that
is great but do it sensibly and set
yourselves short and midterm objectives
and now what if somebody else has the
same idea
and the former slides or or one of the
first slides gave you an idea of the
very many different things I have done
why because people have come to me
asking for help because instead spending
thousands of euros in creating a website
for you well instead of getting a
payment and getting paid for creating
and developing your entire website maybe
I can take in your company because there
are many ways of adding this
technological value to companies so you
may participate in a company in many
different ways for example I can create
your website and everything you sail I
take care of it so if somebody doesn't
have enough money to pay you to develop
an entire website well you can get a
share for every item they sell for
example 2% or something like that this
is but there are thousands of ideas that
you can use in order to participate in a
company what's important here well you
have to know that a company is like a
marriage legally speaking you sign the
paper
you have liability towards one another
and this is very important and I'm going
to tell you story in one of the
companies I used to have I'm not telling
you the name
we were several partners and someone
said ok we buy your company for this
amount of money well we said we don't
want to because this was like our baby
we don't want to get rid of it but one
of the partners said well I do want to
sell it so here's where the problem
starts
well according to the legal terms of
this is devided a continent to the
shares the percentage and at the end of
the day this is very sad in our case our
our fifth partner just vanished
disappeared if you leave the company and
you have a share of that company you
need to sign at the end of every month
and at the end of every quarter so we
had a lot of problems because this guy
leave or left and we couldn't afford him
leaving so well we went looking for him
we had a lot of drinks together trying
to convince him to convince him to sell
the shares to ask to the other partners
rather than disappearing because the
company's paralyzed if you leave if we
had signed a partner's agreement this
wouldn't have happened actually this guy
came back to the company and he is now
very happy working with us again that's
why I'm not saying the name but having
this partner's agreement is very
interesting because you define all the
conditions I know a guy who signed this
agreement this partner agreement with
his two sisters it was actually their
father who made them do it
why because you never know what can
happen
we start with 3,000 euros but what
happens if it's three million euros in
10 years time because when there is
money at stake there are always problems
and fall involved so you have to think
big in that Partners agreement you set
the conditions for example if you want
to go for a capital increase if I
provided 1000 euros but you provided or
100,000 that capital increase needs to
be proportional oh wise you're totally
in trouble if that is already set in the
partners agreement you are protected you
can set the conditions like you cannot
increase the capital by more than this
amount or capital increase cannot take
place if at least three partners don't
agree and many other conditions that you
can set I'm not telling you to do this
yourself there are lawyers who do that
so you can draft this kind of Partners
agreement which is maybe 15 or 20 pages
long because this is what we're going to
find at the end of the day we can sit at
our desk and wonder what are we doing
what are we going to do tomorrow what am
I going to do with my free time well
there are many interesting things that
have shown to you think outside the box
offer your company that disruptive
thinking saying can I visit this client
and prove them that I can hack them well
the company said yes and I got promoted
like that but if it didn't come from me
if that idea hadn't come from me I
wouldn't have gone this far because if I
had stayed all the time in my cave
working on my computer I would have
probably I wouldn't have been promoted
probably so I've told you about
technical profiles about sales profiles
and many more opportunities pen tests
are great but if you cannot explain the
customer why it is important to perform
those pen tests they won't buy them it's
important therefore to promote that
commercial side we have to think big
thick different we have a lot of
opportunities IOT the Internet of Things
cybersecurity many things
so I invite you to reflect think ahead
and I hope my advice is useful so I'll
be happy to answer any questions you may
have it was my pleasure to be here M I
will be around
you