gonna but good afternoon I'm going to
introduce myself
Miguel Correa I PhD students in
computing security and information by
the you see LM also security analyst in
memo and confounder of Connie's honey
SEC in today's workshop or talk I will
speak about bad the USB and ability to
introduce commands or payload by
keyboard impersonation whether Windows
or Mac the vulnerability is the USB HID
that is the human interface for devices
it was created by a Microsoft employee
and it was introduced to USB agency the
idea was to just plug and play to a
computer without looking for
sophisticated drives in the past
whenever you had to introduce a keyboard
you needed the right controller and it
was quite complicated today computers
acknowledge the keyboard without a
problem and they use mainly two
interfaces read both protocols this
interface does not need hid which we
usually use at the by a oh you don't
need anything installed in your device
to recognize the keyboard or the mouse
then we have report mode that is the
interface used by the us to acknowledge
the keyboard or some of the new
is some of the new features like turned
down the computer or reboot they have
some data funds in the USB that
communicated to the OS to provide the
necessary information if there is any
special typology we'll also add it to
the interface if the keyboard had
another tactile and you will have
another interface to that aim as you see
on too many sites there are hundreds of
devices with USB is that can be clearly
seen you go to the bank and you can see
all USB Sun protected they acted the
same about printers and that is very
often the case in hospitals in offices
in they do not realize how vulnerable
these can be in just in five seconds you
can end up having a total control over
the device those are the main
microcontrollers that we can use to do
about the USB the first is 80 mega 32 is
installed in Leonarda
is one of the first projects that
changed the firewall to create a bad USB
the second is 80 teeny is a more
economical version it has less memory
and it allowed more reduced pilot but is
very much used and the last one the
pison it's in
USBC bow or any other well-known brands
and he's very much used the flash memory
because his pen driver is defined by the
pen drive capacity 16 or 32 gigabytes
those are the best known models the
rubber ducky ducky is quite an expensive
the Leonarda was one of the first
devices and the ovipositor that in
addition to be a bad USB is the physical
key logger from phoenix company those
are the most economical versions
manufactured in China that we can find
in Internet the first you can see in
this light it does not have micro as a
d-cup that allow us to change the script
without a flash in the chip if we want
to change if we want to add new commands
with the keyboard we had to flash the
whole the chip again in the micro SD
Inlet this wouldn't be needed we might
just have to change the file what you
see in the lower part is rather simple
project which is adding Wi-Fi you can
always add Wi-Fi with a small FTP host
or you can upload the files were
interested in passwords in Windows or
wherever this is one of the latest
models and as I said before it because
the micro is the inlet from 8 to 10
euros that's the price now for
installing we have two repositories
we have a Stefan Crimson German security
analyst and Ernesto I don't know if you
know nestor he is very often in
Congress's he's given a very interesting
talk in Barcelona about hacking and they
both work quite well and I use her
Nestor's because it's closer to me is as
easy as to download Arduino IDE and
install the software I will do
demonstration now
[Music]
what about a fun distraction - Yamamoto
is our simple as this
Al Gore we've added the code that we
will compile our day microcontroller we
just have to add open and at the
firewall of the downloaded repository
and we press install there are different
things to be taken into account for this
process
as for example the library's Arduino
does not know that we have a Spanish
keyboard will be any and not only that
some other changes in the key and they
might have some others as Tomas so we
download the Puna library we'll have to
replace the main folder so that it
acknowledges the Spanish keyboard it all
depends on our objective whether if we
know there is no Spanish user then it
will be any other keyboard oh another
step is to select the device and to
simplify the use of this installation
without compiling having to compile
anything we can just add it using the
arduino system this is one of the most
simple scripts that we can enter we can
write in a notepad send the characters
chain and print
hola mundo or allow the world this
script system has a sub script system
created by high pi and it's very simple
it's got some similarities with other
programming systems but not too many in
C unbasic it governments with RAM and is
rather intuitive here we have a wonder
is more intrusive basically all commands
that will interact more with the system
will have to be directly in Power Cell
and that depends on our imagination as I
said usually we should introduce a delay
from 1 to 3 seconds
so that the computer has the chance the
hid to keep the communication so that it
knows that is keyboard we're talking
about here we see how simple it is to
deactivate Windows Defender that is the
protection system people have read many
comments in internet of people let's say
that you don't need antivirus that we
with Windows Defender is enough and this
is a way that just in five seconds you
can deactivate Windows Defender and then
what you want to add this is a small
script but you can go on with the rest
of the options here we have the mimic
art I don't know if you know it is a
small script that compiles all Windows
passwords in copy demo and here how easy
it is to download a file and executed in
five seconds we can execute any file in
a computer here in this website we have
different payloads rubber Ducky's the
main is this a file website it has many
many payloads for hundreds of users
Windows Linux we just have to change a
few commands for example when you please
oh you are says that is for Windows but
the same can be used for Mac did you
change the key and this would be some of
the systems protection systems
by companies or individuals we have
GData it was one of the first ones to
include this protection in their
security pack anti-virus and some other
uses and you have a warning with a
message that there is another keyboard
in the device and whether you want to
stop it or continue working with it then
we have the small script made in Python
by Miguel Arroyo there is a similar
system it detects the keyboard but you
have to execute the script beforehand
and now I'm going to do a small
demonstration of the rubber ducky
this is a smaller script a visual script
if you don't want to make it visual we
just have to introduce the commands to
access the website under file is
downloaded that you will see at the
desktop and this file is now this one
and we have just gave indications about
where to be installed we can change this
directory we can choose any other it
doesn't have to be just a file it can be
a web shell or what it will feel like
and if you want to make any concept test
or if you have any doubt you're welcome
this is more or less the main use of the
rubber duck in Tunisia la pregunta do
you have any questions so far
I didn't remove that do you have any
questions and please use the microphone
this was the presentation so that you
could see the dangers nobody is going to
get into your house and going to do this
when they can steal your computer
directly but at company's level or in
hospitals or in many other public places
they should be concerned of these days
to deactivate the USB not only by the
software but also by Hardware and they
should deactivate them by default if you
have no further questions
you