so we have two hours with you and I'm
looking forward to it I always say and I
said it in Twitter yesterday and when
they asked me where are you from I'm
from Bilbao I'm a fan of athletic that
bilbao's from from it but I was born
here in Santander my family are from
Quetta
we're from kappa my yard
we are from Santander so for me being
here it's like being home maybe if you
don't know me this is something that you
always repeat way everywhere you go but
I'm very happy and excited to be in
Santander because it's the first time I
can give a talk about a subject that I
just love blockchain and it is not just
looking for your applause but it's a
pride so we have two hours so yes two
hours of excitement today we'll speak
about blood chain and Bitcoin it's nine
four hundred yesterday was eleven fifty
five hundred it just in couple of hours
business changes so much I don't know
how many of you have bitcoins doesn't
matter no problem we can't see you in
the in the cameras you can't we can't
see you than in the room at least two
people yes six people for the one
dynamics and two other to steal money so
you'll be participating so we're trying
to explain several concepts about how
the blockchain technology works we see
some applications that are interesting
for us and the cyber security unit in
telefónica that we are we feel that
these are apps are attractive for
developing malware and of evil but these
technology offers other functionalities
that are good we need to know them so we
have to have them in mind especially
when we need to make analysis serve
blockchain and sweating Gers cat
this is a metaphor why we'll see that
yes we'd like to explain what is
blockchain why these systems that are
decentralized did appear with this
mental exercise in 1935 was created by
Erwin Schroedinger in this exercise
there was a cat inside a bunker with
powder so for an external agent and
looking at the bunker from outside
there's the same probability that this
powder blasts and kills the cat and in
the same probability that the cat can
survive but until you enter into the
bunker and you see what happens to the
cat that you realize what happens so the
cat is dead or or it has survived
because you introduced powder so it is
it's about curiosity that people have
what's happening inside here it's inside
a bunker but we deal with security and
we have all the tools to enter the
bunkers technology and blockchain in
particular was born because of society
thousands of years ago we delegated
responsibilities on governments
corporations accompanies or we'd evolved
our responsibility and in a way we have
decentralized
about responsibility because we don't
trust them fully so we have a free
software coming out from that what we
wanted to underline is that these
technologies and free software we we are
believers in free software this tries to
answer this opacity this big companies
we don't really know how they're they
operate with our data and our
information every software uses code
Charles Stallman and all the people
working in free software you know that
for freedoms to read Code Red Code study
the code modify the code editing it and
distributing the code and what are the
four freedoms I just can't remember now
so four freedoms are in software and
applications were what happens when this
is included in a connected system the
beginning of the 90s if you had internet
connection you were lucky but today
almost all of us are connected so the
solution to avoid this type of
decentralization problems or
opacification as' of a big companies is
something that we can solve with
blockchain let's see how blockchain
works imagine that Alice wants to send a
bit constable she'll make a transaction
and she'll sign it with her private key
she only knows her key sometimes she
doesn't know that a key so sometimes we
have to be careful with keys so the
information of this transaction signed
by her is notified to the rest of
network hubs and after the validation
one of their hubs will be at the block
to the new the new block to the
blockchain and blocks are not added in
[Music]
in a specific way
blocks are added ones one one after the
other it was it was started with
bitcoins nine nine nine of January then
the 8th of January 2009 that's when it
started
this big coin proposal started in 2008
it's a figure but we don't know if it's
a figure or a group of people or a
collective I don't know it's a group so
this started to be implemented in 2009
and chained in the blocks all the blocks
are
change that's why it's it's called
blockchain so if you change a Bitcoin
the sequence is changed and persistency
is will disappear so information is
replicated you know the hops of the
network and Bob can use the because that
he received and which were transferred
by Alice what does this imply all the
hops to come the full hops in the
Bitcoin network at the copy of the
accounting log of with all the
transactions that are being generated
throughout the history of this
blockchain this implies that in fact
what we can say it's an efficient
because all of them have the exact copy
could be 150 jjigae if we want to buy go
to put this and equipment it will have
to put one SSD with 150 Jigga it's too
much it's too much it's getting more and
more expensive if we only want bitcoins
if we want beacon ghost cache etc our
SSD will need to be terrors and terrors
of our capacity so we add a blog in the
blockchain and for this we need to do
proof of proof of work POWs this means
that you have to solve a mathematical
test if you are faster than others you
have more probabilities to add your blog
in the blockchain this mathematical
problem
in fact if we were all part of the
Bitcoin chain we don't really know who's
the next network hub who's the next who
is going to add a new block so there's
nobody that can say that I'm not going
to add this block you don't know who's
gonna do it after you it's random with
an algorithm and random algorithm that
we will introduce and maybe the next
block is not entering but the next after
next maybe it's someone who doesn't know
that his problems are going to be added
it's not about this accident you give it
away because there are incentives the
goal is to represent what this
blockchain is all about let's do an
exercise let's play a game we need
volunteers six volunteers for this
exercise and then there's an award as a
prize you're going to have to win a
prize please volunteers come up here
these six people have to play together
and pool in two groups with this for
this computational capacity the idea is
to mine so pool to foodtube is made of
three people pool one two people and
there is an isolated hub
fifteen euros from up here there's a
prize there's an award anybody we need
more people come up here we need six
people okay so we're going to team in
the following way a group of three
people
that's pool two so we'll look for a
solution if you know other other people
in the team another group of two people
another person will who will be alone
the isolated hub let's imagine that we
all have a computational capacity that
is standard it's more or less the same
so we are all clever
the team with more possibilities to add
the next block is the one who is
composed of three people because you're
three we are all you have the same
conversational capacity but we you are
three you have more possibilities to
find a solution to this mathematical
problem sometimes we played this game
and people didn't understand so pool two
is three people collaborating two others
will be the pool one Daniel and
Christian second pool the mining pool
not one and you are the isolated hub you
are alone you have less probabilities to
women sometimes the isolated hot winds
well maybe you can win also even though
you're only two or just one we have six
hops in our networks and you have to
show that we are half money we'll have
money so we're now looking at the money
but this address starting with 1 X 7 all
the Bitcoin addresses it starts with the
same letters it starts with 1 or 3 the
Bitcoin addresses in the main it and
test net starts with M or n so when we
see it this chain this long maybe it's a
Bitcoin address in this case what how
much money
0:07 16 pay little money it's about 15
euros 15 years
that's the money that's in there you can
use the point very market cup it's quite
a well-known website where you can see
follow the evolution of prices prices
how much a bitcoin is now
[Music]
$9,500 if the etherium its evolving its
oscillating this is real time you see
how much cost and the change rates
exchange rates at the beginning it was
just one euro one Bitcoin one euro and
we were here telling you stories but we
would have been rich the mathematical
exercise we have a ready and we'll see
the mathematical operation with very
simple mathematical exercise if you
discover the answer raise your hand and
you say it okay now tell me now and
suddenly we have to decide who adds the
next block problem an operation look for
a number that can be divided by 7 8 by 5
and which is greater than a thousand and
lower than 2000 please raise your hand
why 1400 well yeah that's correct
this number is can be divided by 7 and
by 5 this team has solved the problem
first so you have the priviledge plus
the big canoes are you going to win you
have the privilege to add the next block
to the blockchain with the 3 actions
that will be generated the next block
well once this one has been generated
there's another mathematical problem and
then we will see who wins and who puts
the next block next block there's
another mathematical problem to solve
and the problem in fact is not
multiplying 7 by 5 and see if it's
greater than a thousand or lower than in
two thousand it's to identify a hash
that starts me with twenty zeroes in has
the hashes has to have to start with a
twenty first digits and they have to be
zeros and as the conversational capacity
of the network increases six hundred of
sixty or six thousand you will have more
possibilities to identify identify in
the network a hash that starts with her
I don't know how many are zeros the has
generation we don't not know it until
it's generated so it is distributed so
congratulations
pool - yes pool pool - you're going to
win bitcoins do you have Bitcoin address
some of you have a Bitcoin address well
we'll explain how it works how we're
going to make this Bitcoin transfer
let's explain the system and how it
works and how we can we can transfer you
the money so we have a winner
don't leave because I have to give you
the price you have to wait until the end
of your talk so how are we going to
store this private key or this address
that we need to send to our colleague
it's called ET wallets it's a software
or hardware that saves this addresses or
private keys these private keys or
passwords indicate that it's our you
have to save the passwords private key
public key if we lose the private key
word private King we can't really show
that bitcoins are ours because they are
in our address but we have to
demonstrate that what happens sometimes
because we're not very good at that
because you don't give it the importance
of it deserves you get to get the first
your first bitcoins
you go to add pages and you click on
that and you have captures and you get
thousands of bitcoins or the sorry
Milly Bitcoin today is one dollar or ten
dollars you get Milly bitcoins you have
the Firefox you put it in your virtual
machine and you start winning bitcoins
so you started to mine and mine and mine
and you have segments of bitcoins and I
protected them in a wallets that I had
in my equipment in my PC away the
password that was very good so good that
I just just forgot about it and what
happens I don't know the password if I
don't know the key or the password I
used to protect the private key of my
bitcoins I don't I just can't get the
money out if you won't go to a bag one
you need a password to get the money I
can't use my money thirteen nine cents
were two to three dollars you can't
recover that because you had generated
it from your client you know in your in
your computer and my my he wallets were
encrypted and some other software do
that for you but the wallet what about
the wallet I am NOT I can't really look
for my password so my wallet is base64
this is a challenge that we used in
return in 2015 so we put it in base64
this is the the wallet you can paste bin
you can see it in paste bin you can you
see it in the YouTube image in the video
so you you download this space 64 is it
CTF with a real city F it's an e wallet
with encrypted piece and today if you
can decrypt it you can get this 39 cents
of Bitcoin and if you can do it while
you you you can buy us some beers if you
decrypt it
young crew let's imagine this is a
hundred thousand it's $45,000 it's a lot
of money if you can decipher it it's a
problem and we need to solve this
problem that I forgot my my password so
I cannot recover this because I can't
decode because I protected my private
keys that's a problem and I'm not the
only one one of the addresses that we
use well we have the random addresses in
a random way I'll show it to you now bit
address dot or this is a free software
project this is a repository it takes
the positions you see the green dots
these are like random seeds so I don't
know if there's a technology that takes
all the points these are seeds to
generate this a Bitcoin address that
starts with 1 7 etc and a private key
that's been generated from this green
points the seed 0 random points but you
don't need to have an address you can
add many addresses bit address you can
generate more and another one it starts
with 1 e em e 1q k you want
it's a rapid way of generating addresses
another type if I lose this maybe I
shall assist ASIC and she cannot control
that it's what happened to me so take
this into account this is public
the address is public I give it to the
people I want to be paid from and this
is the private part with private key
another type of a wallets the bring
wallets yeah put a keyword Cybercom 2017
Santander this is going to generate an
address and a private key in ruta to two
years ago we did this exercise to take a
lot of dictionaries and generate a lot
of addresses the greater number of
addresses so people had taken this
decision to do this type to have this
type of wallets but if you know the
world you can access to this private
keys and steal the money this is about
bad practice this is a bad practice
instead of using up serial random seed
we have been using a word and that's
full of problems that have their
advantage that I got can go anywhere and
without being a Bitcoin client I am
generating this address on the spot but
we did it in and wrote it and analyzed
four million words I can look for the
presentation password hello very
well-known words in dictionaries and the
number of transfer bitcoins to wallets
that were generated in this way was
around 20 or 19 bitcoins multiplied by
ten thousand it's not bad
three thousand dollars at the time it's
not usual some of them existed at the
time then we have the multi signature
wallets
these wallets have three addresses so
when you configure the addresses you can
choose how many addresses are necessary
or which address is necessary to move
the money to transfer the money and do
you unblock the private key that I was
going to move the money out of the
wallet this is what it starts with the
number three the normal addresses
started with one in Bitcoin and for what
it's generated in this way it's not the
original standard they start with a
number three maybe what is the type of
problem that this tries to solve this
type of wallets we can generate a wallet
with 20 public addresses if I have 20
and dresses that participate in two in
this wallet and I say no we I need at
least 15 of those to move the money to
transfer the money what's the problem
that this solves wait we can't hear what
they say in the room yes we need to you
to say it's in the microphone in a
company where capital is shared between
different people what happens is this
just in one address with one private key
I have the money of my company here in
this Bitcoin address with one private
key and we have two of us we have the
copy of the private key and then I go
away but I trust her I go to the weekend
and gender is the weekend she transfers
the capital of our company because she's
called the private key she transfers it
into her account and she says that it's
been stolen what do I do
I've been cheated so to solve this
problem
yes you can't go back you can't go back
you've done a transaction and you can't
go back you can't undo it there's no
backup unless yatha decided to give me
the give me the back on the money back
so with this solution if you we have two
addresses we can generate one multi
signature address is so requiring that
to sign to transfer the money we have to
sign to
we have our own private key and we need
to sign both of us need to sign for this
transfer this is typical as we can see
here this is not new about stealing
wallets it started in the beginning of
2015 there was malware that used to
steal these small files where the
private keys are stored in your computer
these files are not protected with a
private key and it's left like this any
malicious program a malware can find
that for you and they can steal it from
you if you haven't protected it with a
password or if they are protected with a
bat or a weak password and people are
now using this type of systems with this
type of currencies and there is a lot of
fighting and other types of problems two
years it wasn't for 2015 it was quite
rare was it was unfrequent we had this
it's the banking malware and there were
mmm
instead of banks it was domains and
there was malware directed to that type
of stealing it was it was attacking
exchange platforms and markets etc so
they were affecting platforms and the
wallet stealing malware is there out out
there you can sometimes install it by
defect and you can't see it and it will
stay still your keys and there is a
small file Jason
whether the data related to your wallet
if we don't protect it efficiently if I
was doing malware well it's easy to
steal there's a risk and then we have
another problem
the the more and more projects with
currencies with market cameras a
thousand room or more projects and one
of them is Bitcoin gold this is on the
26th of November we are on the 30th of
November today it was on it was last
Sunday was it a note that was published
the the source code that were published
which is a Bitcoin gold it's a new
crypto currency related to Bitcoin well
the hash of the finder was being
distributed with the official hash but
this file that was distributed for 14
hours
no there was four point five days it's
written here maybe there was a malware
inside that was stealing I was looking
for this type of files this problem is
now affecting cryptocurrencies and now
we spoke about mining incentives you
were contributing with your
computational capacity because you
wanted to win the game because they
don't work on will be new currencies to
be generated in Bitcoin and that when we
make a transfer money Bitcoin transfer
we don't put your Commission on top of
it but we want to include a commission
so that we can attract those miners so
that they can add that transactions or
they prefer my transactions so instead
of others so the creation of new
currencies we can see it in blocks dot
info what are the incentives are miners
with another transaction let's say the
concepts with theoretical concepts we
take a block the last one is starting
with by with four there are hundreds of
thousands of blocks in Bitcoin blocks
and this block was
I don't know if you remember it was a
transaction set no a set of transactions
was a biga were being added by a minor
and being added to the previous one here
is the result up here yes
and in this block well the reward what
is the reward for this block 12.5
bitcoins let's see it
every time we generate or we add a new
block the miners are giving you rewards
because you are increasing the
computational capacity because a lot of
Jigga's dedicated to that so the reward
what is they get paid with new newly
generated currencies and then each of
those transactions which are quite big
each of those transactions we can click
on one not just no not that one this one
this is a transaction where there is an
address you qhj that transfers money to
do 10 different direct addresses each of
these transactions here indicates an
amount for commission that i want to pay
the minor this commissions were just
cents now it's seven or eight dollars on
average that this is the the commission
some platforms have a tracking of his
commissions so when did this system
start well the first the first operation
that was registered in the blockchain
was blocked one corresponding to block
one and it was registered on a ninth
January 2009 there are no entries this
node address that is sending money to
another address these 50 bitcoins are
generated at the beginning when there
was a block added to the
blockchain miners received 50 bitcoins
that was the award
how many dollars a lot that's a lot then
we see another operation of a
transaction that is corresponds to the
currency generation that's another block
but then we see the normal transaction
it's the the one here 12 CB etc with 50
bitcoins and then this is the Miss money
is divided in ten bitcoins plus for 40
bitcoins that's 50 bitcoins so there are
two different transfers to two addresses
so this is the first transaction it was
money transfer a bitcoin transfer from
one address from one Bitcoin address to
another Bitcoin address until then don't
remember the number of blocks but but it
was mined on the 12th of January three
days later we can look for the number
until then all the blocks had all
transactions from Bitcoin to real money
so the money had to be entered into the
system it's not exactly how we did in
the exercise but they started to
distribute bitcoins this is a little bit
about what we said earlier you've seen
the first minting of the money it was
for 50 bitcoins that's what the mines
- got and every four years it's when
there's a new coffee that is mining
received half the money that they
received previously for minting the
money this is November 2012
it's almost every four years and it
really it's every 210 thousand blocks
that are added the reward is divided by
half so what we're seeing the
that in the end - are gonna find it
profitable to mine in this system
because of the mine minting the
Commission's they receive it is going to
be reduced by half every four years the
estimation in this graph is to 2040 21
40 and that's where work reached the
limit 2136
in blockchain info you can have a look
here at block two thousand two hundred
and ten thousand two hundred and ten
thousand that's block two hundred and
ten thousand it's getting a bit stuck
this is block two hundred and ten
thousand here you can see the block
reward is just 25 bitcoins if we put we
look for two hundred 9999 there
the reward is fifty it's difficult that
you you giving the same computational
capacity but just because you did it ten
minutes later you only gets half the
reward and that's a block from November
I think we're now not in 25 bitcoins
we've gone down it's not 12 and a half
bitcoins since about July 2016 so what's
gonna be the other operation which
perhaps compensates a - well the idea of
Commission's to carry out a transaction
they're gonna include a fee
if I was a minor and I wanted the
Commission's of all the transactions
that exist I'd probably want to get
there first I can get more money and the
example that we gave a couple of years
ago we had of a wallet which had an
address with a key word I can't remember
what the key word was now but there were
people within this system who were
monitoring these addresses with these
three words
maybe the key the key word is password
for example we saw that in certain
seconds of times there were three
addresses asking for the money that we
had that is three different people were
signing transactions to get the money
that could happen
three different people are doing it at
the same time so in this process when
you have to be quick as possible what
did one of the addresses do they said
okay I'll I'll increase the Commission
so that - give priority to their
transmission their transaction sorry I
suppose to the others what we wanted to
do is to sort of put out a bait there a
bait of money to see how many people
were out there it's a good example
because there were people out there
monitoring lots of these kinds of
accounts so proximate we've got an
account here how much - receiving at the
moment for minting new coins twelve and
a half bitcoins for minting and a 15%
Commission at the moment is around two
bitcoins so it's two bitcoins depending
upon the time if now we went to the next
having that is the next time the amount
for minting money is half then it would
be so - would then receive 6.25 bitcoins
let's leave the Commission as it was
let's just assume that the Commission's
are what they were but what does that
mean it means as having's continued the
Commission's side of thing is gonna be
increasingly important so the idea is
that - have sufficient incentive to
increase their computing ability and ask
for commissions
this is a typical supply and demand
graph on the x-axis we've got the space
for each forelock
we said that in each block you can
include certain number of transactions
and on access why the permissions that
you have to pay it's important what the
æther is saying because X represents the
space that you can include foot of
transactions every 10 minutes the
mathematical problem is on average
solved by each node in the network each
hub in it every ten minutes if it was a
lot quickly you'd add 24 zeros it isn't
a normal graph here we have something
that limits us which is the space in
each block today a Bitcoin has one
measure of space and at the moment this
system is becoming increasingly
important it may well be that now
initially in each bak block there was
two transactions but now as this system
is becoming increasingly popular more
transactions are being included in the
block space that lease that block is
being filled up so the balance point is
going up and the price of the
Commission's to pay is going up as the
block fills up the commission price goes
up so instead of getting a traditional
supply and demand curve as we've got a
quantity that that we can't go below
beyond then the increase in prices gets
gonna be a lot greater in 2012 people
thought oh you know bitcoins great case
you can save commission but now
commissions are around $8
for example we've tried it you can
sometimes put or 10 euros and you get
three years in commissions but I think a
year or so ago in a hackathon that we
organized we we presented this new
project and when we organized the demo
by the way we've been working 24 hours
all night preparing the product for the
demo we put the Commission's high so
that people could see that what we done
worked but in the end that was how it
looked and some people didn't understand
this project and the block chain didn't
show the transaction we thought it
didn't work we were a bit too greedy
with the Commission's no miner was
interest in the demo time to add our
transaction we just being too clear of
her own good if we apply this to real
life imagine a system in which bitcoins
used if I take 15 minutes for my
transaction to get to be priority and to
be confirmed they're gonna Bitcoin its
clocks up act every 10 minutes in other
currencies it can be every 2 seconds
every 5 minutes so that's what people
are playing with and the problem of the
size of blocks is represented on this
graph initially there were no
transactions because the system wasn't
well no nobody'd heard about it very
much but as time has gone by
people now do want to do Bitcoin
transactions and we've reached a point
in which the tire size of the block is
pull-up this is interesting because it's
got statistics in it
and you can see how in July 2016 January
2017 92 95 percent of the block was
filled it's what we've said previously
so the Commission's gets higher let's
look at Commission's and let's do
another game let's play another game
what we need now are at least three
people three people there's a price for
this as well and not only that it'll be
a price on a wallet on your mobile this
exercise that we told you about that
we'd put in a dress with some money and
we tried to get it to be robbed by third
parties we try to represent it yeah this
is the QR code which represents an
address where we've put some money don't
please show the slide yet because you'll
have another QR code which will be the
private password this is what you're
gonna have to do the exercise it
consists of we're gonna install an app
in your mobile those people that come up
here will do the exercise together if
somebody's got a different model is fine
you don't have to install this and what
you're gonna have to do is read this
private password import it and then
generate an another address and transfer
the money that appears in this address
that we've put up there on to your
personal address it sounds easy but
we're gonna do it with you so that you
can see it as you come up
I'll try to convince some people to come
out come on people
bula course I mean by couple there the
rest the people in the audience also can
I take part as well so let's just hope
nobody calls that there's a moment we
should be able to see what you can see
either what we're gonna do is the ice is
gonna do it if you don't know how to
install a wallet now's the time to do it
go to play store those of you they've
got an iPhone it's easy let's install it
let's install it there are other wallets
you don't have to use this bullet but
this is one let's install it's an
open-source software electro
installation we're going to open it and
the first thing we're going to do is
wait until they've got it as well it's a
different app for iPhone Jack's J a xx
it's a wallet electron is only for
Bitcoin but Jack's is another wallet
for other currencies Jed ax jxx anybody
else got there a couple of people have
raised their hands maybe to imports the
privates passwords you can have to skip
this bit I said to you earlier that's if
you've got a Bitcoin client normally
what you do is download the whole of the
block but do you didn't have to do that
now since the more recent version you
can just download to the to final gigas
of the block we can use light models you
can use jacks or bit Phoenix and
consults the information because for
example in your mobile you may not have
enough memory this is the way which
systems have of making it more
user-friendly
so the first thing we're going to do is
generate a standard wallet it's gonna be
your personal address and you're gonna
see yeah tha's on the screen
[Music]
and the axis now going to create a new
wallet using a seat so we click on
standard and this is how this works
d'void happening what happened before
you just have a wallet using a series of
words and there you can see all the
words up there
these works we have to copy them and
save them somewhere because we lose them
if the mobile it will drop it down the
toilet or if a train runs it over or if
it just breaks if we don't have those
keys these words we're not going to be
able to recover the bitcoins that we've
got in the wallet
[Music]
[Laughter]
see here what we're doing is forcing you
in the case of Jax it's not so difficult
you done
josè those of you that they want to use
Jax's j ax x in this case we've been
forced to use this different one at
different approaches yeah this is taking
a while
with this seat every time we need need a
new password it's gonna be generated
using all those words that are up there
[Music]
think brightest
so that instead of you just importing
these passwords there's another way you
can do it that's why we're doing it like
this now you're gonna be told yes it
coincides so next I had last you for a
PIN number yeah so create yourself a PIN
number
hide first making it difficult
Philippines I remember your PIN other is
gonna have the same problem and now we
keep the password so you're being
generated if we want to if the item
wants to charge us for this bottle she
can say to us okay I'll keep you this
bottle if you transfer to this address
one Bitcoin it's a cheap bottle so we'd
have to write down this address and then
transfer so well here we've got a whole
set of addresses and those have you got
the jacks app we'll see it differently
so what we gonna do now we're gonna show
you on the right the secret or private
care so stated to this bitcoin address
so you have to scan the QR code in to
import it there's probably a part in the
app which says import private keys
I'm trying to do it as well okay we're
gonna go back and you can see where we
are I'm going to show you now how to
import a QR code let's repeat and show
you how to do it again we'll open
electrum and you see all wallets are
similar to this is just to import keys
keys that are written in QR code there
you can see the three bullet points and
wallet and there we go we click on the
new wallet here we're gonna give the
wallet a name cyber camp in this case
and here you can see import Bitcoin and
address or private key you have to write
it in let's go back to the presentation
now so what we're gonna do now and there
you can see their private key anybody in
the public if you can import it before
you should be able to you got it and
anybody was looking at this the quickest
of the quick can get the money that's
associated with this private key and
take it into their wallet the quickest
one will be able to have control over
the money and as we're sharing this with
many people there can be many people who
are simultaneously taking the money in
theory you should have a QR reader
that's another option there are just
different examples what we'd want you to
see where this is that anybody now could
be taking the money that's in this
address they'll give them five more
seconds and let's see if there's any
transaction in plop chain dot info and
see if somebody's stolen it there you go
it's the person here that that did the
transfer look at your address is that
you it may well be you that is we've got
the transactions are unconfirmed but it
hasn't been added to the blockchain do
you have that address is that your
address 18 it may well be that it's you
yeah we transferred naught point naught
naught you want and it's ended up in
naught point naught naught 65 so almost
30% spawn in the Commissioner so what
we're trying to show you with this carry
on with exercise what we've done is
simultaneously and it may well be that
somebody else has carried out two or
three transactions of the same money and
they're trying to move the money all at
the same time now let's go back to this
slide we said that the size of the
blockchain and of the blocks it was too
much so the Bitcoin community says what
can we do if we are paying commissions
of five dollars this is not competitive
and people are going to use other crypto
currencies so we have to take a decision
and all the forks that are we seeing
here from this Bitcoin project
emerge so in these systems we have the
heart folks and the soft Forks part
Forks what are they a change of the
initial protocol there is a change in
which in the Bitcoin protocol until now
since 2009 to 2017 the bid going
community has had rules by consensus
socially accepted by all so from the
first hop to and block from one to end
they follow the same rules one mega for
your block for a block but then are the
people in the community saying well one
mega they pay $8 commission that's a lot
we have to enlarge the size of the block
from one mega to eight Megas for more
transactions and lower prices so the
Bitcoin system is in parallel we have
Bitcoin cash with a size of 8 mega
people decide to keep the philosophy of
1 mega per block following the original
protocol what most people do so the
Bitcoin part it's in yellow this is a
blockchain and another one these people
decide to enlarge the block size to 8
Megas so it's another blockchain so from
the new block chain there's new and
other projects emerging like Bitcoin
cult but what happens there's another
change in the rules communities says one
part of the Bitcoin community says the
problem is that control is in the hands
of minors they are in China all over the
place in many places they have a power
and it's not democratic because those
who have more computational capacity say
for all the transactions to be inserted
they have a power over economy people
say I'm going to invent my own algorithm
to go back to the philosophy the
original philosophy of sakamoto and it's
one person one vote and Bitcoin in gold
has been created in this case
it's the blue chain in this case those
we have bitcoins again that were bought
here on the Left they have the bitcoins
up on top
they have Bitcoin cash and they had one
Bitcoin gold the bitcoins that we've
seen in the wallet I had in 2012 and - -
that was a time with the original
blockchain you can spend it in the
general Bitcoin chain you could spend it
on a yellow you can spend this in the
green ones as Bitcoin cash and you can
spend it in the blue as Bitcoin gold but
I have three ways of spending the same
bitcoins but it doesn't mean that people
having the Bitcoin cash have at the same
time Bitcoin gold if I'm paid in Bitcoin
cash here and +4 I'll come after the
fork I can't spend it in normal bitcoins
anymore I'm in this this chain only some
situations when we assess the value of a
Bitcoin wallet in 2014 the worst that
was before the the fork but if you have
several chains you have different type
of types of bitcoins you can earn a lot
of money the other soft Forks do what
the old one the other ones were hard
folks these new functionalities that are
added to this system as an example of
soft Forks the multi signature wallets a
functionality that was created in 2013
which you need at least some people
belonging to this bullet to move your
money out it's a soft for support
because that should change in the
functionality this currency but it's a
change that is compatible with the hubs
backwards block chains are not totally
different in the previous case if one
hub generates a block of free Megas in
the Bitcoin blockchain it's going to be
accepted difficult it's one it's too
much it's more than one mega these are
soft thoughts new functionalities new
functionalities in this case multi
signature addresses didn't exist in the
concept of the original concert by
Nakamoto it came later on and there is a
map of currencies called web as my coins
but it's not being updated but it's
quite interesting here we see since 2008
these are the different implementations
we can see it from the beginning there's
an explanation of what this is
the first for this NMC namecoin
here you see subdivisions new
implementations of the original source
code code instead of ten Megas for ten
minutes it's very fine five minutes or
instead of using an algorithm for proof
of work they use another algorithm does
happening with lip going and the tree is
growing and it trees growing and grows
more and more so after this
implementation so there's a nuance to it
to each implementation hundred thousand
hundred one hundred six seventy seven so
a lot of them with his Forks this is
another website if you really like this
you want to monitor the price price of
each currency and how much it costs in
comparison with other currencies you can
use this this website to compare the
currencies rates so now it's going up
the price is going up after our talk an
hour ago it was less than that and here
we see a hundred we will yep view all
some of them have strange names I don't
want to point at anyone because maybe
you are the authors but you go down and
down how many are they how many a
thousand a thousand and three hundred
eighteen these are not all of them
we can have projects with more than this
tattoo coin that's another one what is
the philosophy of tatto poin I wonder
it's a reference point so we've spoken
about the mining costs it's not very
cost-effective it's not very profitable
to mine anymore for us in 2012 in BC it
could generate well PC like mine could
generate 20 million hash per second its
millions and millions that you need it
was a very small part of the
computational capacity of the network
now it's growing now this is has been
divided by 600,000 it's a Terra or
something figures are so big sizes are
so big so we normally in the mining was
done with graphic cards but now you have
ad ad hoc chips we have experts that
solve the mathematical problems in the
whole world so that energy consumption
is brutal
it's huge so these are statistics that
were published recently the countries
that spend spent less energy than the
energy needed for the Bitcoin network
159 regions or countries in the world
159 countries that consume less energy
annually then Bitcoin energy needs for
mining small countries well that's an
anecdote for two other cases are quite
significant so what would you do
well what about malicious age and you
they don't want to spend their energy so
instead I will develop malware so that
others mind instead of me on my behalf
this is started three six years ago with
this mal
so malware I in fact using you to mine
and your mining on behalf of them no
it's not only stealing credentials bank
accounts and pictures now they still the
capacity to compute your computational
capacity this is a report it was the
checkpoint report on the 13th of
November so the sixth family of malware
and you in the month used to mine or to
ask you to mine is on behalf of them so
the sixth malware family the most
prolific family of malware was related
to mining it's the checkpoint report how
do mine how to fine finance you can use
a small software with dot XA except him
mine in your computer well instead of
looking at ads you can see JavaScript
does a download upload it underneath Co
Co in hive or crypto loot calm they
offer a small library we can click on it
30% commission out of the computational
capacity that you generate with your
browser 30% commission goes to Coen hive
it stipulated in the project
let's have a look at it so javascript
minor do you trust it this is a
JavaScript code that is an embedded in
website with a high dot mem doc I'm not
an expert in JavaScript minor prototype
json.parse you can read it
something is happening there let's have
a look at the next one it's 12 percent
commission in my encrypt aleut do you
trust this code this is my way let's see
let's see if it's crushes again okay do
you trust this maybe it's optimized I'm
sure of that
this is optimized for an efficient
mining but I can't really see it I can't
debug it really it's more complex this
Cripe dilute and Cohen hive are projects
that you can see it they have their own
business model this is used in websites
with the underneath JavaScript you can
you use pirates bay or any websites of
this type why why it was open it was
mine in underneath or behind it
this is extended and you will have these
add-ons browser add-ons so these are the
websites that you're browsing and it's
identifying if there's a code so age
HTTP lock coin block well you have all
the signs appearing all this threats
that we're having this is no coin you
look in chrome store in Firefox you've
had this project also
did hop you see all the pages that are
being blocked no coin what was the first
transaction in the real world in Bitcoin
system
it was the famous pizza you know the
case in May 2010 a user over forum well
you may have an address and an account
this was a Bitcoin forum last lo was the
name of the user
he set a challenge saying if you bring
me to pizza now to my home I'm going to
offer you 10,000 bitcoins and he put the
photos of the pizza so somebody sends
him the pizza and now well on the 22nd
of May when this transaction was made
its the Bitcoin pizza day and there's a
Twitter account that it's monitoring the
price in dollars of what the.oh of what
this pizza would cost now it's 97
million but pizza so it's 96 million
dollars now that's the value of that
this is an anecdote it was originally
used as a payment system in order to
avoid the central control of banks we
can use your else here so that you know
you know them local bitcoins calm it's a
site where people who want to buy and
sell bitcoins can meet physically and
transfer those bitcoins but the platform
here will charge us a commission for
having these two people meet meeting
really and then coin map dough or here
coin map we haven't looked at this here
in Santander but there's one in Madrid
II if you want to buy you can choose
Spain online offers online offers I
can't see it
here here in person cash let's see do
the search in Spain to see what we can
do in Spain not many of them here in
Madrid another one in Valencia Alicante
Dania Benidorm here different profiles
different people they want to offer they
want to buy bitcoins they want to buy
bitcoins or they want to sell because
they meet in person and they can do that
the transfers they can exchange 10
bitcoins or 10 dollars and they can
exchange their currencies another
website coin mark coin map org coin map
on this website
it's a project with different bodies
upload the fact that they are Bitcoin
friendly like they do accept bitcoins or
other cryptocurrencies let's see the map
who accepts bitcoins see if there's
something in Santander the several shops
images here a couple of dots I don't
know if we can show them or not in some
of these dots they say they do accept
bitcoins in Madrid the quite a number
especially in the centre of the city
it depends on the adoption level then
you can see where you can spend your
bitcoins in physical shops and stores so
this is coin map and local bitcoins well
it's kind of different type of platforms
as you may know this can be used in the
blockchain to transfer money
we're the beacon system but sometimes
it's interesting to include information
for this a transaction is shown like
this is viewed like this but in 2013
there's a new functionality you can use
opera tour that's the code in Opera
return you can put 80 bytes of
information here an example very typical
Charlie Lowe's Haiti
it's the instead of storing or saving a
transfer you can add an exit instead of
making this monetary exchange you can
put 30 bytes that was before 2013 but it
was made official in with open-open
returned with 80 bytes that you can use
in the blockchain so on this is to
include information because we take
advantage of the Bitcoin blockchain it's
distributed in on many Internet nodes
that keep a copy that save a copy so if
we can embed some information some data
what people are thinking evil but also
it's for good for that at the same time
this in this platform we can see in real
time the information in the open return
this is omniscience it's a protocol that
it implements a new functionality with
open return ok return to save and store
some specific information these these
are data what they are sending
most of the projects now you're seeing
in the media for blockchain in most
using open return for the time stand of
the documents or sign in time we know
that it's going to be there because this
protocol is being developed to stay so
it's very difficult to find a single
failures failure point but now you have
a guarantee not only it's there you can
have it in other social media but it's
there and what is there is going to be
there in the future as long as Bitcoin
exists in the new projects for instance
notary registration this project is
quite similar proof of existence the URL
it's there
you only need to put a document there we
type it and then hash is associated to
that document it's at the identification
number of that document this hash will
would be embedded in the opere return
field and this is kept there so so you
have a book and this is mine book I can
generate a hash of this document of this
book it it enters the blockchain and can
always say that this is mine I can use
it and say this is in the blockchain
since the 30th of November 2017 at 7:30
and it's mine there's the registration
is there one bit is modified the next
blocks would have been different but at
least you can anchor that information
and guarantee it it's proof of existence
so
this could be used for that so before
the command and control the command and
control and the tools that you malware
uses to be in contact between the
victims and the administrator
well the infected notes that belong to a
network once it's centralized the
victims have no communication on this
system with our IRC chat so it was the
same in 28 2008 etc well you know our
see charts maybe it's not that common in
web servers and now this is happening in
social media but the specificity of
social media is that that will always be
there like this case was quite
well-known in the social media the the
malware author O's used the command and
cone control in Instagram see if they
find it in Instagram everything
disappears so if Instagram crashes and
it a this is the Britney Spears
profiling if it Instagram crashes it's
the end so Instagram is not going to
crash so I'm going to put comments on
the photos and be given by Britney
Spears and I'm gonna send with the
strange method which is quite difficult
to understand I'm gonna send the
information to which the victims have to
connect to find find command and control
so it wasn't the URL it there it's a
religious system with a comment it takes
the same the first character of each
word and generated the the bitly address
the Britney Spears address why because
he wanted to find a site that was very
very solid and they couldn't crash so
we've seen it in command and control but
also for social advertising of the ISIS
Islamic states I and we found an
extension that was distributing these
Isis propaganda to all the people that
could be radicalized and so they sought
the application in a toll moment they
knew what were the website sites they
had to consult to consume that
information the author of the propaganda
could manage the content of the
propaganda and there was a server
what would with that it was pointing to
the websites where the propaganda should
be present so if next one so if the
propaganda websites crashed and they had
to get a new website there was an
automatic notification the user is
transparent text the add-on was
installed already the add-on was there
we can see it now the add-on was this
had this code very strict stupid code it
doesn't work in Firefox quantum anymore
so on this service that was the number
where it's not available anymore but it
was updating the new address on which
the radicalized content was present so
there was a an updating of the websites
that you could see for a radicalized
propaganda so you can update it
automatically with this but if somebody
identifies that your users is seeing
this content are using this add-on
instead of throwing away the destination
pages you can throw away the central
failure point and the problem for
propaganda was the same they had a
single failure point that could be
controlled and blocked so this could be
optimum this could be optimized what
blockchain but no specific goal in
opinion if we think that English several
years we'll see use case of malware
samples that are anchoring
in this will change my ways and ensuring
itself that this content is going to
persist and it's going to lock it's
going to last so in the blockchain here
I can use it as a command and control
and the source code is there in github
you have it here this is the source code
it's a quite a simple project
requirement fine
Epis time that's all
yeah you have the small software for the
administrator here from two addresses
that are managed by the administrator
we're going to use the testy not to
spend any money and we're not going to
use bitcoins there so we put the
information that we want inside the OPI
return code and then the victim spot
here they would go to the code that we
have published they're going to download
download the transaction list and here
there's another example here let's see
it with an example so it's downloaded
you can do it also it's not just for
command and control you can anchor any
content we think that this is a
possibility with you didn't identify
this possibility we've looked for that
malware samples that try to avoid this
behavior we didn't find any maybe they
haven't been detected by big security
companies but we think that this is a
reality it might be happening already so
we go to the admin part admin and this
is a small file here it is
without pushing it's very simple with
console a first question choose the type
of network that you want you can choose
Bitcoin L it's going and the one we use
for tests is test net buy Bitcoin like
this you don't need money you don't need
real bitcoins you want to transfer any
information not the coins and it has to
be there for a certain time intro and
this the brain or other concept it's
mental wallet we're going to use this
mental wallet for simple operation in
this mental wallet Tosa Bergkamp saber
que saber Camp so have an address and
the private key it starts with M e step
test met by base Bitcoin starts with M
this is the code that represents the
private key test next yes 11 bitcoins in
the test net it's not real bitcoins we
don't want to spend that money and then
notepad dot eggsy now it's asking me
that address that is receiving the money
note by taxi the exit decimal chain and
what is the address you want to send the
money and then we want to anchor the
content there break and then don't need
to have another address
I can resend the money to myself who
don't need to have a new address I'm
generating another address with the same
key the same word have you want its
it's the same that's being generated
with a commission and this is the
transaction that is being signed
what is the aspect of this Bitcoin
transaction this this is a bacon
transaction you can push it with this
command chain with dot sock that's the
centralized service or we can ask the
program to push it alone so the push
option and this is going to follow the
same process
rain rain we choose the key word cyber
can do you have money yes we have money
no too bad
target it's the same use the same cyber
camp okay
Commission 10,000 right effect and
that's it it's pushed it's been
generated it's here
first now it could be a fake you are
showing it to me in the console go to
Cohen secret coin secret the test net
and here it is yeah it's notified to the
network and there's no information that
we want to anchor is there now there's a
Bitcoin address that has no note part
dot XE that has been anchored what are
we going to do the in the inverse
process this is the victims part it's
implemented in JavaScript because we
made a modification of the previous
add-on so that it could be used as DNS
resolution to where they are not on and
this is where the JavaScript okay we're
gonna run it we're on the test net let's
copy the address this address is the one
that was hacked in nee malware so we
copy and paste and if we've done it
properly what it'll do is it'll of
consults at the blockchain just to check
that it works we've got the notepad and
then what we'll do is try it again to
see if we can open the calculator let's
do it again
[Music]
the advantage is that the content that
we've anchored cannot be modified we're
always surprised that these solutions
don't exist yet we'll do it again
and this case we're pushing cyber camp
these are bitcoins in the test net but
there are services that you can get the
bitcoins to carry out your tests you
don't need to get real bitcoins now
we're going to transfer it to the same a
coin then we have to return to test net
you have to wait for a while it takes a
while because the hub may take a while a
few seconds to be notified let's go to
the victims you can imagine what's going
to happen now here you can use this for
example to keep command and control
here's the calculator that's sufficient
for us it but imagine that it was the
central server if the machine doesn't
work we'll get another one we can keep
changing it as a mechanism to avoid
censorship and if you're going to be
able to access the blockchain you can
use these kinds of platforms but these
kinds of platforms are limited to 80
bytes of information but there are other
options if you combine it with our
technology and the technology that's
using is ipfs it's another p2p Network
but what you can do is anchor where the
information is being stored here let's
imagine we want to anchor all of this
content and it's there's more than 80
bytes here it's just an example we've
got a pointer which is all this for this
address it's not a C bytes though and
you link to torrents and with this put
the point in the right place and what we
can do is unload it from platforms such
as IP FS o RG that's one option this you
can use to keep pictures if you can't
anchor the picture in the blockchain you
can have a pointer and this technology
has been used
he used in the 1st of October referendum
in Catalonia it was used to avoid
censorship he they were blocking access
to certain web sites of the government
and so what they did was link it to
other of these kinds these kinds of
places these things exist and we need to
know that they're within everybody's
reach and it's a solution that's
traceable other great things in namecoin
this was the first form of Bitcoin now I
can store 512 20 information guides and
there's an ad on what a browser ads on
namecoin name chain info is like a
Bitcoin info but it's just with name
chain our personal domain is calm but
here we can in the blockchain
here of name coin stored in this
structure for eyepiece if I sit say to
you and you see oh this is a bit and it
may be something in name coins and you
can see the information that unit and
the IP address that you need to
connector to get the information it's
just in a different format
you could have beat the whole block
chains of namecoin there another
interesting project is aetherium
etherium is another platform but it's
also a crypto currency and what makes it
different to Bitcoin is that you can D
anchor certain smart contracts little
programs that you can say o run when
this option is chosen or do this when
it's finished instead of storing
information they're little programs if
their programs you can sometimes
validate them incorrectly in this year
in Def Con there was a talk just on this
about security in aetherium they've been
at least two cases of smart contracts
which gone completely wrong and just to
show you a little bit about the
technology
with the Madrid passer match last year
we did a smart contract a we usually do
pool and letters instead of physically
having to put two euros yet to put two
euros it's a real us and one in a
theorems so it was like the normal
collector and whip-round and that was a
way of giving people the opportunity to
take part so they put the results in
there once the match had finished you
could pay people out and then we've
forecast the user could say to the
contract I think it's gonna be zero zero
three three so when the game finished
the administrator was the person that
had signed the contract said okay the
result was three three and then you pay
the winner automatically what the code
does is check whether results had been
typed in and whether the person that
type hidden' was the organizer
administrator because if he didn't if it
didn't do this check anybody could have
run the contract so we divided it up we
tried to see who'd won if there'd been
two winners we divided it between two
the three three
another interesting thing would have
been automatically to consult the web
and their projects now with Airlines
without a trying to use smart contracts
for example if you if the flight comes
in late you can automatically return the
money that their user actually has paid
for their flight there are lots of use
cases and with blockchain it's all
related to supply chains imagine what we
manufacture cars and each part of the
car goes through a different process and
for example I get a part and it's
perfectly fine
the aim is if you get a part that it's
got a defect in it you can find out
where it's where the chains failed so as
to be able to find out whether something
belongs to you or not that's digital
property ownership proof of existence
you anchor our hash to a document but if
you've got to anchor 1000 documents and
it's different they're all very powerful
and just anchoring a one has tacky you
can guarantee that a document
you do need a thousand transactions
there are startups that just do that
then smart contracts that we mentioned
before and provide security to digital
identity and the Internet of Things and
to finish the I SEOs initial coin
offerings have you ever heard of them
Aiko's is a new way of funding that many
organizers have found what they do they
print they have tokens distribute
amongst those who originally in the
project and they get economic advantage
so if the project is a good one and it
is attractive these people that invested
at the start gets us a profit imagine
that instead of using this kind of
project we want to fund people with wiki
starters and go to here you can do it of
having an intermediary some countries
concerned about this in China they're
very very concerned because here there's
not some many means of controlling that
actually what they say they're going to
do they actually do do and how people
are managing the money if in the real
world we have problems imagine if you
remove all the security measures and you
get into the digital world
so you have to be careful you have to be
very careful tiptoe around things and
let's go back to the metaphor that we
started the talk with it which is
Schrodinger's cat in this experiment if
you're outside the bunker the cats may
be alive and it may be dead what you
have to take away from this talk is that
sometimes you can try out all different
solutions that's just blockchain etc now
they're using blockchain for everything
but doesn't have to be used for
everything it's why what I mean is like
the cat doesn't have to be alive and at
the same time you always have to use
blockchain because if your project has
the characteristics that require
blockchain and if they're persistent
because information is replicated in all
the networks have traceability you know
where your project is at a given moment
in time information is that's a
tremendous integrity you can't go back
and change any of the bytes and that you
do away with intermediaries what you're
doing for example the smart contracts is
trying to do away with any kind of
intermediaries and if you don't have
these characteristics probably
blockchain isn't what you need that's a
conclusion we're trying to draw from
this we're not saying blockchain should
be used just for the sake of it but
rather blockchain because one of the
requisite requirements that are up there
are met we remember in a meeting people
started saying Oh
if you can't tell me why I shouldn't use
a CSV for this project maybe block the
Chinese at the solution maybe we're
getting we're making our lives too
complicated okay
I hope you enjoyed their presentation I
hope you've understood a little bit more
about the world of Bitcoin and
blockchain but if you have any questions
here we are to us answer them thank you
thank you
[Applause]
you