baiyoke availability Lemuria locally
good morning everybody I see that you
first arrived which is wonderful we know
that you've worked hard my entry is
going to be very very brief because you
want to give you the floor directly for
the presentations just some housekeeping
you know what teams there are we've made
it to Sunday we're going to be here from
10:00 to 12:00
from 10:00 to 12:00 it'd be in this room
then we will move over to the second
area so that you do the voting we will
also submit you an assessment form and
around 1:00 we will have the scores the
two will the closing ceremony will take
place at 2:00 that's when the awards
will be giving I like to congratulate
you all for your hard work for your
companionship
for your teamwork you have ten minutes
per team we have a timer so that you
don't lose track of time
if there are any questions from the jury
well we will raise your hand and take
the floor remember you have repository
needs to be ready I like to insist once
again and that it's very important that
you convey clear messages that you also
tell us about changes if there have been
changes as opposed to your initial
approach make sure you highlight that
during your presentation it's very
important that the remaining teams are
aware of those changes we as members of
the URI already now
when we finish we will move over to the
hackathon area we'll provide you with a
questionnaire let's talk about voting
system each team will vote to the best
three armed teams so three points will
be giving to the team you liked most two
teams - the one you liked second most
and then one point to the team that you
believe should rank a third and then at
12:30 you will have already voted
so from 10:00 to noon we'll be here from
noon to quarter past twelve you will be
voting and then you will have some free
time and the award ceremony will take
place at 2:00
as for the order of presentations this
is very important you need to bear this
in mind because you need to be ready
certainty will take the 4 first and we
have Alejandra with passaic Reeve and
then monster hack remember the scores of
milestone - yeah as you can see it's
very tight it's very tight now it's a
crucial time this is the asset test
don't get nervous because we're here to
learn from each other we are also
learning from you I hope you've learned
from us
members of the year as well and let the
force be with you
best of luck
[Music]
hola whenever you settlers
good morning everybody as you know my
name is Santiago I'm a member of masks
team the team that has been working on a
malware web scanner first of all I'd
like to share with you the contents of
my presentation the first part is
basically a copy of what I explained to
unday one regarding my objectives second
I'll explain my proposals of the members
of the jury thirdly I'll explain to you
what I've done in the end based on what
I said and what you said then I'll show
you a demo have brought a screenshot and
I also do a demo with my computer and
then I'll talk about some ideas for the
futures about things I'd like to try out
in the future based and my own ideas and
ideas from members of the audience
initially mask was going to be a malware
scanner that could search and/or clean
and if it could only search the idea
would be to be able to detect files with
infected code in order to to take the
file and report that to the user so that
he or she could manually eliminated and
the idea was that ideally the software
would automatically eliminate those
files and clean them and also identify
potential
I wanted to give it with the behavior of
some well-known software and that exists
in this view it's true that some
scanners are not able to detect a
viruses I wanted to work based on
different scenarios signatures etc and I
wanted my solution to be scalable
meaning that if someone was willing to
add a functionality he could program an
additional part and add it to my
software I wanted to be able to be
compatible with different content
administrators and I'll explain a bit
later what I've managed to do I wanted
to have a scalable architecture I also
talked about the need of protecting on
this side asking for the relations also
offer the user the possibility of
restoring the website ie restoring once
clean and the website and leave it as it
was originally because maybe cleaning
isn't appropriate or is excessive and I
wanted to use this signature so the
worst a malware program that I found
before coming here then that I thought
it would be interesting also for my tool
on day one the members of the jury
suggested that I would register
everything in the log give the user the
possibility of cleaning and adding
protection layer
because the it's true that it's
interesting to know what version we're
talking about and adding and short
another protection Larry then the
reservation option I've already covered
is and whenever there's cleaning done to
do an automatic backup because perhaps
the backup or the clean or rather the
cleaning is too aggressive and damage is
the website we can give the user to do
backup I can do a backup and then
manually work on the tools and do things
that the tool alone cannot do then
restore this side and they also
suggested that the have could be
uploaded to PI P to a dog image and
that's something that I did this malware
scanner searchers cleans automatically
some Moberg I've focused on WordPress
and I've also added support for some
content administrators I've used clean
isolations and I've compared them with
previous versions I work with o
westbound malware signature and this is
easily extendable because I've organized
it in such a way that it's easy to add
support for different the content
administrators it also cleans the
malware and just back of the user can do
this everything is duly registered and
long some I've done some cleaning of the
website as I do the cleaning of the file
and I've included the option of
monitoring the website so that if there
are any changes and the website that is
duly registered and along and now I like
to I'll show you a demo of this tool
there you can see the command line i've
prepared i've prepared a series of site
websites here they are this is a custom
site that doesn't belong to any known
well-known content administrator have
also have our group side in a wordpress
and I've reduced this size because it
was originally very big and since it has
several magus it would take too much
time and I've introduced deliberately
some malware files that I detected with
a wisp and now let's test around the
scanner to see how it works first thing
that I'm going to do for the sake of
time I student run a full cleaning up
WordPress file
I've used the command to clean the
website on now I'll scan it and I'll
also do a backup as you will see first
thing it does is to upload the signature
scenario we do this with the OS project
/ - Navidad octave Allah
Molly
in percentage well you see another thing
we turn it out I see so we're going to
be generous he was the first to take the
floor but please make sure that you have
everything 100% ready okay we're going
to give you two extra minutes okay
thanks for that as for connections of
course the scanner downloads
[Music]
administrator and the version searches
for malware and detects potentially
malicious files that are not going side
with a theme version so there's
suspicious files they are compared and
cleaned and we also anonymize the site
log file is generated that I'll show you
now reflects all the info of eliminated
files and the backup will be generated
as well as well as additional info on
the cleaning process
[Music]
well there you can see on the back up of
the website I've selected
if there's a real feature locking this
is the log file so to say there we have
the suspicious or malware infected files
I'd also like to show you the monitoring
option that I implemented yesterday so
that you can see how we can scan and
monitor a website so that all changes in
the website armed and silly reported
so there we have the monitoring process
the details her data of the monitoring
process are registered in the log and
appear on screen I'll show you this now
a for example file is created this is
reported not a fun and it's registered
in the log with the date and hours so
that I know when that has happened I
will know whether it's smaller whether
it's romantic my times out well that's
the end of my presentation I'm afraid
I'm sorry about those connectivity
issues and you have any questions face
with me no questions no in the sea in
the Kibo this hobby skill I said if you
know you're the team that will take them
for after the next speaker please get
ready sandy has burgundy eyes
congratulations Santi and it's true that
so is hard to be the first and to face
unforeseen events those that take the
four afterwards learn from these
mistakes so please make sure you're
ready you've got everything perfectly
prepared and Santi is on his loan if
you're several members of the team
please make sure that the tasks of rules
are delivers distributed everything
ready please and now it's gone
let's move on to the next presentation
by alejandro
malee Tenace but i referencia but i get
for your reference for the sake of
clarity we have a timer you have ten
minutes and we will draw your attention
when you have five minutes remaining
I see so you know good morning everybody
my name is Alejandro and I'm here to
present my project I'm going to show you
a demo directly and at the end of the
demo I'll show you a file with a speed
test because that was the number one for
my head with this software we boot the
system with no parameter as you can see
there you have the wizard the support
window
the document align is that which is most
important the different options you've
got to make a request to the sufferer
with this program and this demo we're
going to generate a hash of an existing
file that is cold 64k so you can see it
and you'll understand now the speed it
can reach we introduced the document
line we introduce a parameter for it to
store the file inside the hash of this
demo and then we execute it we run it
this takes around 10 seconds yesterday I
discovered that the Windows version is a
bit faster than the Linux version which
was somehow surprised
this is the hash that is generator that
is stored in a file
okay I'll interrupt this here because
this half flow data can take home some
time and the hash has been stored in
this file
once old texts line 64,000 characters to
check and verify the hash what we do is
view the command line and then we select
the compare function
if you have time
you can treat your adapter to a coffee
that was the joke as you can see the
hash has stored the data that they meet
our the name of it tells us that we have
a file stored and the check zone of the
file this means that the original file
can now be changed a flame directly from
the hash because it's installed inside
we can therefore extract the stored hash
I'll get in the middle of the stables
here we have the two files this is the
one generated from the hash the one
that's stored so he have the comparison
between the two files
the comparative corrector you want to
say there you can see everything's
correct and now to complete this I have
to say that I didn't have time to
prepare a presentation but here you have
a comparison oh the speed tests that
I've carried out over the night these
tests will be improved when I'm able to
develop a more efficient compiler
because when the character chains are
very long I'm afraid this software is
not as efficient that's it on my site
thanks very much and good luck everybody
Alejandro just a question
this allows you to have hashes from
messages from a text chain as from a
file yes I didn't say it in the demo but
it does allow a messages a chain of
messages on a file have you
differentiate the settings to specify no
it is in automatic mode what happened a
few days ago is that the program takes
the file name by default even and this
is not a failure but a feature is the
files name by default to open up the
file any other question thank you so
much for your attention
[Applause]
this is here
[Music]
we have created a library that was
planned to implement different functions
based on the Shasha algorithm we've also
thought about implementing a is it was
quite complex so it was just a project
here you have the files is files were
the majority of the functions work
correctly but the problem is to
communicate them the idea was an
implementation that could allow
pseudo-random number creation starting
with a seed that requires some security
so that any other random number
generators they also require a seed with
a minimum level of entropy but the
advantage of our implementation compared
to thus devdas random or use a
[Music]
transmitter in an electronic system
receiving electromagnetic fluctuations
from the atmosphere the advantage of our
system is that is faster Anita provides
the same degree of security the
objective and this has already been
implemented a new Krypton algorithm ah
this is the numbers generator as I
showed in the first presentation we just
need to set acid through this argument
in the context this is a ram context and
it's a structure that contains the
possibility to introduce acid 32 bytes
and announce over 12 bytes so we can get
a siddha 44 bytes which is very
different from the 32 bytes seeds used
by random and LS random the encryption
encryption algorithm here we have the
the encryption algorithm and here the
encryption one we just introduced the
passwords the none the length of the
message and a pointer sign alene where
the encrypted message is going to be
introduced this encrypted message will
have the same length as the message in
blank text but we have also implemented
a parser API this is a client-server
scheme that allows the customer to
connect to the server and through a
secure connection to execute different
commands this is the demo where we
implemented what did you requested
to compile the server in order to
compile the server we can select the
compiled all dot C files of the project
and through a macro with the argument -
D to define the macro we create a macro
server and it generates the server we
compile them and we get the server is an
execute that is not too heavy 23
kilobytes is not too heavy and it allows
information about the port and the
client is the same the compiling process
the same as with the server but the
macro to be defined his macro client
will compile them and when you execute
it
he should indicate the host it allows
DNS and the port through the argument
you can indicate a file to host the case
as it was requested by the URI we can do
it with a server but we don't have time
to show how it works and here we have a
demo and we see
that they are connected we can see in
detail this is the freeway of handshake
based on DCP handshake in the
communication protocol of our library we
include two headers I'm going to open
this in a new window so that everything
is clear to Heather but which is the
header XD and then he sent two nouns in
order to avoid tolki effect if both ends
communicate simultaneously the
communication is interrupted we use
different keys so that each of the ends
use different keys does flow of
different case generated so that they
don't share them and if two messages are
sent as simultaneous lis they can
process it without using the same key or
password for the message the server
parcel that is implemented here
that is parser parser function is very
simple you just have to compare the
received text m in this case with a
chain and you execute the necessary
commands as they are indicated here this
function send msg or receive je sent and
received message we allowed the
communication through the created tunnel
when will receive SD command its sensory
tunnel or if we get WS is RTI and if the
command does not coincide with and non
received command so we get F G H and the
server also shows a log that can be that
can redirect a file and the same with
the three potential or possible commands
we can see in the worse act that any of
the requests in plain text it will be
great to be able to speak about the
whole protocol but there is not enough
time is a rather complex protocol but
I'm running out of time so this is the
end of my presentation thank you very
much
I have a question they'd be directional
part have you implemented it yes now in
the code there is a different background
or context for keys generation server
and client have different passwords
generation relaxant breathe this is not
a test
I just like to see it if you can show
the handshake part whether it goes one
direction or the other the server works
as any other server the main gates the
settings about the port
the rest is optional the file where the
key will be read and the process listen
if the user has opened up a connection
or the client disconnect the process
also disconnects and then we have the
while loop if we get a connection we do
a fork that will execute the function
process request so it allows different
client connections
here you have the function process
request we set the context for the
creation of random numbers in handshake
we do it to generate nouns if we have a
specified file we open up this one and
instead of using the prefixed one in
compilation in the macros defined in the
file as dot page we were in server and
then we call the handshake function that
is defined in the file as dot C this
config function just make an exchange of
nouns and to check each message we do a
Mac H Mac we because cha-cha is a harsh
in itself and touch of three was a house
function but we didn't have time we
haven't slept all night because we were
the struggling with them a is and when
everything is set to check the baby keys
are correct there's a challenge where
if you scroll down you have the function
here of the client handshake this is the
one that the client executes to execute
the handshake with a server so the
client generates an ounce and cents it
first to the feather then sends
different by mentioned the beginning of
the session with our protocol and then
this non CE Center distance is used to
encrypt messages messages will be
encrypted using s nonce to break the
terminus and the server will generate to
generate its keys it will get the nouns
used by the client and is going to use
it to generate the renounce the cedar is
defensive the same passwords or keys
will not be generated through those
functions and then we check that the
password is correct thank you thank you
[Applause]
to get up on the people
I'm gonna go
yeah
I'm ready okay we are the members of the
project Harvey Unchained
you know us already and I'm going to
introduce the contents that will be the
first item the starting point of the
project as we explained the first day we
will speak about the milestones that we
try to achieve during the context the
final project based on all suggestions
the problems and future improvements the
starting point of the project as we said
the first day was that we had Twitter
with very first monitoring of Twitter
profile using the official API and we
had a great deal of information that was
then realized in a file the idea was to
implement it in our platform Alvaro
will introduce what is the final project
once we introduced Twitter the rest of
the social media as one said we started
with Twitter and we wanted to add at
least Instagram a little bit of Facebook
and also Internet the milestones here in
the context this is what we've been
working on the last few days in
Instagram we got the basic profile
information and the latest pictures
published and the main data about
comments and likes then we could get a
location we wanted to get location about
the picture but we didn't have time
about Facebook we selected the friends
from a profile the latest posts
information from the world everything
that is mentioned and then basic profile
information with the world live about
Twitter monitor all information from a
target is tracked or publication banners
images and about past vini we aromatize
search using search and we've also used
I feeI from past event to get data all
of this he's been integrated in a
dashboard to you and enhance the analyst
the viewing of the information in a
simple and clear way even though they
may not have a clear technical knowledge
they may understand it and now we will
speak about each of the social media as
you can see the project has been modular
we have been developing different parts
I was responsible for Twitter this is
all the information from the profiles
what we thought it was most important is
general information that allow us to
view it in a nice way in the platform
once this was a structure we just
inserted it in a database and then to
the platform visually speaking I will
show a video about the platform but this
is just a screenshot of a Twitter and
those are the registers latest tweets
the activity and whether I found
tweeting from different locations this
is also seen here now my colleague
Alvaro will introduce the part related
to Instagram
in Sangram on twitter the number of
follow information is the number of
followers those that are followed and
the latest images comments and likes
which photograph and we could expand it
to specific comments of each picture
location etc and now we're going to move
to Facebook running out of time in
facebook basic information user
information the latest posts in the
world and all the friends this is a
small demo of the script that executes
another together all the friends will
use the system to automatically task and
recognize an image so that it works in
any laptop device depending on the pixel
and we can substitute the manual work to
the analyst so the script does
everything because this is the mobile
version is to include all the friends
from a user and once is finished this
part is executed it gets information
about all difference in the URL and the
information is into a file that can be
uploaded
[Music]
the dashboard the we have three ways of
functioning biography posts on friends
this is information about the latest
post from the target and now information
about the biography we have implemented
three methods so far but this is a
scalpel from Facebook through scrapping
we can use and get all information we
need and it's been totally random and
this person is not my former girlfriend
and this is the file with information
from all friends that then goes through
Python to the database
I will pick up the paste bin as my
colleague said we've been use insert is
asserted that the searches in Google and
open source and paste bin we might have
the keywords of the target that we will
introduce to the database related to
each user and that depend on our
interest once the analysis is carried
out which show the results of the admin
here we have found 313 posts then we
have the things to passive in and the
URL in Google here oh this is a an
example of the script we start off with
two keywords admin and hacker we will
get all the paste bins the new URL for
each keyword once we do this there will
be as lead after searching for all
keywords then we dynamically introduce
new two keywords and we start the
process again this is an automatic
process that is running in the server
and as we introduce new keywords in the
database they are automatically analyzed
and now not just a demo we have prepare
a video of the dashboard this is their
index with our objectives the keywords
users then forma for the new target it
will be user data and the social media
we're going to monitor as we see in
example twitter facebook instagram and
is a scalable to any platform then we
have the current targets that are
already in and actions to view more
about the profile here we could get in a
chess pacific profile the information we
have in facebook is a small facebook
biography latest posts and my friends
section
now Twitter to the description picture
the banner followers for you to its
latest do its recent activity and a
small timeline that is although is not
implemented yet that's a way would look
like the same about the Instagram we
have added bottom do launch the scripts
in an automatic mode in Twitter the
number of tweets whether we won't do
monitor it on an ongoing basis that are
still pending to be implemented but it
would just be a matter of launching the
script from PHP and then to add keywords
as cyber camp and we can see their
results I know that we are behind the
ten minutes but the api's didn't bring
enough information tools integration was
more complex than we thought especially
Facebook we just had two days so it was
not time enough to implement everything
and the solutions proposed by our peers
took some time and we had to implement
it as feature improvements is to
integrate the platform in OVA local this
is one of their recommendations by the
jury and we think that is rather
interesting to integrate new platforms
as you can see on the screen to improve
Facebook data extraction and updating
and eliminating information in it
dynamic manner thank you very much sorry
for going a little bit too beyond the
time if you have any questions now dan
is going to ask something just to look
go to ask for something ready to the
goat but we don't have to do it now you
can talk to Danny
actually means you know Jimmy
CICS should look like a man tell you I
don't know
Oh Yolo - a todos somos ladyboy hello
good morning we're here to talk to you
about the results of the Droid Sentinel
application but it's the main goal of
our tool to decide a tool that's able to
determine whether our device is being
part of distributed denial of service
attack we want to introduce pattern
recognizing and machine learning also
identify denial of service attacks that
are more and more common and we want to
promote the cooperation of the community
we want to create an Corps that can be
able to detect whether a device is being
part about an hour service attack we've
selected Android and a mobile phone but
we can do it with virtually everything
what were the challenges what do we know
when we began monitoring techniques on
top decision-making and prevention
self-organization of networks and
taxonomies of denial of service and very
relationship with botnets what part did
we encounter during the deployment of
this outgoing traffic and us as we come
in from a model in which we're at the
center of a network and we analyze all
the traffic but in this case we're only
analyzing the outgoing traffic of a
device and this is very ominous because
we use the same ten or fifteen after
have very similar in constant traffic
second analysis of non stationary data
what is this about the data from the
data center as we worked in their past
our stationary are more or less
recognizable have a series of patterns
but not in this case maybe you have your
mobile phone and rest mode or you don't
load an app and you and play streaming
there are many peaks and it's very hard
to identify patterns and then Glenn or
Glenn or granularity what does this
refer to our series
are sometimes not too big or our
algorithms rather require very long in
series that's what makes predictions
more accurate since this is a hackathon
and we had a time restraint we had to go
for a more restricted time series how do
we face these challenges and above the
app first analysis of outgoing traffic
both legitimate and malicious second
unexpected behavior third study of only
Authority or randomness through an
entropy and fourth calibration and fifth
measurement and points three four and
five is where we find more innovation in
our projects ie the core of our project
that were in that part where most of the
research lies in the first part we need
to determine whether it's malicious or
legitimate traffic based on the chair
we've finally gone for this approach to
determine whether the packages are
legitimate or malicious second detection
of unexpected behavior to do so we based
ourselves on three pieces of info on
packages the number of flows the average
and maximum number of packages and third
the size of packages we don't work
directly on this we use metric entropy
entropy measures the level of dispersion
of data the probability or likeness of
dispersion is a dispersion of data we've
used to descend
Ricky's entropy but as we used it we
understood that there are different
options and we finally end X an answer
entropy and we thought that this was the
best option calibration Y calibration of
algorithms why
singing a generic algorithm we're
talking about non-stationary data there
are no patters are very few feathers
between the observations this forces us
to calibrate and reset them each time
differently and to adapt ourselves to
the time series that's why we use
genetic algorithm that simulates the
evolution of the species ie natural
selection what it does in a semo's
cheese and creates a population the end
population which would be the optimum
population each chromosome represents a
possible configuration of an algorithm
so we're looking for the optimal
configuration or setting for the
algorithm and to this and we use smarter
which is a measure that helps us know
which of the chromosomes are better and
then algorithms we've had a lot of work
to do we didn't want to limit ourselves
to one sole our goal is in rhythm we
work with five different algorithms and
we use genetic algorithms for each
calibrated them tested them the time
series vary a great deal so we wanted to
choose the algorithm that best responded
to the time series and we went for the
triple smooth exponential algorithm and
the decision criteria and why do how do
we know whether they have been anomalies
or not well adapted to thresholds what
are interpretive fish
these are margins where we expect the
prediction to be to the right and it's a
bit hard to see we have an explanation
The Times uses the blue line and the red
and green line represent the adaptive
threshold upper and low and we see that
generally we're within thresholds but at
a particular moment in time we go beyond
their thresholds and it is here where
our tool comes into play and says there
is a numbness traffic there's something
there and we are reported about a
potential TOS let's move on to the demo
to this end we've developed our app
we've used an Android emulator it's
running already for the sake of time
first thing it's take observations or
make observation needs to feed itself so
it's going to take 20 observations to be
able to start to predict this parameter
as many others it can be customized here
we've introduced only four because
didn't make much sense to introduce more
and for an average user and we
introduced 20 or 30 because that's
possible it would be perhaps too
overwhelming so this is the interface
and the idea is to implement advanced
options for advanced users so that
instead of maybe four you can have 20
and this would have users and developers
have move on and know what they need to
focus on so what are we going to see
with this demo well too
the left you have just a lot a lock so
that you see that it is executing vm and
now it's going to start to predict we're
going to start to see prediction values
they were already all in three and one
normalized entropy as you will see and
we're going to see how it generates
predictions and what we're going to do
is use Loy 2 which is a tool that you
probably know in order to generate a do
s attack okay we're not going to crush
any website and we're going to see takes
some time because it's making
observation but soon we'll see how our
report is going to be issued to tell us
that we may be subject to distributed
TOS here we have 24 this is the value of
24 and now we're going to activate our
tool we're going to introduce whatever
website and we're going to see how this
works
good now we're going to launch the
attack it's starting it's not dangerous
dangerous we're not going to crash the
website see how we have the reporters to
be notified and we've just been warned
that there has been an anomalous change
in the time series and therefore it's
possible that we're being part of the OS
attack and conclusions core
functionalities were able to have a core
that it takes the OS attacks work but
your predictions using genetic
algorithms and entropy
second test scenario as we have seen and
validation of the proposal we were able
to do or satisfy our objectives future
work optimization of code to make it
more efficient scalability as who are
saying this has been done for mobile
phones but are ideas that can be used
for whatever IOT device and computers
etc updating of SDK you mentioned this
is an issue of dating that would take us
some time we decided to leave this for
the future and the AMF report we talked
about possibility of issuing a report
that could be sent so that the community
could have access to that and we set a
standard an ID MF and we implemented it
is still not uploaded and that's work
for the future thank you
[Applause]
Widow
nobody middle city see that I like to
congratulate you for the work you've
done the research s being wonderful
you've explained this very well just a
technical question when you detect
threshold to you enter that value to
feed in the algorithm so that it can
learn from that and maybe it maths real
attacked
yes that's correct when we see that
there's a peak value when the time
series advances that value is going to
be detected and all our algorithm is
going to reuse it for the next
prediction so yes as for the threshold
threshold is adaptive so which each new
iteration is modified way with each new
observation the thresholds are adapted
my kid
good morning we are new products our
crew and we're here to explain to you
our experience with our tool mall Trail
let's remind you what this is about it's
a very simple architecture sensor
customer the sensor will be in traffic
concentration point we'll send it to the
server and the server will be a website
where you can see all this we've wanted
to add a new sensor our process sensor
that is executed meet hot so that we can
correlate the malicious sensor detected
by this traffic sensor and process
sensors so what Montreal detects are and
also a small button that says kill and
that kills it well we had here was the
secure communication between the host
and the server because we're talking
about a package that can kill whatever
process so you need to secure this and
we've talked with it just such a team
and we thought about implementing their
solution they checked Python which is
what we work with and we checked their
upon fashion LEDs and in the end we
didn't implement it because we had would
have to call our Python code from their
PC and
and what we saw was that they could get
a package and reinjected as many times
as possible and we could kill PIB as
many times as possible and that is
dangerous so unfortunately Indian we had
to use SSL that classical architecture
there's an authentication by the
customer and by the server with
certificates the main problem to detect
a PID is related to packages this seems
simple but it turned out being very
complicated but the most difficult is
that you need to treat with very low
level ie in the case of line ups the
currently in the case of the next we
have the audit framework that has some
rules for each call to the system so we
introduced a rule for a socket connect
that we have our PID we long at all and
windows has some more complicated net
events session nobody understands what
this is about it's something that has to
do with a PowerShell you were laughing
the other day but it's really
complicated it's really tough it's just
this power or shell and audit framework
it's a bit Messier man Mac there's
something funny they introduced the data
we need regarding the packages and this
isn't release to the Internet
but that's basically it and we can read
it from there and we see the same
behavior and last a general one Python
Python so you can plug in a Python and
use these of plugging and if you ask us
who sent this we can check our table
maybe the socket is open we can say this
if it the circuit is closed we won't be
able to know that and that's it on my
side now we will show you the demo my
colleague Carlos will be in charge of
explaining the Deemer to you let's move
on to the demo first thing I'm going to
do is explain to you what we're going to
do this team uh so that you don't get
lost we're going to test three different
architecture and we're going to capture
three types of packages the three main
protocols UDP TCP will know you can see
the three and these three types of
protocols although the packages can be
detected in the process sensor of linux
and mac and windows however for a sake
of time we're going to capture on ICMP
and mac UDP and linux and tcp and
windows ok we're going to use three
different architects within mac we will
be executing both the server and this
sensor and the process sensor from mac
within the Mac machine we will have a
virtual Linux machine the hoos packages
will always go through mac interfaces
and we'll use the secretary sensor we
are executing in mac and we will be able
to view the packages in the mac server
and third we're going to test a third
architecture we will have a Windows
machine in the same local network but
not being executed within Mac but
executing its own sensor
this window said device will establish a
TCP connection with a malicious IP the
sensor will detect this malicious
connection will send a love to the
server the server will talk with the
process successor of Windows and will
send it the idea of the process of
they'sa package so now let's take a look
at the real demo as I said let's begin
with Mac we're executing the server the
process sensor and the mall trail sensor
that detects malicious packages so
inside the man we're going to send a pin
to a malicious IP check whether it's
being executed and kill the process for
the mall trade token so here we have the
mall trail core so with previous traces
so that we can see how everything is
being done but now we're going to create
a new process let me highlight that
we've added three columns so in this
console process ID process name and kill
process the goal of which is to kill the
process see the name of the process the
name of the malicious package and the
PID this teams but if you read the code
of mantra creator it was interesting to
know how he did all this in order to
develop
and this allowed us to order the
packages based on the PID or the process
so we send a PIN number with the macro
machine we sends a pin to the lower
right console it's being sent well it's
received we're going to update the mall
trail console and we're going to see
will you take a look at the console when
we press kill we're going to kill the
process it has died well as you can see
here now let's move on to MINIX to the
demo in linux more entertaining we have
the process sensor and running and we
were going to do a routine to a
malicious site so when I press the
button I will have to look for the
process and kill it before it finishes
so let's see how this goes we take a
look we have killed the process well and
now we can read they're killed
it's being killed before the traceroute
is finished good untie now let's move on
to the windows demo in which you will be
able to see that we run from issue
requests to a malicious site we're going
to find that request within the mall
trail console and we're going to see
life how the chrome process that is
being executed in the cathedral fascia
and the screen of this computer is
killed from the mall trail console
there's no connectivity with the
militias well because the malicious web
does marketing and as you can see we can
kill it perfectly well that's report
here it is wonderful we're going to
press kill but take a look at this
screen so that you see how the chrome
process is killed as you can see we have
also managed this error let's see were
able to find the correct process for
doing this via mobile let's see we're
able to find it and killed it
kill it well emotion Blvd Fiona the
request has been sent to the process
sensor of Windows but we're going to
restart windows process sensor I said
that Windows was a bit Messier and using
pythons PowerShell isn't easy either
we have it ready
you've sent the request we're waiting
for to receive the process we're logging
everything here it is we refresh
mulwray's web so we press kill and we
close it correctly you complete the
process you've exceeded our time sorry
for that and thank you everybody I have
a question during how long have you
trained the trace roots and move your
fingers to press kill a couple of times
it's been quite a race she said of the
demo use the mobile point of access
setting the structure took us a
significant part of last night so you
can't imagine well the ideas that it can
be automatically implemented with
severity rules evil if the processes
killed automatically well this demo of
course wouldn't make any sense
this can be implemented as a future
enhancement in the future the automatic
killing of processes we do have time to
do this and to have don't have the kill
button activated if the processes it has
already been killed thank you
let's say that Jimmy
[Music]
hola hey hello good morning my name is
Javier I'm part of cyberwar team and
first of all like to explain to you the
development of our idea from the
beginning of the hackathon till now
because if we consider the comments made
by the jury and we change course
somehow initially we wanted to search
osing by entering the full name of a
person and the city where that person
lives and our to show the internet links
where the info on that person was
located and whether we had found
sensitive info for example I couldn't
make background employment background
and we wanted to add further criteria
this night we've included yet another
search a criterion also search regarding
the user address it's true that we've
identified or face a series of reverse
specifically with the ideas my colleague
will explain also promised regarding the
execution times for the matching of data
because we don't only obtain data once
we have that data we run analysis
algorithms on them to try to obtain info
from those data sources more filtered in
form or screened info and that has first
problems but in terms of scalability
should we have time we would be able to
fine-tune the algorithms and obtain
further data and a more search criteria
one of our ideas for the future is to
introduce a function whereby the data
collected are then implemented a PDF
didn't have time to do this
another idea that we have in mind is
that when we do a research it can be
stored in the database our database only
stores in one search but the idea to
have a historical log of the search
that's an idea for the future as well
and I'll give the floor to my colleague
with cyber watch of what we wanted
initially as my clinic said we wanted to
conduct a search and that whatever
person could do this anybody the problem
was that we couldn't ensure the security
of only looking for the data on that
person in particular and not everybody
the jury gave us some advice to have
security backed certificate backed
security and we decided to use the
electronic idea with a USB the drive
problems we had to carry out two
processes the Spanish national well the
mint issues the ID and works with the
law-enforcement agencies and we thought
ok what if I find a place where this
process that can be done by myself and
that's when we were able to find this
company
Tracie's it's hard to see practice is a
company that does validation with the
spanish mint and with the local police
and this company works with all these
certificates that you can see from Spain
and other countries as well and we can
see how with Spain there's a specific
section there works with the local
police okay
we're aware of this so
now I'd like to show you a demo with my
ID document first they ask me for an
authorization because it's gonna use my
date I say yes access and then it Dell
notes an applet that will be installed
in my computer which is this one that
you can see here I need to of course
accept I open the link now it's going to
ask me for the password I'm going to try
to combine both screens so I'm being
asked to introduce the password for the
certificate I'll introduce my ID number
but there was a problem with the police
so the IDS with specific support number
had been attacked and deactivated I
didn't have time to go to the police to
renew the certificates so the app is
going to tell me that I won't be able to
access here you can see that I cannot
access how can we do a demo well
what my colleague said them the idea was
a surger than anybody could use and
through the certificate user could only
find data related to the public part of
his or her digital footprint without
giving this possibility to anyone else
so we keep security measures that
respect everyone's privacy here it was a
previous search and here we emulate that
the full name could be collected from
the ID now we see the login screen and
everything I presented about the
certificate here we have the code about
the certificate implementation in G hub
here working with an API related to my
Strato server and then we do the
emulation where the full name would come
from the idea and the user will only
have to type the city from a list or the
item extracts which are the rest of
potential searches as sides venues and
this is going to be now the simulation
I'm going to type my colleagues name
Xavier Monica a hero is not seen on the
screen now here Monica be a hero now the
city's
Sadako's and his at present are a gym I
said find and the analysis would start
the data collection until the final
results when you introduce the name of
the person the city and the criteria me
there is a search with those criteria we
get Internet data and then we filtered
whether the data are really there then
we applied an analysis algorithm to find
possible locations in the text we have a
database with cities of the world if in
this register with website text we find
any of the cities that is in our cities
list then maybe some of the cities in on
the database are not real cities so we
have another algorithm for a second
checking that browsers Internet to see
whether the city is a real location we
also have data analysis algorithm to
structure email
relatedly internet browsing and SQL
query we can see if any of the worlds
present in our dictionary or inside the
registry we have as I said a table is a
dictionary it has a field and the name
is field and then we add a value we have
the field whether it is a school course
activity subject mathematics and if it
inside this dictionary we introduced it
in possible studies in addition to these
we show risk percentage
once the fair water is completed that
estimates the relation of sensitive
Internet information based on the total
data received here you can see in the
map possible locations of this joint
search and we see the links where the
information is present and we see
whether we have found emails or not and
in the lower part will show the level of
risk based on sensitive information we
didn't have time to add a graph to make
it more visual but we have the value
this is not finished yet we didn't have
enough time but if we had more time and
we will go on improving it then we will
make it more Pro this is just to show
some data will benefit from those eight
seconds to thank the URI and the
organizers of this event thank you very
much
[Applause]
okay we have two more teams we are on
schedule
the idea is to get ready before the
presentation so we still have two teams
to go we are okay with time and take
into account please take into account
your own votes because you are focused
on your own presentation and then you
forgot about the other team's names etc
but then you are in the other location
where we will continue working you might
have a chance
it was a good old multi like mr. okay
it's a dish from a lot of little things
applicants
[Music]
olá season hello
I will speak not from the stage because
I feel more comfy here this is the drone
please do not suit it down because I
love it
our project is do th transport oriented
to hyvää
as you know here we had to give our best
we are here to compete we haven't slept
much
we just had tons of coffee and that's
the same for the rest is a killer for
all of us in total it was two thousand
eight hundred and eighty minutes to
complete the budget we have created more
than 1 million of code lines from
scratch and we have completed 95% we
haven't been able to attain 100% of the
pre-plan project how did we started we
came here from zero we didn't have
anything not even a line of code we only
had the idea and the draft as I said
this was our starting point we wanted to
be come here and start the procedure and
we are two and two make such a complex
project he was quite a task
he's been difficult but we are quite
satisfied what we have created those
that have created do th have been using
different tools one of them is Cajun dot
as H that generates public and private
keys and is in charge of encryption then
create a s dot as H generates an access
point for our clients so the drone will
provide a nexus point
connection that Sh makes the connection
with the closest spot
kameena that Sh is a script that
simulates the use of a distance vector
that follows algorithmic bellman-ford
used in our AP we also have the tools
inside the server there are different
we've been trying different connections
and different orders and we will do a
demo with one of them so that you see
we've been trying all the application
attempts and recommendations by the URLs
that remember that we started from
scratch all those tools and some more
that I might forget been done from
scratch in only two days what do we have
this is our drone and remember that we
have Elena Elena and the Jose Elena
wants to connect with Jose Elena here
she's she connects to the drone to send
the message send the message to the
drone and the drone will send the
message to Jose this is what we have so
far
and you might say poor thing what about
the rest of the drones we need more
drones yes the idea of this project was
to lunch around 10 drones so that they
could communicate among themselves
because we only had two days we haven't
been able to do we have planet so that
we can continue later on with the
project and develop it with more drones
but this demo only works now with one
with two drones I imagine and then we
had to reinvent the wheel since we
started or working in hackathon will
been given help about Network protocols
we've been following all advice and
we've tried as much as possible then we
realized something
what we said at the beginning our idea
is to bring the future into the present
for that we shouldn't use old
technologies but adapt them to our
project the problems we encountered were
because we should have our fixed notes
because we're going to use drones oral
notes will be moving we have to adapt
old technology and implement a protocol
from zero was too complex that's why we
hadn't implemented communication among
the ten drones
well will the future be like 40 oth this
was just a starting point this project
is going to be the end project at
University we want to continue with just
pressing enters that drones take off and
communicate among themselves this is a
communication system with nodes are
difficult to sit down is not just we
have different nodes our idea is that
you can have a secure communication you
launch the drone if somebody throws a
stone can't set it down but nobody can
physically take it this is another
difficulty and thank you especially I'd
like to thank the members of the jury
for their ideas we've tried to implement
them all thank you to the hackathon and
the organizers for getting this event
and thank to our colleagues for the
support and encouragement throughout the
hackathon and now this is the demo we
have our progress so far
if the URI can now use these two
computers we're gonna leave one to each
member of the URI
said yeah now the drone is the acer one
that would be simulating the drone so
one computer would be a leaner and the
other one hosting to just pick up the
one you like you can be Elena our
hostess
to you buddy
whatever HR submitted
I'm gonna benefit when it is this time
so that you can see we're gonna show you
the starting point at the script and you
will see the communication what they
would do before giving them their own
computers is to go to the folder where
our program is located here they es do
th the name is director and we will be
in director and in order to do the
setting and provide content we reduce
the file country dot es that gives two
options start or help they can be reused
by anybody we might execute start and
we'll give information about the notes
because we want to have a strong as many
drugs as possible he gives us the
password tool for authentication so that
messages can be sent
I believe I've created a folder when he
was already there I type information
about the user and I execute again one
note and everything is perfect so we
might have now the user folder with the
information to the user only for team
should we avoid intrusions folder notes
it will be the folder with this a
specific node we might be in node one
and we will create an access point
because he's already been created with
don't need to do it now but so that you
can see the steps the access point is
created and to set the server so that
they can correct those are all the test
applications each connects in a
different way
one sense everything in plain text
although some others are cryptid now
this is going to be a chat between both
computers and we will feel the
conversation it was already loaded if
you can see it note related to the index
to load our server once it's loaded that
is in port 3000 we will go to our local
host 3000 and this is what they could be
viewing but now it's empty but now if
Elena or people can send a message so
that we can check by sending a message
and Elena's got it Elena can you reply
communicative as you can see
communication works life he sends a
message the server receives it intently
directed to all users connected and this
is demo and the end of our time thank
you very much for your attention
[Applause]
[Music]
hmmm a quick question
the connection between Elena and cozy
and port 3000 is not using HTTPS for
reason is by sockets directly by sockets
if you send it the server receive it and
then send it to the recipient but would
use in normal sockets yes they were
different they must we have the exchange
of tables each folder if you want to
test it makes a connection in a
different ways there's a folder that
sense they change so that you can
connect when you have 10 drones and you
can say the connection we haven't been
successful yet but here it is so we can
develop it later thank you
and the last but not least team
hey Allah hello see ya
[Music]
remember that after this demo we will go
to the hackathon area for the you're
voting so that you can rest a little bit
until one
nice
male estimate Lister's okay we're ready
don't look at the man that is working
behind the stage and this is quite a
complex for just one person
okay as we said in the presentation
r2 is a program to find wireless
networks and devices and we're going to
show some real use cases about
development as we said we started from
scratch the project are a super
important Hardware one in relation to
the code is not too long as our
colleague said code lines are very
expensive in time just to write a few
ones
therefore server is divided in a core
part in that is independent executing
the different plugins and there was much
effort to do to find the right plugins
it's been held to until we found them
and then the silver also has a viewer
through web service and those web
services can be used to view data we
create a small panel and then the
complementary part that is the Howard
were hacking we had to struggle with
many different devices in our three
heavy bags some we managed to make them
work we haven't been successful in other
cases
let us show different demos and we're
now going to move to demo number one
demos we're going to start by the lowest
level or J's there are not so nice and
then we will improve them as we go along
here the idea was to detect an attack
with this gadget is BTS gsm that
emulates a real one the plugin is
implemented is in the repository but is
extremely slow so in just 10 minutes we
don't have time to show it live now we
have implemented a tool that scans gsm
networks and the idea was to implement
and control the power you can see
different channels with frequency and
power
the idea is to compare it with the sign
broadcasted by this device that has to
be higher the problem is that this takes
15 to 20 minutes to go through the 900
to 1,000 megahertz and we don't have
time for this now if we now move to demo
number two what we've done is scanning
Bluetooth 4.0 Low Energy Bluetooth as
this bracelet with a small look if you
now show the control panel those are the
devices because there is a great deal of
noise is not so accurate but otherwise
it will detect more what is the
functionality of this plug-in for
people's control residents if people
wear the bracelet we can see there's a
missing person or we can limit areas
where if there is an intrusion an alarm
might be activated there is a device
that is the name is a smart lock and is
this this one is a Bluetooth Locker
clock with an application if we remove
the batteries it will be switched off
and this goes on scanning and now the
smart lock should disappear from the
panel as you can see is just gone so now
we could activate an alert or whatever
now demo number three is similar to the
Bluetooth one but this is an inventory
of Wi-Fi networks we can have a white
list that we want to monitor our ignore
those that we do not want the monitor we
can't if there's a fall the service if
any of the notes no longer work we can
detect malicious network or networks
that are being used to filter data here
you can see all Wi-Fi networks that are
around this device cyber camp and some
others and as with the rest of the
screens it provides some data frequency
channel and power so we can have an idea
of how far or how close they are
now the next the moment about the Wi-Fi
with this gadget we have here the
pineapple Ricardo can you show it yes
is the pineapple Mar 5
for Wi-Fi network or it and it also
allows attacks if the problem 30 attacks
by default although you can add more one
of the attacks karma captures the proves
that the deliverance lunch to connect
the Wi-Fi networks known Wi-Fi networks
and this device that takes those probes
and emulates the Wi-Fi to DC to you so
that you connect to it we have designed
a plugin that detects this type of
attack but you can see it's in green
because right now it's not the attack is
not in progress but this is the
pineapple interface with all the
potential attacks and here you see the
karma one that when you press the
execute is on
now the attack is not launched yet the
pineapples the same somewhat problematic
you've seen the list with 40 or 50 Wi-Fi
networks available now it's working
from Venus order vamos a posar it works
I'm sure it does let's move on to the
next demo basically would launch the
attack that would be then detected and
so it would turn red let's move on to
the next demo you can execute our F map
directly and hint via Marsh so we're
going to be super fast what you're
seeing here is a real scenario well
let's imagine a real industrial 4 dot L
environment with age a piece of
equipment connected by monitoring
sensors and there are eight links ok so
for example I'm going to simulate that
one of the links crashes for example
number six I'm going to say hit signal
number six from here
another demon unfortunately
what's a team artifact oh my goodness
I'll explain it to you I would be able
to interact with each of the eight
channels it would flash in red and this
will help us monitor that these a links
to the image he said working in in one
fascist we will know that now it's
working yes number six this could be
used for example to analyze a spectrum
and look for gaps et Aradia are number
six and I tell you change this to number
two for example now it detects number
two and this of course has many
applications to look for things that are
pushing and thanks very much
sorry for the delay I have a question
regarding GSM it's true that to do local
mapping it takes time the gsm plugging
once it's big mapping for 20 minutes is
there does it identify new ones
oh no we did the plugging of the core
that collects all data we don't have
discovered that's where we would program
an alert to to take a new one with an
extra different
staying power but that's part of the
front and we haven't done this because
we didn't have time
the others will prepare we're prepared
we're aware of the difficulties but the
core is done that core is done yes it
draws a list and you can see it in text
format but you obtained the list of all
VTS and the power associated power
thank you
you