hola hello good morning everybody and
welcome to Cybercom 2017 the great event
on cybersecurity organized by n CB which
has the support of the major experts on
cybersecurity in the world this year the
beautiful bay of Santander the most
northern capital city in Spain is
hosting this edition we started
yesterday with a lot of activities that
will go on until the 30th sorry be until
Sunday in this wonderful conference hall
we have national and international
experts of cybersecurity we have
students of cybersecurity professionals
from all these sectors of technologies
and we are also opening our doors to all
the families who want to know more about
the views and the safe secure use of the
Internet this is all animated by my toe
a yarn and Mary with who will provide
entertainment to all the attendants our
goal is to make you aware of the dangers
online and to enjoy internet in a secure
and responsible way so without further
ado welcome to Cybercom 2017 before we
start with the protocol of the official
opening I would like to introduce a
major talent that will be with us in the
following days I'm talking about a
musical talent here so when he can play
any style with the violin and make you
travel to places you would have never
imagined creative and curious he's found
a personal way of mixing and
interpreting and performing styles but a
lot better and better than explaining it
is enjoying it Pablo Navarro with all of
you ladies and gentlemen
[Music]
[Applause]
well in gravely emphysema Salafis Paulo
when nebith emotional sigh companion
thank you very much Pablo let's begin
with the official opening with Jose
Morales is Secretary of State for the
information society and Digital Agenda
Francisco Fernandez Regional Minister
for Education Culture and sport His
Excellency the mayors of Santa Clara
eval and mr. uncle passes the Provost of
the University of Kent Aria please if
you are so kind as to come up on the
stage see see us present on the yellow
strip obeys our Mariana saya
al Segundo High School Ramiro Francisco
Szechwan de l'espace Nicholas II yes so
now that I think you are on your seeds
we are ready to begin so I give the
floor to her excelent see the major
ascent and their semi well good morning
everybody thank you very much for
summary a lasagna the Spanish government
and in Sivir for choosing Santander as
the venue for this cyber camp edition
since I am NOT the leading role yeah and
I know you are willing to get to know
the more than 20 activities that are
organized all the talks the workshops
the competitions that are upstairs for
grown-ups
so to say and the part downstairs which
is dedicated to children so the City
Council sent and I would like to thank
the organizers for choosing our city and
we are also here to underline the
relevance of the issues you're going to
be dealing where
during these days with all those more
than 20 activities nobody can question
than the Internet is present in every
part of our lives but during these days
we need to reflect upon whether we are
using the Internet correctly if we are
really aware of the protection we need
and the security we need online and how
we can protect ourselves what we can do
because going online is a lot more and
there are some things we need to know to
use the Internet in reasonable safe and
responsible manner we all use the
Internet but the question is are we
using it well so these days are great
for reflection it is very good news that
this is host in the city of Santander
and Sint and there is up I skipping up
the level of all the cities where this
cyber camp was organized before and I'm
very happy that something those students
can take the opportunity to learn from
this occasion so Casa Maria lasagna
thank you very much because you're
because of your personal support to the
city of Santander to put us on the
national international map when it comes
to technology thank you very much thank
you
Hema now we're going to give the floor
to the Provost of the University of
Canterbury mr. Engel pathos good morning
everybody
first of all I would like to thank the
Secretary of State for giving us the
chance to be here and the opportunity
they've given to the University of
Canterbury to collaborate from the
dissemination point of view the
dissemination of these sessions among
all the students the University and all
the researchers at the University and
also your opportunity they've given us
to participate in several of the
activities including the hackathon and
several workshops I see a lot of
youngsters among the audience today
and I think this is the key element
during these sessions I'm sure that
these sessions will be very useful in
fulfilling its ultimate goal which is
educating students in the safe use of
digital technologies but not only
educating on safe use of the internet
but also encourage them so that
everybody and especially younger
generations are more and more immersed
in the use of information and digital
technologies because that's where the
future is going to go that's why I'm so
happy to see so many young people not
only coming from schools but also
University students because the number
of them is quite high so just one final
word to wish you very fruitful sessions
and I would like to thank one more time
the Secretary of State forgiven the
University of Canterbury
the chance to participate thank you so
much thank you
mr. Parsons now we're going to get to
the floor to the regional ministry for
Education Culture and sports mr.
Francisco Javier Fernandez thank you
very much welcome and good morning to
all the authorities and all the
authorities and Friends this is an
extraordinary occasion for the
government of Kent ability host this
cyber camp 2017 it event we are thrilled
that this is hair celebrated in
Santander with an orientation to its
youngsters school kids who are flooding
in I heard that there were more than
1,000 participants yesterday so maybe we
can break the former's editions record
I'm sure we will
so this is a great opportunity from the
educational perspective as this is a
training activity and we totally
identify ourselves with its goals
discover your capabilities is one of the
mottos that we have at the original
ministry for education new information
and communication technologies have a
great potential and I'm sure your
abilities and your knowledge and those
technologies is huge and Cybercom will
surely give you tools in order to boost
that potential you already have and
consolidates
your knowledge there is something we
cannot forget in this field the
educational field is also involved in
training good professionals you know
that to be competitive with other
economies in the world this is a great
opportunity and this is another goal
that we share with the Secretary of
State and in Sabre which is the safe and
responsible use of a social media and
communication networks it is very
important to protect ourselves from our
vulnerability to protect the privacy of
minor children as you will probably
understand this is basic and it's really
our intention we're really determined to
continue doing so and even if it's it
happens very Sultan it's true that
sometimes we see cases of cyber stalking
in our schools and this is an issue that
we are concerned about we won't tolerate
this kind of behavior as we are
responsible for protecting our children
so we are responsible for as a
responsible use of
the social media and also to have tools
that enable us to say no to set limits
to stalking coming from social media
which have really devastating effects so
enjoy yourself so this is a unique
opportunity we have in Cantabria and in
Santana thank you very much I give now
the floor to the Secretary of State
thank you very much mr. Fernandez the
final word is for mr. Jose Morales a
year Secretary of State for the
information society and the Digital
Agenda good morning everybody original
ministry mayor as Provost the director
of in Syria the government's
representative dear friends I would
first of all like to thank the city of
Santander the government of Cantabria
and the University and Cantabria as a
whole for its collaboration because this
very special event on cyber security
wouldn't have been possible without the
determined collaboration of the
authorities here present so my eternal
thankfulness because I'm sure that the
success of this event will be partly due
to your commitment with the project I
would also like to thank in theory the
National Institute for cyber security
for their preparation work and all the
work that they have been put in and they
will put in the following days taking
care of the people who are attending
this event and being really committed
with the activities that are being
developed this year's edition is focused
on three basic goals the first one is to
become a platform in order to identify
the future careers that will be
needed in order to establish a bridge
with young talents in the field of
cybersecurity second to place families
at the core of the friendly and
responsible use of new technologies via
awareness raising and dissemination
programs and thirdly to encourage our
youngsters ambition in order to build a
compact and robust society prepared for
the new digital era this is going to be
combined with talks workshops for
competitions and educational activities
for the public at large so cyber Camp
must be the meeting point for cyber
security where all members of society
have a say the creation of cyber social
awareness which is diverse and strong
for that purpose since eva has become
vital in order to tackle cyber security
from a brave and multifactorial
perspective the cyber attacks on people
and companies have been fought against
by them and they also play a fundamental
role in socially articulating the
vulnerabilities of the network I want to
remind you the free-of-charge hotline
which is confidential and addressed to
children and which has to do with the
responsible and safe use of the internet
which has to do for example with
conflicts of privacy and reputation
abuse inappropriate contents dangerous
communities and issues regarding
protection of devices fraud and many
more
we also address parents professionals
educators and guardians who provide
assistance and protections in the
households and schools so I please ask
you to disseminate the use of this very
important tool and I want to give out
now an essential message the gender
perspective and the feminization in the
cybersecurity field is a mandatory way
forward it is in all cases and in all
sectors but we wouldn't be helping
ourselves it would didn't make an effort
to include women and fill in a growing
field such as cyber cyber security and
leave the woman's role in a role of
apathy and discrimination only 11% of
the people involved in cyber security in
our country are women in Europe where
the flag of diversity should be flying
high this diversity is very small and
this percentage hasn't changed in the
past few years although it is becoming
more and more important to increase
gender diversity in the new technology
niches and this is not only about the
technology we are talking about opening
the windows of the new digital ecosystem
which sometimes has two biggest NIF of
masculine testosterone we need to move
forwards avoid digital shortcuts for our
consumption Society because sometimes we
are slow and coward if you allow me in
order to adapt to the 21st century
challenges so technology development
should be in
compatible with the axis of
technological testosterone I was
referring to so cyber trust and cyber
confidence is the way to go in order to
build a smart spain which is what we
want to build via the digital strategy a
country that can see clearly where the
digital transformation should go and not
the other way around I am convinced that
this event is a wonderful platform in
order to build the country we want so I
encouraged you to design with us the
future roadmap for our country so thank
you very much for your attention and
enjoy cyber camp
[Applause]
muchisimas gracias por ESO no no scada
la foto de familia so one final
photograph final family photograph
alberto if you please and we can enjoy
our violinist Pablo please
[Music]
[Applause]
timotheus pablo impresionante good thank
you very much Pablo Thank You
authorities and in a couple of minutes
we'll be back and resumed conference
[Music]
you