welcome to
Congress hello good afternoon the first
thing that I'd like to do is do you
thank you on behalf of my unit and on
behalf of the telematic crimes of the
Guardia Civil
of the Civil Guard and would like to
thank you for inviting us to participate
in cyber camp 4th edition a very
important event on a national level in
the field of cyber security I've come
here to speak about social networks and
about the evolution of the Guardia Civil
the civil guard in this respect and I'd
like to say that our corpse since 1884
were told that we would be a protection
for victims and for those who were
suffering and that we would take care of
the needs of everybody in petha MO and
this is what we've been doing since 1884
a 44 driver and we've been evolving and
adapting to new technologies the types
of crimes and we have different we've
been working in different areas and
domains land air etc see right now we're
also in cyberspace and in 1996 so we
first detected the need to do research
in the field of new technologies and
we've been evolving and the group has
been adapted has been adapting as I was
saying to these new technologies and
right now we've become a department were
no longer group the Department for
telematic crimes and very recently we
held
our 20th anniversary and this these are
pictures from another conference on
Security and a Madrid and we were
invited to participate we were invited
to speak about the history of the
apartment and here we have three
different directors of the unit one of
them couldn't attend because they have
been four and I'd like to say the
president the group is structured in the
following way on the lieutenant there's
a section also for institutional
relations and citizens collaboration
that I belong to you and also an
Operations Department that's in charge
of investigation per se and is made up
by four sections one of them has to do
with crime against people another one on
hacking security and also fraud and
economic crime and copyrights etc and
then we have another department that
takes care of developing systems and
applications that will help us in with
our research and also technical support
and support regarding the analysis of
the evidence that we get obviously we
collaborate on a national level with the
rest of our colleagues of other police
from other police forces University the
Attorney General Department the hacker
community and by hackers we mean people
who are interested in security and
Vail's and works for security we don't
use this to mean criminals no way
and we also collaborate with a private
sector and we also hold an international
collaboration through our bilateral
relations with other police forces
Europol Interpol and networks 24/7 and
other institutions such as the ones we
can see that fight child pornography and
abuse child abuse etc and here we have
colleagues from FBI Europe oh well and
this is a an example of international
collaboration right now Internet has no
borders and our mission is the work on
all the information we may get and that
could lead to a police investigation
well whenever judges tell us to
investigate something or whenever the
Attorney General asked us to do so we
work in different sorts of operations
for instance this international
operation for instance children
pornography dealing traffic and others
operations such as the opie riccati a
recent thing by which a group of
criminals were
arrested they had gained made 330
million euros through a malware and
through different cyber crimes and so
these are different operations like for
instance against intellectual property
and copes force has been evolving
because at the beginning Prime in the in
the net used to was 1.0 users went in
the Internet in order to get information
or in order to look at certain things
also so now we work on crime such as
corruption and children prostitution
that was the past and then we moved on
to to door all cyber crime and cyber
cyber crime things more related to
technology and now we move to three
point of and we are in the antechamber
of 4.0 were already speaking about cyber
attacks cyber spying cyber war we're
already speaking about a war and the net
and some people say that were already
into cyber war our department's been
evolving so in 2005 and this one point
web we launched our first web this is a
weapon that was used to do queries we
used to use an email something that is
the used little by little we've been
making progress and this is a picture
from the web we have right now
and right from the beginning we're
publishing alerts news and or any
information that we thought would be
interesting for internodes
in this 2.0 think we have an interaction
of the user with us and I have to say
that telematic complaints I did not
exist but through our portal you can
download forums and once you've filled
them in and you can you can submit them
in order to be able to report on
whatever has happened to you and to this
and we use this service called the II
guarantee or you guarantee and it's an
online witness to speak of so this can
this tells us what was present in the
web at the time of the capture and we
can also use it as legal as legal
evidence then we have what we call
collaborate it's this collaborative part
by citizens through this I want to
report on and they can report on any
suspicious attitude or something they
may see in the web I was talking to
somebody and we're saying we don't need
to know whether this is a crime or not
it's something which as we see it could
perhaps be a crime so through this
portal we can find out
anonymously you can send there's a file
telling us what you are so who the
suspect could be so little by little
were sent information in this case we
are sent
Twitter profiles which in this case went
against children pornography so we work
on this information we analyze it if
it's information we can access to we
start with an investigation or if it's
an investigation that is related to
somebody abroad outside of Spain so this
is information that we submit or sent to
other colleagues in other countries and
then we started with social networks
where the 3.0 thing so since 2010 we
started having our first profiles in
Twitter Facebook and 2020s called a
social network aimed at teenagers mainly
20 as you very well know well 20
disappeared and we added YouTube by
adding contents that I will tell you
about in a few minutes so what do we do
with the profiles we have in social
networks in Twitter and Facebook we try
to we try to somehow we focus on
campaigns launched by Europe or or
campaigns that deal with profile by the
way this is a person who's a disappeared
so we disseminate this or we disseminate
were other colleagues from police forces
tell us of for instance in this case sex
offender was being looked for was being
chaste aim is to find the bad guys and
so if we join forces and in this case
for instance is when the attacks took
place in Barcelona so the regional
police force were telling us what was
happening and we're trying to help and
reinforce and help them wherever
necessary and when we started with
Twitter we started with a hashtag we all
know what this is this is this part of
Twitter and then we created our own
which was gdt Twitter dia this forced us
to publish one to it a day telling
something telling something that would
be necessary it is true that we are
prioritized quality and not quantity so
we want to tell something that may be
useful for citizens so we came up with
this first profile always followed and
I'll tell you about them so we created
gdt alert profile with this a hashtag we
wanted to get to Twitter and Internode's
by telling them something by telling
them about a threat that perhaps we had
discovered in the Internet in this case
its campaign about a fraud given sort of
fraud and we also produce videos we
create gdt news for instance in order to
you for instance since he launched this
forum we we also disseminate our own
news in this case riccati operation that
I've brought here to tell you about how
we start the working with social
networks because here we not only speak
about this operation but this operation
was something where we obtained many
telephone numbers related to potential
victims so you wouldn't imagine the
amount of work trying to look at all
these victims so in our own website we
had a window we had an area in order to
ask people whether this person had been
ripped off so in this case we also
launched a video saying what the
operation was about and how it affected
victims and how these victims were
attracted or attacked was for this to be
easy to handle easy to understand in
order people to understand how these
cyber criminals go to the victims and
then we created this star hash tag this
DDT council thing here we tell people
how to avoid problems with the internet
how to avoid fraud scam
we used pictures images with which we
explained the different steps to be
taken in this case when we are sent a
typical message saying we are an alert 3
or 4 or call this bring this phone
number and these things are fake are not
true so in order to know whether this is
real piece of news or if it's just a
fake we give them advice in order to
tell people how to detect these things
so and we had a problem with this and
this is that was somebody we were
through facebook said everything that
you're telling us is wonderful you guys
but whenever you send us an image a
picture we cannot see it we cannot read
it because we've got a special software
that reads out what you tell us but it
doesn't translate what's in the picture
so in a basic sort of way what we do is
the following we transcribe what we have
in the picture we tell what's in the
picture we explain it we're trying to
make this a much user friendly and we're
collaborating also with the Association
for the blind in order to make sure that
we reach out bigger audience here we
also launched many tips throughout the
day basics security in Internet in
mobile phones and also holidays through
the internet security when buying online
security with smartphones holidays
digital security and something that's
very important
the danger of dangerous communities
and we launched this because we started
detecting too much movement in certain
media related to the problem of blue
whales before serious problems happen in
Spain different security forces who are
launching these alerts just if in case
any kids were going into these games and
these are no games by the way these are
activities these are things where kids
had to keep passing a series of tests
harming themselves during themselves
harm and the last test had to do with
committing suicide for pouring frozen
water freezing water over their heads
and then boiling water burning
themselves and doing horrible things so
this is what we're trying to avoid
and we also so what we want to do is to
address these messages to more
vulnerable groups like people with
special needs the elderly our dear cyber
grandmas and grandpas and to this for
the children we created these DDT G DDT
councils was very small kids and they
need to read these messages together
with their parents because kids need to
be at least 14 in order to go into
social networks so we launched videos in
order for them to view them to watch
them together with their parents or
family members
in theory supposedly there's some music
to this there's a soundtrack there's
some music to it something that little
kids like very much uniformly cantata we
also launched some campaigns and special
days like the internet safe and secure
day some special days like May 17th for
instance the world internet day thanks
to the collaboration of celebrities in
the field of cybersecurity sports or TV
with the help of these people we
launched some video clips with tips and
we are asking people to record these
things as professionally as possible
because the idea was of these videos to
reach out to citizens and I'll show you
an example of a comedian on the or
Olivia
[Music]
now tell me this
there's simply no computer don't forget
to always keep copy back haha
because in case your system has failure
or if it is attacked by a cyber criminal
so that you won't be able to access your
professional information the good thing
the best thing to do is to retrieve this
with safety security copy the backup
that you have that is always ready to be
used
remember this thanks to the help of
influencers easy way to reach out to
citizen so far I've been speaking about
information we provide social networks
information for citizens for us the
information we get is much more
important citizens collaboration and
thanks to this portal for us this is
like a radar in order to know what's
going on in the internet because
unfortunately no matter how much we want
to cyber crews or cyber patrol we cannot
reach out and reach everywhere so
through these communications we can find
out about new ways of crime or criminal
campaigns which back for instance
there's a typical case which once in a
while
shows up again we see this blue screen
in our computer asking us to dial a
telephone number
I know they want us to all they wanted
is to ask my money from us
for instance this gets through this
collaborate portal where they speak
about sort of prime through a platform a
citizen is doing an improper use of
buying and selling platform so we
analyze all this
and if it is criminal campaign we launch
our hashtags will launch our contents
through YouTube and through pictures and
if there are reasons to start criminal
proceedings we start with our
investigation and we report the judge of
course we don't work if there is no
order from or no no warrant from the
judge asking our students we are always
reporting judges and this is useful also
to report to the technology crime
prosecutors office the prosecutor is
always informed and updated and they
know what is currently going on on the
internet and if the prosecutor's office
requires it we collect information
regarding for example crimes of hatred
the recent case of
the death of the general States
prosecutor is an example of this I
repeat all the crimes committed through
new technologies and which are related
to terrorism are dealt with by
specialized groups if we receive this
kind of information we
that information to that department this
is a crime of cyber terrorism we refer
that information to the group the
specific group as I said imagine that we
get information regarding animal abuse
then we refer that information to the
Department of the civil god that is in
charge of that if the crime has to do
with road traffic we refer all the
information to the corresponding unit or
Department this is an example of a
recent case only three weeks ago
somebody said that he read in a forum
that someone was saying that he was
going to commit suicide so we read the
comment and it was actually a farewell
from somebody he was saying it my in a
forum it is not our competence but we
couldn't waste any more time so we had
to verify the information thanks to the
cooperation of the forum we found out
more information about this person we
located that person and found out that
he had attempted suicide before so we
reported this to our colleagues in the
city where this person lived and our
colleagues made it in time this guy had
already taken some pills but our
colleagues made it in time and were able
to save him so we feel very proud that
we are able to avoid and prevent this
kind of situation with the support of
the citizens we also receive all the
sorts of information for example this
person here says I lost my purse with
IDs passports and credit cards we tell
them
we're not competent to work on this this
message actually was coming from Romania
and we don't know how they work there so
what we did was refer that person to the
pertinent authorities and his country
sometimes we get requests for
information there to have little to do
with our work for example good morning
my child is 8 years old and he's 1 meter
40 centimeters high does he need a chair
in the car well that's something we
cannot answer some things cannot be
dealt with by us however we try to give
them an answer and refer them to the
appropriate Department there is also the
risk of confusion between dgt which is
the general department for road traffic
in Spain and gdt which is the acronym
for our units that's why we received for
example this warning from somebody and
Twitter they said that well the civil
guard guys were trying to make some
money and that's why they were
patrolling and put in tickets for for
over speeding on the roads and well
since we are not in charge of road
traffic and security we responded within
all the twits say and well we are very
grateful for your kind remark but we are
not in charge of road traffic actually
the street went viral and a lot of funny
comments came afterwards but that's
definitely not our intention yesterday
somebody
was asking us yesterday where he could
find a toy for his daughter well we had
to give an answer it's not police action
but behind the crimes and behind
everything we do we are human beings and
if that little girl was longing so much
for that toy
well moved us and we decided to help
people and that's actually our
motivation people's thankfulness I
started my presentation by quoting the
8th article of the civil guard statement
and I'm going to finish with another
statement which is the satisfaction of
the accomplished duty and this is our
motivation at the civil guard we always
try to support and protect citizens and
my final word is we are here if you need
us you can count on us
we are available through our social
media profiles or the telephone number
Oh 6 - thank you now there's time for
Q&A if you have any questions thank you
so much thank you very much uncle
you