hola buenas tardes hello I'm not that
daring
I'm not going to bet that much because
my demos have been prepared he's very
courageous I'm gonna make an
introduction my name is Alejandra Ramos
I'm working in security for many years I
was doing consultancy some years ago and
I deal with IMG security in Spain and
now I work in telefónica with a more
international approach I'm the person in
charge of digital security you know in
the case of wanna cry I'm the last
person responsible for the wanna cry
fortunately it didn't affect us and
affect the good work that was done and
the help that we gave to other companies
when a cry wasn't a catastrophe how many
people have done hacking in in the past
you can leave now you're not going to
learn anything new this is an
introduction I'm going to change the new
paradigm of what has been doing
traditionally in the world of hacking
this has evolved and all the hacking
teams are evolving and it's not now we
have a new approaches if you have a
hacking experience if you work in city F
so I'm not going to teach you anything
new but you are welcome and you can stay
and if you don't know this work if you
come from a system administration or
development or if you are curious this
is your place I'm going to talk about
intrusion tests what is being done now
in an industry and there's a change
towards red team four to five years ago
this red team approach started intrusion
test intrusion it's a type of project
that is bought to assess the security in
a company by simulating the attack by an
intruder from a very specific place in
the organization why
to check the impact of having a
vulnerability when CEO of a company
doesn't understand why he or she needs
to patch well it's better to have an
exploited vulnerability that you've
tested you have it abate database it's
for a CEO or four people in the
management and companies this is very
practical to show that security events
can happen of course another consequence
is to know that one a cries can be all
around but we need to do a previous step
to prevent that in an ideal world
intrusion tests are used to identify an
unknown vulnerabilities I have products
and app services I have developments at
home and I want to know if those
developments are well done
vulnerabilities in deployed products for
instance docker security in docker many
people see it but if I develop my own
application there are more probabilities
to have a vulnerability motivations
there's several the interesting in
church intrusion tests sometimes we do
it as a legal requirement
some organizations demand and require
you to do the intrusion test Visa
MasterCard if you want to work in your
store with that credit cards have to
have a qualified company by certified by
us doing a hacking to your store to show
where your vulnerabilities are so
there's as there are agreements so you
have to be audited we can refer to the
data protection laws and sometimes there
is the requirement to make happiness of
this type from my responsibility as the
head of security this is a leverage to
launch other projects I do the ethic
hacking
and demonstrate that the network is not
segmented because somebody has ax Mahara
access through VPN and got to production
we have to reach conclusions but there's
a firewall that is missing
there's no segmenting controls are
missing this is a leverage to know what
is failing and later on to implement the
solution the origin of this intrusion
tests external somebody from his lab or
his office somebody that says that he or
she is an employee somebody connected
through VPN through wireless networks we
can simulate a lot of things and here we
are closer to red team Danny was daring
with his demos and they and I've done
this already I'm here videos of people
talking it's not even my videos out of
all the information that I process I
keep the parts that are more interesting
in the last few years I wanted to show
you the most relevant people in security
these know this not videos in YouTube
just explaining anything I put some
excerpts short fragments of videos
they're very relevant and this is good
for explaining it's not just me mr.
ramus the wanna cry guy in telefónica
it's many other people will say the same
as me because it's true the first is
Bruce Schneier the CTO of a company
bought by IBM is that he's a Chuck
Norris of security he's very well known
in this talk well it's two to three
minutes long he was explaining for 10
minutes what happened to Sony and I put
this part out when he would Sony was
hacked because of the Korean film and he
makes a reflection on that so I cut this
part when he tells about Sony the
timeline and then I leave this part so
that you can listen to him
anybody w por favor a la al video I love
you you say now it's the audio failing
once that's up to lado it's subtitled
contingency plan for videos live let me
a moment give me a sec give me a sec
devour can you see it now this the
technician is now running downstairs
it'll be the moment where I've got to
follow him okay
hey Olli say boy soon all right see I
hear it get the Detroit over my poor
Tati you know we are sesame know we
report that in every market in your
brahma aha a tinnitus and the derma I
save us a truce when I say no container
subtitlers helicoil best subtitles in
the video I can put my microphone next
to the computer for audio
they were happening no personnel con
esta loofah Damascus cow horn availa you
can't even see the subtitles because
there's very very dim light I know I
know what you feel Danny I was very
happy it wasn't a critical
infrastructure in Sony when they got
attacked the first cyber attack this big
to a movie company
I don't believe that any of us is
important against the low focus attack
what matters is are you are you more
secure than the guy next to you but if
you are you doing great against a high
focus attack it doesn't matter if your
security is relatively better than
anybody else what matters is is your
security better than the attackers skill
en masse commend him okay it's just a
Western Europe What did he say under my
viewpoint it's very important this I
found it in Africa we have different
adversaries we have adversaries with
very low skill and low focus occasional
people when you're going to rub a car
and then you're trying to know where was
the there's a door open so very low
skill and low focus but the guy wanting
to rob a Lamborghini he's waiting for a
Lamborghini and he's in it and there's a
focus there and scale behind so he says
the type of adversary has changed we
have the occasional with low skill low
focus and then those were after us and
those who go after us we people in
security we know that the person with
skill and focus if he or she goes after
us they're gonna succeed the probability
is that these people will succeed are
very high but because it's a easy to
find a hole and because you need to
protect yourself you need to block
thousands of holes he speaks about the
new paradigm of the targeted attacks you
you you might be faster than your
neighbor but it's not enough and when I
was working in the bank
people said I don't want to be the most
secure I want to be more secure than you
so if anybody wants to rob a bank
they're not going to rob my bank for
yours so I need to be faster than you so
it's about speed you have to run faster
okay with targeted attacks it doesn't
work anymore because they they just
don't want to rob anyone they want to
rob you so the paradigm changes when
you're not defending yourself because
it's not good to be a faster than young
competitor you have to be protected you
this paradigm is the red team concept
Microsoft has a very good definition
it's there it's a group of full-time
staff within a company that focuses on
reaching client's infrastructure with a
team of hackers its ethical hackers but
with a clear target we know they're
gonna do it we know it because my
Chrisette says that what does them mean
time to compromise how long 10 minutes
half an hour two days it's a lot 10
minutes half an hour or five-hour hours
that's the average time to compromise
it's the time it takes me to murder you
and we need to reflect reflect on this
average time to escalate privileges once
I get in the hole how long it takes me
to escalate privileges so privileged
time to privilege escalation it's very
complex so you know that you're going to
be a victim to your vulnerabilities
another video is by Alex Thomas C as our
face book he speaks about the need
explains what is this 360 red team
paradigm it's very fashionable now he's
been asked about the fake news in
facebook
[Music]
is the kind of security problem nobody's
had to deal with before and so there's
no book you can read and there's no
class you can go to we just have to kind
of figure it out as we go along
that's what we're doing we have to spin
up an entire team it's not just about
DEFCON this was in DEFCON when he was
asked about the fake news and he says
well that's this is the typical problem
that we didn't know we were going to
face because we got a platform by the
uses given to those platforms we don't
know we can't guess before they happen
it's it's about intelligence we have
spoke about cyber intelligence I set up
a social media and I know you don't know
that there's a government that is my
adversary trying to do political
campaigns on my platform so we need to
have people that not only do exploits
reversions and lots of hackings in
facebook there are many languages social
political matters you needed security
team that is completely
friend with well mm complete and full
knowledge not just technological
knowledge and expertise and this guy has
a bigger problem than me so we have a
very right team with he says that the
team is fantastic but there's another
team that tries to solve these problems
it's called the blue team and Microsoft
has this team a team of people are there
to stop incidences and to improve the
security systems they've put in patches
and they repair what others have broken
the measuring object goals are the mean
time to detect so we we do assume that
this has happened I'm long how much time
has gone since you've been murdered to
the detection sometimes there are months
since they sent our launched it until
they detected so we need to reduce this
compromised window and then mean time to
recovery you need to detect it and then
you then you'll recover and re-establish
the service to delete or all the
identity why are talking about this
catastrophic mentality it's about
assuming the green assuming breach we've
lost the war these people will get in
let's assume that they're inside now
let's look for them so I'll be alert I
can't put wool so that nobody gets in so
I'm trying to open all the doors in my
house to see where are my cut boards
where are the corpses the cars etc I'm
looking inside to see where they've got
in we don't know you wanna aware and
they go in how much are going how much
time do I need to recover and then I
need to improve too so that this doesn't
happen again
something is very difficult to explain
for younger people doing hacking is
the purpose is not to break is to train
those who repair if you do you're
hacking activities well I interviewed
people I want to come to my team and I
just want to break things I don't want
to repair I don't want to fix anything
this doesn't appeal to me what is fun
it's to destroy to break things but if
we compare this to boxing the red team
is the sparring partner this guy this
guy trains the blue team who needs to
defend itself her better antivirus with
repairing the repairing the holes
repairing the the walls and it's the
paradigm between the red team and blue
team in big companies this is already
working we have a red team it's called
red team because it's very easily
identifiable the blue team is the third
incident response team and we have all
the terminology you know that the market
and marketing are very powerful in and
we have the purple team the pink team's
the gray purple light teams so it's up
to your imagination but there's a red
there's a blue attacking defending and
the defending team has to solve the
problems what are the different phases
in the stages generally when you propose
a service another project you hire a
team or your company you have your own
team oh and they can launch persistent
attacks see you get your hack your
Trojan ice-t--
and they stay there their latent there
dormant they recover information and
they don't warn the blue team one of the
KP guys knows how much time we need to
detect it it's useless but this can last
a lot of time
first the red team what does it do well
identifying the risk scenarios we're
talking about ethic hacking
well let's attack the internet let's see
the surface it's very typical but in a
practical world history has told all of
these in past attacks but sometimes the
fastest way is to get into an office
take a PC take it take the hard drive
out to take the passwords and you not
know the password and you enter through
a VPN it's so easy it's like going to an
empty installation facility with no
control and you take the hard drive and
you get the password out of the hard
drive it's easy this type of scenarios
are more complex maybe this is one of
the most traditional ones especially you
buy the physical security people what do
we see now providers attacks instead of
attacking my specific target I see what
are the typical all the usual suppliers
and then I tuck the suppliers and
through the suppliers I can get in but
then my supplier had to sign that this
is going to be done the scenarios are
then organized in such a way the final
goal is to look for the costless and
scenario in the most effective way of
doing that I'm not going to get too
vulnerable
vulnerable at a board in the black
market for three million euros and then
it's going to be detected it's gonna put
me publish then you lose it you can use
it very few times and it's too expensive
they should they try not to be detected
so it has to be very specific there had
to be noiseless we're talking about
adversaries that are not opportunistic
they don't want to open all the doors
they just want to see if you close the
door or not and if you not
the door then you will use that door the
less complex from the technology point
of view persistent and they should allow
to assess the lack of control I
explained how you get physically to a
facility and to take a computer there's
no physical control when you steal a PC
or maybe you the one there's no
encryption in in this computer
Telefonica district image where we've
got 13 buildings 500,000 security people
with dogs security staff we've got three
million antennae around the world what
are these antenna tower have this one up
in total Helio the Guadalquivir maybe
somebody might go there at night and
plug in their laptop it's far as more
simple than to find a vulnerability in a
website that would take for ages so this
mentality Minds those people that have
used to hacking they think about these
things
think about those scenarios and and
think about which ones will be most
effective this is a slide and they set
up these this is where I like it that's
why I thought I'd bring this story here
to tell you about it resists stages neil
initial recognition stage and a career
compromised stage use establish a
foothold me to escalate privileges and
once you escalate privileges you can
move internally in the organisation
you can carry on moving move laterally
keep your presence and then you get the
information and then you filter it you
leak it and you publish it on internet
go back to the videos because to
understand it and this is the best video
I've actually ever seen the last five
years at the end you've got link to the
YouTube and the subtitles are in English
as well in this video by the T a person
in charge of T a tailored access
operations which is the team of hackers
that the NSA have to attack governments
I mean I know that sounds odd but it's a
TA oh it's a tio they've got a budget so
there's a team of hackers which is where
Snowden came from the eternal blue that
generated one acquired is the group of
hackers that most evolved today and five
years we're five years behind them here
so they can attack different governments
so let's go to those at the top of the
top the Pope those that invest millions
of views in vulnerability I think that's
a result everything that happened with
NSA and tau this guy decided to give a
talk and Ted which lasts for 45 minutes
and 45 minutes are well worth listening
to every month they're very inspiring he
doesn't say anything that you don't know
but the fact that he says it is so what
makes it so worrying so I recognize you
watch this video so let's just play a
few snippets
and on this in this snippet let's just
explain what she's gonna talk about he
talks about all these different stages
the video tries to explain to us what to
do so that somebody like him can't get
into your organization he gives
recommendations of what should be done
to make life difficult about what to do
to make life difficult I've removed that
so he tells us what he does and so that
you know what you should do to rectify
it
and like I said these guys are cutting
edge recognizing reconnaissance nothing
that you've heard any person say those
of you that work in hacking it's not the
same as me saying it the email important
and dresses it's just repeating in
Spanish what is the guy on the video
saying in English
so another key point inside this you
know the technologies you intended to
use in that network we know the
technologies that are actually in use in
that network it's a little different
she'd catch that you know what you
intended to use we know what's actually
in use inside there so when we look at
that we will learn the security
functionality of the devices inside that
network will study them understand them
find the vulnerabilities in fact we've
got people who will know the security
functionalities of those devices better
than the people who developed the actual
device right so they won't know the
whole product they won't know every
feature that those developers had but
they'll understand the security
technologies and they'll bring that
expertise at a very very deep level so
inside that it's my new attention to
detail inside that security late layer
again knowing the network knowing that
space so what does that mean
we apply the focus and energy to look at
those details important things to
protect and hold dear will you put in
the energy to understand the network
understand the devices cannot a melodic
positive oh mejor que los que la fábrica
básicamente DS entonces el que la
fábrica OS tiene Cinco mil personas en
un producto pero Horacio so yeah so no
choice los cuatro KTN este país está
buscando FiOS mesos deposit Evo's amis
habla de las configuration SI decir tu
sabe para que pone es el dispositivo
pero no tienes Claro todo lo que haces a
D+ o yo en cambio desde fuera puedo ver
que más cosas hace que whore - no sabes
que estas haciendo simple meant a poor
Pony run D you're doing it's just
putting the device on so this level of
knowledge is by no means simple you
don't do quite in half an hour but when
you're in the reconnaissance stage
that's what the trying to do that is the
day know the network better than you
and in telefónica that's really hard
I've been until over two years but in
small networks any other sort of client
or any other large company that doesn't
have two hundred thousand IP addresses
it's really easy you can know the
network it's easy to monitor it to see
what its purpose is what each thing does
and if we go to programs where you pay
for vulnerabilities and what their
latest reports are you see that their
vulnerabilities which will say oh this
had say server turned off that's because
the person that's we're searching for it
knows it better than those that's got it
because the outsider knows the network
better than you do and this is something
that happens there's another bit of this
video for this guy because he's also saw
something very interesting sorry it's
the same thing we look for the things
that are actually think about trends
like bring your own devices things work
from home access
we're facilities come with that physical
location connected to your somebody
else's computer if you have your data in
the cloud right you're trusting the
security protocols the physical security
all of the other elements of trust
basically where does your network n term
where does your supplies network begin
you're using the cloud you usually using
IOT and that's what's so important about
the Tim network you can't just give it
to suppliers the thing is you gotta
guarantee that the network that includes
you is protected and history as shown as
the through suppliers
was for a VPN provided they're very
protected because I've got a supplier
some VPN that could attack that way this
is something that he said about the
wreckin reconnaissance stage we're going
to go into this in more depth because
the reconnaissance stage is what we've
spoken about all our years the IT the
cloud BYOD the IOT and ot which have
been basically cameras and other devices
that exist in industrial park suppliers
employees and physical installations and
I say there's no limits because at the
end of the day it's whatever you can
think of in the end when you start to
study depending upon what sector you're
working and you know that you're going
to be able to find another attack
surface that you hadn't think about you
got to know that about the business what
the business does maybe if it's a
messenger company or TPVs it doesn't
matter the millions of things so when I
say No Limits what I mean is anything
that your imagination can think of is
not very meaningful to talk about
identification I mean these are the
references I like the awesome or
simplest what it does is it has a whole
list of third parties based on names
ip's physical locations emails you where
you can get information from and the
other one or sind framework which is
that the diagram that you can see on the
right which is a whole series of links
to tools that can be used precisely for
this
here I've brought with me I had brought
a virtual machine to see a simple
example of this with it too
I know if you can see it I've tried to
make it a bit bigger bigger you're all
silenced out there not saying anything
no I can't see it basically here you've
got a tool that does this but it's one
of the seven million that are out there
and all they do is ask for a domain and
it make queries to api's and searches
and tries to get domains and what it
does is explore services here it's
carrying out 300 queries to 300 api's
it's scrapping websites and we in my
past I did something similar I did it
with big data but this is so big and
here you can put so much information but
you could talk forever and ever and what
we end up with a whole series of
subdomains
you can see all the different ones so it
gives you clues and it collects
information there's another tool which
I'd also like to show you because this
is called a workshop which what it does
is adds information for more different
sources and it makes a web server and
why via the web you can manage a scan
which I launched last night and I bought
it and basically what it does it
searches for lots of things affiliated
IPs web content descriptions cookies DNS
records eyepiece
junk files I don't know what it is but
they found junk files if if there's any
at incites in things that have been
hacked these are security tools at the
community create and that allow you
basically to generate these kinds of
things I can see here it's cyber camp
dot yes and it scans and depending on
what we want maybe we want to see
footprint you want to investigate the
original malware so it's a well-known
tool one of the most to real well
developed recently and although all
these tools and here it's going to start
so button and you just click on it and
it would start working and just like all
these tools they end up confusing one
thing with another and you need to do it
manually if you talk about a true
persistent attack it would never end it
could spend days weeks months you could
take the time that you want there you
are it's running is very slow and
basically it give it produces a graph of
what it finds for the moment nothing
let's see one that's already been made
it shows a sort of scan that's been
launched so it's a tool and there are
hundreds IDs
once I've got my mouse back okay we have
a surface
so let's now move on to the first stage
the next stage which is called the first
intrusion that is what Rob joy says
about the first intrusion
spearfishing
water calling
but I will have a cone of theta
exploits a known vulnerability
water-holding spearfishing
when I was having it he said it quite
clearly spearfishing
well no vulnerabilities and simple
things like as SQL injections and he
also says please zero date days isn't as
common as you think it is because you
can use them in the jargon of these kind
of people you could burn them if
somebody detects them and publish it we
stopped using it what they want these
0ds these vulnerabilities when they paid
1/2 million dollars they want to have
them as protected as possible and they
don't want to launch them to 500 million
targets that NSA may have so the
mentality is that it's not so
complicated and everything that we've
learned from what CIA has published is
that they're the tools that they had to
were to have spear phishing or to look
like something that their Koreans are
the Russians do all the Chinese so let's
make the tools make them badly so that
they don't look like they're there now
they're ours and no it's absurd but
that's what intelligence is like it's
had more tools and attributes to third
parties so that people don't think that
they're theirs they don't want a very
developed zero-day but it's in badly
written English or it's compiled in
Russian and Windows where they know meta
data are left that analysts think it's
the Russians and it's a life but there's
some meaning behind what it's saying
no Megan Imam Muhammad wali para the
most efficient mechanisms for intruding
is sad to say but but what really works
is a spearfishing
something that you could just have to
double-click on and people will
do it that'll click on it it's it's what
he said it's a less risky if somebody
finds that they click on it it looks
like it's a Korean competition but it's
the easiest way of doing things and they
do about a watering hole watering hole
was a great name but what it is is set
up a web with a vulnerability and the
person just connects that web watering
hole comes from this anecdote it's the
name that they give to those puddles in
the jungle where lions live in the
savanna the lions wait near these
watering holes until the animal other
animals go there
so you put a vulnerability you know that
the target that you want to attack is
going to visit it that's a watering hole
so you just wait for them to connect and
you exploit a vulnerability and the
browser and then there are known and
unknown vulnerabilities when they talk
about known vulnerabilities they're
talking about vulnerabilities that we
know that they exist that doesn't mean
to say that there's a tool to exploit
them that doesn't mean said there's a
public exploit or an executive or that
you can just give an IP they're talking
about known vulnerabilities that there's
a patch or they've been reported but
they've got people that says oh remote
code execution all the Microsoft
bulletins only four or five but there
isn't a tool to exploit them all because
gonna make that tool you need the
capacity to make that and we've got
people that they've got people that can
make it explore it they can look at the
patch they can look at the difference of
code and then they exploit what is the
zero day that does not work as their
patches but it's not something that's
out in the street and everybody can use
and they talk about zero days and that's
where they have the jewel in the crown
these are vulnerabilities that they only
they
no exist unless you have layers security
or protection mechanisms whatever the
most physical intrusions as well and in
the end they're simple what sort of
tools do red teams use when you don't
work for this gentleman and you have to
go to the market to buy something or
you've got to go to open-source tools
we've got Metasploit and there are
others
they've also other framework to exploit
vulnerabilities and you pay and you can
get them what about public exploits
websites engineering kids you can do a
fishing in a website that can make the
task easier another thing that you see a
lot of for now is the commodity thing
you can go to any company there it sets
up their servers and they've got a
hacking team and but there are others
say that they've got a teams that seek
vogner abilities in a chrome or in big
problems but vulnerabilities in products
that don't have such large security
teams these red teams are usually people
that can make malware sethe or
exploiting to try to find
vulnerabilities that are known or
unknown pentesters people that are in
social engineering physical intrusions
there's a whole range of people in these
red teams and it would seem not but each
of them is specialized it's not the same
somebody who's programming a back door
doing an exploit basically used and have
a mop there's a more overall picture of
the platform that they want to access
here I've got I want to follow on from
the previous case a couple of demos of a
water hole water holing of an office you
gotta find this meaningful or not but
let's try let's try and see cuz you're
just got to double click on it and see
what happens
there's no fail risk well there
shouldn't be a failure risk I know you
can't see anything but that's deliberate
there is the virtual machine I couldn't
find it but I found it now I've got four
virtual desktops
- totally on test a Fiero muy
interesante this is something that I
showed you earlier but I'm gonna close
it if I was with docker it would have
closed itself of its own accord of
course it was a shoot I don't use docker
let's hope with a little bit of luck
there we go with just one command which
is meta exploit I can see I'm going to
generate a Word document
and I'm gonna put a dock with a macro
there and I'm gonna get it to connect to
this IP address and to this port get it
to run everything and then we'll leave
basically this will create a word it's
got a Trojan in it so you don't have to
be very sophisticated to make this you
can see it's generated it here test dock
M which is the document I don't if you
can see the command I'm not revealing
the secret so to coca-cola that's what I
wanted to show you ms for looking and
this is a document that I'm gonna create
now I'm gonna copy it I'm gonna send it
to somebody I'm gonna call it some
payroll dot doc or interview whatever
and I'll just send it via email this is
spearfishing I send it by mail and here
I just leave the sister is ready for
when this person double-click the
documents and and frees macros that
it'll take me to the computer but let me
access the computer just a key it's this
one I'm looking at this is the SS in
machine
el momento de mio vamos a su milk a loco
Paola Paola
so I copy paste copy paste and copy
paste so it's been sent by email let's
imagine it's got to the machine we open
the document it's a perfect office and
we see that there's a warning there
saying perhaps been created with a new
of this version and the macros have to
be activated to see the content we
should see a yellow pop-up saying in
enabling macros so I copied it yesterday
maybe it's recorded that I own already
used it yesterday when they send the
document with macros you say enabling
and labeling there's a security warning
then nobody clicks on so this is the
small warning
I met exploit people did this I tested
yesterday I click and it's been saved
because the macros are being executed
and no because this is the market the
machine is connected no I know that this
Trojan was executed it was inside the
document
well it's connected to the machine in
Linux I could do an LS we'll see what
it's inside the machine I could move
around I would be inside with the street
facing a very simple where could secure
and UNC and see what the other machine
is doing this is the inject in the DLL
and the connection is launched and
everything is automated I'm here I would
need to see a wouldn't see the VNC of
the other machine so I have the virtual
machine in my
other virtual desktop I you don't see
the screen but I'm here it's just a
chunk because it's VNC there's a notepad
that's oh but I'm doing it in the
virtual machine but you've seen via BNC
spree fish fising spearfishing so
there's a lot of this type of spear
phishing and Malware in the documents of
this type there's a clear goal real
target for instance the government was
rolling with the browser a Java exploits
in that web server we sent the link from
the machine we click and the
vulnerability is exploited because
there's a Java that is vulnerable that's
all in this circle of the different
steps it was another step establishing a
repository I don't know if it's face but
it it exists the bad guys when he or she
gets into a machine they start to
download the tools the base databases
it's a repository for the bad guys what
the guys stores all that he gets it's
the foot hole the foot hole you need to
escalate a wall
it's a jumping machine what do you get
there you get in through a tool but
you're going to do network attacks
lateral movements password attacks and
you need other tools and you need to
download that into your foot hole from
the incident response this is relevant
because you can detect that somebody has
created that repository you see that new
tools are included in a repository so
you know that something is happening
so in these were the faces of in
Oshin but for the one who has to defend
you need to know that kill chain within
the chain of an intrusion where do I
need to put things to avoid those
intuitions antivirus could be there with
alerts and warnings saying that
something is happening
- well privilege escalation it's the
next phase I just have four more to show
you
vulnerabilities in the operating system
applications or in the third-party
system
Adobe Reader Java this type of
vulnerabilities configuration errors not
everything is vulnerabilities
maybe there's a configuration error that
can cause and/or allow somebody to
escalate privileges simple credit
credentials the privilege escalations
are horizontal I have specific
privileges I can get to another user
with the same privileges I'm not gaining
privileges I'm not becoming a root or
administrator be hard but I have
different privileges I'm another user on
university world if I'm a student a I
can be a student B and if there's
vertical escalation when I go up I
become an administrator I'm a root and I
have higher privileges if I'm a student
I want to be a teacher and I want to
have good grades so these are the two
privilege escalation modes yeah I
brought an example
none known vulnerability in Windows 7
there's more and less and less in
Windows 10 the last versioning we
understand this is getting more and more
complicated so it's more secure there
are tools that allow you to analyze the
patches that are installed in the
operating system in the OS and it it
proposes you one out of the list you
there's no LNS 506 it's an executable so
it proposes you
so you so the goal is that you are
protected with those batches in Windows
well the one I have it I wouldn't like
to have it installed this is the VNC yep
this is my mouse now there's a zoom on
it this is you so that has no privileges
I'm going to load the desktop there's a
powershell MS 16 old 32 is one that
exploits a vulnerability that allows me
to be an administrator so I loaded and I
execute it and well now I'm just calling
the function first
Moroccan there's a semi the opening here
and I escalated the privileges it's easy
well of course there's no antivirus
there's no patch it's easy but this
happens and we learned we learn what
happens when they are there no patches
every time I say the same joke I hope
that nobody is going to see these since
streaming people in in in my company
well these things happen you executor
PowerShell you escalate privileges and
from there on you can continue to play
if this machine is domain controller
server server that connects for instance
to a workstation to for a domain
administrator a key part of the network
it's dangerous I executed two commands
in the PowerShell the PowerShell is in
the internet I download it it's quite
simple so I'm saying a document with a
micro I execute a PowerShell and now I
become the administrator and that then I
could put a sniffer man in the middle I
can do a lot of things because I have no
restricted privileges to operate in that
machine because I'm an administrator now
that's fun
the most difficult part is to find the
mouse and nava classic example in the
privilege escalation is the the errors
in inverted commas in permissions in
services that are executed in a machine
this has happened to us elite Tunes by
Apple or the third party software the it
starts a service when the machine is
started to problems when you put an
entry because the services that starts
when you start Windows included in the
in the log you need double ecommerce
windows
looks for the behavior calls program dot
accident program files and the imagine
that the name of the service is my app
dot X a and so internally Windows tries
to execute that first than this than
this and finally this to get to my app
dot XA here this file doesn't exist this
file doesn't exist if I'm able if I have
writing permissions for this path for
this path and within up dear there are
eight more territories if I have a
writing permission in those pathways I
put my trojan and when the Machine
restarts the service is going to
executive my instructions that's the
normal functioning of Windows the double
double commas the Commerce and the
execution permission and then there are
commas but the my app dot XA would have
writing permission but I'll place my up
with my executable and I start the
machine to start again to restart I'm a
patient person
persistence means being patient there's
a command a ninja a command but there
are other tools to review and to check
what's happening a machine what are the
commands the services with permissions
or not and you haven't really you have a
reporter blender one of them is power up
it's a PowerShell and it may does five
hundred more checks I'm not going to
elaborate this is to escalate privileges
for you can have a register key to
install these the install a new a user
ad DLL injection you put a DLL and when
you start an application you can insert
a DLL that in fact executes its new code
there's a lot of lot of checking checks
and there's a report and it says the
next command that you're going to exceed
to exploit the vulnerability it's this
one you executed and then you discover
it it's all open source github imagine
you have 50 million of things in your in
your computer let's do the demo Danny
I'll talk to you afterwards I hope
you're watching me let's see what
happens in the demo strange ok I
discover that I have here one here too
and here another one no it's the same ok
ok
that's one my windows no Claire's always
good Adam I have to move my mouse
it's just here
I'm going to load the power up now I put
the zoom on I don't know how to type
power exploit this is a guy who stole
note on PowerShell for red teens he
explores Active Directory finding server
and numerating users or sessions this is
a very powerful tool I'm just doing the
privilege escalation part only until the
same with point to point I load the
PowerShell yes I want to executors and
now have a lot of commands and functions
like invoked or objects and this is the
report with all the things it's checking
permissions the auto runs also another
way of escalating is not through a
service but well through what in the reg
edit we have permissions for execution
in those files and we can escalate from
there all the check-ins XML in here more
specifically in this virtual machine dll
service it says everyone
anybody can modify the executable abuse
function the service binary name skocy
so you do execute that part and this
binary would be modified in such a way
that when the machinery starts it will
be executed and it will do what I want
the escape wanted to create a new user
as a demonstrator this executive serve
ball is replaced by one and he becomes
the administrator for that machine
by lame em over here
hockey game pocket or the shit you shot
there's switch user yes it was there to
admit administrator and user I go back
to mine with under its unprivileged user
poor guy and then I execute the
modification of the service so net user
John power one two three and that's the
way I know that I'm here
this will start when the machinery
starts so we wait for two months one
week we have another vulnerability in
the harddrive and the machinery starts
again it's interesting because it didn't
it didn't work apparently maybe this
surface is going to execute when you do
the log on this is another vulnerable
software let's see no it didn't create
the other administrator there's an error
but it's it's been executed but nothing
happened how do I know I don't know
nevermind I I tested it yesterday I left
a trace but then I deleted the user by
hand and maybe it's not properly done I
don't know but it should have worked
but anyway power exploit that's the
concept and permission error report etc
this is good for us because I don't want
you to just remember the techniques but
the
ethical concept various ways of
escalating privileges once we are
administrators well we've had to use XP
exploits we do we need to do an internal
mechanisms in that workstation maybe
there's a person with no access with no
visibility I have to move around the
machine I need to see the databases the
false for servers the domain
administrator I have to look for the
dual to really see the risks in Aria so
we need to know to know the critical
assets in the architecture for instance
the Active Directory there you there's
the uses but maybe my customers database
is not there but at least from the
Active Directory I will I will access to
other places the identity management
repository database etc once it is
compromised I detect the security
elements what are the antivirus what are
the warnings
is there an IPS in IBS we need to smell
what's in there before scanning the
ports and the network instead before
generating events we spoke about KPI
that time to detection 2 minutes so what
we need to know what to do before it
starts the warning so you have to be
noiseless and very discreet before
launching active attacks how do we do
this well asking the right questions
when you get into machine you see DHCP
what is the direction of the eyelids
will occupy a DNS gateway privileges
there is an ATP filtering through
wireless when you have all you have to
do big back home and it's not easy to
take this part how do
get food terror of databases without
them realizing in the that's gonna peak
in the network's II know somebody has
downloaded for terror Sony didn't
realize millions and trillions on
kickers were stolen I've seen filtration
attacks through wee-fee Wi-Fi what a
compromised machine with bacon Trump
when we take a Wi-Fi connection we want
to connect with see the names of the
Wi-Fi because there's a the Bakke
beacons and through this thing is that
cannot be detected because it's not IP
traffic in fact in fact there is an
exfiltration of information that's you
this is possible to exfiltrate through
Wi-Fi and through DNS and through many
other protocols market is a Rob joy Dara
movimento what does rob machines really
so that you can protect against
well he talks about pasta hash it's the
most commonly used technique to move
laterally I take the token the hash not
the password but the hash string and I
use it as a credential it's like a
cookie in HTTP but in ntlm Active
Directory why is it possible if we
escalated privileges we can do the
dumping of hashes depending on the
machine we can even see the plain text
password we can only see the hash of
this password we can use it as an
authentication token into in connect to
a machine as if we had the real password
it's called a pass the hash it's quite
known well known it's an architectural
problem another problem it's something
that is necessary within the Microsoft
world but there's got no solution the
documents in which in microsoft speak
about passed the hat the hash well use
the don't you use the administrator
accounts reduced your exposure level
especially for your password speakers
that you're gonna steal them steal them
from you if you do an administrative
task in a machine if you don't want your
a password to be stolen you please reset
the machine and restart the machine you
can get the hash but not the plaintext
when Microsoft saying that you have to
empty the hard drive because have to
restart the machine to delete the memory
password well if you talk about this IT
guy well you're gonna get this password
stolen from you I'm not going to to to
to empty all my on my drive it's it
through Microsoft document yes but you
you put it in the plaintext Paulo team
there's there's a struggle there it's a
problem from this point of view it's
okay IT and security weak collaborate
when we have this type of conversations
do I accept it I'm not going to budge it
yeah I want you to laugh again we can
talk about patching if you want why do
people never patch
why don't you bash because they break
things that's the problem of patching
Microsoft is delegating in me the
patching process wife in pastor hush
they get energy machine if it's a
workstation of a ministry to of a domain
and it's a domain password oh my
goodness
horrible it's the end we heard you all
right it was almost the last time
lateral movement Network attacks that's
the harsh of their vulnerabilities in
other systems I know it vulnerable
Tomcat a vulnerable talker and then I
can get into the whole it sometimes
happens because we know the network some
better than you but people know my
systems much better than me in fact an
example that I use and maybe people are
going to love because if you're you've
collaborated with this this in the past
the hash there's somebody getting in to
a user PC these are the PCs and he wants
to access to back-end services where the
database is but there's no direct
connection because they are in different
networks there's a firewall segmented
network they try to do things but
suddenly the red team guys say there is
a printer server that is connected to
the back end it's windows has to print
reports and these printer server is in
the user networks so we chomp and we
connect to the printers server until we
get to the back end
something that happens in all companies
is that antivirus service have access to
everything people don't want to have 18
antivirus repositories one for
production net where other for users and
the same for SCCM with patching
platforms with bakka platforms any
centralized service should be
differentiated user production truth
falseness but we are doubling and
duplicating the infrastructure and we
and we're not rich
we need budget for that we need a big
budget for that so we go back to the
same problems how vulnerable are we are
can we do so this green line is not that
green lateral movement we can see it
clearly here you have a demo of how do
you python from cali that compromises
the same Windows 7 and then it access it
has access to a Linux we need a lot of
virtual machines this is the environment
and and I'm going to show you a video of
course it's not very attractive but to
see the scenario this is the Kali were
the anonymous here that's Rob Joyce and
the IP he's gonna hack he's gonna enter
in this Windows 7 with a stupid
vulnerability this Windows 7 has two
interfaces it's a case of the printers
server so two interfaces one for
production production in one of her
users and this is the Linux in another
network from Kali
I would never access the line looks
because the IP read redirection
redirection has protocols that are I
cannot avoid so this is the video where
we can see what happens
I'm going to tell you what it says here
there is a meter praetor that is
established with a macro I'm there at
the administrator here there is a
privilege escalation exploit ipconfig in
Windows this is the IP number plus a
second IP starting by 10 we see that
this is the windows the virtual machine
windows with the two eyepiece it's the
Howards domain now it's my it's my
home's network now it's called marvel
this is the Linux with this IP three
virtual machines the Kali is this one
where the meter preacher is and here it
is a executing a script do you do the
check-in from the Windows machine to the
network not from the Kali I'm an
intruder I don't know what are the IPS
are on the other side who's seen what
happens in the Windows 7 it sends pins
to all the Class C it looks for machines
their linux gateway I don't know
the broadcast IP something that responds
to a ping stopping a Sri Lanka Vallecano
per game Moylan
this is a the accelerated video because
normally it's very slow and now it's
continued oh no I said to Loyola Canio
just doesn't do the scanning
allow me mama Naraku mama bestow as
we've seen earlier but there's IPS that
have been lifted
I just for the Rooter in and I convert
this Windows 7 into pseudo Rooter and
because I've got a gateway I can see I
can get in here this is exploit and I
can do in its CP this is a very very
slow scanner but it's an meta exploit so
you have to specify the ports you want
to scan and the our hosts also we're
going to tune the number of connections
just a few ports let's just put a few in
so it's quicker otherwise it'll take
hours to scan there's the typical ones
then it specifies the network specific
IP number five
from one to six you run it but that it
says folks because it's badly written so
you write it properly and you can see
the IP two hops up the two open ports
and here you can see that two five has a
whole series of things that are open and
that's Linux then I add more ports
because I'm gonna go direct fill the
Linux I run and it's gonna start
scanning all the ports these supports
that weren't there before because it had
a smaller reach and some of them several
of them rather vulnerable I knew that
they were vulnerable because I'm just
trying to show you here how it would
pivot within a network it's a service
which is vulnerable Linux
it can really be met or exploited
no I
the payload it's running now it tells us
it's open so you could run commands it
doesn't have a groan but it's in there's
not much more to it just for password
etc so
here you can see exactly the movement we
used Windows seven and four liner we've
routed traffic but via Windows seven to
attack Linux that's the scenario I've
got an example of hash path to think of
use it it's a very simple example
basically we've exploited a
vulnerability I've got a meta propraetor
machine use these hashes as if I'd
stolen a cookie in HTTP which could be
used with an HTTP protocol and this is
something that's a feature of Windows I
can bring PS X X I can do this if I've
got the hashes it's now specifying the
IP address of Cali which it's going to
send the meta printer to the
administrator and the uses the one
that's at the top and their credentials
because they can be as tough as you like
and that's sufficient for me and then
thing it does is to connect puts the
that you can run and you can do this
just for automatic tasks you can just
say ok let's soft PSX and you say no no
I've got four processes
they're just features of the operating
system people don't use them but the bad
does bad guys can do that as well so
we've used an exploit here unresolved
problems of security there are lots of
unresolved problems with security you
have to be persistent it's very simple
you have your administrator you can put
something in this register you can
install the software you enable remote
access you create a new password new
services what's important is to go as
honest as possible so it's not the same
changing the screen saver I actually
read an article recently of different
ways avoiding the auto runs application
that's all those that when you start up
that's run so if you wouldn't happen the
startup which is update of hover and you
put full comma and another application
you won't see it on auto runs but it
will run and all you got to do is put
comma in a command these sorts of tricks
that appearing in articles and research
papers these I would have used to keep
persistence up when we talk about it
professional ta o there are people and
I'm not going to point the finger here
there are some people that do their own
things they have their own tools they
don't actually upload upload them to
total virus which it allows you to make
a connection the handmade troy trojans
okay an example persistence the meta
exploit that we saw early can also be
used because it's got a module called
persistence what it does is it puts a
meta pre meta pritter there makes a key
and every time the machine is rebooted
it's initiated it starts and finally
let's talk about filtering which can be
more or less difficult there are some
companies they've got USBs where they
can browse and there are others a
completely opposite you can go there go
to the proxy
you can go in often to Internet and you
can make use of the first in the market
which is when most companies have most
traffic or it's like as if you go to
Zara on sales day travel agents what
about July you know go to the peak
traffic times that's when information
gets filtered in they're good but
they're more advancing such as DNS
tunnels ICMP tunnels or Wireless
channels you know imagination is power
you can even put an underground access
point like Rob AP a physical intrusion
to install access point to 7:00 o'clock
in the morning when there's nobody in
the company before you go to work and
they only use the access point to get
information before any warning being let
off and these are things you have to
learn you have to learn what to do so
they don't get an access point
physical security how you managed to
reach this points and all the previous
stages we have detected anything but
these are just the lessons that you
learn so as to put the necessary
security measures up there and now I'll
leave you time for questions and some
references to videos the second one you
must must watch and you can't ask any
questions until you know how to answer
the questions that Rob Joyce arts asks
in the second video questions please but
do use the microphone
I'll pull eCos it okay you public better
online the other talks were really good
you're gonna hear me now yeah virtually
all companies ports 80 and 443 are left
open how can we avoid somebody creating
a reverse tunnel from a machine they've
got at home when they go home you know
to do something how can we avoid that
happening well it really depends on the
type of tunnel I'd be a little bit more
conservative when I would stay that
everybody leaves the ATL four four three
open because I'd actually say then in
the proxy we only use white lists for
example if you're talking about a
doctor's press or banks there you can
browse everything else is forbidden but
there's somebody there somebody in the
PC that's gonna just try to browse
that's where Spanish when I go and have
a coffee or watch YouTube I always
complain so it's something that if we
were going to be practical but certain
something only can be done in
environments where the security levels
are so controlled that you can actually
demand this kind of radical measure and
I'm talk and I've done this before I had
we had this we had two URLs and what
happened there was a list of a 500 URLs
that were hand managed oh you would see
the ABC or whatever but webs aren't two
URLs if you go to wherever they'll do
all sorts of gets and that works people
look at the web as if it's and they're
looking at we wipe it in the 90s
they see the text and they block all the
lists the proxies the categories and
those sorts of things and that also
failed but they wanted to see things so
it really is complicated next thing your
specific tunnels okay specific tunnels
that break sss those it says else you
can break SSL's if you're not going to
end up in prison the Data Protection Act
I know it's a it's a bit of an
exaggeration
okay and I don't want but if you so you
want to it's a proxy sniffer yeah how
can I do that so you break the SSL in
the specific categories you can say oh
here you can't break SSL for example
bank's documents in the legal department
etc etc and with this you can also free
but we don't break this I sell it's
completely impossible but there are
other advantages when we see that
there's a post with a fine that occupies
more than fourteen magus will stop it
because we've reduced a proxy categories
and you can have a cloud and open source
so we want an open cloud that's open
okay database up you go to avoid this
this SSL we look at the size of a post
so you need to see what's being done
what they are what URLs so having said
all of this just as everything in
security there's no perfect solution
unless you can use physical strength
physical force so I could give you some
recommendations
that help that aren't gonna do do away
with the problem any other questions
come on haka colleagues I'm itching for
your questions come on there must be
somebody we've still got a good amount
of time for questions
this is more an opinion than a question
do you think the u.s. is really cutting
edge in one of this you said that I
thought that I said I know that the k
APPA is to me those it's the u.s.
it's light years ahead of us
we're worried here about primary school
things just look at the budgets that
they spend on security
melty security and defense and what this
what other countries spend you just get
an idea but when they buy
vulnerabilities companies they'll buy a
vulnerability just for a million how
much they sell it for I I imagine
there'll add 15 to 20 percent no just to
put the brand on it so that light years
ahead but do you think about it
what about Israel Israel's streets ahead
as well yeah yeah yeah okay nobody like
the u.s. though fortunately we get on
with the US people we don't want to be
North Korea baby for me also they do
data backup which is good see much
course that's going through the conmigo
and do you agree with me that they're
cutting edge
sorry he's asking or saying something
without using the mic yes
they're cutting edge but actually think
Israel URIs is like a huge clumsy
elephant just tramples on everything I
think Israel is just a lot more subtle
yeah you're right this u.s. is a locked
noisier but it's not the same as having
this tower team there's a I don't knows
forty or sixty I mean if you've got
sixty and one one goes awry like Snowden
I'm not saying that's a good thing or
not i don't have surgeon should have
done what he should that's a more
political issue but if you've got sixty
um
one turns out to be a rotten apple he
was a contractor initially but it's such
a big team I think they're very
technologically cutting edge I've got
lots of startups and Israeli a Silicon
Valley is very much security conscious
but their operations may be actually
Israel and the US isn't so different
ants are different it may well be that I
was gonna say I tau is from Israel but I
don't think it is actually no maybe I
said an apple app I don't know it's
getting a bit late come on you're all
tired Danny come on a question
have you not learnt anything from my
talk nothing
Danny and I used to hack together when
we were younger and I had hair
aku Yin are you taking the microphone up
to somebody who wants to ask a question
hello it's a general question would it
be worthwhile to carry on using Windows
I mean should we bother with Windows my
personal opinion is the following
yes no it really depends for what what
environment you're talking about
I like Azure because it's got a a
privacy philosophy which is streets
ahead of other cloud companies it's the
only company that's got all the data
protection seals they get in Europe it's
about they're very much aware of privacy
issues I could talk a lot about cloud
the cloud because at the end you've got
Patriot art and whole series of other
things but imagine that you've got an
infinite budget for all security but the
US has got a piece of paper that which
says this is a national security matter
just give me the server the Microsoft
will give it to them and they would tell
me about it so there's a point comes in
which whatever you do is going to be
useless having said that I think it
really depends I look use my home
workstation with my eight virtual
machines it's a complete world
I think Windows is good I like cooling
windows and then this is the new Windows
10 which has ATP from a business
viewpoint actually evolving a lot
they've you started using RT RT
I like Microsoft on my workstation
with and actually with an administrator
without power you can't connect so I
kind of really depends everybody
suffered from these sorts of things
we'll just stop with the hash patch
that's not been solved the unsolved
major problem actually the other day I
was in a training course for a company
here in Spain there were several days
from the first day they said to me they
had 12,000 Windows XP I can't say the
company but so I showed them
eleven thousand nine hundred ninety nine
so I just wanted to know your opinion
about this the fact that there are
companies that have still got Windows XP
they said it was an economic problem but
knowing for example that part chip
patches for one a cry for XP they they
still know that there are lots of XP s--
out there there's a complex world and
the peasants in charge of security their
only task the only duty is to prioritize
risk that's what I'm here for I have to
prioritize risks so maybe twelve
thousand X piece is probably a lesser
problem the fact I don't have a backup
or abundant contingency FP I've got a
budget so with that budget I've got to
do what I can with the worst and the
biggest risks that my organization have
it may well be that twelve thousand x
piece isn't actually the biggest risk
for my organization because they've got
compensatory controls you know because
they've got a firewall may well be that
that's not a priority I mean I wouldn't
say to how are you got twelve thousand
I've got maybe I've got more but the
thing is the person in charge of
security needs to know what their risks
are and spend their money wisely cuz
there's always gonna be a risk there in
fact we've already accepted that gap
they're an infant number of projects I
know I'm giving the general reply but
it's the plight the pride I have to give
you mine I'd shoot the guy personally
and if I say to you that there was
nobody in charge of security
what would you say them just put your CV
there hand out your CV it does happen
it's an issue of security maturity
unfortunately everybody is and aware of
this this room isn't full
not everybody's
where people are driving this forward
but in in eBay didn't exist 20 years ago
and we already had security problems
then so it's a subject you know it's
it's awareness-raising in large
companies and I hope this is a
medium-sized company that they've got to
12,000 XPS but it lived its time it's
just time I've had major security
problems in many environments even
though there isn't somebody with a
security hat on it may well be that the
CEO is in charge of security so even
though they don't have that that post he
plays the role of the security person in
charge of security what was mrs. respect
to somebody to take care of security
sometimes there's nobody god I don't I
go on she will be mom come on the last
one I know and you might offer career
like yeah fun everybody nobody at the
back of the room has asks any questions
and there's lots of people at the back a
couple of things so I first I'd like to
know how many people are the red how
many people are in the red team in your
case that's a good question Telefonica
in our case is three-dimensional we've
got so much security that we don't
control it but telefónica provides
security services I'm in charge of
internal security so that I think bad
happens to us but there's a friend of
mine who sells security to other
companies the person that sends security
has got thousands thousands of people
working with him and what a thousand say
or nine hundred him something and he's
wearing the security hat he's not the
red team
is the person that can put a firewall in
your computer yours and I consume
services I don't go to the market to
contract services so there's this
knowledge exchange and there's a very
very big team of hundreds of people the
internal security team they're also
hundreds of us not in my domain
cuz I I'm in charge of security for
countries there's one that's in charge
of security for Spain and I mean
telefónica group has 400 companies in
Germany in the UK Argentina Mexico Peru
Chile and each has its own security
director and everyone has a red team so
telefónica spain which has 22,000
employees has a very big security team a
very big red team in Ecuador weather and
I've got a thousand telefónica Ecuador
will have I don't know probably a guy
that just plays the violin goes to the
market to get play and highs in services
it depends in practice I didn't reply to
your question however a lot is all I can
say and they're never enough can I ask
the second question now which is bearing
in mind that you've got a big team to
what extent are you able when you have
to report to superior and struck with
the CEO how can you how can you impose
the needs of this big team otherwise the
CEO wins the battle well to a point
like a seam is better salary wound up I
got a bit lost with a question how do I
manage I've spent two years at
telefónica unfortunately recently I've
been sort of being able to push forward
and make things happen I've there's been
a sort of a free external a warning
which has helped certain decisions being
taken to be taken within the company so
I can say as things stand today I speak
directly to telefónica chairman I don't
talk about Mehta Preta but I talk about
the fact I've got 12,000 XPS window XPS
or some kind of other problem so that
it's dealt with and in my CEO and I'm
not talking about the CEO of the
operators that's why they've got the
head of security CEO the global CEO as
it's very closely related to us and he
supports what we do and this year he
decided that probably is important to
take noses of us so we don't have that
problem
if you'd have come last Friday maybe but
just like all organizations there's no
organization when the security IT
relationship is that good mean it's top
down down top for their companies in
ibex that arrive in which person in
charge if a security needs to spend 3
million euros and they can't they can't
go up but in the case in my case I
talked to the chairman of the company
and I'm gonna tell him things that
aren't true but in fact I don't have to
negotiate with my CEO
it's really the philosophy of the way
week Garf and security McKenzie and
others will say oh you know it's better
to do it this way I think change over
time about seeing in the sector in
general is that security it's being
taken out of the technological field so
this fair playing these kind of
conversations it's not just a matter of
saying oh give me some money for this
and the money says no no I work cuz I
need to give some money to production so
you can get shot down it's complex
that's what makes role you know that you
have to belt title just let alone so
things and everybody can do it no
because in the end security can say no
no no don't do that cause it's unsafe
we're competing in a market in which you
need to be agile there are many
competitors the business and payroll
having said that
did you see you are watching football
when wanna cry or was there you watched
football don't you
it didn't affect our production it
affected some workstations but it didn't
affect production that says a lot about
a telefónica so you've had an incident
but people were able to send whatsapp's
they were able to watch a football phone
each other there was some pop patches
there yeah there were lots of patches
but it didn't affect production and
that's very important
in addition to other help that we got
from NCV
Wes Theresa accomplished a kvo some
super mock antes de que ellos la vista
yeah I know you well don't say where you
work maybe you have to twelve thousand
XPS work running well I'm sorry we I
guess I know you have a question one of
the most important problems that we had
with him when a cries that microsoft
didn't want to have a patch they don't
want to publish do you have out of
support platforms but there was a batch
for when i cry so i thought about that
if you're gonna publish it why don't you
give it to us before it happens
be reasonable you're waiting for me to
ask you for the patch i'll give it to me
now
beforehand that's my reflection and
maybe Bill Gates who should answer this
bill if you watching me answer I saw a
question
I left hand I'm sorry because I couldn't
attend the whole of this talk I was here
at the end a problem that we normally
have in in CB I don't think we have a X
piece well when you have get of service
pastor production especially for complex
services it's very hard from the point
of view of di and security to ensure
that everything is okay but normally
especially in certain services we
succeed especially for the commercial
siding commercial applications and
services it's different
the deployment manual of this mega
solution
well first you deactivate Linux you
disable that and this and that do you
have the same problems in telefónica how
do you tell an Oracle or
if it's insecure for me how can you tell
that those big guys about these problems
well it depends on their company in C
Bay maybe that's hard for in C bit maybe
it's difficult for you to run an Oracle
I in my past I was had this big
technology company and and I was using
commands in in their own in their
applications I'm executing commands and
they told me well we put you in the
roadmap there's a part of expectations
management internally if this is a red
flag in security is it viable not to
change our technology is this a medium a
medium or intermediate worry maybe I
have to accept it it's a risk management
problem if you are worried change your
technology just fire them threat them
threaten them if it's something
intermediate if it's you have to manage
your risk maybe you can change your
technology and your IT or your business
or your Sarah IT can tell you that this
is nothing there's no problem there's a
part of government there has to be
orchestrated with security committees
with signatures with risk analysis this
is for me a red flag this is hi Clarissa
T great impact from 500 to 200 million
euros I validated this with my risk
Department and I know this is a red flag
you have a data protection legal
department everybody can help you there
and please you are going to sign it
because you want to get it for you and
I'm going to keep it here next year
we'll review the same paper are you
going to sign the same are you going
there's an acceptation of risk if they
accept the risk it's ok step problem
you have a security committee where you
can submit to this type of problems with
visibility you need people with
empowerment warning you it's a there's a
fire there's a red flag but I mean I
cannot fight them if they don't want to
accept well I was sharks are in many
occasions because it's about risk
management if you have to do it what I
want you and now it's your problem it's
your responsibility when there's there's
an incident we know that you accepted it
of course you'll be murdered but at
least you've warned them you've given
you'll you you had given all the
visibility to the problem it's your role
and just one more question
I think you switched it off it said five
doesn't matter
thank you very much I hope you
appreciated it especially those who are
watching online