when US adult hello everybody I'm the
first speaker and I'm nervous this is me
these are my social networks and
everything that my colleague just said
and the different conferences where I've
been presenting things oder navaja etc
and first of all I'd like to thank my
colleague Alfonso who's been helping me
out with all the conferences and growing
professionally in the area of security
etc but let's go let's get down to
business I'm gonna be speaking about
social networks free networks and the
ideas are based on the user's privacy
and there are many okay we're gonna go
into the problems of traditional social
networks as a microphone traditional
problems like toxicity Commons addiction
so therefore what solutions have people
implemented in order to be able to
communicate we have different solutions
micro blogging blogs and water
conclusions can we draw from this and
what measures can we put in place in
order for these social networks not to
end up disappearing so what do we
understand what do we mean by a social
network on that first in the first
country or in the first place we have
platform Facebook etc and then a social
network which is a whole structure of
people who want to communicate this is
really important and we need to
understand this very well and the first
problems which you see is toxicity and
messages in any social networks like
today you can not send messages without
offending anybody and some people write
negative offensive messages
this leads to a very mean atmosphere and
there's a couple of networks that are
trying to make sure that people would
not write anything that just comes out
of the blue because you may hurt people
you may some people may feel offended or
there's also threats etc so I summarize
this by saying that there is a lot of a
toxicity you may complain but without
offending anybody without meaning
offense for anybody the next thing that
I wanted to talk about is addiction this
happens in free social networks and in
conventional networks you try and
compare yourself and make sure that
you're better than everybody else when
you see something somebody in the know
social network and you don't know what's
going on you want to connect to it
everybody wants to go in and see what it
looks like so there's a lot of
fluctuation of users many come and go so
network grows then it drops shrinks and
it's not like when people create
accounts and they just leave them there
and another thing that I wanted to say
is that since people try and compare
themselves this may generate depression
anxiety you need to use them you need to
be online all the time and these are
happens with conventional and free in
networks and then there's a whole issue
of censorship there's bad sort of
censorship which is the whole platform
as it's happening in many countries with
Facebook YouTube Twitter and there are
some associations that are trying to
make sure the internet will be free but
like I said this censorship is about any
you need to communicate you're gonna
start seeing alternatives and the best
thing is to know what they are instead
of having them there and just block them
and having people look for other
channels that you won't know this is why
I believe that this censorship makes a
no sense because people are gonna keep
on communicating and there's another
sort of censorship which is more
interesting and which has to do with the
contents especially with pornography
with x-rated things and then there are
some strange channels like kid who had
hormone problem with one nipple one
female breast and a male breast and one
of his nipples or breast only one of
them were censored so we see problems
like this and there are places you can
resort to you when your contestant is
censored for instance showing a pregnant
women something that is nice but others
believe that this should be censored in
any case these these are things we can
use and also the issue of money the
content in advertising if you use a
LinkedIn it will say sign up for this
master's course but and everything's
like commercial and there are some
solutions that say you have a platform
where you can upload your data and let
the media use them yes so Dean so this
is done with bitcoins or cryptic points
you can give your data but not to a
specific company but to our platform so
that people may use them and then we see
changes in the price we see more and
more data so that prices go down in the
old days you could say your data for 60
$70 and then they're worth cents
the only thing was this is that there
are more people more data are generated
so obviously there's going to be this
drop in prices what I'm going to tell
you is an introduction of why but in
this presentation we're going to see how
people try to look for alternatives
because of the problems we've seen
before an interesting thing is that they
you need to keep existing we cannot
avoid accessory or addiction but
monetizing is something that doesn't
appear anywhere a social network doesn't
keep your data doesn't solve and doesn't
use them because because this is based
on the fact that everybody will set up
on their own a social network and you
can sign up or create your own if you're
not interested in this well so they are
free there's no company back in them
they're all independent projects the
only problem this is a scalability
because it so happens that when there
are many users you'll realize that this
is a good solution for them and that
they like the way they can communicate
with smaller groups and so people start
signing up and then this platform there
are too many users it simply won't hold
is that the manager who ministry who
says the limits you see what happens
when you allow our users to just do
whatever they want in free to act and
this is just a summarize of all the
different social free social network so
we've been analyzing together with
Alfonso like I said
and Twitter was created the first part
has to do with micro blogging and the
rest will be blogging or enriched
blogging protocols etc and this is the
protocol on this slide and URL it's very
well set up and here you can see the
whole ecosystem of free social networks
and depending on the protocols some of
them into relating to communicate and
you see our messages are sent from one
to another these are based on the
distribution they also have their it
towards me in soccer supporting
connective a connector you don't need to
be a specific one in order to see the
messages that are going back and forth
first of all there's a conciliation tree
well this is just to give you an idea of
the whole ecosystem that exists here's
the red fairy verse and this is based on
microblogging different servers that can
generate messages and you allow them to
be to communicate and regardless of
where you're registered you can see
other people's messages are as long as
they share the protocol or their status
so here you can see the muffed and we're
seeing here is all the social free
social networks and the largest
employment is the one we have here which
is master the one that is more used is
more broadly used as master than it
started being used in Japan very much
there's very trendy
you can send messages that would be
censored by other social networks so
let's assume there were like five
hundred thousand users in order to make
sense out of all of this there is master
then there's quit another smaller one
but this is the whole universe and this
is where we have the big one which is
mastered and then G etc etc so this
research been going on for a year and we
started with Macedon because we saw that
there were many problems with security
and we wanted to expand it because if
you try and understand a master Dan
right from a scratch you need to go to G
new social new social and this is based
on messages are generated projects are
based Federation you look for a list
list where you can amass hang of the
problem with this is that this is also
when they look for instances many of
them are no longer there because people
have moved to another level other
instances or another social network
there's another interesting thing you
know we can't quit it
would have been good sweetie and
everybody has their instance and is
based on the language if I speak Spanish
or Catalan or whatever so this way you
people can communicate with our problems
and
and but an important problem with this
is that can we see what is being
prejudiced all the messages that are
going back and forth can I read them can
I see them basically yes because there's
no authentication protocol but in any
case there's a limit you cannot see the
first twit that appear but in this case
you can messages are sequential so that
you can look up all these messages in
different instances do some mapping and
well this has been open for two years
and you can look at the messages saving
millions so you can you can find out
well all the users whether they're
administrators because the first thing
is to sign up as usual become the
administrator to the first see no
problem - the problem with
authentication we see that with g1 s and
s warriors
[Music]
service denial service with Salmonella
capabilities do you create users no mo
will fit in different content you don't
move the user is behind whatever you are
discussing there see you can see what
everybody is saying with this because
depending on what you say you may get in
trouble messages and users in quitter
this is easy you create an account you
send a message and then you have the
idea at the level of the last user on
the last message so you go back and you
simulate the maximum amount of users as
you have an idea rough idea of how many
users or how many messages I need to
pick in order to have my own databases
type of blocking or delays or anything
for days yes it is 40 million you have
to buy one repetition per second have
you do it one month from the house all
the users on a network in four days is a
very interesting thing a possibility so
let's send the one to master on which is
[Music]
more problems Japanese is a huge
allows for constant warning and they can
fix messages there's advertising cleaner
it's a pure what do you connect the more
widely used and those that are censored
if you have one you don't want to
receive those messages siempre es porque
allows hatred pretty no graffia just
scan these messages just examples
doesn't matter what you like you'll find
it there if you want to find a group of
people who like the things you like you
can security problems can you monitor
messages or users generated by GNU
there's no limitation you can see the
message is one by one or 1440 you can
here you can pick a group of messages
for two messages for instance
and you can do all this in four days
instead of a year there's no
authentication know everything etcetera
so rough this is a very small instance
for instance and this allows you to see
all the existing relations or the
mapping what users who talks to whom how
many I can see how many messages you've
sent you can do a whole map it's
possible to do it in small scale you can
not do the whole network real-time you
can make your network grow for instance
they're using key words a power of
whatever people are interested in and
you may say well I'd like to know what's
being discussed here and it's a free all
you need to do is to just get in and
this you uh start stalking you can
create all the users that I deem
necessary if I want to come 2000 users
in just a petition to get the
authentication token I send a post to
the instance and in a sense we capture
it sends me a confirmation email you set
up your account and instead of creating
an instance I put the whole listing of
1,400 instance then you create water
school the transversus of a user to the
same email account in all instances
instead of having a single user and you
can control 2,400 in only one just in
just one email address please
give me a camp child because there's a
problems never captured because it's not
difficult
oh so I made get in trouble is the issue
of fighting is interesting to be
validated so in these social networks
green tick in master the first and she
on the frequent frequently asked
questions what you see is an icon if you
read the FA use so with that win nobody
looks at it some people may believe that
this is a real account the president of
the government for instance Private Eye
since nobody knows who's behind an
account like this could be anywhere
anybody so you could impersonate
somebody there's no technology that
allows you to control this issue because
of development problem for cannot please
kids or behave and so what if I want to
create accounts but not just not in all
the existing instances but to any users
in one same instance I need to check my
mailbox
we have a junk mail for instance
temporary one like yup mail I can create
all the users everyone so here I say
create hundred users and just a matter
of minutes and users you can have but
there are tokens you can do anything you
can do messages or so masteren just
allowed you to erase to get rid of users
developers said you just to go into the
database and europe race them my hand
but there's no tool to wipe them all
[Music]
especially for inactive non active users
because some people just try out the
technology and they just leave the most
famous in social and everyone to know
why you're blocked because not everybody
can fit in 700,000 and if your
generators and users you can attend a
service and if you per se or 200 2400
transversal users
if you have advertisements in the web -
tossing their messages this is like any
other socially appears a few seconds
because it keeps us scrolling down
because people keep sending messages to
the messages and stay there
fixed so for instance in the 2400 people
when I sent the click or just once was
seen once 10 seconds maybe you could
visualize it viewers see it for a second
but seventy four hundred forty seven
hundred people that it's very difficult
to control and finally example there was
this other example with cover channel
there was an instance and this is for
real they would use the dolphin language
and there's no joke so we set up a
coding in order to send coded messages
using this so we could send this kind of
message using this kind of coding it was
kind of cool because people didn't know
what is going behind the scenes and you
can use this sort of channels in order
to exchange information you just use an
instance with a lot of activity and send
the messages through that way so this is
the micro-blogging network feed I varies
as you know the micro-blogging instances
need to use captures because otherwise
they're in big trouble then we have pump
IO which is kind of different they don't
consider themselves as micro bloggers
they are group based then there is the
activity pub and activities drink
protocols that are also used by Twitter
and Facebook
it's all based
on exchanging messages subscribing to a
message feed it all has the same basis
so you subscribe to a list and you don't
have a general feed you just have a
group of users and decide which messages
you want to watch and you are sent only
those kind of messages that is different
from all the messenger applications you
know that are totally different in this
case are very few users very few
instances this wind hasn't been really
successful and the number of users has
gone down from 170,000 to only 20,000
this is also based on status net and but
in this case it went somewhere else they
used the Corps they edited it and they
set up this social network as you can
see there are very few instances
published there are two different things
when you create an instance you want
people to know about that instance and
to get logged in case you want to have
people talking about a particular topic
but then you can create an instance that
you don't want people to know about and
you just want a few number of users
talking about that and here you can find
dirty dirty things and that well very
nice thing saying so as I would say in
the row groups in Catalan and Galician
language and spammers when you subscribe
to one of these groups you know merle is
one that what they are going to be
talking about it's no surprise even if
it's free it's it that doesn't mean that
they are not organized people are
actually a lot better organized than in
twitter there is this phonic group
called Pirates of Galatia and in Spanish
you have open off that is about
programming when it comes to login there
is no cap channel
you know that in some cases you have
email axes and others you don't in
others the proces is closed so starting
up an account isn't as simple as it
looks like when it is closed it lets you
derive the authentication to or the pump
io servers so you don't need to have an
account you can have an account
somewhere else use that account for
example the one with data mass you can
use that one you can go to the
authentication step and start sending
messages using copy channel etc the
authentication is derived so for example
think if you have Instagram and LinkedIn
you don't need to authenticate yourself
in both you authenticate yourself in one
and behind the scenes you can use that
account in order to use the applications
of any of them the authentication is
just in one place and you can create
your profile instance have your
credentials there and then the rays and
authentication derivation this is quite
interesting and I think it should be
looked at because it is quite a good
solution for authentication issues when
it comes to authentication and Twitter
and Masterton Pompeo you can list the
number of users you can create Maps you
can see how they are related among
themselves and in this case you need
authentication in order to know what
your who your users are there's this
application that I share with all your
users on a panel so you don't have to do
anything you connect to this URL and you
just the users you have on that social
network in you you can see how many
users you have et cetera without
creating programs
Asian was as I was saying the network is
small and as I said it has several
problems and we have finally hoop Zilly
Zilly and diaspora share the same
protocols this project that we can see
there are Federation it's made up for
GDU diaspora Zilla and social home but
they aren't not balanced in terms of
user numbers basically we have this list
just based on the fact that everything
is known and published you have all the
listings with instances you can see how
many active users you have so if you are
into monitoring data and knowing the
issues that are discussed you can find
all the data here you know how many
people are currently active and you get
yearly summarized information however
here you can get that kind of
information for free because they want
these networks to be known so diaspora
is actually the one that's been more
successful it has six hundred and fifty
three thousand users whereas friend
dykey and social home and Zillah aren't
as successful because they haven't
created the need of knowing the social
network and connecting to it all the
data are available as I was saying and
if you want to analyze what's going on
in these social networks you just have
to log in and start working on it
bobzilla only has 480 users but it's
really cool and it was supposed to be
very successful however it wasn't it's
quite similar to Facebook
when it comes to the panel and the
organization on the website it uses just
a few nodes there were more there are
more and more users but it's not really
becoming a success the reason why is
maybe people don't know about it or they
prefer diaspora or other kinds of
interfaces I thought it was interesting
anyway they have 430 users and I said
but they only have 30 nodes that's quite
surprising but here you can see the list
where you can connect and there are many
different versions people create an
instance get connected and they decide
to use that instance or using all the
one but in the end of the day there
aren't any large numbers in terms of
users the problem is the usual one no
capture so I can automate our eyes the
registration process they ask for your
email account so you have to confirm
your email address but still there is no
capture so I can create users massively
I can have my users stored and perform
massive spams whenever I want I can use
cava channel and have people connecting
between different social networks etc
here now we go to diaspora where they
talk about pods that they call the
instance in different ways in order to
make a difference but the idea is the
same independent people who are interact
this project starts in Kickstarter and
Mark Zuckerberg invested on it he
thought well this is interesting because
they are replicating what they do but I
don't want to go too far from them just
in case they start using it I might need
to get back and say to them ok gave you
money know that you start off so now
guys
so they started in 2010 and their goal
is literally
to create facebook without using your
data that is I want to create a platform
with the same facilities that Facebook
has but I want to make money with your
data I want to do things differently
etcetera but they are looking for
publicity tracking recommend purchases
etc it's free and it's a smaller number
of people they want to continue with
this idea of sharing and work in the
same way as the Facebook but they want
to have a different business model as
per the notes all over the world you can
see them on a map they have two hundred
and seventy five the number of messages
is growing but when you look at the
history of active users you can see
there is a peak in 2015
I've been looking for information and I
really haven't found the exact figure
but my intuition is that in the social
network they don't want to have zombies
or inactive users so after a while if
the network hasn't been used these users
are just deleted this way they avoid
congestion or problems so in that point
in 2015 they decided to get rid of all
the users who hadn't used the
application in two months because it was
impossible otherwise half of the
messages here in freedivers come from
diaspora in this case the difference is
that we have the Capuchin diaspora said
let's do things right the project is
very good and we need to use capture
because authentication works a lot
better with kappa chats and that is very
good they also asked for your email
address and once you've created your
account the metadata of all the pictures
videos and things you upload are
automatically erased by default they
just get rid of them
and they give you the option of sharing
those data if you wanted they allow you
to connect to other social network so
this means that this project is working
well if you take a look at the capture
you can see that this is not a Google
like capture this is maybe ten years old
if you go to Linus the OCR gives you
tesseract and from an image you can pull
out the text that it has so what you can
see here is that from a URL you get a
hash that is the ID of the number and
then a time and that time did nothing
that or made nothing but noise that
number didn't change every time I axed
access to the page so you can actually
remove this from the request and ask the
image without noise so what is what
about creating a program that pulls out
an image every time you use it you can
actually create very easily capture
database and crack those captures
because you can tell people whenever you
get this ID you will get this capture so
it's very easy to create as many users
as you want but if you have tesseract
that requires five digits with different
characters etc if you get rid of the
noise that's even easier so in 50% of
the cases you were right so every time
for every two requests one was right so
if you know about rappers and how to
surf on HTML you can request make this
request very easily and you can create
as many accounts as you want when it
comes to the contents
this is the interface these are the
posts and the question is do they use
sequential IDs for all the comments so
that I can list all the users and
comments with G and a master don't or
pump IO
the answer is yes if I use the first ID
the one that is hello diaspora as alpha
if I use that very first one it is seven
years old so I can set up my program
from number nine on and then with the
join diaspora instance I can see
absolutely all the messages in this
social network pretty interesting isn't
it so the way I see it is that if I
would like to know what was the first
what the first message on Twitter was
it's impossible because it isn't stored
but here it is stored you can see the
subjects of discussion you can see also
statistics that come from the instance
itself you can see absolutely everything
that is very good and there are no
limitations in terms of ap I when I tell
you that you can create a list the IP
isn't going to change there is no
control whatsoever so that's where the
problem is if they are sequential and I
don't need to predict anything I just
can make a list you can see that the ID
is a hash and in this case you cannot
list the social network that doesn't
allowed you to know who all the users in
this network are because every time a
new user was created a new number was
created as this one here you can look up
for them by name but it's more complex
it's easier maybe when you try to look
for administrators by looking for people
who have admin in their usernames but
you cannot look for all the users that
were created
this is something that is under control
by them services so summarize this is
the best of them all now for you to have
a better idea you can see that Master
Dan is the larger one and if you see the
blue line it is connected to G and you
and friend dykey
why because they share the same protocol
from G and you we have status net fan
dykey then you go to diaspora that goes
back to fan dykey so this is what i was
talking about sharing a protocol if i
had a user in each of these social
networks i could create a channel to
federate the message and communicate
among themselves without network you
know in because you are talking to the
entire ecosystem at the same time in
summary networks aren't thought for
constant
privacy but for user privacy you can see
the entire content without
authentication you can list all the
users except for diaspora and there is
no control at all there is no API
limitation there is no limitation of
time for example so you can create the
method that we just saw even bigger
because you can know how many users
there are how they are interrelated etc
etcetera the fising problem isn't it is
a serious one because if these networks
get a lot bigger I can use characters
that were successful in some social
networks and try to impersonate them I
can also use some malicious links as
well so this is all about the sign here
how do I do in order to control all this
how can I avoid impersonation because
this is not well thought in terms of
development when it comes to automatic
in the creation of you users you need
something you just need internet with
the exception of diaspora in diaspora if
you can use tesseract you can do it so
you can crack it every time you could
create as many counts as you wanted in
all the social networks that you would
want causing and DDoS in mustard and
this is even more serious because you
cannot delete it you didn't have uses
one by one that's the most serious one
but in terms of contents you can perform
a total delegation and that is a problem
because they are all interconnected they
all federates
the messages because for example when
you are cracking Twitter you don't crack
Facebook and LinkedIn at the same time
but here you can you can crackle a
instances you can generate loads of
contents so I can actually bring the
entire ecosystem down and leave a
million users without service when it
comes to fising it's the same thing just
happen to deceive the administration
administrator because he's the only one
in control I have this funny story that
someone told to me that someone who
would follow a user with the spider
every time and people started realizing
that there was a spider following them
so I didn't want to be banned so what I
did was to say this but in another case
they they caught me and they banned the
program that was scanning all the users
this is the same story with fising if i
make my message as real as
if the administrator doesn't know about
it I can reach more people with cover
channel there are many different ways
you can use it in the instance itself
you can set up a cover channel with one
single instance with even in capital
letters and in small letters are the
only ones allowed and then you can
create an account with master done and
and all the one with diaspora if you
have the users inside the network's
acting as channels I can forward message
back and forth without people knowing
what's going on so this is a sort of
fising that cannot be detected the
problem is that the users have to know
each other you have to know the IDS of
people sending and receiving messages so
what are the countermeasures that can be
used please use a chat it's for free and
they give you the code so use it because
all the wise me or somebody else can
just create when 100,000 users
another factor I don't know if they have
this and diaspora but most of these
networks don't have a second factor
there are no other controls when it
comes to sequential ideas it's important
to have you and not to having them you
can go from 1 to 100 thousand and cover
all the users and the network the same
in diaspora don't use sequential
messages because I will be able to
gather as much as much information as
possible then you need to authenticate
all the requests you cannot allow a
company using your social network you
know the to send their newsletters with
their own subscript one using this
social network can see what all you are
talking about because you don't need to
login
finally the api's need to be limited
this is a basic thing otherwise it will
grow and till it bursts if you cannot
handle more well he in this case you can
use as many requests as you want as long
as the machine allows for it you are
stocking people and creating many many
many accounts you can bring the Machine
down even if it doesn't look like it I
like these free social networks although
it looks like they are going to fall
apart they are good and they are a good
alternative when you get tired of
LinkedIn Facebook Twitter all the
advertising and all the messages that
are constantly criticized I like this
alternative it's easier to connect and
to have normal conversations and
according to your likes you have an
instance not for you for example there
is an instance about Game of Thrones if
you are into that security is an
important thing it's very serious that G
and you and Status net haven't done
anything for several years they need to
use capture and many other things and
this is an important source of
information for us analysis if you want
to find messages in order to test you
can use these networks in order to get
Massachusetts and do your analysis and
your analytics another important point
is that there is no censorship on these
networks they are controlled by the
administrators and when I started
investigating about these networks I who
is trying to look for a group talking
about dangerous things in order to find
out what happens
when they are talking about dangerous
things so what you find is that there
are no offensive messages the minute
there's somebody who wants to insult
somebody else through message people
just send that message to the
administrator and that user is banned
people are a lot more sensible here one
may think that because this is free
people are going to be watching porn and
saying terrible things all the time but
it's not like that they like to do
whatever you want but you you don't do
that kind of thing because you give the
social networks their real use that is
communication so it's interesting to
think about why people aren't using
these social networks in order to post
things that cannot be post on Twitter
that's the interesting thing they are
more respectful communities they are not
so interested in conflict and
confrontation so that's what I had to
say I finished a little bit early maybe
I was speaking too fast but well I can
now answer any questions that you may
have if you're interested in knowing
more about anything
yes I tell you livin your superhub lo
estoy so if I'm registered in master
could i register within a note in
diaspora yes is diaspora Asterix social
network and they don't share the same
status with master ins so what you can
do is use the same email account to be
in master learn and diaspora at the same
time but you cannot derive the
authentication I think that's what
you're talking about
so what I am proposing is or what I'm
saying is that G and you and have Zilla
well you could create a boat a user
there so that every time you use mustard
on that message is sent over to diaspora
so that the entire network is federated
so you would use master and only and all
the messages would be federated in the
social networks the ones that have the
same protocol they just reach a certain
level if the instance is federated
you're going to watch the same thing in
both in both social networks but if you
also use GNU you can use it in order to
be redirected to diaspora and I asked /
is great it is just Facebook without the
advertising actually the topic of being
automatically registered in diaspora was
a subject in diaspora itself it's really
cool did you know about Masterton
masteren is pretty well-known but what
about diaspora or pom piyo
GNU as the oldest one it is more
old-school I don't know if you've ever
heard of the free social networks no so
thank you very much
[Applause]
muchisimas gracias merrily