retaining as possible so we can go out
for a lot my name is Mario Santi that
come from Mexico City from very far away
it's been quite a long flight and I'm
here to talk to you about a tool that
has existed for a decade but for many
people it's still unknown I'm referring
to the blue window that few people
referred to as PowerShell I hold a
degree in computer science and I have
experienced an incident response
penetration testing and I currently work
in debugging and this is a disclaimer we
have some slice I've brought ten slides
for some demos and this presentation has
been prepared solely for informational
informative and educational purposes
foodist powershell powershell and here
we have microsoft's definition they're
going to do this it's an environment for
scripting language development and the
main advantage of PowerShell is that we
use objects instead of text which is
what CMD your vest does with Linux
why PowerShell here we have some
references pablo home sally author of
these two books that you can see that
are wonderful there are very few
references in spanish huang garrido has
done amazing research in this field and
carlos spirit
who works and Metasploit and has
contributed to powershell pusher mode
and powershell mediated MSH
implementation he has done something
amazing he has contributed very
significantly to this world to talk
about the PowerShell let me give you the
context we have set of components we
have the shell command prompt which is
the blue window then most of you have
seen then we have the commander's then
we have the providers that are command
lists that are specific to work with
specific data with which we wouldn't be
able to work with the command line an
example is the Windows registry then we
have the help for the system or from the
command le'ts and I'll show you soon a
small demo of how powerful this is and
then we have the modules to broaden and
extend some PowerShell functionalities
there are many modules developed by the
community active directory that is owned
by Microsoft the one developed by Carlos
beta as I was saying etc
first of all I like to link up our shell
with penetration testing we have some
tools and I'm going to show them to you
some projects that are specific for
penetration testing we have power cut
which is a net cut implemented with
power shell we also have some other
projects like 14 mod when I mentioned
earlier developed by Commerce fitted and
so wonderful we have power exploit as
well my year this tool was developed by
Hungary know to conduct
Active Directory auditors wonderful you
just need to execute it and it issues an
automated report of n things it's a
wonderful and I'm going to give you some
examples so that you understand the
application of these tools all right
over there's quite a fast
[Music]
here are the tools I mentioned power cut
is the first one I'm going to show you
I forgot to say that this is common
plant which is often known as the blue
window and we also have the development
environment provided by and Microsoft
it's a script development environment
with many features we have the editor we
have the console and description of all
the commandments available divided in
two categories and do a demo for you
we're using power cut
as you can see it's developed here and
of course I don't have time to explain
code to you so I don't have much time
just run it you executed this is similar
to net cut to check that it's open
verify that it's open we're going to do
something very fast and we can verify
that we can have more ports open for
this tool and for example this port is
open we can select that it for you wish
this is just a demo so that you
understand how these tools work so that
you can use them for pen testing or
penetration testing purposes for
forensic computing purposes as well and
when we talk about power shelf in a more
advanced manner there are other tools
worth mentioning PowerShell allows you
to include or handle the dotnet
framework without having to open visual
studio we can create a bit window forms
we can sit or paste api's voice api's or
can we can work directly with objects we
can create from powershell Microsoft
Word or Excel spreadsheet personalized
customized parts let me show you an
example so that you understand how we
can create this without having to open
visual studio this is a very simple
example for example how to create a
condor very very simple
with these lines of code we can also
create well here I have some examples
[Music]
but just like to show you some examples
of what we can do
[Music]
with PowerShell
you don't have to set up visual studio
that consumes any resources
no you cannot create small projects that
can do amazing stuff okay an example
with a voice API that is included with
Windows you're creating a feature of
functionality we are creating an object
using the API the voice operating system
we just run it which is executed
I don't have audio I believe and this
laptop
unfortunately I can't activate the audio
but we can play around with lots of
elements we can send text file thousands
of things in the program software
automatically reads my voice what we are
sending or transferring another example
I'm gonna rush here let me choose this
other example we conduct audits audits
on systems were interested in being able
to use different techniques like google
hacking to be able to identify self to
me there are n techniques to the first
subdomains this is an example I prepared
and the only thing we do is send Google
a request using a google hacking and
ring hacking as well
let's check something from here from
Spain for the bank not doing anything at
this stage and what I'm going to do is
conduct a search in Google regarding
everything related to this and there are
some filters in place
I haven't fine-tuned it 100%
these are subdomains we have and that
can be useful in order to be able to
penetrate visa subdomains a more
customer there are some implementations
that are also quite interesting there's
this sufferer that was presented in
black half-assed some years ago by Jaco
water a kid I called answered he
developed it in Python I tried to
transfer to PowerShell some things were
lost I was able to hone some other
things and search for those of you and
aware with this is a tool that allows us
to work within map
and in a very simple manner and allows
us to search scripts she examined the
documentation pertaining to each script
we've often wanted to look for scripts
that we own and we have to access the
folder then the script folder to be more
exact and try to see whether it's there
here what we do is conduct a search and
we conduct a search by ICP for example
so in a very simple way we can see all
the scripts we have we can search for
well based on name or by category you
don't need to know more degrees just
select them among the list and you can
look for all the exploits in Mack
and we currently have one in this
specific case and we can also do an
author based search and this is one of
the main contributors Paulino Cali Donna
also Mexican like myself friends
he has many different developments one
of the most important ones was to detect
the eternal blue vulnerability and here
we have all the scripts he has developed
here with of m/s 17 all 10 vulnerability
we can also get the documentation just
using talk the name of the script and
here we have all the scripts available
we can just self complete and here we
have the script documentation in a very
simple way the idea is I believe Kokubo
the bacharach is from Colombia from
Dragon huggable community this is his
total the idea of Power Cell is not to
install anything in order to make any
sort of operation to use n search you
need Python and some others but here you
just need to execute the script
and as simple as this you get the
documentation is something very simple
but don't many occasions we'll look for
something like this in Internet and many
of us do not know that this information
is inside the script is always updated
and we have a command to update it to
the latest releases and we can also do
administration rules either updates the
databases downloading the scripts have
until the last date we have the
documentation and updated information
that we can execute this is a clear
example of everything that can be
carried out with Power Cell the idea is
not to install anything in the earth in
order to do our test we have n map and
as you know you don't need to install it
you can just download it and execute it
and from here this is all you can do we
just have to exit and we continue where
we were I would also like to introduce
you the work with Microsoft your office
this is a small script
to check the hardening on OS generating
a text file that generates a report or
that automatically generates a word file
with the help of dot-com objects what we
do is just execute it we're gonna do it
in the local observer we can do it in
remote powers and give us the
possibility to execute commands remotely
using in our M technologies but now
we're gonna do it with a local server
we're going to execute it and here is
when we see what we have
over always as I said this
is not only possible locally but also
remotely and as you can see these
Microsoft Word file is not built by me
but automatically and is Gerren out the
hardening of the equipment always it
will take some time and I've shown of
also Sonia I do buy aspirin for Europe
working in a similar way than the last
script but is integrated in this case
through Active Directory it gets a level
of hardening with a report one in Excel
and the other one in world and this can
save so much time in the daily opera tea
operations just to mention some of the
functionalities but we have some more
there are some tools developed by
different partners that helped us in the
incident response part one of the
best-known is PS reckon that helped us
through powers LT activated their script
takes some time to execute it we can
also do it remotely
due to time reasons I executed in my
device that you can see it now
it builds an html5 providing information
about that system this is very useful in
incident response cases as you know we
have to do things as fast as possible
and we have a great deal of information
here in a nice-looking report all of
these using Power Cell
we have fire world settings and many
things as you can see there are many
different possibilities
in an HTML file as you can see the word
that I left on a few seconds ago it
validates different contents in
different folders and we see all the
information that is comes from the sea I
ask that this script checks in side a
device creating a word here and
everything is simple as you can see to
be able to provide a report is not only
once you can lunch
a number of times and make all the
process automatic of course they can
talk on the resources available I've
tested it with large number of devices
and it gets or need so many resources
those are a few examples I can give you
and now we're going to see some other we
have in the intent response modules or
in tools available there is one named
concern it was developed by a Hindu I
don't remember his name and this is the
same as Pierce freaking but with this we
can get functionalities isolated for
example memory
or certain things that are already
present in PS Rican and here we can
import it to an excel file using some
power shell command let's we also have
nishang go for penetration testing for
everything related to penetration
testing from getting information
exploitation analysis we have many many
different scripts that allow us to do
many things for example to check whether
receive into our machine we can use
mimic at we have a small key lever it
doesn't work too well we have a get
information that brings all the
information from the OS and many other
things
and other great Julius was a mod he can
be imported as a module with all its
functionalities or we can use part of
the tools I'm going to show you a small
demonstration of one of the
functionalities do we have power memory
yes we have power memory this is an
implementation from mimic odds as you
know and the malware antivirus they have
the signature when we're doing a
penetration testing process in Macca's
we have to verify whether there is any
sort of antivirus or anti-malware the
majority we can check it with virustotal
but those implementation in power cell
by mimic arts using the same procedure
it interrupts the process the l has
asked and gets the credentials here
we're gonna do a small demo of how it
works as I said
at present I in my experience I haven't
seen anything that can detect it even
though there are different and the
malware that detect this type of scripts
we have many anti-malware that they
claim that they can do it but they don't
at least they don't do it yet I'm gonna
show you an example we have the same
problems to execute mimic odds we should
have an administration rights we cannot
execute them without the permit
[Music]
aqui tenemos la illaha Boop y know a lot
about punta pacifica we have the ps1
file we're going to execute it and the
only thing is to execute it and here we
have different possibilities let us do
it in really fast way so we're going to
do it a local server we have the
possibility to do it remotely with as as
available and different possibilities as
you can see let's do it locally and this
is if we were to do a filtering we will
say now on this occasion around here
something that is really interesting of
this tool is allow us to eliminate the
trace of our execution
we're gonna press ok to eliminate any
type of traces we start the analysis
and maybe do today o do to them our
purposes I executed it before presenting
it to you and this is the text file by
mimikatz
migrated to Power Cell this is a small
tool but it's very useful if you if it
happens that you know me me that's is
really useful not to be concerned for
any anti-malware or antivirus as I said
although many state that they can detect
this type of scripts in fact nobody
detects them yet
here this is another tool power sploit
is well known it has many different
functionalities one of the most use
eSports can literally it scans ports
using power cell if we don't have AdMob
or we cannot install any other program
this small script waits several many
kilobytes three megawatt and we can use
all those functionalities and having an
end
map
we executed and here wherever the
function named invoke post scan the host
we select is X we can exclude host if
we're going to use n number of IPs and
we can do it
my
hooters it has a limited number of ports
X number of ports but I don't remember
the figure now and we can scan for
example port 80 he's not going to do it
now but it's a small example of how to
use this tool and we have something
similar to n map and as you can see this
is the information the hot water the
participant closed visited and the time
without in map or installing anything
just the blue console that nobody came
blogs either by GPS or anything we can
do many different things appears
weakness I've already showed you I don't
really have anything for this if you
want have a look he's very interesting
is a very interesting tool to check on
an active directory of a minion it takes
on the trees and everything active
directory and he provides a full report
of what we have in an active directory
those are just a few of the tools I
wanted to show you and some of some
examples of it we can do
with parcel as I said we can use it for
penetration testing power exploit comes
up for incident response the most famous
in a way is PS beacon there are n number
of scripts for incident response to
check the user and what application was
executed on the last instance and those
are all the projects the most important
one uses all of them are the name is
Empire there is a framework where we can
use all tools available we can call me
me cut from power cell port scanning
bypass from de UAC is there will be two
very interesting talks about it later on
today and tomorrow and many many things
Empire is the largest power cell project
that implements many different tools
you can install it in Linux is very easy
to install and in addition to being able
to carry out forensics penetration
testing and incident response is not
been in the market for 10 years as power
self love ourselves desired state
configuration we usually the name is
usually power cell DSS but it allows us
to have our infrastructure as a code
I don't know if you know anti-world
puppet it allow us to provision
infrastructure and applications in a
declarative way for many projects that
we might have in mind one of the
examples this is an example in Microsoft
documents in a very descriptive way we
can self set or provision a web server
just by executing this inner OS whether
locally or remotely on a number of hosts
and make different settings to the
applications sequel server exchange
share points in a very simple and
aromatized way this in the box is
incredibly powerful and we can compare
it with other existing solutions
if it rings a bell have a look it has
implementations with acid and it will be
stupid not to mention it we can self
provision many different things as a
code we can have different releases
I know it's lunchtime and this is just
the some information of everything I
wanted to present you would please urge
you to use the tool use the small blue
windows we cover develop and environment
there are many things we can do is very
easy to start working with it and I
forgot to show you something we have
help desk for everything we have a
commander and if you do not know the
tool there's a get help a commander that
brings help about everything we might
need from any command let our module
something as right for example just to
show you an example
if you don't know this to leave your no
parcel please use it
this command is the main one it will be
your best friend so you can start using
it it will save much time when you start
working with PowerShell you can make
everything automatic in relation to OS
and for those that are interested is
also implemented in our Linux releases
since 2016 it became open-source so
there are releases for Linux we can
automatic and no longer depend on bar
space is very powerful but he treats
everything as text and here as objects
we can treat everything as a method or
propriety or settings and he will save
you much time from administration
whether you are admins or carry on
penetration testing me in case you
cannot install anything is going to be
very useful also innocent response sure
that 80% if you does that will you see
there will be on Microsoft there very
powerful tools that you can develop
really quickly the forensics and as I
said we even have devoxx implementations
for the box we can implement it in your
servers in ashes with DSS and this is
the end of my presentation I don't want
to take more time thank you thank you so
much for your attention
[Applause]
you