what it is good morning we're going to
begin this presentation on data
protection I hope you find this of
interest and before I begin I like to
explain what a data protection is about
some background information I also talk
about legislation enforce boolean we'll
talk about computers and I'll talk to
you about the data protection in general
data protection is a right that we all
have as individuals to decide on our own
personal data I'm not only referring to
the data that directly identify me like
my name picture surname ID number I'm
referring to all personal info
everything that can identify me as an
individual and this is a fundamental
right that is linked to my the right to
self-determination 50 years ago was easy
to decide on personal data because it
was written on a paper and it was you to
decide but now it's difficult because we
all leave traces digital traces on the
internet we all have credit cards we all
have mobile phones and we all have a
clinical record and the hospitals
provide treatment so it's impossible not
to leave a digital footprint of our
information have you ever stopped to
think why some apps installed a year
mobile recommend you or ask you for a
station to be able to access your
battery profile or manage your use of
the battery have you ever thought about
that small details that's a way of
identifying someone AV you in the OS of
a mobile that it access your battery
you're allowing it to know whatever
you've got installed and the mobile and
which are the ones that consume
batteries and therefore which are the
wants to use most and that's a result it
will be able to do advertising or offer
that info to a third party on the apps
you have installed a for example you
have a sports app and you practice a
specific sport when you enter the social
media you will receive them advertising
because that everything you have in the
mobile has sold your data to a third
party in that third party is showing you
ads and that third party is making money
and as you access those websites you are
generating money and here is when the
Data Protection Act comes into place
where we need an act a regulation that
sets limits in order to ensure that
people can exercise fully their rights
and freedoms we currently have a
directive in an organic act for data
protection next year we will have a
European data protection regulation the
regulation basically will come into
force on May 25 2008 een we can have
additional regulation as Member States
of the EU according to the regulation we
can have a national regulation in order
to adapt the community regulation to our
Spanish legal framework for example the
Spanish legal framework needs to adapt
the community legislation because for
example here in Spain we have the
autonomous regions and we have some
specificities and this is the
fundamental right that needs to be
enshrined in our legislation as well we
need to regulate this ourselves not only
in EU regulation scope well it applies
to all goods and services
and anything that entails the control or
the analysis of people versatile people
I'm not refrain that people that are
citizens or officially I'm referring to
anyone on you community grounds the
principles of the previous directive are
implicit in this new regulation there
are almost no changes the only change at
a national level is that in terms of
principles we used to have what we call
chassid or implicit consent and this is
going to disappear we're going to move
towards a scheme or a system of explicit
consent what's the main novelty what's
new with this regulation it's not just a
matter of principles it's a matter of
compliance what's new has to do with
compliance the active responsibility or
accountability the principle of
accountability is news regarding this
regulation in the past you had to comply
but now you need to prove that you're
complying with this regulation so there
is an accountability side to it that's
new with this new regulation and you
need to demonstrate that you're doing
this proactively that you're reviewing
the measures you've put into place what
kind of measures well for example first
thing you need to do before the 25th of
May is to have a register if you're
designing apps or info or systems or
digital systems you need to consider
that they are data protective principles
that you need to apply from the design
stage what does this mean well that
before you design your system you need
to think about how you're going to
process information if you haven't
considered that in that voll translate
and
you cost in the future so more than an
expense you should view this as an
investment we by the Spanish Agency have
been contacted with queries and for
example companies that sent date abroad
and we asked them have you thought about
where you're sending that info have you
considered and the fact that you're
internationally transferring data and
they say no we hadn't thought about that
but now they do with this new regulation
you need to be able to secure that
transfer and data protection by default
is very much related to the concept of
opt in or opt out it is the user who has
to decide whether he or she wants to be
part of a list that receives data it is
the user that also has the right to
decide whether he wants to opt out and
there's another novelty something else
that's new which has to do with impact
assessments so you're going to treat and
process data a you're going to process
personal data and perhaps we're talking
about a high or low risk data we are
unaware of that if they entail high risk
you will have to conduct necessarily an
in-person assessment ie an analysis
before processing this involves of
planning all these aspects are very much
related to what we call the risk
approach of the new community data
protection regulation if you haven't
done an impact assessment and you're
still telling on whether you should can
or cannot process data you will have to
contact a Data Protection Authority and
that authority will tell you if you can
do so or not and well specify the
measures you need to implement in order
to process data new acts of
responsibility or accountability up
until now in Spain security breaches had
to be notified by the telecom providers
according to the national telecom
provider Act
but now everybody it has this
responsibility of reporting and security
breaches to the Spanish Data Protection
Agency how can we prove this active
responsibility or accountability well
there are several mechanisms the Code of
Conduct
certification schemes these are also
mechanisms that helped us certify this
if I subscriber certification with ISO
17100 in terms of data protection 282 in
terms of security measures well what was
said previously by article 9 of the L
OPD you need to implement technical and
organizational measures as appropriate
face of this state of art and when well
this of course is a risk approach and
when the regulation talks about risk
approach it does so from two points of
view and the one hand we do have the
security measures and secondly you have
a risk in terms of the rights and duties
of individuals how should we interpret
this risk piece of either rights and
duties of individuals provides an
obligation let me give you an example
imagine that haven't analyzed my risk
appropriately I managed a health center
that processes a citizen's data and I
have reached security and I as a result
all the data from my patients are
accessible this would be an important
security breach because this would
affect these people not only directly
but also indirectly I said it would also
affect their health probably these
people would have greater difficulties
when hiring our
health insurance policy because the
insurance companies who won't view them
as practicable and will probably not one
to engage in a relationship with them
what could be the impact on these
people's lives would it be the same for
everybody won't probably none let's
imagine that if someone has AIDS for
example and is a 90 year old that person
probably doesn't mind about having that
info disseminated because he is no
longer working and but what happens if
we're talking about a child if that info
is disclosed perhaps he's discriminated
at school at university it could also
have negative impact in terms of his
employability
maybe he's unseen as profitable employee
because he requires a medical assistance
and this is what the regulation is
talking about when it talks about the
risk becoming the rights and duties of
individuals as for these security
measures and the activity registered
well first a description whenever it's
possible where possible but it's almost
always possible how am i compliant with
security measures if I'm a public
administration I will have to comply
with a national system if I'm a private
company maybe I have a company that I've
hired that is managing this according to
ISO 17025 a security document are you
all aware of the security document and
how it works there was an internal
document organization in-house document
that described the rights and duties of
employees profiles also a list of
profiles that had to be very much
detailed and you can have a link where
all this information
you don't have to explicit all the info
unit I need to make it public but you
can have a link and that grants you
access to this info and then I here
ensue the code of conduct or a
certification make it said this can be
part of your security measures and you
can adhere to a sectoral code of contact
and aside from demonstrating of my
productivity in the way of process data
it's a way of basically demonstrating
that I'm complying and that I have set
of security measures Julie in place
something that changes as well with this
new regulation and and that renders
managers more responsible and actively
responsible is the relationship between
the users and the managers and the due
diligence element was implicit in the
past now it's no longer the case not a
matter of hiring whoever you need to
regulate a series of things as you can
see on slide on the one hand we have a
known disclosure duty or confidentiality
duty and article 12 of FL opt is also
enshrined here and now we have more
powers given to the person responsible
for example inspection you can go and
see what the person in charge is doing
as the person responsible I can do it
and I can do it with a service contract
in relation to this just to say that we
have published a manual or a guide with
the recommendations to guide contractual
clauses in this direction what are the
tasks for somebody that is responsible
to the compliance
the regulation speaks about the model
contracts we don't have such a thing so
far we just have this manual or handbook
so we see the glosses we can add in this
service provision contract about
international transfers here their
regulation is more flexible than before
here in international transfers there is
more flexibility there are more new
mechanism so that you can carry out an
international transfer that can be
carried out by belt positions VCRs
contractual standard contract or clauses
approved by the Commission the
contractual glosses approved by national
level but also by the Commission and
codes of conduct and certification
schemes and the results of the
possibility of legitimate interest about
rights it pays a special importance to
transparency especially for underaged
any right when it affects an enriched it
has a greater impact in their life than
to an adult regulation ism takes into
account the situation and stresses the
principle of transparency and the
information that the minors should get
in relation to handling his or her data
it includes the right to forget fullness
in a regulated manner we know that this
right is the same as we call in the past
the right to opposition applied to
browsers and his regulation also relates
to civil
responsibilities the right to indemnity
and responsibility when the handling of
data has been missed used what does it
mean for control authorities this
regulation a new supervision model is an
added complexity we should all agree now
are a European level how was the
coordination before in Brussels we had
the group work by article 29 all Data
Protection Authority national data
protection entities work together now we
will have the European Committee for
data protection was at the European
supervise study of a data protection
that would be the European one now a
claim can be presented through a single
shop in any of the countries to any
control authority and then we should see
who can is entitled to carry out this
research there will be a complex system
to regulate sanctions with the
sanctioning criteria about sanctions we
keep the same principles they should be
effective proportionate and deterrent
and as I said they should give the
possibility for penal sanctions or
criminal sanctions in Europe we have the
concept of administrative function which
is not the case in some countries in
Europe that we are in Turbo the pathways
when we refer to the possibility of
criminal sanctions this is our way if
you are obtaining some profits thanks to
sanction they can ask you to pay them
back let us see how this will finally be
realized the fines are very high I was
criticized because we got six hundred
thousand euros Pines but now they are
quite high we speak about 4% of company
what do we want by this those are not
defines do somebody that has a coffee
shop we're not going to sanction them as
much because we it will be the closing
of companies we will be against the
objectives of the regulation itself here
we're speaking about large companies the
idea is to avoid the profitability of
the infraction and there are companies
that in the profit and a second it was
more profitable to pay the fine to the
protection agency than to comply with
the treatment in or handling of
information here we see large companies
large Internet companies what do we have
all information from a new regulation we
have a specific site for this all
information published is in our website
here to the left there is a small
section and in May next year this small
section will be our website and we will
speak about the new regulation and that
all I wanted to say I'm now going to
give the floor to Julio
a little bit
it's
hello following on with Andres
presentation about the regulatory
framework I would like to focus and what
the agency do to raise the awareness of
underage when handling their personal
information especially in internet I
will only speak about the digital world
those are the principles that we all
know the possibilities and the risks for
our private life and something that if
you're a youngster you overcome time and
space limitations and information you
upload will be there forever and we want
to raise the awareness about this fact
in information we give in internet
personal data as Andrea said everything
that can identify you is one is used by
many because we have personal
information to give of course we have
the regulation why we should protect the
children i we all know the principle of
the highest interest to the minors but
the last reform about the legislation
stresses that the highest interest is
going to be taken to account for minors
and he has a prevalence against the rest
of in the interest of those that
surround them and training they are
considered as a vulnerable collectivity
and the exposure of the information that
we give about them but that they give
and sometimes we say they have they are
more capable but those skills are
mechanical the fact of being reasonable
to think in a logical manner they have
to acquire them as in any training
process the famous concept of digital
natives is going to be considered
current code what we can do is if we
adults we don't train them we don't
accompany them they could end up being
digital orphans instead of digital
natives this is a chart of the National
Employment Institute about the use of
Internet
this is includes the whole spectrum not
only minors and if you see global
internet views between ten and fifteen
years we they use ninety five percent
those figures are repeatedly if you get
data from 2016 is slightly below but
it's almost universal the use of
Internet technology is universal in
minors and this is something that is
important the sociological research
center in one of their surveys asked
about
- and Internet access and how it should
be done and you see the results
85% should have a limited internet
access they are those that think that
they should have some limitations does
that be totally limited just a little
limited but if you see in 85% the idea
is to limit it or to raise awareness or
maybe this is impossible
in what are we doing in our agency we
have a strategic plan for four years
been a special emphasis in prevention
prevention tool and here we have an
action plan where - and education are
consider a priority the strategic plan
of course is uploaded in our website so
the idea is to give all to meet those
objectives to promote knowledge to the
right data protection and value of
privacy to educate in a responsible use
of information not only personal
information but also information from
third parties will very happily provide
our own information but sometimes we
give a third parties information whether
in pictures or in some other format
without asking for content
certain behaviors and we will see our
own offense our criminal
below 14th miners can not be subject to
a court case but the responsibilities go
for their parents and between 14 and 18
they've got the minor criminal law some
measures for those actions that are
crime as harassment or grooming are
crimes and they can give rise to some
criminal or civil responsibilities at
the end of the day we try to decrease as
much as possible and from the viewpoint
of personal information but it's
something that permeates in the rest of
the areas we try to reduce risk
situations so that they have a secure
use of internet and join its advantages
in this strategic plan we have all those
actions and some more and I'm going to
stop mainly in the last two of the rest
in our agency to education authorities
we have proposed a Content planning to
develop in the curriculum all regional
governments have a curriculum where
information and ICTs are included in
Madrid they have a scene subject that is
robotics but they are not developed in
all regional governments this will be
part of a module that in this subject
might help to get to know about the
regulation and the awareness about the
subject and the agency has proposed this
so the idea is
that they should work in this direction
and now let us see the new teaching
materials the action of the agents in
addition to collaboration with other
administrations in creating teaching
materials or materials to raise the
awareness the title is you decided yes
we have redesigned a new website and I
invite you to visit it those that are
here so that you disseminate information
about it where we keep everything for
underaged for parents for teachers there
are awards and there are screens help
screens when people are at risk and
teaching materials guides where we teach
about the good use of Internet we have a
version for children and other for
parents and educators in this teach had
to read in Internet we speak about what
behaviors can be harassment or crime
what are the consequences and the guide
that will teach them how to be legally
Internet we teach parents and educators
the regulations and what is the
consequence from a more serious
viewpoint all those are found in PDF
files so the idea is that they are known
and useful to all this is a publication
quite recent publication it was
published on the 13th of September
devoted to school centers more than
children school centers
ask as many questions about how to treat
personal data or situation by parents as
presented by parents association we have
cases where in some occasions Christmas
party was over because father said that
they wanted to record the party and
somebody else said this was not possible
but this is not the case but in some
school centers they ended up suspending
Christmas party for problems related to
the recording and we give solutions to
those problems all this material is
available in Internet here we have some
copies that are available to all of you
those are some security and privacy
forums in collaboration with the in TV
their objectives and the target is
generic but for enriches very useful you
also have all this material in our web
site
he will teach you to protect portable
devices to manage information in the
cloud and it has six tutorial videos to
set your privacy settings in the most
common social medium there are different
videos the data tutorials and they are
available in the website we collaborated
with the Spanish public television and
they were some small videos made by
professionals is a television
series with from clan channel the
children's channel of a Spanish national
television that tries to send a brief
messages about the use of information
that they are at the website but also in
clan channel they are available they are
various short and brief videos very
effective and they were recorded buying
a suit by professionals those and I will
give you an example we have presented
those videos on the past 30th of
September this is a series of four
videos they last four or five minutes
and I will show you one and they use
fullness for families and school centers
and also in video and in documents
last year the agency organized a
workshop with families given by a Pablo
that he has attended this cyber campuses
cyber expert this works about the result
of the workshop is nine videos / topics
they are heavier than the ones entitled
you control in Internet the target
audience is the families in this case
but they are also available and we also
have some awards that we call every year
data protection Awards and the results
no word for good education practices for
secure surfing the net that is for all
school centers and for those
institutions that
disseminated information among winners
about good internet practice in January
we will communicate the winners and in
2016 we had 17 education centers that
presented projects the winner was a
school from Salamanca and we had some
candidates to the individual that helped
the promotion and dissemination of good
practices because I don't have much time
I wanted to go back and speak about
something that is interesting the agency
started in September 2015 a
communication challenge channel that is
open for the handling of data by minors
or for minors because were not the
police were not well known especially
among the minors but parents and school
centers and health care centers and City
Council's and social services they asked
questions about the good or bad handling
of data for example at school I after
request content by all students but it's
just for an internet but if I say no
they say that I cannot take pictures so
what do we do in those situations those
are the type of queries or questions we
get and since its implementation we've
got around 13,000 queries and
and those are our channels to respond
the email address is the more advisable
but you also have a telephone line or
walk what shop and before giving you the
showing you the videos to say something
or just comment about the legislative
framework for minors the handling for
everyone we implement all the regulation
but it has some specificities for
example that give consent
you should be above 14 below it has to
be your the parents or tutors in any
application any information society
service devoted to minors below 14
parents should give content and those
are asked for consent they should
correspond the burden of the proof of
that age and I know you're gonna say
that is complex and difficult the social
media juices have contests you introduce
your age and if you are above 14 they
just open it up but the residue
diligence duty in establishing mechanism
to check the H you should take into
account that minors we cannot get
information from miners families context
from economic situation or job of
difference you can ask data about your
parents so that the company may address
the parents pickles
I can ask permission to treat this
information because I am a tourist
producer or I offers services devoted to
minors information when is addressed to
minors the information about the
handling of information should be in an
accessible language appropriate to the
age range which is not always the case
it corresponds to the leaders to certify
those procedures that verify the age or
the parents consent and not the minor
pretendin is one of keys of her parents
and in relation to the European
Parliament consent should be given from
16 onwards but it also sets pay so that
member states can lower the range from
13 to 16 because this is an open process
under is a draft bill for data
protection this new bill is still in
progress but it has said that concerns
age for minors is 13 and this is equal
to the European scene and also us the
large social media Facebook the age
range in United States is 13 when they
arrived to Spain they had to adapt their
counters she made it up to 14 so now we
are equal to Europe and do
u.s. social media and here I just wanted
to show you don't look tan
listen one of the four videos it lasts
not even five minutes and I hope that
you enjoyed
[Music]
what you see here is not a bicycle it's
a fit to run three one of the best BMX
bicycles in the market this is right his
owner he's 14 years old and his BMX
crack
Rygel's riding everywhere in the morning
to go to secondary school after school
goes to practice different jumps every
weekend he writes to record videos for
his YouTube channel explaining his
tricks he rather goes on a bank than
doing anything else very often he just
interrupts any conversation to go riding
at night
he always takes his bike with him home
he's always with his bike for long he
hasn't been sitting in his chair but to
do his homework to have dinner a so we
think his bike when he showers he also
washes his bicycle and of course when he
goes to bed at night the bicycle goes to
bed with him yes I know what you're
thinking maybe Rai is exaggerating you
my enjoyed your bicycle but something
quite different it's not to be able to
separate from it let us make an
experiment well if we change Ray's
bicycle by Internet do you think is an
exaggeration have you ever taken your
smartphone to bed haven't you ever watch
your tablet while you are doing your
homework or having dinner
you've never interrupted a conversation
or any other thing because you've got a
whatsapp message how long can you be
doing an activity without interrupting
it for whatsapp message or any other
thing Internet is not bad it's got many
good things is good to communicate with
friends family find new games watch
films read books find sites and
information and to sort out all sorts of
problems to buy to sell to teach and to
learn do you have internet
is really grand as having a Duke x3 bike
but if you spend your life in Internet
you will be missing many other things as
if you were always on your bike there's
something else the Internet is similar
to a bike if you misuse it you can have
disastrous consequences no matter how
good you are riding if you are on the
opposite lane without brakes you might
end up crashing to a car okay there are
not cars in Internet but have you ever
thought about your digital footprint
whenever you publish something in your
media you are live in footprint whether
a tweet Facebook post or picture in
Instagram this digital footprint is the
memory of what your activity in Internet
and I will go along all your life for
good and for bad imagine that tomorrow
you want to work in a company the first
thing they will do to decide whether
they will hire you or not is to look for
your name and in turn they will google
you they will look at your blog your
facebook comments your profiles
everything just previously published and
they will have a better or worst view
depending on your digital footprint so
she'll me they are not dangerous
bicycles are not dangerous if you drive
carefully that's why be fortune in
something in the media is good to think
about the impact it will have in the
digital footprint first league much
dismissed a player because they found
that they had insulted the team in
twitter he just uses it many years
before but they left trace so remember
when you publish in Internet stays and
your digital footprint will be with you
for long and it might have good or bad
consequences that depends on you keeper
reflexive attitude when you publish in
the media in the social media internet
and social media are great but there are
more other great things in life
and you can enjoy them when you're not
connected
[Music]
this is one of the examples of the four
videos that are in the agency's website
the objective is to disseminate them and
use them as much as possible as the rest
of the teaching materials let us see if
I can come back to my powerpoint this is
your sunrise
justice
listen to you
L mean my long period since they started
on an SS just
those materials are available in our
website the teaching guide that you have
in hard copy the you control in Internet
videos and some tutorials and the
workshop for families from the agency
whenever we make an investment
our objective is prevention support and
the - best interest in area we would
like is to be used and disseminated at
home at school centers and for families
and we have a queries spot where you can
communicate with us for questions about
data handling foreign by minors whether
the parents or the school centers there
are things that we might not be able to
respond but in this channel we have
further information when we speak about
situations where he goes beyond the
handling of personal information and our
actions that can be an offence
we have channels that we take you to
police agencies when people are at risk
we have foundation on our for cases of
harassment or losses that require
something that we don't have weather
report or psychological help this all
this information is in our communication
channel please visit it and disseminated
and is 105 and that's all I wanted to
tell you thank you
[Applause]
to see we have a question I think you
for the information I work at a public
administration and I admit that I didn't
know much about this at work as a public
servant I found out a few days ago that
there isn't any sanction against me for
misuse of personal data
I've been used working as if it was the
case just due to my ethics but does the
new regulation include sanctions that is
not just an evaluation that states
you're bad employee if you work in the
public administration you have the same
problem the agency can sanction you as
civil servant by an infringement is not
always economical but is an infringement
whether to you or to the entity you work
for but as you can be fined either
economically or disciplinary or you can
have a criminal sanction sorry we didn't
get the comment she's not using the
microphone so we cannot translate this
lady's comments
okay no I myself you're economical and
paralyzing there's no economic fine for
public administrations but I saw it as
an admonishment well it goes beyond that
it can be an admonishment or they can
open let's say a complaint against you
well this bill is still a bill but when
the bridge is perpetrated by a public
administration there's a possibility of
initiating disciplinary proceedings
against that person this is something
new and the new bill is still being
discussed so ever proof is not only
making that let's a punishment public
not only then there's also the
possibility of having the administration
start disciplinary proceedings against
the perpetrator but this is part of a
bill I just found out three days ago
that there was there was no economic
fine I can of course adhere to
professional secrecy but I was working
with the idea that the data with which I
handle and I work with women that are
victim of domestic abuse and I always
insisted don't leave any documents on
the table you do very well you do very
well because one of the sanctions are
punishments that we had to issue against
the civil servant but precisely because
this lack of professional secrecy so we
I should a penalty to the administration
and to the per worker disciplinary
proceedings or sorta against the
employee I have a couple of questions
[Music]
the implementation of the general
European regulation will it replace the
Spanish law the LPD or will both coexist
well it will depend now it's at a bail
stage on the 25th of May we will be
talking about an act and there will be
perhaps a full or partial tear or Gatien
so on the 25th of May our current ello
PD will disappear but the regulation is
community regulation has already been
approved why are we losing time and
doing a new L OPD if it's going to
extinguish or terminate on May the 25th
well the current framework is applicable
and basically what happens now is that
our ll PD cannot have any terms or
articles that contravene the community
regulations
European regulations can be directly
implemented they don't need to be
incorporated in the internal framework
but this one is a bit special because it
led some leeway to states for example
the ages of minors between 13 and 16
years of age so you can decide the age
group and with a new act what we want to
do is complete or cover those aspects
that are not governed by the regulation
because the act can never regulate or
against the European regulation
I know if you check the text or the bill
for the first time we're talking about
the possibility of accessing to data of
people that have passed away and
normally the loped didn't apply to the
disease but inheritors can now access to
the suppression of data regarding to
teach people this is something new for
example the new loped covers video
surveillance this is uncovered by
Europeana regulation also
representatives of companies but what
the new actors has to cover those
aspects that are not covered by the
community regulation and as I was saying
you do have some leeway as happens with
directives and there's the typical
example of minors the bill has talked
about thirteen year olds but states will
have the final say
you