all right
thank you and welcome everyone to
confidence 2020
my name is vitaly cremas also known as
vk intel on twitter
uh my talk it's basically i wanted to
talk about the
the north korean group lazarus
intersection between trigbat
i also want to dive deeper into the
evolutions of crimeware
intent or criminal intent and how we can
use some of the adversary knowledge we
know for
hunting and some of the use case i
wanted to show you and demonstrate
it's one of my favorite tools of course
yara signature so we'll
quickly walk through how knowing
specific
aspects about yara and maybe helping
explaining one
unique angle across the er signature
development that you can use in your
day-to-day activities that produces high
fidelity results
so okay let's start so the talk
outline we'll talk uh in the beginning
we'll talk about the crime where intent
evolutions of criminal intent
will go back into uh the financially
motivated beginnings of malware
writers and what they were pursuing
we'll talk more about
how the current trends across the
malware landscape
and what the current aspects of malware
developers
and malware attackers and ap advanced
persistent threat groups and crammer
groups
what do they realize how do they search
for the targets of interest to them
and some of the ancient things that came
out of that of course you will see
it will will again will just decide
network parsing and active directory
exploitation
and then uh the apt approach and
ransomware
and it's kind of like um seamless
interactions currently beginning to
happen
as we know that ept approaches to the
advanced persistent threat
it seems to be very targeted in many
cases
and ransomware becomes the uh the flavor
of the day
we'll talk about that quickly or
emergence of ransom hacks
and then uh through that approach we'll
also talk about the net trigbot
before that and lazarus we'll talk about
unique
aspects that make uh make it more
interesting it's the yara hunting for
crypto implementations
i am a strong deliverer in yara as a
tool for day-to-day activities across
the enterprises and networks and
security
security products and something that
will show you an example of uh
one specific the three but crypter used
across the anchor and many many other
projects that will
go over to the stations and how we can
go
write a quick but good and sound yara
hunting rule for
looking for crypto implementation within
the malware because that's the future
who am i my name is vitalik kramez i'm
uh um i'm pretty well known on twitter
land i previously work in the
uh for the you know in the us uh as a
prosecutor's office i used to hunt
cybercrime for
for a living working for kevin helping
prosecute some of the most
sophisticated and technically savvy
groups
um my work was focused on around taking
down big
big crime work gangs and crime war
groups
and again of course those they had
nation state component as well
so my work related to the government
work led to my private industry work and
of course
one of the interesting things that
stands out about me is that
one time of course the apt-28 group as
we know
that belief to be targeting uh literally
to be breached actually the democratic
national committee in the u.s
uh that the same entity actually left my
name uh in the malware after my blog
went live so
it's a kind of like a tribute to the
malware and if you follow me on twitter
feel free to follow me vk
intel my personal blog where i write
quite a bit on
deeper like malware reversing topics
some of them are more technical but
they're
more technical on purpose um
yeah so let's dive deeper into that
so the cyber crime trends of 2020 what
do we see
currently on the um on the landscape
is that the sophisticated criminal
enterprises
some of the most sophisticated currently
are ongoing is trig but quackbot
and of course ta505 they are all focused
on parsing
identifying high-value targets actually
you can include z-loader as well
as they also look for those machines
with local domains and those machines
that have
rich networks it's also the cybercrime
meets apt
where they no longer rely simply on
fully automated approach
where they would basically uh extract
the value from the bots
and and automatically launch and kind of
search for them
but they hire crew of people and network
um operators used to be
quite some time ago used to be the fraud
operators used to be the highest
value addition for the malware groups
but now it seems to be both
fraud operations and network
exploitations and ransom hacks
become also important as they used to
amplify extortions
and it's kind of like lead to public
disclosures and
and some of the groups that also work
with apts for example
we know for a fact that our evil works
with the fin7
group of course he um share you some
snippets on that as well but also we
know that
some groups also including lazarus
previously used some ransomware is
either for cover-up or additional
financial gain
so these are interesting aspects of um
and almost all the majority ransomware
groups actually i believe
the almost all of them are becoming
ransom hacks
where they deploy a website and threaten
to leak
the data if it's not being paid it's a
pretty clever way of uh
monetizing maybe predicted before that
all the groups will be doing
similar activities across the landscape
so big
big data collectors necessity scalable
solutions to identify high value targets
it's corporate networks with local
domain so some of mine uh my machines
may not be as use as useful
as the corporate infection of course
especially now with the kernel of irs
what they look for
those that are connected to networks and
those that have remote services
available
including the rdps citrix vpns for
example etc
and the idea is just to squeeze more
value dollars pounds euros
from the bots as possible so they deploy
different kinds of
operations the banking malware they have
a crew that monetizes that credential
stealers of course miners and ransomware
the key component or the father of
crimeware and it's
why this person is so impactful to this
to the talk we have
because he the person who
professionalized
the approach of targeting the approach
of essentially
um developing new novel methods and
scaling them to
perfection so the slavic essentially
that led
of course the business club and before
that he built the kind of hybrid attack
model
or uh they used they used basically
an automation attack where they would
deploy uh
malware but also they were considering
well they had the fraud operation as
well
this was known to be the business club
but also business club introduced the
crypto locker which is the first
ransomware
and some of the uh operators that we
were talking through the presentation
especially those connected to lazarus
groups
are also also interconnected and going
back to
the models and frameworks that slavic
developed when he was uh when he was
running the business
so the idea is why and what the top
sophisticated crimeware and apt groups
do they hunt for
those machines that have network records
and those are
those machines are deemed to be high
value targets outside of the direct
targeting that they might have through
uh direct specification
or direct targeting by other means so
one of the interesting things of course
that uh that the the key component now
which is super popular is that the
automated malware
where they deploy a kind of an image for
example is a typical
loader for trigbot or a trigger on its
own so it's pretty equal
where the deployed by you can now of
course quantity
ran somewhere county ransomware is the
substitutional right
but the method and methodology and
and everything works the same except now
they have a leak website actually
where the extort victims but the way
they differentiate across the spectrum
of infections is through network and
active directory person
yes there seems to be a problem with
slides they are not moving we are stuck
on the we're stuck on the initial slide
for a long time
okay one second right now we are at the
automated malware plus interactive human
exploitation operator slide
okay one second yes
can you see the slides again yes i can
see it and we are
the slide with yeah the automated
malware slide
okay i was going with
and then after
after basically the network and active
directory parsing
they oftentimes deploy the powershell
empire and cobalt strike beacons
and use it for network network and
active directory parsing
one of the interesting aspects of course
uh just to share with you some of the
incidents we've seen across the trigbot
installation that of course the cobalt
strike and interpreter
load loads basically this is some of the
images from the attacker side
and and why it's so important for them
to target them
so it's it's the view once they're
infected oftentimes they deploy a cobalt
strike
through the powershell tasking of the
bot or the interpreter itself
as you can see in the slides this is
kind of the adversary view
on the malware and botnets on their own
once they are infected
as you can see they're looking for the
admin credentials and exchanging and
harvesting credentials using for example
ps exact to spread
etc but this is the beacon tasking and
an armitage
for the cobalt strike beacon as well
so one of the ancient aspects of course
that why so becomes such a big issue on
the horizon from the malware side
is the 5 billion extortion amount if
that's what the extortion amount that
the groups asked earlier
uh essentially once they infect the
cloud jumper
which is the huge uh msp msp provider
essentially providing the
access to many active directory
installations and many many other
components across customer interfaces
and across the interface they infected
one of the of course most notable
infections was the la times
los angeles times one was infected and
it was a huge debate
if lazarus was inside the tree by the
tree but it was
part of lazarus because because they
also found that
the hermes ransomware was potentially
deployed or
in that case everybody thought it was
hormone hermes but it was in fact ryuk
which was the ransomware used by trigbat
and of course they'll show the direct
intersection between those groups
but this was a pretty interesting and
novel component when they realized
instead of like squeezing bots through
credentials activities and they can ask
for a lot of money in cryptocurrency
and launder them pretty safely and the
way it allows them to enable to do that
it's through the of course having a
steady flow of new bots
having steady flow of new corporate bots
or infections that have
the most impact and interacting them
with ransomware
and it was also sorry to
sorry to interrupt you once again i'm
sorry about it but the chat says that
you are probably shooting the wrong
screen
instead of the one with the actual
presentation you are sharing the one
with
earlier that that's the case brought so
much notoriety
to the ransomware target ransomware
approach where they realized the value
of having a targeted
team of exploitation operators to staff
their
bots will be extremely successful as you
can see the amount and extortions were
over
60 600 000 bitcoins across their
customer interface
but this is of course more than five
billion dollars in
in bitcoins if after conversions now so
it's pretty huge huge amount
and hugely profitable and that's
something that they also noted
and also like just to give a quick
survey of some of the interesting groups
we've seen as well that utilize the kind
of advanced persistent threat
angle as we talked about that the new
flavor of them
that network park sync for high value
targets or we can also call it
the apt or crime where meet uh
the criminal groups become apt groups
advanced versus persistent groups
they approach they adapt the same
approach as you can see here
doppelganger
it's when when they were engaged in the
pam extrusion of course i'm showing the
debugging window
and that's where the they were
essentially attacking and extorting over
565 bitcoins
with again with the leak and extortion
portal in on their website
and this is just kind of another
ransomware that also engage
ransomware group also linked to evil
corp also behind drydex also linked to
slavic and this is kind of like the um
the genealogy or like the uh the tree of
crime where oftentimes uh comes back to
slavic
as a person because the groups also were
at one point in time their customers
this is the group that was also doing
the same advanced visit thread groups
once they're on the networks
another interesting group of course is
that the tta 505 favorite oftentimes we
are
asked what's the ransomware they
deployed and that's the one that we so
continuously
deployed across their targets after
extensive network
profile and operation deployed by them
where they would essentially run a task
and look for the bots with
the network records and you can see that
that the group is linked to university
hostel friends attack
and then of course very targeted not
every bot would receive
the club rent somewhere but those are
those that have the
network records those the boss they have
breach access to
the network environment or local domain
and active directory
those are the ones that are especially
targeted and you can see this just an
example of
of the one that we are conclusively
linked to the ta-505
so almost all the groups now have some
sort of like
a unique flavor of ransomware adopting
pretty similar approaches where they use
their own infection as a basis they
deploy
or hire people to staff their infections
to be the exploit operators
what they would for example open a
connections via what they would ask
hey can you download and install
additional tool on the bots or
additional toolkit
asking to back connect to the bot for
example open up the powershell task and
download for example powershell empire
or global strike
oftentimes they are operating very
similarly some of the
exploitation operators also are shared
across the groups so that's why you also
see similar ttps
they also rely on open source tools or
or those tools that are already used by
penetration testing teams
across the across the corporate networks
so something you can always see across
the environments that they are no longer
having exclusive provider software but
also use
uh the open source software and the way
that actually once the access to
corporate network is secured or
government network
the two things can happen as we've seen
that the
different the access is sold as a
commodity but also offered as a service
to different sophisticated groups
and that's how we came across the
lazarus infections
and some of the most interesting some of
the most prolific
and highly regarded infections that
we've seen are those that of course as
we mentioned earlier
have rich network records those that
have big corporate environments that can
be infected
or exported in some other ways but also
offered as a service by trusted
relationship between those groups
so they can also be sold directly on the
various underground forums
as if you know like uh so the access can
be commodity
uh as an open like auction style forum
if the network access is not sold
oftentimes it's provided by
different other actors to to look for
specific files or databases or run
specific urls across their botnet
oftentimes the access is used as a
service of course where they take
part in the profit sharing model of once
they monetize
the for example ransomware so they can
be a percentage of the fee
when one state once they exploit basic
land and secure payment from the victim
so just
different profit sharing models that
we've seen in the
underground landscape
again just to uh two three ideas
direct dark web sales we've seen
financial data manipulations for example
one stock trading some of the groups
also sophisticated apt groups do that
and we sell to malware teams or those
teams that are exploitation teams
that are um those are the ones that
would deploy a cobalt strike as we
showed earlier or interpreter
and use different specific toolkits to
either move the cross laterally to
network
or target for example point of sale
terminals
or deploy ransomware directly
so what's the unique things and we'll as
we talk through the
can advanced piston thread approach and
ransomware and trig button lazarus and
how does he
connect so trigbot just to take it one
step back is the
russian-speaking sophisticated crime or
group that were former customers
where actually comes they do derive back
to dire
and dire with the customers of slavic
who the person we discussed earlier
the father the godfather of crime where
if if i can call them that
way and the lazarus is the north korea
pro
uh for profit for profit group that
is believed to be supported by the
nation state uh government
the task with procuring currency
bringing back to the north korean regime
so what do the russians
do with north koreans or what is the
russian group that believe to be
similar gang cyber crime game but
actually they are more than just a game
their sophisticated
criminal enterprise and how do they work
within lazar's group
which is we know it to be the north
korean group so the specific
unique things that we talked about the
trick but enterprise
it's now also no longer that we've seen
the groups are
just games as i mentioned or
or single like as you've seen the the
trig bot has sophisticated operations
that comes from crypto mining ransomware
steelers and bank fraud
where they deploy different types of
operators to staff it
uh and ransomware of course right you
and now kante
steelers of course and then crypto
miners and bank fraud
and the idea just to monetize their
infections
and this is used to be and this is kind
of the core model behind the trick but
dyer and slavic that he developed he
realized that he can squeeze more value
through
ransomware and then they also do
ransomware now and they operate as a
professional coded
coding coders actually something that
is pretty actually impressive when you
look at into them
and now the specific intersection
between
the kind of the crimeware uh an apt
domain
is the kind of the whole the holy grail
of the nexus between the two
was that the specific task you know bots
as i mentioned earlier
two and two waves access to crime crime
net uh
to to to networks procured by criminal
groups or
uh it can be sold to apt groups or
different other crime work groups
it's through access as a service for
example where the
profit share you have a profit sharing
model for example
and if i'm a crimeware or an apt group
and i'm asking them hey can you just
let me know if you have specific bank
internal access for example
and they would say like yes we do and
then we'll either pay
them a fee for the for example if they
target like point of sale terminals or
systems
behind it they'll just pay a fee steady
fee depending on the relationship or
sell them as a commodity
as you can see here the camera domain is
that the steelers fraud
ransomware network content module
injects password grab module that's the
typical trig bot and the apt domain was
that the anchor project
the anchor is also a name used within
the trigbot
pdb path loaders or bots itself as you
might see in our blog that we published
with
actually when we discovered with
sentinel labs was that the anchor
was the that's kind of the flavor of
trigbot almost like a fork
of the core project of trigbot you can
see that they also derive
the memory scraper point of sale malware
also there is also used exclusively by
the group
there's also anchor bot and then the
unique thing it was the power tank
that's the tool believed to be uniquely
attributed to lazarus group
it's a powerful version of a tangoba
same malware that used to use actually
targeted the polish central
authority uh bank actually quite some
time ago when bae
noticed that so they're also kind of
pretty notably attributed to the group
that we were talking about
and the unique aspects that the kind of
is
just to come back and been home the idea
is that
once they identify high value targets
there was a trigbot anchor server
that has this task as you can see econ
box store
with the actions he get passed that was
executed and downloaded and high profile
victim bod
and uh and that was the exact powershell
version of power tank
which is also again uniquely attributed
to the
lazarus group and that's where the
unique nexus is
and that's also led us to believe that
so the groups are also
very connected connected more than just
uh on the relationship side
they're practically part of the access
as a service model
or for example the group or the person
who actually asked to download power
tangba
on behalf of uh we're assuming
the lazarus group was also very familiar
with the trigbet
operators or might be in very close
proximity and we also know that for
example that north korea also deploys
practices or very connected
to the underground world as it is as
there have been
numerous documented cases of them either
working directly
or sharing bots with also the group
called ta 505
or the trig plot and it's also just to
show you the example of that as you
remember earlier i showed you the ecom
backstore
url where the action was again psb
and it was downloaded through on the red
bank
that the bank in chile uh intrusion and
that was
the part-time but through the fake i
guess resume
application process where some of the
software developers inside the bank
was targeted by the lazarus group by
linkedin apparently
and they spoke on the phone and skype
and actually and they downloaded this
app
as an application it was just to install
and bruce them into
uh direct bank internal installations
but the same url we found in trig
budgets also with one
difference is uh the the one that they
saw
was that a get psb but we also see get
psb that's a last action
argument used by the same server so
pretty interesting
and uh and that's kind of shows the
unique and first uh
opportunity we saw of the direct link
between uh
first confirmed technical link between
the trig bot and lazarus it was pretty
exciting when we discovered and continue
to see that
and it kind of highlights this idea the
bot that they actually tasked on was a
high profile victim
and the way they profiled again as we
mentioned is that through network active
network and active directory parsing and
also just trying to identify if
a high value target
i guess the idea is that can also as
we've seen that are evil and mace for
example some of the most sophisticated
groups
also become apts on their own
also work with apt for example the our
evo works with fin7 pin 7 supplies some
infections to them
uh and kind of like not infections but
uh pin 7 actually extorts some of the
companies deploy ransomware as well
because ransomware become very
successful and this is kind of like the
new the flavor of the day where the
crimeware also takes this now the step
model with kind of the merged the ept
group
the advanced percent threat groups and
ransomware and now they're also using
that approach to maximize
publicity as we know we live in the
world of the social media and
the uh journalism so that's what they
try to do they try to
bring more publicity around breaches and
force some like legal actions and that's
something that
our evil unknown which is the
representative
behind the group that was super
successful currently
that the successor of the game crab
operations
it also kind of implies that hey if you
do not like
uh reply back or not like really
interested there's a gdpr
of course concerns and then he basically
says
that uh yeah instead of like encrypting
just files they threaten to publish them
and it kind of like becomes the flavor
whenever you do needs a response work on
ransomware cases
look for evidence of exploration because
that was the key in many cases
they no longer just simply deploy
ransomware and leave but also
find some means and ways and hooks to
download more data
and make it available for for them to
later to extort basically to force
the payment from the victims
so one idea i want to show you and i
want you to
when you to get out of this talk it's
also as we talked earlier the whole
evolution chain
from from zeus father of crimeware zoo
slavic
to the trigbot operators working now
with the
uh person or reported like person worked
before who
is linked with lazarus group through
technical evidence that we saw
uh we also want to find out some unique
yara hunting opportunities for code
reuse
i i definitely believe a huge believer
and the code we use across
the different malware samples is the is
the easiest
not the easiest rather i would say the
most successful and the most
highly profitable i guess from from the
hunter side
to to obtain more value is just to look
for unique
implementations of code but i want to
like to make you think about even a step
further
do not even look for unique uh code
implemented but look for crypto
implementation
or like if there's opportunity to find a
unique
cryptographical implementations in the
mall or just pursue it and write a quick
signature
that's something that i've we've been
doing for quite some time and that's
something that allows us to
even sometimes they convertedly see the
new samples before they getting flagged
or identified by anti-virus engines and
that's something that allows us to be
ahead of them
in many ways it's it feels like a cat
mouse game so from the
malware developer side they try to be
ahead of the defense
they want to make sure the code is not
detected or it's
by passes certain av antivirus
detections but also from our side we can
also hunt for the human behavior
which is the unique implementations of
code
so this is kind of like it's also kind
of leads to unique positive
issue things like that like reducing our
workload and allows us to have high
fidelity
uh long standing rules across across our
signatures
and this is an example of has been
tracking this is the trigbot loader
this is the one that has the typical
custom crypter
with the unique rc4 key implementations
as that we've been tracking since 2019
and the way we can actually we're
tracking
through that specific group through
unique character
and as we talked about the trigger
button is linking to anchor and anchors
also was used in the same
cryptic before as well as the ryuk and
now kante
and also imitation was using similar
crypter but there's a
huge opportunity for us for defense
knowing what their evolution is knowing
what their
behavior is and focusing on them allows
us to identify unique
yara signature opportunities and this is
an example where the
trigbull utilized its own unique
encryption service
for some time and now it's been
frequently updated and the latest
versions also kind of uses the kind of
rc4 with the twist
and it's kind of like a key aspect of
learning the adversary behaviors and
applying
the our intelligence hat and our
intelligence knowledge to the technical
domain
it's a perfect opportunity to write a
simple and packer and at the same time
to force analyze a modified routine this
is kind of like on the bottom
you'll see it's going to slightly change
a changed s
box size of the the rc4
key the unique implementations that we
saw across the malware
including including all the loaders that
precursors to lazarus that we saw
earlier and
actually going forward even of course
going forward that's the future
we're looking into that's the unique
what they actually added the ror
13 api hash and now they have rc4 key
with null terminator and s
box size you see s bucket size is very
non-typical
for rc4 it's not the usual size
it's actually 184 so like
as you can see those who track the crypt
implementation that kind of be super
valuable
once you see uniquely uh changed
the uh rc4 key and oftentimes when
you're looking to try to develop
automation tools
allow you to have advanced visibility
into malware oftentimes you can be
questions of
why why my rc4 doesn't work especially
after recognizing the same as boxes you
see here
and cache rotating uh kind of you and
this
the reason why it's that they slightly
altered it to make it less
uh less easy or uh
for for defense to essentially obtain uh
information about the bot
and this is the key there it's an
example of how you can
search for this is this is just looking
for the unique snippets
the unique snippets as i mentioned
actually in tweet as well as you can see
this unique
key they used uh
oftentimes that's used actually within
the stop of a crypter
and stub it's basically the program that
used to kind of like uh
to decrypt uh and essentially run the
crypto itself
and uh and impact the core binary of its
own
just kind of the terminology across of
it and and it kind of like remains
sim somewhat consistent as you can see
the snippet of this
oftentimes when you look into um ida pro
i recommend to turn on the um
these essentially to the up codes to see
what the up codes because of that my
right signature is off the op codes as
you can see on the left side
and snippets will have certain
components of course you can wild card
certain bytes
especially those can be changed and and
provide opportunity to those that be
flexible
and the s box size as you can see that's
something super notable
for us to track but something that's
again unique opportunity
here that the xbox size does not account
for 184 but
uh but this is just a unique example
across the samples as you can see
two aspects of the signature can be used
is that the snippet of the key component
and then
again we are tracking the packed malware
uh so
pretty interesting and kind of like
ahead of the thread and then the s-box
and that's what the unique
um trigbot s-box rc 4k implementation
the condition of course the snippet and
xbox size
just uh for those who are into writing
the art centers that's something the
unique
unique crypt implementations in the
malware that we were just talking
through
allows us to have uh future visions into
what they've been doing and what's the
new state of malware
and then of course you can use unique
different things and look for
yara scan for example custom as box and
key for
automated static unpacker and scripting
or you you
utilizing a reliant on certain sandbox
feature so there's a huge and
rich opportunities for you to learn and
kind of like apply your knowledge on the
technical
side and then essentially write this
simple or
not simple to simple static and packers
so i want to talk and kind of like give
you a few takeaways
of from the presentations and talk about
what the unique things and uh
of course beyond even uh the truth but
anchor and the evidence that we showed
earlier
is that the new kind of flavor of the
day is that the automations in malware
approach to spam it's it's no longer
just the span
it's no longer just the financial fraud
exploitations that we saw that they
deploy
network exploitation operators to staff
their infections
there's a convergence of apt in crime or
as we talked earlier
is that the network access or the bot
access is sold as an access as a service
or access as a one one opportunity right
so like access is a commodity
so there's a different ways and
different means and methods how does
crimeware and ebt
groups especially in a financially
motivated side and those are they
actually work with apt groups for
electric bot and
uh for example that's one of the
evidence of uh the lazarus group
and that was kind of the hidden nexus
between those groups and that's how they
work and
once they trigger an inc identified high
value target and they're in close
contact with the person who works or
affiliated with
the group as known to be a lazarus north
korean state sponsor group they would
ask them to download a task and profile
the machine
or doing something similar to that
extent whatever they would do
and the way that we do it through for
example this was the powershell or
actually download and execute
type of task and this is kind of the new
flavor or rather the trend the trending
flavor of the day
where the cyber crime meets apt
especially on the
ransomware side where after successful
network
exploitation operations after they steal
all the databases
all and squeeze the value from the
financial direct flow
fraud exploitations that would
essentially use the
uh to essentially use it for ransomware
as ransomware
to be highly profitable in other ways
not only use a ransomware but also
you used ransom hacks so connect the
data
and then extort the victims publicly so
make sure the news can cover the stories
and journalists can report on them and
of course enforce more pressure to the
board to comply with the
cyber crime demands and one of the
interesting things across
all of them i want to like get away with
the kind of
quick tips and quick idea behind the
presentations as to how to use the yara
which is a signature matching tool
and just looking for the malware
developers and the way to look for our
developers for unique cryptologic
implementations
so the logical keys are the future the
logical keys provide the highest value
add for for us and also
and i think it's also very efficient way
of going forward
because oftentimes the stream match is
not enough or even the code we use
does not mean meet the demand of hunters
to search across the new and emerging
malware threats
and uh so yeah the idea is to hunt for
decryptive logic implementations
so on this note i would like to thank
you for attending
my online virtual talk i would love to
be in person but this year is a special
year for many of us
please feel free to reach out if you
have any questions and
i'm passing the microphone back to the
organizers
you