hi guys uh welcome to my talk
so what i'm going to talk about it's not
the
technical side of iot attacks and iot
devices
this is more interesting because what we
are noticing
is that whenever we hear on the news
about
iot attacks the kind of the kind of
attacks that they are right
they tend to focus on the theoretical
attacks
the kind of attacks that can happen as
opposed to the
kind of attacks that are happening and
that's a very very big distinction right
because you can talk theoretically about
barbie dolls being attacked but yeah are
they actually happening those attacks
not really and we're gonna see how this
is the kind of stuff
that uh the the media are talking on the
news right
i i put that there as a news header
because that it
has actually been used at the iot
armageddon
wow look at this this this is a real
um a real news header from 2017
five nightmarish attacks right they call
it nightmarish like it's gonna cause you
nightmares that's going to be terrifying
another one is uh this is kind of true
right iot attacks are getting worse
they are getting worse but no one's
listening why
but well let's see this is very very
scary
the five worst examples of iot hacking
and vulnerabilities
it's like wow you know lots and lots of
very new attacks against
amazing uh kinds of uh devices
and this is a another one cyber attacks
on the rise
iot and ddos right the world gonna end
very soon um in the in the actual
real life well this is another example
this is my favorite example because
every time that you see a news header
with a an exotic device being vulnerable
they always start with a cyber or the
toaster your toaster is going to be
attacked
it was like a toaster once i started
researching iot attacks i started to
okay
maybe there are everybody has toasters
that can
can be online right i have a regular
toaster so i
i don't know about this so i started
researching and there's not actually
any toaster that can be purchased this
is from
uh from ces 2017 so this is a
theoretical
toaster that i can't i can't find
online i couldn't buy it on amazon so my
toaster can be attacked but i can't buy
any toaster that can be online so what's
the point right
this is uh the kind of thing that we can
see you know the iot invasion how to
avoid being hacked by your toaster
okay what toaster um
again every time you see this news
header my toaster hacked the pentagon
really wow and i can't find any toasters
i can't get online
uh this is another one you know as i was
saying before uh the hello barbie
uh wow your barbie doll can be hacked
and the barbie can inspire your children
really i mean
we need to settle this right because
this news headers are
very terrifying and uh i doubt that
these
iot devices are really in the plans of
any
real criminal like we're talking real
world hackers right
so what we did it's try to look at
the real this is the reality somebody
using mirai botnets to shut down
countries that makes sense now that now
we can see that
what does uh mirai uh work on does it
work on barbie dolls or in toasters
no it works on normal devices right like
uh
routers routers are the most uh common
device
to hack by far like there's not even a
comparison
there's some printers that can be can be
uh
hacked and can be monetized but the
monetization plans are really routers
not barbie dolls not toasters not
any craziness and yet we see the news
headers going like this
the botnet of smart air conditioners and
heaters
air conditioners or heaters i mean who
is using that to hack anything you know
we don't see that and
we only see it in the news but we don't
see it in real life criminals are not
using these devices
so what we went and did is uh try
to survey the criminal underground of
russian uh language uh portuguese
uh instead of the portugal flag i put
their brazil
because uh the portuguese speaking
underground is mostly focused on brazil
then the english underground
spanish-speaking underground and arabic
speaking underground
we surveyed those five environments
trying to see
what the hackers were targeting what
kind of attacks they were planning
and very important if there is actually
a monetization plan because if there's
no monetization plan
what's what is good for a hacker to hack
why would you hack something that you
can't make any money off
you hack your barbie and you listen to
somebody's kid
screaming what's the point right that's
not gonna happen
from the defense perspective yeah you
might defend against it from the attack
perspective
why bother so we wanted to see if
there's any monetization plan
for those people then we see the
distinction between all of these uh
five kinds of undergrounds so first
let's clarify what is iot what do we
consider to be iot
so any device any device that
uh does not have a a normal operating
system a windows
operating system anything is fair game
so we
we can see there like uh dog feeders
printers air conditioners that's fair
game
all of these kind of devices we don't
consider it to be
phones so phones in a different
environment we're not going to talk
about phones
not servers not desktops nothing
this is the kind of thing that we're
talking about so what do we see
what kind of devices do we see it being
attacked the most of course
routers we're going to talk about the
monetization plan
um first on cameras online cameras are
are very interesting now and you think
why would you bother to
check on a camera to look and hack a
camera
the camera is very interesting because
it's pointing somewhere right
and that somewhere maybe potentially
interesting for other hackers to look at
why you can see number one uh for
perverts very very easy all these
cameras that have
uh like like that's a beauty salon at
some point somebody
is going to show something there right
and you can see that it's wide open on
the internet there's
the ip don't try the ip it doesn't work
anymore but
that ip at some point had that password
and that
username there you can see the port
there and
that's interesting it's interesting i
mean there's a public who
who might find it interesting and would
potentially buy access to them
what else is interesting and this is
much much better right
uh there's a lot of security cameras on
top
of payment systems and this is you can
tell that
you can see the cart whenever somebody
inserts the car you're going to be able
to see
the the car and you can see the pin
being entered so that's super
interesting right that's
immediately much more interesting for
any criminal and
you can see any warehouse anything that
has a security system
when when you're able to monitor the
security system you can see
when the the the guards come in when the
cars go out what the ships are like so
if you're planning on robbing a
warehouse
having uh the camera access to all of
the warehouse
you can see when the the the trucks are
coming
what kind of material is coming when the
guards are off
you can see everything so how do you
make money out of this
now you can see this um this is uh on
the pervy side right all the
changing rooms i have no idea why a
chain changing room would be
on an open webcam but there's a lot of
them
so what the bad guys do is they package
all those uh
into channels like netflix and then they
sell access to them like you can see
there right
all of these uh channels all of these
are camps like
pervy kind of uh cameras and then you
can see the access
it's 50 rubles that's very very common
in the russian underground
and then they accept visa for payment
perfect right that's one way of
monetizing
they do it thematically so they do the
porn channels or the
beauty cam channels and they do the
the atm channels there's
a a variety of different themes that uh
you can pay for so if you're interested
for ins
for instance in in getting and cloning
uh credit cards
you go into one of these channels and
then you can get all of that
uh at the end of the day all these are
either open cams or camps with default
passwords so that's immediately
interesting if you can
use a vulnerability to to have access
to a closed webcam all the better right
that's worth a lot more
but these are the cheap ones you can see
that the prices are really really cheap
50 rubles
is not allowed to access one of these
channels so that's way of monetizing
another way of monetizing and now
they're talking about routers which are
by far
the most popular is selling ssh tunnels
so they get
into your router and then they install
a node of a vpn so that now
your router is now an exit node of a vpn
and then these guys the criminals go
online and then they sell
access to your and any other
member of that botnet for sale so you
can see there
this one this guy is selling ssh tunnels
or vpn
that it's sitting on private home
routers they they exclusively say that
because it's very difficult for
isps to block this so they're selling it
and there's a clear monetization plan so
there is the reason for criminals to
take over your router
and own it because they can sell access
to it
through a vpn channel the vpn
channel yeah this is another example you
know ssh tunnels
being sold they're not that they're not
that expensive if you look at the prices
they're super super cheap
and then they they particularly say home
or office routers so
this is really good because if you're a
criminal and you go online and buy
a vpn that's sitting on somebody's
router then your exit note it's that
uh that ip that the ip of that router
right so
the police will see that somebody is
being attacked or robbed
with an ip from a guy in argentina who
god knows right
and very difficult to trace and of
course there's no
official vpn logs so it's very very
handy for
criminals this is another example again
same thing
and it's telling telling you um
specifically
they're renting a botnet spot with mirai
and you can see the speed and it's also
for
um for ddos you can you can uh
tell what the throughput is so you can
even use it for for ddos
uh by the way ddos is very very common
so i i neglected to say that but
vpn it's super common but if you have
access
to the router then you can redirect any
amount of packets through
that uh through that node right so you
can use it as
a ddos uh channel so that's why they
tell the throughput there so you can use
it as a channel or you can use it as a
as a vpn now this is a
really interesting one that we saw in
brazil in
up until now very common in the in the
russian
underground this one is relatively
common in the brazilian underground in
the portuguese speaking area
so what they do is they they take over
your router and once they have access to
the router they change the dns
right so then people behind the router
they
they the dns is not exactly working well
right so they go to google and they
probably
they redirect you to google without any
problem but
then they have the possibility of
changing those uh
uh those uh conversions right the dns
conversion
so they do that with uh with specific
banks right so they go to bank of brazil
and instead of going to the real bank of
brazil
they go to a fake bank of brazil why do
they do that because then
once you have a botnet of uh infected
routers then you sell dns
redirections to people willing to do
phishing
so if you're a client right then
you set up a phishing site for bank of
brazil
then you go to the botnet uh owner and
says okay could you redirect
all of your routers bank of brazil dns
uh routing to my fake site so then
all of those people behind the router
they go to bangkok brazil.com writing it
you know not a bad link a real link
and then they'll be redirected to the
fake
website so you can see um
you can see an example of an
advertisement
it's not very expensive if you look at
this it's a 1000 reais
per week that works out like 250
dollars per week that's not a lot i mean
if you have a
fishing site and you manage to have true
dns redirections to your fake side
you can make that in with a couple of
customers you know
a couple of victims so that's not really
bad and it's very very good for
um for the botnet owner if you have a
bunch of infected
botnets a bunch of infected routers with
with this system
then you can sell those redirections
pretty quickly very very easily
here's another another example you know
again the same you know pretty much uh
the prices are are very similar they
call it kl
dns banker so it's it's a dns
redirection system
for infected routers that's again
something very novel we've only seen it
in the portuguese speaking underground
and it's a clear way of monetizing an
infected router so if you infect a
router how do you make money of it well
you can install a dns redirection system
other than that what have we seen the
portuguese
underground and the russian underground
very very
active in trying to own routers and own
mostly routers in the rest of the
undergrounds like
this is an example of english
underground right there's a lot of
interest
in owning but more in the knowledge side
they want to know how right this is
uh using exploits to own uh netgear
routers
using exploits to exploit printers
but there's no clear monetization why
it's more of
i want to hack it because i can as
opposed to
i want to hack it because it will make
me money so
once you own a printer what do you do
you reboot it i don't know what
it's very limited that the amount of
stuff that you can do with a with a
remote printer you can print stuff
right hello but it's not not
really the focus of these undergrounds
these undergrounds have not
found yet a way of making money off of
those infections
so they focus more on the knowledge on
the how to
hack um this is a
interesting one right on uh on the
english speaking underground
with a router scan you know it scans the
whatever ip range that you want it scans
for a router
and uh it tries to uh see which ones uh
may be exploitable or not so you see
which which uh
which routers are online and then it
tries to
check with usernames and passwords is it
useful
it's marginally useful i mean i think
that this
shows an interest by the hackers for
owning routers
but there is no clear monetization plan
behind so
you own the router username and password
and after that i don't know you're on
your own
so there's no clear monetization there's
no clear why why would you do this i'm
not sure what a hacker would do
with with these owned routers you know
you have to
um infect them somehow but the the
infection is separate
from the intention of owning them which
is the only thing that
is shown in these undergrounds
this is an interesting one and this
apparently was a portuguese guy
uh and he was uh he was uh
advertising on uh the english
underground and uh
speaking uh portuguese speaking and
spanish speaking underground and
he made apparently i haven't been able
to test but
the advertisement is selling a tool
that will look whole ip
ranges for a specific device in this
case it's an
hp officejet pro it will look for it and
if it finds one
it will try to connect automatically
with username and password
right again it's a way of
detecting the devices online is it
useful for them
it's marginally useful i mean it shows
interest it shows that people want to
own this uh
these uh printers uh with what intent
i i couldn't say there's no clear
monetization plan
and plan there's no way of making money
off of those infections
immediately with with these tools
again lots of interest right we see in
the spanish speaking underground
somebody was doing google dork to find
the
online refrigeration systems like
industrial refrigeration systems
that were open in this one you use that
dork
you get into a refrigerator system what
do you do with that i have no idea you
can lower the temperature or up the
temperature
i don't know marginally useful again it
shows interest
it doesn't show uh actual intent
uh the arabic speaking underground is
pretty much the same
right the very low sophistication and
this one this is a translation right
the image is the original but the rest
is a translation uh it's
it it's pretty much telling you that
there are tutorials on how to break into
cameras
but again it doesn't say what to do with
them you know
if you find a good camera then you'll be
able to look at a swimming pool right
okay no there's no monetization plan
way way way different than that russian
plan
trying to break over packetize them and
sell channels uh like
netflix completely different environment
this one
is just the technical how to this is how
you
try to break a camera period that's
where they stop
another one there right this is a whole
translation
uh how to hack you know penetration
cameras
how to do penetration testing on uh
online camps
okay marginally useful not really a show
of intent so what
we're saying here is that these people
do have uh or they're amassing
the knowledge they have the interest
to start attacking iot devices all sorts
of devices there's interest in a lot of
devices
we're seeing uh mostly uh
routers and cameras but also all sorts
of
very strange devices right every time
that there's a new vulnerability on
x device somebody will will try to
create a tutorial on how to own it but
in reality hackers
do not um try to attack just because
they can right it's good to try and
attack uh
just because you can once but you're not
going to keep attacking
if there's no way of making money out of
it and
what we're seeing is that they are
developing mostly in russia
in the russian underground they are
developing very clear monetization plans
for making money off of infected routers
same path a little bit behind it's under
brazilian underground they have created
some
money some monetization plan for making
money off of routers also
the rest of the undergrounds completely
completely behind
as to what pertains to attacking routers
they know how
they're sharing how they they are
technical enough to know
what kind of uh attacks can be performed
but they have not figured out any
monetization plan therefore
hackers from those environments uh we
can only assume that they're trying to
attack
just for kicks just for fun but uh we
don't see any concerted effort
that that is going to be successful in
the long term
unless they find a real clear
monetization plan this is my bottom line
so you have routers and other devices
they they can
and they will be attacked so if you own
a sizeable amount of them you have to
start devising a plan
in order to protect them they will be
attacked there is a clear
intent there is a clear monetization
plan to make money
off of those attacks therefore those
attacks will keep going and will keep
increasing as other hackers know what to
what how to make money off of those
your barbie dolls i think they're safe
for the moment
thank you jenguya barzo
you