good morning everyone
thank you very much for joining us today
and good morning from london
thank you for joining our presentation
on the lazarus group's use of the
detract remote
access trojan and we're going to be
performing a retrospective analysis
of the various campaigns that we've
observed over the years
my name is john southworth and i am a
senior threat intelligence analyst
at pwc uk i primarily focus on tracking
threat actors based in the asia pacific
region
and i've been tracking north korea based
threat actors for the past few years
and instead i don't know if you can see
me um
hi i'm sabra i'm also a senior
intelligence analyst at plvc uk
i also focus on introductory space in
asia pacific region
but instead of doing comparative malware
in university i used to do
a comparative literature instead so
that's a bit of a jump there
and speaking of drums let's go right
into our agenda for the day
so we thought we'd start to talk a bit
about the lazarus group whether you
known them already or not
and we're going to give a brief timeline
of the most high profile operations that
have been attributed to lazarus group
we're also going to be touched on the
different ways in which lazarus group is
tracked across the industry
and touch on some of the subgroups and
aliases
that the lazerus group is known as then
we're going to go into
the detract remote access trojan and
we're going to trace its evolution
its different characteristics and
functionality
and take a look at some of the campaigns
where detrock was used as a payload
from there we're going to look at ditrax
dropper
track drop as we call it and how we have
observed track drop
working and dropping some tools
associated with lasers
and other tools associated with a laser
subgroup that is known as
andario including a downloader which is
fairly sophisticated and which we known
as anonymous talking about the anonymous
downloader which is associated with
andario
we're also going to be talking about
anonymous connections to another
on the real tool the back door rift door
and then we're going to pull all these
threads together look at how all of this
is connected to lazarus
and what this tells us about lazarus
operations and finally we're going to
give a bit of
insight into how defenders and end users
can protect themselves
from ditra campaigns but without further
ado i'm going to hand over to john who's
going
to be talking to us about the lazarus
group
thank you very much seba so
i imagine that most of us listening to
this presentation
have already heard of the lazarus group
but if you haven't
i'll do a quick overview it is a north
korea-based threat actor
that has been active since approximately
2007.
and on the right-hand side of this
screen you can see several of the
well-known campaigns
that have been attributed back to the
lazarus group
now lazarus group is not the only name
that this threat actor is known by
and internally at pwc we track the
lazarus group
under the name black artemis
it is also known in open source which a
name that has been given to it by the us
government
as hidden cobra now what is interesting
about the lazarus group
is that its motivations have been
changing
over time and on this slide you will see
several of the motivations associated
with it
namely that of espionage it's well known
for its espionage campaigns which focus
on
stealing information from organizations
for the purposes
of turning it into actionable
intelligence but perhaps it is more well
well known recently for his campaigns
that target organizations for the
purposes of cybercrime
that is financially motivated campaigns
but originally the lazarus group was
also known for
its campaigns that were targeting
organizations for the purposes of
sabotage
that is they have more of a destructive
or disruptive angle
now in the threat intelligence community
it's sometimes hard to come to a
consensus
of what the term lazarus group actually
means
after all it is a threat actor that has
been around for a long time
and its motivations have been evolving
what i can say is that
within pwc the way that we track this
intrusion set that is known as black
artemis
spans these three motivations that you
can see on this slide
that being sabotage espionage and
cybercrime
now this name black artemis also aligns
with the open source names that i've
also mentioned
that being lazarus group and hidden
cobra and throughout this presentation
we'll be using the terms black artemis
and lazarus group interchangeably
however there are also other ways to
track subgroups of the lazarus group as
you can see on this slide
for instance in the column describing
the lazarus group's sabotage campaigns
a known subgroup or also an alias of
this
group is called dark soul which was
originally known for targeting
organizations in south korea with the
purposes of sabotage
i.e through denial of service attacks
but also on the far right you can see in
the cyber crime column
there are a couple of names that can be
used to specifically track
the subgroups of lazarus that focus on
financial crime
specifically apt-38 and blue narrow
one that is also worth pointing out is
the subgroup of lazarus
known as andario that we assess spans
both the motivations of espionage
and cybercrime and it's worth pointing
out that all of these are still
a part of this lazarus umbrella but you
may be asking why
don't we track them in this more
specific way
and the reason we do that is that we are
seeing an overlap in the tools that it
uses
for the purposes of espionage with also
for the purposes
of cyber prime so for instance a remote
access trojan that we'll see being used
in an espionage campaign would also then
be reused
in this different campaign targeting a
completely different organization
for a different motivation i.e
cyberprime
so on this slide we've mapped out a
timeline of some of the really
well-known
lazarus group campaigns and the way
we've done this is that we've
named the campaign and given the year
and a brief description
of what that campaign involved so early
on in the timeline you'll be able to see
campaigns that were more focused on
sabotage
such as operation flame and operation
troy which were well known to be
targeting south korea
as we go through the timeline there are
more focuses on
espionage campaigns such as operation
blockbuster
and the further we go we can start to
see more and more cybercrime-focused
campaigns as well
such as the well-known bank of
bangladesh heist
and targeting of the bank of chile
if we get up to the modern day we start
to get onto the topic of this
presentation
which we started tracking in late 2019
where the lazarus group used a tool
known as d-trac
so what is d-track d-track is a remote
axis trojan that has been used by black
artemis
since at least 2014.
the name d-track itself comes from the
kaspersky blog
released in late 2019 where they named
this tool
we assess from our research that there
are also a couple of other names
that are associated with this tool
specifically
preft which is the symantec name for it
and hadesbot which is the crowdstrike
name for it
we released reporting internally at pwc
on these various campaigns
at the end of 2019 and the beginning of
which builds up the basis of all this
research
now i've been calling d-trac a remote
access trojan so far but it's a little
bit more nuanced than that
in fact when we were tracking it we
found that earlier variants of d-track
were closer to back doors that is they
weren't so much there to
interact with the file system of the
infected machine in depth
we're more so there to provide basic
functionality
and drop further tools whereas later on
we found that d-track was more close to
a fully fledged rat
in that it could perform a lot of
capabilities that the back doors could
but also exfiltrate data as well for the
threat actors use
and in the next slide we're going to be
breaking down these capabilities
as we've observed them over time as such
and you can see this is
broken down into almost two sections
at the top we have two capabilities that
we have observed being consistent with
all
the track samples that we have picked up
the first being the capability to
download a file to the infected system
and the second being the ability to
change the time between beacons to the
command and
control servers
we have also seen the abilities to run
shell commands
and remove persistence and exit from the
remote access trojan
but there are slight gaps in these
capabilities where they weren't present
now we can explain away some of those
with some of the capabilities that were
also present that would fill those gaps
but these four capabilities at the top
make up what we call
the core build of d-trac
as we go through the rest of these
capabilities though we start to see the
changes
over time in the color yellow you can
see all of the capabilities that are
more associated with the backdoor
variants
of d-track and in orange the
capabilities associated with
the remote access trojan variants with
2017 being the pivotal year
between them changing these capabilities
so for instance for the back door there
are various capabilities
such as downloading and immediately
executing a file
performing code injection or executing
shell code within the same process
these are all more experimental features
as they only appear
for very short amounts of time and then
i'm seemingly never used again
one capability i want to highlight which
is at the top of this section
is this removing persistent mechanisms
if they've been set
and immediately executing a file now
this could be explained by
the lazarus group using this capability
to
remove detract and then install a new
implant
maybe a new remote access trojan that it
wants to use
but some security researchers have also
speculated
that d-track has been used to deploy
more tools
for the purposes of sabotage such as
disc wipers
and this capability could also explain
that
we're going back to the end of it from
this year 2017 onwards
all of these experimental features were
gotten and instead we're left with the
two capabilities
of exfiltrating files and getting the
current configuration of the remote
access trojan
which builds up a stable build of
detract that is used consistently
from 2017 onwards
so let's dive into the internals of
detract a bit more in depth
before any malicious code is executed by
d-trac it must perform its
initialization routine
this consists of generating a victim id
which is made by combining the values
such as the computer name
and the hardware id of the infected
system
it will then gather some basic system
information such as the operating system
type
and the ip address of the infected
machine
and finally it will decode a number of
hard-coded command control server
addresses
and you can see this at a high level on
the right hand side of the slide
a nice feature that you can also see on
this slide in the bottom left
is a screenshot where very kindly of the
threat actor they
or rather a mistake on their part they
forgot to remove their debug logging
messages
which spells out the key functionality
of these samples
and in this case you can see that it's
begun the main thread and that the
initialization has finished
successfully so how are these strings
decoded how are these c2 addresses
actually decoded well we have observed
three variants of the string decoding
routines
being used in d-track in particular we
have seen rc4 being used to decode the
strings
with a hard-coded key stored within the
binary itself
we've seen a method of xor being used
where a one byte key is stored at the
beginning of the string
and then used to subsequently decode the
rest of the string
and we have seen a variant or multiple
variants
where strings are prepended with the
characters ccs
underscore and are then removed at
runtime
now the kind of strings that are encoded
by these routines
are as mentioned the c2s
but also things like the api functions
and
format strings that might want to be
used and you can see an example of this
routine on the right
where this routine has the capability to
decode ccs
underscore strings and xor strings
so in combination with this string
decoding routine
d-track for the most part will perform a
technique known as dynamic api loading
this is where rather than having all of
your
imports and windows apis stored in your
import address table
instead they are all loaded at run time
using the windows api's
load library and get prop address
this can make static analysis harder as
you won't see these apis present in the
binary
using only static analysis tools and
this is actually
a technique that is quite consistently
used by
black artemis or the lazarus group it's
not unique to the lazarus group
but it is informative that they carry on
using this technique
in most of their tools
this technique combined with the string
encoding can make detract
a bit of a pain to analyze statically
but we developed some hydro scripts
internally just to make our lives a bit
easier to automatically decode these
strings
and to help us retype these libraries
so for the most part i've been
describing features of d-track
that are consistent across all samples
but i want to talk about a few features
over the next few slides that we've only
observed in a couple of samples
again sometimes more experimental
features
in this case we've observed a couple of
persistence mechanisms being set
by the d-trac promote access trojan
specifically we have seen them use
a service using the sc command to create
a service that will automatically
execute
when the user logs in and we've also
seen them
dropping shortcut links into the user's
startup folder
that will again execute detracts dropper
at runtime
we'll be talking about the dropper a
little bit later on and as i've said
not all of these samples have a
persistence mechanism this was more
observed in older samples towards 2014
variants of detract
and i quickly want to go over a couple
of different techniques that we've seen
detract use
to try and evade analysis the first
being antivirus evasion
specifically we have seen some detract
variants
look for file paths and running
processes associated with the armlab
antivirus
software and even so far it's going to
try and
destroy the windows that are associated
with the ad process
this is interesting in of itself as
onlab is a south korean anti-virus
vendor
and could indicate some targeting
there is also a technique we've seen
used in some d-trac samples
that will evade sandboxes and this is
done by using the windows api
get cursorpos to get the position of the
mouse cursor
and not continue executing until the
mouse cursor has moved
this can be defeated by a lot of modern
sandboxes by
simulating mouse movement but given this
was present in all the samples it might
have been enough back then
to actually evade sandboxes there are a
couple of more anti-analysis techniques
that we've observed as well including an
anti-virtualization technique
that would look for the vmware drag and
drop folder
and a few cases where detract would look
for the following running processes
you can see in the bottom right
including process explorer
wireshark and process monitor standard
tools that are associated
with malware analysis
so i've been focusing on the
capabilities of e-track so far
i quickly want to touch on some of the
command control features
so as i said before at the beginning of
its initialization detract will
decode between two to five hard-coded
urls
for the most part we've seen them
decoding three urls but this is varied
over time
most of these urls contain domains
themselves
and from our analysis we assess that
most of the domains observed
are likely compromised infrastructure
being used to host the lazarus group's
command and control servers
however we've seen some interesting
cases where
rather than a domain being used we've
seen ip addresses being used and more
specifically we've seen
internal ip addresses being used for
command and control
this likely indicates that the lazarus
group has
embedded their commander control servers
within a victim organization's network
and are using them for command and
control
c2 is done over http as you can see on
some images on the right hand side of
this slide
but the communications are encrypted
using a custom cryptography routine
right so john has
kindly given us a very good technical
deep dive into d-track
but i thought that maybe we could take a
look also at some of the campaigns
that detract has been used as a payload
in
um so both from our geographic
and sectoral and motivation perspective
firstly we've seen
a variant of the track called atm
d-track by kaspersky being used in
targeting of financial institutions
for example for the purposes of atm
cashlet attacks
but we've used d-truck mostly being used
for espionage purposes for example palo
alto unit 42 actually reported that
what we assess is that d-trac variant
which they call
t-drop 2 was used to target
transportation and logistics companies
in europe we've seen the track mostly
deployed against south korean targets
but then in late 2019 several
indian organizations including the
indian space research organization
and kundan kulam nuclear power plant
reported that they had been compromised
with d-trac now as john mentioned there
also have been reports
that d-track might have been used to
execute disk wipers and other
sabotage-oriented malware
we have not observed evidence of this
firsthand
but we cannot rule out based on the
capabilities of detract that this could
have been a possibility
now let's take a closer look at the kk
and pp
incident because it's been a pretty big
headline and it's also a very particular
case
of use of the track so let's start
and what we have here on screen is a
sample that we assess was highly likely
used in the kkk mpp
intrusion now the sample works like this
there is a portable executable dropper
which has been patched
to lead to a decryption routine which
decrypts unencrypted overlay
and then loads the decrypted payload
into memory
which is a direct standard thing but
this sample is particularly tailored to
the victim environment and we're going
to get to that in a second
now if we look at the structure of the
binary we have a win
main function which contains three main
subroutines which neatly subdivide the
main functionality of dtrak
firstly we have a subroutine that takes
care of initialization
and of the windows libraries import
which we can see on screen here on the
right is done with the ccs
underscore obfuscation which is a fairly
trivial obfuscation method if you think
about it but actually
might have been just about enough to
bypass
static signaturing methods or any kind
of like static
detection then we go into another
subroutine which takes care of victim
fingerprinting and identification
and then there's a third function which
actually contains
the huge chunk of the main detox
functionality and
the ability to actually look more in
depth at the victim and not the file
system
so victim fingerprinting and
identification in the kk and ppp
track sample are done pretty much as
this direct standard so we'll have a
victim id
which comprises of computer name windows
owner and windows copy organization as
well as some hardware information
and the kmpp direct sample will also
like other detroit samples
gather the machine operating system and
local ap but then that's where the
differences with the standard detract
build begin
because in this case we have no external
ap addresses being decrypted
and we have no external c2s and no
configuration files
rather we just go into the main chunk of
functionality
and we jump into much deeper victim
fingerprinting
which is affected through a whole series
of sequential
command line commands that are just run
one after the other so you can see on
the screen here
a task list or netstat and the results
of all of these commands that have been
run on the btm system
are then logged into specific files
which as you can see on the top are
saved in a folder
called temp within the user's normal
temp folder
you can never have enough temps and then
after this is done all of these files
will be packaged up in a compressed
archive and password protected
the kmpp direct sample will also gather
browsing and internet data which is
saved in a folder
again in the temp folder with the name
of the machine's local ip address
only after all of this information has
been captured
the malware will try to reach
on internal ap and if a connection is
possible it will go on to further
functionality if it's not you will stop
executing now if it has
reached this internal ap address which
is in the 192 range
the malware will then proceed to
enumerate drives and
files present on the viking machine's
file system and
again package up all this information
that it has collected and compress it in
a password protected
archive we've mentioned that the sample
is highly tailored
and if this is not already interesting
enough
the exfiltration method that the sample
uses will definitely be
so what we see here is that this sample
also contains
a whole series of hard-coded commands
using
net in order to mount a network share
onto another internal ap we see here in
the 10 network range
using hard-coded account credentials
which are specific with the compromised
environment we see
that it's trying to mount a network
share on a domain controller
so this is very distinctive and very
relevant for a whole series of reasons
firstly because what we're looking at
here
is not really a backdoor
well we would have a normal detox sample
in its main chunk of functionality
having a huge jump table
interpreting commands received from the
c2 and then taking further action based
on the command received and then feeding
back information
there is none of that here there is no
interaction with sc2
what we have instead is basically an
infostealer
uh with just a whole series of hardcoded
commands this is not going to download
any further payloads
it's just going to execute whatever is
hard-coded in the sample and then
exfiltrate the results
so what does this tell us that firstly
the binary has been almost carved out
of its main functionality and replaced
with these specific
ad-hoc capabilities but also
that the threat actor would have needed
to have a very
deep level of penetration of the kk and
pp network
in order to firstly move laterally
secondly compromise the domain
controller and be able to use it for
staging
of exfiltrated information and thirdly
to even pinpoint
systems of interest on which to drop
these tailored
detox samples to then perform
information stealing
and we also need to remember that dtrac
is not a standalone executable it
it's not like it just arrives magically
in victim systems
it needs to have a prior foothold the
tractor proper needs to arrive there
somehow in the first place
all of which requires prior compromise
of the environment
and now let's look at a bit of an easter
egg which are
the links to lazarus now
kkmpp d-track is effectively
d-trac the binary structure is exactly
the same and you can tell that the code
base is the same
what is changed is that it's almost been
carved out like a pumpkin
and then the ad-hoc has been added in in
its place
we can also have a few very interesting
details for example
one of the passwords that is used to
encrypt the compressed archives
is the one they dkw ero
38 etc now that's
such a well-known lazarus password that
varistoto
actually ended up using it as a case
study for their ida
plugin so it's pretty much a known
convention
and it actually dates back all the way
to the days of operation troy
which was a series of destructive and
disruptive attacks on south korean
targets in 2009 so we're
seeing the same password a decade later
now
a caveat here very huge caveat this may
well be a threat actor convention we
also know that false flag operations are
very much a thing
but we also know that malware-based
attribution
is very much limited and so
the important thing to remember here is
that whenever we're looking at an
intrusion it's not enough to just look
at the malware and say
yep this is this or to look at these
details you also need to be looking at
the tactics techniques and procedures
involving the intrusion as well as the
infrastructure in order to be able to
make
a comprehensive assessment
so we also said that d-track effectively
is loaded in memory it's not a
standalone executable it doesn't really
touch disk
so how does it get there maybe john can
tell us
thank you very much so as weber has
highlighted
dtrak has never saved a disk in a
standard format
so how do we track it if it's never
saved a disk it's never going to be
easily shared on online multi-antivirus
scanners for example
what we found through our analysis is
that
d-track is dropped by a unique dropper
that we call track drop and has been
around since at least 2014
i.e the same time that detract campaigns
began
track drop also goes by a couple of
other names that we assess
are similar in open source including
export control
and t-drop 2 although the connection to
t-drop 2 itself is a little bit more
nuanced
and we'll get on to that in a few slides
so
what is track drop itself for the most
part track drop binaries are benign
executables
that have been patched or modified in
order to
execute a unique cryptography routine
that will decode a payload stored in the
encrypted overlay
of the portable executable and then run
it
the nice thing about this unique
cryptography routine
is that we were able to go away and
using yara
signature this cryptography routine and
then we were able to use this
to track all of the track drop samples
that we have observed
over the last few years from 2014
onwards
now there are two variants of track drop
that we have observed
the first loads detract into the same
process
as track drop itself but for the more
common variants
we see it use a slightly more
complicated process of
hollowing a randomly selected system
binary and loading detract
into that process i.e process hollowing
so for the most part we've observed
track drop
dropping detract samples but not
exclusively
in fact through our analysis we found
that track drop
also drops a suite of other tools
including downloaders this is where
t-drop 2 comes into play
key loggers and then slightly more out
there
bank fishing pages and even a case where
it was dropping some adware
so ever we'll also be talking a little
bit later about
another sample that is dropped by track
drop which we call the anonymous
downloader
so by taking d-track and pivoting back
to track drop
we were able to map out all these
various tools being used
by the lazarus group and detail them
so let's start talking about the
downloaders
now this is where the connection to
t-drop 2 comes in
and it's a little bit more complicated
than just saying track drop
and t-drop 2 are the same incidentally
we named
the down uh the dropper track drop
independently of t
drop two so the names are just being
similar just a coincidence
but track drop more refers to the
component that is used to perform
the process hollowing or code injection
whereas t-drop 2
appears to more describe the complete
set of the dropper and the downloader
so how does the downloader work what it
does is that
it will download a payload from the c2
save it to disk with a file with a dot
exe extension
and then we'll overwrite the first two
bytes of the file
with the values mz that is
the dos header magic value otherwise it
wouldn't be able to execute properly
without it
and then we'll subsequently execute that
payload
open source research that we've looked
at specifically palo alto's
analysis on t-drop 2 and the payload
that it drops
we assess are likely highly likely
consistent with that
d-track being served by these
downloaders
track drop samples have also been
observed dropping key loggers
and screenshot gathering modules
as independent samples that will save
these
key logging files to disk this is a
technique that we've seen
the lazarus group used before
specifically in financially motivated
campaigns
where rather than having their key
loggers and screenshot gatherers
automatically exfiltrate this data to a
commander control server
instead they are saved to disk and it is
up to whatever remote access trojan
is running on the system to accelerate
that data for the threat actors use
in this case you can see on the right an
example key log output
and this will be stored to disk in a
compressed archive
encrypted with the password that you can
see on screen
now a 2017 variant of this keylogger
also had the capability to gather
screenshots of the infected system
but this was later removed in a 2018
variant
so this is where some of the samples
being dropped by track drop
gets a little bit odd in this in the
case of track drop
we saw it dropping this html page that
you can see on the right which is
masquerading as a banking page almost an
email
for an indian bank claiming that the
user's account has been compromised
and they need to input their details
note that this is a
campaign that is targeting customers of
a bank
and there is no evidence to suggest that
it is targeting the bank
itself while we couldn't obtain
the next stage when we would go through
that click here to update sign it is
highly likely that
this would be some form of credential or
financial information phishing
but what's even more strange about this
sample of track drop is that it didn't
just drop this banking phishing page
but also dropped a sample that we call
the anonymous
downloader which server is going to talk
more about
yep so what is this an honeywell
downloader that we have been mentioning
for the past 20 minutes
thank you john for the introduction
anonymous
is a downloader that from the limits of
our visibility and collection we assess
has been used by the black cartomist
intrusion set
since at least 2016 and the name comes
from the anonymous string
which is used as the key to the crypt
the strings
of this downloader now the way anonymous
gets
on the victim system is via the standard
track drop installation routine
but there are a few added quotient and
anti-analysis tricks which are
interesting to touch on
firstly a sandbox check which you can
see here on screen and which is
incidentally
the same as the ones in a 2014
environment of d-track
so we have here a 2016 downloader a
different malware family
being dropped by the same dropper that
is associated with j-truck samples and
which
also embeds code taken from 2014 v truck
that's a bit of a connection there now
anonymous
also performs an antivirus check the
samples that we observed
specifically checked for kaspersky and
quick heal antivirus
by trying to read whether there were any
registry keys associated
with these avs if any of them was
present on the victim system then
another neighbor would record it
and then would actually append data to
the end of its own binary
in order to potentially change its hash
and
bypass hash base detection anonymous
would also check
whether a mutex of global anonymous was
present on the beacon system
and if it was then the binary would stop
executing otherwise it would go on to
further functionality
such as persistence which in this case
was affected by placing a link file in
the user startup folder
masquerading as a windows updater which
is a technique that we are seeing
lazarus use after the present day for
example in its blinding
campaigns in terms of anonymous
functionality
the downloader would just loop back to a
payload staging server until it got a
positive response
and it then would download a payload and
then prepend
the mz header on it very similar to
tear up two actually and then it would
set persistence for this payload and
execute it
after doing this anonymous would proceed
to
empty the file of track drop that
existed on disk
but not by deleting the entire file just
by
emptying all of its contents and leaving
behind
only the letters bm now this is a very
interesting detail because
bm is a very well-known lazarus
and andaryl typical encoding for the
dust header and set
we can see here in 2016 in the sony
pictures hack
incident novetta's operation blockbuster
report
detailed how the india whiskey lazarus 2
had its first two rights being bm and a
2018 ant lab presentation also touched
on anandario specific backdoor
known as vm door which would also use
the bm
header and it's also interesting as an
anti-forensics techniques
because investigators could not maybe
get back the original track drop file
and would only see this random file with
only the bm letters left in it which
would be
a bit odd but let's look a bit closer at
the anonymous
encryption and what it reveals to us
about its connection to andario so
the anonymous encryption works like this
we have a custom implement
implementation of rc4
with key anonymous and then we also have
got base64 encoding
and this same exact mechanism of hiding
strings
from simple analysis was found in a 2019
variant
of an andarian backdoor known as rift
door
now reef door is a long-standing
well-known underworld tool which unlock
published
a really cool report about it's been in
use since at least 2014.
when it was a very basic very
lightweight backdoor with limited
functionality
but then in 2019 we observed a reloaded
version of reef door
which used an oliver encryption
mechanism and
had so much added functionality
including for example the possibility of
spawning a reverse shell on the victim
system so it went from
a lightweight back door to a fully
fledged route
and if we look here we can see kind of
like the connections that start
multiplying so we have
track drop which is associated with the
d-track lazarus trojan
dropping the 2016 version of the
anonymous downloader
and then we see the same encryption
three years later in a 2019 sample of
reef door which is uniquely associated
with andario
so a lot of connections there and it's
by no means the end of it
we've said track drop drop c track and
also not neighbor
anonymous leads us to restore fast
forward to february 2020
and u.s cisa releases indicators on
two more families one of which it calls
hot cross sand which never fails to make
me really hungry
and another one which is known as bistro
math
now in our analysis of hot croissant of
a few samples compiled in 2018
we realized that actually hot croissant
was a sort of
baby version or early version of the
2019 variant
of rift or and what i mean by this is
that the structure of the binary was
effectively the same
but with smaller chunks of functionality
and fewer command
and control codes but then in turn
from this connection we also found that
bistro month
and hot cross sound actually had a
similar
cryptographic routine which was not
publicly
known before so it was a pretty strong
connection there
and furthermore bistro math itself then
had
in some samples the same exact string
encoding to detract with the ccs
underscore method
so we have this like absolute loop of
connections round and around
and what you're gonna ask me right now
is why do we care
what do you do this for what does this
mean and
to be honest you're right but let me get
a bit more serious for one moment
now the reason why this is important is
because what we have here
is several tools that are attributed to
some
lazarus group some to andario which is
another subgroup
but what our analysis shows is that we
can make a reasonable assessment that
all these tools highly likely stem from
a same code base
or at the very least we use the same
code chunks
and there is this idea of iterating on
or rehashing an established code base in
order to make new our families
or embed tricks that work from our
family into another
and there is this concept of like
sleeping up on habits
in the coding stuff so at least from a
development standpoint there's a
connection
and it also hints to the fact that
lazarus and andario
are not in fact separate entities
they've been
linked in the past but very much from
our assessment it's highly likely that
they continue
to be linked i mean also all of this
analysis
gives us a window of insight into the
development modus operandi
of black artemis as an intrusion set
which has a very sprawling tool set new
additions
very often but then all of these tie
back to an established code base
and then there's also this idea of
really investing into an implant
that has been developed and kind of
maintaining it and then
iterating on it and then in some cases
even tailoring it to
specific intrusions like we saw with the
kk and pp case
and what if we take a step back what
does this tell us
about d-track and about the lazarus crew
thank you so drak
has been well known for its use in
campaigns
that are targeting organizations for the
purposes of espionage as we've
highlighted in this presentation
but not only that it is a dual tool
with multiple purposes i.e through the
research that was released by kaspersky
detailing atm d-track
a variant of d-trac focused on dumping
the
atm tracks of compromised atm machines
this was focused on financially
motivated campaigns
now this use of tooling as we've
mentioned before for both the purposes
of espionage and cybercrime
continues to be seen through our
tracking of the lazarus group
in particular the remote access trojan
known as manuscript
and recently analyzed by the the us
cesa team blinding can or what we call
internally as show state
has also been used for the dual purposes
of espionage
and cyber but not only that
through our dtrac analysis these
campaigns can be tied back
to previous campaigns including t-drop 2
and subsequently t-drop which was a part
of operation troy
which are campaigns with the purposes of
sabotage
so this remote access trojan and in
general
lazarus code has been developed since at
least 2009 and continues to be
seen in samples even in this year
now it's important to point out that
despite
our thorough investigation of d-trak
we've not seen it being used again since
these prolific campaigns at the end of
this could likely be explained due to
the fact that
there was a lot of public reporting on
it at the time and the threat actor
might have been spooked off a bit
but that doesn't rule out the fact that
in the future they may use this tool
again
and all of this research will enable us
to carry on tracking it
and has also led us on to tracking
further malware families
used by lazarus
so what can we say about the lazarus
group as a result of all this
well it's lazarus still being lazarus
really
but with its constant adapting and
iterating on its previous campaigns
from the perspective of espionage it
continues to go over the same kind of
targets
such as government organizations but is
having an increasingly broad reach
such as recently there have been many
campaigns targeting the aerospace and
defense sector
as details in the us government's
report on blinding can and from the
financially motivated perspective of
lazarus group
it's still doing the same kind of
campaigns but
having a different avenue of monetizing
the results of those campaigns
in particular all the lazarus
financially motivated campaigns were
known for targeting organizations such
as large banks
with the purposes of compromising their
swift systems to forge transactions
whereas more recently again with the u.s
cesar team's
release of the beagle boys research
which is a subgroup
of the lazarus group and its financially
motivated subset
these detail campaigns that were
targeting organizations
for the purposes of compromising atm
systems through use of the fast cache
malware
in order to perform atm cash out attacks
so what kind of advice can we give to
organizations and defenders
to try and stop these campaigns if your
organization has the capability to
monitor network traffic because detract
uses just http
and not something like https you can get
a quick win out of that
we would also recommend that you don't
rule out internal traffic being used
for command control beacons because as
we've discussed
lazarus c2s have likely been deployed
internally
on compromised networks
from the perspective of endpoint
monitoring if the tools that your
organization uses
has the capability to monitor api usage
we highly recommend looking for the
usage of specific apis
that are used for code injection and
process hollowing
if you can stop track drop before it
injects d-trac into memory
you've stopped the whole thing
also look out for the usage of things
such as
living off the land techniques such as
net as we saw being used for the kk npp
detract samples being used to exfiltrate
data
we also highly recommend that you look
for new code signing certificates being
used within your organization
as over the last couple of years we've
observed the lazarus group
either forging or stealing code signing
certificates
in order to sign their malware and make
it more likely to go under the radar
sorry what can we recommend to end users
as well
look out for banking and recruitment
campaigns
that might be targeting you as
individuals we've seen the lazarus group
especially in the last year using fake
job applications
and sometimes even programs that would
generate application pdfs
to target individuals and
this is also
added to the fact that the lazarus group
has been seen in open source research
recently
using linkedin as a vector for this and
then for the threat intelligence
analysts and reverse engineers like us
we highly recommend that you keep
signaturing lazarus malware
look for any interesting strings look
for any particular encoding routines
look for all the cryptographic routines
that are unique to those samples
or unique code chunks as we've been
saying these code bases developed over
time and
yara rule for one sample may find you
many others in the process and it is
highly worth your time
as we have shown with this presentation
to finish things off
we've also provided the mitre attack
mappings for all of the techniques we've
observed being used in these campaigns
microattack is an amazing framework so
we'd recommend you check out all of
these
and we also provide some indicators of
compromise for the various tools that
we've been
looking at through this presentation in
case you want to recreate
some of the research yourself and
after the final slide we also provide
all of the references
for the various open source blogs and
reports that we've been using
to help us with this research
thank you very much for listening and
we'll pass back over to the host