so
hello everybody i hope you can hear me
loud and clear
thanks to first thing first i would like
to thank the confidence committee for
choosing my talk
and of course for still having this
virtual conference
um so my name is omar tsofati and i am a
security researcher at cyberarklabs
and my recent researchers were focused
on cloud security
and on the authentication mechanism and
i've been chosen also to be one of
the msrc most valuable security
researchers for years
2019 and 2020.
right uh let's begin with our
presentation
and today i will show you two critical
vulnerabilities
that i found in microsoft online
services
those vulnerabilities affected millions
of users and
potentially could lead to mass account
takeover
if the bad guys found them before we did
i'll briefly speak about azure and its
features
and general including uh in general
including its integration with
on-premises
environment as known and as hybrid
environment
then we will cover uh the first
vulnerability for today the manifest
vulnerability
everyone vulnerability relates to
misconfiguration that was in
azure portal extension manifest that
eventually could
let a malicious attacker to take over
victim's account
and right after it we will understand
the fundamentals of the
authentication protocol off and of
course when you're talking about off
you must also speak about the openid
connect or
adc in short and moreover we'll talk
about
an off configuration related
vulnerability in the second part
and it's a vulnerability that we found
in a microsoft
that affected all microsoft 365 users
including all the users created in azure
active directory
even if you didn't have a 365
subscription
and um and we will see our simple link
of monitoring
brought up to like a dangerous account
takeover vulnerability
and at the very end we'll talk about how
you can mitigate those vulnerabilities
and right after it will have some time
for q a
all right so microsoft azure microsoft
azure is one of the rising stars of the
cloud computing services providers of
this time
and also a tech leader in this area
considering the four year gaps
microsoft as compared to aws which
launched
launch in 2006 and the azure which
launched in 2010 it is impressive to see
how azure closed the gap
azure today offers more than 600
services
and it actually increases daily
irregularly
one of the primary key advantages azure
has compared to its main competitors
it's the excellent integration with
on-premises
active directory and as you know guys
um every good platform need a good
controlling panel this is the azure
portal
which is an all-in-one controlling panel
that microsoft offers
in order to manage your cloud assets in
azure
and in one of my researchers i happened
to look at some
azure features and while looking at the
at outcome traffic i identified some
bizarre
requests i saw those requests telemetry
ones
and were sent to strange aust a local
loss called
ura abs which is what's really odd
so those are the requests at first
glance i thought that was just a bag
something that i did to my browser just
a random black magic
that happened to visit me from time to
time
so i refresh the page and close and open
my browser restart my computer
and i even went to another computer and
i still saw those strange requests
to the local server and i also changed
an account to another account and
just the same request went out
so let's see the world quest so
let's let's take a look on this request
it's a bit weird
why would azure sandals request it's
weird doesn't it
and um and if you will take a closer
look we can see the art is
your rehabs and so i search for the
string hurry up in the capture traffic
to see what what triggered this
but i couldn't find any results beside a
few files
that um that the yori absa string was in
it
and there one of those of those files
was the configuration file
which is the extension manifest file uh
extend the configuration files is
located at portal azure.com
content slash extension manifest slash
the cone version dojs
so you may ask yourself what is
extension manifest
so every extension in azure located in a
json
manifest file that defines basic
information about extension
we can see in this picture uh the app
extension
as a your uri attribute that contains
the azure apps
have string if we take a look on the
other extensions
we can see clearly that those as your
attribute and their uri attribute is not
like the one we have
well that's interesting doesn't it
so we know it is something that is
connected to the extension manifest
and another thing to say about extension
manifest is that
um every if not all the pages we see in
azure
is actually an extension that we browse
to
so that's a great starting point to
understand
the issue itself so in order to
understand better
uh what triggered this a request to go
out
uh we set a xhr fetch breakpoint
in chrome developer tools and so the
breakpoint will break on every request
that contains the url string
in it so very shortly after the break on
the breakpoint
set it triggered and then we could
analyze the
uh the function that triggers that
and which one is passing the your uri
attribute of the extension
um so we found out uh this is the one
uh each it's an obvious catenae
a function named tt at first glance uh
can you see what could
be problem in this function that uh
possible problem
uh well it is a bit odd at least for me
uh so let's let's see what happens when
the function actually
called the with the relevant parameter
so it looks like that uh and now it
actually looks better i think
uh so we can we can see the result
function returns
an object um which is which include
origin protocol and a drive and we could
we could also uh see that the origin is
malformed and also
uh it's just the same as that we saw in
the strange request before
well that's interesting so i really ate
obfuscated functions
and uh to make things a bit clearer for
me i wrote
i rewrote this obscrite function so we
could understand it better
so this is the the one that i wrote that
does just the same logic
so the function get uri object uh
receives the string
which is the uri that needs to be parsed
the function looks uh
for the location of the first a double
slash
and if it finds it it's at the flag
variable called easy uri
contains four slashes so in short it
looks for the
double fault slashes in the ui parameter
that pass to the function then if the
uri string contains those
fault slashes the function will takes
everything
that is before that and consider it is
the protocol
the protocol that needs to be used when
sending a request out
using this uri if the ui doesn't
a string doesn't contain the two slashes
the skip takes the current page protocol
and set the value
and set it as the protocol value
right after it it search for the
location of the single slash
index after this two slashes
then if there is no single slash it will
search for the question mark
which in our case there is a single
slash so we want to search for the
question mark
and um and right after it it tries to
extract the origin that
it should be sent to or the domain name
and so as you can see it tries to get
the
it will go to two characters
after the fourth slash location uh index
in our case
the index is zeroed by the function
because it couldn't find the two fourth
slashes in the uri parameter
so it will take everything from the
index to
until the index nine
which is the one that before the slash
and the
the one the single fault slash and then
the function wraps up
everything into an object and returns it
and that's about what we got eventually
uh so now we understand the bad passing
part and
what really went wrong there so instead
of parsing a uri
as a relative path as it should in this
case it passes it as a regular uri
or url all right so
with that understanding in mind let's
figure out
a way what can go wrong with those
with those requests and what is going on
there
so we can see this is an option request
and option requests are made in order to
verify a destination is ready to
talk with us and accept the request
method we would like
to use in case everything's okay and the
browser will then send a real request
that that they intended to send
at the first place so the request in our
case
looks like this and it contains a very
interesting header
which is the authorization editor of
course and authorization header contains
a valid access token to azure resource
manager
api and which you can
actually use to control almost uh all
the resources in azure
of course according to the user's
permission
so that's interesting if i was in tucker
i would like to put my hands on
this token of course so if we will
consider the attack scenario it will
look like this
and so um the user is browsing into the
azure portal
and debugging the portal sends the token
to the ura abs asked
which the attacker owes in some way and
we'll talk about it in a second how it
can be happen
and then the token is sent to the
attacker now
after the attacker has access to the
token it can impersonate the victim
and take action on his behalf so
in theory that sounds good but can it
really
be exploited in real life that's a good
question
um so yes indeed it can be exploited
this attack scenario is real and can be
exploited in both local environment
and irregular environment all right
so the first attack vector is the local
environment scenario
which in it that packets spin up and
asked in the network
in the local network and calls it your
rehabs then it gets a signed certificate
by
by a root ca or by a local domain root
ca
and after setting this all up whenever a
user
will browse to the azure portal will be
affected by the bag
and send is talking to the attacker
um but this this
this local environment attack well it's
not that interesting
we thought it would be much more
interesting if this attack could affect
every azure user out there in the world
does not it does no matter where it's
located
so it actually can be done and the main
reason for this is a dns service
configuration dns servers
most of the time do their job do their
job well
but some dns servers may actually do it
too well
and let me explain what i mean by that
some dns servers configurations
add the suffix from the commonly known
top-level domain
like com net organ etc and they added to
the localhost names when
when they don't meant to when they can't
manage to find the
uh the recorded them their
their host name in the local record in
this case
the dns server uh when it uh when it's
trying to resolve the array ups
it's also trying to resolve your
reapp.com uriab.net
etc so a potential attacker can
abuse this behavior by buying buying
many
and registering many different urea
domains
with different suffixes and then exploit
them
so yes it won't actually be enough as
the attacker still needs
a valid certificate for the local server
sign up by a public
root ca and as of november 1st 2015 caa
slash
browser forum no longer allows public a
publicly trusted ssl certificates to
include those local names
such as internal server names and
reserved ip addresses
as it could lead to manage the middle
attacks in local
networks but there are still a malicious
root case and some routiers that have
been compromised over the years like
commodore in 2011
and diggy notre in 2013 for example
so it actually still can be happen this
kind of attacks
so um for uh making a poc out of this
uh we bought 27 uh different theory of
the
domains with different suffixes like
uriab.com uriab.net
org and etc and of course it was a as a
responsible and a protective measure of
course
um another important point to make uh
that um security mess uh features are
great
uh browser knows how to validate the
certificate is is okay and everything is
good with that
but some users actually turn this
certificate validation off
in their browser and there are many
reasons for that some of them is because
they
are receiving surfing errors or maybe
because they need to access their input
incorrectly
sign their website from time to time
like your web developers
and uh seriously please don't do that
try to find another solution and when
you do that you expose yourself to to
risk
and that could be really a big problem
and um
we actually made the poc uh which uh
we just we created a self-signed
certificate for our servers
and uh and actually um we we got
we started to get requests and uh
some of the requests and um sent with
the authorization token in it
and uh it was really cool this was
actually um
a token from external organization which
nothing to do with
with us it was really really nice to see
this
and uh by that we actually demonstrated
that this attack is real
and uh you guys should not turn off the
certificate validation
function all right so let's talk a bit
about the fix
um so mike microsoft fixed this issue
on uh september 6th to 2019
and microsoft decided to fix this issue
by adding a simple
a simple simple thing
uh they created a new a tag element then
set
the a draft attribute to the past
parameter
this change this change actually fix the
problem with the help
of the the way that the browser handle
uh relative paths
uh the browser takes the url as a
relative url
of course and therefore the browser adds
the current ost
to it and so it's actually uh
solved this problem because now it's a
valid valid url and not
no no longer just a relative one and not
to say uh microsoft managed to fix this
issue
before we had the chance to report it to
them we found it like
four or five days before microsoft or i
think one week before and microsoft
fixed this this vulnerability and
actually it was really cool to see this
[Music]
right so let's wrap it up
this was the first uh first part of the
session
and so um we had the wheel telemetry
request
to a local server those telemetry
requests contained the user's access
token in the authorization editor
their request eventually ended up in the
attacker's end
and if if the token ended up in that
accent
it will be able to impersonate the
victim and take action on isbiaf
in the azure environment and attacker
could create in
virtual machines deleting data accessing
data and actually do much more than that
and so my main takeaway at least from
this vulnerability finding
is always to investigate and go deeper
into things especially when they see mod
like the one like the weird request we
saw
i'm sure that um there are many more
vulnerabilities like this out there
on other platforms and just waiting for
you to find them
all right um so that was the first part
of the session
now we'll talk about uh the second one
and
we will cover a even more dangerous
account takeover vulnerability that
exposed
all 365 users and
and aad users and the vulnerability
which we called it black direct is an
off relates vulnerability
so in order to understand the
vulnerability itself we first need to
briefly understand that what
off and oidc are
so let's go over it so
what is off let's answer this a question
first
off is an open standard for
authorization
which sometimes it mixes up with its
extension
oidc which is the open id connect
which is actually extends the protocol
to also support
authentication of supports authorization
and oidc extends it to support also
authentication
so in short off is used to delegate
permission
of the users account to first and third
party applications
in order to understand why would need
such a thing we need
first go back in time so let's talk a
bit history
uh in the first in the past in order to
let the third party application access
to your data
you needed to provide your password well
what do you think what do you think
about that what could actually go wrong
with doing this well everything can go
wrong
in short app stores the user's password
in plain text apps get a
and get complete access to the user's
account
users can't revoke the app access to
their account
except by changing their password and
also
if the application got compromised it
exposed
all its users password
so should we make something different
absolutely
there were efforts to implement new
methods similar to off
before a offer was released but every
implementation was
slightly different from from the other
and not compatible with each other
uh we had a flicker off we had a
off sub which was a google and
implementation uh we had a bp off of yao
and really much more um
so um all of those companies and
and others joined together and brought
up to life of portugal
the authorization protocol that provides
everything that you needed
uh in order to in order to give third
party and first
party application access to your account
securely without giving giving the
password
all right so let's see how it looks and
in real life so as you can see there is
a user that wants to get access to
office.com
the user browses to office.com and then
clicks on the login
button you redirect it to the microsoft
authorization server
the authorization server receives a
request with the relevant parameters
like the client id which represents the
application that asks the user's
permission it also includes the
resources
that application wants to get access to
and the redirect uri
parameter which states where the token
should be transferred
and the authorization server validates
that everything is okay
uh he evolved he validates that the user
is logged in
the application is authorized by the
user the redirect uri
is in the lowest and etc and after all
those checks
the authorization server creates a token
it creates a token and uh actually uh
after after it creates a token the token
will be sent to
back to the office.com server and by the
the user's browser and that application
can use this token to get the user's
data
uh so that's the flow in general uh and
every off application needs to be
registered in the authorization server
in some way and also
it needs to be approved by the user
so if you take microsoft for example in
azure every application is represented
as a service principal object
which is an instance of application
object the service principle looks like
this the
like in this image that you can see you
can see a json object that represents
the application settings that include
application name
application id and also includes
authorized list of urls
that can receive the generated tokens in
the future
in this example you can see that the
allowed list allowed urls
in this case is google.com and
google.com
a slash anything that will come after it
um
so so far so good it sounds like nothing
can go wrong here
uh well almost nothing can go wrong we
found out
there are some a pre-installed service
principle by a microsoft
er in every azure ad environment
which includes also 365 users
when i say pre-installed i mean that the
user doesn't need to approve
uh approve those application manually
because they're already
approved those off applications are
considered privileged because they can
ask the users for accessing highly
sensitive
apis uh like the graph api uh which lets
you make changes in the active and the
azure active directory
and uh to uh the uh azure
resource manager api uh which lets you
uh control azure
resources your cloud assets
uh so we looked for those principal
service principles
for finding any any kind of bug that can
be
in in those applications and so we found
out that those applications a very large
white listed url list as we saw before
uh we checked every application to look
at if we could take it take it over take
and actually we could we could manage to
do so
so some of the uri were subdomains
that were vulnerable to subdomain
takeover uh which i will explain it
in short uh subdomain takeover it's it's
an attack that makes a
the subdomain to point on an ip
addresses of my choice
because of a bad dns configuration um
and actually um we we managed to take
over some of the whitelisted the uri
uri your eyes and that this actually um
led us to uh to the following attack
scenario
so um we for the
in this example we see that uh we took
over a secureserver.office.com
and in some way and this
this this one is a whitelisted in the
office application which is approved by
default
in in microsoft off application
and that's just an example it's not uh
it wasn't that one but um
yeah so you do understand that uh so the
user clicks on the link or
a subway um browser to this secure
server
office.com which is a trusted one you
can see it's
called it's with office.com and
everything should be fine
uh so um the user is actually browser to
it
uh secure.com the bet server redacts the
user to the authorization server
the authorization server validates the
request parameters
uh and the authorization server
recognized that the rig directory is
whitelisted and everything else is okay
uh and therefore it creates an access
token that eventually
the victim browsers they send the access
token to the malicious
website which is controlled by the
attacker and then the attacker can
actually steal every every data that
the users add change that uh compromise
things can do a lot of bad things
so let's see how it actually um
looked in real life so this is the proof
of concept that we made
of this vulnerability uh as you can see
this is the victim user
it doesn't actually have any any third
party application installed
that has access to its um its account so
it's
only the very
built-in off application that's
configured by microsoft
okay uh we'll search for an attacker
user that
might be existing in active directory so
there is no such a user of course
um then the user's uh going to outlook
he receives a new email uh actually it's
um
it's a social engineering email it
receives a new
phishing mail from a generic financial
company
and they clicks on the link and actually
when
when you see this screen the attacker
already have the um
anti-access token in it uh it already
stole the access token
this takes only a second so the users
won't actually feel anything and see
anything
and we'll actually after it will
redirect it to
um to innocent website that he won't
suspicious anything
so it won't look suspicious and
and in the meanwhile we created a new
user which is the attacker attacker
created a user for im
with the highway permissions of a global
administrator
so as you can see a new user created
and let's see the assigned roles
and global administrator that's kind of
cool
so that that is a really dangerous
vulnerability that
was closed so let's talk about the fix
and
so we reported this vulnerability to
microsoft and together we
uh we managed to uh to fix this uh
vulnerability
and it took a while because it's not
that easy to fix there are a lot of
application that
you need to monitor and and look for
those uh kind of
bad uris that could be uh taking over
and actually microsoft remove the
vulnerable
urls from the redirect uri list of those
applications
which basically fix the issue for their
application
but i must say there might be more
vulnerable application
which not created by microsoft
that might be in your account and might
expose you to similar vulnerability like
this
so in order to find those application
and mitigate the risk we created a free
online tool
that you can scan your environment with
it
it will tell you which application are
vulnerable and to similar attack in your
account
uh so let's talk a bit about the
statistics uh
we ran a more than 200
scans and the two detected more than a
vulnerable urls in 700 different
off applications in addition
we found with the help of this tool of
course another for
microsoft vulnerable applications and
reported it to them
of course microsoft um so
if you want to see if your environment
might be exposed to such risk
you're more than welcome to want this
tool in the
in in the website uh black direct
your model welcome to do so so guys
that's it i was almost zafati i hope you
enjoyed this session
and if you um and if you would like to
read more
about those vulnerabilities you can
check our blog posts on cyber art clubs
website
links are shown on the screen so thank
you for attention
let's get back to the studio