all right so i would uh
i would prefer of course to be
physically in poland um
but i guess this is the second best
thing after that
uh so polls keep telling me that there's
uh never too early for vodka so i'll
start
this talk with a little uh refresher
all right so um
about me uh like edo as uh mentioned
i've been working in the industry for
the last 15 years
i've mostly i've started on the network
security side
then i moved to bot detection which is
more or less in the
intersection between network and and and
the web
security i moved to javascript code
protection to client-side security and
i've been
mostly focused on the website
i've been a speaker in a few
conferences these are a few of the one
ones that have been i have several
patents in application security and my
main interests are
hacking the web browser security
application security
reverse engineering and heavy metal
music
so for today i'll be speaking about
magecart which is a
fairly new type of attack then i'll move
to
addressing web schemers anatomy and
the the the talk will progress by
showing you
how we are hunting down web schemers
with a few demos included uh at the very
end i'll present you
uh a bluetooth minus uh which i'll
let's keep it a surprise for now and at
the very end a little bit of q a
so about magegard um assuming that
you are not familiar with this type of
attack i'll i'll just start by
telling you how a mageguard attack goes
so
um it's it's it's a client-side uh
browser based attack uh where you have
first-party code and you have
third-party code third-party code is
usually loaded
dynamically from a third-party server
that code can load more code dynamically
you can have iframes and those iframes
can load extra code
so all of this code will end up in the
same executing context the browser
and will be able to fully view the dom
and all the the other javascript code
running in there
so what happens if one of these files
is compromised uh maybe the servers were
breached
maybe the attackers were able to
penetrate the the server and
change the javascript in place and by
doing that they can
inject arbitrary javascript code and
that javascript code will have access to
everything
including form fields or paying forms
and and that's what they do they target
payment forms
and they excel trade the the data that
the user
inserts in the payment form namely the
credit card information
so when one of these
gets compromised the whole environment
the whole browser and application uh
provided that
it's running in the same execution
context gets compromised
as well so what happens next
is uh the form gets
hooked gets uh we we call this a form
jacking this
it's another term for this type of
attack and
the the data is sent out to um
what we call the drop server the drop
server uh
might sit in um in a like
unsuspicious domain name like coolest
fonts.com
or it might leverage one of the existing
third-party
servers and domains uh
and and that usually uh takes care of
bypassing csp
and and things like that that are white
listing the domains where the
application
can communicate with so mage cart
attacks
the name comes from the
might come or it's probably coming from
magento because the magento
e-commerce web stores were the first to
be targeted and
the majority were magento breaches
but nowadays they can target any
any type of web server as long as it's
serving uh
javascripts dynamically to
e-commerce web shop it's it's good
enough for the attackers they just have
to find ways to breach those
those servers it's also called the
supply chain attack
because it's uh it's going after the
components
of the web application not served
directly
by the the first party and um
it all started back in 2015 more or less
uh a single group started it but right
now we have
tens of different uh cyber criminal
groups uh doing mage card attacks with
different
uh mo's the the good thing about these
attacks at least for attackers is that
they they scale very well
they only need to breach one server
modify the code and
they hit all the users at once so uh
if they stay one week in the server
they will able they will be able to
scheme all the payments
uh of that week of that website from all
the users
um they also uh they are also a
good preference of the attackers because
they they seek the weakest link so
usually third parties
are the are smaller companies uh
probably with less resources to dedicate
to security
um they are probably using ubqs software
like magento or other things
they are probably doing all sorts of
mistakes in configuring those uh
those softwares and and that's how the
the attackers are able to easily breach
them
so you might ask how often this happens
uh right now
almost every week certainly every month
uh
i'm not going through all these attacks
um
and and and and that's the the sort of
thing that
has been happening so it's it's very
profitable for attackers so
it's no wonder that they have been
increasing
so talking about the anatomy of an
attack um
did what you're seeing right now it's uh
the inventors
web schemer it has been used in the
ticketmaster breach
back in 2018. uh you are just seeing the
schemer
it's a one-liner it was concatenated at
the end of a file
and as you can see it's obfuscated
but this obfuscation is not really very
resilient um
by doing a bit of a manual uh the
obfuscation
you you get the the gist of what
the code is doing so basically it's
first checking
if it's running in the right page order
checkout or one step then it iterates
all form
fields and known ids
installs event listeners in
on click events collects all form field
values
replaces also the on submit events uh
installs its own event listener
and eventually sends the
scheme data to the drop server
and does it all again after 30
milliseconds
so it needs to keep running
in order to to give enough time for the
user to
enter the credit card data
so web skimmer kits are
are available on the dark web
so attackers don't need special skills
they can just
buy a ready-to-use kit
they the these kits have loader codes
skimmer code generation
and apply javascript obfuscation uh they
provide also a c2 admin panel like the
one that you see
on the right uh they go roughly from 250
to 5000 um they are mostly used in spray
and prey
kind of attack so they they the users
get access to breached
third party servers and they just
installed this
and basically they are attacking a lot
of different web applications because
the
multiple applications are linking to
that the file that
they had just modified um
[Music]
there's even a toolkit called inter
which
goes roughly around 1300
and uses this special caesar plus
javascript obfuscation
which also is also available on the dark
web for 100 bucks
and but the problem of this toolkit
is that it does fake checkout pages
what this means is that the user is
entering the data
but then click submit and the
transaction will not be successful
so this is actually a bad example
because the user will
uh will will will realize
that something has happened uh will
probably contact support and probably
the
the infection will be discovered uh
sooner rather than later
so the the best web schemer kits they
they try to to be as stealthy as they
can be
uh they will make sure that transactions
are successful
um while still skimming the credit card
data
so um now i'll i'll present what we have
been doing
to to hunt down uh schemers before i get
into the
the main theme of this talk i will tell
you about
um the solution and approach that we
have been following
lately so we have built a tool a
client-side defense solution
that it's basically able to alert and
block malicious behavior
and it allows you to for each resource
in the page regardless of being a first
party or third party
you set permission levels so you can
control
whether a certain file can be loaded
should be loaded or be blocked
you can control if you allow it to load
you can then control uh high-level
uh behavior assumptions uh about what it
should be doing
and you can block it if they they they
go outside
your expectations uh things like uh
should this file be touching any cookies
you can you can set those expectations
and the solution will be able to
to fence the scripts and and and block
and even block it from accessing cookies
and then at the third permission level
you can
go as deep as you want in terms of
specifying the behavior that you want to
allow
or to block to give you
a few examples we can alert or block
scripts
if we see it installing a specific
listener like on submit
obviously if you're using third-party
code you more or less know what it
should be doing if
it should be touching forms and
you you should have these expectations
and
you can actually create rules um
to make sure that your expectations are
met
we can block uh from sending data
to unknown domains or using a specific
method
like web sockets um or if a file
javascript is touching a specific form
like a payment form
um obviously you shouldn't be including
all your
third-party javascripts in the checkout
page but
some might be needed there uh
for good reasons but still
there's no reason why you shouldn't be
limiting the ones that should be
actually touching the payment form or
installing
listeners so our
solution will give you the tools to
actually go
deeper and enforce that as you know
using conventional web technologies you
can
do things like iframes and boxing but
uh what you are able to limit uh inside
the knife frame
sandbox iframe is is
extremely limited so you can either
allow all javascript or disallow
the javascripts you don't have fine
grain
ways of controlling and enforcing
specific behaviors that you want to
allow and
behaviors that you don't want to allow
so you can block um
you can block javascript from adding
elements to the dom
so changing the interface or
using a specific api um
and and or even to add more javascript
dynamically
using a pen child or insert before uh
for instance
so in general what it allows you is to
to fence scripts
to to create a cage around the scripts
and enforce a list privilege principle
applied to
third party code and why not also apply
to first party code because
you you can also be breached for
first parties can be preached and and
attackers can change
the behavior of that code too and
not to forget of course if a third-party
script is tempered and
and is actually able to execute on the
execution environment
it's also able to tamper with first
party code and make it do
something different so everything should
be
fenced and and and we should apply the
least privilege principle to
the whole web application
uh to do this we we use a
technique called javascript
virtualization um
i will tell you uh roughly how it works
so we need to add an embedded agent this
is actually
a javascript that you need to include in
the page it should be loaded
as early as possible and what it does
is it's proxies
a bunch of things in the in the the web
apis
uh i create element insert before um
xhr open and send and uh
when when the other files are loaded
uh they will actually see the proxied
versions
of those uh methods and
and and by going through our virtualized
implementations we are able to
enforce the rules uh that uh were
configured
so this is uh more than enough to
mitigate
this type of attacks match card from
jacking or
any type of event handler hijacking um
it's it's very useful to prevent data
leakage because you can enforce uh
to to what domains data can be sent out
and you can actually control
what data is being sent out so you can
enforce the the the syntax
and uh of the data going out um
and even our embedded agent code is
protected with
um with with temporal resistance
javascript obfuscation so in a nutshell
this is javascript virtualization
but what we are we have been doing
lately and
the main topic of this talk is
magekart's classification so
um obviously by using the solution i've
just described we can fence the scripts
we can block data from going out
but uh we do that because we
we can roll out the rules uh to prevent
those
those things from happening but how can
we know for sure
that the the thing causing that behavior
was a schemer in the first place uh
so this is a question that we had and
also
if it's if if it's indeed it's a schemer
which schemer are we talking about so in
order to solve this problem
we started building a mage card
classifier
and we started a simple
with a simple solution based in static
code analysis
a little disclaimer here this is a work
in progress so we have been working on
this and we'll
keep working on this and it answers the
question
how likely is that this specific file
contains a magic card schemer
and the answer is a percentage
so the requirements for this classifier
is
are that it should be purely based on
behavior
so we didn't wanted any hard-coded
signatures or regexes
because they are very easy to bypass
you can change you can change the the
the aspect of of of javascript very
easily
by just applying code transformations
obfuscation
minification so it's very easy to modify
the the aspect of the code just enough
so that the signatures break
that's why we didn't want any anything
related to that we wanted something
based on behavior
because um at the very end
the the behavior of the code will be the
same
uh it should also deal with obfuscation
uh like i said
it should some some um some code is
obfuscated
most schemers are obfuscated
and since we are using static code
analysis
we we have to have a way to look
underneath the obfuscation to be able to
pick up the
features that we are looking for so the
the solution uh needs automatic the
obfuscation
in order to be effective uh
it's we also need to extract a very
diverse set of behaviors because
right now we know what schemers are
doing but we never know in the future
so we need to look for a very complete a
very diverse set of behaviors
in order to better learn how they are
evolving and
and to be very effective in in finding
them
and finally needs to be accurate so when
we say it's uh
it's a web schemer it needs to be a web
schemer
here you can see the architecture very
simply put
um we have a notification detection
module
it just tells us if it's obfuscated or
not
and what obfuscation it has been used
what tool
and then we have uh the obfuscator
module
that the office gets the codes
then we have a features extractor and
these features
are passed to a scorer that comes out
with with the
final score of the
of the file so we are using heuristics
and simple heuristics and we are
grouping the features um according to
semantics
and and establishing weights for
different groups
so right now no ai has been used um i'm
saying this now because
otherwise i would get the question at
the end
but we do have plans to to use ai
in the future namely machine learning
to learn what features uh schemers have
been starting to do
um starting to to use and and
and to to grow this classifier
these are the some examples of the
different
features that we are collecting
organized in groups so are looking for
very diverse
types of things obfuscation of course
fingerprinting if they're using hooking
into events or
forms if they're using the network
so a lot of different things uh even
keywords we're looking for certain
keywords
uh usually used in in them
in payment forms like billing or credit
card etc
and we have been growing this list
so now time for a few demos let's start
by the british airways web schemer um
this skimmer uh it's actually very
simple
so you can see the whole skimmer uh on
the right
uh it didn't use obfuscation so it's
very
um and it was one of the first
high-profile
mage guard attacks that we have seen uh
and um it the the problem happened when
uh dependency modernizer um was
tempered by someone and someone
at the british airways has pulled a
modified version of modernizer
and deployed it locally um
so this is uh one one um
one one problem is dealing with third
with third-party codes
sometimes a lot of people decide to host
it themselves but they have to be
careful
uh where they are pulling that code from
and and make sure that you
audits that third-party components
frequently
um so it's using target selectors
it's using event binding and serializing
the whole form
and sending this using it it's xhr
post to this domain uh be
a waze.com which is not a
domain that belongs to british airways
this was actually the biggest gdpr fine
ever
so um some say
that it lasted 15 days some say that it
lasted two months
uh the the official numbers
say that uh almost 400
000 credit cards were schemed um
and because they didn't have any
protection mechanisms in place
uh they they didn't took precautions
um the british airways was fined with
roughly 230 million us dollars
so it was the biggest fine ever of the
gdpr um
so here is the demo uh to save time i
pre-recorded the demo in my laptop
so let me just hit play
so this is the modernizr library
and the code has been beautified because
it was minimized
minified and here at the very end you
see the the web schemer
and it's uh running in the onload events
uh actually using jquery and and
binding the the mouse up and touch end
events
and serializing the whole form and
sending it
to um that endpoint controlled by the
attacker
so we are running our classifier next uh
it's a cli tool
um we use as inputs the
the web schemer file
and the output is the features that have
been detected
and the final score which is uh 52
so it's we consider over 50 to be the
threshold that we consider to be a mage
card schemer so it's just
over uh the threshold that we are
considering
so we would still consider this to be
magekart
uh but
but not for much so
so the detective features uh so we
detect a lot of different features
uh but uh this web schema is actually
very
very different from the the current web
schemer so it doesn't use obfuscation
um it's only a single function so it's
very different looking from the current
um
web schemers second example the
inventor that has shown you before uh
so this example um this schemer is
is quite different from the the previous
one so it's obfuscated
uh it does page location check so
it's actually checking if it's running
in the checkout page
uh the ticketmaster web uh
schemer wasn't doing that and and and
basically it was running in all the
pages so
um that can be uh more noisy
because by running in all the pages
there are
higher chances of being discovered so by
limiting to
just one or two pages they're actually
being slightly more stealthy and and
that's good for them because the longer
they stay
in the page with without being detected
uh
better chances that they are collecting
more credit card uh
credit card information uh they're also
using multi-page checkouts
so they're this is uh
this is used because uh sometimes the
checkout forms
they collect data uh across different
pages
so they are they are storing data in
cookies and then
uh in the final step they they pick up
the data and send it send it to the drop
server
so um i'm going to run the demo
uh in three versions of this file
so the first one is a de-obfuscated
version
of this web schemer the second one is
the obfuscated version of the schema but
just
the schemer not the file where the the
schema was
inserted and finally the third
version is the the off-scale version but
within the scope of the full file so i'm
doing this because i want to
provide a comparison between the the
the scores of all three versions
so this is the the obfuscated version of
the schemer and just the skimmer
the drop server is very easy to see
let's run this
okay so we the final score is 66 percent
and a few features are detected
obfuscation is not detected because
we de-obfuscated the the schemer
and we see like the use of rejects is
uh keyword password set timeout
uh location checking
now next we will run with the obfuscated
version but just a schemer
and it gives us a final score of
181 percent so uh certainly a
good increase compared with the previous
uh version
and obfuscation was detected
and finally the full file used and
with the obfuscated schema so and now we
we see 85 so as you can see
um as we detect more features
uh the the the score gets higher
and we are more certain that we are
dealing with the
with the web schemer and even detecting
uh one line of obfuscated javascripts uh
in in in the file that is not obfuscated
is very suspicious and something that uh
weighs on the scoring uh heuristics
so as you can see detected features a
lot of different features detected in
the first version
it was de-obfuscated so it was easy to
collect these features
the second version was obfuscated but we
were able to de-obfuscate the
the file and grab the same features
uh we also detected the type of
obfuscation it was used the
sun x tool which is um an open source
obfuscation it's not very good but it's
it's free so it's it's used by a lot of
uh
bad guys um and and finally
uh we detected uh
the same things as before but uh more
than that we detected that the
obfuscation portion
was just uh about on the bottom of
of the scripts the final
schemer is this caesar plus skimmer
this schemer is basically i brought this
example because it's using the caesar
plus obfuscation
uh you can have a look at it
in the image to the right um
so the obfuscation is uh slightly weird
weirder because it's using encoding uh
it uses multi-page checkouts but not via
cookies
it's using local storage and
it was hidden inside
a jquery plugin
and ready to download by anyone looking
for
that type of functionality
so i'll i'll actually demo uh these at
the end when the
i i'll talk about our the obfuscation
for caesar plus
um for now i'm just saying that this
scheme this particular schemer was
scored
in 86
so it's slightly higher than the last
example
uh and the reason why is because the
caesar obfuscation
is uh is more unique um
we don't see a benign code using caesar
plus obfuscation that much
so it's uh when we see caesar plus it's
it's it's very likely that this is uh
some some kind of malware and together
with all the other features that we have
extracted we
concluded that that's good chances that
we are talking about the web schemer
so comparing all the schemers uh that we
have seen
um i present the
presented the samples in increasing
scoring order
and uh as you can see all of those
samples were considered to be
schemers one of the good things about
this classification is since it uses
static code analysis it's very it's very
easy to scale so it's very easy to
run this through thousands or even
millions of files uh
we don't need to run a browser we don't
need to do dynamic analysis
so it's it's very it's very cheap to run
this classifier
and the the the results are very very
promising
so regarding the testing um we gathered
a collection of 244 schema samples
uh we also collected all the javascript
from the top
1000 alexa and we
pre-labeled all the skimmer samples
we ran the classifier through
all the samples including the the
schemers
and at the end we compared the score
that the
the tool gave with with the label
if any and we measured false positives
and
true positives and false negatives and
true negatives
the results are were very good so we we
got a 95 percent true positives
so we actually considered to be this to
be very promising results
obviously we are still uh optimizing and
and improving the the classifier
but uh for the the first
batch of results uh i think they are
very promising
um so now i'll present brutus minus
uh this was the surprise i saved for
last
um so when working uh
in this classifier we as you saw we
we were finding a lot of different uh
web schemers using scissor plus
obfuscation so we decided to build our
own
tool that the officegates caesar plus
and and i'll i'll i'll show you a
a very quick demo of that tool working
on the
on the sample before that uh a brief
context about
caesar plus obfuscation uh
as i mentioned before it's available on
the dark web for 100
so it's uh it's pretty uh affordable for
an attacker i would say
um so no wonder that um
they they are adding this type of um
protection techniques to to their
schemers it's actually more than this
they are they are they are
web schemers are evolving a lot uh
they they have been using things like
bot detection
or stenography so it's it's a cat and
mouse game
for sure so this particular obfuscation
it presents two layers of obfuscation
that i will detail next it uses
different techniques to obfuscate
strings and integers
uh for instance they are converting um
converting a number to
a string to the base 34
representation of the string it's a way
to encode the string
they are using ternary operators they
are encoding
chars they are using regexes to
find and replace portions of strings
they are using that code injection
um and they are using things like
um unresolved symbols to break the code
uh depending on certain checks
so the first layer is using a lot of
encoding
uh as you could see here this is
isn't valid javascript uh what you're
seeing there it's a
a bunch of strings that need to be
decoded using
uh eval and um
but but it's just meant to to hide what
they're doing underneath
but it's more than that it's actually
doing
anti-tampering uh in the second layer
so in the second layer uh after decoding
it checks
for a crc the crc is
included in the file in the first layer
using a variable and it's checking if
the
after decoding if the the decoded
matches the if thing actually if the
encoded for uh
code is matching the crc and if not
they're running
um they're calling an undeclared
function to break the code on purpose
uh so it's actually slightly uh
it's more difficult to automatically the
officegate
code that it's trying to self-check and
and
trying to be temporary resistant uh
compared with other obfuscations that
are more passive like the sonics that
you saw before
so here is the demo of us running brutus
minus
this is the obfuscated code
so most most of the code is just the
encoded strings
and here i'm running the brutus minus
which is a cli tool as well on that
sample
and redirecting to a new file
so here you can see the brutus version
of it so
as you can see it's much more the
obfuscated
um we can still see a lot of different
um so you can see that code but we see
what what matters we see the page
location check
we see it using local storage to do
multi-page checkouts
we see it's sending data out
hooking um grabbing all the data from
the
those form elements
and finally we see the the drop server
address
and the xhr post to that address
so everything that we need in order to
classify is here
um and it's full
fully automate automated uh the
obfuscation so
again the cost of running this is close
to zero
so wrapping up
so we mostly address the the topic of
web schemers
they are getting increasingly more
sophisticated as i
uh mentioned before uh they are using
things like bot detection
uh they are using stenography they are
trying to use
heavier obfuscation and
it will only get more complex as we go
so the the defenses need to be
sophisticated
as well but they need to be scalable
and they need to be effective so our
approach is
based on behavior which is good because
it's more resilient to
the code changing form um
so we needed the classification a
classifier to
know what type of schemer we are dealing
with so we decided to build one
that's what we presented um you can work
with different
layers of obfuscated code as you seen
as a as you saw the results are very
promising
if not if not deciding automatically
it can at the very minimum select the
best candidates for analysis
and it scales very well at the very end
as a bonus represented brutus minus
uh which is the our caesar plus the
obfuscated
and of course this uh will keep working
um
on our classifier so um
i don't know when we will be the next
talk but
uh we'll probably keep presenting the
results uh
as we develop this
that's all for me uh thank you and
back to the studio