all right so thank you very much for
attending my talk so in this talk I'm
going to discuss how we actually empower
reverse engineering using the latest
techniques in machine learning as well
as data mining
so the overall process the overall
process that we try to optimize about
binary and it's about binary analysis or
program message so we start with
typically we start with a binary file
which is the sequence of 0 1 0 0 1 and
then we have a disassembler we can get a
list of assembly functions and each
function basically is a list of assembly
instructions and then here is our
reverse engineering fellow and he or she
will try to do a manual Narus it has to
take a look at a functionality or high
abstract high-level logics of the
assembly functions and depending on what
kind of ties such as the malware Nancy
or one durability and Nancy so so they
are different they have different
purpose here but the overall process
this is the over simplified process of
the workflow the reverse engineer buffer
that would try to optimize of course we
have a different kind of techniques that
here and there helping out this process
as well but we really focus on the last
steps here for reverse engineering by
trying to answer two specific questions
so when a reverse John you try to
understand a specific functions where we
try to address the information needs
information needs of the reverse
engineering task is this something that
has been analyzed before by himself or
herself or is something that has been
analyzed just couple seconds ago by his
or her teammates or interests and no
library functions or variation of the
known library functions we try to
address this information needs their
information needs by using an info group
information retrieval approach so we
develop an open source of assembly
called chrome search engine camino and
so suppose it's like a centralized
repository of assembly lang
courage that people can build different
repositories just like on github instead
of a repository of source code the
Creole repository of assembly code
depending on the task that they are
working on and then reverse engineers is
a team or within organizations so they
can index the assembly functions they're
analyzing and they can search for the
chromes as well so by using this
high-level system we try to address the
information needs for the reverse
engineering but when we talk about
information retrieval we need to define
what is exactly exactly similarity right
what is exactly is a chrome so in the
literature so in the literary Church of
assembly assembly language chrome search
so there are typically three different
type of Chrome's so the first type of
chrome is exact room right so there's
nothing fancy here they're exactly the
same so to find this kind of chrome we
can simply do exact hashing right and
the second type of chrome is that is
costing tactically a quick Bolin so
these two pieces of assembly code looks
are different but they are actually
corresponding to the same logics but may
be due to different compilers or
different versions of the compiler they
use different registers or different
offsets or on the stack to represent
different variable so after normalizing
the assembly code or normalizing
instructions and variable into the
abstract high-level token representation
they are actually the same just like two
minifigures here is that that the
picture is taken from different angle
that's why they are different but if we
normalize the camera they would be the
same so this kind of cross that is not
difficult to handle as well and the
third type of chrome is the minor
modification so for minor modification
means that we allow a certain degree of
update or change to the come out to the
assembly code so this this can be done
through any like firstly firstly hashing
or locality sensitive hashing algorithms
for nearest neighbor cool search but
much
what is more challenge is that we also
have different kind of Apophis occasion
as well as optimization techniques that
make the same assembly functions that
look completely different so for example
in this case suppose this the
minifigures that on the left hand side
is original ones we can break it is a
different prognosis and even inject
different noise to it so the image here
looks very different so how does this
translate to a real-life scenario so
here we have four different assembly
functions they are actually come from
the sock the same source code so the one
on the left is the original one that
without any optimization and then the
second one is that with the all-day
optimizations turns on and the third one
is obfuscated by the control flow graph
F a flattening techniques in the OEM so
all the basic blocks are break into
different parts and and duplicated and
arranged by a big switch gigantic switch
and the last one is above asked aided by
the abacus control so because we're
trying to do a search engines right to
find this kind of Chrome we can one
possible way is that to do dynamic and
there is e right we can run the program
because they're the same thing so should
expect the same input and output
behavior but as a search engine we
cannot really able to afford the luxury
of time dynamic and nursey so we don't
want the user to wake for let's say 10
minutes - for the query - to dynamically
execute it or symbolically execute it so
I will look into existing literature or
existing methods to static remodel the
assembly code so we identify two main
challenge or problems so typically when
we try to model assembly code the
relationships among the tokens that we
think as Enrico is mostly and glad so
for example we have XX m m0 register
versus the artist reading the streaming
operations they're not exactly the same
but I mean they
on high-level day they focus on same as
back of the assembly instructions or F
curves and I versus F opens they're
different but the can occurs bonding
both to the file operations and string
compare men compare string coffee and
memory copy sometimes they are swappable
right and the second challenge the
second problem is that it's about how we
wait this information so as experience
reverse engineer you may not actually
with every single line of assembly like
assembly instructions when you try to
analyze something right so reverse
engineer look for something interesting
so we put higher weight on something
that we never saw before they violate
what we commonly know what we can really
know and regular rang them with repeat
the better
repeat the patterns and now interesting
so we want to put a lower way on that so
these two problems actually quite
similar to the problems in natural
language processing or using machine
learning
so actually what we're trying to do is
that well we try to build a a new
network to help us to address these two
challenge but Before we jump into how we
build this new network for assembly
language I want to talk about how I
learned learn English as most of you can
already tell so I'm not a native English
speaker so my first language is not
English the way that I was the way that
I learned English is that it's quite
brutal we do a lot of multiple-choice
correction in exams they're trying to
complete a sentence with different
options right so to find the right word
fit fit into the context or the thus
impacts of the sentence right so this is
how I did before and it turns out okay
so I can speak English right now and ten
years later people find out that this is
a fantastic way to change to train and
you never to learn human language so
given a new network so we asked a new
neighbor to solve millions of this kind
of multiple-choice questions following
the same way so in this case first we
need to have the questions
right so let's say if I have some text a
sequence of text that cat said on a map
so we apply a sliding window on the text
and ask them your network to predict
what is in the middle which is said
given the context so you can see here
the input is the cat on and the output
is set right so we warned you never to
make these kind of predictions over all
the questions and this approach turn out
to be great we can learn actually very
rich semantic relationship between
tokens from the natural language so you
can see that one typical example is that
the representation of King - man press
woman actually is queen and the Batman
is good and its meaning a copula it
actually kind of makes sense right and
the paragraph vectors here actually can
capture what is unique about this
question suppose you always said the
castle on America sort of met but one
times I told you that you make a you
make a wrong answer
the right answer is not set is speaking
and then you will be okay so the exam I
took last week actually as a very weird
correct answer that it's not said it's
is about speaking right so this
information is captured on the paragraph
ID which is like the exam ID right you
recorded in aspects of exam there's a
real answer well we're following the
same way applying this model and
directory on the assembly code it works
great but the problem is that assembly
language not like tags is that linear
layout right so we adopt this model a
little bit so instead of asking the
model to predict what is in the middle
of the token we ask the model to
reconstruct the instructions assembly
instruction in the middle by considering
the neighborhood instructions right so
given a sliding window over the assembly
instructions let's say a size of three I
asked the model to predict reconstruct
words in the middle by taking the
context the neighbor instruction into
considerations and this this more it
turns out it works pretty well on
assembly language and
visualizing the relationship among the
assembly took at the tokens that we
soften as soon and which is quite
interesting so we can see that on the
waxer space 16 bits register so the
register pretty much group into
different bit lines they kind of be
similar to each other considering their
context and then the term operations
equip the crew together we also have the
condition condition operations that
critical could do together and if we
look into the function course the seal
I've received the Lipsy function course
is that it Co we can also find a fire
operations I could be together as well
as the networking access control
functions are very similar to each RS so
these are the data token the under the
call instruction right after the after
the coil instruction so also we have the
memory operations that tend to be routed
together as well as string stage and for
all the math related function calls I
also could be clear but it's not shown
in this life and we conduct the Chrome
search evaluations by comparing the
original barrier against the optimized
one and then we compare our approach
with all different kinds of aesthetic
approach including grab base assembly
language base as well as to most reasons
are dynamic and there is a base approach
it turns out that approach is pretty
accurate matching between the Orangemen
one as well as the optimized one even
compared to the some reasons dynamic
approach but we don't have enough
samples to make conclusion that is the
significant test is a statistically
significant difference and then we also
conduct the cone search and nursey using
the OEM obfuscator it's not the best out
there but it makes it already makes the
assembly code looks very different and
it also turns out that our approach our
performs very well on this on this for
this of a skater we also conduct a
Studies on vulnerability retrieval data
sets like it's like you have a
repository of different assembly
functions some of them are
vulnerabilities we try to retrieve them
compared to esh which which relies on
dynamic and there is the our pro our
approach without any modification
actually have a zero force positive and
as a static approach it takes only
couple million SEK like a couple hundred
milliseconds to get the results and we
take another extreme we use the tigris
obfuscator which relying on
virtualizations just-in-time executions
to apophis kate at the assembly language
simply code and so for the inquiry
through alpha station well it performs
great for virtualization we can still
recover some of the vulnerabilities for
JIT execution well still recover some of
them but if we apply all of them like is
you apply the in curvature and then
virtualization and then we applied a JIT
execution unfortunately we cannot
recover anything because it looks
already very very difficult out
different so of for this model for this
approach we developed to to push the
boundary of static analysis against coop
investigation and optimization so even
performs a lot somewhat better than the
recent dynamic approach ass aesthetic
approach if isn't scalable we can just
use it for our search engines and but
the problem is that where I went
prosthetic chrome because it's a vector
representation right it's very difficult
to explain to the end-user to reverse
engineer that why exactly these two
functions are considered as a chrome
unlike and the other sub grab based
chrome search method but I mean after
above of assocation the graph Bhangra is
it's broken anyway so so the SUBSCRIBE
the concert of a subscribe is no longer
valid
static approach of course has some
inherent this disadvantage so there's no
it cannot recognize for example the
dynamic jump table and we also assume
the assembly code coming from the same
family so we are talking from our
searching English against English but
not English against French right so it's
not like it
six against the Armco and actually we
put this model as part of our Camino
binary and then it's a platform so it's
on github it's open source is ready to
use it can be deployed on your laptop
and workstation or you can deploy it on
a cloud services rely on spark so it's
ready to use besides of ASM to where
which focus on optimization and apophis
occasion we also have ASM chrome which
is the typical subgroup Chrome's
approach cool search approach that given
the query given a target we can identify
the chromeless subgraph it's like really
showing the reverse engineering which
part of the function is a chrome to
another functions and we also have a
seminal module which search for the
clocks across across architecture
assembly instructions so you can search
x86 against an arm call so that this
approach actually we relying on the
intermediate representation for the code
matching and this is also following a
support from such a pro so it has a very
good degree of interpret ability for
search engines so that's it okay so any
questions any questions from the
audience please come to the microphone
and before you ask questions please
state your name and affiliation please
thanks hi personally from IBM I'm not
sure if you had any discussion about
different architectures I mean I've
different during network architectures
for higher-level languages like Java I
think people have used it as James or
Shannon's and all actually Sheena has
been also used for binary so have you
compared them with this see bone
structure so so the reason why we use
the most similar architecture is that we
want to prove like a high throughput
rate of the of the of the of
the training model because we want the
model to learn as much as from the data
so that's why we didn't rely on ASTM so
another reason why we don't use our
statements that we've observed that when
we increase increase the context the the
larger the context we increase the the
higher chance that you can actually just
directly predict how the assembly
instruction that as our target and if we
have less information propagate back to
the exam ID that we can remember oh I
make it's like make the question
extremely difficult for the model so
instead we make a lot of simple
questions to the model so actually we
did try our SDM on our own but the
performance is not very good because the
frupa rate is very small yeah compared
to thank you thank you all right due to
the time limited we may only take one
question for this this talk so let's
thank Stephen one more time
[Applause]