all right so I'm Robert and I'm happy to
be here today to talk about our work on
cache side-channel detection with our
two large chasm
so to start I'd like to go over at a
high level how trash based side channels
work so if we imagine that we have a
program here and the programs you want
to take some sensitive data as input and
as we process the data it's going to
leave some artifacts that may be
observable in the CPU cache so the
adversary can extract these artifacts
maybe using a primum probe or a flush
and reload style attack and then if we
imagine a program that takes this
different the same program with the same
public inputs but a different sensitive
input and it also processes the data and
the final cache state is a different the
implication is that there's information
flowing from the sensitive data into the
cache and that's the unintentional
information transfer that's happening so
just how a severe as this problem so at
these attacks have been shown to be a
rather high bandwidth so there's been
work that's shown the baton yet up to a
hundred over 100 kilobytes of leakage
per second
they've been shown to work on a secure
Enclave such as until ice chips and
they've also been shown to be able to be
launched across cores and the across
virtual machines in the in the cloud
using the shared last level cache and
most recently respect during meltdown
vulnerability that brought the side
channels to the forefront taking
advantage of speculative and out of
order execution delete arbitrary data
from the victim address space and one of
the main problems is finding these
vulnerabilities in code is often quite
challenging because micro architectural
properties are often quite a subtle and
hard for people to think about as
they're programming so there's been some
prior work on this so one of the first
ones would be a cache audit that was
from 2013 from Euston security and what
they do is they use abstract
interpretation to try and relate a
program execution to how the cache
behaves
they try to compute an upper bound on a
deleted from the source code via the
cash based side Channel but they don't
provide any information of the
programmer on where the vulnerability is
in their in their program and then more
recently in 2017 a tool called cash see
uses symbolic execution to build a
relationship of how a program executes
from the cache state and they're able to
detect where the leakage happens but
they may miss side channels because they
require some inputs to be concrete which
means it may not go down certain control
flow paths that actually have
vulnerabilities and they don't provide
any way to fix them so because of these
two limitations are also not able to
verify that programs are actually
side-channel free so that's where our
work comes in so we proposed using cash
aware symbolic execution so we're able
to soundly model a cash base side
channels so those resulting from memory
arson see is where the the memory
address is computed from some sensitive
data and also branches where the
condition is tainted and the different
branches will access different data and
we're able to detect where the
side-channel happens in the code so we
can identify the line in the source code
that causes the vulnerability and tell
the programmer why it happens and we're
able to provide some simple fixes to
remove the program and then verify the
absence of the side-channel we also
include a variety of different cache
models that yield different precision
and efficiency so as an overview our
tool tapes as input a C a source program
and uses the client Pilar to generate
LLVM IR code we then perform our
analysis on the LLVM IR code and we will
require a model and the model is going
to include an attack model and a cache
model will then generate a verification
condition which will be passed on to the
XIII SMT solver and if the SMT solver
reports an unsatisfiable result that
means that there's no cash base side
channel with respect to the models that
were used and well if it's satisfiable
will generate a localization report and
the localization report will tell the
user why the sidechain will happen and
where
and with that information the
mitigations can be applied and then if
the user wants to verify the absence of
the side channel I like to run it back
through our tool and if it report is
unsatisfiable it means that there's no
side Channel so trying to go over an
illustrative example we talked about the
square multiply algorithm which is used
in modular exponentiation so this is
commonly used in asymmetric cryptography
so in these cases the exponent is
typically the the private key and here
the loop is joined iterate over every
bit of the key and waiting to see online
stitch that there's a key dependent
branch and inside of the branch that's
trying to access some data that wouldn't
be accessed if the branch wasn't aging
and this is going to leave a some
observable remnants in the cache that
can be exploited by an adversary to to
learn information about the key so our
tool uses a symbolic execution so unlike
some tools that use a symbolic execution
we actually treat all program variables
as symbolic values instead of mating
some of them concrete so this is true
for both public and private inputs and
then we also introduced cache variables
in the cache we're going to create a
cache variable for every public variable
and these cache variables are going to
be expressed differently depending on
which cache model is selected so the
verification step is going to require us
to take a program and essentially we
start off with the original program and
then we're going to duplicate the
program renaming all of the variables so
we're going to run the program twice and
initially all of the public variables
and the catch variables are going to be
equal and only the sensitive data will
be different so the SMT solver will be
able to select two different values for
the private data what I want to see is
at the end are there two different
possible cache States that these
sensitive data can cause and in the
event that the cache variables are not
equal that means if the cache states are
different and we'll report a side
channel and if there are always equal
for any two possible key pairs now that
means that there's no information
flowing from the sensitive input into
the final observable cache state so the
reason we use these cache models to
abstract
some of the details is oftentimes
trashes are rather complex to the cash
hierarchies replacement policy
inclusivity and a lot of these
properties vary tremendously and a lot
of times they're not even available to
us a lot of the details are kept private
and even if they were known they vary
amongst many architectures anyways so we
developed these models to be more apply
more generally so our infinite model is
a rather simple model and under
approximation of a lot of real behavior
and treats caches if it's an infinite
set but we find that that even though
it's a simple it actually is pretty good
at finding side channels and then we
have our age model which over
approximates real policies by
essentially keeping track of how old
each variable is so essentially the age
is how many accesses have passed since
it was last used and then we have a more
realistic model called a least recently
used model which also uses an age but
essentially the expression is going to
be a binary result which is either it's
cached or it's not cached so to
demonstrate how these models would work
we have this toy program here and we're
going to initialize the cache to be all
false and then when we execute the if
condition here we're going to access the
key so we'll mark that as true and then
you'll note that the key value here is
assigned to be once older than the then
branch and we'll get a is access and
we'll get true and then on the next on
the second execution the SMT solver
might select zero to be the key value
and we'll still execute the condition
and this time we'll go down the else
branch and we can see that there is
going to be a difference in the final
trash States and this is what our tool
is looking for and then to demonstrate
how the age model might work so here we
start off with all of the ages to be
affinity infinity which means that there
haven't been abscessed yet essentially
then when we access P initially we'll
increment all of the ages and here
intermitting infinity by 1 is still
infinity so they stay the same and then
since we asked this T will set that age
to 0 and then again when we get to the
line and the in the Ben branch
I will increment the ages first and then
we'll set the members of the program the
tranche variable that was used to 0 and
then when we do it out in the else
branch it'll be very similar will do the
increment and then do the access and at
the end this model will actually provide
essentially a sequence an order of the
memory access pattern and we can see
that with the age model it'll still
it'll also report there's a side channel
in this program so we had to make some
trade-offs to improve performance
because symbolic execution is typically
rather an expensive process so the array
reads when we read from arrays are going
to be unconstrained so when we drop the
constraints that essentially we'll treat
them as private variables so in order to
overcome this we use a taint analysis to
be able to tell if they're sensitive or
or insensitive and then we have we have
this reset command which is going to
reset the constraints so it essentially
allows us to break a program up into
multiple components and verify the
individual components and we also apply
this tain analysis to make sure that
when we drop these constraints that we
still know which variables are sensitive
and insensitive after a reset and this
command is particularly useful when we
do it to reason about loops so we also
have a loop transformation that will
soundly rewrite our programs to be a
loop free by using our reset command and
it makes it very convenient because then
we don't have to unroll loops and when
you do loop unrolling and symbolic
execution it typically causes that path
explosion it was a difficult so to get
performance some more information about
this details can be found in the paper
so now to briefly talk about the two
different attack models that we consider
so in the
access model essentially an adversary is
able to observe before and after some
window and there they're able to see a
sequence of memory or a set of addresses
that are accessed but they can't see the
sequence they can't tell the order in
which the data is accessed and then a
much stronger attack model as a trace
base model where they're actually able
to see a and B after every single memory
access so they're able to get a sequence
of memory addresses that are are used by
the victim so as far as a result so here
I'll talk about our cryptic results for
using our trace model so using our
infinite model and we're able to
identify 269 unique of vulnerable points
in these benchmarks and about 200
seconds which is quite good considering
that the infinite model is actually an
under approximation and then we have our
age model which is able to identify one
more vulnerable location and the
trade-off here is that it takes an order
of magnitude more time to execute and
then our most realistic model actually
more closely corresponds to our infinite
model which highlights actually how
effective our more simple model is of
finding these vulnerabilities but it'll
still actually tell you a significant
amount more time so the one benchmark
where we see a difference here is going
to be on the square and always multiply
routine and the only reason the aged
model still reports a difference is that
the the order of the accesses is still
different and the LRU model doesn't
report anything because there the
difference is actually very close
together so it's only a couple of memory
accesses apart so there's two actually
both going to be cached and it's going
to be indistinguishable and our infinite
model reports the same as our LRU model
so we're also able to verify the absence
of side-channel so we introduced two
primitives pre loading and pinning so
pre loading the data is going to be
cached at the beginning of the function
and with pinning that's going to be
cached throughout the function so when
we analyze the program we see that with
the infinite model it reports that there
is no side channels because things will
never be evicted from the cache with
that model so it was a bit pre literally
at the beginning it will permit
in the cash and with the age model we
still report side channels because the
order of the access seizes remains
unchanged and then pinning the data is
going to be cashed throughout the
function so what that means is that the
age that we use for that the age model
is always going to be zero for those
sensitive values so it won't ever change
so we're able to verify the absence of
side channels in those crypto benchmarks
with these defenses so in conclusion we
build our tool chasm to automatically
identify vulnerabilities and programs
and we're able to support a variety of
cash models that will deliver different
amounts of precision and efficiency and
we tested on assortment of benchmarks we
confirmed existing vulnerabilities in
crypto code we verified the mitigation
strategies on some of the crypto
benchmarks and we found over 20 new
vulnerabilities in the postre sequel
database which I didn't have a chance to
talk about today but you didn't find
that information in the paper so thank
you
[Applause]
I start on France hike van fuschak
so I see it's interesting work and a
great talk by the way idea so I see you
simplify the model for accessing
addresses but have you considered
confused deputy attacks where you have a
benign component in your CPU that you
can mislead to do cache attacks for you
an example of this was previous year at
usenix
transferred attacks or malicious
management unit why stopping cache
attacks is hard and software than you
think so
how are you planning to actually address
these kind of issues I'm not sure is
that can you explain more details with
everything yeah so what the paper showed
back then was that you can use the
memory management unit just by accessing
addresses to get page tables in the
cache to still perform a cache attack oh
yeah so we don't consider the page
tables in this model but so one of the
nice things that we can still apply the
base symbolic execution to as we just
need to formalize how that model would
work so in our cache model if we
included that with it it would be able
to reason about that but that's not
something on the we considered okay
thank you hi network so you initialize
all the global variables it's symbolic
values some of those variables as
pointers how do you handle some
symbolize the pointers so for pointers
we actually have to simplify them a bit
so we typically once say we we have to
we only allow them to point to
essentially one data structure at a time
so if they point to a different data
structure we don't verify the program
but that didn't happen in any of our
benchmarks but we can reason about like
pointer arithmetic as long as it points
to one memory region so one array at a
time that will be verified have your
salt airboats like if I might find out
to my those kind of techniques you
handle no thanks
any more questions we still have some
time left here well maybe then let me
ask a very quick question here for the
three cash models you constructed are
they generically applicable to different
architectures or different processor
families oh yeah so that's why we wanted
to have these abstract models is so we
don't make any assumptions about how the
architecture works so they are
applicable to multiple architectures
thank you let's thank the speaker one
more time
[Applause]