hi
everyone my name is Han I am from
Virginia Tech today I'm going to talk
about disposable email services and
email tracking email address is
popularly one of the most important
online personally identifiable
information using email address we can
link on my activity to real world
identity and that's why leaked email
address can lead to real life scandal
and such present a privacy challenge
Ashley Madison's data breach is a
perfect example Ashley Madison is a
website where people look for an affair
and in 2015 it was hacked in after
amounts 32 million user email address
were released by hackers many government
military and corporate email address
were found in a league data and in just
10 days
Nikki users start to face black nose
threats email can also be tracked to do
user profiling let's look at this
example this is an email sent to me from
Facebook when I try to reset my Facebook
password at the end of the message
there is a tracking pixel is usually
transparent and it's usually one x one
but I used color black and bigger size
here to make it easier to observe but
just open the email my email client will
send a request to the tracker and this
way the tracker will know whether the
email has been read at a time a location
and a device associated with the email
using email tracking technique business
company can know which email users are
more likely to open thesis allows them
to infer user preference for targeted
advertisement which might lead to
discrimination even features can using
email tracking technique to make more
informed and flexible fishing strategy
because of all those privacy concerns
users go for a alternative solution
called disposable email service for
example mail job the CC is a disposable
email service website users can use any
username they want without a password
for example let's use David as our
username and click view inbox we get a
temporary embossed card David and Mel
job that CC let's say I'm restoring a
Twitter account instead of using my real
email address I can use this temporary
temporary inbox to finish the email
address verification process and in this
way the unlike tivity are disconnected
with real word identity here we have two
research questions first what do user
use disposable email services and what
are potential risk for using it to
understand those two research questions
we did a Merriman study we choose 7
disposable email services and monitored
17,000 disposal inboxes and in total we
collected 2.3 million messages from
210,000 Center domains and finally we
use the collected messages to study
image tracking we choose these 7
disposable email services they are
highly popular
according to karela mail to come it has
processed more than 11 billion messages
with more than 100,000 emails per hour
going in
according to melon leaders privacy
policy all the emails on melody leader
calm our public readable and
discoverable by anyone at any time
let me first explain what it means that
those disposable inbox are probably
shared remember that I use mail job
that's easy to register a Twitter
account so I triggered this email from
Twitter to this inbox but because the
username David is highly popular at the
similar time other users use this inbox
to register Cora and a lot of boardgame
website so disposable email inbox is
shared by multiple users and popular
user dreams are used by more users and
sus receive more messages here's how our
data collection works first we get
popular usernames from existing data
breaches then we use those popular
usernames to collect messages from
disposable emo services in total we
choose 10,000 popular usernames just as
info John or the main then we Molitor
knows popular usernames on each of the
seven website would choose so in total
we monitor 70,000 disposal inboxes and
because user use knows inboxes to
interact with online services like
YouTube Facebook or Twitter then we can
use those inboxes to
to user message then infer user activity
in total in total we collected 2.4
million messages from 210 thousand
centered domains from October 2017 and
January 2018
during our data collection we observe
that different services keep user
messages for different periods of time
here's how long they claim to keep user
messages but based on our observation
here's how long they actually keep user
messages some of them are not consistent
some of them keep user messages for too
long so disposable email services don't
always delete user messages as quickly
as neha promised after data collection
we found some risky usages of disposal
services the rich the first risk is that
we found sensitive personally
identifiable information in collecting
messages so we use the regular
expression to look for those sensitive
PII and here's what we have found we
have found critical numbers social
security numbers and employer
identification numbers besides NCBI we
also found emails related to account
creation so remember that this is an
email sent to me when I try to reset my
Facebook account
but I wonder how many emails like this
exist in our data set here's what we
have found as you can see we looked for
registration password reset and
authentication code emails their
percentage are not high but there are a
large number of them in total 86,000
emails related to account existing or
data set here are some examples of the
risky usages there are more than 4,000
emails from healthcare.gov some users
use those inbox to register account
there and those account care sends
information we also found emails from
Air Force and those that account carry a
social security number and date of birth
is very easy for user to reset the
password and get those sense information
we there are also emails from the iOS
scanner attackers can use the disposable
inbox to receive all the scanned
documents from that account and
including signed contract or others
sensitive documents this North dataset
of email messages is really valuable
it's rare for researchers to have access
to they store data set of email messages
and indeed to present a valuable
opportunity to study email tracking
previously a mission when Facebook sends
an email to me it will insert a tracking
pixel at the end of the message
but just opening the email my email
client was in a request to a tracker and
this way
the tracker will know whether the IMP
has been read before studying or
tracking we need to know the difference
between first part tracking and sir part
tracking if the tracker is also faced by
comm then it is first part tracking but
it's also possible that Facebook is
using some kind of third party tracking
service let's say it's Google comm then
is third part tracking you know to study
email tracking the first step is to
detect tracking to be a tracking image
tag it has to satisfy either of the two
conditions first the image URL contains
a identifier of the receiver so that the
trucker knows the request comes from
certain receiver the identifier could be
the email address of the receiver such
as my new address the identifier could
be the hash value of the email address
such as md5 hash value of my email
address
in total we looked for thirty two types
of hash functions and more than thirty
three cells and combinations of them
it's also possible that the tracker is
using some kind of ID that we cannot
guess instead of keeping looking in the
form of the identifier we also consider
extreme small image tags as tracking
pixel to your conservative we only
consider image tag that has a touch size
of 1 x 1 as tracking pixel during our
tracking detection we found some evasive
tracking technique the first evasive
tracking technique is that some image
tag are hiding your actual sizes they
don't have any sites attributes but if
you cure them it turned out to be a
tracking pixel and our solution is to
dynamically fetching all the pixels to
get to their actual size in your dataset
23 four point nine percent of all
tracking images are high
your sizes also we found some Checkers
will redirect you other trackers for
example tracker a comm may redirect you
be calm then sitcom then finally
returning a tracking pixel here we call
a a direct tracker and B and C hidden
trackers in our data set 54 points a
percent of all tracking URLs have
redirections and in total we identified
2825 hidden checkers here is a list of
top hidden trackers the most popular
hidden tracker is double-click the net
more than 96 thousand emails will
redirect to it and double-click done
that is a complete owned by Google
popular hidden trackers retrieve receive
tracking information from a large number
of direct trackers in real time after
detect email tracking we can finally
answer those two questions how prevalent
is email tracking and how prevalent is
first party and server checking let's
first look at a few basic statistical or
data set as you can see twenty four
point six percent of all email messages
and 5.5 percent of all email senders are
performing tracking and what about first
party I can't serve per tracking our
result shows that first part tracking is
slightly more popular than for third
part tracking and overall only a small
percentage senders are performing
tracking we consider center domains with
Xing Alexa top 10,000 as popular senders
our result shows that although overall
only 5.5 percent of all senders are
tracking receivers but almost half
popular senders are doing tracking and
here are some examples of those popular
senders that are tracking receivers
let's compare email tracking to web
tracking web tracking has been
extensively studied Google is the top
tracker tracking 80 percent of Alexa top
ten top one minion web site however
email tracking isn't well understood yet
previously largest email tracking study
only collected messages from the
hundreds in our domains we used a much
larger email dataset and our result
shows that email tracking is
not as prevalent as web tracking yet
only a small portion of senders are
tracking receivers and email tracking is
not dominated by a single company yet
top 10 truckers only covers 31.8% of all
centers who are doing tracking in
conclusion with the first measurement
study on disposable email services we
collected 2.7 million messages from 7
disposable evo set email services and we
provide a new understanding of what
they're useful and it risky usages we
improve CLE analyze email tracking
activities we study prevalence of email
tracking activities and we study the
divisive tracking technique gdpr is
pushing to better protect users privacy
and data and we hope our work can
recruit the vilest of the privacy
concern of email tracking and accelerate
the defense and vegetation of the
deployment thank you do you have any
questions
hi thanks for the interesting
presentation I had a question about the
first part of the the the thing you
presented about the disposable email
addresses you're relying on being able
to guess the disposable email address so
those are like the examples you gave
like names and info and that kind of
stuff you know to what extent do you
think of can you estimate how that
biases your results because this is a
you know a subset of the things that
people typically do this is a very good
question we in your paper we talked a
lot about a bias and so we only choose
like a certain percentage of the other
receiver all the message they received
buying those and newsroom we receive
right and we we think that we kind of
used that disposable the sender's we
receive as a way to say that we have a
diverse you know messages from a diverse
a kind of online services so that would
be like a kind of way to say that we
have you know a great way to avoid the
bias
can you explain it again because I mean
you're saying that you if you observe
several different email sources
associated with one disposable email
address then that is an indication of
non bias or I think a repeater Crescent
yeah I I didn't quite understand your
response you were saying that if you
receives many different emails from many
different domains associated with one
single disposable email address and then
that's the signal of what exactly we
receive messages from a diverse kind of
senders yeah but what does what does
that mean exactly
and hardly is that meaning the messages
are from a diverse source of a diverse
source it is quite representative okay
well let's take it offline thanks maybe
related question so you you you guys
only looked at the user names that are
popular
and those are the ones that are likely
to have multiple different people using
them are the problems you've discovered
at the various statistics actually are
is multiple people viewing them actually
irrelevant to the to the dangers of the
statistics or it doesn't really matter
even if one person is being tracked that
seems pretty bad to begin with but how
much worse is that if multiple people
can access this tracking information so
we this is a good question we didn't do
a user study to to ask if you actually
know the risk of using this kind of
service but based on observation all
those website explicitly tell users that
your messages are public and as for the
perspective of your tracking I don't
think most people will notice in a small
pixel at the end of the message so they
probably don't know do do any of these
services prevent users from using
popular names I guess I don't know how
they would do that there are some kind
of services they don't allow you to
choose your name they allocate your like
random address yeah there's one question
over there where they preload the images
do you notice any of these disposable
email services might do the same thing
that like read some of the tracking that
occurs are you saying there are some
services well prey load the out the
external images yeah yeah
we have notice we have notice on the a
lot of the popular email providers are
doing this such as gmail is proxying the
out the request sent the external
resources but we don't we didn't observe
that you know and II know this votes
were your services are doing this okay
thank you mm-hmm okay one last question
so you only focused on these one by one
pixels but what prevents someone from
tracking on a larger pixel that's part
of maybe the logo or some
- look we have a letter standard to look
for the identifier of the receiver if we
can find like this is the identifiable
receiver then we also consider as
tracking yeah we have time for some more
questions
thanks for the interesting talk this is
follow-up to one of the previous
questions so for example my gmail asks
me whether it should always download
images from a particular sender or never
download images and I was wondering if
you had thoughts on whether that defeats
such type of tracking because now in
some sense there's a predefined rule for
Gmail users that images will get
automatically either downloaded or known
are you asking is there a way we can
stop email tracking yet does this defeat
we can there are actually a lot of ways
we can do HTML filtering we can like
Gmail soon we can we can proxy it all
the outcome the requests so that every
everything the tracker gets is from
Gmail it's not from the individual users
we can also preload every image so once
you send an email to me I will always
always read the image like this an essay
from California so the tracker won't do
nothing about the individual receivers
yeah any last questions okay if no other
questions then we're done a few minutes
ahead of time let's thank hang one more
time
[Applause]