area and eaten this
of Indiana University Institute of
information engineering Chinese Academy
of Sciences and the University of
Virginia
the title is demystifying Acadian
practices using mobile apps first let's
see what is a privacy setting take an
example Facebook there is a certain
named in your best friend's for better
service the Facebook use users current
location to enhance the social
connections to get users agreement they
provide a setting in the app and users
can set a setting to decide who can see
their current location to protect
themselves
so for understand more cat functionality
categories of privacy settings wait Lex
600 privacy settings from 200 apps and
according to that date have a project
the settings can be classified into six
categories the first one on the best
date has that has do share contacts with
wicker the sixth one about users
personal profiles such as show age on
your profile and the third users social
connection such as ask users who can see
your friend list and force users
behavior such as don't show my lesson in
history to my friends in musician app
fifth users posted content such as who
can see my diary and the last and his
band such as don't accept if users has
no profile I can it is important to note
in all the categories only on device
data can be protected by and resister
permission for the other eighty-seven
percentage of the privacy they can only
be controlled by the privacy settings so
in our study we want to understand
besides that for being your privacy data
protected by and resister permission
whether people really care about other
privacy protected by privacy settings so
we performed user study to an
users attitude check the Facebook as an
example game we showed us setting
screenshot and grab the city use a to
him in a question there like here we
tell them Facebook access your location
even when we are no using the app and
ask them what do you feel about if this
case happens we provide five choice for
them to choose from very upset or I
don't care the user study last for two
weeks and more than 200 people
participating from the user studies
result we find the 83.5 percentage of
participants choose a absent or very
upset for at least one process it into
your questionnaire and 71 percentage
participants think the privacy's that
you relate theater as important as or
even more important than those covered
by and resist permission so the problem
comes if users cannot find this valuable
privacy settings the privacy may be
disclosed the way those users consent
let's see an example named ali pay a
chinese famous financial app has more
than 1 billion users worldwide it has a
certain limited show message details it
can't control whether show the message
details such as a month change of your
user account when user lock the screen
lock the mobile screen it is a privacy
setting but it's hard for users to find
in practice this is the settings UI pass
users can only find it by click the
indicator me in a home page of your
engine click the setting and then click
the general instead of the privacy
indicator in the settings view and click
the notification and eventually they can
find their setting this process setting
height too deep for users to locate so
in our work we call this hard to find
privacy setting as hidden privacy
setting besides Ali pay will also find
this problem in other apps such as
Facebook in to new 16 Facebook even was
given a Big Brother award as a biggest
privacy offender of the year because of
the hidden price of a team so we want to
understand what are the fundamental
causes of the problematic of the privacy
setting so we perform a second the
others that it'll clear to users
perception of the privacy setting design
way prepared testing apps and install
them on the emulator and real device for
users ask them to find for example we'd
tell them some social apps such as you
love often provide settings for users to
set whether to share location please
find it after they found it whereas them
how difficult was it to find a setting
and we still provide 5 choice for them
to choose from very easy to very
difficult if they choose a difficult or
very difficult we'll further as then why
did you have trouble finding it this
study includes about 600 privacy
settings and as for 3 months more than
700 people participant from the user
studies result participants think that
47 pointed to a percentage of the
privacy setting a difficult or very
difficult to find and they also provide
us 1008 feedbacks for why they think
they are difficult to find or why they
think they cannot find it
for instance purchasing a participant
camera I don't see anywhere I go to
privacy settings it's not anywhere to be
found
you've seriously heavy there so with
some real settings and we find the root
causes of hidden privacy settings can be
classified to two categories the first
one when the privacy setting design
violates a user's habit for example when
the your app has is uncommon participant
it cannot find the settings in their
familiar path so they may ignore the
uncommon you have has to find the
privacy settings the second when looking
for the privacy
challenges users patience for example
when of you can't have too many elements
such as facebook again one of its real
contest even more than 50 UI elements to
click users were lost their patience
will find it so here we summarize the
six root causes from the feedbacks in
total so unless we want to understand in
a real world how seriously the hidden
privacy setting program covers to
discover hidden presence ative from a
large number of real word apps we probe
we designed an automatic patrol named
hunter the hunt had the design the
high-level design of the hunt has to say
steps first instructor privacy settings
wrap and identify the hidden processes
in front of privacy settings each step
contains a key classifier in this 9
probe extract settings from an app can
already be done by existing works that
have super so the key of the hunter he
returns to how to design suitable
features for the to classifier for the
class for the first classifier we use a
tf-idf of each word in the settings
description to design of features the
tf-idf can reflect how important a word
is to a document and in our work we use
it to reflect how important award is to
a privacy setting description so in our
work we model each set interesting
description with the high level
dimension feature vectors each dimension
responding each race each dimension
represents the word in a word back if a
word in a sentence the corresponding
dimensions value is a word here for you
otherwise the dimensions value is 0 for
the second classifier way design 14
features to characterize summarize the
six root causes from the feedbacks for
example the cause of you can
gives too many elements we cancel number
of the elements in the view place in our
privacy setting as a feature line and we
also calculate a percentage of the
privacy setting of view as a feature 10
since in user studies some participants
content that privacy setting and other
general settings mixed together it's
hard for them to single out a jacket one
as a more detailed features can be found
in our paper and after we designer 40
features we found two calculator
features we need to know the Europe the
privacy setting spray precise uipath so
Nestor how to extraction web has becomes
the key point to calculation of features
one may think dynamic of one may think
of dynamic analysis but this approach is
ten consuming and can only extract the
material number of UI passes window so
in our work we use a static to extract
way way statically extracted but is
still challenging due to the complexity
of the layouts design and the limitation
of Java language a static analysis such
as how to do is inherent so in our work
weight is a novel technique named a
semantic base to bypass abstraction it's
based on observation as a title has a
semantic connection with the indicator
user Creek the Siddha
web has example of the era paid each
texture of the indicator has the same
semantics with the title of a view after
Calicut so we live ridges the menus of
the indicator and views to build up the
connection between them and the way back
trace from the view placing the privacy
setting to the homepage and structure
the UI path so next way a detail how to
express this dimension from the
indicators and the views in app
indicators as to category two type of
category text and
I came for the text the text itself
provides best asthmatics and for that I
can we bridge the Google search engine
we upload images such as setting as a
figure showing and the Google's basket
says it might be a setting or idea so we
can know the semantics of icon and for
the view intuitively the title above you
can user for at least medics but if the
title if the view doesn't have title the
class enum and lay out file names such
as privacy setting totally out also may
have used as the views mannix so in this
way we can extract those methods of
indicators and abuse and build the
connections between them and extract a
given process that in the UI path we
developed our our to a hunt and use it
to analyze 170 apps from the real world
we found about 7,000 apps has about
18,000 process setting and in the seven
thousand apps nearly half of them have
hidden process setting and in the
privacy settings more than one third
more than one-third are difficult for
users to locate this results reveals
that in the real world the kingdom
professor setting is person massive and
we also study the problem to the
popularity from in a study we found in
an app with more increase it downloads
the app more of them have present
settings and in the meanwhile the app
with hidden fractionating increase an
educator an educated guess could be them
the developers of popular apps they may
pay more attention to the privacy
settings and they are more likely to
provide the make the settings more
explicit and we'll also study the hidden
privacy setting problem over time for
the 7000 apps we crowd the latest
version in a 20
and finally we've got about five
thousand ones and we after comparing
them we find some neo professor sitting
up here has some original privacy
setting disappear but the Sten use is
the hidden crevices team problem becomes
more serious not owning the such as the
figure show and not on in the app with
hidden privacy set him but also the
number and the percentage of hidden
privacy settings they all increase and
tourists donate some apps some apps
changed from easy to find in to hidden
in a new version after we look into them
and funded these apps increase the more
functionalities and corresponding
settings maybe it is because that it's
hard to balance the usability of that
and the control and privacy so that
developers do not even approach the set
him well but we are also happy to find
some as changed into easy to find in the
new version for example search has Baidu
map and BMW Motorrad they gathered the
previous schedule the privacy settings
such as in the tracking set of view and
legal notice view into users familiar
view not practice setting view we also
found this improve the apps or have a
large number of Eternals it appears as
again the popular apps attach more
importance to the designs of privacy
settings they are more likely to make
the privacy setting usability better and
over when the freedoms have the same
problem will be even more serious when
they ask the to leak users privacy by
default so we collect Randy collector
privacy settings to study and the
results has your astonishes 78
percentage alpha 2 leaked user privacy
and on our hidden privacy city a higher
percent in 82 percentage of them
virtually killers privacy and char
surprise 100 percent of hidden privacy
setting in
user social connection categories expose
users privacy by default and one more
thing we find an interesting thing that
some text look like they are protecting
users such as a showing a picture to not
show people I follow and groups I've
joined but the switch the setting is
switched off by default so in fact the
privacy exposed we in our way you know
randomly selected privacy setting data
cells we find that more than 220
percentage of them has this problem so
users may just leave the set in there
and do not change the switches Deportes
status and they may leak their privacy
without any consent so based on our
study we provide winner de 5 suggestion
for developers to design better user
usability of a practice setting such as
less set improvisation starts and Europe
has and finally less conclusion let's
summarize our conclusion in our study we
have new understanding of hidden
practice setting we summarize the
potential causes of hidden process
setting and reviews the significant
impact in a real world and our work can
help make helped design better usability
of a practice that in any has the
protection of the user protection and we
also provide a new technique to
automatically discover hidden privacy
settings we developed our hunt and it
helps us to a large study in the real
world there's for listening welcome
question
[Applause]
so if you have questions please come up
to the mic and your name in affiliation
please hi brian Mastan Burke Western
Digital did you evaluate how many of
these applications were available on a
European App Store or were otherwise
from vendors that would be subject to
gdpr sorry so I think many of the
settings examples you show would
potentially violate the European GDP our
regulation and so I'm wondering how many
of these examples were applications that
were potentially subject to GDP are
maybe the more popular applications that
seem to be cleaning up their privacy
settings were doing so for compliance
reasons yeah we we actually analyzed the
app and we evaluate this estate in Spain
and as a user study so we we we heard
them 200 people to evaluate to the
settings we the hidden perhaps a setting
we discovered yeah any other questions
so I have one I guess so with your
reviews you were doing a lot of user
feedback on you know this is hidden were
there anything surprising in terms of
what users actually liked in privacy
settings can you invert the analysis to
say these are the best practices that we
found from users sorry you focus mostly
on hidden privacy and things that users
found to be confusing or difficult to
find but the inverse you could also say
like what was good to users what did
they actually find was helpful with
privacy settings from the surveys that
you ran yeah sorry
I heard the first the the the first part
of the people find their processes in
the people to find that I didn't catch
your question I'll follow up offline
let's think again
[Applause]