hello good afternoon hope everyone had a
good lunch as men well said my name is
Emily stark I'm here from the chrome
security team and I'm gonna be talking
about work that I've done with
collaborators at Google and University
of Sarajevo and CloudFlare so imagine
that one day you go on the web to your
favorite search engine and you see a
security error like this you might think
that's pretty weird it's not every day
you see an error like this on a major
search engine but maybe you go about
your business and later that day you see
the same error on your bank website when
you're trying to pay some bills and then
you start to think things are a little
weird you go try to figure out what's
wrong and as you try to see what's up
with all these sick area security errors
you find the same error on some of your
favorite news websites and tech blogs
over the last several years a system
called certificate transparency has been
in the process of being rolled out
across the internet and if things have
gone wrong it could have resulted in an
experience like I just described for
millions or maybe even billions of users
with these scary arab pages on lots of
websites across the internet uh-oh my
slides are gone oh well so but instead
with the exception of a few kind of a
few hiccups the deployment of CT has
gone pretty much unnoticed by end-users
and in the process it's brought about a
pretty big improvement in the security
of the web by bringing accountability
and transparency into the issuance of
HTTPS certificates this paper that I'm
going to talk to you about today is a
measurement study of how CT has been
deployed in the real world looking at
things like its adoption and compliance
over time from different perspectives
and focusing on the end user impact in
terms of how much breakage or errors
users experience as a result of CT there
were many interesting design decisions
and a lot of nuance that went into the
deployment of CT and in the paper we
look at what what made those decisions
successful or unsuccessful and what the
lessons might be for future similar
stems in the first part of the talk if
you're wondering what this whole CT
thing is about I'll give you a little
bit of background about what CT is and
what some of the data sources are that
we use to measure it then I'll talk
about some of the metrics that we looked
at and in particular our metric of
interest is called the CT compliance
rate and finally I'll talk about some of
the aspects of CT that proved quite
challenging to deploy in the real world
so I'm not gonna go into a huge amount
of detail about what CT is so that I
have more time to talk about its
real-world deployment but at a very high
level CT is designed to enable the rapid
discovery of malicious or miss issued
certificates it's a system of public
cryptographically auditable logs which
are run by different stakeholders in in
the HTTP ecosystem so for example CAS or
browser vendors when certificates are
issued they get inserted into these logs
and the result from the log is so it's
called a signed certificate timestamp or
SCT and these SATs can be thought of as
verifiable promises that the certificate
will appear in this log so the end goal
of CT is eventually all certificates
come with these s CTS and all browsers
should verify these s CTS so that
certificates are only treated as trusted
if they have been logged in CT logs and
even though it isn't fully deployed yet
CT has already been a pretty big had a
pretty big effect on the HTTP ecosystem
discovering allowing auditors to
discover Mis issuances and other
issuance practices that need to be
corrected now as I mentioned CT is not
fully deployed and it's been in the
process of being deployed over many
years now and the point of this slide is
not that you should read everything on
it but that there have been all these
all these milestones in the deployment
of CT over several years so there has
not been and there will not be one major
flag day where a CT is required for all
websites by all browsers B
in practice that would likely lead to a
lot of errors and breakage so it's
instead it's been this this gradual
process of deployment and in the paper
we focus on how deployment has rolled
out in the Chrome web browser and we
focus on Chrome for two reasons
one is that we had access to telemetry
data from Chrome that we could use to
measure CTS adoption and the second
reason is that at the time of writing
chrome had the most advanced CT
implementation but since then Safari has
deployed a CT implementation and Firefox
also implements CT partially though it's
not not enabled by default in production
so in this work we measured CTS adoption
from a variety of different perspectives
and time periods our primary data source
as I mentioned was telemetry from Chrome
users but we also did some active scans
of popular websites and we did that to
characterize server-side support for CT
and we also did a qualitative analysis
of data from the chrome help forums
where we looked at users posting posting
help forum threads about CT errors that
they encounter so that we could try to
understand how they how they perceive
and understand CT related breakage so
the first question that we asked
ourselves in this work was how widely
has CT been adopted we found that at the
time of our measurements CT was
supported on 71% of HTTP requests in
Chrome so we thought this was pretty
cool because at this time CT was not
required for nearly this much traffic so
CT had been pretty widely adopted even
before it was required and in the paper
we do some analysis of why that is for
example 1600 of the Alexa top 10,000
supported CTS simply because they were
behind CloudFlare and CloudFlare enabled
CT for all of its websites by default
even though it wasn't required to this
adoption metric is what a lot of
previous work focuses on but we looked
at a different metric as our main metric
of interest and
what we called the CT compliance rate
the compliance rate is saying when
chrome requires a site to support CT
does it actually comply successfully and
the reason that this is our metric of
interest is because this is what
translates to end-user impact when a
site is required to support CT but is
not compliant
that's when users see breakage or errors
our main finding here was that at the
time of our measurements CT compliance
was quite high ninety-nine point seven
percent of the time that chrome required
a site to be CT compliant it was so
that's pretty good but I want to dive
into this a little bit more deeply and
convince you of a few interesting
properties of the CT compliance metric
first I want to convince you that
compliance is actually something we
should care about because low compliance
would be very very bad so just to remind
you comply low compliance means that
sites are not supporting CT when they're
required to meaning that users see
breakage or errors on those sites so
security errors like I showed at the
beginning of this talk are generally a
bad user experience there's lots of
prior research about why we want to try
to avoid security errors but they also
turn out to be particularly bad in the
case of CT when they're caused by CT so
for example we found that even though
these CT errors are pretty rare users
react to them badly they click through
them they ignore the error and proceed
to the site even though they're being
warned not to do that twice as often as
they do with certificate errors overall
and we try to avoid error click through
security error click through because it
is an indicator of users learning to
click through security errors and
becoming habituated to them we also
found that when we looked at help forum
posts about users encountering these CT
eras sixty percent of the time there was
an incorrect solution or explanation
attached to them and so in some cases
users are actually taking damaging or
destructive action to try to get around
these errors like clearing settings
disabling
extensions in some cases because can
actually be security negative actions
and we looked at the top ten websites
that are causing sea tiaras in Chrome
from our telemetry data and we
categorized them and found some pretty
upsetting categories like government
portables financial services these are
very important security sensitive sites
that users are encountering these errors
on so altogether we have security errors
caused by CT on important sites that
users don't understand don't understand
why they're happening or how to fix them
and that they're clicking through at a
much higher rate than certificate errors
overall so those are the reasons that we
particularly care about CT compliance as
a metric now the other thing that I want
to convince you of about CT compliance
is that it shouldn't be taken for
granted it's not automatically going to
be high just because Chrome says CT is
required for this website
doesn't mean that the website is going
to comply so we've seen several examples
of CAS or sites just implementing CT
incorrectly one example of this is in
2016 chrome began requiring CT for the
Symantec CA due to a pattern of CA
misbehavior when this requirement went
into effect Symantec offered this sort
of custom version of CT that wasn't
supported by browsers and they offered
this aimed at enterprise private domains
that didn't want their domain names to
appear publicly in CT logs unfortunately
a number of public popular websites
chose this option as well as
unintentionally and that resulted in
those sites temporarily breaking in
Chrome so this is an example of CT gone
wrong the kind of thing that can happen
that can actually cause compliance to
dip and this wasn't an isolated incident
we looked later on a couple years later
at the top web sites that were causing C
Tierra's in chrome and found that a
number of them were due to C A's
implementing CT just with bugs other
types of bugs or the C age is not
implementing CT at all despite chrome
requiring them to so knowing that we
care a lot about CT comply
and that it's not something that should
be taken for granted the paper dives
into a few of the design factors and
deployment considerations that we think
helps keep CT compliance high I'll give
one example here which is what we call
staged enforcement and I'm showing this
timeline again to illustrate that Chrome
has rolled out CT in a series of stages
as I described rather than one big flag
day where CT is just required for all
web sites all at once
so first Chrome began requiring CT for
evie certificates that was for to the
sort of the first stage of enforcement
evie certificates are extended
validation certificate they're a special
type of certificate that requires some
extra validation and is treated with
special browser UI so that was sort of
the first stage of CT enforcement the
first dipping of the toes in the water
subsequently chrome began requiring CT
for particular CAS
semantics as I as I talked about before
then there was this opt-in stage where
sites could opt in to CT enforcement for
the protection of their own users and
finally chrome began requiring CT for
all certificates issued after April 2018
which is where we are today
so in the paper we talked about how a
lot of these different stages
contributed to successful CT deployment
I'll give just a couple examples here if
we look at this evie enforcement stage
this was the very first way in which CT
was required for certificates and the
way that this enforcement mechanism
worked is that this evu I would be
dropped if the certificate didn't have
CT so it wasn't a full breakage or error
it was just the dropping of the the e v
UI now overall this enforcement stage
went pretty well I at any given time it
was less than 4% of connections that
lost their evu I do too due to the CT
requirement but we also learned from
this stage of enforcement that even
though CAS will implement CT when
required to they won't necessarily do it
Tribune Aversa Lee so
even after this this CT requirement
rolled out for Evy certificates we saw
that a number of CAS kept issuing Evy
certificates without CT even though
these certificates wouldn't work out of
the box in chrome so the lesson learned
from this stage is that CAS will
implement CTE when required to but not
all not not all in necessarily and so we
had to be mindful of that when
implementing future stages of CT
enforcement as another example I talked
about this opt-in stage where websites
could opt in to different levels of CT
enforcement in the browser one of the
levels that they could opt in to you was
a reporting mode so when chrome observes
a connection to these opted-in sites
chrome would just that doesn't have CT
chrome would just send a report to those
sites to say hey something's up you
think you're supporting CT but you're
not so in this in-between stage there
was a large website which you can see
here which discovered a Mis
configuration in how they were serving
SATs and when this configuration was
non-obvious they needed this reporting
mode to figure it to figure it out
basically the MIS configuration was that
the website began serving an SCT from a
new log that was trusted by chrome but
not yet widely distributed to all chrome
users yet so it was an update that was
still in the process of rolling out but
the website already had began serving an
SCT from that log and the result was
this very sizeable dip in a successful
CT adoption as measured by chrome but
because this happened during this
in-between optin reporting mode stage
this didn't result in any end user
impact and this miss configuration was
fixed before it did result in any
breakage or errors for users so I don't
want to claim that everything has been
sunshine and roses for CT there have
been many design decisions and
deployment considerations that can have
contributed to successful adoption but
there have also been some challenges one
example is the large implementation
investment
that CA requires from multiple
stakeholders in the ecosystem but
especially from browser vendors so I
mentioned that at the time of writing
chrome was the only browser that had a
mature CT implementation and this isn't
just a problem because it requires a lot
of resources from browsers it's a
problem because users don't get the
security benefits if they can just
switch to other browsers so in 19% of
the help forum threads that we looked up
users talked about how when they
encounter a CT error they just switch to
another browser and the site works there
because the site doesn't implement CT so
that means that even though chrome had a
CT implementation users weren't
necessarily getting the security
benefits of it and the large
implementation burden put on browser
vendors was getting in the way of users
getting the full security benefits of CT
to wrap up the talk I just want to give
a few tidbits of some of the other
things that we talked about in the paper
that I didn't have time to get into here
we looked at how CT adoption and
compliance has changed over time how
it's grown and what's what factors have
gone into that things like why popular
websites have adopted CT and why they
haven't we also dug more deeply into the
user impact looking at not just things
like the click-through rate and they use
their reactions to these errors but also
client-side performance costs and
finally we talked about some of the open
research problems that need to be solved
before a CT can be fully deployed and
achieve its full security benefits so I
think that CT is a very interesting
system technically but it's even more
interesting maybe to look at how it's
been deployed in the real world with
systems like this it's not always
obvious what to optimize for what
metrics to look at and our hope is that
by looking in depth at what has worked
and not worked so well for CT we can
bring out some lessons that can be
applied to other similar systems in
future Thanks
[Applause]
thanks for the great talk Emily probably
you have considered using a public city
log auditable for that using a
blockchain what are your thoughts on
that is it possible or what do you want
to do that what are the performance
issues have you have you considered it
well I'm not a designer of CT myself so
it's it's more a question for the CT
team I guess I think the question is
what exactly do you mean by blockchain
and what properties are you hoping to
get out of it because some people would
call the internal CT log structure a
blockchains no I mean literally a chain
of blocks for example using a theorem -
so taking advantage of the fact that a
theorem already has some proof of work
and blocks going on to store data there
so that we don't depend on a federation
but we can relax some of the security
guarantees some of the security
assumptions I think the proof of work
model does not fit particularly well
into CT but it's an interesting maybe
discussion to have offline perhaps on
like one of the CT design lists because
like i said i'm not a i'm i work on
chrome not the CT implementation itself
thank you thanks hi there Nicholas Allen
from Amazon so one of the early adoption
reasons for CT was for EB certificates
like you talked about and recently we've
kind of seen a decline in interest in
evey from certain sectors do you think
that the adoption of CT has kind of
reduced some of the need and use case
for EB certificates overall I think the
I think the the tying together of EB and
CT is now sort of dissipated because CT
is now required for practically all
certificates for all newly issued
publicly trusted certificates so I do
think they're sort of separate at this
point not tied together
however because as you said evey is sort
of on the dick
in some ways there is an interesting
question about if we were going to
deploy a system like CT again and Evie
was not widely used enough to make a
dent or if browsers dropped to their
Evie UI and that wasn't something that
could be used as a first enforcement
stage for something like this there's
kind of an open question about what what
we would do there there's no if there is
no more Evie to use as a first kind of
slice of certificates to to experiment
with enforcement
[Applause]