okay so hello I'm Ben I'm a PhD student
from ben-gurion University I'm here to
present drone script analysis a joint
work made with the help of husband at an
El profesor additional mill and
professor LaValle all of which my PhD
adviser so let's start and I want you to
have a look on this picture now can you
please tell me what is the drone that is
being boxed in yellow is being used for
is it being used for conducting the
privacy invasion attack or is it being
used for a legitimate purpose in this
case is taking a selfie is it B R C so
the answer is actually D it depends and
this is a real problem nowadays because
many operators now use drones to spy
after their spouses after their
neighbors after celebrities and even
after random people and this challenge
is even expected to get worse in the
near future because many businesses
around the world now adopt drones for
various purposes deliveries is only one
of them moreover legislation and
regulations are being changed in order
to support what we call an open skies
policy allowing drones to fly in
populated areas ok so we went to the
literature in order to check what is
what was suggested in order to detect a
privacy invasion attack and we actually
found that there are various geofencing
methods that were suggested over the
past few years such as radars and
cameras and even some hybrid methods and
these methods are able to detect the
presence of a nearby drone however let
me ask you the following question is
detecting the presence of a nearby
ground actually effective at detecting a
privacy invasion attack and the answer
is no because as I said earlier
the present is no longer restricted in
populated areas also even if you manage
to detect the drone does it necessarily
means that the drone is being used to
spy after the organization as you can
see in here
this two picture actually were taken
from the same location of the drone that
is being located that is being boxed in
yellow so the drones location doesn't
necessarily implies that the drone is
being used to spy after the victim after
a point of interest it's actually the
camera orientation that determines
whether it is being used for a
legitimate purpose or not so we actually
concluded that geofencing methods are
irrelevant for detecting a privacy
invasion attack in an open skies era
okay so our main objective is actually
detecting a privacy invasion attack and
let's go through the detection scheme we
actually assume that there is a malysh
malicious drone operator that operates a
Wi-Fi fpv drone and you use the drone to
spy after a victim that can be located
up to five kilometers from the malicious
drone operator now we assume that we
managed to using a radio receiver to
intercept the packets that are being
sent from the drone back to its
malicious operator and we also assume
that the victim is using some kind of a
gadget we don't name it watermark al and
I will explain what what what a market
is actually being useful in two or three
slides from now so for now let's talk
about Wi-Fi first-person view Channel
and Wi-Fi fpv channel actually intended
to provide two things one is to sling
the video stream for from the drone to
its operator and the second one is
actually to allow the operator to
maneuver the dome while it's up it's in
air in this study we actually
focus on the downlink which is the video
stream and when you are using Wi-Fi for
a Wi-Fi for a first-person view channel
you actually get the encryption only
just by using the Wi-Fi standout so you
get the encryption for free so it means
that the video stream is encrypted
however that's encryption ensures
confidentiality so again the answer is
no I wasn't here if the answer was yes
and let us talk about how first to
intercept an F PBS stream and most
specifically how we can intercept a
Wi-Fi network so we actually apply the
three stages we sniff Wi-Fi packets sent
from of a specific network you can do it
using applications such as l1 we're
extracting the time series signal from
the unencrypted metadata in the second
layer now indeed the payload is
encrypted however the metadata that we
are using is not encrypted which is the
the size of the packet now we use it in
order to extract the time series and we
done sample the the time series by
aggregating the time series in in a
fixed window it's actually makes me more
more faster so let us now talk how you
can classify a Wi-Fi network as fpv
channels so the key observation in here
is to understand that the Dome is
basically a flying camera now by
combining these tops of this algorithms
for moving device detection with
algorithms to come at a detection you
can actually classify a Wi-Fi network as
fpv channel and the way that we do it is
actually we managed to find that if you
take the intercept the bitrate signal
and analyze it
in the frequency domain the most
strongest magnitude actually corresponds
to the FPS rate so as you can see in
here
this was actually taken from one of the
dolls that we used and this will help
you actually to detect not only drones
but also cameras so how you can exclude
the cameras from the drones really are
using algorithms for moving object
detection this can easily be done by
analyzing the received signal and
vindication that is also present in the
in the Wi-Fi packet and combining these
two observation to a single algorithm
you be able to detect a drone within
three seconds with high accuracy and
very low a false positive rate okay so
after you manage to detect the flame per
second rate you actually get something
else for free which is the resolution
that is being video streamed that is the
that is being used for the video stream
and this is actually being done only by
dividing the the bits per second with
the frame per second you get the
resolution there are many calculators
online that can actually solve it to you
[Music]
okay so now let's move to the more
interesting part on how to detect
actually whether the fpd stream that you
classified is being used to videos to
him the victim to spy on a victim and in
order to do so i want you to have a look
on the third stage of the downlink which
is the video encoding the video
compression now this stage actually
follows the h.264 standards now for
those of you who are not familiar with
h.264 compression standards basically i
will summarize it in this way instead of
sending an entire frame a frame is
actually described as delta frames as
delta changes from another frame and
this information is being sent in this
structure a group of pictures structure
GOP structure so the result of using
this video compression algorithm is
basically if there are two consecutive
frames with high similarity
means that lower amount of data needs to
be encoded and sent to the drone however
if there is a big similarity between two
consecutive frames actually a bigger
amount of data needs to be encoded and
sent back to the to the drones operator
from the drone and having that in mind
we actually place the drone as you can
see in here in front of an LED board
this is the LED board was connected to
an Arduino and we actually used the LED
board as flicker we actually turn it to
a flea helps flicker as you can see in
here and intercepted the traffic that
was sent from the drone to the
controller now as you can see this is
the intercepted bit light signal over
time and it actually contains six
beautiful bursts every time that the
flicker changed from on to off and vice
versa so you can we actually concluded
that the flea Health's flickering LED
actually watermarks the six created the
six health phenomena in the intercepted
battery signal so understanding this we
actually managed to watermark each and
every frequency of the intercepted bit
light signal and by doing so you can
analyze the influence of how the
magnitude was changed as a result of
initiating a flicker in a given time and
by doing so you can decide whether you
can determine whether a drone is being
directed to a flicker now if the flicker
is actually located nearby the victim it
means that you can imply that the drone
is actually being used to spy after the
victim okay so for now you understand
how to classify a suspicious radio
transmission as fpv Channel and how to
detect whether the fpv channel is
actually being used to spy after the
victim however with a big sorrow great
sorrow I can
I won't be able to explain you how to
locate the drone in space by analyzing
the intercepted bitrate signal I didn't
manage to squeeze it into a 16 minute
stalk so the details are on the paper
you are invited to read it you will
invite it to estimate in the question
episode afterwards ok so we have a
flicker and we want to hide it from the
drones operator in order to not raise
this suspicion that something is
happening and we actually analyze
several ways in order to achieve it
however the way that we find as most
effective was flickering between two
similar use instead of just turning it
on and off flicker in between two
similarly news that their only
difference is actually in the brightness
component and this actually satisfies
the following requirements it's actually
exploits the inability of the human eye
to distinguish between two similar use
it's also so it means undetectable by
direct observation it means that if the
operator will look at the flicker you
won't be able to detect it it also it's
undetectable by indirect observation it
means that even if you will look on it
via the controller you want to be able
to detect it and as you can see in here
it does watermarks the intercepted fpv
channel okay so I want to show you we
wanted to test our method in real
scenarios and in order to do it we
actually applied it to a victim that is
on the move
actually driving in a car and a static
victim that is actually located in its
living room and let me show you the
demos here you can see a siren that is
actually flickering in
specific frequency I think it's three
point three point nine Hertz and the
victim is inside the car and here we
used a smart film as a flicker as you
can see the flickering window it is
installed on the window we use it as a
flicker now for each of these scenarios
we also recorded a legitimate use of the
drone and we did it by locating the
drone 180 degrees from the from the
house and from the car we call it a
legitimate use now we wanted to evaluate
at our method on on the intercepted bit
light signal in each of the cases and we
fixed the to positive way to 1.1 1.0 it
means that all the privacy invasion
attacks should be detected and as you
can see inhale in about two-and-a-half
seconds we were able to detect privacy
invasion attack with very low false
positive rate this is how the
spectrograms looked like when the
flicker was on okay something I'm about
to I'm about to get to the end so some
additional information that can be found
in the paper you will be able to find
the exact details on how to locate how
to locate the spine grown in space just
by analyzing the intercepted bitrate
signal and we do it with only a single
Wi-Fi receiver you will be able to read
about the countermeasure methods about
the analysis of the impact of ambient
factors which are wind and ambient light
and other methods that we considered for
hiding the flicker and the exact details
of the experiments that I described in
this talk
the preliminary version of this paper
which actually presents a method on how
to detect a privacy invasion attack
using
time domain analysis instead of
frequency analysis as I described in
Hill is on the Alki we named it back
then a year and a half ago game of
drones in order to get some good PR
however considering the latest course of
events I might have to change the name
of game of drones in order to maintain
some good PR ok so I want you to on
behalf of a cyber let BG you I'd like to
thank you all for attending this talk
you can find us just by looking cyber at
bgu this is my twitter account you can
find more of our works in there and this
is the paper website and i think that
this is about the time to take questions
thank you so again we have time for few
questions
can you please go to the mic hi I'm
Chris from UCSB a couple of questions
you said the Flickr would not be visible
but it showed in the videos what's up no
in the videos we didn't we didn't intend
to to hide it but there's a video in the
picture and it shows how you can hide we
actually figure with the smart bulb
between two similar use and it's not
detected to the human eye so you can
find it by the way there are photos in
the paper that show you the how the use
are similar and you won't be able to
understand that there are that there is
a difference between them okay cool and
the second one is when you set the
experiments or the false positives the
drone was facing like exactly away from
from yeah 180 degrees for the other side
so what about the scenario that you
described were you actually were spying
on the room and the drone was like the
legitimate use was it was looking down
right no maybe it had some reflection
from walls that it would pick up ah
regarding the reflection so basically
when you are looking at the room we use
the smart film this is not even a
flicker which
creates light so there is no in this
case there there is no chance that to
get reflections from a smart film
however in all of our experiments using
an LED we did not get any you know false
positive as a result of the reflections
that were somehow yes yeah interesting
work so I was wondering on the
robustness of the of the approach and in
particular Hawaii did you change from
timing base to frequency based analysis
and I was wondering if it was based on
the on the like the false positives that
you might be able to get because at
least in timing analysis I would I would
expect that unless the scene is very
steel like if the drone has is like
looking at a street that has a lot of
people moving across then the timing and
I'll here is probably going to be very
similar to the flicker analysis now in
there because it's yeah basically you
ask and give that proper answer when you
are using time domain analysis there is
a larger kind of false positive light as
a result of some other things that
happening during the time that you are
trying to apply the flicker link so when
you are using frequency domain analysis
things are getting more neater and
cleaner because you can exactly look for
the frequency that you want in order to
understand whether privacy invasion
attack is actually conducted so it makes
things more clearer and as you can see
in the as I showed you in the experiment
of the car the extent of the car I don't
believe that can be detected using time
domain analysis there is too much noise
my point yeah okay
there was also been some work on trying
to sort of like you see visuals
challenges to identify or example if
they if the camera is looking at the
right place but it was it was a
different kind of scenario was on
authenticating the image like sort of
like verifying that I'm indeed looking
at at one area and not
sort of like the typical Hollywood
attack where the attacker is replaying
the old video from yesterday and it's
not there so it might be worth to take a
look
thanks thank you okay so let's think
been again thank you very much
[Applause]