all right good morning everyone welcome
to the fortieth I Tripoli security and
privacy symposium I'm your general chair
mark gondry thank you for all being here
this is a truly exciting year oh I have
a thing that lets me advance slides
sorry about that
welcome to San Francisco this is our
40th year we are here for the second
time at the Hyatt Regency San Francisco
we're in the middle of a multi-year
contract with this space and we're
excited to be making great use of this
iconic hotel this is a truly exciting
year it's our 40th symposium so it's an
anniversary year for us according to the
I Triple E it's a debatable among our
community if we should celebrate it this
year or next year but this is our 40th
symposium and we are celebrating that it
was an amazing program we have a
tremendous program we accepted 84 papers
which is a huge increase relative to
last year what a giant exciting program
we have this year we have astounding
attendance our tenses up relative to
last year we have broken another record
in terms of you all in this room today
we awarded more travel grants to
students than ever before an astounding
increase to support to our students to
come to this event and we saw a greater
donor participation than ever before
sort of huge donor turnout gigantic
thanks to our generous donors for
supporting our travel grants program and
the symposium and all of this really
couldn't be possible without an amazing
set of volunteers in this community that
used their time to try to make this
program together so please join me in
thanking the amazing organizing
committee that worked for like over a
year and a half to bring this together
thank you to all of you and thank you
especially to our technical committee
who provided more guidance than ever to
us as we worked with our program growth
and our 40th celebration so Thank You
shaunell far young and EJ for helping us
this year thank you to our donors our
gold donors our platinum donors ARL
Microsoft and NSF if you are supported
by a student travel grant it is likely
due to the support of ARL and NSF
especially so please thank them if you
see them if you receive support for
travel grants thank you thank you to our
Gold donors our recurring support from
our Gold donors has extremely
appreciated a vast Cisco Facebook Google
thank you and thank you to our silver
donors who I couldn't fit them all in
the slide easily so they're gonna appear
one by one so I get them in the right
order Baidu cert sei IBM Research Intel
cows the King Abdullah University of
Science tech technology
Lincoln MIT Lincoln labs the NSA onr
Palo Alto Networks Symantec visa
research and VMware thank you to our
silver sponsors an amazing turnout
thank you to our bronze sponsors long
time dedicated support from IAI our new
sponsor siege technologies as well as
thank you - now publishers river
publishers and Springer and also thank
you for in kind support from the I
Triple E security and privacy magazine
on our 40th page there's actually a link
to a special offer from my Tripoli
security and privacy magazine so show
your support and interest in the
magazine and sign up they're giving us
some free articles in support of our
40th anniversary thank you security
privacy magazine we have an amazing
program events it's a huge program
tonight is the poster reception it's in
the atrium it's not downstairs this year
it's upstairs where we had breakfast in
the middle of the poster reception you
can take your drink and go on over to
short talks it's on the same level it's
just basically adjacent to the poster
session toward the end of the poster
reception is our speed mentoring we
moved it earlier this year to try to
make those connections with mentors
earlier to try to enjoy them all week
long Tuesday we have our paper awards in
the morning and then in the afternoon
session mattias payer our 40th and a
celebration chair has crafted a kind of
really exciting session in which we have
a panel moderated by Giovanni Vigna Deb
Frankie Peter Newman de Kemmerer
and Dorothy dining astounding sort of
fan favorites we actually kind of
surveyed all past organizers and said
who do you want to hear from under 40th
and we had a big list some names kept
reoccurring we asked those names they
all said yes it's an amazing panel after
that we're going to start a new
tradition we're having our first test of
time awards in which we celebrate things
that results from Oakland that have
withstood the test of time after that
we're going to have a light reception
we're gonna reflect and connect and
celebrate and have some cake and then
after that is our technical committee
meeting and as a reminder everyone is
invited to come back
and go to our Technical Committee
meeting then on Wednesday after the
final session we have a bridging
reception that everyone from the
workshops and the symposium is welcome
to attend and after that on Thursday is
our workshops we have five awesome
recurring workshops and programs for all
the workshops are online and also in
your printed program this week we have a
scavenger hunt it's part of our four-day
celebration
mattias is set up jeopardy style CTF
that is filled with Oakland themed
trivia and challenges and it starts
today the link on our 40th page is
active you can jump online now and
create a user ID and start answering
trivia questions there are some hidden
flags in your program there are some
interactive things we have to take
photos of people to be really fun
there's a leaderboard at the end of the
event on Wednesday at noon we're gonna
close down the scavenger hunt the top 40
people on the leaderboard will win a
very exclusive 40th anniversary souvenir
I say very exclusive because we're not
gonna make them ever again and they are
what they are they're kind of fun little
mugs but also bragging rights that's
what we actually do it for right
bragging rights so please participate
some reminders and announcements the
media all the papers for this are on the
online compendium they're available at
that link it's also on the back of your
badge
we're video recording as many talks of
speakers allow us to and they'll be
posted to YouTube shortly after the
conference please participate online
with Twitter use the hashtag SP 19 and
send things at I triple ESP will retweet
them and let's keep this kind of
extended into cyberspace so that people
who couldn't make it know how awesome
this is and can be extremely jealous of
what we're enjoying
especially photographed food everyone
food pictures some notes from the hotel
after our plenary sessions many of them
are going to transition the room into
two so like a that the break here will
be transitioning into two sessions to
get our dual track so we can feature
this giant program the room transition
might encounter a hotel staff asking you
if you could kind of get out of the way
as they transition in the room don't
take offense
they're just trying to get you back in
session as quickly as possible so you
might be asked to move seating in each
of the two rooms is maximized for this
setup so we can't bring in more chairs
and we can't move chairs from room to
room so we have to help each other out
as a community take your bags off chairs
help people identify where their open
seats do not be afraid to walk to the
front of the room to get an open seat if
the session has already begun we have to
kind of help each other out to maximize
the use of both rooms because it might
be tight you have huge attendance and
some sessions might be more popular than
others also just as a note a couple
inches outside the glass that way is
downtown San Francisco we are
essentially on the street level of
downtown San Francisco we are in an
unsecured public space where people can
wander in from the street and do the
nature of this being a popular venue for
conferences this is a target of
professional thieves who dress like
conference goers and steal laptops and
cell phones be aware of your things this
isn't a problem that can be fixed by
security they look just like us don't
leave your things unattended have a
friend watch them secure them away and
take them with you and also the same
with at meals we've asked the hotel Dole
check for badges so you might be asked
to show your badge before you get into
breakfast or a meal please don't take
offense they've been asked to do this
it's a way to preserve the part of the
most expensive part of your registration
fee the food and beverage also a
correction our program has a misprint
many of our papers went through ethical
disclosure processes and we're embargoed
for a period of time so the online
program just had titles redacted
we unredacted them as of last night and
so the titles appeared all of the
unredacted titles are in your printed
program but sadly these two papers had a
typo in our printed program we mixed up
the titles so big apology to the authors
that like the lbm paper is in session 11
and is not in session 1 I apologize the
author's that we mixed up their paper
titles and as a final reminder the code
of conduct that we enacted last year to
make sure that this is a professional
and enjoyable environment for all of our
conference attendees is kind of we're
maturing our policies to meet our values
this year you'll notice attendees who
have a white ribbon that says code
steward we have a number of volunteers
who are acting this year to help us with
our code of conduct violations so if you
see something that you perceive to be a
code of conduct violation you can call
that number it'll reach all of our code
stewards or you can go to the
registration desk and ask to contact a
code steward and that person will help
out take a report try to mediate and
help enforce our code conference code of
conduct as we go to a multitrack this is
more than a one-person job so I'm
extremely grateful to our code stewards
who are helping us this year make sure
that this is a professional enjoyable
environment for all and that we actually
have procedures that meet our values and
with that I am happy to introduce your
2019 program chairs
Christopher Krug 'el and hove F shotgun
but Christopher kugel will be presenting
thank you
[Applause]