it is 2019 and we still hear such news
as Facebook accidentally realizing they
had been storing plaintext passwords for
millions of users Google closing its
social network platform last month after
data leaks among other concerns and last
year records of the Indian national
identity database being exposed every
year hackers managed to be breached
through security differences and access
valuable information of millions of
people
a study from IBM estimated that the cost
of data breaches was around 2 billion
u.s. dollars among 500 companies
worldwide just in the last year tame
tracking is a solution that detects and
defends against information leaks by
monitoring dynamic executions so it
tames sensitive user data tracks teams
throughout execution and then prevents
stains from flowing in to untrusted
channels train tracking has three
components sources propagation and syncs
sources identify well sensitive data
enter the program state and mark them
with tapes so for example program
arguments input from keyboard or data
from the file system of the network can
be typically tamed sources the
propagation policy defines how to
compute paints for values that are
derived from sensitive data
so typically taints explains propagate
explicitly via operations that are data
dependent on tainted data so for example
x equals HX + y here X will be tainted
by secret and white but taints can also
propagate implicitly for example by a
control flow dependence so here we see
operations that are control dependent on
the tainted secret and with implicit
propagation distant also flows to the
result of all operations inside the
condition well implicit propagations are
rarely used in practice because they
lead to over tainting and so we only
focus on explicit flows and finally
sinks our program locations where we
check the taint state so for example
data being sent over the network should
not contain certain types of things by
adapting the source sink and propagation
policies taint tracking has been useful
in several domains for example
preventing buffer overflow command
injection of cross-site scripting
attacks detecting information leaks and
also in software engineering for testing
debugging and other program analysis but
despite is useful applications live
train tracking on production
systems has been challenging due to its
performance overheads so a nice dynamic
monitoring approach would have to
instrument each instruction to look up
the taint of its operands compute the
taint propagation and then modify the
taint state so in our example here for
the first instruction X equals Z plus 3
we monitor taint of x equals taint of Si
and constants are never really tainted
next secret is a taint source in our
example and for the assignment y equals
secret we explicitly transfer the taint
of secret to taint of Y next inside the
F block where we compute Z as C
multiplied by Y we monitor taint of Z
equals taint of C or taint of Y meaning
Z can be tainted by both C and y and
again for the assignment we explicitly
transfer the tails so these are all our
taint tracking monitors additionally
since the tainted value out can reach
the sink that is the print statement the
analysis has to check the taint of out
before performing this operation so all
this additional work amounts to huge
slowdowns primarily due to the metadata
tracking operations now most programs
are mostly correct and a majority of
instructions would not propagate in
streams in their correct dynamic
executions so many of these taint
monitors are actually unnecessary and a
static analysis can alight some of the
unnecessary monitors so for example here
it can reason that the first instruction
would never propagate think because
because both its operands C and the
constant value are never going to be
tainted
so if static analysis can prove that an
instruction never propagate stains using
dataflow analysis we can elect tracking
teams for such operate operations the
static analysis is sound but as I will
show you next
it is imprecise unscalable and
ineffective in reducing the overall
dynamic overheads now in order to be
sound static analysis needs to consider
all possible program states but
computing this exact set of possible
behaviors is undecidable so it
conservatively considers an over
approximation of the possible States
including many infeasible States as a
result the analysis becomes very
imprecise and unscalable this is a
fundamental limitation of traditional
sound static analysis optimistic hybrid
analysis
a new technique that attempts to
mitigate this imposition problem so it
it observes a few tested program states
and then predicates the static analysis
by using invariants learnt on those
states these invariants are properties
that are otherwise very hard to prove
statically but almost always hold
dynamically and by assuming them the
static analysis significantly reduces
its state space thereby making it
precise and scalable but careful design
is still needed for soundness when a
case when a state outside the predicated
analysis is encountered so looking back
at our example if the variable P always
takes non-negative values in all useful
executions the static analysis can
assume this invariant to induce more
aggressive optimizations so assuming the
if block never executes it can reason
that why stain would never flow forward
to Z and then out and so on so it can
alight those taint monitors further
using backward reach ability it can
reason that why stain would never reach
the sink that is the print statement and
illite tracking that as well so this
simple assumption allows us to alight
all the taint monitors in our example so
this predicated analysis is much more
precise targeted to the common case
behavior and scalable optimistic hybrid
analysis works as follows it profiles
the target program to gather invariants
that hold in most dynamic runs the
static analysis then assumes these
invariants predicating its state space
thereby improving precision and
delighting many more dynamic monitors
and the optimized dynamic analysis then
executes so the property that we assumed
in our example translates to the
highlighted code block not being
executed this is in fact our simplest
type of lightly invariant unreachable
code views to other types of invariants
that deal with function pointed Colley's
and function call contexts as long as
these invariants do not fail in an
execution the analysis outcome is the
same
as the conservative sound approach but
what happens if an invariant fails so in
our example we started with the tainted
secret shown here in the taint set and
after we execute yko secret originally
we
Tainted why as well but using the
optimistic assumptions we alighted
tracking one if the invariant table
failed and we execute Z equals Z times y
now we have no idea if Y is tainted as a
result we lose tracking the stain flow
and Y can now propagate to Z and out and
leak without being detected so when the
invariant failed the problem is that
eliding y stained monitor resulted in
losing y's tainted State and that would
require us to roll back to recover this
last analysis metadata state so the
dynamic analysis needs to be able to
detect when an invariant violates and
then recover the analysis in order to be
sound so we need to add dynamic
invariant validation checks for the
detection and a recovery mechanism that
can correct the effect of the
incorrectly lighted monitors and then
resume will be correctly optimized
analysis so the question is how do we
recover the analysis well because you
could have lost essential metadata state
anywhere in your program prior work
conservatively rolls back and reacts
Acutes from the beginning well this
approach works for offline postmortem
kind of analysis we cannot tolerate roll
backs on live production systems
bounding the roll back window is hard
for whole program analysis because an
invariant failure anywhere could have
affected in missing metadata state as
early as at the beginning of the program
so you have unbounded roll backs and you
end up going back to the beginning but
even if you could bound it all back
window supporting roll backs incurs
additional check pointing and logging
overhead even during normal execution
other than the actual roll back replay
costs
so to recap pure dynamic monitoring is
obviously very expensive conservative
hybrid analysis is imprecise and
therefore inefficient optimistic hybrid
analysis improves precision by assuming
likely program invariants but roll back
in case an invariant violates remains
challenging for live production systems
so we need to eliminate roll backs in
order to apply or a child to live
systems so the role that issue has
essentially due to potentially missing
metadata state instead if we make sure
that we never miss any metadata that is
somehow we correctly maintain the exact
metadata state as in a conservative
sound analysis upon an invariant
violation
the recovery mechanism can simply switch
to the conservative analysis and
continue forward if the predicated
analysis can prove that a monitor does
not update the analysis metadata state
it essentially becomes unknown so for
example if we have a tenth monitor of
this type tenth of Y constant of public
where the value public is never really
tainted this taint monitor would not
modify the taint State if we were to
alight this monitor even if we encounter
a subsequent invariant violation that
would not affect the elation of this no
op monitor because the taint State is
unaffected we would not need a rollback
to correct the effect of the solution so
by restricting the predicated static
analysis to only perform safe Elysion of
no op monitors guarantees that the
analysis metadata state is exactly the
same as in a conservative sound analysis
and that in turn guarantees that the
outcome of all analysis checks are
correct this is our key insight so
looking back at our example remember we
had assumed the invariant that the if
block never executes so if Z is not
tainted the taint monitor for out will
not add tame to out and we still only
have secret and wiring the taint set if
we were to alight the state monitor
people end up with exactly the same time
set and that is the reason this elation
is safe under the assumed in very and if
the invariant table failed we would have
detected so and switched to the
conservative analysis without missing
any metadata so Alicia's induced using
predicated forward analysis are safe and
they keep the correct metadata state now
we could have also elided the taint
monitor for y because we reasoned it did
not reach the sink but while having this
taint monitor adds secret and Y to the
taint set if we were to alight this
taint monitor the metadata state would
diverge and we would lose the taint of Y
if there was an invariant failure at
this point the analysis would have to
roll back to recover this last analysis
state so this illusion is unsafe and we
have to keep this taint monitor so the
forward recovery mechanism essentially
leads to reactivate the monitors that
were optimistically elided this works as
follows we have two versions of the
program instrumented in separate control
flow domains the fast path with the
optimistic analysis and the slow path
with the conservative analysis execution
begins in the fast path domain and upon
an invariant violation simply switches
to the conservative slow path domain and
continues forward this switching is safe
because the two versions only differ in
their analysis logic and moreover safe
elations guarantee the correct metadata
state at the point of invariant failure
additionally when returning from a
function call if there was an invariant
violation in the callee the caller
should also switch to be conservative
slow path so we implement iodine using
the LLVM compiler infrastructure for c
programs it implements two variants of
hybrid plain cracking the conservative
analysis uses pointer and data flow
analysis to identify instructions that
propagate times and only instrument them
using a state-of-the-art pure dynamic
tracking framework LLVM state of flow
sanitizer and the rollback free
optimistic variant performs profiling
followed by predicated pointer analysis
and the taint analysis uses predicated
forward reach ability combined with
conservative backward corage ability the
resulting dynamic analysis is more
optimized and we also had the invariant
checks as a recovery mechanism we
evaluate for two different information
flow security policies for email
integrity on the post fix mail servers
for example the DML body is sanitized
and encrypted and against overwrite
attacks on the nginx web server so for
example that derivatives of user
provided values and not used as return
address ease function pointers format
strings we observe cadres of magnitude
speed-up over pure dynamic monitoring in
an average of four point four times
speed up over conservative tracking now
this improvement really comes from the
precision of the predicated static
analysis and we look at a few more eggs
using generic policy this graph here
shows the fraction of instructions that
are instrumented by the stack
conservative static analysis and after
assuming the likely invariants iodine
elides instrumenting almost half of the
monitors
finally a key question is how much
profiling is needed in order to see the
optimistic benefits and we observe that
profiling on existing software test
suits is adequate for reducing the
analysis overheads so these graphs show
how the dynamic analysis time varies
with more time spent in profiling and we
observe that the dynamic overheads
reduced generally with more profiling
and the reason is that the numbers on
the graph indicating the total number of
invariant violations encountered reduces
significantly with more profiling
now our profiling methodology is split
in two phases first in the left unshaded
part of the graphs we run on existing
regulation test suits to learn
invariance this alone turns out to be
yielding most of the performance
benefits that is so because testing
ideally attempts to exercise most
realistic program behaviors and then we
also further run on a few more profile
inputs representing beta tests to see
the full benefits of our optimistic
analysis so to conclude iodine enables
practical low overhead pain tracking
using optimistic hybrid analysis which
can make such expensive dynamic analysis
much faster by assuming likely program
invariance but this leads to a major
problem that is unbounded rollbacks in
case the invariants fail this is
critical for running on life executions
we fix this by restricting to only safe
elations thereby enabling fast aim
cracking with correct semantics without
requiring rollbacks
we also show that profiling on existing
test suits is adequate for most of the
performance benefits thank you for
listening and I will answer your
questions now
[Applause]
a very nice talk and we have plenty time
for questions so please you favor if you
have questions please come to the
microphone
Herbert boslough SEC Amsterdam nice talk
I have a few questions and comments
perhaps so first of all I I'm always a
little concerned when the case for taint
analysis is made from the viewpoint of
data leak it's by attackers I think this
is really problematic right because as
you mentioned you don't take into
account implicit flows and if you have
an attacker it's actually really easy to
create implicit flows or you know
pointer pointer tracking or what have
you so I'm a little concerned there
always and the other thing is perhaps a
comment or a question did you compare it
to some of the the faster taint analysis
approaches so you compare it to one that
has an overhead of I think between five
or eight acts or so but even on binary
ones are faster ones right
did you actually look at those okay so
today's point in your first question
about implicit propagation our technique
is broadly applicable to implicit
provocations as well but we do not
explore them because it turns out that
if you have a large fraction of your
program state tainted the benefits of
optimistic analysis and even a
conservative static analysis it reduces
that is true with even conservative
sound static analysis oh you know it
would explode anyway yes yes it would be
impractical and that is the reason we do
not look at implicit propagations
regarding your question so there are
broadly two ways that you can reduce the
overhead of dynamic gain cracking first
is by reducing the number of actual
monitors that you execute and the second
completely orthogonal direction would be
to reduce the that overhead of each
individual monitor so our focus is on
the first problem if we could prove that
monitor is unnecessary we would
remove that but it turns out that
proving that statically is hard so we
make assumptions that let me lead us
prove this property for most of the
instructions and we also handle those
cases where those assumptions go wrong
we take care of the recovery mechanisms
so existing techniques that improve the
overhead of each individual monitors
would be orthogonal to our work and we
could combine those techniques to
further improve the overhead of pain
tracking but but I think that would have
been a good baseline yes
Munich I have a question and the
question is actually quite technical
time if if it's very time-consuming to
answer we should take it offline
afterwards but the question is basically
the solution should require all the
analysis that you already need to
basically add the code that you would
alight into the paths that you're
excluding so in your example do you for
instance you alight a check that you
could easily move into the if statement
so that seems to me would be the easiest
thing to avoid going back to another
safe analyzed version and so either my
idea is so stupid that you already
thought about it and it doesn't work in
case I would be interested in your
answer or there may be an interesting
optimization opportunity there so I
think for the simple example that I had
on my slides as you pointed out you
could have easily merged the paint
monitor for the following instructions
inside the f-block
and if that is the case we are assuming
the invariant that the if block is never
executed so it it is meaningless to
alight that paint monitor but in general
with the whole program analysis you
would not be able to bound the effect of
an invariant assumption so if you make
an assumption it could enable you to
induce optimizations much earlier in
your
Flo so you could have optimizations
induced using invariant that take effect
much earlier in your program so in that
case
the ability to merge the program the
ability to merge monitors would no
longer be cool I think it's a different
question but it's probably good to take
it offline okay all right thank you
let's thank the speaker one more time
[Applause]