hi I'm Matthew Jocelyn and I'm from the
University of Texas at Dallas today I'll
be presenting my paper measuring and
analyzing search engine poisoning of
linguistic collisions this is joint work
with my adviser Shuang Chow and our
collaborators young Lee and house and
Zhu from Shanghai Shanghai Jia Tong
University and Minho Sharif from
Macquarie University so search is very
important to the web when a user wants
to find a page even one that they
visited before they often won't search
enter the URL or domain name instead
they often use a search engine to search
for the keyword for example if you've
needed to find the ESPY conference
program over the past three days you
probably just search for the keyword in
fact most of us probably can't remember
the URL not surprisingly a majority of
web traffic comes from search and up to
ninety percent of users stop searching
after the first page websites know that
search is important so they carefully
optimize their sites to return remain on
the first page of results as a result
the great ranking on the first page of
results is very difficult for popular
terms users also make spelling mistakes
when typing in their searches for
instance if a user wants to search from
Adobe and they accidentally swapped the
last two characters they may actually
search for a misspelling adversaries
have known for a long time that this is
a problem and so they've targeted
misspellings in search engine
optimization for instance
Snickers targeted a variety of
misspellings in their search ad campaign
you're not you when you're hungry and
Amazon was recently ordered to stop typo
targeting misspellings and Birkenstocks
a German shoe retailer to help improve
the user experience and to protect users
from type of typos the search engines
have introduced auto correction and auto
suggestion defenses these defenses help
improve the user experience and they
warn the user that their search query
may be misspelled they may even it
odd edit the search results if they have
high confidence so for instance if a
user searches for miss Dobie and they
accidentally swap the last two
characters the search engine has high
confidence that they actually meant to
search for the company name Adobe and so
they change all of the search results to
B for Adobe similarly if a user searches
for a Dobek by appending a C to the word
Adobe and the search engine has medium
confidence that they meant to search for
Adobe they may only change the first
result in Adobe and only warn the user
that the search query may be misspelled
finally if a user misspells Adobe by
replacing and Oh with au and the search
engine has low confidence they may not
change any of the results and instead
ask the user did you mean Adobe these
all of these different types of
Defense's offers some sort of protection
to the user either they warn the user or
they even change the users search
results these defenses seem to be
effective as we observed spammers on
underground forums complaining that
these defenses have made misspelling SEO
much more difficult to avoid these
automated Corrections by search engines
attackers can employ a new type of
attack which we term linguistic
collision misspellings these
misspellings can avoid automated
defenses because they coincide with
existing words even in other languages
for instance if a user searches for
cialis and deletes the a they may
actually search for sillas which the
search engine won't autocorrect this is
because sillas is an existing word in
the esperanto language meaning Chili's
however the search user will not be
shown results that were related to
Chili's instead they'll be shown a
variety of different URLs that are
advertising cialis in fact they may even
see advertisements that were purchased
by advertisers to promote cialis or they
may see illicit pharmaceutical websites
which managed to achieve high rank for
this
to understand how widespread linguistic
collisions are we analyzed the two most
popular languages on the Internet
English and Chinese for English we
looked at the Google search engine and
which has the highest market share and
we looked at the Baidu search engine
which has the which is the most popular
search engine for Chinese speakers we
also looked at to understand how
prevalent these active or active
attacker activity is across different
types of keywords we looked at the Alexa
10k names and we checked for English and
then we also wanted to understand what
types of keywords attackers may target
so we looked at 13 different categories
for English and Chinese so in English we
looked at four different spin English
and Chinese we looked at four different
spam related categories the drugs adult
and gambling and software so these are
typical targets for spammers that we
thought they may continue to a target in
linguistic collision attacks so for
instance in English we looked at cialis
the popular drug and poker a gambling
game and in Chinese we looked at dama
which means marijuana and mahjong the
popular gambling game we also looked at
nine other types of categories which
include popular product names and brand
names because we believe these terms
could be also be targeted by attackers
similar to what Amazon did so now that
we have our set of target keywords we
can look at the generating the
misspellings using a variety of
different processes for both languages
once we have the misspellings we can
check on the search engines to see which
terms will not be Auto corrected and
avoid the defense's and finally after we
know which search results are not auto
corrected we can check on a public
blacklist to see which ones are poisoned
so for English it's relatively
straightforward to generate misspellings
we can use the Demerol Levenstein edit
distance one operations these
was to insert a character replace a
character transposed two characters or
delete a character
so in particular we limited the
replacement operations to the adjacent
keys on a QWERTY keyboard we also looked
at the vowel replacement operations
because we believe users may
accidentally misspelled the word and
these words also have a higher chance of
still being existing words in another
language so for Chinese so brute force
checking all of these different
generated misspellings is a bit
time-consuming we don't want to check
all of the Alexa 10k generated
misspellings as that's going to require
a lot of different searches and although
you might expect that we could just
check dictionaries these dictionaries
have poor coverage for things like slang
product terms and some languages have
poor coverage just in general so we
introduce a character level recurrent
neural network to predict which
misspellings will not be Auto corrected
by the search engine we train this
network with existing words and
dictionaries and then we are able to
predict the probability distribution of
the next character and a sequence of
work characters so for Chinese the
situation is a bit different Chinese
users use pinyin input as a main method
for searching on Baidu the pinyin input
method allows users to type Chinese
words using the English alphabet so we
can use the Demerol Evan Stein at a
distance one operations that we
mentioned previously however we can also
use some more interesting properties of
Chinese to generate other types of
misspellings
for instance the same pinyin can map to
different words and different tones can
map to different characters for instance
mahjong with the same pronunciation can
either mean a tile-based game or sesame
sauce we can also look at the fuzzy
opinion because there's multiple
dialects in Chinese some users may not
be able to distinguish
similar-sounding sounds and so fuzzy
pinyin allows these users to enter
similar sounding consonants and vowels
interchangeably so we use these
substitutions to generate other types of
misspellings because the pinyin input
method requires that a misspelled
Chinese word still be an existing
Chinese word for the Chinese data set we
can simply check to see whether it is in
a Chinese dictionary so now that we have
our set of input misspelled keywords
we're going to check on Google and Baidu
to see which terms will not be Auto
corrected after we know which ones are
not auto corrected we can check across
virustotal to see which ones are
blacklisted we also check to see the
search volumes and the device types of
users who are searching for these terms
on Google Adwords and Baidu index and
finally to understand why search engines
may fail to auto corrects English
searches we checked using Google
Translate to see what languages they are
identified as so overall we collected
just under 1.8 million
misspelling keywords and we found that
for misspellings which aren't auto
corrected by search engines that is
linguistic collision misspellings just
under 1.2 percent have search results
that are poisoned on the first page so
for English we can look at the different
categories here on the x-axis we have
the for spammer perennial favorites on
the left and we also have the nine
product terms on the right and on the
y-axis you can see the percentage of
searches which were poisoned we also
have five different cases here the
original search term and then three
types of auto correction defenses and
finally we have the non auto corrected
case that is the linguistic collision
misspellings which are not protected at
all the users are not warned so you can
see that some of these perennial
favorites the drugs adult and gambling
categories are targeted at over four
times the rate of others similarly for
Chinese we can see that these perennial
favorites are again targeted in Chinese
it's interesting to note that overall
the autocorrected cases exhibit a lower
overall poisoning rate than English
finally for Alexa we checked the 1k
domain names exhaustively so that we
could compare with our RN and based
results we found that the RN n is 2.8
times more efficient than randomly
sampling the misspellings we generate
using the processes described earlier we
also check the Alexa 10k names using the
RN n and we found that attackers do
industry exhibit activity across the
long tail of domains and this makes us
think that this is quite a common
technique we also examine what types of
devices users are using when they search
for these words for English we got this
data from Google Adwords and for Chinese
we use Baidu index so you can see here
that we have both the original keywords
and the misspellings that were poisoned
by attackers and you can see that for
the original keywords desktop has a
higher break higher user percentage
while the misspellings that attackers
target have a higher mobile number this
may be due to the fact that the mobile
users can more likely make misspelling
mistakes on small screens so we also
looked at the top domains in English
that contributed to the these poisonings
we found that the top traffic
monetization is malvert izing and we
also saw that there's a wide range of
different domains here some are
poisoning a large number of searches and
using a wide variety of URLs and you can
notice here too that the zero catch and
at space domains are using third level
domains this means that they're actually
free hosting sites that the attackers
are using to host their infrastructure
and avoid paying for their attacks also
note that the one of the names
censored and we can check the paper for
the bill
I mean and finally we also checked the
languages as identified by Google
Translate and we found that English is
the primary language that we're seeing
linguistic collisions with from English
to English that is and you can also see
that drugs has a lower overall English
percentage we think this may be due to
the fact that most of the inputs and the
drugs category use more scientific or
chemistry based names and so the sir the
Google Translate may auto detect them as
being something other than English and
finally there's also a longtail of
different languages here we found 74
different languages with collisions so
in conclusion we conducted the first
investigation into linguistic collisions
for English and Chinese and we found
that 1.2 percent of linguistic collision
misspellings that's is misspellings
which are not auto corrected have
poisoned search results on the first
page we also found that certain
categories are more heavily targeted and
mobile users are more likely to search
for poison terms thank you for your
attention I'm happy to take any
questions now thanks Matthew we have
time for a few questions
Luke desert house from Samsung research
America uh maybe this isn't the paper
but it didn't come up in the
presentation have you had any response
from Google or by dude this seems like
their responsibility but if I searched
for peppers I should see things about
peppers yeah this is kind of a difficult
problem for the search engines to solve
because you know users may actually be
intending to search for these in some
cases and it's not exactly obvious that
you can cleanly define which terms are
you know actually misspellings and which
terms are actually you know what the
user is meant to search for no le canals
I'm gonna give other universities
auctioneering Institute
kind of surprised by that one result you
showed where the Chinese results were at
a much lower base rate of infection if
you have any insight into why that might
be yeah
so that's seems to be I should have
mentioned in the talk but we found that
basically Baidu seems to heavily prefer
reputed domains so we saw that the same
thousand domains actually occurred for
about 93 percent of the search listings
in the non autocorrected case are in the
autocorrected cases yeah does that mean
the poisoned ones would be farther down
the chain farther down the search
results so they did something not
present no so they're still ranking in
the first result about as often as the
other domains they're just if I
understand your correct question
correctly they are still showing up and
they're not those searches aren't as
competitive so those misspellings aren't
as competitive yeah thank you question
from the back please so my name is Tina
I'm from the Federal Trade Commission my
question is I noticed you were looking
primarily at organic search results do
you bother looking into like the ads
that show up do searches as well that's
a great question yes we plan on doing
that in our future work my second
question is in terms of the range of the
malicious URLs did you notice that
they're primarily in the dot-com like if
they're trying to particularly take
advantage of brand names or do you
notice that they were taking advantage
of like different retail DS as well I
think we should take that offline yeah
Bhuvana tracing them from University of
Texas Dallas it's a very interesting
paper so my question is what is the
ultimate goal of the attacker right yeah
yes could you sort of expedite on that a
bit yes so they want to promote these
poison
URLs right it's really difficult if you
want to rank for the first result on
Google but it's much easier if you want
to rank for a you know a misspelling of
Google and I think some other types of
delivering spam have gotten less easy to
conduct for instance I don't open all of
my email and most of it just gets
filtered by Google Mail so
this is a pretty easy way low-cost way
low-risk way to promote yeah okay thank
you thank you let's thank the speaker
one more time
[Applause]