good afternoon everyone and
mine
dr. researcher Tampere University
Finland and I will be presenting our
paper port contention for fun and profit
this is a joint work between Tampere
University Finland and Technical
University of Havana Cuba let's start by
introducing a new side channel technique
we call it port smash the technique
targets the shared execution unit in
simultaneous multithreading environments
by monitoring the port execution a users
of secret data dependent control slows
now you must be wondering from port
contention various ports match terms
form from so in this talk I'm going to
explain how our new side channel
technique of how using port contention
we can actually create a timing side
channel this is a figure of a typical
modern microarchitecture it's been taken
from the internet so this should be
pretty close to the actual architecture
as we all know that traditional
approaches to the microarchitecture
design has focused more on the
performance while limiting the silicon
area and and power dissipation so more
more and more components are coming
closer to the processor for example to
reduce latencies for DRAM accesses we
got caches and then for in increasing
throughputs we have pipelining different
buffers in the pipelining stages we have
branch predictors and we have
speculation speculative execution on the
instruction level parallelism we can
either I have two different physical
cores or we can replicate the physical
core or we can use simultaneous
multi-threading so the idea of SMT is to
have two logical cores per physical core
where each logical core assets on
architecture state on the some set of
registers
and they share some of the components of
the physical course such as the l1 l2
cache and execution engine in this
example here so due to the inherent
nature of sharing resources in SMT
architecture security researchers
started looking into it that is it
possible to leak sensitive information
by having contention on these subsystems
in this pioneer work first of all in
2005 I demonstrated that I shared l1
data cache can leak information and that
was used to recover RSA key and later on
I am use specific to the Pentium 4
processors which was shared among
logical cores was targeted again on a
real-world application then there was an
attack on l1 instruction cache again
this was innocent environment a shared
resource and very recently a cache plate
which instead of attacking the cache
line it was targeting offsets within the
cache line and finally just last year
another shared resource which is TLB
this partially shade was exploited to
recover keys from the serious in our set
and where we come we are focusing on
execution engine and how the contention
on the ports can actually leak
information so let's zoom into the
execution engine so here we have a
simplified figure of how an execution
engine looks like on a high level we
have some instructions which are first
then they are decoded into smaller micro
operations and these micro operations
are scheduled to be executed on
different
Genet so the scheduler keeps a queue of
these micro operations and there are
channel to different ports to be
executed there is a port contention
whenever two or more micro operations
are issued to the same port when we
discovered first about this port
contention we started looking into
related working and we came across this
very interesting blog post from Fogg
this mentioned about a tool called code
shotgun and the idea was to try to find
contention in subsystems and SMT
architectures of a pair of instructions
were running the the post a blog post
specifically mentioned about congestions
due to execution unit and ports and also
a caching of D decoded micro-operations
now they were to open question first
which substrate systems were getting
congested by by the inspire of
instructions that is the source of
leakage and then whether that source of
leakage could be used to create a side
channel attack so in other word from
cover channel to to a side channel and
import smash we have tried to fill this
research gap so what a sports match
again it exploits the shared execution
engine creates a timing side channel due
to port contention among two processes
running on different logical cores and
same physical core so in order to and
physically verify that there is indeed a
port contention and and there is some
kind of a covert channel to secretly
communicate we performed an experiment
on intel core or cable 8 processor we
selected a set of instructions based on
their performance characteristics and
also
so their porches a footprint we had to
recreate two processes on different
illogical course we call them Alice and
Bob here we decided that for sending a
bit zero we would use or execute
instructions through port one and force
in sending a bit one we would execute
instructions using port five so let's
starts listening on port 1 and then Bob
G cute some instructions on port five
and Alice looks at the values of the
latencies here and then the same when
Bob sends a one zero sorry in this case
so started issuing instructions on port
1 and there's a contention so we can see
the clock cycles went up and this means
there was a zero being sent to Alice so
now that we have seen that there is some
kind of a code channel going on and that
two processes Alice and Bob on on
different logical course their
performance depend on each other sport
usage can be used that to H place by and
create a timing side channel so for that
we created a spy process here now you
can see there are different three
different configurations here one is on
port 1 then there is port 5 and then
there is pour zero and five six
depending on the instructions that we
have selected the spy would based on one
of the configurations start running
these instructions while computing the
latencies we created our victim process
here you can see there is a condition
based on the secret bit value it will
either take the first branch
it will jump to the second branch if the
bit value is one now the tag starts when
the spice when we run this by here we
configure this by on port 1 so the spice
list aspires executing instructions on
port 1 and waiting for the with victim
to start running its code so when the
victim is when there is a bit 0 the
victim will start or executing the first
part of the branch and if you can see
here for both on port 1 there is a port
contention we get a timing side channel
and we have our latency 0 and when the
victim or is on the other branch the
latencies are flat here so from this
timing side channel or we can infer
which secret bit is being executed on
the item so another important aspect of
port smash is that it has a very fine
spatial resolution if you look at these
are two different victims but they have
the similar port to the footprint
because they execute the instructions
are based on this condition either on
port 1 or or port 5 in this case but
there is a difference here if you look
at the memory footprint there this is
different so this one resides within one
cache line but the other one is between
two different cache lines so for the
second victim it is a good target for
attacks such as flush and reload or the
cache based attack but those attacks
will not work on on victims which reside
within one cache line for example so for
port smash it doesn't really matter as
long as we
we are able to identify the victims port
usage footprint we in order to prove
prove that this is a real attack or this
this is a attack this is a side channel
technique that can be used to attack
real-world applications
so we performed an attack on TLS server
and specifically the ECDSA
our signature generation we chose the
open SSL one 100h branch because at that
time it was the latest branch which has
a secret dependent control flow in the
code and we actually fixed the branches
like the future release branches whether
another work that we did previously
so the code always executes double
operation and then it looks at value of
a secret digit if it's not zero it will
do error operation so here we can see
there is a conditional branch and this
is what we are going to export in the
indie attack phase so we started the
attack by procuring procuring TLS crisis
and for that we cubed multiple to TLS
sessions while there was a spy running
in parallel monitoring the one of the
ports which we actually selected based
on experimentation you didn't see here
we have the Thiele stress which as you
see the HN ECDSA
because we are interested in the ECDSA
we creamed that out and when the signal
processing phase we tried to recover the
double and add operations so here you
can see after different steps of
filtering we are able to
our clearly identify Peaks as the ad
operations so for example here this end
that our ad which means we are able to
learn at least one bit of liquid shape
we did that for all the creases and then
build a partial nons information and use
that in our lattice attack to recover
the long term key of TLS over here you
can see four different trailing
sequences of the point multiplication we
get really good distributions so this
information is provided enough resources
this is this information is enough to
mount a successful Redis attack well and
if you want more information about this
how the attack work you can also refer
to the paper so port smash is also
effective against Intel SGX so here you
can see we have two different traces on
the top we have point multiplication
running insider Intel SGX
in clave and on the bottom we have known
as three X version so you can see we can
clearly identify the eight Peaks so
because we are focusing on the execution
engine any isolation provided by the in
SGX on and wheel subsystem does not
affect our side Channel finally we also
proposed some mitigations we have
learned the hardware hardware in
security community that we should always
avoid conditional branches all caused so
there I think is the best solution write
the code that doesn't leak information
and as a result of this work
we were assigned a CV and we also
contacted OpenSSL and the backported the
timing resistant implementation two
older versions which by the way was also
or another work we did on open ssl in
very on highly secure security critical
applications we can always disable SMT
so this attack will not work in
environments where there is no assembly
and if there's a highly threaded
application where we really need some
kind of performance so there are options
where we can have isolation on the voice
level so we can conditionally turn
office empty but it is hard to implement
because we need to change OS level and
also underlying library so and also it
might be difficult to put two different
so what is the takeaway a port smash is
a new side channel attack or which can
be used to attack real-world
applications it can be configured using
different port it is portable so we just
need an SMT architecture we can run it
it has a very fine spatial resolution
since we are talking about the microbes
on the execution in general
and then it doesn't require a lot of
prerequisites we don't need to know
eviction sets and and and other things
we just have to end aspire and configure
it based on the architecture and as
Marko microarchitectures are becoming
more complex so there might be new
side-channel attacks coming on in the
future
but the idea of this point is that now
it's time for the security community and
the architecture researchers to
collaborate and to get to have solution
better solutions we don't have these
kind of security of problems and finally
such an analysis is still a practical
and powerful tool to detect exploits or
to find exploits in the software and
finally mitigate them and thanks
everyone for listening to me and I'm
open for questions in the meantime you
can go on and just pull our proof of
concept from this repo and just start
smashing your ports thank you thank you
so we have time for some questions so
maybe I'll take a quick question why you
want people come up to the microphone so
there's like a whole gaggle of side
channel attacks now available at this in
SMT setting and so and you're gonna loot
to sum the talk so in this can you
compare a little bit more about like why
port smash would be better or worse and
obviously there's the spacial I think
which is very nice but in the victim
code for example that you're looking at
other attacks would have been applicable
as well or or not oh so I mean in the
paper we have a bit more detailed
analysis on that but one different thing
in port smash is
we are not relying on the memory
subsystem so we are just focusing on the
execution unit so when most of the
attacks have been high garage from
Georgia Tech excellent talk loud
listening to it two questions first
could you quickly maybe ballpark how
much bitrate you're able to get through
this versus c-care side channels and if
there is any difference in noise
sensitivity and second did you
subsequently try trying to fit this in
with broad speculation based attacks and
trying to use this cover channel in that
context Thanks I'll answer the second
question first so I think there is a
paper smother Spectre which have
actually used the sports mash technique
and they combine it with the specter
attack so instead of cash and on the
first one so we get a very fine
resolution because like for example in
cash based attacks where you're looking
so I think the cash bleed is is one of
the attacks which is which has the
finest resolution because you're taking
the cash bank conflicts within the cache
line but here we are actually talking
about micro operation level so I think
the resolution is time for one more
question i debit Ken's UC Irvine a
really cool talk interesting work I have
a technical question about the port
assignments you had a table we showed
the different instructions and for ad
there were different ports right um the
way that I understand it it means that
add instruction can go to all of these
ports yeah yeah correct
so in your second analysis you showed
that you extracted secrets from open SSL
I believe yeah and it used yet
instruction right and in the first
analysis you use instructions like CRC
or instructions that go
to the vector Boris okay so only B could
you elaborate on that
yeah so your question is that or in the
attack we used add instruction no
actually that that as is air is a
different actually so this is related to
the implementation of the elliptic curve
cryptography and then we have our
outpatient and within these add in
double operation we have different
finite field operations like squares and
multiplies and and those turn into
instructions and then into microbes for
the sake of the attack like depending on
the architecture we have to do
experiments of which on which port we
get the better signal so I think we use
port 5 in this case first okay yeah
thank you okay well we thank the speaker
one more time
[Applause]