okay so this
joint work with a record of Accardi
Matos namitha visitability
marco square Gino so as you all know
HTTP is a protocol which is not secure
doesn't provide any level of secure
security in terms of confidentiality in
terms of integrity but luckily it is
going to be replaced really soon by
HTTPS so we observe a major increase in
the adoption of HTTPS in the last few
years and were several is not from this
one of the reason is that now it is very
easy to get access to trusted
certificate thanks to authorities like
let's encrypt and when we observe that
major web browser certainly pushing for
a better HTTPS adoption by marking HTTPS
insecure directly in in the address bar
and based on data from Mozilla we
observed that the amount of web traffic
which is encrypting now is higher than
the amount of web traffic which is not
encrypted so this means basically that
we can be happy to safely use Wi-Fi
everywhere at the base of its work web
this question can we really trust the
CPS and the reason behind this is that
of course it's CPS is much better than
HTTP but there are plenty of attacks
which have been published against TLS
which is the cryptographic protocol
behind the security of HTTPS you can see
you can see a few logos of in family
attacks against TLS in this image slide
as you can see we have attacks like
drown a robot which operates
thanks to cryptographic weaknesses in
implementation and when we have nasty
bugs like heartbleed which can reveal
cryptographic keys and all these attacks
can completely compromise the security
of HCPs and you might think that visit
acts are so severe that we have been
fixed on major website so we should not
care about these attacks anymore but our
observation here is that the web is a
very complicated and interconnected
ecosystem and the security of a website
is actually a function of the security
of many other website in particular what
will service that TLS vulnerabilities
get amplified in the web ecosystem you
can see a picture here which we built
from using our analysis tool
so this is actually a picture of a real
website you can see in the center of the
picture we have a gray circle which is
the main site but you can see that this
site is loading content from any other
different toasts which are the white
circles in the in the picture also the
security of the website depends on the
security of its subdomains in particular
when it comes to authentication
credential like cookies and these are
the grey circles in the picture you can
see but is a very complicated ecosystem
a lot of inclusion so the main site is
loading from any other faust and the
strife lost are a host which are which
suffer from some TLS vulnerability so
you can see in this case we have a
website which is apparently secure it
doesn't suffer from any TLS
vulnerability but since it load stuff
from other web sites which are broken
it is a mentally compromised so what we
did in our work was to take a systematic
look of this class of problems so what
we did is first of all reviewing most of
the existing attacks against TLS we
identify those with still work in modern
clients through modern browsers and we
characterize these attacks in terms of
attack trees we define very precisely
the condition which are needed for the
talk to work after were defining these
attacks we build a tool which is an
analogous platform for web application
and idea of the tool is what the tool
collects data for a bunch of relevant
toasts it will be clear what I mean
later but as you can already see from
the previous slide the security of our
website depends on many other hosts from
which contents are loaded for instance
and when we use existing tools to
analyze this other host and build the
security report we use a word platform
to carry out a large-scale analysis of
the web and we focus in particular on
three different aspects we focus on page
integrity so the possibility for an
attacker to engender content in the page
and in particular script when we focus
on the security of authentication
credentials and they will discuss in
particular cookies and then we will
reason about the security implication of
web tracking and broken TLS
implementation in what popular web
trackers to sum up I can say that this
is the first quantitative analysis
of the impact of TLS vulnerabilities on
web application of security this is the
first contribution of our work so we
start by reviewing known attacks against
TLS and we characterize these attacks
using attack trees we serve roughly
boolean formulas which can be used to
express attack condition you can see an
example of a simple attack tree in the
right part of the slide so let's assume
that the goal of the tucker is learning
the session key so that the attacker it
might be able to eventually decrypt the
traffic this is possible if the attacker
is able to decrypt the RSA key exchange
offline which in turn is again possible
if it two conditions are true the first
condition is that an RSA key exchange is
used and this is only possible if either
RSA using the is the TLS version or it
is possible to force a downgraded
Vitelli version which prefers RSA and
the second condition which must be true
for the ductwork is that there is an NSA
decryption Oracle which is available on
the target toast or on a host with the
same certificate or on an Oscar with the
same public RSA key we develop this kind
of attack trees and by building on top
of that we characterize a family of
insecure channels so we have channels
which are tainted which means in
particular that with channels suffer
from confidentiality and integrity
issues which might allow the attacker to
run many in the middle attacks so to bin
in the middle of the communication and
read modify everything which is sent to
despite the use of HTTP when we have a
leaky channels which are not let's say
as broken as to allow many the middle
attacks but still allow decryption
so if something is sent where the
attacker might be able to recover the
content at some point and then we have a
class of partially leaky channels which
are channel which suffer from sides a no
sooner abilities which means that you
can leak secret the sent over the table
over the channel for instance what one
bit at a time so if a same secret sent
over the tunnel multiple times you might
be able to actually try to the full
secret by using the side channel this is
a useful abstraction layer which we use
to reason about security issues in what
network applications
we don't care on why our channel is
broken but we try to reason on what
happens when the channel is broken if
you are interested in this part of the
work you can see the paper for food
details this is our methodology the idea
is that we access the website we want
analyzed using Atlas Chrome we collect a
bunch of information including the
sterilized dome of the page cookies and
holy oath which serve the sub resources
to the page like script images etc with
a non subdomain enumeration on the main
website to find other security relevant
hosts which are important for our
analysis and after collecting all this
information we run existent Els analysis
tools on the collected host we map the
output of such tools to the condition of
the tag trees so we are able to identify
the presence of leakage channels tainted
channels and partially decayed channels
where and we use all this information to
build a security report what is
interesting my opinion is that now we're
on Elizabeth with scan tank a website
from Alexa and we eventually added to
scan more than 100k hosts so it means
that indeed there is an amplification of
the textual face against this website we
want analyze 10k but we haven't only
analyzed more than 100 chaos these are a
few premium statistics so we were able
to find the telephony liabilities in
more than five chaos which is roughly
the 5% of our data set you can see the
breakdown in the table you can see that
change change painted saunas are the
most represented here but you can also
find a presence of liquid channel
partially channel you can say that with
number somewhat concerning but they
don't tell much about web application
security and the impact of this number
application security is actually the
main contribution of our board so let me
start by discussing the first issue
which we analyzed in detail in our paper
which the problem of page integrity so
let's assume we have a web page and
which web page load the JavaScript from
two different hosts the first host is
fine but the second dose is broken
because it suffers from a TLS
vulnerability which allow the attacker
tuned in
content over the channel what were
serving practice is that around the 900
webpages are at the danger of script
injection due to the presence of tainted
channels and what I find interesting in
particular is that in the large majority
of cases the problem is not on the
homepage itself but the problem is due
to the inclusion of scripts over tender
channels so it means that but they are
the main host is fine but it loads stuff
from other hosts which are actually
broken and this is the case for the 75%
of the website we analyzed we can
impress upon defend against miss attacks
by using sub resource integrity because
you can provide a national descriptor
for the browser to check but whatever
serving practice is that at the moment
the adoption of SLI is really
ineffective Azariah is not really used
on many website and even websites which
make use of as I do not actually patch
all the possible channels for content
inclusion another interesting takeaway
from this part of the analysis is that
there are a few popular scriptura
provider which lead to a vulnerability
amplification because many websites load
the content from this script provider
but we script providers are broken here
you have a couple of examples you can
see that around the 200 home pages are
broken by the inclusion of scripts
served by a vulnerable hosts of Baidu
and we have more than 100 home pages
which include content from a vulnerable
host unbinding Kadeem a second aspect
when allies is the use of cookies
cookies are the cornerstone of client
authentication of the web where a
security critical component they can be
set as a first only which means that the
host will set the cookie for itself but
most of the times who Jesus set as
domain cookies which means that were
shared across different subdomains the
application of this choice is that the
attack surface against cookies is
particularly large there are several
tricky consideration to be done when it
comes to cookies in terms of
confidentiality we have to be careful
about which domain sharing because it
means that if a Cook is shared between
multiple subdomains a vulnerability of a
single subdomain might be
enough for the attacker to disclose the
cookie value and if the tackle exposes
the cookie value it might be eventually
able to impersonate the victim which is
the owner of the cookie then since
cookies can be forced to be sent by the
attacker
by forging HTTP traffic it means that
four exfiltrating cookie partially
leakage analysts are good enough so the
attacker can use with simple set
channels to leak a cookie values by
forcing a lot of web traffic so cookies
are particularly vulnerable in this
respect and it is also possible for the
attacker to steal cookies by injecting
script inside pages because scripts can
normally be accessed can normally access
cookies unless with cookies are marked
with the HT poly attribute so the
texture face against cookies is
particularly high and similar
consideration applies to integrity
because also in the case of of integrity
consideration the subdomains can set
cookies for the main website and it is
possible to mitigate this issue by using
the house prefix which forces cookie to
be set without the domain attribute so
without any formal domain sharing but as
we will see this is not very commonly
used in the web at a time being these
are a few numbers so you can see the
percentage of cookies on which we were
able to find a confidentiality or
integrity issue due to the presence of
some
TLS vulnerability as you can see from
the table the attack surface against
domain cookies is much larger than
forest only cookies as I said since the
main cookies are shared between multiple
hosts it is much easier to attack them
so we find a roughly double the number
of vulnerable cookies if we just focus
on represented and in particular we
observed that for more than 400 website
it is all the session cookies a below
confidentiality so it means we use some
heuristic to the text session cookies
but whatever service that it is very
easy to have possibility of session
hijacking of this prominent website if
we called mark always cookie with the
HCP only attribute we would in very
limited at Duxford phase because
number of vulnerable website will be
around half of this number but of course
which might have an impact on
compatibility so we cannot just
stipulate that this cookie cannot be
accessed by JavaScript and at the same
time being sure that this is not going
to break website when we observed that
more than 500 website had the session
cookies all of which have low integrity
in principle we can mitigate this issue
by using those prefix and in particular
this will help in more than 100 cases
but we solve at only one web site in our
data set is using the host prefix to
prevent cookie sharing between
subdomains and we also estimated that
there are a few cases 22 where it is
possible to deploy the host prefects
world breaking compatibility but the
websites are not to doing so last part
of the analysis related to the web
tracking in particular we start from the
salvation that TLS vulnerabilities in
popular tracking trackers might enable
privacy leaks in particular if tracking
cookies are sent over leaky channels the
attacker might be able to build cross
site navigation profiles of users and
this issue can be amplified if the
attacker can actually force scripts to
load this content from the trackers in
other pages we have a similar analysis
for tracking cookies published at the
ww2 thousand 15 but what analysis
focused on HP traffic here instead we
focus on HTTP traffic which is not
completely secure due to the presence of
will not ability but the methodology is
pretty similar here a few example these
are example of a host which are
vulnerable these are used by trackers
and they are very popular because you
can see that we're included by many
different hosts and we estimated based
on the numbers that we have in the paper
but attacking a single publisher alone
like pub Matic
will allow profiling over more than 140
web site and the attacking can be
amplified if the attacker plays the
active role of injecting scripts in
error pages and it is possible in
particular to increase the profiling to
almost 1,000 websites
so to conclude HCPs is essential for the
application security but it is not a
final solution
in particular we have to ensure that its
base is deployed correctly otherwise
attacker might be able to exploit the
last one an ability to run nasty attacks
we have seen some other tax in visto
particularly we estimated the page
integrity issues in 10% of the home
pages which we analyzed and we observed
that in most cases these issues are
related to remote script inclusion so
the main host is fine but the home page
is loading stuff from hosts with the
deploy a CPS insecurely in the case of
session cookies we found that it is very
easy to leak cookies through broken TLS
channels and very likely this is due to
the fact that these cookies are shared
between subdomains however very large
attack surface and in 13% of the website
we found problems similar to cookie
forcing where the attacker might be able
to compromise cookie integrity it is
possible to reduce the tax surface for
this by using the osprey fix for cookies
but no one is using it basically as of
now and finally we analyzed web tracking
and we have served that broken TLS
implementation in web trackers can be
used to build the accurate cross site
navigation profiles across different
website and a single track in a single
leaky tracker enable profiling on more
than 140 website and it is possible to
make this attack stronger by exploiting
the script interaction so let's say the
main goal of our research was showing
that even if we move to full HTTP the
last release can still represent a
serious issue to the security of the
deployment and we want to really listen
on how to improve on this state of the
art in particular the upcoming release
of TLS 1.3 major browsers will
definitely help in improving this
situation so very briefly to conclude we
are currently looking for internships
because we are still developing this
tool in collaboration with crypto since
because we want to let
is the tool as a web application for
people to use so if you are interesting
in development work on these kind of
topics you can contact me or Ricardo for
cardiod visa dresses thank you for
attention
[Applause]
thank you very much therefore no
questions line up at the microphones and
fire away with your questions until you
get up let me ask one so you said that
for the quantitative analysis that you
did you had to start out with those
attack trees can you share a word or two
on how you came up with those trees
what's the process for doing that yeah
so basically the construction of the
tech trees are based on extensive
literature order review it's a review of
the literature and you can see an
example in this slide and what we did
was taking assumption but the user is
navigating the web using a modern client
so we have some strict requirement by
Mozilla which is called modern
compatibility requirement for TLS
security so we assume that the user is
accessing the web from a client which is
updated and based on this we dint if I
condition for attacks which fall into
this category to be true and we estimate
the the presence of his kind of
vulnerabilities by scanning Austin and
mapping the output of a known tools like
TLS attacker against the condition of
attack trees hey Thomas Koba University
of Edinburgh I wanted to ask what
sampling set of websites did you use
because you for a lot of numbers around
but I don't know what the corresponding
references okay so we access a lexer
website so we took the top 100 k and
then we started sample until we get 10 k
website all of which are deployed on top
of HTTP so that's a better setting we
use the Alex List which was the most
updated when we perform our own
investigation okay thank you
any other questions
if not then let's thank Stefano once
again and I think we're due for a break
[Applause]