and I'm standing I'm from the University
of Cambridge and today I'm going to
present my recent work regarding sensor
calibration fingerprinting for
smartphones and this is a joint work
with my supervisor
Alistair Beresford and Ian Sherrod from
the parlament so what is device
fingerprinting well device
fingerprinting is a technique to
generate unique identifiers or sometimes
called a fingerprint of a device it has
many use cases for example it has been
used to protect against identity theft
and credit-card fraud however is more
often used by advertisers to monitor
your activities and to study your
personal interests for example I am sure
many of you had experience on finding
that right after you search something in
a shopping app and the relevant
advertisement just popped up in some
random website and that's device
fingerprinting if you think of the use
case of the whistleblower then the
consequences is even more severe because
the attackers in this case could simply
buy or inject some advertisement on the
news website and this could help them
uncover the identity of the
whistleblower so to protect against the
device fingerprinting both iOS and
Android have deployed a set of
countermeasures for example iOS the
developers has no access to a phone
number or the MAC address of the
hardware modules while Android this is
enforced by permission based access
control nevertheless there is a major
piece that is has been neglected in the
current measures and that is the motion
sensors so modern smartphones typically
include a set of motion sensors
including the accelerometer which
measures the acceleration of the device
the gyroscope which measures the
rotation of the device and the
magnetometer which measures the magnetic
magnetic field around the device data
from these sensors can be accessed by
from either a mobile app or from a
mobile website and it does not require
any user permissions or user
interactions we find that this is pretty
dangerous because we have proposed a new
type of device fingerprinting attack
which we called the calibration
fingerprinting attack so this attack
works by inferring the calibration data
of these sensors by simply analyzing the
sensor outputs which does not require
any permission and further furthermore
we can use the calibration data because
normally if they do calibration is most
likely to be per device calibration and
we can use this data to uniquely
fingerprint every device we found this
attack extremely efficient and effective
the whole attack takes less than one
second and it as I said earlier it can
be launched from either website or an
app and it can actually generate a
globally unique identifier even for the
homogeneous devices such as the iPhones
or iPads and here's a demo of the attack
so here we have two iPhone terrorist
devices on the desk and this website
generates the calibration fingerprint of
the gyroscope for each device as you can
see here these two iPhone has devices
have a different fingerprint which is a
three by three matrix so how does this
attack work well the motion sensors are
suffering for different types of
deterministic errors or often called the
systematic errors due to manufacture
imperfections and this is inevitable and
in general these errors can be
classified into three categories the
scale error which means the axis of the
sensors is different from the design and
no Auto analogy which means the axis of
the sensors are not perpetuate which
other and also the pious
which means the reference point of the
sensor is different from the nominal
value Corson's accuracy is often crucial
and therefore some manufacturers may
choose to do factory calibration to
compensated for these types of errors
sorry in particular three different
types of calibration matrices would be
calculated and the format of these
matrices is shown on this slide and each
of them is correspond to the one the
type of arrow on the left and during the
factory calibration after the
manufacturer got these matrices they
would bake this data into the
non-volatile memory of the device and
this data will not be changed afterwards
which means is consistent over time in
general motion sensors would first
convert the analog environmental
measurements to a digital value through
a component called the analog to digital
converter and then this calibration
matrices would be applied to the ADC
outputs to generate the accurate sensor
readings using the formula here and the
formula up there can be further
simplifying to the formula down below
and the objective of our attack is quite
straightforward because we know the
sensor output which is the matrix so
here and our objective is to recover the
value of the gain matrix G here is how
the attack works we first collect a few
data samples from the sensor then by
subtracting the conservative sensor
measurements we can effectively remove
the BIOS from this equation and
eventually we can get a formula down
below which is Delta equals to the gain
matrix G times the matrix Delta a
however with the only know the value of
Delta L which is the difference between
the sensor outputs and normally it would
be impractical to infer the value of the
gain matrix G here because we don't know
what the Delta A would be but there are
some nice properties we can exploit here
first of all we know that the output of
a DC can only be an integer which means
that the matrix the other a here only
has integer values
and we also know that the game matrix
here it's close to its nominal value
which means the value that sensor is
designed to operate at and this value is
often documented in the datasheet and
these properties allows us to infer the
value of Delta a and further estimate
the value of the gain matrix G here so
here is the example this graph shows the
gyroscope output from two devices the
Samsung Galaxy s8 and iPhone 10 one
thing you can notice here is that there
is a clear quantization on the sensor
output and this is because ADC values
are integers if we subtract I'm sorry if
we subtract the sensor outputs as we
talked earlier then we can get a figure
here if a sensor is not factory
calibrated then all the values within a
single quantile would be the same value
and this is the case for the Samsung
Galaxy s8 but you can for a 20 but
clearly notice that there is a strong
fluctuation in the quantile between the
two black dashed lines and this is a
proof that the gyroscopes in the iPhone
10 is factory calibrated furthermore
thanks to the clear quantization we can
also know the value of Delta a for each
data point by simply observing which
quantities poi slicing and in many cases
we don't really know the nominal value
of the gain matrix because especially
for iOS devices the data sheet is not
available to the public
but is not a big issue because we can
still estimate the value of the nominal
gain using the distance between the
adjacent one house as shown on this
slide and this diagram illustrates the
major steps to recover the value of the
gain matrix and to further generate the
calibration fingerprint so the
calibration fingerprint is just another
representation of the gain matrix based
on the device model because we found
that different mass models use different
representations of this gain matrix
and we already talked with the first
three steps which allows us to recover
the value of the ADC and once we have
the value of the Delta a and we know
Delta o and then the linear algebra
would allow us to estimate the value of
the matrix the gain matrix G here in
practice we found that in order to pull
off this attack
you only need around 100 data samples
which you can easily collect weight in
one second you may also notice that here
we have an improved approach and this
approach the improved method ensures
that even if the device is under intense
movement for example if you are shaking
your device this algorithm consider
generates the fingerprints quickly and
we are reliably so just to fresh the
memory this is the gyroscope calibration
fingerprint in the previous demo a part
phone telescope we found that the
magnetometer in iOS devices is also
factory calibrated but different from
the gyroscope the magnetometer the
calibration behavior in the magnetometer
is more different across the different
models for example you can clearly
notice that a stronger fluctuation in
the iPhone 10s max than the one for the
iPhone 5s but it nevertheless our
approach is applicable for all iOS
device models and can generate the
fingerprint reliably furthermore we also
found that the Google picks or - and
pixel three the the accelerometer is
also factory calibrated and can also be
fingerprinted using the same approach we
defined the sense ID adds a collection
of distinctive sensor calibration
fingerprints which means for iOS devices
this includes both the gyro ID and the
mac ID and for google pixel devices it
includes the ik ID and here is how this
IDs look like one thing you can clearly
notice here that the ACT ID is like
looks quite different from the other two
and the reason for that is we found that
in google pixel 3 they actually mapped
the calibration parameters to a local
file system so if you have the root
access of your device of your Android
device then you can actually read out
these calibration parameters from these
files and this serves as a grunt chose
for our approach because we compare the
the gain matrix we estimate it with with
the measurements written in this file
and they're exactly the same so now that
we know that we can generate this
anxiety the next important question is
how unique is this fingerprint to answer
this question we compared our approach
with another fingerprinting framework
called the fingerprint gs2 which
utilizes
a set of traditional browser
fingerprinting techniques including the
cameras fingerprinting so here
the group size means the number of
devices sharing the same fingerprint so
for example as you can save all the
fingerprint GS to 45 out of 870 devices
have same have the same fingerprint and
another 36 of them has another
fingerprint but all devices has the
unique ID and this proves that both the
chera ID and the mac ID has more entropy
than the fingerprint just to which
stands for traditional browser
fingerprinting techniques and to
quantitatively analyzing the entropy of
the society we collected sensor data
from 870 iOS devices while crowd
sourcing platforms to ensure that we
didn't overestimating the entropy of the
society we also studied whether there
are some correlations between the values
in this in the society and answer is yes
they do have some called strong
correlations and shown on this slide so
basically the graph shows that the
relationship between array true values
in the Jaro ID here and if the
scatterplot appears to be a strict line
it means that there is a strong
correlation between those two values so
in this figure I'm
this junk related pass in red and for
this junk related the past were deleted
one of them in the entropy calculation
to avoid the overestimating the over
estimation of the entropy and as a
result we estimate that the gyro ID
itself has around 42 bits of entropy and
the mag ID has around 25 bits of entropy
but this is for the iphone 6 iphone 6s
model because this is the most popular
device model we have in our data set so
what are these entropy means it
basically means that the chance of you
having two iPhone 6's devices sharing
the same fingerprint is pretty low as
you can see here indicating that this is
a globally unique fingerprint story and
to mitigate this attack we proposed two
options the first option is to add noise
to the 80 state outputs this could help
to obfuscate the quantization and the
second option is to run the sense
outputs to the multiple of the normal
again and this would remove the
fluctuation we saw earlier in the graph
but there is orbit the third option here
which is the most secure option among
the three that is to remove the access
to the motion sensor at once and so we
reported this issue to Apple last year
and Apple in the recent release of ours
to appoint to Apple adopted our first
option which added noise to the sensor
outputs and they further removed the
sensor access in Mobile Safari by
default however this is not currently
not implemented in WebKit which means
the sensor data is still accessible in
our Chrome or Firefox in other browsers
in general and we also reported this
issue to Google last year in December
and so far they haven't effects this one
a bit yet so if you have a pixel devices
the attacker can still fingerprint you
using this approach so to conclude we
have proposed a
type of device fingerprinting tackle
attack called the calibration
fingerprinting attack that can track
users across apps and websites and is
extremely efficient and effective and I
think the highlight of this attack is
that way basic we highlighted that so
this normally the calibration pattern is
not something that you wouldn't normally
concerned consider as a privacy concern
because it's basically a trade-off
between utility and privacy but we had
at you that this actually is also a
source a major source that exposes a lot
of the personal information and we show
that this attack is extremely efficient
because it can uniquely fingerprint
sandbox and homogeneous devices such as
iPhone and iPad and if you're interested
in this work you can find more details
on our website since ID d'Orsay out or
can not act or he okay and if you are
running an iOS version is that is below
twelve point two you can actually find
out what your gyroscope fingerprint
looks like on our website because
there's a proof of concept implemented
in JavaScript to do that okay thanks a
lot for the talk thanks for coming we
have time for a couple questions if
folks can line up at the mics
thank you for the interesting talk and
my name is Alma Mannion from University
in Germany and regarding your
countermeasures you have option one two
three yeah I didn't get the difference
between option one and option two is
there any scientifically speaking the
same to add noise or to round the sensor
output so both of them are not are not
like completely secure because you can
still do this attack using probability
like attacks yeah right but wait I don't
have like quantitative like analysis
about which one of them is more secure
because especially for the first option
it really depends on which noise you are
adding to the ADC for example we
proposed adding a uniform distribution
noise but it's more secure to add it
like Gaussian noise to the outputs and
that in that way the effectiveness of
the first option is like differs a lot
depending on the noise you are adding
okay thank you thank you
any other questions
so one question I have is this seems to
pop up a lot as mobile phones have tons
of sensors available on them do you
think there's a general purpose strategy
to solving this so do you think you have
to do something unique for each of these
cases
you mean for other sensors yeah or like
all the different measurements you can
collect from your phone it seems like
fingerprinting is a huge problem yes so
this approach is not just restricted
motion sensors there are other sensors
that I know you
you can basically fingerprint using the
similar approach so do you think it's
just a function of being able to
identify wherever this might crop up or
do you think there's a more elegant
solution - I didn't like stopping this
before you have to write another paper
on the next sensor III I don't think I
will write another paper above another
sensor if that approach is similar but
if the calibration behavior is different
from the model that we used here then I
might yeah cool well thank you speaker
again thank you
you
[Applause]