okay thanks Michael for the introduction
I'm too young song a PhD student at UC
Irvine so this is a joint work with my
collaborators Julian Prabhu Yost and
pear and my adviser Michael friends so
this talk is going to be about tools
that find vulnerabilities in C and C++
programs so this is an S ok paper so
there will be lots of materials that's
in the paper but omitted from the talk
I'd like to start by looking at how C
and C++ programs are varied for security
vulnerabilities today there are broadly
speaking manual analysis static analysis
and dynamic analysis our paper focuses
on dynamic analysis allow these tools
often called sanitizers to find
vulnerabilities in C and C++ programs so
this is a mature area as you can see
here there is a large body of research
published in the area over the last 35
years starting from 80s when C started
gaining popularity some of them are
already widely adopted and behind these
covers of many software vulnerabilities
many other tools however only exist in
the literature without being adopted and
deployed in practice so by surveying and
tax on emerging these tools we shed
light on why during the talk I'll
highlight some of the challenges that
remain to be solved in designing and
implementing a dynamic analysis tools
for C++ ICS C++ and addressing those
challenges will increase adoption and
also lead to discovering more
vulnerabilities that might be might be
lurking in today's software so by
looking at these tools here however you
might wonder that why some of the tools
that are often discussed as exploit
mitigations are shown here in our paper
we consistently view these tools as
sanitizers and both finding tools
because these tools do have some of the
characteristics that's desirable in
detecting and finding vulnerabilities
let me use this example flow of a
control for hijacking attack to explain
how exploit mitigations and sanitization
might differ and
perhaps overlap so this control-flow
hijacking attack starts by triggering an
integer overflow which triggers a heap
buffer overflow and the attacker uses
this heap buffer overflow to override a
function pointer which is later used in
an indirect caller so the goal of
exploit mitigations is to mitigate
consequences of a vulnerability that
might be present in a program as such it
does not need to detect the
vulnerabilities as they occur if
especially if it comes at a cost so in
this example tools enforcing certain
forms of control flow integrity and cool
pointer integrity limit possible
consequences of a possible vulnerability
in the program but they do not
necessarily find vulnerabilities
themselves as they occur on the other
hand tools that perform forms of bound
tracking such as soft bond and address
sanitizer can be viewed as sanitizers
because they do detect the heap buffer
overflow to vulnerability itself as it
occurs their differences can further be
summarized as follows to put to point
out a couple more tools sanitizers do
have more relaxed performance budget
than exploit mitigations do so it's
often more desirable to track more
diagnostic information as the program
executes because such information can
tell you about the location of the
vulnerability now what makes C and C++
so special from the security standpoint
one of the things that distinguishes C
and C++ from perhaps managed languages
is that the presence of undefined
behavior undefined behavior is a
possible program behavior that's left
undefined explicitly and deliberately by
the language standard so in fact CS C++
leave quite many aspects of a possible
program behavior undefined which include
buffer overflow use after free and type
errors and so on these are all widely
known security vulnerabilities and more
specifically the security implications
of undefined behavior can be classified
into two first and foremost of course is
a memory
violations which is vulnerable to memory
exploits on the left-hand side of this
slide is an example program statement
which is vulnerable to lower pointed
reference and on the right hand side is
compliation result null pointer
dereference is undefined behavior and is
also a violation of memory safety
that's exploitable under certain
circumstances
besides memory safety violations there's
the second security implication though
which is perhaps often overlooked it is
that the presence of undefined behavior
in a program can surprisingly result in
vulnerable code being generated by the
compiler let me take the same example
but this time with an added law pointer
tag and some privilege code that's
protected by the null pointer check as
you can see here unfortunately the null
pointer check is placed after a possible
nor pointer dereference in the first
line this can create a very interesting
fall or ability so what can happen here
is that the compiler reasons about the
value of the pointer turn here and
concludes that the pointer can't be
known when the null pointer check is
performed the reasoning here is that the
pointer was already being dereferenced
in the first line before so it can't be
known since the pointer can't be null
the compiler removes the lower pointer
check that was supposed to protect the
privileged code that follows so combined
with compilers cool reordering the
result can be rather unexpectedly that
the null pointer check present at the
source code level becomes a privilege
escalation vulnerability in the end even
though the null pointer check that was
protecting the privilege code was
present at the source code level so
these are vulnerabilities that the
sanitizers we studied cover most of
these can either directly or indirectly
lead to memory safety violations besides
direct memory safety violations spatial
and temporal memory safety violations
things like type confusion and integer
overflows are also considered harmful in
the
sense of memory safety in c and c++ in
addition some undefined behavior such as
using uninitialized variable sum of type
errors and nor pointer dereference and
others can even today lead to vulnerable
code being generated by the compiler
this is because the mainstream compilers
are already reason about actively reason
about like such undefined behavior
having recognized that risk you might
have already seen that many projects
actually set different compiler flags to
disable certain optimization behavior
flex that disable deletion of null
pointer checks like the disable
optimization based on strict areas in
room incipiency
but but bad news is that things can
change as the compiler optimizations
evolve so a sanitizer implements a bug
finding technique using various program
instrumentation and metadata management
techniques about finding technique
describes the key mechanism that a tool
uses to detect a given target class of
bugs
for instance address sanitizer inserts
so-called red zones between objects in
memory to find spatial memory safety
violations by checking each memory
whether each memory access goes to red
zone or not program instrumentation
technique describes how and when a tool
instruments a program to monitor is
runtime behavior address analyzer uses
compiler based instrumentation for
example a metadata management technique
describes how a tool stores and manages
various types of static and dynamic
metadata at one time and address
sanitizer again for example uses a
shadow memory to indicate whether a
memory region is red zone or not and
precision and overheads are a more or
less direct result of the implementation
and design choices and this is our
analysis of 37 tools along these axes
above
finding technique program
instrumentation metadata management as
well as their performance and precision
characteristics I'll not go into details
about each axis and each of the tools
here please refer to our paper for more
details for the remainder of the talk I
will instead focus on and highlight some
of the challenges that remain to be
solved in designing and implementing a
dynamic analysis tools for C and C++ as
we all know performance is not a major
concern for a book finding tool for
example tools having 3x performance
overhead are widely used in practice so
the bulk detection technique book
detection precision problems are the
main concern and challenge here there
are many false positives even especially
in tools that are not widely deployed
and there are many false negatives
especially in widely deployed tools they
can miss many types of box to elaborate
further let me describe how false
positives and how false negatives can be
understood and perhaps be defined so
there is the ISO standard and real world
programs that are well defined by the
are ISO standard as you can see in the
diagram and there are also programs that
are not well well-defined which include
programs that transiently construct
pointers that go out of bounds of an
array however there are many many
real-world programs that transiently
construct such are abolish pointers
which is reflected in what's called de
facto standards so de facto standards
reflect dialects of the language that an
actual corpus of real-world programs
follow so sanitizer policies do not
quite aligned with any of these
standards so red shading here it
represents programs that violate a
sanitizer policy is
often too strict generating false alarms
for programs that are legitimate under
the ISO and de facto standards and it's
often too permissive leaving many real
bugs unsanitized
so how can we reduce these gaps one way
towards reducing these false alarms is
to take into account both ISO and de
facto standards supporting more of de
facto standards is desirable because it
means that a tool is applicable to a
actual corpus of real-world programs
that are out there and which in turn
means that a tool can find actual bugs
in real world programs for example many
real-world programs transiently
construct out-of-bounds pointers however
many tools do not actually permit this
some abound tracking tools and dengle
important in pointer invalidation tools
for example can incorrectly invalidate
pointers when programs construct
out-of-bounds pointers let me also take
a look at the other precision gap namely
false negatives there are still many
challenging bugs that elude existing and
widely deployed sanitizers many
subclasses of memory safety violations
for example such as intra object buffer
overflow elude a widely deployed
sanitizer address sanitizer and also
type error detection tools type error
detection efforts are also focused
mostly on bad casting detection but
there are many type unning constructs in
C and C++ that programmers can use and
any errors in using such typing
constructs are not detected by existing
bad casting detection tools in general
finding these elusive bugs requires a
finer-grained metadata tracking such as
tracking bounds for every single pointer
and tracking effective type of every
single object in memory however it
brings its own set of performance and
precision challenges which to our
knowledge has not been properly
addressed
yet let me describe some of the
challenges first uninstrumented code can
cause problems for a pointer pointer
metadata tracking for example if you see
on the left hand side fat pointer
technique is incompatible with
uninstrumented code because if a peppy
for fat pointer gets passed to
uninstrumented code the program can
crash as the fat pointer gets the
referenced and on the right hand side
maintaining metadata disjoined from
original pointer values can be an option
but now it can create another problem as
you as you seen on the right hand side
of the slide uninstrumented code can
update a pointer without updating its
metadata which can cause problems when
the outdated meta data gets used in a
sanitizer check I should also mention
that full instrumentation is also an
option but it's often not viable due to
things like binary only libraries even
with full instrumentation like for
example using dynamic binary translation
sanitizers has still failed to keep
track of pointer meta data for example c
supports pointer to integer casts this
is incompatible with fat and tagged
pointers and destroyed metadata can also
be an option here but pointer flow
tracking across pointer in either casts
remains to be an often problem to our
knowledge no existing tools address this
problem another challenge is maintaining
thread safety if the original program is
multi-threaded for example if there are
two threads that are atomically updating
the same pointer value concurrently and
if the corresponding metadata update is
not within the same atomic unit meta
data can go out of sync here one may be
able to address this problem by
introducing locks for every memory
location that's accessed atomically but
no tool actually addresses this problem
yet the
five errors beyond bad casting
vulnerability requires tracking
effective type of all memory objects
however the effective type rules in C
are complex mainly because it's not a
strongly typed language it supports many
constructs that support type punning and
there are standard library functions
such as mem copy that work that work
right on by byte level data
representation without knowing its
high-level type so C's aliasing rules
also make type error detection difficult
this is because a stored value can be
read by using pointers of different
types for example reading a stored value
using a a pointer of a character type
it's always allowed
besides addressing challenges related to
both detection precision problems there
are also several areas that we find
areas for future research that we find
promising composing Fanny titers would
help users to find bugs closer to their
source and help users to use resource
more efficiently and press more
importantly there's newly with newly
available hardware features such as
address tagging and memory tagging in
arm we may want to revisit some of the
precision and performance challenges
that the software based tool had to face
and it would also be interesting to see
whether research in user space
sanitizers extend to non user space
programs such as OS kernels with that
I'd like to thank you all for your
attention I'm happy to take any
questions
[Applause]
anyone with questions please step
forward to the microphone okay I guess
we have no questions thank you very much
oh we do have a question
so Mike since you're the advisor I'll
save your question right I'll ask it so
well you mentioned those potential
future directions on those are something
big right can you share some actual
thoughts in terms of doing this in the
tech architecture or even composition
compositions is such a big word that's a
difficult question actually so so the
main problem is that there are so many
research tools there but they're really
not comparable with like real world
programs that's kind of hindering
adoption so I think I think there is
room for research especially like
performance is not a major concern for a
sanitizer and trying to answer some of
the precision problems by sacrificing
performance probably that might also be
a possible future direction some
concrete so I think I do want to add
that you know so performance is not a
concern but if you start layering these
things on top of each other then at some
point possibly people will not want to
do this anymore right so if you have
three sanitizers each of them gives you
three X at some point you know but where
do people want to draw the line I I
don't know yeah okay so thank you very
much again thank you all for coming
thanks to the speakers