good morning everyone today I would like
to present our research on challenges
pitfalls and perils of using hardware
performance counters for security this
work was done in collaboration with John
Warner Manos antonio khakis nicolas
polychronic is Fabien Montrose my name
is Sanjeev dass I'm a postdoc in
University of North Carolina Chapel Hill
modern processors provide a unique
ability to visualize Hardware related
activities through a special set of
registers called Hardware preference
counters they are available in
processors for more than two decades
they are used to monitor and measure
Hardware events such as instructions
memory accesses cache hits misses
translation lookaside buffer hits and
misses they have been used in many
application domains such as software
profiling debugging high-performance
computing power analysis and we have
seen recent rise in the use of reference
counter in security domain at species
provide a good foundation for measuring
microarchitecture and information that
are typically not available by any other
traditional tools for example branch
misses cache misses moreover they this
information can be obtained at a very
low performance overhead given these
advantages it's no surprise that it has
been used in security applications for
various purposes such as malware
detection rope detection rootkits
development side channel attacks so the
talk on Spector even for recent
side-channel and attacks such as
spectral emailed on researchers have
looked into how performance can be used
to defend these attacks
given the wide popularity of performance
counters I got an idea can we use
performance counters to defeat data only
attacks joining the new research who had
the good experience on data only attacks
and since I have some I had some good
experience working on performance
counter I thought it would be a quick
win for me we can quickly write a paper
and impress the group working on this
idea we encountered several challenges
there are hundreds of performance
counter events understanding micro
architectural interaction is a daunting
task which which are and more of these
events are related to one another so the
bigger question was which events should
we choose to model the data early
attacks
moreover there are many different
frameworks built using hardware
performance counters and the collection
techniques varies across these these
frameworks so the another question
raised is is there a standard way to
collect performance counter measurement
after spending weeks on these challenges
we encounter more substantial problems
we found the seminal work by Weaver and
McKee which highlighted the
non-determinism issues in performance
counter measurement of given by
preference counter varies across
different runs
non-determinism issues drove us crazy
we are baffled on top there is lack of
application level profiling of
performance counter data at the hardware
level I felt to be on the edge of the
cliff a quiquina idea turned out to be
Herculean task we thought of it and we
realize these issues cannot go unnoticed
this beat falls must have been
encountered by other researchers as well
thus we started looking into the
literature and we wanted to understand
if they have been addressed how can we
use them in our approach therefore after
spending two months full-time into the
literature survey we analyzed our own
hundred papers from different
application domains such as debugging
power analysis performance analysis and
security to supplement our understanding
of how performance
counters can be used by different
approaches we sent questionnaire to the
authors even though response turnout was
not very high of these hundred papers
fifty-six papers where those papers that
specifically acknowledged the
non-determinism issue
they were mostly from non security
application domains which initially
where the users of hardware preference
counter quite surprisingly we found that
45% of these papers did have reservation
of using performance counters they they
do not recommend using preference
counter because of two reasons one lack
of determinism in the performance
counter and two lack of portability of
performance counter events across
different micro architecture some events
could be present in one
microarchitecture but may not be
available in the another architecture
thus my initial idea of using a hardware
preference counter for data only attacks
defense was doomed next we look into 40
security papers that has recently used s
pcs we found that only 10% of them
acknowledged non-determinism issues some
of them argued that their approaches are
not affected by non determinism
it made us it made us constantly go back
and rethink Hardware performance can be
trusted which was initially raised which
was the initial issue raised by Weber
and McKee ten years earlier going
through the literature survey we found
two common failures that has been
followed by many security approaches one
mishandling upper phones counted data
this mainly occurs because of lack of
process level filtering at the hardware
level and the other main his issue was
ignored ins of ignoring non determinism
issues non determinism mostly
because of two reasons skid and over or
under counting of the events to
understand these issues in detail let us
walk through hope reference counter data
is collected from the hardware there are
limited number of programmable counters
that can be configured to a specific set
of events the configuration is done in
the kernel mode there are two modes to
read the counter data poling and
sampling in polling mode one can read
the counter data at any given point of
time for sampling mode a specific
interrupt is provided by the performance
monitoring subsystem called preference
monitoring interrupts it can be
configured to trigger trigger the
interrupt after certain after n
occurrence of this event as one would
expect
first the event has to be configured in
the sample mode such as after an
instruction retired as the program
begins execution after n instructions
the performance monitoring interrupt
isn't rated at this point of time all
the counter values can be read now we
look into how performance counter data
has been mishandled by many approaches
as this as discussed earlier this is
mainly because of lack of process level
filtering at the hardware level many
approaches take a shortcut and try to
filter the process at the interrupt
level to demonstrate that let's say a
process executes and interrupts is
triggered at the interrupt one can
measure the a one can observe whether
this belongs to process a or not using
process ID etc however after context
switch there is another process that
comes into execution and again one can
observe whether the current processes
process a or no not however there is a
pro
when once we identify that this is frost
this is not process a we may disregard
that counter data and this can lead to a
loss of events from performance process
a similarly when the process a resumed
execution at constructs context which
and we observe we observe whether a
current processes process a or not we
might might incorporate noise from
process P however there is a an easy fix
one can save the province counter data
at the context switch and can restore
the province counter data before process
a resume the execution but many papers
did not follow this is this small fix
and this is especially hard harder in
some some of this operating system such
as Windows operating system which is
closed source and it requires the
changes in the kernel which which might
might not be trivial another main issue
in performance counters is the skid skid
is the most frustrating issue and most
difficult to deal with it occurs in the
sampling mode the PMI is not delivered
at the time it has it is raised there is
a late delivery of the interrupt which
leads to various in in the measurements
for example let's say sampling is done
configured to be done at every end D TLB
misses however that PMI is delivered at
n plus 10 or n plus 30 this leads to a
nice kid and this typically affects
certain applications such as data only
attacks for example this may be because
the signature lies in a small code
segment in Edison to his kid nan de
tourism may occur due to other reasons
to dig further into non determinism
issues we revisited the work done by we
were at all we performed the empirical
analysis using their benchmarks we added
new benchmarks we found that some issues
has been fixed in the newer processes
however some issues still persist we
also found that there are some new
issues base Falls peaceful leads to our
counting of instructions after working
on several papers I'd go I got buried
into the baseball's why do these issues
matter for security perspective and
improper uses of performance counters in
security application can be disastrous
for example incorrect data can Delic
data collection can lead to a in
correctness of the approach similarly an
advances adversary can use the non
determinism and for example they can
trigger pace falls to undermine the
defenses to demonstrate that we saw our
case study on malware detection module
classification we selected the
state-of-the-art approach proposed by
Tang at all for following their approach
we sample every we sample events every
end instruction retard
and we try to see how incorrect data
handling can lead to any correctness of
the approach we perform multi-class
classification using machine learning
approach we found that incorrect data
collection can impact impact detection
accuracy for certain malware families
the discrepancy between the two of the
discrepancy is almost more than 30% in
some of the cases even handling data
correctly doesn't have a higher accuracy
this begs a question rhpc is a good
foundation for malware detection we
refer the audience to the concurrent
work done by Joe at all which was
published in ACS CCS however the title
speaks for itself we also perform a
another case study on rope detection for
detecting return-oriented programming
attacks
the most that Wang and Baker proposed a
state-of-the-art approach where the
basic idea is that the rope attacks have
higher number of return instruction per
total instructions executed which allows
them which allows us to set a threshold
value such that these attacks can be
detected besides they rope attack also
incur lot of return misses within a
small section of the code to demonstrate
that let's say we have to probe
performance counters instructions and
return rope gadgets execute in the chain
and we can observe that just four six
written instruction then the total the
total number of instructions is less
than say only 16
this helps to figure out the rope attack
now is demonstrate that an advanced
adversity can trigger the pace falls by
embedding manipulator gadgets inside the
rope chain and can bypass the detection
the point to be noted here is that
irrespective of the parameter choices
base Falls can still be leveraged to
bypass such detection the boat mode for
more technical details we defer the
audience for two hours paper in
conclusion performance contours offer a
powerful capability however
Davises in the detail we cannot blindly
apply preference counter for critical
applications such as security defenses
one has to take care of direct way of
handling reference counter data and
knowledge issues such as non determinism
to guide the future work on this on
performance counter we provide
recommendations to correctly use
performance counter in our paper thank
you for listening I will talk any case
you have questions come to the center
member state your name hello my name is
Erica Leal I'm from the University of
Texas at Arlington using your
recommendations to use HBC's regarding
security where do you see the future of
that so it depends for critical
applications such as security defenses
we cannot allow more more inaccuracies
so for tolerating those noises because
of the non determinism or incorrect
non-deterministic effects it would be
very hard to implement that it would be
not not good for those defenses defense
mechanisms because those can impact the
inner accuracy of the approach whereas
if an if an approach can tolerate the
non-determinism effects and if the data
can be handled correctly at the at the
context switches and all then I think
those applications can be using security
can be using preference counter
so I have a question so you know those
we're gonna find out next with the
eviction set talk sometimes what's good
for defenses are also good for attacks
namely if I have a fine-grained notion
of time or events it that may be good
for having a low cost defense that uses
hardware primitives but it also might be
good for attacks that want to create a
side channel or covert channel do you
what you what are your feelings about
this trade space yes I think since the
attacks needs to be done only once the
success through it can be low in the
attacks I think one can use attacks
performance counter for attacks that
would be more beneficial for the
advanced adversity however for the
defense where we need to have a high
accuracy we cannot allow the defense
mechanism to break because of the
manipulation of the events I would
suggest it's better for the attack
mechanism great Thank You Sanjeev
everybody thank our speaker
[Applause]