okay and thank you miss for that enter
we were both hit Purdue and of course
Matthias who is now at EPFL so this talk
is going to be concerned with mitigating
control flow hijacking so at blue hat
this year Microsoft made the interesting
disclosure that 70% of their bugs are
still memory corruption vulnerabilities
and these bugs are interesting because
the control and data planes are
interleaved as I sort of have a little
illustration here where the gray cells
are data and the green cells are the
code pointers so you can imagine that if
you have a memory corruption in your
data it can overflow into a code pointer
which allows an adversary to redirect
the control flow of your application so
we would really like is a defense that
allows us to at least logically separate
the control and data planes as
illustrated here so when thinking about
code pointers which are the subject of
attack for these control flow hijackings
they sort of come in to two different
varieties
first there are forward edge pointers
these are function pointers or virtual
calls in C++ there's a well known
defense for these called control flow
integrity that works by statically
calculating target sets to limit where
these indirect calls can go in practice
so to see how this works consider a
function pointer that's being used to
make an indirect function call and
without any defense it can target every
executable byte in the program but when
you apply CFI analysis you restrict this
to some limited set of functions within
the program this analysis runs into some
trouble because there can be a wide gap
between when a function pointer is
written and when it is actually used for
the call
which means you run into all sorts of
the typical static analysis problems
with alias analysis etc trying to
connect the exact set of function
pointer rights that might flow to a
given indirect call site the next class
of code pointers are backwards edge and
in particular these are return
instructions so a natural question is
does CFI analysis style style analysis
work on the backwards edge and so you
know it's the same sort of setup you
have a return
destruction and we where can it go - and
the answer is of course you know every
call site in the function that might you
know called the function that you're
returning from and so the answer is
really no CFI style analysis does not
work for the backwards edge and the
reason is that because you have to
include every call site for the function
if you're doing static analysis and the
target set you end up with these huge
target sets potentially for especially
for popular say library functions and as
control flow bending and control jujitsu
have shown the larger these target sets
get the more insecure they are in
practice and so we feel strongly that
for backwards edges these sets are too
large to provide meaningful security and
practice and that doing security really
requires integrity for return addresses
and so yes so sort of to sum up the
state of control flow hijacking
mitigation today over the past 10 years
there have been 50-plus papers on
control flow hijacking dating back to a
body at all seminal paper which did
include a call for a shadow stack
unfortunately subsequent research lost
focus on this and only paid attention to
the forward edge problem which means
that now that we are getting deployed
versions of CFI by microsoft and google
they only cover the forward edge and we
have no equally strong protection for
the backwards edges that is being
deployed today and so our solution to
this is shadow sacks this is a
well-known research area which is why
we're writing an SOP on it trying to
promote awareness to get people to
actually deploy shadow stacks in
practice shadow stacks work by
separating return addresses from the
data plane which allows us to provide
integrity for the return addresses and
it turns out that these are performant
and highly compatible in practice and so
the punchline here is that we need to
deploy shadow stacks with control flow
integrity to have the complete
mitigation against control flow
hijacking attacks so to illustrate why
we need shadow stacks I'm going to go
through a control flow hijacking attack
in a little bit of detail here here we
see the program stack with one stack
frame it has the return address
a stack canary stack Canaries are the
strongest currently deployed protection
for return addresses that are designed
to present you know splashing the stack
for fun and profit style attacks that
use a contiguous buffer overflow to
directly overwrite the return address so
if you put the stack canary which is the
sort of magic value in the middle and
you can then see if it's been
overwritten and if it's been directly
overwritten you can detect an attack so
also on the stack frame here I'm I've
put in a pointer and an array so as you
might imagine we're going to write to
the array and eventually our buffer
overflow is going to happen which allows
the attacker to control the value of a
pointer if there is subsequently an
attacker controlled right through this
pointer the attacker can bypass the
stack canary entirely and directly
overwrite the return address say
changing it to a pointer to a rob gadget
or you know at the beginning of a sled
of such gadgets to perform their attack
so what is the shadow stack a shadow
stack is a way of as I mentioned
separating the return addresses from the
normal program stack so here we can see
the program stack which has a collection
of stack frames on it or call frames on
it for the different functions which
include the return address and any
information needed for local variables
etc and on the shadow stack what we're
going to do is pull out the return
information so that it is separate and
you know not subject to these buffer
overflows etc so to see how this defense
works we'll return to our previous
example here where we're midway through
it so the attacker has already written
over written the return address but now
instead of returning and using this
attacker controlled value we instead
compared the program return the return
address on the program stack to the
shadow return address and if they
mismatch we can detect an attack and we
can take any action we like in response
to this typically people just terminate
the program but you can imagine more
sophisticated recovery policies so the
key advantages of shadow stacks are that
you know at runtime what function you
were called from which means that we can
move from the static style of CFI
defenses that are trying to pre-compute
target sets to a more dynamic defense
that is focused on remembering the
return addresses correctly so there's no
guessing or pre calculation required
here simply by separating the code and
data planes for backwards edges we end
up with this very strong defense for
return addresses and in particular it's
fully precise again because of this
dynamic nature of the information where
the call happens before the return so
you know where you're supposed to return
to if you can only preserve that
information in the program so here this
is an S okay so I'm going to briefly
introduce the shadow stack design space
before moving to our recommended shadow
stack for deployment so there are two
main methods of mapping from the program
stack to the shadow stack starting with
on the right side of the screen here the
indirect mapping so here you are
maintaining two stacks which means that
for every call instruction which pushes
the return address to the program stack
you have to add instrumentation to also
push the return address to the shadow
stack and similarly for returns you're
going to get two pops because you're
maintaining two logical stacks the
advantage of this approach is that your
shadow stack is very small it only has
to be as large as needed to store the
return addresses and maybe the stack
pointers to support recursion and so
forth the alternate scheme is direct
mappings so here you're only maintaining
one logical stack there's only the
program stack that you're going to push
to and pop from but you're going to
create a shadow stack that is as large
as the program stack which means there's
a direct one-to-one mapping or
correspondence or mirroring from the
program stack to the shadow stack so
given any byte in the program stack you
do a little bit of arithmetic to say add
a constant and you directly arrive at
the relevant shadow stack address which
means that once you push to the the
return address to the program stack it's
very natural to propagate it to the
shadow stack without having to do this
additional data structure maintenance
the so this is sort of trying to do a
performance versus memory trade-off
where you're trading the extra memory of
allocating
the shadow stack that is as large as the
program stack but hoping to get better
performance because the mapping is
simpler
so our recommended shadow stack turns
out to be an indirect mapping that uses
a general-purpose registered to shore
this to store the shadow stack pointer
and we find that this leads to optimal
performance in terms of both processing
time and memory use and high
compatibility and I'll now walk through
why this turns out to be so so for the
mapping the indirect mapping to evaluate
this we took all existing techniques and
a for shadow stacks and a couple more
that we identified as missing during our
survey we implemented them all in LV m7
and went and did some quantitative
analysis and found that when using a
general purpose register the indirect
mapping can be as performant as a direct
mapping and because it also saves memory
space obviously we go for this because
it's a rare case of having our cake and
eating it too because the fastest
mapping also has the lowest memory
overhead so as I mentioned we're
recommending using a general purpose
register for the shadow stack pointer
during there's been lots of discussion
about you know does this lead to
increased register pressure is this
going to be terrible for performance and
the answer turns out to be no that on
64-bit architectures which have 16
general-purpose registers all
applications we evaluated not only the
spec CPU 2006 benchmarks but also a wide
variety of image processing and other
desktop applications from fir onyx as
well as the engine Dex web server there
was no you know huge performance hit
from using a general purpose register
and in fact it was the fastest scheme so
the takeaway here is the dedicating a
register to the shadow stack pointer is
actually an infective optimization
across a very wide range of applications
so the last issue here is compatibility
which we evaluated along three
dimensions the first is support for
threading so of course every thread in
the program has its own stack and you
need to have be able to support a shadow
stack or program thread as well you
a general purpose register to sword the
shadow stack pointer this is very
natural because general purpose
registers are thread-local and so each
you know thread has its own copy of this
which points us to the relevant shadow
stack for that thread and everything
works nicely the next issue is stack
unwinding which is mainly used for C++
exception handling although there are
some other uses the interesting thing
here is that calls and returns are no
longer a one-to-one correspondence
when you have a leaf function that
throws an exception you might unwind
multiple stack frames and thus you know
have multiple calls that don't have a
matching return because we're directly
going further up the stack until the
exception is handled so this turns out
to be a non-trivial but not
fundamentally interesting engineering
challenge to deal with and we provide an
instrumented version of Lib unwind and
set jump and long jump to handle this
similarly for unprotected code there's
this issue that when you cross the
protection barrier you have to save your
shadow stack pointer and again we
provide a solution for this and so the
punchline again is that we support all
applications and incremental deployment
so we really believe that shadow stacks
are mature enough to start being
deployed with control flow integrity so
we've talked some about separating the
code and data planes and so there's this
interesting question of now that we have
our return addresses in a separate
location can what additional security
can we provide for them and in
particular because they're separated out
we can provide integrity protection
return addresses have this nice property
that they're only supposed to be written
by call instructions which means there's
a very you know narrow window that we
can identify what the correct rights are
that should be allowed in our shadow
stack so to do integrity enforcement on
the shadow stack there are three
techniques that we were able to identify
the first is a software-based
randomization technique unfortunately as
shown by research on ASLR these are
defeasible and practiced through
information leaks and other techniques
so then we looked at two hardware based
schemes that we hoped would provide more
sound protection
good performance overhead this did not
turn out to be the case the first one we
looked at was Intel's memory protection
extensions or MPX this provides hardware
support for doing bounds checking and so
as shown in our previous paper see fix
at nd ss-18 you can turn isolating a
region of process memory into a balanced
checking problem at moderate performance
overhead the newest scheme that we
looked at here has intel's memory
protection keys this is a cool new
hardware feature that allows you to
assign virtual pages or ranges of
virtual pages to one of sixteen groups
they then provide an unprivileged
hardware instruction to toggle the
read/write permissions for all virtual
pages in that group with a single
instruction as opposed to having to do a
in protect call that has a page table
walk-in ends up with huge amounts of
overhead unfortunately when you use the
mpk instructions across the call and
return boundary for whatever reason you
end up with terrible performance
something they've done microarchitecture
only so none of these are really fully
satisfactory we need new hardware
solutions on this issue of doing intra
process memory isolation comes up not
only for shadow stacks but for any
defense that wants to maintain some sort
of dynamic state information about the
application for instance the type safety
defenses come to mind here personally
I'm a big fan of tagged architectures
and believe that they will provide a
interesting and performant way to do
this in the future so finally I just
want to sort of wrap up by highlighting
some of our performance evaluation
results I'm running short on time so
I'll go a little bit quickly here but
the punchline here is that our
recommended shadow stack has 3.65
overhead on average and that this is
lower than the you know direct shadow
stack mapping which was previously
thought to be the most performant and
then here are the overheads for the
different integrity enforcement
mechanisms that we just talked about
where randomization adds about a percent
and then MPX comes in at 12% an MP
61% but it has this huge outlier of 420
percent in some cases so in conclusion
the stack remains vulnerable to code
reuse attacks solution for this is to
separate return addresses from the data
plane and to do so we recommend using a
compact register base shadow stack and
really the key takeaway from this talk
is that you need to combine shadow
stacks with control flow integrity to
have complete and practical control flow
hijacking mitigation our code is
available or will be available shortly
at this URL on github and with that I'm
happy to take any questions thank you
awesome - 2 second 16 minutes any
questions yes please because currently
need Google have you thought at all
about the hardware shadow stack
implementations like intel has I think
it's C yes eet will be great if and when
they ever actually manufacture it and of
course it will only apply to x86 so
there's this question of how do you
protect arm what do you do for legacy
processors and so forth so even with
hardware support emerging they're still
going to be at least a rather large
window where shadow stacks and software
base defenses are necessary thank you hi
I'm near from Intel that was exactly my
question so I'll ask another one can you
comment on Harvard vs. von Neumann as
far as separation goes if you're
designing something new you said
Hardware diversity
I'm sorry hard hard word versus buying
women there are two kinds of
architectures Oh Harvard in von Neumann
excuse me sorry yes so I think from a
security perspective a Harvard
architecture would have been better
although I understand historically there
were excellent reasons at the time for
doing the von Norman approach of mixing
code and data
which is why I think we're sort of at
the point now where what we really need
is a logical if not necessarily a
physical separation of the two thank you
hey man we regulate Boston University
this was very amazing I like the stuff a
lot I had one question you said you
implemented the various schemes that he
found in LOM seven so what did you do
with the libraries that were linked into
those binaries did you also recompile
all of those so when we were evaluating
things we recompiled
Lib C for some of the others that had
dependencies we did not we looked at
recompiling all of FreeBSD for full
support and just weren't quite able to
make it work in time for the deadline
any other questions okay let's think
nice Megan
[Applause]
[Music]