thank you so much for that introduction
my name is Marcela Hastings and this is
an S okay
so I'm gonna be talking about the
results of our survey so the tool we
were looking at was secure multi-party
computation this is a cryptographic tool
that allows a group of mutually
distrustful parties to compute an
arbitrary function on their joint inputs
without revealing anything beyond the
output of the computation so the most
famous example of this in practice is
the Danish beat auction in this setting
we have sellers who are Danish beat
farmers and a single buy or the only
beat processing facility in Denmark the
sellers have prices at which they're
willing to sell their beats and the
buyer wants to find a market clearing
price but the sellers might not want to
reveal their bids because it could
reveal information about their
businesses and their farms especially
over several years so they use secure
multi-party computation to find an
appropriate market clearing price
without revealing the value of their
bids another example is a collaboration
with the Boston Women's workforce
Council which is studying the gender and
racial wage gap companies might not wish
to reveal or might be legally prevented
from revealing financial information
about their employees but by using
secure multi-party computation they're
able to compute the relevant statistics
and analytics without giving up that
data now all of this is to say that
secure multi-party computation is a tool
that's efficient and practical enough to
be used in real situations however many
of the practical examples we've seen in
the past have required a team of
cryptographers to implement a
special-purpose MPC engine for that
specific use case and if we want to see
NPC it have more widespread adoption we
need tools that are usable by the
layperson so although algorithms for MPC
have been around since the 1980s they
were assumed to be too inefficient for
practical use until the fair play
compiler was presented in 2004 this was
the first general-purpose framework
which could take an arbitrary function
and execute MPC on it and it started the
beginning of a huge and fruitful field
performance improvements over the
decades rapidly advanced the state of
the art both algorithmic and in the
implementations and the number of end to
end frameworks exploded in the past
decade so in this work we're looking at
general-purpose end to end frameworks
and so end end frameworks looks
something like this
they have two phases a compiler and a
runtime this is because most MPC
algorithms operate on only a limited set
of primitives like addition and
multiplication Mata Prime and it's hard
for a developer to reason about
interesting computations using that very
limited model so we looked for
frameworks that have a compiler which
takes a function description in a
high-level language and converts it into
a representation that can be executed by
the algorithm then the runtime phases
the actual execution of the protocol it
is run simultaneously by multiple
parties and who each take the output of
the compiler and the private inputs of
each party and compute the function
output and of course the architecture
varies a lot based on different
frameworks but they're all taking this
general shape so in this survey we
wanted to ask some questions about where
we are where the frameworks are you know
who can use them are they ready for real
computations can they express
interesting functions and you know can
they be used for real situations in
order to answer these questions we
surveyed nine frameworks and to end
frameworks and to circuit only compilers
we recorded different features of them
based on the protocol that they
implement the data types and operations
that they support and other details of
the implementations and we evaluated
them on a variety of usability criteria
in order to collect all this data we
implemented three sample programs in
every framework so we collected our
sample programs plus complete build
environments for every framework that we
used and put them into an open source
framework repository this also has
additional documentation based on our
experiences using the framework we
estimate this repository took about 750
person hours to produce
and it is open source and we're actively
maintaining it so I encourage anyone to
check it out now I'd like to talk a
little bit about what we found after
doing all this work over almost
frameworks are in good shape we have a
diverse set of threat models and
protocols that they implement so
depending on a year use case there are
different options we are able to
implement our sample programs and almost
every framework which means that the
high level languages are expressive for
many situations and overall most of them
were open source and compilable and
usable however we did find two major
areas for improvement one is that there
were significant engineering limitations
for example complicated build systems
and the other is significant barriers to
usability which are mostly rooted in a
lack of documentation so before I go
into those issues I'd like to give you a
higher level picture of what we found so
these are the nine frameworks we looked
at and the two circuit compilers at the
bottom you can see the number of parties
they support in the threat model we have
two threat models here in the semi
honest model and adversary is going to
execute the protocol correctly but we'll
try to learn something about other
parties in put in the malicious model a
party the adversary may not stick to the
protocol and will try to induce an
incorrect output we also created a loose
taxonomy of three different protocol
families which I'm going to talk a
little bit about the first is garbled
circuit protocols these are first
introduced in the 1980s by Andrew Yau
and work have been essentially
continuously developed since then
well theorists have produced a wide
variety of settings in the garbled
circuit model we found in practice that
they're almost all implemented as semi
honest two-party protocols where one
party garbles are encrypts the circuit
and sends it to the other party who
evaluates it based on their input and
these typically represent functions
using boolean circuits the second type
encompasses a wide variety of protocols
which we call multi-party circuit based
protocols now these are protocols that
have two things in common the first is
that they implement they represent
functions using a circuit either
arithmetic or boolean and the second is
that data is represented as linear
secret shares so the linear secret
sharing means that these protocols can
typically support an arbitrary number of
parties where the parties work together
going gate through gate gate by gate
through the circuit to convert secret
shows of the inputs to secret shows of
the outputs however within this model
the way that they do this conversion can
be executed in different ways may be
information theoretic or
cryptographically secure models now we
expected these two protocol families to
cover the majority of implementations
however so in theory most theoreticians
define MPC protocols again on a very
limited set of functions of operations
either addition and multiplication mod
an integer or bitwise and an XOR however
in practice and these are universal
representations so you can express any
function using that however in practice
you can often define optimized sub
protocols for common functions that you
have like division or comparison in an
arithmetic model that are more efficient
than reducing all the way that these
very low level primitives so we found
three protocols that improve that
implement certain sub protocols and we
call these hybrid protocols and then at
the bottom you can see our two circuit
compilers now one major thing that
people need to consider when they're
choosing an appropriate framework for
their use case is the level of
abstraction of the high level language
so we saw a variety of these and I want
to walk through a couple of them the
example we're gonna use as one of our
sample programs which is the inner
product it takes the sum of the pairwise
product of two vectors so frigate is a
circuit compiler and it uses a pretty
traditional C style abstraction you can
see a implementation of the inner
product here you take a result and then
you loop over your vectors for each
element in your vector you multiply them
together and add them to your sum now
this is pretty straightforward and makes
a lot of sense however if you're
familiar
MPC you might recognize that in a linear
secret sharing based model you can
paralyze all the multiplications into a
single round of communication so if you
want to have that optimization and you
might use something like pico pico
recognize that you can do this
optimized multiplication step and so
they implement a custom primitive this
is one of our hybrid languages for the
inter product operation and you can see
you just use this very simple infix
custom infix operator to execute an
inner product on any size vectors now
this is really good if you're not super
familiar with the cryptography and you
don't really care what's happening under
the hood however if you are a
photographer and you're working on
perhaps a more complicated function than
the inner product you might want to have
more control over exactly the circuit
that you're gonna have produced in that
case you might prefer a framework like
ABY ABY is implemented as a is an
end-to-end framework it's implemented as
a library in C so you can see we have a
share type that holds our private data
we put a multiplication gate in and ABY
does implement these parallel parallel
eyes multiplications so you need a
single multiplication gate to do pair
wise multiplication across your whole
vectors and then you sort of break apart
your vector representation to add up the
individual elements now this gives you a
lot more freedom to do exactly the thing
that you want to do but if you have less
cryptographic familiarity you might not
want this much power so that's sort of
the range of front end high-level
languages that we saw the next thing I
want to talk about some of the
limitations as I mentioned software
engineering was a major issue you have
to keep in mind that most of these
frameworks were developed in academic
settings and are therefore subject to
the engineering constraints of such a
setting so keep that in mind as I go
through the next couple of things one
major pain point was the build systems
which tended to be extremely complicated
you often had to compile a specific open
SSL version from source which takes a
long time or set up a custom certificate
authority to ensure private channels and
your
communication an average it took us one
to two weeks just to compile the
existing frameworks this is very
frustrating but luckily for everyone
else we've put this all in our doctor
repository so no one should ever have to
do this again beyond these build systems
though these are significant software
projects that require a lot of software
development in addition to implementing
cryptographic protocols which is
notoriously difficult to do correctly
programmers have to implement a variety
of supporting systems like distributed
communication and interfacing with other
systems that you no other communication
systems and insecure languages this
results in just small but frustrating
things for example in Oblivion we
weren't able to write a computation that
returned more than 32 bits you know this
is a problem that could be solved with
more hands on keyboards and some time
but given the constraints of the
academic setting not all the frameworks
have these kinds of engineering
perfection the other major issue we saw
was Muse ability and especially in
documentation we defined five types of
documentation which you can see here
half the frameworks had no more than
three of these I'm not gonna go through
all these different types in detail but
I do want to give you a few examples of
places where there were limited language
documentation that made it more
difficult to use the frameworks the
language documentation is anything that
describes how the high-level language
works so CBM CGC is a circuit compiler
that consumes it compiles a subset of an
zc so most people are familiar with
seeing you'd assume that a simple
program like this which multiplies two
numbers together would just work however
we get an error that says did you forget
to return a value it turns out that in
CBM cgc all private inputs of the
computation have to have variable names
that start with input and this isn't an
issue but it wasn't written down so we
had to sort of figure it out another
examples from oblivion again we this is
an end-to-end framework that consumes a
Java like language and again we have our
program to multiply two numbers together
and it encounters a parsing error it
turns out that Alice and Bob are
reserved key words in the language and
so you can't use them as variable names
wisteria is an end-to-end framework that
was developed by programming languages
people and so it uses a novel functional
representation and they include an
extensive language guide for people who
might not be as familiar with that
functional style however the language
Doc's this tutorial doesn't account for
the limitations in the parser so
developer has to put a lot more
parentheses and then the tutorial would
imply and then EMP toolkit is a
framework we really liked using it's a
garbled circuit based framework however
we found an average one comment for 600
lines of code with no additional
documentation in separate places so
these are all things that make it more
difficult to use these frameworks
however there were some frameworks that
did a really good job with documentation
I just like to thank them here we do
have two major takeaways for anyone who
maintains a large open source project
like this first is that having multiple
types of documentation even if it's
mediocre can drastically increase the
usability of your framework this could
be something like one document that
explains the architecture of your
framework and then a commented example
file that demonstrates some features of
your high-level language the other thing
we recommend is an online resource for
example a mailing list or a github issue
tracker these are a super sustainable
way to produce documentation for your
framework it creates a living FAQ so you
don't have to repeatedly answer
questions by a private email and it also
allows a place for users to interact so
they can answer each other's questions
and if you end up not maintaining your
framework users can still talk to each
other and find solutions to their issues
so looking forward even given these
engineering and usability challenges MVC
is in pretty good shape we were able to
implement lots of examples example
programs and you know overall things
pretty good these usability challenges
are acknowledged by the community the IR
per hectare program is funding the next
generation of MPC frameworks and they
have specific usability criteria
included in the grant we do recommend
that future developers consider working
with programming languages researchers
most of these frameworks were developed
by cryptographers and therefore the
front-end languages are perhaps not as
principled as they might be with if
somebody with extensive compiler
experience helped develop them and then
one last plug our repository is actively
maintained and we're accepting pull
requests from new and existing
frameworks if you maintain one of these
or would like to use this as a starting
point for your academic project we
encourage you to check it out and then
one last plug I am looking for projects
related to MPC in practice so if you are
a potential collaborator and you have an
interesting project please come talk to
me later thank you very much any
questions please come to the microphone
hello first thank you very much for all
this this was very much needed for the
community and I think it's a pretty
amazing work so I know that you did all
these great compendium of things and
then you got the good things and the bad
things of each but you didn't really
like give like a sort of like this is
the framework like this is the one we
say the community should continue we
didn't build it on top of this one or
something like that and I think it's
important like if you have some some
word than that because if not like what
people end up doing is like oh no there
are 12 standards let's try to
standardize this and of course you end
up with 13 sure so in the paper we do
give stronger recommendations as to
which frameworks we recommend if you're
looking for a specific recommendation
for a setting there are sort of four
that I would say stand out above the
rest for garbled circuit frameworks of
live C is a good general purpose
framework and EMP to look at is really
good
if you have a little more cryptographic
expertise and then scale Mamba is sort
of the best of the multi party or it's
actually a hybrid protocol so it's sort
of the best of these linear secret
sharing based protocols it's really
extensive and it's actively being
developed and then if you are a person
who has actual security needs you might
be interested in share mind this is the
only framework that has paid developers
working on it who are in academics so
those would be the sort of strong
recommendations I have so I'm actually
absolutely going to develop a
programming language in which Alice and
Bob are reserved words that's that's
cool okay thank you very much again
[Applause]