yeah thanks for the winter
and sorry about
hello everyone again I'm SATA moriyama
I'm presenting tapping ghost a
comparison of Naga attack techniques
against smartphone touchscreens this is
joint work with mr. Satya Wakabayashi
and my supervisor professor Satya Mori
was at the university hopping ghost
it's an attack against Android
smartphones and the attack connects the
attackers Bluetooth device or a Wi-Fi
access point to the victim smartphone
this attack consists of two techniques
the first one is an attack against NFC
enabled smartphones the other one is an
attack against capacitive touchscreens
of smartphones these techniques can be
covertly embedded into common objects
such as food furniture now I'll explain
how erotic works this time we assume
that the attacker implements the attack
in a wooden table and puts a table
somewhere in advance in this table in
NFC card emulator and a metal sheet are
embedded when the victim put the
smartphone on the table this NFC Cal
emulator requests the smartphone to pair
with attackers Bluetooth device then a
dialog box pops up on the screen as
shown in the slide this dialog box says
are you sure you want to pair the
Bluetooth device the victim will touch
the no bottom because they don't know
why this tile box pops up and they don't
want to pair with unknown Bluetooth
devices however using the metal sheet
embedded in the table
the attacker conducts the attack against
capacitive touchscreens then the
attacker can scatters a full touch event
as shown by the orange circles in the
slide and make the device act as wave
the other button or
yes button had to be in touched with a
certain weight so the victim smartphone
is paired with that I've got Bluetooth
device as a result the attacker can
fully take control of smartphone for
instance the attacker can install any
applications using our pet Brutus Mouse
and here is a short demo video as you
can see the attacker puts an NFC tag and
a metal seat there when I put my
smartphone on them a dialog box pops up
on the screen
and I touch the cancel button however
the smartphone is tricked into thinking
the connect button has been touched this
post message indicates that the connect
button has been touched and it means the
success of the attack in the following
slide I'm going to describe two attack
techniques that compose our attack first
I'll explain the latter attack technique
called stud generator the ghost touch
generator is an attack against
capacitive touchscreens among a variety
of touchscreen technologies we focus on
mutual capacitive touch screens because
they are widely used in smartphones a
controller of a mutual capacitive touch
screen consists of the grid of the
transmitter electrodes
TX and the receiver electrodes rx these
two types of electrodes are very close
together and walkers capacitors so the
alternating electric current from the TX
Electro's flows into the RX Electro's
when when a finger approaches a
touchscreen the finger also works as a
Kappa
so some of the current also goes into
the finger thus current that rose from
TX to rx
decreases by measuring this current
change that touchscreen concerns finger
touches and yeah here is what we did as
explained before the touchscreen sense
touches by measuring the electric
current change as the RX electrodes so
if the attacker injects noise signals
from the external metal sheet to the RX
electrodes the touchscreen detect
touches at locations where no real touch
is present we named this technique
called touch generator and yeah this is
a demo video of the gosset generator as
you can see the touchscreen works
properly at first however after the
attacker start injecting noise for study
band are scattered along the line where
the real touch is present we implemented
the ghost touch generator and tried to
attack seven smartphone models listed in
the slide as a result we succeeded in
causing force touch event in five out of
the seven models however we also found
that the noise frequency to call this
malfunction varies by smartphone model
here's a summary of the ghost touch
generator this attack technique
scattered false touch event on
touchscreens by injecting intentional
noise signals however to mount the
attack the attacker needs to identify
the victim the smartphone model in
advance now let me talk about the
the other technique before using the
ghost touch generator the attacker
employs the attack against NFC enabled
smartphones this technique requests a
victim smartphone to connect to the
attackers device via NFC also this
technique enables to retrieve
information which is indispensable to
the ghost touch generator such as victim
smartphone model so what is NFC NFC is
an abbreviation for Near Field
Communication it's communication range
is less than 10 centimeters taking
advantage of this short range the NFC
devices establish a connection just by
bringing devices close to each other
NFC is used in various things such as
credit cards smartphones and smart
posters NFC enabled under the
smartphones always look around for
nearby NFC devices when the smartphone
is held over an NFC tag it performs
various operations by reading the data
recorded in the NFC tag such as a
opening girl website connecting to a
Wi-Fi access point or pairing a
Bluetooth device before some risky
operations like the bluetooth pairing
Android OS shows the confirmation dialog
box as usual before and before using the
ghost touch narrator the attacker has to
do two things
identifying the victim in smartphone
model and requesting to connect to the
attackers device however each NFC tag
can launch only one operation so to deal
with this program the attacker
makes use of any
the emulation it mu it enables to
emulate an NFC tag and the dynamically
change its content so the attacker can
launch much more operations see can
surely the attacker can obtain
information and request a bluetooth
pairing by following these steps first
the attacker requests to open the
attackers website and this website
identifies the victim in smartphone
model from the user agent and tells it
to the attacker then the attacker
changes the content of NFC tag and
requests to pair with the attackers
Bluetooth device we call this technique
a tag based adaptive ploy now let me
summarize the two attack techniques that
compose our attack first
the attacker attacks victim in
smartphone via NFC in this attack the
attacker can get smartphone information
and we request a Bluetooth telling then
the confirmation dialog box pops up if
the yes button on the dialog box is
touched the attack is successful next
the smartphone next using the smartphone
model information the attacker attacks
the touchscreen of the victim smartphone
in this attack this smartphone is
tricked into thinking that the yes
button has been touched with about a 50%
chance consequently the attacker can
fully take control of the smartphone so
let's move on to the feasibility of this
wet our attack must make use of NFC the
communication range of which is short so
the attacker also succeeds if the victim
uses their smart phone near the table
you know
tabletop in which the attacker has
installed the attack device so to
evaluate the feasibility of the attack
we conducted a deceptive study in the
study
we asked 16 participants to sit at the
marshal's table without telling them
investigated how often the victims
device came within the attack range and
yeah the last picture shows with the
table that we used in the deceptive
study and the right figure shows a
result of the study this horizontal bars
in the right figure represents the
result for each participant and x-axis
represents a time from when the
participants sit at the table yeah so
let's take a look at the top bar the
black part in the bar indicates the time
when a participant was vulnerable to the
attack that is when the smartphone were
being unlocked and close enough to the
table to summarize a result 15 out of
the 16 participants presented several
opportunities to be attacked within 15
minutes when they used the smartphone at
the table based on the result of the
user study we evaluated overall success
probability of the attack and we found
that our attack had a 71 percent chance
of success if we assume 30 people take a
seat at the table and the attacker can
try the attack three times for each
person so we conclude that the threat of
the top and Ghost is feasible
in our paper we also proposed
countermeasures the first countermeasure
is to add user approval processes before
opening a website specified by an NFC
tag the Android OS should get users
confirmation then the attacker who don't
get to information about the smartphone
so they wouldn't be able to conduct
attacks against touchscreens the other
countermeasure is to detect the
malfunction on touchscreens the kosta
generator generates for studies with
characteristic spatial patterns so
identifying these patterns will help to
prevent the attack with the aid of jpcc
we share the result of our study with
several smartphone manufacturers
including Sony Ericsson Fujitsu and
sharp with one of the manufacturers we
performed an additional experiment using
their latest smartphone model and
confirmed that the attack was successful
on the device and they are in the
process of looking at at a possible fix
in conclusion topping ghost is a new
type of attack which exploits NFC and
touchscreens this attack connects the
attackers Bluetooth device or Wi-Fi
access point to the victim smartphone
and we have confirmed the feasibility of
the attack through user studies and have
provided possible countermeasures thank
you for your attention and I'd happy to
take any questions
please line up for questions and give
your name and affiliation hi my name is
near security researcher with intel you
mentioned spatial characteristics of the
attack
to what degree other was inherent in the
existing touchscreen technology are they
always horizontal that's the first part
of the question and then the second part
I'll get to ok so your question is why
why the force touch event appears on the
overlying horizon terrain
yes mmm this is because the ghost has
generator only affects the RX electrodes
which is touched by a finger so last
week so mm yeah if when when the finger
doesn't touch the touchscreen the noise
from the ghost touch generator only
changes the entire voltage of the
circuit so it doesn't change a electric
current flow as our works Electro's but
when the finger is attached the the when
the finger is touched the RX electro
laws it forms a loop sub kit including
rx electrodes so that is the ghost touch
generator is directly connected in
parallel with the erector erector laws
which is touched so so this is why the
first achievement appear on Orion or
corresponding rx electrodes so so this
is also why the area character oh sorry
the force touch event appears on the
horizon terrain
we used the smart touch screen that the
rx
Electro's installed horizontally so this
is sorry
understood yeah and had you considered
range extension as well of your attack
you considered ways of extending the
range of the attack yes yes yeah we
think this attack can be not only
smartphones but also other important
devices which have touchscreens
as something like electronic voting
machine or ATM or something like that
and nowadays many important many devices
have touch screens as a user interface
so we are seeking that the cost a
generator can operate to these machines
of each of touch screens thank you
defensively oh but I'm Hilary Orman and
I'm not from anywhere defensively what
what would protect the user how much
distance a kind of case stack of napkins
what would work yes in this attack the
ghost touch generator attack range is
longer than NFC communication range so
yeah to prevent the attack the users
don't the smartphone are close to the
table or that is longer than the NFC
communication range and NFC
communication range is about four
centimeters so if the big team
could hold their smartphone away of
longer than four centimeter they are
safe there was a question you should use
the mic otherwise okay well let's think
this speaker one last time then yeah
thank you