yeah thank you for the introduction okay
so this figures are just to show that
the problems have real real factory
floors have become the victim for cyber
crimes and more importantly comparing to
the traditional attacks that are
targeting at consumer systems these
attacks are different in a sense that
attackers are not only trying to make
profits but more importantly they want
to cause physical damage they want to
cause safety hazards learning from the
prior incidents we know that the PRC
actually is a major attack vector
so PRC stands for programmable logic
controller which is a core country unit
for the entire factory floor so safety
violations actually can be introduced
into the peers he called either by
accidentally by mistakes were
intentionally by attacks either way the
problematic code will eventually cause
damage to the infrastructure so knowing
this a great many of prior work actually
has aimed to automatically detect the
safety violations in individual Piercy's
however a common limitation of the prior
work is that they overlooked a important
fact that the industrial control system
is actually a highly collaborative
environment piercing is never working
alone so this photo actually shows our
tester that it so called smartest bet
it's a precise miniature of automotive
production line sexually developed by
domain experts from rockwell automation
which is a number-one manufacturing
vendor as you can see even within this
small scout system it has already
included a lot of a different components
he has a PRC and also has multiple CNC
machines each of which is also equipped
with a small TRC
and we also have multiple robots which
are programmed to perform different
actions aside from all those
programmable units we also have some non
programmable units for example here we
have a circular conveyor bed and we also
have pallets that are moving on top of
this conveyor so these pallets are used
as containers to hold and carry these
parts and deliver these parts to
different CNC machines for processing
as a result PLC's are actually
intensively communicating and
collaborating with all the components on
the factory floor and a Piercy code is
actually driven by the external events
from other machines what that means is
that in order to be able to detect the
safety violations by testing PRC code we
also need to take all the external
inputs events into consideration so
essentially this is the contesting
problem for event-driven programs which
however is a well studied problems in
other domains for example Android
applications web applications in order
to understand how to test a Piercy code
which we can just first learn from this
prior work for example if we want to
wrong of what we found to test a Android
app what we can do is that we can first
a riding emulator and then we can a
model and assimilate into events as a
sequence to improve code coverage we can
further rearrange the order of the
events to generate different
permutations so all the sequences will
be used that you drive the program to
run and eventually help us to find the
bugs essentially we can do the same
thing for testing PRC so we can first
simulate the PRC execution and then
further simulate input events of course
we can rearrange their orders however in
practice what we have noticed
is that just a rearranging the order of
the events it's not sufficient to test a
Piercy code what we have observed here
is that two event sequences of the same
ordering may or may not cause a safety
problem because there are timings are
different to give you guys a more
concrete idea let's take a look at this
running example this is actually a
real-world problem that we have
discovered from our testable so here we
have a conveyor bed which is sending a
empty pallet or cell so this cell
consists of two CNC machines and a robot
the entire system is controlled by a
Piercy
so once this pallet has arrived at this
cell it will be blocked by a stopper
during this process five events will be
sent to Pier C and once Piercy has
received all these five events it will
trigger two actions first it will update
the state of the part which is actually
stored on the part once that is down
Pier C will receive a signal event six
update complete the second action is to
request the robot to pass a process
depart from the CNC machine to the
pallet and once that is down the
piercing will receive event seven part a
a conveyor so once both of these two
events are true then Piercy knows that
now the pallet has already been loaded
waits apart
you will then retract the stopper to let
it go
so notice that here this event seven
part of conveyor actually has another
purpose so when it is also used to
control the robot when the signal is on
the robot will always wait at the
conveyor bed only if it is turned off
meaning the part has already left of the
cell and the conveyor bed is now clear
then
robot can move towards a CNC machine to
prepare for another delivery however in
practice for the sake of a throughput we
don't want the the robot to always wait
at the Convair bad
instead we wanted to move towards the
sensi machine in advance right to save
some time for another delivery
regardless of whether the conveyor belt
is clear or not and therefore we will
proactively terminate this event 7
within 0.5 seconds nevertheless this
does not cause any problem in normal
situations the system works fine and it
conforms to our predefined safety rule
which requires that the time duration
between pallet arrival and a pallet
departure is no greater than 30 seconds
we further or formally define this
safety rule using T BTL time the
proposition no temporal logic however if
somehow the event servin happens very
early for example because of the
increase of a robot speed then what can
happen is that this signal will
terminate prematurely
even before the occurrence of event 6 in
this case there's actually no time
window when both of these two signals
can be - and even if the pallet has
already been loaded with a part the
piercing will never know and will never
retract the stopper to lead the pallet
go
this will definitely violate our safety
rule to detect such a problem let's
first reduce to try the traditional way
which is to generate event sequences
based on different ordering to test the
piercing code so for example we can
create a sequence like this right from
event 1 to event 7 so in this case
everything works fine then we can
rearrange the order of the events by two
five seven six so in this case something
wrong happens so this is actually
exactly the same as what we have seen
the lastest slide however such a
sequence may not always be able to cause
this problem for example we can create a
third sequence which actually shares the
same ordering as a second one five seven
six however since the event six actually
happens before the termination of event
seven ever since still works fine so
this actually explains that pure
ordering based event sequence generation
cannot sufficiently help us to discover
the safety violation seeing the PRC code
to solve this problem we proposed our
solution that PRC which can create timed
event sequences to do so we first
performed program analysis on tiers and
a robot code to extract the causal
dependencies among the events right so
this can help us to drew out the
impossible permutations and reduce
search space and then we further resort
to the avantime data that is collected
from our physical test beds and
performed data mining to extract timing
invariants for events so this timing
variants are corresponding to some
certain machine operations so eventually
this timed event sequences can help us
to perform testing now let's see how we
actually apply that PRC to our running
example so first of all we want to
perform program analysis in order to
extract the causal dependencies among
events however if we just look at the
PRC code what we can see is a bunch of
independent if clauses so which are
effectively the event handlers in the
PRC code we do
really have any knowledge how this
events are related to one another
to address that problem we further look
at the collaboration between the PRC and
a robot so in this case when the
parallel conveyor is forced in other
words the event negative particle varies
received the PRC will send a signal to
di zero which is the digital input zero
at the robot side upon receiving this
signal the robot will trigger a routine
in which you will first perform some
robot movements and eventually it will
send a signal to the digital output tube
which is then mapped back to the part a
conveyor event at the PRC sign so now we
know that there's actually a causal
dependency between these two events and
by further performing data mining we
know that the time duration between this
events two events is actually a soft
invariant which is actually
corresponding to the time cost to
deliver part and furthermore if we
consider the speed of reconfiguration
for the robot we can also computer the
theoretical bound for this deliver time
then by digging to the robot code
further we know that the event seven
actually can only last for 0.5 seconds
which is actually a constant hard-coded
in the robot program and again by
performing data mining we know that the
time duration between event five and
events 6 is also a temporary invariant
so there are some technical details due
to the time limit I just a do a flyby so
in order to model the crossover
relations among the events we actually
introduce this a timed event causality
graph so to build this graph we actually
borrow some idea from the N war graph
and eventually we perform
context-sensitive flow census of
interprocedural data flow analysis so
the detailed algorithm using our paper
and in terms of the data mining we also
follow some existing approach
particularly we follow the Synoptics
approach to determine the qualitative
relations between events and further we
leverage perfumes algorithm to determine
the quantitive relations between events
and eventually for this case we can
discover three temporary invariants so
now that we have butyl graph and we have
extracted the temporary invariants we
can leverage its knowledge to create
time to event sequences particularly for
those independent events for example in
this case the first five events which do
not bear any relations we can actually
arrange them in any order so when five
events are all received the time is T
and then further by leveraging the
knowledge from a data mining we know
that the event update
complete actually happens between time T
plus 15 two T plus 20 and further in
order to encode this attending timing
knowledge into event sequences we
discretize the continuous time range
into multiple slices and for each slice
we will create a version event so for
example here we can discretize this time
range into a three slice to two slices
and therefore create three versions
event so in in this time sequence we
only need to pick one and we can do the
same thing for another event parlare
come here the only difference is that
since we know this event only lasts for
0.5 seconds so we will a pro actively
terminates this signal accordingly so
here we actually can create this event
sequence that can actually cause
the safety violations that we have
discussed however another question
remains here is how do we discretize a
time range in a proper way so we will
answer that in our evaluation so our
evaluation is actually performed using
real-world physical test beds we
actually applied it to two different
test bed why is a smart house pair the
other is the fish technique which is a
smaller but more complex test today we
also have applied at that PRC to ten
different real-world scenarios in terms
in order to detect the real-world
problems so the first question we want
to answer in our evaluation is how many
event sequences that can actually be
created using different techniques so
this chart shows the result so the red
curve is a baseline which represents the
total amount of event sequences that can
be created using state of our technique
or sequence and so all sequence consider
only the event ordering by a consider
all possibilities when we further apply
program analysis to remove the
impossible permutations we Koide that
PRC sequence then we can reduce its
amount from the red curve to the green
curve furthermore when we apply time
discretization this amount will be
increased it will be increased from the
green curve to the orange curve to the
black curve and eventually to the blue
curve due to different granularities
so as you can see so this shows that the
time discretization actually increased
the amount of our general description
that the generate sequences to a large
extent especially with the highest
granularity however since we have
already applied the program analysis to
out
impossible permutations so the time
discretization with a median granularity
in other words this black curve can
still give us some reasonable numbers so
in the end we perform a comparative
experiments between state-of-art and the
PRC to see whether we can find real box
so for state of our technique we have
adopted to our algorithms or sequence
and versi sequence and for very PRC we
choose to still go with three different
parameters for the granite granularity
levels
the result is promising so while the
state apart pure ordering based the
event sequence generation cannot help us
to detect any safety safety violations
in our test abets that PRC which
different granularity selection can
always help us to detect those problems
and furthermore we noticed that when we
apply time discretization with different
granularities
the discovered error triggering ranges
are also different for example in
scenario 1 when we divide the time
duration into two slices then what we
can see is the problem may occur only
when the robots is running at his
maximal speed however if we improve the
granularity and divided the time
rearranged into five slices then we
women know that as long as the speed of
the robot is greater than 550 then the
error may occur so in general with
higher granularity we may get more
precise error trading ranges for the
discovered problems however in practice
empirically we also noticed that the
time discretization with a media
and granularity Canora already give us
some reasonable results and not to
mention that the amount of a generated
sequence is also acceptable so to sum it
up so we have studied the real-world ICS
test beds and got very important inside
so real-world PRC is event-driven and
timing sensitive to detect the safety
problems in such PRC so we developed a
system called their PRC which can
automatically construct time to event
sequences and the result is promising
so that PRC outperform state-of-art and
can detect the hidden safety problems
that cannot be discovered using the
prior techniques so with that I conclude
my talk and I'm happy to take questions
[Applause]
thank you I'm how from UC Davis you
mentioned that you used data mining to
find the timing information now do you
use that as a ground truth or do you use
as a starting point but you are going to
find the exact timing later uh we use
actually use their ground truth
okay so then my question I said because
it's data mining you may not have
observed all the states that's true so
will this cause false positive or false
negative or both in your approach some
say it's generally a challenging problem
so the coverage problem so for us it's a
best effort and also our focus is to
find out the timing variance that is
related to the Machine operations and in
our case those machine there there's
limited set of machines as long as our
system goes through all those critical
state
for the mushing operations then we can
guarantee the discovery for those timing
parents so we say guarantee which part
you guarantee together so for example we
want to look for the time cost to
deliver deliver part for example as long
as we in our in our data mining we
always go through that pass then we can
always observe that behavior so assuming
that your data mining is perfect then
you guarantee that the safety property
will never be violated that's true thank
you