good afternoon so this talk is focused
towards practical differentially private
convex optimization and this is joined
to work with my wonderful co-authors
that are listed on the screen so let me
start by briefly stating the
contributions of this work so the first
contribution is that we design a new
private algorithm which we call
approximate minimum ohter bation or amp
for short it is designed towards being
deployables in practice and it has many
advantages I'll describe in detail soon
the second contribution is that we
conduct a broad empirical study of the
state-of-the-art techniques in the field
we do this over 2 models and 13 data
sets four of which are high dimensional
and all of our benchmarks as well as the
code for a technique are open source and
available on the following link so in
this talk I'll start by providing some
motivation of why do we need privacy for
learning then I'll cover some background
first I'll introduce what is
differential privacy and give a quick
refresher on convex optimization then
I'll introduce our technique amp and
I'll conclude by presenting the results
of a study so that's the plan before I
dive in let me first define the
framework that will operate in so we are
given a sensitive data set D that is
input that is given as input to a
learning procedure a which gives out an
output model you can think of the output
model theta hat as a set of vector as a
vector of waits for some network many
recent works have shown that these
models can leak information about the
training data
these can be split into two broad
categories for example in membership in
Printz attacks an adversary can
confidently predict whether any sample
was introduced in the training process
by just access
the output model theta-hat so without
even looking at the data set by only
accessing the output model the adversity
can predict membership inference how do
we prevent such leaks so differential
privacy has been recently used as a gold
standard to prevent such leakage
let's start by intuitively understanding
what does the notion mean so we have a
data set D comprising of several members
that is input into a randomized
algorithm a which gives out some model
theta since a is randomized it has some
distribution over the set of outcomes so
here on the x-axis I am denoting the
model space each point represents some
model theta hat and the y axis denotes
the probability of algorithm a
outputting that particular model when
the input is data set deep imagine that
I change one person from the input
dataset so I have replaced ohm by Felix
let me denote this dataset by D Prime
since the dataset changes the
distribution over the outputs can also
change which is represented by the red
plot what differential privacy
guarantees is that the change for any
particular output is small so in some
sense the algorithm outputs each each
particular model with about the same
probability whether D or D prime was
used and effectively it does not depend
much on any particular individuals data
the definition is characterized by two
parameters epsilon and Delta it has a
mathematical precise formula but in the
interest of time I will just say that
epsilon bounds the multiplicative change
in the probabilities and it is standard
to consider epsilon as a small constant
whereas Delta bounds the additive change
and typically it vanishes with the data
size n its standard to consider Delta as
one over N squared
the important thing is as these
parameters go down the level of privacy
goes up a quick intro to convex
optimization and also to formalize the
notation we have a data set D that
consists of n samples from some
population we are given a loss function
L that's parameterize by a model and a
data set and the condition is the loss
function is convex in the first
parameter theta the goal is to output
the minimum of this loss function so the
goal is doubt output Teta hat such that
it minimizes the loss and this has many
applications ranging from machine
learning deep learning recommendation
systems many more so there has been a
lot of work in the area of
differentially private convex
optimization there is a technique called
objective perturbation which as the name
suggests it perturbs the input loss
function there are a couple of
techniques that add noise within the
training procedure itself and there are
a couple more that deal with the output
model they put up the output however
what is important to note is that two of
these techniques require the exact
minimum of the loss function that you
are optimizing over and as we know this
is never guaranteed in practice you can
not guarantee the exact minimum whereas
the other techniques requires some
custom optimizer so if you already have
some T owned optimizer using some
infrastructure in place these techniques
might not be the best suited
this motivates us to design what we call
amp here we are given a data set D and I
will denote the privacy parameters by B
corresponding to some budget in addition
this technique requires what is called a
gradient norm bound I'll denote it by
gamma I'll describe its significance
soon so the technique is very simple it
can be described in four steps at high
level so here's out how it goes so the
first step is to split the privacy
budget into two parts using the first
part you add some regularization to the
loss function and for the members that
are familiar with objective perturbation
this step is very similar to that
technique so effectively now the loss
function at our disposal looks something
like this we denoted by L probe
consequently the minimizer also changes
we'll denote it by theta proof so now
you can use your favorite optimizer to
optimize over this perturbed loss but
when do you stop this is where the
parameter gamma comes in so gamma
defines a region around the minimizer
where the norm of the gradient is
bounded from above by gamma
note that the norm of the gradient at
the minimum is a theta probe is zero so
around it it should be very small so you
continue optimizing until you reach any
point within this region so let's denote
it by that point by theta procs as it is
an approximate minima of the as as it is
an approximate minimum of the perturbed
loss what you do is you add some noise
using the second part of your privacy
budget and release that model so this is
the output of the algorithm
we also provide formal util utility
guarantees for this technique but rather
than trying to explain you this
beautiful slide I'll just provide the
takeaways so one major advantage of this
technique is that it can leverage any of
the Shelf optimizer we don't place any
restrictions on the optimizer used it
also works for all standard convex loss
functions most of the techniques in
prior work applied to only GLM's
or generalized linear models next if you
sit gamma small enough the gradient norm
bound small enough then the utility
guarantee of this technique is on the
same order as objective perturbation
objective perturbation has the best
asymptotic utility guarantees in the
field but it requires the exact
minimizer which is not practical in
addition to it our technique also has a
better dependence on the data set size n
as compared to private permutation bay
stochastic gradient descent that is the
state-of-the-art and output perturbation
so you have to set gamma small enough to
obtain this guarantee what we see in our
experiments is that gamma equal to 1
over N squared is very easily achievable
and like only using standard Python
libraries so you can hope for much
smaller gamma as well so next I will
talk about the second contribution which
is the empirical evaluation we conduct
our evaluation over thirteen data sets
that we bucket eyes into we categorize
into three buckets low dimensional high
dimensional and real-world data sets
that have been obtained by a
collaboration with uber so here the
categorization is if the number of
samples is much larger than the number
of features we say it is no dimensional
if it is comparable we say it is high
dimensional
the algorithms we have evaluate include
amp two of the techniques that add noise
during the training process and two
techniques which are practical variants
of output perturbation one important
point to note is that all of these
techniques have some hyper parameters
that need to be tuned for performance to
be good this involves some cost in
itself that has to be taken into account
and so we also provide a hyper parameter
free variant of amp basically the only
hyper parameter in our technique is how
you split the privacy budget within the
technique and we provide a schedule that
we provide a schedule for doing this by
only evaluating it on synthetic data
sets so you have no cost to privacy we
also compare all the techniques with a
non private baseline that is the
technique which provides the best
performance without considering privacy
so what is the experimental procedure we
consider to loss functions in this talk
I will focus on logistic regression we
first split the input data set into we
randomly split it into a training and
testing set we fix one of the privacy
parameters Delta to one over N squared
and we vary epsilon from 0.01 which is
very high privacy to ten which is lower
level we tuned each algorithm and then
report the mean accuracy and standard
deviation over ten independent runs we
report the accuracy over the test set
note that the steering does not apply to
high-priority free
so let's start by looking at the results
so here what I'm showing is the results
on the synthetic data set that is
low-dimensional on the x-axis you have
epsilon which goes from a very high
privacy level to a lower level on the
y-axis you have the accuracy of the test
set the blue plot on the top represents
the non private baseline and it's
difficult to see the different
algorithms in this plot as they're very
crowded together next I'll show results
for high dimensional synthetic data set
here what we do is we generate data that
is actually low rank but high
dimensional and here we see that private
Frank wolf which is the pink plot
performs it beats the other algorithms
by wide margin and one of the reasons is
it is designed to operate well on sparse
data and over these two data sets is
where we tune hyper parameter free amp
which is the green plot so next I'll
show some of the results on high
dimensional data sets namely real sim
and RC v1 here is where it is clearer
that both variants of amp even the hyper
parameter free version performs better
than all the other tuned algorithms so
the orange plot denotes amp and the
green one denotes happy parameter free
amp and they almost always provide the
best performance
next are some results on real-world use
cases where these are large data sets
they have millions of samples and the
first observation here is that many
works many prior works have theorized
that differential privacy can act as a
regularizer
and in dataset one we see that the best
algorithms the best private algorithms
almost always outperform the non private
one also notice that since we have
millions of samples that the x-axis the
range of the x-axis changes on data set
one it's just one twentieth of a percent
whereas it's it's still pretty much
small in the other data set we also see
that all algorithms basically show a
smaller variance and the accuracy of amp
is very close to the non private
baseline even for the lowest privacy
level be considered so I'd like to
conclude by giving a summary one
observation in our study that we show
through our experiments is that if you
have a large data set the cost of
privacy is very low we also see that amp
almost always provides the best accuracy
and it is designed to be easily
deployable in practice in addition to
this it also has a hyper parameter free
variant which is end-to-end
differentially private and it is
competitive with the tuned versions of
the state-of-the-art algorithms and
finally we open source our benchmark and
our code it's available on the following
link with that thank you for your time
and I'd be happy to take questions
[Applause]
we have any questions thanks for the
great talk sorry this might be a naive
question because I'm not an expert on
differential privacy but I was just
wondering that so what makes the
decision of the absolute value of 0.01
kind of adequate for for privacy so it
is majorly a policy decision as what
epsilon value you should use it should
depend on the sensitivity of the data
itself for some tasks value like 1 or 5
might be reasonable for some sensitive
tasks a lower value might be reasonable
what we tried to show is that for
basically the range of values that we've
seen in the literature so it's very rare
to see even epsilon as low as point 0 1
so we just show that how the privacy
accounts for in this in this region so
thanks for the answer I have a follow-up
question so in the case where you have a
real world data set like the Wilber Dale
said there are only two classes right
for the classification task so in that
case even for epsilon equals 0.01 isn't
that just having two classes make it
easy to distinguish the two cases where
you have two two different data sets
that its neighboring so even though
there are two classes the guarantee
holds over the complete sample so if you
notice the each sample has a lot of
features hundreds of features and the
privacy guarantee holds whether a
particular vector is within the data set
or not and so in addition to the class
we also give privacy to the values of
the features themselves any other
questions
so you'll mentioned there are four steps
in your approach and you mentioned the
second step is similar to some existing
techniques and the last one is just add
noise
so what's intuition here that your
approach is better than all those
optimized for specific you know those
techniques Ultimates were specific tasks
you know why was the magic here that's a
very good question so two of the
techniques that are output perturbation
and objective perturbation they have
really good utility guarantees but the
privacy holds only if you release the
exact minimizer so if you manage to
reach the minimizer and release it you
get great guarantees in practice that's
never guaranteed so the thought process
here was what if you are very very close
to the actual minima can you get privacy
guarantees for it because if it is close
to the actual minimum I it should
perform well so we add noise in the last
step just to give privacy to that
approximate minima that that's the high
level review Thanks
hi I have question is do you use
convexity of a objective function in
privacy guarantee or utility alert
that's a very great question so the
privacy guarantees will depend here like
you require some properties like
smoothness and basically it's not
required for utility it is for the
privacy you need some other guarantees
to hold but you'll be fine if you have
like smoothness and strong yeah it's
it's mostly for their utility guarantees
any final questions okay last question
hi a very nice talk have you evaluated
against any of the attacks that you
mentioned in the beginning like
membership inference or modeling version
so so basically what the notion of
differential privacy gives you is a
guarantee that you can avoid influence
for example and how much the attack will
be successful will depend on the level
of Epsilon
so basically inference is whether an
adversary can distinguish whether a
sample is there or not and differential
privacy is a mathematical guarantee to
prevent precisely that so I think other
papers that concentrate on the attacks
do carry on evaluation we have not
carried that to that question the
differential privacy guarantees on the
output does not vary too much but
inference membership inference or the
other inferences are guarantees on the
input so can you actually relate those
two so the guarantees are you cannot
deduce anything about the input from the
guarantee itself just says that the
output cannot vary but it doesn't say
anything about what it can infer about
the input it's precisely that from
seeing the output you cannot deduce much
about the input samples so if you
observe the output
you cannot confidently say whether my
sample was in the data set or not
so this isn't this is this is more than
just that the original differential
privacy definition that you're sort of
inferring a little bit more from from
that no this is this is exactly the
maybe I'll talk to you after yep let's
think on one more time thank you
[Applause]