I give you the 10 5 and okay so I'll be
somewhere around here all right cool
all right folks if you could take your
seats our next speaker is about to get
going
this means you alright folks if you
could please put a big hand together
besides Toronto hand together for an
Lara Ana Lorimer and sorry about that
and her time and her talk security
internships bringing the next generation
of hackers hi everyone thanks so much
for having me
this is actually my first time giving a
talk at a security conference and you
all have been wonderful so kind of
changing sorry
kind of changing mindsets from thinking
about malware and how to break things
instead I want to talk about how to make
things better and bring people into this
super awesome community today I want to
talk about internships I want to talk to
you about how you actually like why
they're important how you structure them
so that both you and your intern are set
up for success and how you actually find
like a real human intern um we are out
there I promise
um so my career so far can basically be
described as professional intern I've
done six internships and a wide variety
of things um and they've been absolutely
vital to making my career in security
and I think they're like a really great
way to help bring people in and just
make this industry like the best it can
possibly be cool so like I said today
we're going to talk about why
internships are important what makes an
internship actually good and how to find
a real live living breathing human
intern this has been my path I started
out in QA I wanted to some web
development for a while and then I
finally broken security and I'm
currently doing my undergraduate degree
in computer science and basically they
really only trained me how to be a
software engineer no one along the way
told me that I could like break things
for a living instead of building things
for a living
um which kind of really sucks and I've
been really into security for like ever
and until it wasn't until my like at my
third internship that someone was like
hey you're really into this stuff you
should do it for like money and it
could've been any one of you and this
audience who had given me that push and
without that push I really would have
never gotten the confidence to go after
these internships in these jobs or to
pursue
security as my full-time career so kind
of giving you a hint about why
internships important but let's go into
depth obviously internships encourage
newcomers to go into security we
constantly talk about how hard it is to
hire a good security person in this
field and that we constantly have all
these open jobs and no one to fill them
giving people the opportunity to learn
all these skills through internships and
to bring them up that way it's a really
awesome way to help make this pipeline a
little bit less broken and get people in
there in the first place it's also a
really good opportunity to find out who
on your team would make a really good
manager being able to work with junior
people is absolutely vital to running a
team and if someone can't handle a team
of one they certainly can't handle a
team of many finally interns are going
to be the full-time people of the future
hiring interns is a really low risk way
to find out if someone is a good fit for
your company you know after like a few
weeks or months they're working into
place you basically get to see how they
work how they interact and then their
contract ends and you can decide if you
want to bring them back or not and
that's you don't really get to do that
with other traditional avenues for like
full-time hiring when you go through the
interview cycle you hire someone and
then you find it with interns you get to
check beforehand and the thing that I
really want to bring home here is that
it's actually really hard to break into
security on 100% intended um
journey is unlike other software
engineering disciplines where there's
actually a really high barrier to entry
to get into security you know if you
wanted to be like a Python developer you
can literally just Google how do I learn
Python and you get like 15 different
tutorial websites and like 15 thousand
different medium posts going into like
the intricate details of how you could
learn it and the counterparts for
security aren't as readily accessible
you know software engineering even has
like cracking the coding interview which
is like a whole book dedicated to how to
get a job in that field but thing the
counterparts and security like micro
corruption Google Gruyere a wasp there I
think it's called juice their framework
for practicing with hacking you often
know like basically how computers work
at every level to do those already like
micro corruption you have to know how to
read assembly which I I don't
I barely know how to do and it's
definitely really hard to expect someone
who's an entry level just starting out
in this to also know how to do
internships can really help break down
these barriers like I said you're
learning skills on the job you're
helping teach people as they're doing
stuff it's not like they're doing these
little practice things on the side to
get better they're actually doing the
real work that we all do on the job
every day hopefully you're not convinced
that interns are great and we don't just
break things all the time but
internships can go one of two ways that
can be really great or they can kind of
not be so great and there's a couple
different things I want to talk about
and how we can make these the best we
possibly can the way I see it there's
like two major parts to an internship
there's the actual learning environment
that you put the person in and then
there's the actual project that you have
them work on so let's start with how you
make a good learning environment for an
intern kearney a good learning
environment involves buy-in from every
level of your organization you know if
someone's not on board with having an
intern it shows and your intern will
definitely pick up on that and there's
nothing a couple things that we want to
do and a couple things that we don't
want to do so let's start with what we
want to do talk about expectations and
goals
in turn your internet is basically
coming on to work full-time for however
long their contract is and you should
expect to have the same sort of
interactions with them as you would a
full-time employee in terms of talking
about what their career goals are
talking about how their tasks are going
if there's something going wrong in the
project and basically having this open
dialogue through something like regular
one-on-one meetings you know maybe this
is weekly or it's bi-weekly when you
start depending on your intern they
might be like I'm good to go I can only
talk to you like once a month now but
definitely beginning expect to interact
with them a lot they're going to be kind
of nervous and they're going to want to
do so well and they just want to know
how they're doing the other part of an
open dialogue is mentorship so
mentorship is when someone who has a lot
of breadth and knowledge and experience
in industry helps guide someone more
junior through their project and their
tasks in their day-to-day work life this
has been like I can't explain to you how
helpful mentorship has been to me in
particular the internships where I've
had an assigned mentor who's basically
like signed on to be my go-to person for
when I'm stuck when I need help as an
intern it's really really intimidating
to ask people for help you already kind
of feel like you're a bit of a burden on
your team because everyone's just doing
their job and you're they're trying to
like sponge up everything they know and
not get in the way but like I said
having someone who's signed on to be
your go-to person just makes it so much
easier you feel so much more comfortable
and he learned so much more how many
people have heard of sponsorship right
it's not a really well-known thing and
this is it makes it really sad
sponsorship is when someone who's
playing usually higher up in your
company vouches for you so for me this
was a really example of this was
actually the first time I gave this talk
back in Ross Portland was someone up and
someone up higher and the company I was
working at said you know what you should
put your name in for this or like I'll
put your name in for this and that's
really great because as an intern I
didn't have a lot of leverage within the
company or the community to be like I'm
going to go do that but someone who is
higher up and had a little bit more
know-how within the community
a little bit more respect to the
community really leverage that to help
make my career better okay so what don't
we want to do I'm gonna go over a couple
social rules here which you marry me
don't heard of the first one is called
feigning surprise and feigning surprise
is when say your intern comes to you and
they are stuck on this buffer overflow
problem and you look at it and you go
man that's super easy I can't believe
you can't get that and the other one I
heard once was Wow I can't believe you
don't know who zero cool is I was born
in 1995 feigning surprise really just
makes someone feel like crap for not
knowing something and it's it's just
totally detrimental to making someone
feel like they're in an environment
where they can learn things and the only
reason someone doesn't know something
it's because they haven't had the
opportunity yet so give the person the
opportunity to learn it instead of
getting them down for not knowing
something say oh yeah that was really
hard when I first learned it so let's
nerd out about it together and work
through this problem you don't have to
you can make it such an awesome
opportunity to share your knowledge
rather than dunk on someone for not
knowing something the other thing that I
really really want you to keep in mind
is gatekeeping keeping is also one of
those ones where I feel like people
haven't heard of it much but gatekeeping
is basically when you guard knowledge
until someone has somehow proven that
they are deserving of it a really
typical way that this gets expressed
actually in the functional programming
community is that they set up this
artificial barrier where you have to
know a bunch of like Laki boolean
mathematics and able to do to do
functional programming and this isn't
true you can go out and like learn
Haskell or whatever without knowing all
the intricacies of how formal logic
works so they set up this artificial
barrier for you to start doing this
thing and security this might be
something like oh you can't do SQL
injection until you know how to do
buffer overflows or oh you can't do
cross-site scripting until you have
cross-site scripting vulnerabilities
until you've done SQL injection you set
up these artificial barriers for people
to start doing things and there's really
no reason to there's no connection
between needing to know how a buffer
overflow works and how SQL injection
works at the bare minimum when you're
just starting and finally I one of the
things that happens when you start
bringing people into this community is
you work with people from different
backgrounds subtle isms refers to when
you are subtly racist sexist homophobic
transphobic ablest all of that jazz
these will encourage people to leave
this community I myself have been on the
receiving end of things like wow you're
really good at security for being a girl
which like you laugh but it really does
make me feel like I don't have a place
in this community and we're all guilty
of this I've certainly done it I'm sure
everyone in this room has done it and
the best thing to do in these cases is
to apologize educate yourself and
educate yourself again doing things like
this can make a huge difference in
keeping people in this community and
helping people bring them in so now we
have an idea of how an internship should
work we know how to make an intern happy
how did concurs them to stay here but an
intern actually needs to do something
during their internship and that's
usually in the form of a project and
like I said interns have this really bad
rap for breaking stuff all the time
I know I definitely have friends who've
done internships and cause like sev ones
which is a good learning experience I'd
like to point out but I really really
really can't encourage you enough to
give your interns projects that are
meaningful to your organizations when
you give an intern a project that has no
hope in hell of seeing production or a
client using it you silo them off and
isolate them from seeing just how cool
it is to work at your company and just
how cool it is to work in security when
you give them something that matters
that you get invested they start to
think it's really cool to work at your
company
now this doesn't mean that you have to
give your intern the absolute
mission-critical you know if this
doesn't work our company's gonna go
bankrupt or all gonna be have jobs kind
of work a really good example that I
heard was give your interns the
nice-to-haves on a project so maybe
there's like one or two features like
you know maybe it could just be a little
bit clearer how it sends this thing or
you know adding documentation to a
project that has an impact but won't
cause a sub one these projects mean a
lot to interns we get to work on stuff
that actually matters but you don't have
to worry about it
breaking everything the other thing to
point out here is that interns talk to
each other if you give your intern a
super cool project that they think is
awesome and has a lot of impact they
will tell all their intern friends and
your company is suddenly the coolest
person ever to work for and I can't
vouch enough for like the intern back
channel like network as advertising for
your company it's amazing like your
hiring pool just expands exponentially
when the interns think you're cool so we
kind of know we have an idea of how we
should treat interns in the workplace
get them work that's valuable but now we
actually have to find an intern the good
news is that there is a lot of us out
there a lot of us are super enthusiastic
we are all graduating and our terrified
of what we're going to do with our
futures so there's a lot of us out there
it's really good the mediocre news is
that often we have trouble finding these
opportunities or accepting them for
reasons I will get into so you can
physically find us at things like
conferences to second particulars when I
want to highlight I realized the graphic
kind of sucks but it's the Canadian
undergraduate software engineering
conference and basically it is 300
Canadian undergraduate students crammed
into one hotel for three days and they
are all looking for internships and they
are all very excited to be looking for
internships they've been practicing
their interview skills
for months and they are ready to go I
also really want to courage you to go to
things like Cusick that aren't directly
security-related one of the great ways
one of the really important things about
this community is we need to bring in
people who don't have a traditional
security background like I said I
started off in like QA and web dev and
broke into security we need to really
really think of those people who are
really into security and just need a
helping hand to get into it through
something like an internship twitter is
also a really great way to find us every
intern ever follows the companies that
they want to work for and the people
they want to work for on Twitter and
guaranteed that if you tweet out that
you are looking for interns
they will reply incredibly
enthusiastically mailing lists are also
a great way to reach out to us
universities often have a kind of job
hunt mailing lists or internship mailing
lists my school in particular has like a
really formal way you can do it but if
you don't want to do that you just shoot
an email to them and asking if there's a
mailing list and finally going to like
physical meetups again maybe not
security related are a really great way
to find us as well a lot of us go to
these meetups to try and get a feel for
what it's like to work in an industry to
see talks given by people to kind of see
what companies are about so we're really
great way to find us there I also want
to insert your local University /
college here like I said my school in
particular has this big formal program
where you can go through co-op but often
you can partner with companies on campus
or clubs on campus sorry or committees
on campus
to run workshops have talks give a panel
I know a particular the computer science
club and the women in computer science
Committee on my campus are super super
active around this and we love it as
students because you come in you talk to
so how could your job is we get to learn
something new especially if it's a
workshop we really really like those
because it's like an internship
condensed into a few hours or a day and
yeah there's a really really great way
there's a really great University
Network out there you should definitely
take advantage of or if you want to find
an intern the reason an intern may not
be able to accept
offer really comes down to pay and
housing for reference I pay about $7000
a term in tuition before additional fees
and if you can't pay me enough to help
me support that I can't take your
internship I just can't and that makes
it really tough so I really encourage
you to pay interns above minimum wage
upwards of $20 an hour's usually best I
looked up the stats from my University
of how much I turns get paid and at
least by your second internship you're
looking at 20 dollars and up unless your
Facebook and your pain your interns like
50 dollars an hour but that's Facebook
they're rolling in dough they don't know
what to do with it
another thing that really helps with us
is housing stipends helping us pay for
rent
my last internship I wouldn't've been
able to take if they hadn't helped me
pay for housing transportation is also
really important it is expensive to use
public transportation pretty much
anywhere in the world so helping us pay
for bus passes or transit passes in
general may really really help us take
your internship your company will also
get an amazing reputation and interns
will love you forever and will want to
work for you full-time I also really
encourage you to give us the opportunity
negotiate this isn't again we're really
trying to figure out what it's like to
work in this industry and negotiating
offers as part of that and accepting an
offer may come down to you being
flexible around how much you give us for
housing or giving us one or two extra
dollars an hour now I just told you that
Facebook pays their interns like 50
bucks an hour and you might be going oh
my organization can't do that my company
can't do that were that's too much for
us right now and it's really important
to recognize if you're not ready for an
intern if you don't have team buy-in yet
if no one wants to sign up to be a
mentor if no one wants to sign up to be
a sponsor it's probably not the right
time to take an intern but there's other
ways you can help sponsoring conference
tickets is life-changing for a lot of
people this year there's a really big
push to get I think it was 40 women in
the end to Def Con and that's 40 people
who went to the biggest security
conference ever and who learned how how
cool this industry is and who wouldn't
able to get there otherwise running
workshops is also life-changing for a
lot of interns and people looking to
work in this industry it's like an
internship but condensed like today
we're doing the Kali Linux training and
that's all stuff you could learn on an
internship but it's been condensed down
into this one day and that's really
really awesome and that's something that
these people can put on their resume to
get more internships or to get a
full-time job it's also a really good
opportunity to do PR for your company
because if you give interns like free
access to your API for a day or they get
to use your hardware for a day they will
want to work for you and they will tell
everyone about how cool your company is
and lastly pay for licenses I've been
really lucky a couple internships I've
worked at have covered things like my
burps sweet license which has let me
continue to educate myself and continue
to get better at what I do this is again
paying for tools of helping people to
learn things and they will think your
company is the greatest and they will be
so much better when you go to hire them
full time to reiterate internships are
valuable for everyone not just the
intern your organization gets to find
out who would be a good manager who
would make a great potential full-time
hire and we generally bring really
awesome people into this industry when
you give interns meaningful projects
they think your company is thebomb.com
and they get to actually learn about how
cool it is to work in security and how
awesome your company is and also bring
new people into the pipeline through
things like going to conferences that
aren't directly security-related there's
a lot of people like me out there who
felt like they could literally never
hack it to get into security until
someone gave them the opportunity to do
so that's it for me thank you for having
me you can find me on Twitter here and
the glycerine - awesome project and if
you want to learn more about how to
create a good learning environment I
can't recommend the raker Center social
rules enough they're basically retreat
in New York and they spent a lot of time
working on their documentation about how
to create a healthy learning environment
for people thank you
[Applause]
I can take questions I guess yeah yes I
don't want to be without any names um so
a project I worked on recently was so
the company I was working at we
regularly interacted with every other
team in the company to do security
reviews for whenever releases went out
and we had this super janky script that
let us know when a team was requesting a
review through JIRA and it broke at
least once a week often spectacularly
and it wasn't like something that was
mission-critical like it worked well
enough we found out about them but my
project was to rewrite it and to make it
more robust and to integrate it into
slack actually and it just made such a
huge impact we actually discovered that
teams had been created that we didn't
know about or requesting security
reviews so yeah it's really an example
of something that wasn't
mission-critical
the company would have survived if I
hadn't redone it but I got to see like
how much happier my team was and just
people would come up to me and be like
it works so well now and that was really
rewarding yeah yeah
[Music]
it yeah I couldn't really only speak for
people from my school but our first-year
education is pretty comprehensive we can
go straight into development usually for
security things in particular securities
and something that's not really taught
in universities especially first year I
think buffer overflows are mentioned
once in my entire first year in terms of
how much you can expect an intern to
know I think that's definitely something
that would fall under talking to your
intern and when you do interviews see
where they're at
it's hard dislike blanket knowledge say
like an internal know how to do this
because we're all different and we all
have different experiences and
backgrounds but if you have like a thing
in particular you want an intern to work
on put that in your job description yeah
sorry that's bliss our guide way in the
back
and how much they've taught themselves
outside of university sometimes I'm
gonna counter that a little bit just
because the interns are will like
husband no the shortcomings of our
education will often go out and teach
ourselves the things that we think are
cool this has been expecially my
experience in security like I had to go
and teach myself everything but yeah it
depends sorry
that's the best I've got yeah yep
exactly and take your internship as an
opportunity to teach them those things
you're looking for yeah thanks oh so
many hands
mm-hmm yeah so the question was is it
better to have an intern work on
something completely that they don't
they've never worked on before or to
have them jump in on a project it's
already existing so your question more
on their back on their skills right
mm-hmm okay it depends I started out in
web dev and very much did not want to
continue doing that so I really looked
for something that was going to take me
on and teach me something completely new
about security but some people decide
really early on what they like and they
do want to help onto those projects and
continue to grow in that vein again it
kind of comes down to if you have the
resources to teach someone something
completely new or if you only have the
resources to help someone like have
someone who's more advanced and jump
onto a project and kind of almost
consider them a full member of the team
at that point you can structure you can
decide early on which one you want to do
it doesn't have to be like you get an
intern then figure that out you can put
your job posting things like I'm we're
looking to teach this person everything
they need to know is a really helpful
thing when interns are looking for jobs
and it's really clear about what your
expectations are then does that make
sense yes
[Music]
yeah my best advice is to not back down
especially when you're an intern you
feel you have absolutely no leverage at
all and that feels horrible but if the
company does give you an offer they want
you to work there use that definitely
come in with examples of things you want
like say I need a bus pass it will cost
you this much or I looked up rent here
and it is this much I need you to help
me out with that yes and no if you have
multiple offers I know people who have
leveraged that in a perfect world you
have multiple offers and you can
leverage that but yes okay if you want
to talk to me I'll be hanging out in the
front happy to answer more questions
[Applause]