we are things are moving along here and
I hope you are enjoying yourselves
please be sure to give us feedback at
info at besides tota so we know how
we're doing both positive and negatives
are good because otherwise we can't grow
all right the next talk is called cyber
zoology protecting your network from new
breeds of attacks with a Raspberry Pi
would you please put your hands together
and welcome to the stage Patrick Kelly
good afternoon can everyone hear me OK
to loud to quiet be quiet
go home go back to America gotcha
ok so really excited to be up here
really excited to be in Toronto Kem
sektor a couple years ago
director around this area I'll be honest
with you 2 years ago it would never have
even crossed my mind that I'd have the
opportunity to speak to any of you today
and to say that I'm humbled as would
really be understating it so we're going
to talk about some things I've been
looking into the last couple years and
we're gonna scope this down on the
Raspberry Pi so that you can take this
home and/or take it to your lab or
wherever you can to try some of these
concepts out I will be releasing all of
the code that you'll see in here the
detection x' on a github repo you can
grab it also the production image for
the PI 3 that I use for the things I'm
gonna showing these slides will be
available as well so you can image it
and just do whatever you want to do it
so
all right so Who am I
to be honest with you I kind of get
bored of myself so in short I'll skip to
the most important part last night I got
to see the first Leafs game go Leafs got
really exciting time again if you're
gonna kick off in Toronto on something
you never dreamed you're gonna get to do
starting out with the Leafs game winning
is a pretty great way to go so let's
rock and roll
okay why are we here logs lie
if you've ever set up a sim if you've
ever done ir if you've ever reached into
a Windows machine Linux box if you've
ever tailed syslog after an incident
you'll understand that logs lie even if
they don't lie you're stuck to the
technology and the fidelity of when not
logging concept and that mechanism was
created in fairness it's a good effort
but it's never going to be good enough
so you know intrusion intentions on the
board are only tail portion of story and
this is something that I learned working
for years with Sourcefire and with Cisco
and Dell SecureWorks we would be able to
pull some of the traffic down and we
would be able to see north to south but
we really didn't have any context around
that what did it mean what did it do
when it got through passing through that
thing bless you
I but you know we can't go around
dropping $20,000 Sourcefire sensors
every we want them to go it's just too
expensive in even setting up 1u you know
super micros may be outside a bunch of
your organization so probably we're
having is that the visibility was not
multi-dimensional it wasn't contextual
and without qualification of threats too
much time was spent chasing things
around does anyone in a room ever walked
into work and had 7,000 indicators come
out of your sin their IDs and you find
out that only seven of them meant
anything it's a long day right probably
didn't get through this so here's why I
wanted to solve you know first what is
this
traditional is north-to-south your
signature-based they look for isolated
atomic indicators there's very little
correlation it takes place for instance
if it's store traffic you may not care
if that's coming off your guest Wi-Fi
network you would really care if you're
doing IRC private messaging between your
to Vienna or ESXi servers that would be
something that would probably perk your
ears
unfortunately this past year we worked
with a client gave them packets of that
happening and they hugged it welcome to
my world
so we're trying to do here is
correlating those atomic indicators with
full bra IDs proto analyzation so that
you have a better idea of what that
attack traffic looks like and what's
really going on then you can do some
enrichment on those locks from disparate
sources that way you can add a little
more color in context to it so again
kind of beating this to death because
even when I look at machine learning
even when I look at AI concepts we're
still leaning back on those old
principles that we'd already determined
are broken such as machine learning off
of a signature art fellow shown to
artificial intelligence off of a
signature we keep looking for that one
atomic indicator hoping that we get to
see it again and chances are you're
probably not going to so another problem
that I wanted to solve right is when
you're working in industrial control
environments and things have been
engineered to have a shelf life of 20 or
30 years even if you want to log things
you can't there isn't a space to do it
if you wanted to back haul logs there
isn't a mechanism there to do it with
you've got some significant issues here
just getting the data to a place where
we can figure out what's going on so in
my ID after working with Sourcefire
through the conversion to Cisco and they
are acquired working with SecureWorks
working internally these are some things
that I look for when I'm making an
effective security platform blended IDs
it's not good enough to have sericata
and then another signature base we have
to have the ability to drive deep down
in packets done in protocol flows and
bring that stuff out
the other part that I'm finding out is
okay you find something now what do you
do with it most environments isolate you
and silo you to their environment that's
not an environment that you're spending
the rest of your time in so you're
having to make a concerted effort to go
back and forth that's why I really like
being an import and export and Stix
models is anyone here familiar with
sticks thank God I thought I'd be the
only one
okay so short version of it just so we
can move along is that the idea behind
sticks is when you would export your
indicators of a compromise you would
have a little more fidelity and
construct in context around it
see how better understanding what was
going on at the time that that took
place again I talked about logging a
beat on that pretty hard when I said you
know even your logs are going to lie to
you but the fact is is Jason's going to
be better than syslog I know that there
are other things that are coming out
that are a little less overhead but JSON
works I was gonna show here in a minute
that you've got to have some portability
because everywhere you go is not always
gonna have a nice 42 you rack in there
for you to shine you know push your
shiny blinky light box into you right so
API is to pull things back extensive the
extended connectivity connectability
pardon me to windows logs pass a total
virus total so I started working on
trains that's called in by DHS as
culling some vendors or something that
are up here and they said we have a
problem
we're doing positive train control but
we're finding problems we have trains
we're putting Wi-Fi ended in but we
don't really know how to get our heads
around it we think that there's
something to happen on our train network
but we don't really know because we
don't have any logs because we wanted to
do logging but there's no space in the
ACC or the recs to actually do that what
are we gonna do so well great I'll tell
you what I'll build an appliance will
come out little rack it will take the
data back out of it we'll take a look at
it sorry sorry sorry sorry when we and
when we engineered this 30 years ago
there's no special slots there's nothing
open for you to use by the way you're
probably gonna have a problem getting
power for what you want to do as well
awesome so I started looking at these
things differently right
you have OTN you have IT I t's a little
bit easier you know we can drop sensors
in between VLANs we can profile those
sensors if you're going to put it in a
VM and the thing that you're wanting to
look at is V motion traffic then we
don't really need to load up protocol
detection and deep packet inspection for
everything else you can lower that
profile and that usage down additionally
what if the places that you need to
backhaul traffic from don't have a
dedicated hunter mag drop or a gigabit
drop what if they'd only have the cable
coming into it at all we haven't had a
problem so the things considering going
through this is consider remote sites
consider executives personal networks I
know that they hate to violate privacy
but if anyone's done IR they understand
that insider threats and layer 8 is the
worst so here we go
let's move in the in in whatever you can
make fit on a train this is a real-world
Jam right here you don't always have
Rackspace they wanted to understand what
was going on inside their traffic
Wireshark isn't going to do I can't
stick a laptop or a Dell powered server
in this environment you have to think
and do something different
it's a great let's build a Raspberry Pi
I can power it our batteries I can do
something with it and then I can do a
proprietary which are really hard to
find and make cable to plug to the j5 so
we can get all that monitor traffic off
but here's a set of problem security is
a narrative right it's based on a fixed
construct of time if you don't have time
and you don't have context then you
can't really determine exactly when
things happen in the order and if you
should carry you shouldn't care but when
you're dealing with trains you know
reader doing Wi-Fi between white side
boxes and if you're driving down the
highway and you see the big metal boxes
by the road those are way sites to
connect back to the back office for the
carrier
or if you don't have that we can do
cellular cellular is very expensive and
then we move to the third option which
is a just horrible for us they're trying
to solve security problems which is 220
megahertz radio so imagine if you need
positive train control to work in the
back office must have enough bandwidth
to say you're running into a flood zone
and they can't get that across because
we're blasting the wire with JSON full
fidelity bro packet logs we didn't
reduce the threat service we just
increased the threat surface and this is
a serious thing I like my french fries I
like my orange juice and unfortunately
we carry nuclear waste on trains too so
we have to think of how do we do back
pressure and properly store and forward
messages to the point that even when
they come out of an area and we can get
these logs that do we get to fidelity
that we need to make good decisions so
this is hard to do but if you can and
you can get the logs coming into a
Raspberry Pi using bro and sericata
here's a lat long the next flow I try to
keep big words because I know these it
can be hard to read but in that one next
one is introducing the great this is
train going up is it going down what is
the speed that it's moving in we can
plot this across time and as we do this
we look at how to determine a behavioral
model around this so did a train
normally go 52 miles an hour up this
grade or down that's great is there a
problem in the cabin that caused there
to be a change
did we lose consciousness consciousness
of the engineer can PTC take control so
you start getting some very interesting
data when you start tearing down a
protocol it's stuff you're not going to
get out of sericata and you can't run a
laptop with Wireshark in these
environments all the time but it gets
really interesting
here's the brake interface here's a
warning so we talked about new breed's
for us talk about old ones before we get
to the new ones when you're dealing with
trains we're dealing with airplanes when
you're dealing with cars still with
canvas most of that traffic is still
using protocols that were cutting-edge
25 years ago they're subject to replay
attacks they're subject to you just tell
netting in using web tech web tech or
admin admin an unfortunate thing is that
most trains can be driven with a
lockpick kit and admin admin and if you
can't use that just alter the GPS that's
being fed to the PC PTC on the train and
it'll be glad to do what you want that
way in case you just don't want to pick
locks so here's where I started solving
this problem with Breyer that you can't
really get out of that our IDs solutions
D mp3 you're gonna be concerned with
reset commands that they're coming from
places that shouldn't be sending reset
comments if I jump onto network and I
want to alter an environment or I want
to stop a job where I want to make a
change I can drop in pull the tape pull
that traffic in plain text because dnp3
and Modbus both are an indie replay
attacks or do resets or do any number of
things so one thing we can do it bro and
I'm sorry if this is a little hard to
read
they go ahead and define what you want
to look for in there that would be
suspicious to you such as a function
code reset I'm really sorry about this I
really am I tried to get the leanest bro
script I could find so that you could
see it in this room and it may make
sense and not be trivial but new attacks
and what I started finding when doing
with sericata and other things is that
we are looking for a foul hash or
looking for one piece of code that was
in a Wireshark in a packet or we were
looking for some single atomic indicator
the problem is we're having to write
signatures for every single thing that
gets really
that does the same thing 29,000 some odd
individual roles in sericata is heavy
it's heavy and snort too I mean I try to
point this out if I can but the idea
behind doing this what bro is that if
you're using Empire if I'm using
Metasploit if I'm using any a number of
things I use one our red team to get
control of you know local admin and then
escalate up I'm gonna want to get the
hashes off the domain controller now
pulling in CC or NC changes between two
domain controllers is not a big deal
that's normal behavior it's called
replication it's been a new hotness
since 1999 right for it came out but if
you're a workstation that's not a DC and
you're not and not list that's defined
above as 192 168 0 2 then you're gonna
want to know about this this may not
fire sericata in fact it probably won't
this is normal behavior there's nothing
for it to tell you that there's wrong
with URIs in PowerShell PowerShell is
generally allowed in every environment
on every workstation so having the
ability to contextualize what that DRS
in C changed and that replication looks
like to someone who isn't and a main
controller is going to be valuable I
didn't find an easy way to do this in
sericata I found a very easy way to do
this with bro
no this is just looking for one
indicator to contextualize this the only
thing that's making a difference in here
is that we've got a domain controller
defined but we could do this differently
like you can some start this yes I'm not
really worried about doing one time I'm
worried about doing nine times and or
let's say we're looking for a
brute-forcing and I'm not so much
worried about you know the nine ones
that failed because I'm used to my
networking getting skinned I'm used to
the nine ones failing an attempt when
succeeding so that's something you can
write in bro scripting and you can run
on a Raspberry Pi so that regardless of
what that malware signature is
regardless of where its
from it doesn't matter if I'm using me
me cats Kiwi Empire bro you know on and
on and on you're still gonna see that
behavior and you're still gonna be the
fire on it so now it's a problem you
know how to ingest probably transport
data I've seen a lot of people in
networks push things over syslog and
just send it to a narcissists lock host
please stop doing this I know it's easy
the problem with that though is I can
see all the traffic in I try and an
attacker can see all of your try all of
your traffic - additionally in this kind
of an aside but if you load a new device
in and you move it from HTTP to HTTPS to
make it more secure and you turn off
telling it and you get a SSH make sure
you turn off SNMP while you're at it
most your vendors won't tell you that
they left version 1 with the default
private or public community strings
that's kind of a bonus around sorry I
did this pen test last week and you know
you know it was like hah man that's to
say H an HTTP and man this company's
really doing the right thing that's in
the MP version one damn so you can do
splint with sun certificates that's a
super easy to do you can use log stash
to bring the data back out if you want
you can do ssro ssl curl direct to
elasticsearch from bro which is a lot of
fun and you can use Kafka no oh speaking
of somebody at lunch today and they kind
of kind of lifted an eyebrow you know I
said you know I'm using Kafka on a
Raspberry Pi I know this seems I'd be
strange to somebody to use Kafka every
day but a problem that I had what beats
Splunk and elastic and logstash was that
they're heavy they're really heavy and
if you start burning up the processor
back hauling logs and you're going to
reduce your ability to capture traffic
and log that traffic at all so what a
feeling that had to do in trains and I
had doing other environments when I'm
using PI is that there's a Kafka plugin
from Apache metrion that works really
really well with bra and you can tie
some of your sericata traffic back to it
as well you can send out in the
environment
lightweight over to a Kafka server and
then you can kind of manage that data
any way that you want the biggest
problem that you're having I'm gonna
showcase this in a second is though
Splunk is easy when you start tearing
apart bro network packet logs this is
heavy we're not looking for a single
indicator we're gonna tear down
everything from the Mac all the way up
to the authentication so when you're
capturing all that data and you're
bringing back in a JSON city you can
make good decisions with it that means
it's very heavy and you're gonna blast
ass punk ass punk license pretty fast so
that's why we started looking at Cabana
we started looking at ways to drive
Kafka back in back hauling things over
SSL and curl and these things worked
really well once you have it you can
visit stuff out in more meaningful ways
these are and should be when we verify
because I can't see on that screen very
well and I'm sure you can't either
but most of this thing set for that
bottom right-hand corner is all bro
locks now I'm extracting protocols if I
see a protocol that shouldn't be in my
environment salmon on an entirely
Windows environment or probably
shouldn't see SSH so very simply by
tearing down all these protocols we can
see those things happening again
carrying it further just on network logs
and using like je3 we can tear down what
software is that in that environment
well as well just off network traffic
we're not worried about pulling from the
endpoints we're not worried if someone
remember to put that brand new shiny
server into our asset management and
connect the agent to it it doesn't
matter when we're working with briar we
can see the traffic there we can see the
protocols that we're using additionally
we're dealing with bro we have entity
tables that get created so you know what
you've seen before and you have good
elements of what you haven't seen before
so it's a nice effective way that when
DevOps is shoving more machines in your
environment and they're playing with
live data instead of development data
that you're gonna have the ability to
pull that apart and see what's really
going on in your name in your network I
know you're not gonna be able to see
this you know this like slide deck fell
one after another here it's okay
what you can't see real well is that you
can push those logs out and take
everything from the size the length of
the flow the size of the flow so if
you're looking for persistent
connections if I'm using me me cats or
done persistence through Metasploit I'm
probably gonna have a really long
running flow here
so using bro and using those things you
can start picking apart that information
for free and you can start looking at
what's going on inside of it just make
sure before you get started that you go
ahead and allow or basically you mute
and hotmail outlook on Gmail those
persist forever and they're really going
to skew the the size of the other data
in the session that you're being and
bringing across but again that this is a
highly modified but not too terribly a
modified version of Kabana so you can
pull this down use it at home completely
free we've had to do some changes stars
to ingest the amount of data that we're
bringing in we are working with a huge
social media vendor just just couple
weeks ago and then they may not may or
may not have been in the news lately but
when you're ingesting many many gigs of
log data some of the things that you're
that you're doing are gonna have to
change so 10 gig links require some
massaging say the least so lessons
learned pies are finicky some of the OSS
that are released for them are finicky a
been too was working really well for us
when we first started this up with
trains then they released a version that
drops snap into it and everything fell
apart we did Cintas for awhile and that
was working really well and then there
are some changes came out with it and it
fell apart who had a lot of success with
raspbian we were using the older
versions of older binaries of FAL B for
a while that were compiled and built for
arm and a run on a PI the unfortunate
thing is that they were abandoned so now
once again we're increasing the attack
service
we have known buggy transport software
that you can attack right on the wire
and there's very little you can really
do about that so that's when we started
using spunk for a little while then we
realized man this is going to kill us we
have to do something different again the
Apache metrion Kafka plugin works really
well in raspy and Umbro the patching is
super simple you can with with very few
edits you can include that into your cpu
into your landscape environments and
ever been to or you can manage a three
shuttle but if you're doing about five
or six hundred of these PI sensors at
one time you really want to have the
ability to pitch those patches without
the issue log verbosity requires some
real consideration here I kind of hit on
this earlier but I want to pitch this
across if you start playing in
industrial controls you start messing
around in trains and airplanes if you
start occupying and taking up that whole
line to get your logs back you're going
to cause some operational problems and
unfortunately some of those are going to
cause some accidents so again
bottom line don't das PTC so where am I
going from here what am I going to
release in the future for everyone to
use sandboxing for file extraction bro
will do Fe life you determine what mime
type you want you can have it pull that
off of the wire drop it into a folder
Kaku can pick it up for those familiar
with cookies and boxing and you can blow
that up and get the analytics I finally
have automated an investment from
pastebin and tor taking place right now
which has been really exciting so what I
mean by that is every 20 seconds I've
got an engine that's going and scrubbing
all the most recent pay so they're
coming down in real time and in gluing
that data together with my logs in the
enterprise so instead of me waiting for
a point in time equifax tripled dark web
cafe latte scan whatever the hell that
means I can go ahead and get that in
about twenty or thirty seconds almost
all the data like he talked about in the
last slide is going to end up in a
former it's going to
upon paceman for sale if you can get
that information in 20 seconds
you know you can fire an alert off of it
it's going to save your hide
waiting until something blows up to
figure out if you can find those pace is
not going to be very helpful more proto
analyzers Megan verbose I think I have
three minutes left so I'm going to rush
through the rest of this but the hard
part is we have to do route
determination if you're operating in a
train we have to determine what route
that the traffic's going to go so we can
determine the verbosity that we can get
from those logs without pushing
something over I've solved most of this
but this was not easy to solve because
sometimes it's very hard to figure out
what route something's going to go out
once it passes accr the racks but still
it's very helpful to still be able to
get some of those logs even if you're on
a 220 a grading OT is hard if you don't
believe it
try upgrading 600 trains at one time and
then you know so we want to make that
easier and then the other is finding a
more efficient way of transferring from
there got networks one thing some people
in my last 60 seconds my wife she put
doubled its trash she brings me food and
more dry erase boards Fred Wilmot from
Splunk he's helped me out all the time
Chris Robert to hack trains and planes
with me my team Berkeley for giving up
all the webcasts and lectures that they
didn't know they're actually doing until
someone pointed it out and then God cuz
I'm here alright I think do I have time
for a question or am I done
okay any questions yes
I don't remember exactly the amount of
time but it was not very long I was
having to do it daily at the lease and
on trains we were still filling up we're
still filling up the SD card that was on
a PI I'll be glad to give it to you the
integration is actually part of and you
can actually get it before I have a
chance to get online its built-in to Bro
right now so if you download the most
recent source code the Kafka plug-in is
already there for you one more okay
thank you very much
I appreciate your time thank you