[Music]
thanks for the introduction yeah you've
actually set me up uh perfectly for for
the presentation
um but before i do that uh just on a
personal level i just want to echo the
uh statements by by chris and alexander
and silvio um obviously regarding the
current situation ukraine um you know
we're we're thinking about our
colleagues there and obviously hoping
for a
uh swift peaceful resolution uh to the
situation
so let me jump into my presentation now
all right
so uh
everyone plea please let me know if you
can't see that um
but as chris said i'm going to be
talking a lot about critical
infrastructure sectors uh sector sea
certs
um but more than that uh what i really
want to emphasize in my presentation
here today
um is the idea
of integrating your sector c certs into
the rest of your country's
cyber security capabilities
which we call a national ecosystem
so i'm going to talk about a couple
different things today
um here in the presentation so i can get
the slides to
to advance
there we are
so
in order to get to that point where
we're really understanding uh not only
how sector c cert functions
independently um but how sector c certs
can interact with one another
uh and with the rest of your uh
national ecosystem
including
law enforcement including national
c-cert
including private sector and all sorts
of other entities
we want to talk about first what exactly
a sector c cert is what our expert
expectations are of an organization that
we call a sector c cert
um then we'll talk a little bit about
this framework that that that the
software engineering institute has
developed for building sector c certs um
and then we'll talk a little bit about
that national ecosystem what exactly it
is uh and how organizations can interact
there
um i do have a short case study that i
hope to get to
um if i have time and will hopefully
illustrate some of the things that um
that i'll cover here in the rest of the
presentation
so first of all
you know
i i think sector c cert is probably a
term that a lot of us are familiar with
um maybe some of us aren't quite as
familiar
but coming up with a real solid
unified definition of what a sector c
cert is is kind of a challenge because
this term means different things to
different people right
how do you define what a sector is um
you know are we talking about a sector
of an economy does it have to be
critical infrastructure sector there are
a lot of different questions
and then
extending that from sector to sector c
cert
what exactly is a sector c cert and what
does it do
this is a definition that can vary from
country to country um and then we see
additional terms we see terms like
isac
we see terms
now we're starting to see things like
sector socks and things like that
and different cyber security centers
partnerships uh public-private
partnerships so there's all these
different terms and it can be a bit
confusing to understand what exactly
we're talking about
so for the purposes of this presentation
and the purposes of the framework that
i'm going to talk about
we call
we consider a sector c cert um any
incident response capability that is
responsible for a subset of a country or
or an economy
now
this means that
it includes a lot of different things so
our definition is pretty pretty wide and
pretty all-encompassing so we include
things like i sacks
under this definition even though
you know these are slightly different
organizations with slightly different
missions
when we're talking about it for the
purposes of this framework and of this
sort of discussion about national
ecosystems
we think we can sort of categorize and
group all these organizations together
so just keep that in mind throughout as
i go through the rest of the
presentation
of course
each organization is different
but for what we're talking about here we
can group them together
um there are a couple important things
that we have to understand about sector
c certs
there are different tasks and different
functions that a sector c cert
can carry out
incident response of course is one of
them
one of the more important tasks of
sector c cert or any sector capability
is communication and coordination
both among the members
of that sector but also with other
sectors and the rest of that national
ecosystem that i'll talk about
um hosting discussions providing
training
and building trust and confidentiality
among members are all important
things that a sector cert
or sector capability can do
again
not every sector c cert is going to be
doing all of these tasks
some may
but some may only perform a subset of
these tasks
that's okay
that's still a sector c cert but again
we have to keep in mind that each
organization is different
and that might be true even within a
country you may have sector c certs
within a country
that are performing
um
at one set of services and then for a
different sector there may be a c-cert
that performs a different set of
services
so the question and the challenge then
becomes how do we get these
organizations to work together and to
cooperate
for the betterment of of the whole
um
one thing that i do want to emphasize
here
is that sector caesars are unique
organizations uh they differ from
national sea certs or the piecerts that
chris would have just talked about um
so
there are some things that we we say a
sector c cert must do
in order to be considered a sector c
certain
the most important thing
is working to bridge the gap between
public and private
sector entities in a given country so a
financial sector sea cert for example
may work to bridge the gap between a
financial regulator and private sector
banks
um that's a key function of a sector c
cert and and perhaps one of the only
things that we can really say that a
sector caesar has to be doing or we may
not consider it a sector ceaser
again just something to keep in mind
um
but when we have sector c certs we can
say that they provide certain advantages
over these other organizations uh over
um national c-certs or things like that
the two advantages that are most obvious
and most important for sector c certs
are scalability and expertise
the scalability
is important to understand
because
having implementing a regime of sector c
certs
allows the rest of your organizations
the rest of your incident response
organizations to sort of focus on
different missions so when we start to
deploy sector c certs now we see that
the role of a national sea cert for
example can be expanded and can focus on
other things
and in terms of expertise
we see particularly in critical
infrastructure or critical information
infrastructure sectors um that there is
a lot of specialized knowledge and
specialized skills necessary to respond
to incidents in those
sectors
so
for example the threats that are faced
by a specific sector may be unique to
that sector um think of
uh
power
critical infrastructure
financial sector
all of these different sectors will have
specific threats that aren't seen in
other sectors so when you develop a
sector c cert you're developing an
organization or a body that can really
focus on gaining expertise in those
particular areas
gaining expertise against particular
types of attacks gaining expertise with
particular software systems or hardware
systems
um so the level of specialization that
is enabled by a sector c cert
is one of the unique
and critical roles that a sector ceaser
will fill
so
with an understanding of what a sector c
cert is and what we mean when we use
that term
the next term that we have to really
define or describe is that national
cyber security ecosystem
so for a little bit of background
um what when we were developing this
sector c cert framework that i'll talk
about here in a little bit
um
we were thinking about
a lot
about the role of the of the sector cser
and how that sector ceaser interacts
with
the rest of the organizations in a
particular country
and what we kind of realized was that
there are a lot of different
interactions between all of the
different organizations that occur on a
daily basis
or an annual basis
you have day-to-day communications
information sharing
sharing of threat information sharing of
vulnerability information
but then you also have less frequent
interactions
such as trainings
or awareness buildings or just
cooperation
and then you have ad-hoc cooperation
in the form of incident response uh or
something of that nature
so there are a lot of different ways
that these organizations would interact
or work together
and we realized that we needed a term to
describe all of those interactions
between all of those different
organizations again those could include
law enforcement national c certs
private sector entities
regulators
and in some cases this could even
include transnational organizations
such as first
or some of those sector c certs that are
international in nature
such as financial sector
or transnational corporations
so there are all these different
stakeholders and all these different
interactions
so
we thought that this was best described
as a national cyber security ecosystem
and that
term describes both the organizations uh
and the interactions that occur on a
daily basis and on a sort of more more
spread out more like an annual basis
so
there are a couple different
important things to think about and to
consider when we talk about that
national cyber security ecosystem
uh one is the central role of a national
sea cert in that national cyber security
ecosystem
national c-cert tends to be
at the center of it and they tend to be
the most common
or most heavily relied upon
organization for coordinating and
communicating across that ecosystem
and then the second important factor
is establishing trust
within the national cyber security
ecosystem
a lot of the interactions are based on a
level of trust between the different
organizations
without that trust
the types of helpful and necessary
interactions
and sharing of information starts to
break down
so when we're thinking about sector c
certs
we have to think about
okay how does my sector c cert interact
with the national ecosystem
which means thinking about
how will my national sea cert interact
with the national c-cert
and how will my sector sea cert
establish trust with all of the other
stakeholders and all the other players
within this national ecosystem so these
are really important things to keep in
mind and important considerations uh
when you're developing or implementing a
sector c cert
so in order to
answer some of those questions
we started to go back um when we were
developing the sector c cert framework
and think about how do i develop these
sector c certs or these sector-based
capabilities
so we broke the process down into these
six steps and these six steps that we
described within the framework are
designed to take you from a current
state which we call the as is state
to a future state which we call the 2b
state
now the acid state can be either
nothing it can be that way we don't have
a sector c cert
or it can be that we have a sector c
cert but we want to improve its function
and further integrate it into that
national cyber security ecosystem
so
our 2b state we hope
is a functional capable sector c cert
that is integrated with that national
cyber security ecosystem
and is capable of interacting with its
peers
and sharing information and being
successful and operating in that way
so to do that
we break the process into again these
six steps
first is considering prerequisites
these are things like understanding
who's hosting your sector c-cert um who
are the constituents who are all the
stakeholders
i'm thinking about how are you going to
fund and staff and operate this sector
cesar
step two is gathering information this
is going out and talking to all the
stakeholders
understanding what their requirements
are of the sector c cert
what they hope the sector sea cert will
be able to provide
and what they may be able to do to
contribute to the functioning and the
success of the of the sector ceaser
step three is to organize all of that
information that has been discovered
and evaluate the gaps so the gaps will
help you understand
what is missing between your current as
is state and your desired to be state
once you've evaluated and understood
those gaps you can build a roadmap that
will help you get from the as is to the
2b
so for example if you discover that you
have a nascent
undeveloped sector c cert but you want
to have a fully integrated sector c cert
your roadmap may describe things like
how do i establish protocols for
communicating and sharing information
with other sector c certs or with the
national ceaser
it may describe how i implement new
incident response capabilities for this
sector ceaser
so the roadmap is really going to be a
detailed document
that describes not only what you want to
achieve
but how you are going to achieve it
that lends into step five which is to
plan and implement the sector c cert
implementation is where we see in our
experience a lot of sector c search run
into trouble right it's one thing to go
and gather information
and to say okay here are the challenge
areas here are the gaps
okay we're going to put together a
document that says what we want to do to
fill those gaps
but when it comes down to actually
implementing that and this is where
organizations run into challenges
so in the framework itself
which is published on the seis website
we have a lot of of ideas and
suggestions and plans for how to avoid
those challenges
for example
securing stakeholder buy-in ahead of
time
building trust i mentioned the
importance of trust in that national
cyber security ecosystem
so things like that understanding where
you're going to run into problems ahead
of time will help you plan
to have a successful implementation
and then the last part of this process
is to conduct post-implementation
activities
to understand where you've been
successful and where you might need to
do additional rounds of development in
order to achieve your goal of really
developing that sector c cert and
integrating it into that national
ecosystem
as i mentioned the national ecosystem i
want to emphasize that there are two
points in this process two steps where
we really see the importance of
interacting with that national ecosystem
understanding who all the stakeholders
are
and getting their buy-in and their
participation for this process
obviously at the beginning when you're
thinking about the prerequisites
you really need to consider
again who are all the stakeholders
in this process
who are the organizations that my sector
ceaser will rely on for
cooperation for communication for
assistance
and then which organizations will be the
constituency of this sector cesar
all of those things again are what will
make up your national cyber security
ecosystem for a given country so this is
where you're really defining your
national cyber security ecosystem
so you have to keep that in mind as
you're doing that part of the process
then again in step five as you start to
implement
it's very important to keep in mind the
national cyber security ecosystem
because this is where um we start to see
actually the national cyber security
system being affected
by the presence of this
either this new organization this new
sector c cert or by the sector c cert
that now has an expanded role
or a more
in-depth or more detailed mission
so a lot of times the challenges here
are that new roles or responsibilities
are being allocated to a sector c cert
and this is a change from what was
happening previously
so maybe previously a national national
sea cert was handling certain tasks for
certain roles that are now going to be
done by a sector ceaser so we have to
understand how this affects the
operation of the national sea cert
and also how it affects the constituency
that previously worked with the national
c-cert and now we'll be working with the
sector ceaser
so again thinking about all the
stakeholders and how they're being
affected
at different parts of this process is is
really important
um
[Music]
i'm going to skip that
a couple important things that
we want to keep thinking about as we
talk about
um especially integrating that that um
sector c cert with the national cyber
security ecosystem
is services services that the sector csr
will offer
um and services that the sector ceaser
may not offer
um so again a lot of you are probably
familiar with the first c cert services
framework
um this breaks the function of a c cert
into several service areas and then sub
areas or subservices of course
and what i just want to emphasize here
is that
when you're thinking about the functions
of the sector c cert and the rest of the
national cyber security ecosystem you
have to consider
which services will be offered by which
organization essentially
so in the framework the sector seizure
framework
we have in an appendix
that describes different service areas
and considerations for which may be
appropriate for a sector c cert
and which may be best left to other
organizations like national sea cert or
private sector
or things like that
but as you're establishing your sector
cesar or thinking about developing a
sector c cert
what you want to do is understand what
is needed for that organization to
provide those services
what sorts of knowledge skills and
ability your sector cert will need if
they want to offer different services
so we cover all that
in the framework
there all right i already talked a lot
about integrating with the national
cyber security ecosystem um but i think
it it bears repeating some of the
specific considerations um again if
you're
operating creating or or improving a
sector c cert
we want to ask some of these key
questions
as we go through the process
i mentioned the relationship between the
sector c cert and national sea cert
that is critically important
of course sometimes we see
it's the case uh particularly in in
developing countries
sometimes there is no national sea cert
but sectors may be ahead of the national
government in implementing csr
capabilities
so we see in particular frequently the
nashville or i'm sorry frequently the
financial sector
can sometimes be ahead of
the national government in implementing
a sector-based capability
um but you have to understand even then
um what may be the future state uh in
terms of if a national c-cert is created
later on how will my sector ceaser
interact with that
and even if there's no national c-cert
um what are government requirements
um for instant response or for cyber
security is there law enforcement
are there national security
considerations are there legal
requirements
and so these are all important
considerations
um and then finally
how will sector c cert address
issues of bridging the gap between the
public sector and the private sector
again this is a critically important
part of of understanding that national
cyber security ecosystem
and understanding how
or what role the cyber the national or
the sector seizure
will play
[Music]
so i just wanted to go through a quick
case study that i i think illustrates
some of
some of the challenges that that you can
see in this process
of developing a sector c cert
so i'm not going to name the country
that we partnered with
but this case study is based on an
actual uh partner that that the sei
uh worked with to develop sector-based
capabilities um
so just by background
uh in this country prior to our
engagement with them
this country had implemented
a bunch of cyber security and incident
response measures
in their sectors
there had been government directives
not not legal legislation
but sort of executive actions that had
required these sectors to create new
cyber security capabilities for the
purpose of securing that country's
critical infrastructure
however
what had happened in this country is
that there was no strategy
um there was no
um ever put into developing
any strategy or understanding how all of
these organizations would interact not
only with each other
but with it with the national government
and with law enforcement and other
organizations
as a result um
essentially there was a lot of wasted
time and effort
as these sectors went through the
process of trying to establish the
capability um but without any guidance
or without any understanding of what the
other sectors were doing
um so we started our collaboration
with this country and our engagement
there in in 2016
and we started by doing um basically a
review of the current state
um and helping them to develop a
vision to move forward in sort of an
organized
collaborative fashion across sectors
so we developed an action plan which
would be equivalent to that road map
that i would have described or that we
described in the um in the framework
and we've revalidated that
work plan or that action plan
by
discussing it with all the stakeholders
in february of 2017.
to implement this again implementation
is the stage where a lot of challenges
can occur
um we did a couple of things
we did some workshops and some training
um but what we did is we brought the
national c cert and the sector c cert
partners together
and had them go through these workshops
and these trainings together so they all
understood um things like roles and
responsibilities
and had an opportunity to meet each
other in person and interact with each
other and to establish some of those
relationships that are critical to the
success of that national cyber security
ecosystem uh so you can see here just a
list of trainings and topics that we um
that we did with these organizations
and then at the end we made a few
recommendations
we recommended that the
the government
and the stakeholders in this country
put together a series of documents um
and a series of artifacts that would
help guide them to implementing their
sector c certs and integrating those
sector c certs
with the rest of the ecosystem that they
had in existence in this country
so
we recommended that they put together a
charter for each of their organizations
concepts of operations
um staffing guidelines training
guidelines um
and then we put together a list of
sort of work that they that these
organizations could be doing and could
be cooperating on
and we had them define these in policy
and in documentation
so that everyone knew
with what each organization would be
doing and understood how they would
interact with each other
so that said um with that example
um i just wanted to sort of
bring it back to
um
the section ceaser framework
um and talk about that really just a
little bit
um again the purpose of the document is
to establish you know what a sector c
cert is and and how we develop one
um so
we understand when we're developing
sector c cert um that there are
different procedures and different
policies that are applicable based on
um
what the sector needs
what technology it's using what the
sensitivity of that sector is
and what critical infrastructure or
non-critical infrastructure is being
protected
so again
that document is published on the sei
website we encourage you to
to go check that out
and learn a little bit more about the
process
and a little bit more about implementing
sector c certs and integrating them into
the national uh ecosystem
[Music]
so that is it that's my presentation i'd
be happy to answer any questions uh at
this point
i saw there were some there have been a
couple of comments on the chat channel
uh
i think andrew cormax talked about going
open mike if he wants does anyone want
to raise a hand or put something in the
chat
uh
andrew
oh no
okay i guess we'll leave it there there
are comments
if you want to address those in the chat
yeah i see a couple comments
um uh thank you mark for sharing the
link uh to our sector seasirt framework
um
[Music]
and
i see uh ammar has also shared uh just a
resource there
um
yeah into andrew cormick uh to your
comment i absolutely agree um with the
the distinction that you've made between
uh c cert
and something like uh i guess like like
an isac
or a different organization
um
i think
it just to go back to
you know where i started
for the purposes of this
process that i'm talking about um we
actually
in in the framework we use the term
sector-based capability
as sort of a more broad all-encompassing
term just to talk about the process of
developing a capability
um that will be part of your national
cyber security ecosystem
um
i kind of slipped into just using the
term sector c cert
which is is one type of sector-based
capability uh an isac is a different
type of
sector-based capability
but when we talk about the process of
developing these capabilities
integrating them with the national
ecosystem
we think that the same process is
applicable regardless of if you're doing
a c cert or an isac or something else
um but obviously you have to understand
that
the actual function of the team the
functioning of that capability will
differ depending on its mission and what
type of team it actually is whether it's
a c-shirt or an i-sack so yeah i
completely agree with the with your
observation yeah
good yes
it's easy to
to confuse the terms and i apologize i
was not using
sector-based capability
um yeah
i think you're absolutely right
i've seen this as well that you know
people banks talk to banks because they
understand each other they can have a
common taxonomy they've got the same
problems and making sure that that
doesn't stay purely in the banking
sector and reaches that national search
so you can then look for patterns across
multiple sectors is really really
important so that was very interesting
thank you justin i appreciate i
appreciate you taking the time to spend
this for that
that's great
more one more raised hand
what more
yes so does this work actually yes looks
good
uh some comments from myself because we
actually have done this so then also
there is the austrian engine sector's
research and
some points from our experience
it's not easy to get the whole sector to
come together and and reach a common
goal not easy at all for some it's
easier for some others it's quite
impossible
but once you get this this really helps
second point is funding uh in our case
uh the electoral season is actually
funded by the sector itself
that's
has some positive effects because uh
that way it's clear that the sector is
theirs it's their um
their
the team that they're buying services
from it's not a government uh forcing
them to interact with them it's a
supplier for the for the sector and that
makes for a very
different type of relation than between
the private sector and the government
entity
this really helps in some way because
very depending on your country but
in some places
it's not easy to tell
employee talk to to this government
government agency versus
talk to this our self-selected uh
supplier of services this is a very
different
way of interaction it really helps
so if you have any other questions
regarding our experience uh just
ask me in the chat or whatever we're
happy to share our experience thank you
thank you for that those are really
really important comments
um and i think they emphasize the fact
that and again we talk about this a bit
in the framework um the every
deployment of one of these capabilities
is unique and different and needs to
meet the specific requirements of of the
country or the sector um at the time um
you know the idea of
of
who should host this and who should fund
it is is really important
uh for example we see in some countries
um
the
regulatory body for a particular sector
may also host the sector c cert
um and there are advantages to that
model but there are disadvantages as
well right um so if if your financial
regulator is also the government
organization that hosts a financial
sector sea cert
uh
or a sector capability um
you know you could have some some
hesitancy over reporting of incidents or
things like that
because
the people who are supposed to be
sharing the information are also your
regulator um
there's
of course advantages to that model um
but i i think to your point there
you have to carefully consider the
advantages and disadvantages and and do
whatever is going to be um
most
most advantageous for your specific case
i very much agree with that i think we
had similar things in the uk with the
bank of england who wanted to join to
learn how people to defend themselves
but also were the regulators so yeah
that's a very important point
excellent i think that's it justin thank
you very much