[Music]
thank you for joining us today it's it's
hopefully towards the end of these
virtual meetings but i think we've made
a real success of them they've been
really good at bringing people together
but hopefully we can start meeting in
person soon um
thank you to jaund and tfc cert for
helping us you know working with us and
us working with them to build this the
agenda it seems i think we have a really
exciting agenda there's some really
interesting pieces i'm looking forward
to seeing and hearing about so those are
those are good for things
um
we're moving on to the agenda very
quickly and the first thing we have is
both a welcome from alex our chair of
first and then followed that by silvio
so i'll pass the chair or the microphone
so to speak over to alex who has a sort
of a statement comments on the present
situation
thank you very much chris um
dear tfc third members and dear first
members and like dear participants
from all across the world
this is a deeply sad moment for me and
for our members and the global community
we have
colleagues who are directly affected we
have friends or family in eastern europe
and we feel
deep empathy for those affected
the board of directors condemns the
attack that is happening in the ukraine
and we are horrified by the
violent violation of international law
i think we are a global community tied
together by by a shared mission and
motivation
um to bring together instant response
teams and security teams from from every
country
across the world to to ensure a safe
internet for all
um but we also tied together as as
citizens of the world
um so our role is to to provide instant
responders a worldwide
contact to the right teams and
information
achieve a common understanding and also
help technical and non-technical
communities
to understand what we do
[Music]
and all of this becomes even more
important
uh in in crisis situations
now our community really inspires me and
the
common goal that we share which is
making the internet uh more secure
helping protect critical infrastructure
or just listening to our colleagues
friends and family
so your your contribution to this goal
really matters um
and with that i wish you a a productive
and fruitful event
um thank you very much for all this to
all the speakers the organizers and the
volunteers
uh who make this this event happen
um and with that back to you chris
thank you alex i'll pass now over to
silvio so i'll stop sharing my screen
sylvia you should share yours now
for a welcome from the kfc
also welcome from my side
to everyone who uh participate here and
uh also we from tft third has a
statement to the actual situation
we all were all shocked when we heard
about the news about the russian
military invasion at the ukraine a week
ago
um most
of us know that there was an armed
conflict in the eastern border of
ukraine
um but we could not imagine that there
would be a war in the middle of europe
in this
century uh we
as individuals as well as the syrian
committee of tfc cert condemned the war
on ukraine
in principle
uh we at tfc cert have a process to
address team misconduct to a desperate
solution dispute resolution process
and to request sanctions
in the present case we have a breach of
trust not by the teams but by the
controlling authority of the teams
therefore at the request of members
in this extraordinary situation
we have taken an extraordinary decision
to temporarily suspend the membership
of the two teams russian cert and search
by until the situation returns to normal
i would like to note that we also
condemn not only the physical
attacks but also virtual ones regardless
of which part in a conflict they came
from
and with this
um
we hope that you understand our position
and
we will wish you a fruitful
uh you see my
uh
my uh my slides
unless i cannot add
my
video
but that doesn't matter
um okay
uh we have a small update um to the
community we have a new ti associate um
that's jan capriva who is uh
who we like to welcome
as a ti associate we have a new
certified team in the tfc cert that's a
search pg from portugal
and we have two re-certified team that's
c cert as he said
from czech republic and ncsa dot fi from
finland who has successfully
done the recertification
we have a new liaison member candidate
um
that's
search cc from justin we heard um
shortly before
um
they are in the process now uh to become
eliezo member
um one
short notice to the transits training um
we will have transits training again
physically in harlem in april or next
month
there are some seats left so if
anyone
has uh like to have a
seat or like to join training feel free
to
um
contact
nicole and
for a seat
look on the home page
um the last
thing
is um
okay the second last thing is
um
we
as you might know um
we have a future working group where we
will start a own foundation
this year
so at the moment
we are working or the notary is working
on a dutch version of the bylaws for the
foundation
um
with all the legal stuff in it that we
afterwards can share it with the
steering committee into partners and uh
when we have finished this to get back
to you
um
we
have a blog about this
have a look at that
and also we opened um for the community
all the work that was done
by the
by the future working group
so
until september there will be a lot of
things coming to you so one of
them is that the invoicing organization
will change it uh will not be shaywa
anymore that will
invoicing you for the dfc third
membership fee
and also there will be an election
um
for the supervisory board in the
foundation so
we like to have participants of the
community in the supervisory board of
the foundation and also
there will be a la uh we need to elect
this year two members and also the chair
for
tfc cert
and the last one um like chris mentioned
with the first meetings we like also to
meet us personally
so we
have tentative physical meeting in
amsterdam in week 19 so it's march
uh it's um
may
9th and the days after that
um
we but we will do this tsc stuff stephen
committee update also in a virtual way
um
that if you cannot travel you at least
get the
um
the update
and we are looking forward to september
to meet
physically
and there we are looking for hosts so um
if you can afford or if you
like to support us for a physical
meeting
feel free to contact
nicole or myself
then we can get in contact each other
that's it thank you and
back to chris