so our next presenter now is Andrew
Jameson Andrews been working in the
security embedded systems for over 20
years Andrew works in the innovation
team of underwriters laboratories
transaction Security Division he holds a
bachelor's degree in electrical
engineering and a master's degree in
information security his presentation is
titled IOT security it's in the stars
please welcome to the stage Andrew
Jamison hello everybody happy to hear me
I haven't been miked up previously my
clicker ok so I'm going to be talking
about IOT obviously a theme for asset
ubiquitous I ot's everywhere i'll try
not to use too many peas and kind of
bounces off the mic i'm going to be a
little bit controversial and some of the
things that i'm saying i have some
controversial views and a controversial
sort of guy but I figured I'd start off
with the most controversial question
right let's don't get it out of the way
so does it make me look fat on this
stage was expecting a bigger stage I
don't know but the question then is how
much do you think I wink I mean people
wear different things but you can
objectively make an assessment could be
wrong i hope it's wrong at the time
about my weight how do you do that how
are you able to objectively assess my
weight you can do that because we have
units of measurements we have metrics
for weight and so those metrics based
primarily on this for weight this is
what's called the one kilogram prototype
it is a lump of metal it's based around
various places you can see them in
museums and so forth platinum iridium
alloy ba-ba-ba-ba ultimately this is the
way we can all say you think I way you
know as felt 70 kilos based on the fact
that we all know what a kilo is because
we have the metrics to do that question
then question for the audience and the
question for this particular topic how
we measure
if we're going to have an assessment of
security systems we need to be able to
measure it we need to be able to
understand when we say something is
secure what we mean by that or when we
have two different people two different
organizations two different
methodologies of looking at something we
can compare the two and say well if this
system says it's secure this other
system should do the same thing
ultimately we need to define this
methodology and we need to have some
acceptable level of risk based on this
methodology now we've got security
evaluations already so how do we do this
how do we do this in the existing
methodologies that we have well let's
look at those so here I've got you know
a plane and you've got at the top a
formalized methodology and coming down
the axis their informal across the
horizontal individually defined risk and
formally or externally defined risk and
if we look at the types of security
evaluations that are common today come
criteria phipps 140s 0134 91 or sorry
yeah 13 491 pts penetration testing I've
been involved in all of these one way or
another usually doing assessments on
them so how do they fit into this plane
well common criteria is very formalized
because of that it's actually quite
expensive and takes an awfully long time
it is very structured it goes through
what's called a certification body which
is generally the information security
organization within that government that
it's being done in within that country
it takes a very long time costs a lot of
money I was at a cryptographic module
conference just last week in Canada and
everybody was talking about how
difficult time-consuming and costly
security evaluations are because they
take this amount of time they cost this
amount of money because they're very
formalized fips 140-2 also very
formalized interestingly enough the risk
is quite individual they don't really
have a lot of men
tricks in that system but they do have
statements such as it shall be secure
which is great what exactly does secure
mean I saw 1349 one kind of sits in the
middle a little bit because you don't
really have a lot of metrics in it you
don't have a formalized methodology
there are no testing requirements PTS
which is a system that I use quite often
for banking devices a little bit more
formal little bit less costly than
common criteria although to be honest
with you it's kind of merging with
common criteria in a large way at the
moment becoming more costly more
time-consuming and then penetration
testing varies greatly depending on who
you're doing it wears depending on what
you're testing you can have some
formalized methodologies around this or
alternatively it can be very subjective
and very informal so these sorts of
things then define how the methodology
is performed but then there is the
question of the threats so we talked
about methodologies with threats from my
point of view I like to think of
security problems in three ways i like
to call it security DIY three types of
security problems they're deliberate
problems these are the back doors that
people bake into systems because they
want to have access later on in the best
possible light you could say that people
do this because they want to enable
features later on they want to upload
code so forth certainly not saying
that's a good thing but often it is so
that others can get access maliciously
surreptitiously ignorant then ignorant
problems and these are the majority of
the problems that we see in my opinion
this is where you have poor security
settings and configurations often it's
done through ease of use to make the
consumers life easier to make the
product better more feature risk more
feature risk risk rich sorry but often
as you add features as you add functions
as
you add new things you increase the
attack surface of the device and you
increase potential full security
problems yet to be discovered so the why
of security DIY this is where you have
problems you don't know about yet and as
we know security problems in devices in
systems in software come up all the time
people find new methodologies of attacks
new classifications of attacks new ways
to attack things and this then requires
that you must continually maintain your
systems so how then do we currently
address these problems in systems that
we have at the moment so deliberate code
review if you're going to find a
backdoor really the only way you're
going to find that it's by looking
through the code and hunting for it sure
you can fuzz it a little bit but
generally code review is going to be the
way that you would find something in
there how do you find the problems of
ignorance well code review again yes but
also penetration testing fuzzing you try
and find the incorrect the poor
configurations that have been set up how
do we address that why the yet to be
discovered well for prayer we can hope
that they don't come up and then we
patch later on security evaluations then
in my mind have three defining features
I talked about the threats three
features of security evaluations they
take time they cost money and they
always fail what I mean by that is there
not a set and forget' type of system you
don't do a security evaluation and then
walk away saying that product is secure
you do it saying I've done the best I
can within a time and cost budget I have
found a number of vulnerabilities or not
and they've been remediated hopefully
but at some point in the future and it
could be a second you walk away from
that system a new vulnerability will
come up and that system is no longer
secure so okay I've talked a lot about
security testing and so for
how does this fit in with IOT well let's
talk about it i OT devices are becoming
smarter now a lot of this is based on
the fact that processing elements are
becoming smaller cheaper less
power-hungry when I was designing
devices back in I won't mention gears
but a long time ago 8-bit processors
used to cost a lot of money now I'm
amazed when I do evaluations on products
how cheap security processes are and
their security processes you then look
at general-purpose processes they are
remarkably cheap and with that you can
enable all sorts of wonderful features
and functions and products to do strange
and unusual things as part of these
slides I decided I was going to try and
google the most ridiculous IOT things I
could think of so I thought I know
connected nappies well they exist
connected kettles they exist connected
cat litter boxes sure why not so you
know when your cat's going to do a poo
that's important funny thing is
connected toasters which is often the
one that people talk about actually not
so many this is a concept of one there
which I quite like it prints out the
weather but everything is getting
connected because vendors are trying to
differentiate their products based on
features so it's a problem with that I
mean features are great new things are
great why is that a security issue why
can't they just bake in security we saw
in the last presentation one of the
questions why isn't security just baked
in at the start anyway one of the
problems then the major problem that I
see is that as well as trying to
differentiate their products based on
features the design prototype and
production cycles are getting compressed
and this reduces the amount of time that
the vendors have to test for and
remediate vulnerabilities I see this in
the security industry when I work with
people who make products
designed specifically with security in
mind they still have end dates and they
say I've got to go to market date on
this day I need to do that I've had
people in the lab coding up new releases
of code as we found problems with it
every day so they can hit their go to
market date now if that's a problem for
people who are making security devices
it's an even bigger problem for people
who are making commercial devices where
they're intending to sell millions of
products and therefore their margins are
razor thin and every day they're not on
the market they're losing money the
other problem customers can't
necessarily differentiate products based
on security sure everybody kind of talks
about security and says it's important
and you know we need to be concerned
about it but I'm not completely
convinced that when it comes to actually
paying for it everybody would do that
talk about that a little bit later on
your vulnerabilities as i mentioned
released all the time the final point is
the product vendors the people who are
making these products there is no
incentive for them to make more secure
systems sure we'd like it sure to be
great the end of the day we live in
mostly capitalist world they want to
make money and so if they're going to
spend extra time and extra production
budget or development budget into their
products to make security there needs to
be some incentive otherwise why would
they do it they're interested in
differentiating their products based on
functionality and cost at the moment
they can't necessarily differentiate
their product on security and that's in
development once it's released why would
they patch it they're making device
money they sell once they make their
money no incentive to patch so where is
it fixed already been around for a long
time we've talked about security
security is important okay so why don't
we just do pen testing code review on
these systems well cost time issues once
again time budget costs
I just personally don't think it's going
to work to the extent that we need to
why well it doesn't scale gartner
article here talks about you know 25
billion things connected to the internet
that's a lot of pen testers we already
have issues at the moment where there's
not enough security people in the
industry to service the existing need
we're going to pen test every product
before it's released not only is a time
and cost issue there's an issue around
how many people are going to be
available to do that pen testing as a
point-in-time solution once again we
need to maintain these products over
time doesn't address ongoing security
security evaluations are inherently
subjective you're going to choose the
gold dress pen tester or the blue desk
pen tester because as I mentioned at the
start it's a subjective evaluation
there's no floor my eyes methodology or
at least if there is and there is in
some contexts it's not well maintained
and as somebody who manages a number of
security labs around the world for one
company I can tell you it's hard to
maintain parity with in the same
organization let alone when you're
dealing with tens or hundreds of
different organizations that do
different things have different
incentives monetize things differently
finally the cost of this isn't exposed
to the customer and the value of it
isn't exposed to the customer so what I
mean by that let's say you go to into a
store there's two televisions they have
the same features same resolution same
smart features you know as far as you
can tell the picture is exactly the same
it's going to mount on the wall the same
way it's going to perfect in your house
this is the television you want there's
two of them one costs 500 bucks one
costs 750 bucks now without any
additional information because there's
no information that you can get from
this in terms of security which one are
you going to choose but what if one was
more secure would you care how would you
know that it's more secure
and how much would you care are you
going to care two hundred and fifty
dollars worth that's certainly going to
be a point at which you're going to care
less but security takes time and costs
money so that cost needs to be exposed
this means that I OT security in my
opinion is a commercial problem sure
it's a technical problem but that
technical problem is because there are
no correct commercials wrapped around
the ability to externalize the
development costs and the ongoing cost
of security there is no incentive for
vendors to maintain security over time
so what is the solution then how are we
going to fix this well commercial
problems need to be addressed
commercially kind of make sense we need
to create an incentive for the vendor to
build security into their products we
need to be able to inform customers so
they can make a purchase decision so
when a product costs more because it is
more secure they can decide whether they
want more security at more cost or less
security and just take a little bit more
money home we need to also provide
methods for the vendors to understand
security now security is hard but of a
cliche but ultimately a lot of these
people are very good at making products
very good at adding features but they
don't always understand why or when that
causes problems in security once again
work a lot with device vendors for the
security industry even in that context
they don't always understand why
something is more or less secure and so
if we're going to make products more
secure we need to help educate the
vendors because otherwise it's not going
to happen and we need to do all of this
within a framework that allows for rapid
development because products need to go
to market on their go to market date we
need to do it in as little time and cost
as possible because things have budgets
and whereas little overhead as possible
sounds easy well whenever I'm faced with
an insurmountable problem I always refer
to the
Oracle that is Battlestar Galactica all
of this has happened before and all of
this will happen again and look to the
Stars for salvation star rating programs
nice segue there have been used to
change consumer behavior in the past so
we've got star ratings for energy to
help change consumer behavior around
energy consumption do they want the more
energy efficient product that is going
to cost more money or do they want to
spend less money now and have a less
energy efficient product this system is
used around the world this is the EU
rating for that sort of thing we also
have star ratings for water consumption
now my personal anecdote around this is
I was purchasing a dishwasher at one
point we went in I saw the one that was
cheaper I said wow I really like this
one my wife saw the one that had five
water star rating said I really like
that one because she had been
incentivized around environmental issues
and so forth to buy something that had a
higher star rating when you looked at it
the difference wasn't actually that much
the star rating though was changing the
purchase behavior at the point of
purchase you have star ratings the cars
as well for safety in cards why don't we
have this for security well there are
problems how are we going to compare
devices in terms of evaluating their
security you could be comparing a router
to a smart light bulb how we can do that
you could be looking at something that's
written in visual C sharp or C++ or Java
how are we going to compare across those
platforms the operating system could be
different how are we going to compare
between systems objectively so that when
you have something that's running
embedded windows against something
that's running Linux how do you compare
them how are we going to assess them how
we going to do that in a cost-effective
way well let's keep it simple I always
like to try
main keep things simple whenever we can
as far as I'm concerned devices any
device any computing system can be
defined by three simple things
interfaces it will have inputs and
outputs if it doesn't have an input or
an output it's a brick that only has
inputs it's a heater they have to have
inputs and outputs to be a computing
system processing a tack surface so this
is the code that makes the product do
whatever it does everything has code in
one of my pet hates is when people talk
about hardware only systems everything
has coding and that has some sort of
attack surface based on what it's
written in how big it is how many
functions it has then you have the
system architecture what does it run on
is it Harvard architecture is it von
Neumann architecture does it have memory
protection is it all being run directly
out of ROM does it have relocatable
memory these sorts of things are
interesting when it comes to how a
device can be attacked I'm going to call
the combination of those things the
vulnerability surface so the more
interfaces the larger the attack surface
and the less secure system can be
objectively considered the architecture
then can help make the system more
secure or less secure by changing the
vulnerability surface changing your
ability to exploit features or
vulnerabilities in the attack surface so
all we need to do then once we've got
these ways of assessing a system we need
to address the metrics we need to wrap
metrics around that how are we going to
do that how are we going to define the
metrics well this is where we can go
back in history and we can figure out
what they did they just made them up a
kilogram isn't a specific physical thing
it's something people made up so you
could compare weights so we can make up
metrics to enable us to compare the
security of systems so I'm going to call
this the logical security posture or LSP
based on point system
and you have points assigned for
security features and you deduct points
for increasing attack surface incorrect
configurations poor architectures these
sorts of things you can do this because
most computing vulnerabilities have
similar root causes like of randomness
big one happens all the time default
configurations passwords cryptographic
keys happens all the time over
privileged invulnerable code in secure
updates communication methods little or
no logical protections these are the
sorts of things I see in products all
the time and so we can wrap some metrics
around that so let's look at interfaces
then every interface is doing you damage
each protocol supported increases the
attack surface of the system and if you
run that code or less a privilege you
can reduce the vulnerability surface
sure most people don't do that so you
can exploit the vulnerable code for a
meaningful option so in LSB we assign
negative points for all of the logical
interfaces that run at the same
privilege as the assets and the assets
could be personal information it could
be cryptographic keys it could be
anything then you apply a multiplication
factor because it's more vulnerable
you're increasing the vulnerability
surface factors reducing the
vulnerability surface maybe it's being
run in a te these sorts of things add
points or decrease the multiplier now
this gives the vendor clear guidance
that more interfaces is bad now it
sounds obvious but it's just amazing the
vendors are trying to differentiate
their products based on features
features require more protocols more
code so forth you make it clear to the
vendors that that's a bad thing for
security that could affect their sales
later on that helps the vendors make
sensible decisions so why do we need yet
another attack rating method we've
already got Jill which is a methodology
that's contained in common criteria
we've got CBS s why don't we just use
those
well they're for actual vulnerabilities
what I'm talking here is not costing a
vulnerability it's a theoretical concept
about the obscurity of a system the
system has a vulnerability should be
patched it should be fixed now that's
where pen testing and code review comes
in LSP helps to inform the vendors about
security as i mentioned provide clear
incentives and costings require if
you're going to use Jill if you're going
to use cvss you need to do the pen
testing you need to do the code review
that takes time costs money I'm not sure
that's going to work in IOT I just don't
see how its scales I don't see how the
vendors have enough time I don't see the
consumers being willing to pay for that
so look an example so we look at two
linux-based systems basically the same
i'm going to call them routed and router
router mcwrap face these have certain
features and functions greatly
simplified obviously I don't have enough
space on these slides to include all
features and functions but they do
certain things they've got various
interfaces and so forth so if we take a
closer look at route it well okay we can
start off saying there are
vulnerabilities they're easy to fit see
it's got no linux kernel's got multiple
vulnerabilities it's got an old openssl
version got multiple vulnerabilities not
a very fair comparison so let's assume
that they're fixed and now we have
exactly the same systems running exactly
the same code but it has different
vulnerabilities surface so external
interfaces exposed at route that's
problem that causes increased
vulnerability surface so minus points
default passwords problem minus points
default certs problem minus points and
they may not even necessarily be default
just generated the same each time and
because they don't have a a non stateful
random number
system so ultimately if you start up
that router system whatever it is you
start that up the same cert will be
generated at the same time each time
they did a scan essentially of the
internet a number of years ago and found
that of all the systems that you could
access routers firewalls so forth on the
internet three percent of them had the
same certificates they weren't default
they were being generated randomly the
same way because the random number
generators weren't being used properly
non-secure interface exposed minus
points you get the idea no commitment to
updates an important part of this is you
must patch because we have to assume
that new security vulnerabilities will
come out so you absolutely have to patch
your system you have no commitment you
do not get to have a good score so what
does this mean what it would look like
ultimately no patching zero stars an
automatic fail the other one not too bad
it's got some good features if they're
running things at different privilege
levels using the right random number
generator they have a unique password
and username that's on the sticker so
you can always turn it over but if you
don't have physical access you don't
know it these are good things and
importantly there is a date limit on it
because they have said that they would
patch it for a certain number of years
certain period of time so the star
rating is fixed for that time it's not
forever it is only until it stops being
patched at which point it is considered
insecure so is Rowdy more secure than
routed well yes it has better
configurations it has better
implementations it has a smaller
vulnerability surface even though they
both do the same thing does this mean
reality is secure no it'll still need
patching and if they don't do that then
they need to lose their star points not
only on this system they need to lose it
into the future as well on other systems
they've demonstrated they're not
getting their commitments they lose
points and star rating into the future
so this mean that the less secure system
routed will be exposed and vulnerable
first not necessarily more secure
doesn't necessarily mean doesn't fail
what we're not saying here is the system
is secure we're not talking binary not
saying secure an insecure we're saying
this configuration is better because
ultimately that's really the only thing
we can do within the time cost
constraints that we have that's why we
have patching them how do we ensure
patching how do we make sure that the
vendors are meeting their commitments
are patching their systems are doing
what they say they do and now I've just
going al patch up for three years but
then they ship it and nothing ever
happens well once again this has all
happened before and will happen again so
I'm from an organization called ul ul
does a lot of electrical safety testing
has done for a hundred years but it's
not unique in this lots of organizations
do this I'm not here to talk about you
well at all really but the interesting
part of this they had a similar problem
when they're looking at electrical
safety how do they know when you test
the electrical safety of a speaker for
example that they don't just ship you a
perfect speaker and then they
manufacture something in the factory
that is cheaper but completely unsafe
there is a system called a follow-up
service every product that has a ul mark
on it there are six billion products in
the world that have you all marks on it
every single product that has that mark
somebody goes to the factory where that
product is created every quarter and
make sure it's still being made the same
way this already happens so we can do
that for security as well we can make
sure that when a vendor says I'm going
to patch this somebody goes in and
checks it they don't necessarily have to
redo a pen test or anything like that
it's just go in and say okay so I see
you know you've got this particular
Linux kernel version or something like
that needs patching show me your latest
patch they haven't done it they lose
their stars can be done can be done
simply can be done cheaply fits in
time cost budget so if they don't do it
then they lose their points that's the
important thing so ultimately IOT
security the problems are consumers
aren't security engineers they can't
differentiate products based on security
and to be honest with you even those of
us who can still make decisions based on
features and functions and costs for
example I assume we're all security
people in this room and I don't want
people put up their hands but I equally
assume a number of people in this
audience have phones that are produced
by you know Android manufacturers
Samsung who are way I'm not going to
pick on a particular manufacturer that
aren't really patched because you've
made a decision on the phone that you're
buying based on cost and based on
features personally I only use Nexus
phones and big android fan but also a
big fan of patching and I'll make sure
the phone i have is patched every month
with security updates so even security
people don't necessarily make decisions
around security all the time features
functions cost is important security is
hard that is true but because it's hard
it is a costly and time-consuming and
ever and that is the problem it's not
that it's hard being hard is simply the
thing that makes the problem and the
problem is you can't fit security into
easily into the development cost of a
product commercial problems need
commercial solutions insurance is a
great market driver I think insurance is
going to be something that changes
things over time I want to be very clear
when I'm talking here actually that i'm
talking about consumer products to a
large extent i think when we talk about
industrial products health care products
they need to be tested more thoroughly
they have a better time and cost budget
in which to absorb the cost of security
I'm talking about consumer security but
I think insurance can still play a part
in this but they need metrics the
insurance industry needs to know that
not just throwing money away when
they're ensuring somebody so they need
to be able to assess whether something
secure or not now markets also don't
respond well to step functions what I
mean by that is if you say tomorrow
every product ship must be secure it's
not going to happen it takes for example
the payment industry it's taken them
let's see about 15 years to change from
Des does Triple DES and to be honest
with you some people still use single
des it takes a while to build security
into systems into products to educate
people so we need to make sure that we
have metrics to drive the commercial
responsibility into the vendors and in
fact we need to encourage the vendors to
build more secure systems and maintain
them over time I would suggest if we're
going to have a five-star rated system
and some product has five stars they
need to have a bug bounty on that
product they need to be committed to the
security of that product so that people
are actively looking for vulnerabilities
in it and they're going to patch because
they've committed to patch so ultimately
IOT security personally I think it's in
the stars not necessarily these days
though these does thank you very much
okay so do we need to wait for a large
but I have to read them out I think this
whole silent question thing is really
weird and when do we need to wait for a
large breach for companies pay attention
probably although i would go so further
is to say i don't think a large breach
will be enough i think there needs to be
buy-in from governments and consumers on
this I think it'll take time we're going
to need something big yes my concern is
we don't do something soon it's going to
be a little bit too late so I think we
need to build it in now but yeah we
probably need a bridge yeah I don't know
of any there might be some in the car
industry but in terms of consumer
products I personally don't know of any
I don't know whether anybody in the
audience does but I don't know of any
other baby monitors yes yep yeah and
those vtec as well which had some issues
so yeah okay just good point
I I think regulations are good I I mean
ultimately if anything's going to happen
it needs to happen one of two ways you
either need your legislator and you need
some either an industry body to step in
and see these the rules it's probably
not going to happen or a government step
in and say these are rules which could
happen or you need to try and drive it
commercially as I'm saying through
something like star ratings and let
basically the commercial sort themselves
out I think there probably is a place
for regulation but as I said the problem
is that if you just regulate it today
and said everything must be secure
tomorrow it just wouldn't work you just
can't do that the vendors don't know
what they're doing and there's not
enough people to test all the products
so yes I think we need regulation but
that needs to be built around a testable
framework okay I violated my whole rule
of reading it out so I'm going to read
out wood making vendors liable and legal
sense of security issues and the
products make a difference um it would
it absolutely would I think we've seen a
change in the way companies take
security seriously in terms of when
board members have been held liable that
really changes the way the company you
know behaves to a large extent so I
think making vendors liable would but
the question is then liable for what I
mean what exactly are we going to make
them liable for is it loss of
information is it just vulnerable ities
in their product some companies won't
care as much how do you make a vendor in
China liable for a fraud that happens in
Australia I think there's a lot of
complexity around it would help but I'm
not really sure how you do it
I I think yes is the answer I think they
would so I was at a meeting in where was
it sweden at the start of the year
talking to a large vendor of consumer
products i won't mention any specific
names but they were very interested in
having their devices tested for security
in some way i think and they were very
interested in exposing that certainly if
they're going to do it it's going to put
in the hard yards they absolutely want
to expose that they don't want to do
something and then increase the cost of
their product without being able to tell
everybody why it's costing more so I
think there is definitely a an appetite
for this in some areas and certainly
there is not an appetite in other areas
but I think once you have some companies
doing it it will drive others to follow
because I think consumers will choose an
i personally don't think it will confuse
consumers if it's done right but maybe
I'm just I'm not the average consumer so
i don't know but i don't think it's
confusing
yeah I think I've tried to build that
into this system certainly in terms of
patching however I think you can at
least make a go at assessing the
security of the system I think just
saying you know what I'm not even going
to look at it you just have to patch is
fine but it's very reactive I think you
need to be reactive but I think also we
need to have methodologies to assess
them and I think it can be done I think
it can be done so I agree yes she'll be
patched should be all these sorts of
things but I think we can build the
methodology in for assessment at the
same time and apparently that's it thank
you very much