afternoon everyone thinks I'll sit for
the invitation to come and speak with
you today about ID care and our
operations 18 months on from cutting the
ribbon with Minister Keenan in 2014 and
colleagues from the Queen's Own clue
service amongst others in in the brief
time I have with you this afternoon
granted it's it's sleepy time so I'll
try and make this relatively engaging
I'm going to take you on a bit of a
journey as to where we've been what the
nature of our service is and where we're
heading this year that might resonate
with you and your organization's on I'm
probably going to annoy a few people so
I let use that as a caveat i might upset
a few industries on the way but it's all
in the interests of the community so
what is ID care this is a very
simplified version of the landscape you
have certs and response organizations
for industry and government so whilst it
obviously being one now our secret
squirrels in Canberra and cert Australia
at the calm of attorney general's
department and on your right is ID care
and our focus is not on organizations
government and business so much it's
actually on providing that support to
the community so that's where we sit
within the landscape and that is a very
simplified version because in between
all of that are a bunch of other
agencies and organizations that offer
reporting lines and while so it might be
a good thing I might challenge some
debate around whether or not that might
actually be adding a lot of confusion to
the community as to where one needs to
go to get support and help it's a very
complex and crowded space the reporting
space but in terms of support we are it
I'm going to share with you a story
about Joanne Joanne not her name by the
way ID care service is free and
anonymous for the community it's a
not-for-profit organization and a
charity and we intentionally don't ask
the clients that engage our national
hotline for any of their personal
particulars not surprisingly nor do we
charge them for our service although we
have been a target of scams scammers
already which we wear as a badge of
pride Joanne is a young victorian and
Joanne is studying at TAFE she's
studying tourism and through employment
gov that I you through the job active
service a commonwealth government
initiative she she had expressed
interest in a job as a part time travel
administrative assistant and and this
was on the thirtieth of April thirtieth
of April so it's a fairly recent case
and when we've experienced around twenty
to twenty two thousand cases over the
last 12 months so it's a fairly recent
one and and Joanne's quite excited
because within 24 hours they had
arranged an interview of her via Skype
without the video enabled function and
and asked her to complete a personal
particulars form send scanned image of
the driver license pass on her tax file
number bank details things that you'd
expect when things get a bit more
serious in terms of employment prospect
she SAT a skype interview and and
provided it referee details and some 24
hours later was given the thumbs up and
got the job and shortly thereafter that
same day she was emailed by her
intact who also provided a new south
wales landline and was asked to
reimburse a company official for their
travel as you thought that was a fairly
consistent activity to her job the only
difference is that they the company had
transferred the money to reimburse the
employer to her account a personal
account and she was to retain five
percent and then move the balance of
that money to the individual in China
via moneygram now Joanne is in her late
teens and is new to the workforce and as
is the case with a lot of these types of
situations mum gets involved and mum
wised up to the fact that this didn't
quite add up and so she went down to the
local police station and they said you
need to talk to the Department of
Employment the calm of develop on not
not the place and so she did and they
said you need to then report to acorn
the Australian cyber online reporting
network which she did and in her mind
she's thinking have I just been
recruited by organized crime is one of
the first thoughts that she has the
other thoughts that she has as she is
expressed to us is I have five percent
of some proceeds of crime sitting in my
personal bank account what should one do
with that but her primary concern was
there there now asking me to move ten
thousand dollars a week how do I
disengage with this organized crime
group they know where I live they know
everything about me so from from the
local police not the queen's own place
the local police and other states local
police to employment department
employment
to a corn she was then looking around
and thought I better get a scam watch
she went to scam watch who then said
thanks for your report we're going to
now pass you to the Attorney General's
Department who then passed her to us now
now you might think that's a bit
stressful and and that might be the
exception to the rule but that is the
rule that's what happens so that's not
the minority cases that is the majority
of cases so the slide i showed you
before around the tapestry of who's who
in the zoo whilst might be
well-intentioned actually creates
further harm to those that experience
identity and cybercrime are your
customers so where did it leave that
Joanne so Joanne's story continues we
are ID care is resource with counselors
and psychologists so we're not a tech
outfit we rely on good organizations
like lost certain others to perform that
role we're there to pick up the pieces
emotionally and we're there to provide
the pragmatic pathways that individuals
need to take to build resilience around
their identity once it's compromised
whether it be online or physical
Joanne's still waiting for police to
engage with them and it's now the 25th
of May after reporting it to them in the
first week of May via acorn the reality
is she probably won't hear from place at
all that's the reality she's not quite
interested in police investigating to
arrest at the time she was interested in
actually getting some advice from police
as to what to do with the five percent
commission in the bank account because
she doesn't wanna be seen as a money
launderer and she wanted some advice at
the time as to how to disengage with a
large crime drug which the police are
well accustomed to so we've been
providing ongoing counseling with Jo and
we've got grave concerns about her
mental health at the moment
so what is ID care primarily it is a
national case management center that is
our bread and butter so we operate a 13
hundred number and an hour eight hundred
number so all all calls in New Zealand
route through to the Sunshine Coast
where those that don't know the sun's on
coast where 200 kilometers up the road
just off Mooloolaba and we're lucky to
be there because the University of the
Sunshine Coast has provided in-kind
support to our t care to the tune of
around 800 thousand dollars to help us
exist so it's not a a token gesture
that's actually keeping the lights on
most of the revenue that we raise
through our partnerships or sponsorships
go into paying for our counselors so the
national case management centers quite
key to everything that we do but we have
the philosophy within ID care that we
knowledge shared his knowledge doubled
so there's an onus on us to do things
like this and inform you of what's going
on out there and we also run community
programs so we have programs in schools
and programs in aged care facilities as
two groups that we believe are a
particular risk of cyber and identity
related crimes our board is made up of
industry and government leaders and
they're quite keen for IDK to share our
view of how organizations can be better
supporters of their customers and how we
can support them support the community
so a lot of my effort and time is spent
engaging with business and government on
what we can do to give them a view of
the customer experience that they may
not see and we also have a fair bit of
fun of the national ID lab and that lab
is all about looking at the human
factors around cyber crime and what are
those triggers psychologically that
individuals might experience either pre
or post these type of events and we work
very closely with our tertiary sector
partners in Australia New Zealand in the
u.s. they're a big part of what we do is
not just
the national case management center but
you could imagine if if you lose your
wallet or purse how many organizations
you might have represented in it we
spend an enormous number of resources
maintaining a library of over a thousand
response plans across industry and
government so that if you call the
hotline not only are you able to access
the counseling support but you are if
you don't need that you're able to
access support that says of those 20
organizations in your wallet here is
precisely the journey you'll need to
take with all them and that's a huge
investment that we make to maintain that
library we maintain it in two ways we we
engage directly with organizations and
seek their views on how that like their
customers to behave and what they should
prepare their customers to do we don't
really pay much attention to that I
should say that might seem
self-defeating we we actually test
organizations so we have a secret
shopping area if you like and so we're
ringing organizations and testing what
they're doing in terms of providing
advice and the pathways that they enable
their customers to go through and so
what you have here is the results of
that and so let me explain that postcode
3174 in in Melbourne so noble park and
surrounding suburbs our data is getting
so good that we know that if you
experience the same type of cyber
identity crime in that post code you'll
actually experience more harm that if
you resided here and so let me just
explain what that means putting aside
the fact that that's the premier of
Victoria's postcode it means that
through our secret shopping testing and
through our what we call our client
experience scores so every client the
cause IDK almost we asked them who have
you engaged before and what was that
experience like and what do they ask you
to do and was it useful and all those
measures that big business and big um
probably collect in terms of customer
experience and what spits out as a score
out of 10 the client response score is
our testing of organizations so we look
at things like how many times your call
transfer is the information available
online to tell me what to do if I'm a
victim of cyber crime involving your
company or government agency how long am
I waiting on the phone we do a 10-bit 10
am-2 p.m. test to make it a bit more
consistent is the advice consistent so
we don't test just once we test multiple
times so there's a lot of effort that
goes into that so this is where I might
upset a few people do it anyway your
industry so if I'm to if I'm to guess
most here would probably work in that
industry you are the worst performers in
the country at the moment to in terms of
client experience schools so that means
a score of 1 point 8 out of 10 means
that not only our clients dissatisfied
the chances are that through their
engagement with that industry they've
actually been more harmed that's what
that means so it's the reality if you
look up here at sunny Queensland if
we're just looking at queensland
government responses so that's an
aggregate of number of government
departments it's generally on average a
satisfactory result not a great result
but just a satisfactory result and and
so a lot of our emphasis as you would no
doubt see now is not just placed in
supporting the individuals but it's in
trying to raise the standards of how
organizations treat their customers it's
a really big part of it eight percent of
our clients need face-to-face mental
health treatment and the reason why
that's the case has got almost nothing
to do with a crime but everything to do
with how they're treated as a result of
it
so I don't paint a picture of panic but
the country is broken when it comes to
this stuff we're not in a good place at
the moment we invested over 65,000 hours
of counseling last year and the question
that I'm often asked is how long as a
counseling session and my response to
that is as long as it takes because as
the last presenter mentioned it impacts
people in very different ways we collect
around 114 variables per client it's not
question one what's the answer a
question to what's the answer it's a
conversation and we get their blessing
to use that information or bed it's
anonymous anyway but use that
information to inform groups like this
and others about how to improve response
standards we're estimating that will
invest over 80,000 this year balance in
response I mentioned the library that we
maintain then we do share that with our
partners VicRoads is a good case study
VicRoads is the driver licenses you're
in Victoria if somebody hacked my email
and I have scanned copy of the grades
license different to what somebody might
be told via other channels the driver
license number is the most important
credential to an identity thief it's the
number one the card who cares it's the
number that matters because the number
is the gateway to a lot of products and
services out there ok so so we hear
repeatedly every day with our clients
when they report to particular law
enforcement jurisdictions or government
agency X or industry why that it's ok if
you've still got the card the number
doesn't mean anything it's the opposite
it's everything ok so even advice around
that's important to get across to groups
like this VicRoads if you have your
license compromised
they can't do anything well they won't
do anything it's different than card
they won't do anything you have to wait
for it to then be further misused so so
we're not in the prevention game we're
in the response game so we'll have to
wait for you to become more a victim and
even then nothing will be done unless a
letter is signed by a superintendent of
Victoria Police to say that you're
VicRoads license number has been
compromised a misused now the chance of
that happening because we've done some
testing on this is zero so that won't
happen VicRoads in victoria police are
providing two different pieces of advice
albeit by are dependent and that's the
journey of a cyber crime victim that's
the journey which is why things a little
bit more harmful in Victoria the good
news is that that's the same process in
Queensland I say it's good news because
we've actually cracked the jackpot and
had one or two clients manage to get a
new driver license number in Queensland
but it's still a process that's a bit
backward it's not at all preventive or
supportive with univ jewel and then we
might just go to the internet so this is
the the news that's just come in so if
we just click on the ever been knocked
back for credit so this is this is a
live feed how many credit bureaus have
got in australia how many three on the
mainland one in Tasmania the community
only thinks there's one there's three
how much they have to pay for a credit
report nothing yet most times the client
won't be told you can get it for free
and we'll pay 80 bucks most times okay
who knows what a credit ban is credit
band means under the privacy law that
you can request of the three credit
bureaus that your credit report gets too
turn off the shelf and that's actually a
positive thing because if I go down to
Harvey Norman or Westpac or whoever it
might be and I say my name is David
Lacey and I want to get credit and
here's my driver's license number that
I've just compromised dived over they
see they'll go and check a credit record
and it won't happen because you got a
ban in place it's it's one of the only
things that a victim of this crime can
do to prevent misuse where credit is
involved it is actually one of the only
things that can be done the problem
there's several but the problem with
that particular one is you need to go to
all three bureaus it takes two days to
get it in place criminals on average
take 72 hours to misuse it's only in
place for 21 days now although on
average the criminals take 72 hours to
misuse some criminals might decide to
misuse you in 18 months time or 12
months or eight months so so what does
the client do that and do they then
asked for another 21 days well they
can't because they need a police report
number and they can't get a police
report number for a cyber crime because
it goes to a corn and nine times out of
ten you're not going to get anything so
that is the journey that's what happens
for people in relation to credit bureaus
thanks Dean so what have we learnt 18
months on look at leave you negative
let's talk about positive stuff in the
previous the previous presenter from Sri
Lanka cert spoke about you know offline
and online victimization what's
interesting as we see a blue in
Australia so a Microsoft telephone scan
might very quickly relate really into a
remote access to a personal computer so
I was at an online where's that physical
right so it's a blurring of that
environment we see a mix of about half
half compromises occurring offline
compromisers cheering online
we see almost exclusively that then
misuse occurring online so their shift
to the online environment in terms of
issues so we don't we don't do couple
physical versus online easily lady care
and and when we started ID care we
certainly didn't define identity theft
her identity crime we let the consumers
define it for us what you see there is
the summary of what our data tells us 18
months on 19 hours is the average time
it takes someone to effectively respond
as much as they can through all of those
scenarios i just presented to you
unsurprisingly what's interesting which
I think parallels the sri lankan
experience is the dominance women I
don't think it reflects who is actually
a victim here I think it just reflects
the gender that's more likely to I'd say
my wife would say mature enough to reach
out but those that are reaching out
unsurprisingly 25 to 44 year olds is the
segment of the market that's most
prevalent and that tends to reflect
those that are transactional more so as
I surprise there this is a kicker
eighty-seven percent self detect so of
all the money going into organizations
in terms of detection the vast majority
of people calling us are the ones who
are detecting at first and they're often
detecting it through the misuse activity
such as a bill in the mail or some other
type of indicator that their identities
being misused as opposed to the
compromise as mentioned the eight
percent referral to mental health
treatment three and a half percent or
just shy reporting to law enforcement so
there's a massive gap in the
intelligence around law enforcement as
to what's going on here or other
although I think that might be changing
with a corn at least the information
around that and 27,000 or just over was
the average value of misuse experience
but there was a huge range so the medium
was around 12,000 for that one we had
only three percent unsurprisingly
feeling very dissatisfied with their
experience with organizations
so this is probably knew the most of you
that don't see then that consequential
impact of the industry that you work in
and love so much in terms of security
that this is the human impact we do have
a partnership model so those are
interested in tempting fate and
partnering with ID care as an
organization then and we'd love to have
a discussion with you as I mentioned
before we don't exist without funding of
our partners and what we can provide you
is a bit of a sense of where your
organization sits in terms of how it
responds to its customers but also
there's a bunch of other activities you
might be interested in engaging with us
on such as some of our awareness raising
programs we also have a process of
accreditation where we are looking at
your processes and we do test you out in
terms of the customer experience Chrissy
if you got to be the dinner tomorrow
night Chrissy will be there with soo Lee
they're two of our most experienced
counselors and I'd love to hear from you
and they'll be more than willing to
share their experiences on the phone
with people like Joanne and others do
take the opportunity to pick their
brains you don't have to pay consulting
fee for it it's a free hit and their
their national treasures in my mind
chris is the one who's been leading our
cyber education in relation to aged care
and students so we have a program in
Queensland in the Northern Territory
that we're trying at the moment we were
connecting years 10 11 and 12 students
we're coaching them around identity in
cyber security and then we're teaming up
with aged care providers and we're
actually letting the students educate
the aged care residents on this topic to
try and get some intergenerational
socialization happening on this
important topic and soo Lee's the other
person will be here tomorrow night and
she's heavily involved in the respect my
ID program which is targeted at school
kids that Queensland Police have been a
good promoter oven participant which has
been most welcome happy to take any
questions that you might have do I do
this electronically can we do it the
old-fashioned way
yes yes yes yes yes so typically what
will happen is that people will check
the three credit reports after speaking
with us they'll request their credit
report and one of the only ways unless
you get a bill in the mail or some
strange things are happening with your
email you'll start to see inquiries
being made so if you're with Vodafone
you might see an inquiry from Telstra
won't sign your credit report identity
theft it'll say inquiry Telstra this
date and you'll think of yourself well
I've never engaged with Telstra and
that's an indicator that your identities
being misused now that the issue there
is if on your credit report you see
instances of identity theft the credit
bureaus aren't the one to correct it it
has to be the credit provider so then
you have to go to each of the individual
ones to get them to investigate to then
correct a credit record yeah yeah the
most important thing the police can do
in this crime type is obtained
confidence that it's a legitimate report
and provide a report number if police
were to investigate all identity crime
they would do nothing else except
investigate identity crime so that's not
the solution it's we can't arrest our
way out of this that they play a very
important role and the role that they
play that so important is a legitimacy
exercise to say this is a bona fide a
victim and the ecosystem needs to pay
attention
why call up and they gave me a number
you'd be able to extend your credit band
if you need to you'll be able to get a
police you'll be able to get a new
license number if it's been misused you
can't get it without a police report
number yep it's the only one the address
points to where they get the utilities
bill to get there so it's my city could
be theft in the making but one of the
things that really worries me is that
they tell me that my driver's license is
the property of the queen's own
government so do you think it would be
viable for the Queensland Government to
start to say to these people who are
scaling Queensland official documents
that they have to for example RPC idea
says they have to have a stand for if
they want to keep those licenses
certain period of time because once the
criminals work out that these licenses
are sitting on servers in the surf club
down the road and everywhere else and
there's millions of them being scanned
every day I just listed the queensland
government can and all governments can
take away and say that is our
application the hotel yes I I have a
copy right here so this is a this is a
fantastic topic under the privacy laws
in Australia we have a legal right to
say no but the reality is we don't have
a practical right and I would argue as
those friends in common would and I've
heard them before say why would you put
your organization and risks like that by
scanning those documents it is a pretty
legitimate question and I pose that in
the media last year and got a hotel
association representatives say that
they've got the best security and
they're all fine so so we can just relax
I think it's a great point if Queens
ain't government said it's our
credential then I've got about 50
million dollars worth of loss that I can
shift to them from the people that are
called ID care if they're happy to
accept that i think it's a it's a debate
that's a debate for most that issue
documents of one of convenience and it's
convenient in one hand to say you own it
and when it's not it's convenient to
just wipe your hands of it i like that
as a thought i like the idea of maybe
taking identity to the place of
seriousness that it actually needs to be
the reason why it probably hasn't got
there yet is because not many people can
see that human impact that it's having
in the community now the financial
institutions that we work with every day
the big banks I've got processes that
are generally good
and you'll see that no scoring that
already showed you before they do it
because they're motivated financially to
get it good okay but but i think you
know we can't say for example credit
card frauds ok because it's point zero
zero two percent of a transaction when
the reality is we inconvenience 1.1
million people a year waiting ten days
to get a new card that's the human
impact and it's about getting that human
impact message out there but good for
gram yes yes yes oh most organizations
when you if you see a telco has decided
to set up an account in your name it
comes through as a bill you might happen
to stumble it across it on your credit
report unfortunately most organizations
aren't savvy enough to tell people what
of theirs was used to set up the account
although that's something we do stress
with our clients to go back to these
organizations to get and it's at that
point that one realizes that it is the
license you could you have to look or
reengineer what the application process
is to see how your license might have
been misused there's seventeen percent
that have no idea I've got an assumption
but they have no real confidence of
where the compromise was are we get good
success because we we refer them to the
Privacy Commissioner who we have on
speed dial to just make sure they
understand what the rights are of the
consumer you know you organizations
don't want things to go down Financial
Ombudsman path or our telecommunications
industry Ombudsman path because they
then starts costing them more money than
just telling them or was their license
yeah but that takes us to do that and
and we are seeing the tip of the iceberg
yeah
don't feel disappointed or depressed we
can do something about this thanks
everyone