but now I'll ask you along to Fraser
tweedell from Red Hat giving his
presentation on network bound encryption
with tang and clevis if you want to read
um phrases bow you can again use the app
to do so give him a warm welcome
so good afternoon I know this is the
last session and probably half of you
either have full brains and the other
half just want to go get beer so you
know thank you for coming to my session
yeah I am a software developer at Red
Hat so I'm definitely not on sort of the
business and risk side of things that is
quite prominent here at this conference
so I do feel almost like a fish out of
water but it's good to be here and get
these other perspectives on security
technology I'm going to talk to you
about network bound encryption and and
some interesting tools we're building
around that at Red Hat so let's start
with a story and the story is the story
of a hard disk this hard disk lives in a
employees workstation or laptop computer
or maybe in a data center and this disk
has full disk encryption so it has
volume encryption keys on it and when
the machine boots up a passphrase needs
to needs to be supplied in order to
decrypt the volume and continue with the
boot and so we have a we've got a bit of
a management problem here because every
time the user boots up their computer
they need to go and key in this
passphrase this is obviously a step that
must be performed every time depending
on how often they boot their computer
hopefully not too often but depending on
the operating system you might need to
reboot it more or less frequently to
apply critical system updates in a data
center again you're not going to be
rebooting your systems particularly
frequently but they might need to come
up again because you've had critical
system updates to apply or the kernels
panicked or whatever so you need to get
a decryption passphrase
to this system so you know datacenter
this can be over a lights-out management
system or as a last resort someone
physically at a terminal key in a
passphrase for your user it's something
they have to do every time you boot the
system the advantages of full disk
encryption of course is that if the
machine you know needs to be sent off
for warranty service or is
decommissioned you don't need to worry
about the security of that data but most
of the time the machine is the disk is
going to be used in a secure context the
employee is at the office or the disk is
in its usual rack in the data center so
it would be nice if there were ways to
automate the unlocking of disks so
another common use case for decryption
of Secrets is TLS private keys and other
secrets used in your network
applications and once again these need
to be supplied not a server boot up time
but the boot up of your server software
so you know there's a basic example you
bring up the Apache web server and it
prompts you please enter the passphrase
for your private keys so again there's a
management overhead here and ideally
we'd like to automate that away but also
have our secrets encrypted at rest it's
quite common to see advice on the
internet you know it's don't have to
look far on Stack Overflow to find
someone asking the question are you know
every time I start the server it's it's
prompting me to enter my password and
you know if my machine gets rebooted or
something I don't I just wanted to come
back up and usually the advice is
something like well just run this open
SSL command and the result is that the
keys are just sitting there on the disk
in the clear which is poor security
hygiene and then how old friend USB so
USB drives containing potentially
sensitive corporate information being
taken home by employees is an issue and
it's something that many organized
have to be concerned about whether the
exfiltration is malicious or nearly
merely negligent and of course the flip
side of of the USB scenario is people
bringing in USB sticks from outside the
organization containing unauthorized
software malware you know they've picked
it up off the footpath outside the
building and thought oh this this looks
interesting let's take it into the
building and plug it in and see what's
on it and then you're hosed so it would
be nice if there were ways to encrypt
the data on the USB disks in a way where
they can be used securely within an
organization transporting data around
you know something that many people are
quite used to doing I've got to get this
big file from my system over to Bob
because Bob needs it just plug in the
USB stick and you know throw it at Bob
so we want to still enable these use
cases but ensure that the USB volumes
are useless when taken outside the
organization and also to prevent
unauthorized volumes being used within
your within your organization so these
are some use cases that we're looking at
developing solutions for in Red Hat and
right now I'm going to jump into a demo
of the software that we've been
developing I've worked a little bit on
it but I'm not the main developer and
this software what you're going to see
in this demo specifically addresses the
full disk encryption use case ok so on
the Left we have a it's a virtual
machine but it's it's got an encrypted
disk
so I've booted it up and it's currently
prompting me for the passphrase to
unlock the volume keys and continue the
boot so I'm just going to enter the
passphrase
over on the right this is a server it's
on the same network as the client on the
left and I'm going to set up some
software on this system so it's a server
the software is called Tang so the
software is installed if we
just have a look at the RPMs is this big
enough for everyone by the way can
anyone not read this okay
so the package is called tanki d it
contains a number of binaries one of
which is Tang ki gen which we'll use to
generate a couple of keys we need to
specify an elliptic curve group there's
a few supporting groups and don't worry
too much about these details we're going
to advertise the key and it's going to
be a signing key okay hmm
demo gremlins okay
I just done a little way directory oh
yeah okay so we've generated a signing
key we also need to generate what's
called the recovery key and then we can
start the server so we'll say a system
control start tang key demon dot socket
so we can see the socket for the
server's listening it's a socket
activated process so the service itself
is not actually running over on the
client we can see that the boot is
completed so I'm now going to login to
the system
it's fire up a terminal okay and over on
this system if we have a look at the lux
header so Lux is the Linux unified key
set up disk encryption system for for
Linux so if we do a pseudo crypt setup
Lux dump and the name of the disk and
we'll just grab slot whoops that should
be Deb so we can see that there are
eight slots in the locks header only one
of them is in use and this is where the
encrypted pass phrases that so all the
yeah the metadata that can be unlocked
when I type the passphrase containing
the volume keys so what we will now do
is we'll run the Tang Lux bind command I
need to do this as route again will
specify the device and the host name of
the Tang server which is F 2033 don't IP
a dot local
hmm
always with the demo gremlin say 10
bucks point hmm
spare with me while I should try and
work out in approximately 10 seconds
what's happening here
always with the gremlins hmm well this
is a problem
is the server running oh the service
failed to start that's a problem golly
gosh okay
well always the demo gremlin say suffice
to say I'll talk you through what what
will have happened should the binding
program have run successfully and should
the server have started successfully of
course in the first instance we would
have been prompted with the question so
it'll print out a key fingerprint of the
service signing key and it will ask be
wish to trust this key so it's a trust
on first use scheme or tofu if if you're
familiar with that abbreviation having
trusted the key it will perform some
computations using the clients private
key and the service public key and then
use the result of that to in cipher the
secret then and store that data in the
lux header then I would have rebooted
this system and presuming the tain
server on the right-hand side was still
running the boot prompt to enter the
passphrase will have come up but whilst
waiting for me to enter the passphrase
in the background in the boot
environment the client will be
communicating with the server and
executing the Tang protocol and should
that execute successfully it will reveal
the key encryption key and then the boot
will complete without operator
intervention so the idea here is simply
that we want the systems to come up when
they're in a secure network where the
Tang server is available over the
network in that environment the client
will will come up automatically and I
really do apologize that this demo is
not working honestly it's it was all
going fine you know this morning and
yesterday and I I regret that it's not
working but if you would like to see the
demo working coming
I am around for the rest of the
conference and I promise to to get it
going again
okay so that is the unsuccessful demo
concluded so let's review what we would
have seen had the demo worked
successfully we would have seen simple
provisioning of encryption for secrets
at rest in this particular example for a
disk encryption key automated decryption
when the tank server is available when
the tank server is not available we just
fall back to the existing method so a
user inputting a passphrase the
terminology we use here is that the
secret is bound to the network because
the automated decryption capability is
only available when it can communicate
with the taint server the final point
the server never leaving the client is
not something that is apparent from the
demo but in this protocol the secret is
only ever learned or known by the client
the server gets no information about it
whatsoever
so in this sense it's quite distinct
from key escrow has a very good privacy
guarantees around it the security
assumptions here of course the taint
server is only accessible from the
secure network if it's globally
accessible then you lose the ability to
prevent the disk from being unlocked if
it's been taken out of the premises or
you know you've decommissioned it
someone gets a hold of it if they can
access the tank server then of course
they can decrypt the disk so this is a
security assumption with this software
and of course that the secrets and the
keys are safe in the clients memory but
if your client is compromised in that
way you of course have big problems and
Tang won't save you
so Tang Tang is a protocol based on
diffie-hellman exchange and if I have a
show of hands in the room as anyone
familiar or was once familiar in a
university with diffie-hellman exchange
and how it works ok so diffie-hellman
exchange is a key agreement protocol
where two parties with their public and
private keys public keys can be
public/private are kept to oneself the
two parties can agree on a shared secret
for the establishment of a secure
communications channel but an
eavesdropper Eve cannot learn the shared
secret there's an encryption school
there are a few encryption schemes based
on difficult and one is the integrated
encryption scheme where this shared
secret is used as the input to a key
derivation function to derive a
symmetric key of a particular desired
length and that symmetric key is used to
in cipher a message so on the one side
Alice
given Bob's public key can encrypt the
message to Bob and transmit the message
and then Bob is able to compute the same
shared secret and derive the same
symmetric key using the information he
receives from Alice and decrypt the
cipher text but again an eavesdropper is
unable to obtain enough information to
decrypt the message so the new
cryptography used in tain is the
McCallum Rayleigh exchange so this is
due to Nathanael McCallum and Robert
Rowe you who are both employees of Red
Hat and that URL there is the original
posting to the cryptography mailing list
so the algorithm is public and in a
couple of slides I'm going to take you
through it
the intuition of McAllen Rally exchange
here is that Alice encrypts a message to
Bob's public key but does not send it to
Bob in order to decrypt the message
Alice has to ask Bob to encrypt an
ephemeral key with Bob's private key and
then the response from Bob can be used
to recompute the the original secret
read arrive the same symmetric key and
decrypt the message so it's about Alice
encrypting a secret that only Alice
knows and Alice in the future can
decrypt that but Alice requires the
assistance of Bob to do so
Bob cannot learn anything about the
secret and also neither can an
eavesdropper so caution math ahead it's
only a couple of slides I promise if
this causes you pain it won't last long
so the parameters for McAllen Rally
exchange much the same as for
diffie-hellman we need a cyclic group of
order n with a hard problem such as the
discrete log problem or the analog to
discrete log which is a elliptic curve
point factorization in elliptic curve
groups there's a generator which is just
an element of the group and is public a
key derivation function a symmetric
encryption algorithm and by the way for
these two in our implementation we use
pbkdf2 and AES GCM which is the Galois
counter mode but again you can choose
any secure KDF and symmetric cipher and
the message m to be encrypted which will
be a key encryption key
TLS private key these sorts of things so
the secrets you actually want protected
at rest so in the encryption phase Alice
generates a private key which is an
element of the group Bob also generates
a private key Alice can generate a
private key separately for every secret
that needs to be encrypted the service
private key is persistent so it doesn't
change over time in order to encrypt the
secret all the client needs to know is
the server's public key this can be
obtained in a in what we call an
advertisement request so the client asks
the server
what are your public keys or it could be
distributed you know in some sort of you
know base image or corporate stand and
build image or whatnot so it doesn't
necessarily involve network
communications for the provisioning base
so given the server's public key B Alice
computes this secret G to the AV the
group generator ^ a times B to private
keys and then that is the input to the
key durable
function and then that is used to key
the symmetric cipher and encrypt the
message
Alice stores Bob's public key her own
private her own public key and the
ciphertext and crucially discards her
private key and the symmetric key so
this ensures that in the future without
the help of the server there's nothing
that can happen on the client in order
to decrypt that secret so for the
decryption phase or the acquisition
phase the client generates a new private
key X again just an element of the group
and then calculates this value X which
is a public key multiplied by the public
key corresponding to the ephemeral key X
transmits that to the server in what we
call a recovery request the server in
ciphers that with be the server's public
key which you'll recall this assistant
so the server remembers its public key
and private key and then this value X
prime is returned to the client and then
X prime is used in this computation to
recover the original secret G to the a B
and running math through the key
derivation function once again we get
the same K as was used to in cipher the
message and then this can be used to
decrypt the decrypt the original message
which is the secret you want protected
at rest okay so that's how that's the
cryptography that's in use in this
protocol okay so the implementation it's
a server-side daemon so that's the
detain key D that we saw in the demo
that didn't come up because reasons I
need to investigate and there's a clever
spin we'll get to what that is in a few
slides it's written in C has minimal
dependencies the only dependency is open
SSL which we use for the asn.1 which is
what the wire protocol uses and for the
elliptic curve cryptography
Rafi so we don't use any TLS or anything
like that and it's small so the
implementation is quite small and it's
very fast the protocol as I mentioned
uses asn.1 objects serialized using the
distinguishing coding rules the packets
are UDP there's no encryption in the
channel because you don't need it and in
its current in incantation it's trust on
first use you will you would have seen
how the demo worked in the demo the
prompts do you wish to trust these keys
however it's entirely possible to
implement key pinning so you could for
example distribute the valid key
fingerprints in your corporate standard
builds you know or other offline
provisioning methods or you could store
them in DNS using DNS second and have
records that are the fingerprints of the
official taint servers in your
organization for example so you can in
this way potentially avoid having to
prompt the user and say you know do you
please check this fingerprint is it
correct yes or no why is it important to
do the fingerprint checking is because
if you get man in the middle during the
provisioning phase or someone
masquerades as the tang server then it
could cause the client to encrypt to
bogus or a non-existent recovery key
which essentially means that that secret
will be lost for all time and the client
if you know if it's full disk encryption
is just ddosed itself forever unless you
remember the passphrase a running Tang
server is also a live d OS target and
importantly the security of the protocol
depends on not being able to guess the
ephemeral key X so if you are using tang
for full disk encryption you want to
make sure you have enough entropy when
you go about initiating the Tang
recovery stage of the protocol because
if you can guess X then the security
breaks down also this is all the
algorithms that we're using the the
public key algorithms are vulnerable to
Shor's algorithm so you know if we see
practical quantum computing in the next
10 or 20 years then you know this
protocol will be broken in polynomial
time so hopefully we can find quantum
computing resistant algorithms to use
instead by then so a mission
accomplished right we've we've succeeded
in having our automated unlocking of of
secrets when on a secure Network so when
they have access to the to the Tang
server but you know we're not we're not
really there yet because one Tang server
is not really gonna be very resilient
it's it at the end of the day one one
piece of a larger puzzle and if we're
going to bind secrets to detain servers
on a network what other kinds of things
might we want to bind secrets to so the
first one obviously which is not on the
list is users pass phrases that they
remember so you use a key stretching
function based on or applied to user
input to to get some sort of secure
secret assuming the user has a good
passphrase which of course is as we know
from many talks today and generally
usually not a valid assumption we also
might like to bind to trusted platform
module chip so you see all secrets in
the TPM so that the so that you've disk
is bound to some physical machine or
some machine State we might want to bind
to smart cards with crypto processors in
them so a user has to plug in their
smart card in order to get access to a
secret and then potentially we can
derive secrets from biometric data you
might want to have some master unlock
key for a user that gets escrowed in
your organisation so when they first
come on board and their equipment gets
provisioned we have a master unlock key
that gets escrowed and then if that
person gets hit by a bus or leaves
leaves the organisation and you're left
with a disk and you say well how do we
get back into it
you
potentially use a master key kept by
your organization and so and so we get
to the point where you know we make the
observation that security it's not a
binary thing it's not like you're secure
or you're not secure but it's a sliding
scale of risk risk but convenience on
one end and security but less
convenience or outright inconvenience on
the other end and you know where where
to position yourself on that spectrum
that's going to be different in all
kinds of different organizations or some
sub organizations and the policies for
Disco mocking or secret unlocking should
be driven by business requirements and
not by the technical capabilities or
limitations of the technology as as a
completely made-up example of an
unlocked policy that you might want for
a user's workstation you could say okay
well I want either their past their
passphrase or a Tang server on the
network if they're you know physically
at an office or their smart card or some
a secret derived from some biometric
data like a fingerprint so you say any
two of these is good enough so that's
stage one and then at the next stage you
say well and we want to make sure that
the disk is plugged into the computer
that we gave them to the physical
machine that we gave them so we're gonna
bind to the TPM and in this case we want
the result from stage one to be true yes
it's good we'll let them in but then
also the TPM so we need both of these
threshold of two out of two
possibilities and then finally at the
lowest level we say okay well we want
either a yes from stage two or some
master passphrase that that we escrowed
when they came on board and we'll pull
out as a last resort if we need to so
we've got sort of this nested nested
unlock policy where we have thresholds
involved and this you know it's a it's a
contrived example but you can see how
you might want to implement a policy
like this in your
organization so we want to make that
possible for people to do so there's an
algorithm called Shamir's secret sharing
which is basically a secret splitting
algorithm where you can distribute any
as many shares in the secret as you like
and require a threshold of K of n
secrets to come back to you in order to
be able to get at the secret the
intuition of Shamir's secret sharing
again comes from math and the
observation that K points describe a
polynomial of degree K minus 1 so to
describe a linear function you need two
points three points describes a
quadratic and so on so in Shamir's
secret showing you randomly pick
coefficients in your polynomial of
degree K minus one where you want K to
be the threshold you distribute points
to on this line to people who are to
hold shares in the secret crucially you
do not distribute the value of the
function at zero because the free
coefficient is set to the value of the
secret and then given K points you can
compute the Lagrange polynomial to
recover the secret so as an example this
is a cubic function degree three so four
shares are required to recompute the
secret the secret is minus three here on
this black line so the value of the
black line add zero and there are four
points distributed here these are the
colored circles on the other lines the
four colored lines are what's called the
lagrange basis polynomials and basically
you compute the four basis polynomials
given the four shares in the secret and
that allows you to interpolate the
original polynomial and then you just
get its value add zero practically in
practical implementations this is all
done in modular arithmetic but this is
the intuition behind it and so I also
have a demo of Shamir's secret sharing
and hopefully this one does work so I
have a
tanks over running on this host and this
is the clevis tool so this is what
clevis comes into it so I do clevis
provision I'm going to provision a
secret - Oh for the output file over
stop JSON and - P for a pin
specification and we're gonna specify a
password pin and it's going to ask me
for a passphrase and I'm gonna type that
in
it's then giving us the secret so clevis
is actually generated the secret itself
and told us what it is the secret is now
encrypted but we go and we use this
secret to encrypt a TLS private key or a
disk encryption key for the acquisition
we simply provide this same metadata
file the metadata or the clevis
configuration I'll just show you that so
if I pretty print there clevis JSON you
can see it's got information about which
KD FS and ciphers are used the type of
the pin that was used and the cipher
text containing the secret so if I do an
acquire handing it back that same
configuration it's going to prompt me
for the passphrase again and if I
fat-finger that it's gonna not give me
the passphrase and if I type the right
thing it's gonna give me the same secret
that was originally spat out and so the
secret that was provisioned is the
secret that it yields so this is a very
simple clevis policy but let's do
something a bit more sophisticated if I
use the Shamir's secret sharing type
that allows me to specify an additional
layer of nesting so additional pins as
an array of nested clevis pin
specifications so here I'll have a
another pass phrase pin
and then I will also have a tame pin and
I need to give it a host name and I'll
just talk to the tanks over running on
this host and finally finally I need to
tell it what the threshold is I want a
threshold of one and I am missing his
square bracket yeah okay
so it's going to do two provisioning now
one is the password provisioning that we
saw a moment ago and the next one is the
tank provisioning here is the the trust
on first used here's the fingerprint do
you want to trust it I say yes and it's
provisioned the secret now if I kill the
tame server and run clevis acquire
giving it the clevis JSON it's prompting
me for a password and it's also trying
to talk to the tain server but the tain
server is not running so I need to put
in the passphrase and it's going to give
me the secret if I fire up the tame
server once again and attempt the
acquisition it's going to prompt me for
the passphrase but also in the
background it's talking to the tame
server and it's completed the Tang
recovery and unlocked the secret because
the threshold that we specified was one
so this is the sort of thing that you
would have seen in the full disk
encryption example if it was working so
reviewing what we just saw there clevis
is client-side pluggable key management
based on Shamir's secret sharing plugins
are called pins we have 10 and password
plugins and the sky's the limit in terms
of what you could write JSON
configuration name is written in C with
minimal dependencies the history of
these projects basically early last year
we started the diode project it was
using x.509 for authentication and also
the encryption certificates were x.509
and in this protocol the client sent a
blob to the server the server decrypted
at thus learning the secret and sent
that back so this didn't have the
privacy characteristics that we wanted
in around September
Nathaniel McCallum hadn't had an insight
and thought maybe we can use something
based on diffie-hellman he worked with
Bob Rowley and the outcome of that was
the McAllen Rally algorithm that I
showed a slightly earlier in the
presentation and then in December we
realized that we were actually trying to
solve two different problems here so we
split the project in detain and clevis
the Luxe integration is currently only
supporting teams so we don't have
support for arbitrary clevis policies
for Lux integration yet we're working
with the Lux developers and we're hoping
that Lux version 2 which is going to be
designed to be more extensible will have
support for richer clevis policies but
that's only in the very early stages at
this time integrating with USB guard so
this is designed to satisfy the use
cases that come from that story at the
beginning of the talk with the USB
sticks so using them securely in the
organization but taking them out of the
network means that you can't access
what's on the volume and also locking
down the systems with policies that say
only time provisioned USB storage
volumes will be allowed to be mounted on
our systems so yes the USB guard
integration which is in the early stages
at the moment as well for the Tang
server and product
itself we're currently looking at the
key rotation possibilities so the fact
that we have the sign-in keys is what's
going to make that possible so you can
generate new signing keys and new
recovery keys change which ones are
advertised and over time migrate away
from all the keys to newer keys and also
looking at what people who are going to
hopefully install and run this in the
organization expect of the daemon and
the clients in terms of logging so what
do they actually want to know for audit
purposes if I had time right now I'd be
working on a TPM clever spin and let's
encrypt integration is I think let's
encrypt is an excellent initiative but
currently just splats all of the keys
onto the file system in the clear which
I definitely don't like I've played
around with Apache integration for
clevis and I have a blog post on that
it's fairly ad-hoc but I you know it
does it does work availability so
currently we have some unofficial
package repos with Batang software we
don't have any packages for clevis the
source code for both projects is GPL v3
up and it's available on github we're
hoping to get the tan bits into Fedora
24 you can help by doing a review of the
crypto if you're a cryptographer
protocol review and code review if this
stuff interests you please try it out
and talk to us about your use cases so
if you think we might have an
application for this but maybe we
haven't considered it or I didn't talk
about it today please let's have that
conversation and contributing clever
spins so if there are interesting
sources of Secrets that you think would
be worthwhile supporting in clevis then
the the pen interface is fairly
straightforward if you know see you can
write one so that's the end of my talk
but one final point on the terminology
that the terms come from a kind of
shackle called a clevis shackle so the
clevis is the shackle and this is the
Tang and pins are the bits that hold it
all together so that's where the
project's mo nology comes from so
questions hopefully we have time for one
or two
yeah but ever got a couple questions
firstly how would you deal with client
hardware failure right that's an
excellent question we don't have
anything in particular to deal with that
I mean if the disk crashes and crash is
hard you're going to lose that data no
matter what so yep yeah for sure then
you can mount it into it into a separate
motherboard and do it but then you know
in the future if we have TPM support in
there and you're physically bound to the
TPM well that's going to be a bit harder
so of course having having an
appropriate backup regime is important
as well one more question is 2016 the
year of a limit from the desktop cuz are
they Daren should probably know better
because he knows that 2010 2011 2012
2013 14 15 well I'm gonna go I'm gonna
go ahead and answer that question in the
affirmative
because I plugged into this projector
and things worked so yeah I think I
think it's arrived ok thanks for
listening to my talk
you