Darrin kitchen is the founder of hack 5
and in a television show inspiring
hackers and IT pros since 2005 breaking
out of the 1990s phone freak scene
donors continue to foster his passion
for information security throughout his
career as a systems administrator
presenter and creator of best selling
penetration testing tools so later on
again there's another first for me the
first time I've ever introduced someone
using the phrase 1990s phone freak scene
give it up for darren kitchen ladies
yeoman
oh man it is a absolute pleasure to be
here guys let me tell you this is gonna
be a lot of fun we are going to talk
about the curse of convenience and I'm
gonna ask the question would you believe
me if I told you that your grandmother
might be responsible for the propagation
of the world's first cyber weapon and
that she may in fact uh sure in a new
era of privacy and security this is a
talk about lies it's a talk about trust
it's a talk about convenience and your
grandmother as well as duckies turtles
and pineapples and this is something
that I've been noodling on for some time
been asking myself the question that in
a culture of convenience can we strike a
balance for between the need for
security and the need for simplicity so
just a show of hands who here is
familiar with hak5 all fantastic ok so
that's where I come from I'm the founder
of hack 5 it's a show on discovery
digital and since 2005 we've been
inspiring hackers and IT pros before
hack 5 I did my due diligence as a
systems administrator I did the IT thing
yes I was a 1990s phone freak I don't
know if that was a thing here in
Australia did you guys use blue boxes
and red boxes to get free long distance
ok well in this scene it was all about
building these boxes these tools of
convenience these devices that would
violate the trust built into the
telephone system so that you could call
Venezuela for free and for the last
decade I've had the absolute honor to be
able to continue that spirit in both
hacker media doing my podcast hack 5 as
well as to continue to build these boxes
these physical manifestations of these
hacks these simple info sack tools that
violate these implicit trusts with
usually very simple lies and I've
learned over time that these
conveniences
err an absolute curse but they may in
fact be our salvation everybody here has
done tech support for their parents or
grandparents right just making sure I'm
in the right room so I have a few
stories to tell you and we're going to
start with Stuxnet Stuxnet was the
world's first known cyber weapon unlike
heartbleed or a poodle or shell-shocked
it didn't have a really cool logo but
what it did have was the ability to take
down Iran's nuclear program it's a very
targeted worm so just so we have some
background nuclear power nuclear weapons
kind of difficult to make
they require something pretty unique
they require enriched uranium and
uranium is composed primarily of this
u-238 stuff which isn't fissile that
means there's not gonna be any nuclear
fission less than 1 percent of it is
u-235 that's the stuff that goes boom
that's the stuff that it'll do that
that nuclear fission chain reaction so
if you want to do something useful with
uranium
you have to enrich it if you're trying
to make some nuclear power with it
somewhere around 4% will do if you're
trying to make somebody have a very bad
day the weapons-grade stuff takes about
90% and so to create this stuff the most
common way is to use a centrifuge it's
it's a device that will help separate
that 235 from the 238 it's big cylinder
spins the stuff centripetal force will
push the heavier 238 to the outside 235
stays on the inside Bob's your uncle and
to control this specialized piece of
equipment you need some special hardware
you need a PLC this is a programmable
logic computer it's just a very
specialized piece of industrial
automation equipment to find similar
stuff in automotive factories and in the
case of Stuxnet
this particular unit is from siemens
running step7 software and this was what
was specifically targeted by Stuxnet and
it did a fairly good job at making a bad
day for the Iran nuclear program it
ended up doing some damage to some 20%
of these centrifuges so here's the thing
nobody has really taken responsibility
for Stuxnet I mean there have been many
coy acknowledgments from senior US
officials specifically Hillary Clinton
but when all of this came to light in
2010 in 2011 there's never been somebody
being like I'm behind Stuxnet now it's
2016 it's it's pretty obvious that this
was actually a joint Israeli and US
effort but I know in my heart that there
was another party that was involved in
this that has been more influential in
information security than any nation
state actor that's grandma this is
grandma she is awesome she bakes cookies
she has a book club she yells at the TV
she plays bridge and she is about to get
on the World Wide Web we're gonna come
back to Stuxnet but real quick let's go
back to 1997
because grandma just got her first home
PC she got herself an IBM PC 330 that
thing is sweet it's got a pentium MMX
processor in it
he's got CD ROMs she's gonna be checking
out encyclopedia on cd-rom it's gonna be
scanning and photos she's gonna email
her book club on the information
superhighway whose fantastic stuff
everything was going perfect until of
course it came to the printer this is
where things go awry because grandma had
gotten everything set up and
everything's going swimmingly until of
course she's plugging in the printer
getting the power go and plugging in
that opt cable everything seems kind of
obvious he can't
log a parallel port into a serial port
just doesn't work until of course it
gets to setting up the drivers she goes
to put the little plastic thing in the
cup holder and she's looking at the disk
and it says click start click run type D
colon backslash setup.exe where D is the
letter of your cd-rom what how are we
going to print the newsletters for the
grandchildren now everything is ruined
call NORAD we have a problem the
honeymoon is over we are about to lose
grandma actually what's about to happen
is she's about to call her grandson for
some tech support we've all been there
on the phone for an half an hour walking
through a driver installation just
praying and wishing oh dear God if only
I had a remote desktop session you know
you've been there but that didn't happen
in this case it was actually kind of
brilliant Microsoft did us a solid this
was the late 90s computers were going
mainstream everything was becoming user
friendly everything was becoming
plug-and-play
so when trick grandma popped the CD and
the drive on a computer read it well she
got a nice little wizard it's really
just a matter of clicking next next
finish well that's fantastic
how did that happen well it's Windows 95
everything needs to be made poor
convenience trying to make these
consumer devices now so what will happen
is the operating system is going to
check the cd-rom and see if on the route
of the drive there's a little file
called autorun.inf sort of similar to
your autoexec.bat on a floppy and so the
operating system is just going to trust
the cd-rom and it's just going to
execute whatever is in this file and
this behavior would continue on through
Windows XP I know I learned to take
advantage of this inherent trust
that's a USB Drive but not just any
that's a fancy one that's one from
SanDisk
called the cruiser I like to call it the
switchblade it sounds cool it sounds
lethal it's got that sliding action and
the way that this drive worked similar
to many other USB drives is that as soon
as you plug it into the computer it's
gonna do this fancy little handshake
it's gonna say to the computer hello
computer I'm a mass storage device it
hands over this descriptor as it were
and it says I'd like to be your friend
and of course this new wonderful USB
specification in the late 90s we have
these descriptors and the computer says
fantastic mass storage I know how to
work with you let's do this and so drive
letter pops up everything is happy
well this sand disk did something extra
special in addition to saying well good
afternoon computer I am a mass storage
drive and I would like to be your friend
it also would say I am also a USB cd-rom
drive and the computer of course is like
ooh a cd-rom drive oh you don't happen
to have one of those autorun to INF
files do you you can see where this is
going
SanDisk saw this as an opportunity to
make this drive automatically pop up
whatever applications they want they
sold this with portable apps they took
advantage of that trust and they used it
to make a very convenient product they
bundled it with Skype they bundled it
with opera they had this cool little
launcher you know to add insult to
injury they put Avast Antivirus on here
so I kind of find hilarious and so what
we did was we said huh
well that's really convenient what if we
removed those portable apps what if we
replace them with our own penetration
testing tools
so rather than Skype end and opera we
have payloads that steal
password hashes off of the computer or
install back doors or exfiltrated off
the documents folder I like to call that
an involuntary backup it's important
that you backup your files if you take
nothing else from this talk backup your
files if you don't a hacker may for you
and this was fantastic
Microsoft eventually got wise to this
issue there was a pretty cool white
paper about it and such and it's not
present in Vista and above you have this
little dialogue you have to go through
some clicks so this was actually only a
viable attack vector for I don't know a
little over a decade which brings me to
tell you a story about Grandma's
grandson and a rubber ducky
you see I paid my dues I worked in IT in
the early 2000s I was a systems
administrator and like many systems
administrator I had one goal and that
was automate my job so I can play
counter-strike and I got pretty good at
that mainly because I found myself doing
very similar tasks over and over the
support requests for things like I lost
connection to the intranet or I can't
get on the share Drive or what's up with
the printer down the hallway and so I
found that the quickest solution to many
of these problems was always to just
open up a terminal and you know bang out
a few commands in the prompt well I was
using the USB switchblade for that
automation to just fix computers because
I could just plug in a drive and be like
there we go we're done but of course
that was no longer a viable option so
with the switchblade not really a good
attack vector anymore I thought to
myself well if all I really need to do
is just lean over and type into
someone's keyboard for a while what if I
could automate me what if I could become
a robot
all I need to do is grab a keyboard and
type a few commands well remember that
USB descriptor that little bit in the
enumeration of the handshake of that USB
device that says hello computer
I am mass storage I'm a cd-rom well it
turns out with the right microcontroller
it's pretty trivial to just say hi there
on the keyboard let's be best friends
which is pretty cool because computers
trust keyboards they do because they
trust humans the majority of our human
input to a computer is over keyboards
there's in fact a specification for
humans in USB it's called the head or
the human interface device and it is a
perfect example of that relationship
between man and machine
that trust and that convenience and that
ubiquity and I would expect this
relationship to continue until of course
Skynet with singularity but what if we
were to lie what if we were to tell the
computer our microcontroller was to say
hey I'm a keyboard and then start typing
keystrokes as if it were flesh and blood
it would then violate this inherent
trust between us and at that point all
bets are off so that's what happened I
developed the USB rubber ducky I
developed this to automate IT tasks like
fixing printers and what's beautiful
about this is as opposed to the USB
switchblade as opposed to taking
advantage of an inherent trust built
into one operating system having to do
with cd-rom drives we're taking
advantage of a much lower level trust
between machine and man so its OS
agnostic it doesn't care if you're a
Windows or a Mac or Linux or an Amiga as
long as the computer supports hid this
beautiful specification that was built
into USB to support
keyboards and mice and joysticks and
many other devices without the need for
any drivers so that you would just plug
it in and it would just work and it
would be user friendly it would be plug
and play it is amazing it is convenient
it is ubiquitous it is unauthenticated
and so you get to the point where well
if you can't trust your users who can
you trust there was a recent audit of
the company's policy against foreign USB
drives funny how that happens suddenly
switchblades and everything and nobody
wants USB drives under corporations and
so you guys know what happens when on a
Windows host you hit Windows you hold
down Windows key you hit R and in the
run line you pipe in backslash backslash
and IP address those two mount Samba
share like grabbing a network drive and
part of that initiation to that server
somewhere is to tell it
hi I'm this workstation logged in as
this user so this major bank drops all
of these USB rubber Ducky's and as you
can see it looks like a thumb drive it
smells like a thumb drive it's not a
thumb drive when you plug this into the
computer it enumerates as a keyboard and
starts typing at over 9,000 characters
per minute and so it's it's trivial it's
only a moment before it's pulled up just
the run line and hit that one-liner and
enter and then suddenly a very
well-crafted server somewhere is logging
the workstation the time and the user
that violated that policy this is
actually a screenshot from mr. robot
where they used this tool so that's kind
of cool another really fun one with this
is this 2k reverse shell this is really
cool you can plug it into a host and
just have it type whatever you want and
in this case what we're typing is a
base64 encoded reverse shell and what's
brilliant about this is it's
not downloading a payload from over the
internet it's not copying it from mass
storage which may be in violation of
some group policy
it's like typing the program into the
computer as if I were 13 again writing
basic into my IBM PC from the magazine
from the library and yet unlike 13 year
old me it was doing that at superhuman
speeds never having a typo never taking
a break never missed a semicolon which
is kind of awesome because then we get a
reverse shell in like 30 seconds on this
machine another really fun one again
because it's OS agnostic is we plug it
into say an Android phone and of course
the Android device any modern operating
system these days is like cool you must
be hid you must be a human yeah let's
start typing oh wait hang on though I
got a lock screen so we're not going
anywhere anytime soon
Oh unless of course you want to type in
the pin code in which Keys go for it so
a payload that will just type zero zero
zero zero through nine nine nine nine
becomes absolutely trivial until of
course you realize that Android thought
ahead I know every five attempts they
make you wait 30 seconds and so there's
the possibility that you could literally
watch this phone until it says excuse me
you've missed typed your password over
9000 times you're gonna have to wait
thirty seconds I know it's it doesn't
ever self-destruct it I can only imagine
that the FBI must love Android as
opposed to some other vendors I was once
on the phone with the with a sheriff's
office in the United States and I'm
walking him through setting up this
payload it's really fun because it
generates itself with bash and bunch of
sad and Hawk and grep and stuff and so
he's he's got it deployed in the rubber
ducky and he's got it plugged in to this
Android phone from the suspect and he's
asking me he's like alright so got the
payload there huh
got a plug into his phone huh it's
typing uh-huh what do I do now here's
the thing with those 30-second timeouts
to exhaust the entire key space it's
gonna take 16 hours the bin code is zero
zero zero one it's gonna be no time flat
but if it's nine nine nine nine you
might be there for a while some like
sheriff it's time to deputize someone
and so all of this works because of
convenience when inherent trusts are
baked into a system for the sake of
convenience it only takes the right lie
to completely compromise the security
and yet at the same time this is the
stuff that is going to make grandma's
life easier
grandma she's huge she's on the snapchat
she's on the Facebook on the Instagram
on the Twitter on Bebo whatever that is
and she's got the latest smartphones the
latest tablets she is hip she is cool
she is tech-savvy she's also pretty
well-off retired and likes to travel so
she stays at the Hilton she stays at the
Marriott she flies virgin and United she
drinks coffee at Starbucks and
kaleidoscope and when she goes to her
coffee joint
she expects her devices to automatically
connect to the Wi-Fi I recently saw a
t-shirt with this you guys have no idea
how happy this makes me because we're on
our grandma's going all of her devices
are sending out these little probes and
they're saying hey is H honors around is
Marriott around is gogo in-flight around
is Starbucks around and when it sees one
of those it connects and when it
connects if there's a captive portal one
of those things where you know pops up
and you typically have to accept a
license agreement or acceptable use
policy or maybe make a payment or in the
case of many hotels especially in Vegas
if you go to deaf
they will ask for your last name and
your room number which by the way is
awesome because all you have to do is
put in kitchen and then try every single
possible number and then Bill thinks my
room don't do that at Def Con so
wherever she goes her phone
automatically connects and these captive
portals just automatically pop up for
convenience because again we want
computers to be toasters we want them to
be convenient we want it all automatic
and plug and play we don't want Mission
Control we wanted a little appliance
that does the thing so any modern OS is
going to pop up these captive portals
any modern OS is going to automatically
connect to these remembered networks
because we don't want to inconvenience
the user in fact here at the Marriot
this was in my room it literally says
after you've connected to the marriott
wireless networks that the hotel landing
page will automatically open because
that is the default on all modern
operating systems how fantastic is that
they even have like a caveat here if
you're running an older OS that you need
to open a browser and just go to any
page it really doesn't matter what page
because the captive portal will grab you
this is fantastic because the network
operator can push you to any web page
they want hosting any iframe with a PDF
or whatever have you and so this is the
kind of convenience this is the kind of
trust that we violate with a Wi-Fi
pineapple wearing one right here it's
quite fashionable what the Wi-Fi
pineapple does among many other things
is it sees these probe requests coming
out of out of your phone your tablet
your laptop saying hey is XYZ network
around and like the mirror and
harrypotter it shows you what you want
to see and it says yes I am XYZ network
come and join and then it continues to
advertise that and does very wicked
things with manipulating frames so in
addition to gathering some passive
intelligence
about the fact that that grandma drinks
coffee at kaleidoscope or that she
stayed at the Marriott Surfers Paradise
we collect grandma as a client she joins
our network which then puts us as the
penetration tester specifically poised
as the man in the middle which means
that much like your home ISP much like
any network that you've ever connected
to the operator is sitting in the middle
and has that ability to monitor the
traffic to manipulate the traffic we
could replace all of the photos on the
internet with cats we could turn all web
pages upside down
seriously look up upside down Internet
it's fantastic or we could pop up a
captive portal of our own and start
harvesting corporate credentials all of
this for convenience because Wi-Fi is
ubiquitous and because all it takes is a
simple lie to go ahead and violate that
inherent man-machine trust and yeah it
is what is making life so convenient for
Grandma
a little word on Wi-Fi pineapple this is
the the first-ever generation Wi-Fi
pineapple and I know that a bunch of you
guys were able to come out to our
workshop on Monday and and got
yourselves some
thankfully you didn't get the mark one
version because if you did I would tell
you when you go through airport security
with one of these as I did you may end
up in a situation where the the security
agent says um excuse me what is this I
was so caught off guard I was like ah
it's my novelty router did they make
them in coconut - oh that's so cute
you're gonna have to take it out of your
bag next time it looks like a grenade in
the x-ray
oops they don't look like that mmm
they look like this now you know
speaking of hardware though let's talk
about grandmas laptop but told you she
is a tacky she has got the sweetest
little machines i7 4k display weighs
less than a kilogram the thing is beast
only one problem
no Ethernet port this is a big problem
too because grandma was a gamer she is
killing it in dota 2
she is climbing ladders and call of duty
and counter-strike go and you don't need
me to tell you that lag is the enemy
don't get me wrong Wi-Fi was great I
love Wi-Fi but wired is better and so
what she's gonna need to do just go out
and grab a USB Ethernet adapter they all
have one of these kicking around the
office here's one it even says USP
Ethernet adapter on the back these
things are becoming commonplace I would
use these as assisted men when machines
would die like I would have a dead Nick
and rather than open up a box and
replace a PCI card it's just often more
convenient to just go ahead and plug in
an inexpensive USB Ethernet adapter and
move on with my day
actually I had my dad once asked me when
I was getting my A+ certification if I
was learning to solder chips onto the
PCB like node Ave you don't do that
something's broken you just replace it
that's that's the society we're in you
know we're a culture of convenience
so while Ethernet may be fading because
machines are getting lighter and smaller
these are becoming more and more
ubiquitous and so as you imagine this
USB Ethernet adapter well it smells like
one and looks like one well it actually
is one it is a USB Ethernet adapter as
well as so much more there's an embedded
Linux distribution on here little sock
and it allows us to do remote access
into networks it allows us to do
man-in-the-middle fun we call it the
land turtle
because getting shells is fun I know you
can kick me off the stage at any point
but it looks like the real thing and I
don't think Ethernet is going away
anytime soon and so we end up with this
which means that I can drop at any
client site and as long as it's powered
over USB
I have remote access into that Network I
really wish I had one of these when I
was assisted min because I was managing
multiple client sites and this would
have just been beautiful that said as a
penetration tester this is just as
beautiful because that's not leaving the
network closet anytime soon there's
another way to deploy it that's actually
kind of fun remember those USB
descriptors hi I'm a cd-rom drive I'm a
storage I'm a keyboard let's be friends
there's another really cool one it's
called CDC ether or our NDIS and what it
basically means is a computer I'm an
Ethernet NIC let's be friends
and of course computers are like Oh
Ethernet I love Ethernet that's
fantastic
let's what's the first thing they try to
do when they connect to a network it's
for convenience DHCP hey there turtle
USB Ethernet adapter can I get an IP
address and of course the land turtle is
like Oh fantastic an IP address yes we
have a fine selection in fact I'd like
to introduce you to our DNS servers it
is the physical man in the middle it
allows us to much like the Wi-Fi
pineapple over Ethernet monitor and
manipulate traffic DNS poisoning really
couldn't be any easier and so all of
this again exists for convenience we
wanted to just work in fact when you
plug this guy in it's just going to
automatically install drivers it's going
to automatically get an address from
DHCP and yet all it takes is a little
lie and I feel like in many ways we have
grandma to thank for this because
computers need to be
user friendly they need to be
plug-and-play so remember the
centrifuges spinning her way enriching
that uranium with those programmable
logic controllers that Stuxnet attacked
Stuxnet targeted specifically and said
hey they actually they were pretty
effective you know doing damage to
nearly a fifth of the these centrifuges
and these aren't easy to replace this is
in fact old soviet stock and see you're
wondering like well how did how is that
possible because of course these aren't
you know connected to the internet this
is an internet of things this is an
amazon echo you can't say alexa order
you riched in rate uranium let me try
that once more alexa order enriched
uranium okay i just want to make sure
that I get the listeners at home on a
watch list because of course these
things are air gapped right so how do
you get information on to an air gapped
PC I mean it sounds secure no it's not
connected to a network so you got a
ferry data to it somehow we got to push
those updates we got to tell it you know
some programming what to do and of
course these expensive PLC's are being
run by boring Windows boxes so how are
they infected well it propagated over
USB it's actually a really cool worm it
employed several awesome zero-day
vulnerabilities including a really cool
LNK vulnerability it was it was pretty
awesome but it did so over USB because
it's understood that convenience is king
you know network operators systems
administrators and we don't have a
network we're gonna sneaker net that
thing but then it begs the question all
right well then how did the centrifuges
destroy themselves and they did so by
being induced to spin in such a way that
they would literally tear themselves
apart which is kind of crazy to think
because alright I'm a worm I'm telling
this piece of equipment to just
to its death you'd figure a network
operator would kind of like notice that
but they didn't the operators of this
these equipment the operator is managing
these PLC's of these centrifuges
enriching this uranium
didn't notice that they were being spun
to their death because of a simple lie
because the worm told the centrifuge to
go die and told the operators
everything's a-okay which is kind of
fantastic I think it illustrates the
point that we live in a culture of
convenience we are willing to trade
almost anything for convenience well
trade money will string quality we'll
trade security
I mean ransomware right a lot of times
just easier to just pay up and in fact
if you need to pay up there might even
be a support line they're willing and
able to help you transfer your money
into Bitcoin or streaming audio this is
by no way as good a CD or vinyl but it's
on demand it's convenient much of the
same way that we're willing to binge on
TV shows and movies with often terrible
bit rates rather than buying the blu-ray
which is obviously much higher quality
but we don't because it's less
convenient and yet we still end up with
this that's okay I hear that you guys
get a lot more of that too security is
hard it really is so let's let's just go
shopping in Christopher's keynote
yesterday a question was posed about who
has in the last week use encrypted email
and there were very few hands in the
audience I know because encryption is
hard PGP is not convenient if you would
like to email me about this afterwards
go to key based io / Darin kitchen
you'll find my PGP key that said I fear
I received very few of these so with
security not being convenient I'm
wondering though is grandma on to
something right
is convenience actually a curse or can
convenience in fact be our salvation
I'll give a very similar example to
yesterday whatsapp implementing the
signal protocol end-to-end encryption
for a billion users users that have
never thought twice about key exchange
or fingerprint validation or iPhone
users with iMessage within certain
caveats couple million people using
end-to-end encryption and the thing
about this though is this is what
grandma's already using it gets better
for us sis admin's that's the sell
certificates so much fun to install
right okay it's gotten so much better
let's encrypt an initiative backed by
the likes of Akamai and Mozilla and EF F
providing free certificates that install
in just seconds with a couple of
commands and so sites that wouldn't have
otherwise implemented security now have
security because it's convenient you
know it's it's these intersections that
are so interesting if these just like in
ecologies where you have the
intersections of land and sea where
things get really interesting I feel
like we're security meets convenience
things get really interesting now I'm
not telling you guys to trust every
sketchy look in USB Ethernet adapter or
shady Wi-Fi out there but I do believe
that we should trust that if security is
default and if security is convenient
not only are we going to be living in a
culture of convenience we're going to be
living in a culture of security thank
you
one of your stuff down I've got time for
a couple of questions throw any
questions on the conference app now if
you want to ask him um a couple of
questions one that has already come
through there was that shot there of the
there was a high-heeled shoe with a love
tattoo on the inside someone asked was
that your foot yes absolutely that's me
now you can find out later
you just got to enumerate all of the
hotel room numbers and put in kitchen
and see what's where I'm at no I'm
joking
yeah your personal we talked Chris was
talking Krista gone was asked this
question as well yesterday about his own
personal protection regime and we spoke
you mentioned iMessage whatsapp etcetera
did you hear his presentation what did
you take from that and what's your own
personal protection regime I think it's
fantastic that more and more
technologies are becoming ubiquitous for
security and privacy
whatsapp and iMessage are interesting
pushes in those right directions as we
find the the clash between governments
and corporations the citizens and the
users and the fight to protect those
users so I think it's fantastic that
those technologies haven't ended but
again they're those silos I am a huge
fan of PGP just because it's an open
specification with that said so is
signal and that's the protocol that's
been implemented by whatsapp and so I
say alright if that's not your dam and
you just want to use you know text
signal the actual application and whose
specification was you know the founder
of this the use that formerly text
secure now signal cross-platform
fantastic stuff we are gonna sleep
Darren later in the great speed debate
tomorrow afternoon as well when he will
give us these opinions on four different
subjects one minute each give him a
round of applause great stuff Darren
thank you now we're gonna give you as
you leave you're gonna be given a lovely
gift I want to explain the gifts that
we're giving out today are quite
beautiful you'll see the ones our
speakers yesterday and today got there
these are the maca day there are bought
a little Bowl there's a Queensland based
company that makes product macadamia nut
products and then manufactures these
beautiful little bowls out of macadamia
shells and it's a gorgeous story because
this economy there were big floods in
Queensland reason these guys are almost
completely wiped out they're an
international design where they're one
Nordic design company so when you start
winning the Nordic ones that's when you
know you're doing pretty well so you're
getting get one of those as all our
speakers do so one more riddle Corsa
Darren thank you very much Mike great
stuff wonderful