good morning ladies and gentlemen
welcome to the first session for the
this morning
this session is lessons from a quarter
of a billion breached records with you
presenter Troy Hammett choice a local
gold coaster who runs the free service
have I been honed which aggregates large
data breaches and notifies impacted
subscribers of their exposure he's also
an author for Pluralsight where he
creates online security courses for
developers and is a Microsoft regional
director and most valuable professional
now Troy said his presentations going to
run right down to the wire so might hold
off for questions he said he was going
to hang around after the session to take
any questions so please make Troy
welcome all right thanks very much
everyone it's nice to be so close to
home I had to walk here this morning
which is which is a really nice change
so what I want to talk about today is a
bunch of things that I have seen as part
of running this have I been phone
service and I did this talk the first
time earlier this year and this was the
talk it was 220 million records and by
the second time I did it I had to revise
things upwards and every time I've done
this talk I have to keep changing it
because the landscape changes so quickly
and I sort of had things prepared the
other day and it was like okay I'll just
round it up we just got quarter of a
billion it's it's not a quarter of a
billion anymore it kind of went a little
bit higher during the week due to one
particular incident any one in a data
breach this week yeah
either you are you don't know you are
because pretty much everyone was in
LinkedIn which took the total numbers of
individual breached accounts sort of
I've got an assistant I took just over
half a billion which is kind of a crazy
number so what I want to talk about
today is some of the things I've seen
running this service so some of the
people have had interactions with some
of the ways that they're sending data
the way they're monetizing data and
hopefully give everyone just a little
bit of insight into what's actually
going on behind some of these data
breaches but
other things I find really interesting
when looking at security incidents is
the way hackers are represented and we
probably all see this right like we see
the news it's a story about hackers in
there and we see some interesting
patterns one of the things about this is
that hacking incidents make the news
like so many other technology things
just died it is actually mainstream
consumer news and if you have a look at
the way hackers are represented you
start to see some patterns
now here's what stands out to me here
and you'll see this throughout the talk
it's a recurring theme hackers have
hoodies which is one thing that's very
important ah hack is very much like
binary as well and they very much like
green and we all see this right in all
these stock photos and there's a certain
perception which is created around the
way hackers work so it's interesting
looking at things like kujaku Joe's
little Kickstarter project it's security
in a box for consumers and they have
this little video you may not know it
but you've probably already been hacked
thousands of hacking attacks occur each
day now notice how that ticks all the
boxes right so we've got the guy in a
hoodie so he knows a hacker he has a
green screen as well so you know that's
that's good some scary music because
we've got to instill enough fear in
people that stuff will go wrong that
they gone by the security in a box
because they've already been hacked even
if they don't know but there's a curious
thing about this and you have a look at
the screen that he's typing into and
I'll zoom in on a little bit of it here
and there's a browser Chrome on the
screen the guys hacking on and I thought
this was really curious like I want to
know how he does this because I might
learn something right and I figured it
out and here's what you do and any of
you can become a hacker by doing this as
well
what you do is you go to a website
called hacker typer net now you've got
to put it in full screen otherwise you
give the game away and then as you type
that's what happens this is exactly what
he used in that video I literally zoomed
in and it's exactly if it's code they
are selling security in a box because
I in a hoodie typing on a green screen
in a browser is hacking your things
apparently so we have this really
inconsistent representation of hackers
now the reality of it is ah did you see
this one is oh this is the dormant cyber
pathogens this was on the news just the
other day
ah this was one of the one of the stock
photos we'll talk more about stock
photos later on notice also he doesn't
hoody so therefore we know he's a hacker
so so this is the way these incidents
are being represented and the way the
threat actors as we'd call them are
being portrayed and the reality is
actually quite a bit different so guys
like Ryan Cleary he was part of LulzSec
19 years old he's turning up at court
there with his mum who is seriously
pissed just well the guy's so grounded
after this he's not going to be hacking
anything for a long time but 19 years
old and he did do a lot of damage same
with Jake Davies he was 18 years old and
the interesting thing is is that often
these these guys and it's almost always
guys are either kids in the legal sense
and that they're under 18 or they're
kids and that they're kind of younger
than all of us so we think of them as
kids so that the reality of it is is
that the scary hackers are usually not
quite as scary as the media would like
to portray them and when we actually
look at what's going on behind the
scenes we realize a lot of the time
certainly with the data breaches that I
see so frequently it's kids that have a
combination of curiosity and time and
how can be a really destructive
combination but it allows them to do
things like this to break into the likes
of talk talk talk talk was interesting
so Talk Talk is a UK taco
they got hacked late last year now after
they got hacked this detective came out
and said we think it is Russian Islamic
cyber gr DS which is a terrifying
prospect
for your average person because every
one of those things apologies xx
Russians sounds kind of scary right
Russian Islamic cyber jihadi and this is
the way it was represent
and then it turned out to be a
fifteen-year-old kidneys bedroom I
assume in his bedroom because where else
he going to be happy from when he like
15 years old you at your parents place
right so that was him there was another
guy field a little bit older you're 16
this is really old guy it was 20 and
these are the folks that broke into talk
talk and the interesting thing is you
look back on on how this happened and it
was sequel injection using sequel map so
effectively the 15 year old knew how to
download a free tool and then you had a
copy and paste and that is about the
extent of the competency that he needed
to get in there and frankly I'm a little
bit sympathetic to some of them know
they shouldn't be breaking into this
sort of stuff but when you're 15 and
someone says copy and paste a link into
a tool you know he probably had no idea
of the consequences but this is often
the level of confidence of the
individuals breaking into these systems
and then leaking this data publicly very
often there is actually a financial
upside there is money that they want to
make out of this data and it's curious
to look at the different ways that this
happens and some of the things we can
learn so give me an example I'm going to
share some of the private conversations
I've had obviously anonymized and here
was a case where someone said look I
think for for this particular breach
Nexus mods I would like to receive a sum
of Bitcoin so people want to sell these
data breaches now for me it's pretty
easy I have a default response which is
I'm not giving anybody any money for
anything and I'm not giving anybody any
sort of exchange data or anything of
that I don't want to be the one that's
perpetuating either the incentive to
break into these sites or perpetuating
the spread of particularly data breaches
which which don't go anywhere else so
there are some data breaches remain
pretty self-contained but regardless I'm
not going to be the one spreading it
around so this is a conversation which
often plays out and it just for
curiosity I'll give the same answer even
to security researchers often security
researchers will say we would really
like the LinkedIn data breach because we
want to do analysis and it will be all
honest and just
give us the hashes it's just easier for
me to say nobody is getting anything
because then I can at least with all
good face say I've never given stuff to
other people so that's my rationale Matt
looking at some of the incidents things
like OPM so this bloke said look I've
got OPM OPM is the Office of Personnel
Management bunch of US government
identities about 18 million identities I
reckon it's worth more than 100 Bitcoin
bitcoins about 600 ozzie dollars at the
moment so 60 grand for OPM and you can
understand that because if you had 18
million individuals with a whole bunch
of personal attributes including things
like Social Security numbers which the
Americans love to use as a verification
attribute it's going to be pretty
valuable other times it'll be stuff like
this and this one I found quite curious
so this was after triple-a web host
which is one of these sort of freemium
hosting providers so they got hacked
last year they had 13 million accounts
with plaintext passwords hacked took me
about a week I couldn't get in touch
with them kept going through their
support lines and I didn't want to
escalate it and they basically basically
didn't to pay much attention to it
eventually the news comes out goes
public and this person contacted me and
what I found really curious about this
this was someone trading in the data
he says the database is private and it's
better kept that way now his definition
is private of private is that a bunch of
us have got it and we're sharing it
between each other and it's ours yeah
okay we did hack it had a triple-a web
base but now it's ours and I'm not real
keen on the fact that it's now public
knowledge now he went on to say I can't
understand which moron would be
considering giving you a copy for free
because they want to sell it and the
problem that these guys have is that
once these incidents become public
whether it's in the press or searchable
and have all been piled or whatever it
is the value goes down so in a case like
this
he said the database is selling upwards
a 2 grand which is conceivable 13
million accounts plain 2 credentials
there's a site which had it publicly
listed this is a clear website down the
bottom left they had
for one and a half thousand dollars
similar sort of range I guess to two
grand after all the news went public and
a little bit of time went by and the
data started to spread the price drops
because there are so many people who
have these accounts that are now
changing their passwords and are now no
longer exploitable by the people that
have these original data breaches the
value drops and I find that really
interesting and as much as we don't want
websites getting hacked once they do
this sort of early notification and
letting everyone know that yes you're at
risk and you probably want to go and
change that password that you've reused
everywhere on everything ASAP there's
less people to exploit value goes down
often I see headlines like this so this
was only last month a couple of months
ago and obviously someone's broken into
a pawn network here and there's a
comment from the guy so this was the
hacker I want to publicly shame them all
right maybe it's kind of a little bit
altruistic he wants to put them on
notice how you've done something bad you
deserve to have your name drawn through
the mud for that and it was almost sort
of represented as though he's doing this
for the good of society says the guy
who's selling the data so there is very
often a financial upside for these guys
they want to monetize the information
that they've stolen or that they've
traded with someone else now a lot of
people sort of say okay well like where
does this come from how hard is it to
obtain this data am I sort of spending
all day trolling around the dark webs
now how do I find this information and
the reality of it is it comes from a
variety of different sources and now
that this service has been running for a
little while there's enough people that
follow it and support it many of them
who sort of travel in these circles
where they're trading data who come to
me and say look such-and-such has been
hacked I'd like to send you the data so
I get messages like this so this was the
person who sent me the triple a web host
data this was the the original email
from him and
and it's sort of a couple of interesting
things is so one is it very often what
these guys do is once they have the data
they'll upload it to a service like mega
so there's no authorization or anything
around how you access this data it's
just a great big long obfuscated link
they'll send it over and go here it is
this guy with the benefit of hindsight
may not have been so bright because he
said I'm going to give you 2 million out
of the 13 million database the 13
million database of 30 million
individuals is a bit secret I want to
share it he did accidentally upload the
13 million record one so maybe not
paying a lot of attention there but the
interesting thing about this particular
guy see now the data went out there had
got press who had lots of headlines he
then got really really nervous
afterwards he sent me this and what
struck me when I read this is how much
it sounds like a kid it sounds like
someone who has not thought through the
ramifications of what they've got
themselves involved in and it kind of
speaks to that point earlier on about a
lot of the time these are legally minors
or very young people who really haven't
considered the social consequences of
what they're doing other times I'll see
things like this now this is an
interesting one so someone reached out
it was last year and said I've got some
data for you from a Dutch financial
institution and particularly once it's
once it's dealing with money and there
is serious ramifications on people it
all gets very delicate I tend to not try
and ask too much about did you go in and
hack it or did you get it from someone
else but when they literally send you a
screen cap of sequel map where they have
extracted the data out themselves
it like the ambiguity goes away at night
also green he did actually put his
screen into green before he started for
anyone looking at this and going look
I've been doing it wrong I really need
to go green if you do jump into a
command window it's just a little bit of
color a and you'll be good to hack so
that's what most of these guys appear to
be doing now in this actual case I end
up getting in touch with the
organisation there are a lot of data
breaches you never see on have a bean
pie
that stay quiet for various reasons in
this case I got in touch with the
organization this was something which
didn't seem to have spread very far they
managed to deal with it all internally
it's a listed company dealing with very
very sensitive financial information so
they kind of cleaned up a little bit
quietly oddly enough though after that
I've since had multiple people reach out
and say by the way would you like XYZ
data so even when you think these things
are contained you once it sort of
spreads just that little bit far enough
it's very hard to put the genie back in
the bottle
there are a lot of clear websites
springing up that also trade in this
data this is one which is accessible
without jumping on the Tor and here's an
interesting thing as well often you see
the news and they go yeah look at this
data is out there's being traded but but
it's on the dark web and it's almost
like that makes it harder to access the
sort of guy most of you probably know
jumping on the Tor is not a particularly
difficult thing you download the tor
browser bundle or you go to web to
torrents for all intents and purposes
the barrier to entry is a fraction
higher and clearer web but better as it
may this is on the clear web there's a
site that frequently post started
breaches in full you can see here
they're actually a triple a web host on
there as well so sometimes it's very
very easy to obtain these breaches this
was LinkedIn so this was obviously very
topical this was just last week you've
probably all seen the news on LinkedIn
this site is a tor based web site called
the real deal they they have the
LinkedIn data there and this is sort of
the first place that appeared 167
million records with email addresses and
sha-1
hashes of passwords with no salt about
90% of those have been cracked already
so for all intents and purposes it's
just about clear text they are on their
selling four or five Bitcoin a pop
they're actually down a two Bitcoin at
least as of yesterday so their price is
now dropping as the data is spreading
and people are changing passwords
interesting thing though on a site like
this so this is a dark web trading site
is to have a look at the classes of
commodity that
two breaches sit next to got drugs there
on the right on the left you can see we
got weapons all sorts of other things
that somehow this class of data which is
data breaches and now sort of sitting in
there it's like ei guns drugs and data
breaches all being traded in the same
place so the point is is that this data
comes from a number of different places
there's no sort of one tried and trusted
this is the way it always comes kind of
channel one of the things though that
I'm really really conscious of when
there are incidents where someone pops
up and says you know hey look we've got
a bit of data for you is that very often
it's fake so you might have seen in the
news probably about four weeks ago so
big story said something like 272
million accounts hacked out of Gmail
Hotmail mail are you and the the press
went apeshit about it because it's a
good story right it is a really really
good story Reuters broke it very early
on another security researcher had
gotten in touch with them he founded
this on the dark web serious stuff and
by the time the likes of Google and
Microsoft actually looked at it they
said yeah there's like a fraction of one
percent of accounts that are actually
legitimate it was fake not necessarily
saying the guy who reported it made made
the whole thing up but he could have got
it from someone else who fabricated so
verification is really important and
I'll show you a couple of different ways
I verify these things so give you one
good example last week adult or last
year Adult Friend Finder got hacked now
if you're seeing friend and you're
thinking well maybe this is a social
network friend means something quite
different in this context the thing is
though when there's a breach like this
and look I mean this is obvious it's
pretty self-explanatory right it's a
hook-up site sites like this people sign
up to and they have an expectation of
privacy they don't want their wife to
find out that they're on there and if we
put our moral judgment aside for a
moment that's probably a reasonable
expectation but pretty much every time
there is an enumeration risk where you
can go it'll literally just fat-finger
the keyboard you may have to solve a
super super safe capture
huh and you'll be told pretty quickly
that it's invalid you guess what happens
if you put in a correct email address
yes well it it exists so mostly sites of
enumeration risks and what that means is
I can look at a data breach grab several
male inator accounts out of it
so if you never use male inator you can
send an email address to anything you
like at mail a NATO comm and then go to
Milan Aida and look at the mailbox it's
basically a public open mailbox for
disposable accounts if someone signing
up with the mail inator account they
have no expectation of privacy it's not
real they're just trying to gain access
through whatever entry criteria there
are so I can grab several of those and
if they return positive matches you're
pretty sure that the data is going to be
legit it's one indicator it's not
exhaustive someone could have seeded it
with monitor accounts now often it's a
very explicit enumeration risk like that
no it doesn't exist yes it does other
times it's more like what actually
Madison was doing where they had on
their password reset page a situation
where you could jump in like this with
an invalid email address so you just
fat-finger something up and they'll come
back give you a message like this and
when you look at this there's like a ray
of hope if that email address exists in
our database you'll receive an email and
you kind of read that and go well if it
doesn't exist maybe I won't but it's not
telling you right so it's not giving
that explicit confirmation whether you
can't exists or not
so I created a research account I better
explain my wife many times how many
research accounts I have and create a
research account did a password reset
and I got this message do you see any
disparity between the results so it's an
implicit enumeration risk so it's
telling you that they don't have an
account but it's not quite telling you
black and white like Adult Friend Finder
does so that's one really easy way most
websites will do this if not on password
reset many of them will do it on login
many of them will do it on registration
many of them will do it as a mechanism
of brute force protection because they
will lock out an account that exists
after three or five failed attempts but
they won't look at an account
it doesn't exist more recently I've been
using this approach so I've got
approaching half a million subscribers
on have a bent poem it's a free thing
you just go in put in your email address
you verify it you get an email with a
nonce in it and go yes I did actually
want to be on here and now after when a
data breach comes up I'm saying okay
well let's find which of my subscribers
so people that have been trusted me with
looking for weather exposed which of my
ones are in there and I'll grab maybe 20
of the most recent people who've signed
up so it's still kind of front of mine
and I'll say look your names come up in
a bridge would you be happy to help
verify it and usually they say yes I
actually have had not had anyone say no
I'm sure a lot of the time the modus
goes to spam but certainly ever on this
replied is going yes I'm interested I
mean that's why they've signed up right
so I'll send them a little bit of data
send them something like this you know
nothing too sensitive
Sasa like theater when did you log in
what's your location
who's your ISP based on the IP address
this lady very unfortunately for her was
also on Talk Talk and she's like oh geez
I just had Talk Talk and now got this
one
so unfortunately many people do see
themselves over and over again anyway in
this case she came back and said yes in
this case was VTech I did actually
register on there so now you've sort of
got this confirmation from the person
who was on the site that they existed I
did this recently with the Philippines
Election Commission breached 55 million
people in this breach that's half the
entire population and one of the guys
actually sent me like two characters out
of his passport as well because a lot of
passport data that was leaked so it's
not just them sort of having some kind
of confirmation bias they're actually
providing a secret that only they'd know
so that's verification I find the way
companies respond is also interesting
and I think we can sort of draw a lot
from their priorities when we look at
what they say after a breach happens so
if we look at avid life media parent
company of actually medicine so we had
over 30 million people hacked out of
Ashley
Edison now again it's an affair site
right it's there to commit adultery
these people are worried that their life
is going to be destroyed there what's
going to leaving and never going to see
their kids again and the first thing
that I would like media tells them is
hey good news your credit cards alright
you know the guy's gonna give a
about micro like you thought credit
cards owned my bank will give me fraud
protection I'll get a new card in the
mail like the worst thing that will
happen is I'm going to go and change my
direct debits which yes is painful but
less so than your wife leaving you but
that is what they focus on same again
with VTech VTech lost a whole bunch of
kids data the first thing they focused
on was your credit card as okay
why do you reckon I do this why is this
the focus credit cards everyone's
whispering the PCI there's what they
write about because there is retribution
from PCI they want to be able to
continue to take payments which is
understandable but that seems to be the
first thing they focus on a lot of the
time rather than focusing on the fact
that there's actually a really serious
human impact particularly for something
like actually medicine people killed
themselves as a result of actually
medicine
this one was a little bit unique this
was only about last month this is a
minecraft site they had 7 million
accounts hacked out of their site and
they knew about it and didn't tell
anyone until someone sent it to me and
eventually it got airtime and this was
their reasoning and they weren't really
sure of why this was not a good thing
now after this went out the number of
people that popped up and said we'll
hang on a second I've used this email
address everywhere this password
everywhere and this is the problem
because these credentials are exploited
in other locations and these guys just
had no idea of the ramifications
downstream to other services in fact
what they did is they forced a password
reset so that when you next logged on to
their service you had to change it now
of course this was after you logged on
as well so someone had their credentials
they would have logged on and they would
have done whatever you can do with a
minecraft site or you can log on the
Sonde's Gmail well their social media
these other places where the credentials
are reused so often these sites don't
think about the downstream ramifications
we've seen this from LinkedIn as well
there's a lot of weirdness about who
LinkedIn has notified about who was in
the data breach and there's a lot of
people who had changed their passwords
shortly after LinkedIn was originally
hacked in 2012 on LinkedIn but I haven't
changed it anywhere else but LinkedIn
may not have sent them a notification
because I said well you changed it on
our service do you really need to know
now I find the way the press covers a
lot of this really interesting it's like
we can learn by looking at the way the
press covers data breaches and if we
look at LinkedIn last week this was sort
of a follow-up story so Lorenzo from
Vice who does a motherboard here he
often writes a lot about these incidents
often gets very early stories he's one
of the guys I often work with when
something comes up he says look can you
see if this is legit or not so he sort
of broke this story about LinkedIn
originally and he had this follow up
story a week ago all right so this is
precise I was just talking about so it
counts from LinkedIn having password
reuse and then other things being hacked
so people's Twitter accounts being taken
over so he wrote this story which is
okay that's fine and then on the real
deal dark market site selling the data
they used his story in the description
in order to give authenticity to the
data so it's almost like they leverage
the press and we saw it with the guy
earlier on yes I'm doing this to make
them aware of the issues by the way the
data is for sale so they leverage the
press in a way that works in their favor
now it's it's also interesting to look
at the sort of stories the press will
cover because sometimes there are
incidents which are a lot smaller but
due to their nature the press picks them
up and covers them there was this one
recently and I've got to be honest I
never expected to see my name in a story
with a headline like this forearm for
those of you who may not be familiar
with the term
wait till you get home before you google
it get a very stiff drink before you
start looking for it
this is what it was so the fisting site
there's nothing there's no way to
sugarcoat it this was a hundred thousand
records which in the scheme and data
breaches is not a lot but it is a really
salacious story so it gets picked up and
it gets covered but one of the things
that I found amusing about this is
amusing as a story about this can be is
the press always has to find stock
photos right and I'm looking at these
photos and they're they're fairly
predictable rubber glove style photos
but I think the prize of the best stock
photo of probably all time has to go to
the register and then my mum's like so I
saw you in the news the other day what
was it about I want to get off the
internet so uh so that was a bit
unprecedented this year so moving items
on the alittle bit more serious one side
of all of this is obviously going to be
law enforcement so how how these data
breaches perceived how they dealt with
and in particular how do individuals
involved in these sorts of exercises do
law enforcement and that's sort of
dawned on me particularly over the last
year that there is there is a perception
that many people have about law
enforcement which at least in my
experience is inconsistent with the
reality and certainly every time I've
spoken to law enforcement here overseas
everything has been very constructive
with everybody having the same objective
or just trying to make the web a safer
place trying to stop people from getting
abused and taken advantage of but time
and time again I hear from people
particularly people who find breaches
let's just sort us or rather find
vulnerabilities let's just suspend
judgment for a moment in terms of how
they go about finding that there might
be a sequel injection risk for example
maybe they're Irish and they put in
O'Reilly and the thing just
spat the dummy maybe they are being a
little bit more creative but they found
a vulnerability and very often they'll
say I don't want to report this because
I see the headlines and it's security
researcher goes to jail but the
interesting thing is in pretty much
every case I can think of when we see a
headline like this there's a bigger
story you know know who this is you
probably don't want to know who he is
that's another timeline you wait to get
home and you have a stiff drink before
you look at antor Oppenheimer also known
as weave he found a direct object
reference risk in AT&T with the iPad
registration process I think about 2011
on some years ago now and basically what
he found was he could look at a URL
change a number and pull back someone
else's data this is the nature of direct
object reference risks and then just to
make sure it wasn't an accident
he did it another hundred and fourteen
thousand times and and then gave all the
data to the press and people like a
security researcher arrested this sucks
yeah but look at what he actually did
there is normally a story where they
have gone well beyond just the discovery
of a risk this guy's in the news just
recently Dave Levin the bloke on the
left and the black and black shirt by
all accounts a very nice guy I have a
bit of a chat to him afterwards and he
was in the news he was arrested because
he found this hole in a in an election
site there in the one of their local
counties in the US but what happened
with Dave and I think quite frankly all
of this was pretty political because the
bloke on his left is campaigning for
particular seat and I was just very
quinces identity somehow found a sequel
injection risk on the site so he found
their sequel injection risk and then he
fired up havoc which is a pretty Mickey
Mouse sequel injection tool whacked the
URL in sucked out all the data including
the plaintext credentials to
authenticate to the admin interfaces
logged on to the admin interface with
the plaintext credentials videoed the
whole thing put it on YouTube and when
you believe it he got arrested you know
like this is the story behind that if it
had a vein he found the risk and he
contacted them and he got arrested that
would be a very different story but it
is normally someone going well beyond
just I have found a risk so in that
context of Lauren frost I think this is
really important where we want people
when they identify vulnerabilities to
have channels where they can disclose
ethically and obviously things like bug
bounties are getting a little traction
these days but not to be fearful of
going to jail just for finding a risk
because usually there's a much bigger
story behind it so sort of thinking
about how we can how we can try and fix
all this and none of it is an easy
problem but there's a few things that
really stick out to Mickey looking at
these incidents time and time again and
one of them is we've got to get really
early notification so that lifeboat
example was was probably at one bad end
to the extreme it took months and in
fact it was a conscious decision not to
tell anyone if the data hadn't been
given to me I don't know how long it
would have taken before people actually
realized even with the likes of forge so
forged got hacked they had about a
million accounts leaked a couple of
years ago they took about a week before
they let people know I mentioned
Philippines election commission the
other day 55 million accounts floating
around there in the web they still
refuse to acknowledge that that data
came out of their system they
acknowledge they got hacked because
their entire site got two-faced so they
can't really deny that but they're not
reaching out to people and saying hey
very soon after the event all your stuff
just got leaked you now need to think
about where you need to change your
password possibly change your passport
given the data they leaked we're heading
in this direction Frost will get
mandatory disclosure and it may be a bit
vague and it may take several iterations
to get it I was going to say right I
don't know deliver get it right but get
it better but we've got to get to this
point because the premise that people
can have their data out there doing the
rounds being traded and sold and
exploited and the company try to cover
it up it's just hard to fathom because
we've seen throughout this talk about
how many places it gets reused and abuse
and the final one and this is probably a
little bit contentious and a lot of
companies don't like this but if you
lose someone's data I reckon you got to
tell them what it was give you a good
example this week LinkedIn so I keep
hearing from people I want to know what
my password was on LinkedIn now again
I've got this sort of blanket thing
where I'm not giving anybody anything in
terms of whether it be the entire breach
or whether someone comes and says please
give me personal attributes like I'm not
your personal data lookup person to
troll through breaches and in fact to
several of them I said look I understand
you want to know what your password was
because you want to know where you've
reused it you should never use it but
you want to know and it was four years
ago - so it's hard to remember and in
fact several of them went back to
LinkedIn and they said can you please
give me the data and LinkedIn said well
no we don't have it you changed your
password since then we don't have the
original one and I'm going hang on a
second there's all these people all over
the web who have 167 million of your
records the data is there you guys
should have to give it to them same
thing happened a lot with Ashley Madison
because people wanted to know could I
possibly be identified where my payment
records there did I have my address on
there these people are really scared
about severe consequences to their life
they want to know what was leaked I
would love to see providing data to
victims being part of what goes into
things like mandatory disclosure laws
you've got to tell them what happened
one final thing out of curiosity who
here is primarily security Pro show
hands who here is primarily developer oh
just a few okay cool so speaking mostly
to the security pros friend of mine sent
me this the other day and this is often
what it feels like
you laugh but I think some of you may
have been on horseback riding down the
mountain with the big sword and I see
this very very frequently and I think
it's it's a little bit a bit of fault on
all sides we've got a lot of developers
doing quite frankly a lot of stupid
things often just due to lack of
education the rest of it we've also got
a lot of security pros often telling
them that they're doing stupid things
now go and fix it in you on your own and
that there needs to be some point in the
middle where everyone gets together and
says look ultimately we're all here to
try and deliver working secure software
like that is our grandeur objective if
you like you know how we're going to
make that happen and I would love to see
more engagement between everyone because
developers genuinely love getting
involved in security when they get given
the opportunity so I do a lot of
workshops with developers and they see
sequel injection they go if this is
amazing this is so cool like I was
always doing the code to stop it from
happening but I never knew how it works
they say they see things like the
pineapple Darwin's talk about the other
day
they're like this is amazing I want one
of these and they get really engaged and
for those of you that are security pros
you've got this opportunity to sort of
take them on that journey and get them
excited about security and just about
every vulnerability we see exploit it in
order to get these data breaches and
mistakes that developers have made that
you guys can help them fix so if they're
sort of a positive note to leave things
on that's what I'd love to see more of
all of us trying to help the developers
on this path and giving them something
that they can enjoy doing that makes
everyone a lot safer thank you very much
everyone for coming
I know I'm out of time if anyone wants
to come and see me afterwards I'll hang
around for a bit