foreign
one two
let's go
can they hear me
can you hear me
okay awesome
all right
hello everyone Welcome to our talk on
web isolation
um man it was such an inspiring keynote
it was amazing like it will be very hard
to follow you know we basically should
sit down there yeah we should run away
right
all right so
um
I'm co-founder and CTO of J scrambler
um I also helped started the new Oasis
boa chapter
basically you had our first meet up uh
this week I hope the the other chapter
leaders are somewhere in there
uh but basically I've been working in
security for as far as I can remember
there is uh stands for virtualization I
think uh
no no response at all huh all right
um I've probably been working in
security almost as long as uh Pedro can
remember
okay so time for a little story better
it's 10 a.m I'm barely a coffee in are
we gonna do this yep we need to push
through like people are waiting
so
um it's a story about a ship
um some of you may recognize this ship
it's the Titanic
and it was built in Belfast in their
famous Shipyard which I was lucky enough
to visit during the absec absec EU 2017
I guess
but we want to talk about how it was
built many people do not know this but
when he was built it was bleeding edge
in many ways
so the bottom of the ship was splitting
to 16 water type compartments so it was
made such uh it could withstand some
damage without compromising the whole
ship
it could I think up to two adjacent
compartments could be completely flooded
which back then it was like the worst
situation they could imagine and that's
mainly the reason why they deemed the
the Titanic to be Unsinkable so they
made a great fuss about it
but depending on the exact location of
the damage it could actually withstand
up to four adjacent water type
compartments completely flooded without
sinking the ship
so we all know how this story ended
when the Titanic hit an iceberg the six
forwards compartments were completed
flooded and the Titanic sunk so even
though the story didn't end well
compartmentation was a great idea and it
is still used in shape design to this
day
so the main idea is that if a section is
damaged it doesn't compromise other
parts of the system
the problem with the Titanic is that its
implementation was flawed but we'll tell
you more about that later it's a this is
a cliffhanger at this point yeah I guess
so
all right so
um
let's talk about web isolation then a
little bit of History before we start
okay so the first real attempt at web
isolation was introduced by the same
origin policy to restrict how two
different Origins interact with each
other but restrict how if actually we
can embed a third party like a
cross-origin script from the third party
origin directly to a web page and this
script will actually have the same level
of privilege as any other script like
same origin scripts so where is the same
origin restricting anything here
so it turns out that
embedding is permitted what is
restricted is writing to or reading raw
data from cross-origin domains so the
reality is that the same origin policy
is complex and has lots of exceptions
and to this day many developers don't
fully understand how it works which is
frequently a source of security issues
two years later we they have given us
like iframes okay with which we can
isolate two documents or scripts running
on the same web page
but the problem is that people uh soon
enough
started to look for ways to have these
two different Origins communicating with
itself like coming coming with hacks and
creative hacks basically and and we only
threw the towel 13 years later
and made it official by introducing the
web messaging API with which two
different Origins can communicate using
a post message basically
but not every problem went away so for
instance iframe still had a lot of power
an iframe document can navigate to the
top window among other things so we had
to solve that problem too and 13 years
later we got high frame sandboxing with
which we could restrict very heavily
what an iframe is allowed to do
the problem is that at the same time
they have given us this configuration
attributes that allow us to relax the
iframed sandbox I frame so it's it's
like they given like the power and then
they take it away
and people obviously they're going to
use these things to relax the sandbox
about the same time we got content
security policy version one uh with
which you can do domain-based allow
listing
um which was later found to be
completely broken and you can read all
about it in the paper that you can see
on the right
plus it's very hard to maintain so later
on versions two and three they fixed
these problems but they are not
straightforward to set up
so I would say that like the main
critique that we have on CSP is that it
is kind of binary like either you fully
allow a script to run or you fully block
it there's no middle ground so basically
um if it was more more granular it could
be more useful for sure
and this basically concludes that the
problem with this isolation mechanisms
is that they are they lack granularity
um they the the the boxes that of
isolation that they provide are not are
not configurable
so you basically
so there was never one isolation feature
with which you could do like full
isolation of a web app so it has been
more about stitching together all of
these isolation features and hopefully
to cover as much ground as you want so
this is both complex and error prone so
inevitably you will leave holes or all
blind spots for instance Jason p and
cores are good examples so if they were
configurable and granular maybe people
wouldn't like
had the need to try to find ways to
relax these features or to poke holes on
them
and here you can see the timeline where
these features were introduced you'll
notice a huge gap between 97 and 2009
which you really have to wonder what the
browser people
were doing back then we needed our
pacemakers configured at a higher Pace I
think
all right so what Pedro has been talking
about is a large variety of different
features that browsers give us the thing
that we are trying to get to is
isolation what we are trying to build is
the ability to isolate different scripts
and their actions uh but what we have is
a variety of security features that the
browsers have implemented almost
reactively as different attacks arose
the question is can we use those
features to put together a more solid a
more systematic uh way of building
isolation
and I think that the answer is yes and
you shouldn't just believe me the
community you and I we all have been
building
um essentially a a mechanism for doing
web isolation
on top of the browser features that we
have
um I'm going to describe two different
primary mechanisms that we use in order
to
um in order to implement uh web
isolation and the two techniques that
mostly we use are
um
are uh
virtualization and transformation now
there's three projects that I've
randomly chosen to put on this graph but
most mechanisms for web isolation end up
falling somewhere on this graph on this
graph you have virtualization where what
you do is you virtualize you replace
the versions that are provided by the
browser with our own attenuated version
if you see something that is dangerous
you replace it with something that is
less dangerous or easier to control and
then you have transformation where
you're simply changing the source code
so that you remove the bad things from
your application so we have a way off on
the on the top right we have a project
called Google kaha which was an open
source sandboxing project with which I
was intimately involved which uses both
a combination of virtualization and
transformation to achieve this
sandboxing there was a another open
source project called jsrag which uses
mostly transformation in order to
achieve the same kind of effect and then
we have A J Scrambler with which Pedro
is intimately familiar which uses more
virtualization but essentially what we
have in our we have two tricks in our
toolbox to use to build
um to build isolation which is what we
are trying to get to now I'm going to
talk first about virtualization what is
virtualization well I call it
virtualization but we all already know
this as polyfills right uh what is a
polyfill you have features that are
provided by the browser
or sometimes you don't have a feature
that is provided by the browser you
implement it using other mechanisms that
are available
when you use virtualization for Security
even in cases where the browser provides
some particular capability you end up
replacing it so for example if you have
date this is the real date object
provided by the browser you might
provide a virtualized version well date
unless you care about timing attacks you
can just provide the original date
object directly to to third-party code
another case we saw in the in the
keynote uh a browser I'm going to name
the browser am I going to name the
browser ie6 which uses ActiveX ActiveX
was overly powerful if if a third party
had access to ActiveX there was a huge
number of things that they were able to
do and maybe you don't want to provide
access uh to to
um to ActiveX so you you never provide
this uh to third-party code but you can
also
an innovation where the ie6 also did not
provide a compatible xhr object but
ActiveX was able to implement
um was able to implement uh xhr and so
what you can do is Implement a version
of xhr on top of ActiveX and then via
the power of virtualization you hand
only a version of xhr to uh to
third-party code and you can even
provide a version of xhr that only
connects to particular proxies or
connects to only particular third-party
sites and therefore you're sort of
controlling exactly how much power this
third-party code gets
similarly you can virtualize the Dom you
can virtualize access to location you
can virtualize access to Inner HTML Etc
and you build up this way of controlling
not whether a script executes or not but
how much power the script has when it is
executing so that's virtualization for
control
there is another version where we use
transformation now this is easily my
most favorite slide Pedro gets a little
uh nervous when I get very excited about
this but essentially the only this is
the mechanism by which almost every
language based sandboxing control works
on the on the left hand side left hand
side my right hand side what you have is
the variety of functions that you're
going to call so you have alert which is
like a like a system call for for the
browser right these are functions that
are provided externally you have strings
which are types you have function types
and array types you have a variety of
primitive types which are provided by
the browser what you can do is transform
this and rewrite it so that each one of
those functions types and primitive
objects are instead
accessed only as a result of an argument
to a function so this is very simple
kind of transformation but if you think
about this this means that the caller of
this function controls everything that
is happening inside this function every
call goes by a uh is controlled by the
column and this basic primitive allows
you to essentially sandbox large pieces
of JavaScript now I know those of you
that are familiar with JavaScript I like
just as look there's all this eval that
allows you to break out of the sandbox
and there's ways of Walking Up The
Constructor chain there's ways of
walking up the Prototype train and
you're absolutely right but the basic
idea is this one and this is really I
mean it's a basic mechanism of
sandboxing and it fits on a on a single
slide and I think that that's one of the
reasons why it's power and simplicity
together mean it is the basic building
block of what we're going to end up
building you see how he gets excited
about this too if you you can come talk
to me after this I can talk about this
for ours
um can we do this for HTML and the
answer is obviously yes it's actually
even simpler for HTML because HTML is a
much simpler language and so you know
you can do a a a series of rewrites for
HTML uh on the um on on this side you
have styles and for CSS it's even easier
if you prefix every CSS rule with let's
say in this case uh dot gadget123 that
means that the scope of what is affected
is now limited to only uh the children
of uh of an element that has
um that has that particular class
overall what is happening here we're
turning we're not allowing or blocking
HTML we're not blocking or allowing CSS
we're not blocking or allowing
JavaScript what we're doing is
controlling how much access any
particular part of the code has access
to
um and this is a very powerful General
technique right you can you don't just
need it for uh visibility you can also
use it I mean you don't just use it for
control you can also use it for
visibility you can transform each one of
these functions such that all of the
access goes via one function that you
control and it can do a variety of
things in yesterday's talk I think JB
talked about uh
um how valuable observability is when
you're doing pen testing observability
or visibility as we end up calling it is
very critical because sooner or later
functions fail now you know this room is
filled with clever hackers and sooner or
later the foolish people who are
standing on stage who are building
sandboxes our code and our sandboxes end
up failing what is critical is not to
build sandboxes that remain absolutely
robust but build sandboxes such that
when the sandboxes fail you get
visibility you can to find out that the
attackers are in and so that you can end
up responding and virtualization ends up
giving you the same kind of control
um in general what is happening is
there's some general design principles
that we are using in order to build
these actually in yesterday's keynote
there was a a a slide that Alyssa
presented which as you as I go through
the the three principles
mirror the the the principles that she
was talking about as well Prince so
there's going to be three principles
it's visibility ease of use and control
um
compartment size let's say we are
building a ship one of the problems in
the Titanic was how small uh the the
unit of isolation is if you think about
all of the controls that we have
generally built
um
the controls are either you know the
size of the host or the size of a domain
or the size of a particular path in the
domain or the size of a particular file
or the size of a particular function or
in this in the case of J Scrambler
specific actions right and and you had
the other example of CSP like you either
allowed the whole script or you don't
you block it at all like you you cannot
have a smaller box for that exactly so
the the smaller the size of the
compartment the more control you have
over exactly how much functionality you
are allowing now there is a counter to
this which is the smaller the size of
each one of these compartments the
larger the number of
um the larger the complexity of the
configuration is going to be but we can
counter that by building additional
tools that make it easier to configure
these fine-grained compartments
the second thing if we go back to the
story of the Titanic that we need to
keep in our mind is the strength of the
isolation material now I'm stretching
the analogy a little bit but essentially
um when we build mechanisms for
isolation like iframes like csb
um if they are cut in the wrong
direction we end up having to drill
holes through them and like any
structure if you start out with a solid
structure but you continuously drill
holes you start out with a ship but you
build little
rooms into them so that they are able to
do what the functionality you require is
then you end up weakening the structure
in order to build the in order to
maintain the strength of the isolation
material in order to maintain the
strength of the isolation mechanisms
that we have we have to align with how
developers end up using the software
most of the mechanisms that browsers
provide were built for web 1.0 which is
a very different way in which
applications were being built then the
way in which we build applications today
and sooner or later developers come up
with ways of working around the the
isolation mechanisms that we provide and
the third one is of course visibility
and user friendliness this is very very
this is is a point that I was making
earlier what you don't know may end up
really hurting you you need to
understand the nature of the attacks
in order to understand exactly how
attackers and your users are responding
to to to to the mechanisms that you're
building I end up sometimes saying to
people developers are people too which
is sometimes not obvious to us uh the
user friendliness of the tools that we
build is a very critical part of uh
enticing developers to use our tools and
to use the tools in a way that
enhances the security of the application
rather than being something that they
need to work against
and we are back to our Cliffhanger so
basically we told you that the Titanic
implementation was flawed and this is
kind of a summary of some of the things
we already said like for the Titanic the
compartments were too big okay so they
would need to have smaller compartments
in order to be able to withstand more
compartments being completely flooded
because when you flood the compartment
you flood the whole compartment if the
hit is more precise maybe the the size
of the thing that you're flooding is
smaller and that makes you more
resilient the the materials so the
obviously it wasn't uh strong enough
because like you hit an iceberg so it
would if like if it was uh um made of
like stronger materials maybe could
withstand the hit uh the damage model
had the wrong assumptions uh or in other
words basically the threat model was
wrong was was flawed and last but not
least the lack of visibility because of
obvious reasons if someone had spotted
the iceberg in time they would not
collide with the iceberg so uh
visibility and analytics which are an
interpretation of what you're seeing are
very critical for avoiding these set of
problems
so now time for some demos
and before and to understand the
challenges we first need to understand
what we have been doing wrong so as as
for like browser security isolation
native security isolation features
things have moved slow and erratically
um like I said
we didn't have a feature one feature
that could provide the type of isolation
and user friendliness and like uh
flexible enough
um it has been mostly about
stitching together all of these features
that we talked about as for other
Solutions beyond the browser native
Solutions
there are very few Solutions out there
like Google kaha is a good example of a
analystic web isolation solution but
sadly it was discontinued which Jazz if
you don't know he was the lead of that
project back then at Google
um apart from kaha
there's web page Integrity the the one
the the project that we are doing
ah
so what does the next 20 years look like
given where we have come from what what
we need is a single holistic client-side
web solution that covers all of these
different angles uh that we've talked
about what we need is a sort of a broad
coherent plan
um and I think that those that plan will
come together Guided by these three
principles we've been talking about
limiting the size and granularity of the
compartments that we're building
providing making sure that each one of
these granular boundaries that we build
are solid and reliable and then
providing visibility and user
friendliness so on the one side making
sure the developers find these apis easy
to use but also have these apis provide
feedback so that as they are being used
not only do we know whether developers
are using them well but we also know
when attackers are bypassing them when
as we were making this presentation
Pedro and I joked about uh how do you
make a a ship that is actually
Unsinkable uh and uh I think Pedro said
you give it wings and you can take away
from that what you want uh I I wanted to
pull an example of uh of a feature that
was introduced into browsers that has
this particular characteristic so that
you don't walk away going oh this is all
doomed I have seen no progress uh Shadow
Realms was uh formalized and has made
quite a bit of progress in being shipped
out to to browsers this is an example of
something that I think uh demonstrates
the design features uh what a shadow
realm allows you to do is to create a
separate Enclave that you were able to
interact with uh but uh that you're able
to insert third party code into and then
it executes independently of the rest of
your code it has
um you know it's a very tiny little
isolation boundary it has strong
foundations the user friendliness is an
interesting question but it operates
mostly like an eval but the context is
controlled by the caller that means that
uh developers are going to be able to
much more easily roll out the use of
things like Shadow Realms and there are
other features like that coming into
browsers
uh like in the same way the WPI provides
all of these I think that you know other
browser features that are going to end
up having these kinds of characteristics
um
how far along are we well
large complex features like web
isolation take a long time to build and
they take a long time to bake as well
because what one of the things that we
want to be able to do is put features
into browsers that remain solid they
remain usable so that the next
generation of web applications are not
merely secure but also functional and
usable and it
characteristics like that take time to
bake
that's all we have for today thank you
we can take questions and at least for
the foreseeable future unless Twitter
goes crazier
we're also contactable
so thank you Jazz and Pedro for any
questions
a few more seconds three two one zero
okay thank you very much guys thank you
thank you
yeah I forgot
actually done yeah
[Music]