foreign
[Music]
hello uh so my name is Luis fonse I work
as a product security engineer at a bank
and I've been working with GitHub action
for a while and trying to secure some
some GitHub actions for some companies
and I've seen some
common patterns let's say and bad
designs that I want to bring some
awareness of and that's basically what
I'm going to do in this meeting in this
presentation so first of all
um I'm not going to be talking about
things like cicd top 10 or something
like that just common designs that I've
seen everybody implementing that had
some security implementations so I hope
it can be helpful for you guys
so first of all what is GitHub actions
so it's basically a CI CD tool from
GitHub where you can basically build
deploy test your your code
and it works basically like Jenkins or
or a bit uh bit bucket and so on and
um it has some nice features you
basically create uh definitions on on
the codes and it will run the CI for you
but this brings also some some
challenges mainly uh securing these
these pipelines
um so most of the things that I see are
basically on the on the cd part so on
the deployment and this is because you
either need to to deploy for example to
AWS or to Google cloud or something like
that and you need to have some kind of
permissions uh to to push your code
either credentials um Runners with with
whitelists and so on and there are a lot
of things that can go wrong here so
first of all you can basically uh
somehow leverage the secrets on on
GitHub
um you can compromise the machines that
do the deployment for you and from there
you can do a lot of privilege escalation
or lateral movements and I've seen for
example a case where a user have a
regular right access to a GitHub repo
and it got from there to an AWS admin uh
so that's that's how bad that can go and
let's hope that we don't see a lot of
those but it can go that way so um
first of all the most important part is
to understand how GitHub actions work
right so
as long as you have right permissions to
a repository you can basically run the
the pipelines the the actions itself or
the workflows and you can basically
change them as you want and do whatever
you want with them so
um
let me let me show you how you can break
with with all of those things
so first of all um
GitHub has a thing called secrets and
it's basically supposed for you to to
store your your passwords your
credentials there so that you don't hard
code them in the code but the name can
be misleading right so when you actually
have a secret you can extract that
secret you can dump it and although you
cannot do it from the UI it gives you a
false sense of security because if you
can actually control the action or the
workflow and for that you only need
right permissions you can basically
extract any secret configured in a repo
or in an organization so that's that's
mainly the the first thing that that you
see failing so a lot of companies create
secrets and store them most of them even
in organization level and you can just
create a random repository with no
permissions you create an action and you
have access to all the organization
sequence and it's just dumping all of
them quite easily so in this image you
have a definition of a workflow at the
left and at the right you have the Run
of that workflow and basically as you
can see if you try to do an echo of a
secret on GitHub uh GitHub will
automatically hide the secret from you
in the output
the issue with this is that GitHub is
basically doing a fine search and
replace so if you have a secret with a
value test and if you have a test in the
output GitHub will filter that word test
so if you start doing things like
basically for encoding it or print a
character in the space a character a
space or just a character per line you
can easily dump a secret obviously you
can do things much more complex like
doing requests to external web servers
to send the secrets but basically as as
long as you don't print the secret as is
you can basically uh print it in the
output
um and this is where it all starts right
so most of things are secured with
Secrets still and you can start dumping
them quite easily again
you just need the right access to the
repo uh Branch protections don't work uh
because as soon as you create a new repo
you can control the workflow and you can
change the entire workflow and put that
whatever you want and your version of
the workflow will run even before it's
merged to the default Branch to master
your Dev or wherever is the default
Branch so this is one of the most common
things usually one of the most dangerous
as well
so still on secret uh when you run the
workflow GitHub generates automatically
for you uh a secret called GitHub token
and this is a femoral so it only lasts
as long as your your action is running
so um the thing about this token is that
it has basically by default uh write
permissions to the repository that
you're working on so you can basically
call the API and do operations on on the
repo level so for example here
uh
you have Oh I thought I thought then I
have an example but here you can see uh
the default permissions on the workflow
which has read and write permissions and
you can also uh uh have the token to you
the token can also be used to to approve
PR so uh there was a security issue
reported uh while ago where
um Branch protections that had like a
minimal one approval for merging PRS
could basically bypass that by using the
GitHub token to to approve the pr and
merge it
so obviously you can also leverage this
token to do malicious things
it's it shouldn't be that necessary
because if you have right permissions to
the repo by default you don't need to
use this token but this gets more
interesting when when you start using
third-party actions right so basically
an action it's it's can be compared like
a library in a piece of code so it's
something that you import to do a
generic task or a common task and you
can send that GitHub token to to the
action to to do something for you for
example in this case we have a a
creation of a release in GitHub and you
need to to send the GitHub token for it
to be able to to call the API and do the
release process
so by default when you're actually
sending this GitHub token to the to the
action it will inherit all the the right
permissions that the token has right
um what can go wrong with with this is
that you don't know what the action is
doing and for example in this case you
you just have the the action tag to
version three but you can have multiple
version threes and the one lay the
latest one can do something that you're
not expecting for example and leveraging
that token for for something that it's
not supposed to so it's really hard to
control
um
what what the what the action is
actually doing
um unless you you for example pin it to
the commit to the committee and you
review that that got me to make sure
it's safe
um so one thing that you should do with
with with this so whenever you're you're
sending GitHub tokens to to third-party
actions
um you should always make sure that you
specify which permissions the token can
can have so there's a there's an option
on the workflows where you can say this
token will only have read permissions to
to the repo for example and uh you
should trim it down to to the basically
Essentials of what the the action needs
to to use the token for
uh I've seen I've also seen some some
common issues with the guitar tokens on
on malicious third-party actions that um
Leverage The the token permissions for
things that shouldn't be uh using it
okay
um in in this case uh we have an example
of running the
our workflow in your own Branch as I
said before so let's say that you have
branching policies uh branching rules in
place so that you need let's say two two
reviews to merge to master for example
and you have an entire workflow to push
to to production let's say and you're
quite confident that you have a secret
there and can't be dumped because uh you
need you need to two approvals to
actually merge the code so that's that's
not what happens and this is a a big
misconception and there there are a lot
of security issues also around this
because people don't understand that you
can create your own branch and just
change the workflow and run your version
of the workflow even before being
approved so approvals mean nothing code
owners don't do anything either so the
the workflows can always be controlled
by anybody with with right access to the
to the repo so here the same thing so
you have on the on the left side an
example of a change on on my own branch
and on the right you can see that the
changes that I did run and took effect
so another cool thing is the workflow
dispatch tag so this is something that
you specify on on the workflows and
basically mean that as soon as you add
this you can run the workflow from the
UI so by default you run workflows on
trigger events like when I do a push
when I do a PR on this case you can
basically manually invoke a workflow and
you can even specify user input if you
want to earn it and usually there's also
a common injection here when you when
you ask for inputs because they almost
always end up in in a shell script
but yeah so a thing about the workflow
dispatch is that you can run the
workflow dispatch also from any branch
that you want and uh a lot of times when
developers add this this workflow uh
Dispatch they don't have that in into
account so you can basically go to the
UI run a workflow on your own branch and
for example deploy a malicious version
of your code
another another issue with that is that
um I don't know if you can see it here
uh nope but basically
uh
let me
yeah so I think I have a line there so
when when you create this you need to
actually push this master to be
um you need to push a version a code or
a version of the code with a workflow
dispatch to master to actually show up
in the UI so if you don't have this in
the master Branch the first time you
don't have this option but as soon as
you put this option on on the main
branch it will show up in UI and you can
basically call the the workflow from
from any from any branch so all all of
these issues are can can happen because
when you work on an organization You're
Expecting to have some segregation all
right and some some restrictions about
permission so if if I have a team
working with repo a b and c I I don't
want them to have access to 2D and E for
example right because they shouldn't
have access to things they don't need to
do their work and when when you start
um thinking about all of these things
and and The Insider thread risk that you
have here most of the times companies a
member inside the company can leverage
all of these permissions and basically
take down a lot of things that they they
should not have access
okay another cool thing and that GitHub
implemented and it's somehow trying to
to help with the secrets it's the the
concept of environment so environments
allow you to Define like a set of rules
like you can say that a workflow will
only run
um on this specific Branch or for this
workflow to run I need two approvals
from x y and z
so that's interesting but the thing is
that you define which environments are
associated to the workflows in the
workflow file so if you own the workflow
file right you can just remove the the
environment tag and it's game over so
although environments work and you have
you have to be careful with that because
a cool thing also about environments is
that you can store secrets in
environment so instead of having Secrets
associated with the repo you can
associate them with the environment and
they are only injected in your workflow
if all the conditions in the environment
pass so let's say that I have a password
to deploy to AWS obviously you shouldn't
do this way but let's say you have
um on on an environment unless the
environment passes like with two
approvals and it's running from the main
branch the that secret will never be
injected into the into the workflow so
for environments to actually work you
need to have secrets and those Secrets
need to do something uh interesting
otherwise you can just remove the tag
and you bypass all the all the features
of environments and it's also a common
misconception that people add
environments with approvals and you just
go to the workflow and just remove it
so another nice thing and because I
think I think I made my point that
secrets are are hard to to manage on on
GitHub another thing is to use cell full
set Runner so by default when you run a
workflow it runs on on a container on
controlled by by GitHub right so they
have a this container is called Runner
by the way so you have a concept there
that is cell phones Runners and
basically you can configure your own
machine anywhere to run the the workflow
for you so for example if you configure
an an ec2 or some container on AWS it's
much cheaper than being running a a
runner on on GitHub so that's mainly the
main motivation to use cell phones
Runners most of the times but they have
some some cool advantages as well so
when you're using a self-hosted runner
you don't need to to have secrets on
GitHub because if you have a cell phone
server for example in AWS you can
leverage that and just
use the permissions that your Runner has
inside the AWS to do wherever you need
to but this also comes with some
challenges so if you do this you
basically have a back door to your
systems right so uh if I control the
workflow and I can run whatever I want
in my workflow I can basically control
the the cell phone server Runner which
can be a huge risk as well so there are
some pros and cons on on using cell
phone surrounders you need to make sure
if you use one you need to make sure
that you lock them down pretty pretty
well otherwise you'll have some issues
the cool thing is that when you when you
configure yourself with a runner it's
the cell phone surrender that
connects to GitHub and not the other way
around so that's why you don't need any
kind of permissions on GitHub so even
admin users don't control the runner by
itself just from the workflows
so having seen all of this uh let's see
some ways of of actually exploiting
GitHub actions and try to be silent
um so that you you don't get caught and
nobody sees what you're doing so
obviously there are tons of ways and the
imagination is the limit right but there
are some some interesting things of what
you can do to hide your tracks so in
this case
um you can see that I just run a
workflow and for each step in a workflow
GitHub prints what it's going to do so
in this case I'm pushing a version of an
extension that I have and you can see
basically all the code that it's being
run on the on the workflow so if you
change a workflow and add some malicious
code there it will be printed
as as the output of the step so what
what you can do is that you can find for
example a workflow that is calling an
external script
and you can change the external script
so you create your own branch you change
that script and you don't see anything
in the logs because if you if you're
just calling a script from the workflow
what you see in the output is that you
call the script you don't see the
content of the script right so and you
can start from there and you can create
even more complex things so for example
in this case uh this is yeah a little
bit complex uh for for trying to to be
quiet but the idea is that you have an
external server and you find a workflow
that is calling a batch script or
something and you create your own Branch
you change the the best script you add
your logic for example to to retrieve
some malicious code from a server and
after retrieving it you shut down the
server so nobody else can do the same
request and get the same code
and uh you basically run your your
script and you shut down the server and
you delete the branch so from there it
will be really hard to try to understand
what you did uh because you basically
deleted the branch with with the changes
on your script so it's it's not easy to
find these kinds of this kind of actions
and uh that's why you should always try
to limit the GitHub actions as best as
possible
and I have some tips for that as well so
first of all as I said before it's
securing the GitHub token so you can
basically specify the permissions that
GitHub token will have so when you're
sending it to a third-party action uh
they they cannot abuse that much of your
token
so another cool one
um is to is to specify which actions you
you allow to be run on your organization
on or you're on your own ripples uh if
you're doing this on your own ripples
it's not that that important because uh
probably nobody else will control them
right uh but when you're when we're
talking about organizations anybody can
just use any any third-party action and
there can be a lot of issues with that
so you should try to restrict which
actions can be run and you can even pin
them to specific commit ashes which is
the The best scenario here because you
can review those specific comments and
make sure there are no issues if you pin
them for a version uh I don't know if
you guys try this but you can just
delete the version that you created on
GitHub and create the exactly same
version with different codes so it's not
that worth it
okay
another one and I I cover that one as
well it's disabling the the pr approvals
permissions from the GitHub a lot of
companies have like one approval two uh
if it's just one it's critical because
you can basically bypass and merge to
master wherever you want
and that's basically it because I don't
have more time as well so questions
thank you Luis any any question for Luis
we have before our break
anyone
okay thank you that was easy thank you
thank you all
[Music]