[Music]
I coordinated this event as a student
and I pretty much did everything I like
to think a little bit of everything you
know competitions was handled by another
club and I try to you know oversee as
much as I could I organized them in a
you know in a fashion that was easier
for the workers but they did most of the
actual organization in-house so I wasn't
in the events creating the competitions
you know I have to give a lot of credit
to BC BC that did a great job of putting
together the competitions and the other
events you know drone hacking was
someone a department that did a good job
with that and then we also had a guest
from slippery rock who brought in his
own competition we essentially
coordinated so five in total with the
drone hacking being kind of like the
biggest war like that was like the main
event for this Wi-Fi hacking that we've
had before as well as the forensics
basically what our setup was here that
the army brought in they brought in a
drone and we had to take it over well
someone
controlling it and gain control of
ourselves so there's a few different
routes you can fill about that we use
technique where we just send packets to
the drone itself to be authenticated and
then we took over control tomorrow it
was a timed competition so whoever could
hack the drone ticket or a very classic
not so impatient fastest one and at the
end they did a had the head thing where
we're going to battle about to try to
gain control over a routine to their
side faster and the drone kind of acts
like a like a Wi-Fi like a home router
or access point yep so this access point
is essentially broadcasting looking for
someone to connect to it so when
someone's connected to it which is of
the person like running the
we were then try to disconnect them
essentially by hunters a few commands
that you follow with certain syntaxes
now you know it quiet or like you would
be connected to a network in this case
that network use the drone so you're
sending information back and forth and
with all those packets and then it will
attack
the packages that you send them to the
person that's connected to it are so
malicious and they're telling them that
that you need to disconnect from this
router
we're basically tricking their device
into thinking that the router is telling
them to disconnect so they disconnect
and that gives us the opportunity then
to take their place on that network the
University we got three drones to
practice this hacking and we're also
gonna look into doing forensics on the
drones - so now that this is over we're
going to take the drones and see you
know if someone flies them around and
then we capture it can we capture you
know their GPS coordinates or can you
capturing their video feed while they
were flying and just time see what's
there for us to be able to capture it in
the Friends of self
[Music]