okay hi guys index talk we are going to
talk about how to remotely exploit and
attack on seismological networks so
disclaimer before the talk is all bull
abilities until report to the US and
Europe cert to avoid any issue legal
problems and this is very important that
we are not responsible of any action
that anyone here can take off straight
and in this talk because we also we are
providing the source code to exploit all
the zoological networks so what we are
not talking about on the motivation and
the background we hand this research
basic introduction to system illogical
networks to understand better all
elements and topology of the network
they impact and then we are going to the
t-mo about the attack on penetration
inside the network this research has
been done with Burton burpees which is
in the a dot 8 in Chile right now myself
you see my name is James djarum we have
been at the DEF CON black hat echo
parian several international conference
we are from Costa Rica I don't know if
you know where it is located but this is
America as in drugs this is Latin
America we are a small small country
yeah it's not Puerto Rico because
everybody thinks Costa Rica is berto
Rico but it's not okay so which is the
motivation behind this research well an
average attacker is not interested
because this is like a scientific topic
so also because these are cool a
scenario and this means that these
devices are located maybe on the polar
cap hundreds of meters under the ocean
so if you denial of service over I'll
these devices
will be pretty expensive to a company to
make it work again also the school leads
into a financial sabotage to a specific
companies or countries so that's it that
is why the average attacker is not
interested this is more so kind of
Google government stock or red team's
this is an example of this is mecom
volcanic activity over the world so
basically we have sensors over all the
world there are a lot basics isma logic
terms which is the main purpose of the
seismic network is basically record the
earthquakes movements and waves they
want to find the location of the air
quakes they want to make sure the games
calculate the magnitude also they will
be processing and storing all these data
in different at concision servers across
the world this is one where certain
instruments danisha the wave of the
earth so they're common applications are
earthquake detection freaking and dealer
for oil and gas recovery except or
analysis of the earth mine safety this
is life is very important because the
sensors works also for oil and gas
recovery so there are companies that use
the same sensors for earthquake sections
in the research of oil and gas this is
how it looks they are really small and
we have the broadband sensor we have a
salam accelerometer and the geophone
which at the Bender's in this space we
have a lot of vendors but nano matrix is
claims to be the number one in the
industry and then we have the group
system or research is on top of this
to vendors the internal of each device
the internals they are an linux-based
they have a remote management system
they have several services like ssh
telnet event ftp they have a web server
which is injury they have an accurate
gps system and they contains a battery
or at least one year so what is todos
terrace is a portable digital cisco
graph because we have the sensor which
connect to the towers and tyrell sends
the data to the acquisition server this
is how it looks their deployment which
is pretty simple and the ocean water
deployment which is complex we are
talking about deployment of one month we
have a deaf butter which is the
marketing leader of nano metrics who
claims the instruments malfunctions
wherever it's in the bottom of the ocean
or a top polar icecap did that the data
will last forever so if they don't work
for all this one second they will lost
the data forever there is not another
way to recovery this is how the looks
the topology of pathologic networks we
have as I said before this is moment
which is a sensor and sends the data to
the digital portable and deeds will be
sending the data to the acquisition
server so inferior we will see how to
execute a man-in-the-middle attack holes
there is an organization in search of
all related to this political neighbors
which is the international federation of
digital system agra they have out
several books and reference manual will
help us to understand how it works all
network especially the seat manual which
is the most important because this is
the protocol that they are using to
exchange the data so talking about a
little the impact on on the real war we
discovery that these devices are located
in any part of the world but they have a
lack of security in all sense so
basically all the different points of
failure are vulnerable so I have a
question here what if an earthquake
we're checking the city of Madrid and
even being a hugs this will be having an
impact of the economic of the country so
that is possible right now we have
another example which is involved a lot
of money what if the company modifies
the sensors of other company which is
researching specifically in space we
which have oil and gas that is a
possible environment also and this one
which is a more critical and what if a
data consistent servers contains faked
data corrupted data so we are wondering
if the predictions will fail because we
have an example here here about the
scientific is who get jailed because
they did not predict correctly another
quake so what happen if the data on the
acquisition servers get corrupted well
this cool having so yeah to stalk
basically this political networks are
pretty big so I have tried to give you
an idea about the different elements so
we are going to attack them penetration
all the system basically how the process
of printing how we discovered these
devices so let's see
we are using LED TV I 0 which is an IOT
search engine is root 3 so anyone can
try this is different than challan which
has Alvis in syntax we have query
builder syntax which is very easy to use
we have several operators and ssl
operators especially on geolocation
operators but for this case we will use
headers which the key will be sober and
the value will be terrace
so those are the results of this query
as we can see they are locating here
from here so this is how we discover
these devices and we have many
fingerprints that we can get to see what
what contains as you can see here a
little is visible we have the jury the
line looks and different fingerprints
so as you see that is how we find the
tablet devices but this is from the UI
we have on a script which will be
provided to anyone which will be
searching / Zuma sober strollin an
auburn atv to get all the towels devices
of the world so as I say contains Jerry
contains Linux we have the version to
execute anything we want also we get the
field where how we get it we're looking
google but it's not available so we send
an email to the nemetrix an order
vendors um I don't know why they the
replying or email with the finger that's
crazy but we have the finger so you get
a study Hubbard the finger but one week
later we get another email from nano
matrix this case which says nanometric
software can only be provide to register
your customers and i do not see the
organization registering or customer
database but ok we will use ignore
decimal ok coming back to the seat man
I'll deceit reference manual is very
important because this is only way we
can reproduce the package which is the
standard of exchange of earthquake data
so sit protocol how do you work the SIP
protocol we have four sectors the first
one didn't work out the station code
because we can have several devices in
the same sector a location ID and
channel coach also for group system is
pretty easy to find these devices using
again LED TV but looking inside the
certificate ssl metadata
and this is a not that common quarry but
it's a really good to search data inside
the certificates for the case of Chillon
is available I'll also need to be so
it's pretty cool to search rather than
busca de looking of the headers looking
inside the certificates so with which
tools we used to start looking what
services has each each device we have on
the script which collects the IP so
worldwide that is one and we have fun
under the scripts will be a scanning all
the parts of each device so let's see
so this is pretty simple as you can see
we are looking over shut down and they
are different scripts of an ATV on to
hang alerts so this will be create a
file then we will use as can devices and
this will be just our map looking for
each IP and will return all the option
parts of each IP
so we can see here on output of all I
piece which is are a lot of hype is so
all this appease our only tablet devices
and this is a friend of Costa Rica which
is helping us to look the end map
devices maybe you know who is so
basically which are the common parts we
are talking about the surface of telnet
SSH and HTTP server we have also n
script to get an image about our highly
looks all these devices so we have
worldwide map contains all continuous
all all the screenshots of the web
application and let me show you how to
hide looks so this is how he looks at
out this device yeah is that that is
pretty simple we have graphics about HUD
HUD what is happening the waves etc also
we execute fussing web technique however
the jerry server and it crashed it crash
out which because this devices dozen
contains too much memory and which is
very sad very sad javaserver it's pretty
easy to crush it they have a lot of
information disclosure issues every word
this doesn't have any kind of security
going back to think where analysis we
had cell looking for the root password
inside the files and we decoded we have
also discovery a back door there is not
an official user documented which is
called factory as you can see here in
the image we have central text and user
the factory is not documented in any
place
anywhere of the documentation of nano
metrics so everyone can use it also when
we get inside the system of any of this
device essential come auto kind of
vulnerabilities and available the idea
is to take a malicious users protect
perfected to protect your data what is
it with we always say to all the vendors
because we can now execute a
man-in-the-middle attack so let me show
you
for this case we have a video because we
cannot execute this and real because
cold will cool it into any legal problem
so a friend sent me this video yeah so
we are on going to the streaming option
for this case this could be by a script
but for presentation purpose we are
doing from the front and each device has
the exactly position in the world so we
are looking for
you
so as you can see this device is in the
middle of the ocean
you
the video is is lovely okay so there you
have this is near to here and now we are
going to the settings of the device
especially to the configuration
so we are going to the data streaming
options we will assign you dps reveal so
as you know which this is using UDP will
be pretty easy to do IP spoofing also we
are going to add a new streamer we are
setting or a target IP this is an
observer destination server so now we
are in the destination server and we
will start getting all the data so as
you can see we are getting all the
packets this is on n/p format
and now we are redirecting the data of
course we are not presenting this data
for the data acquisition circle because
this will lead into a very big issue
right so as you can see all the package
sang taek's plane there is nothing using
SSL communication or anything like that
there they are not out ten tific ating
the data also so you can set up right
now here fake device and they start
sending data to the acquisition server
so basically the protocol works like
this is not real this is just a visual
propers but they have sent in latex
latitude longitude and altitude so we
can modify all this data pretty simple
we can use a spoofy for example so I at
the end we have on the script which will
connect to each IP and will execute any
comment this will be doing in a massive
exploiting way so for this we recommend
to disable your ssh holds a key shaking
feature and then you will need to have
an IP txt file with all the pieces and
execute parallel ssh zeros so for
example we can execute all these
examples for shell shock you name to see
which server is we call or even opping a
reverse SSH or even use a framework to
end do anything inside so
so for example as you can see here this
screen you need the parameter with the
text it is the eyepiece and the comment
so we will execute your name
so there is or any comments possible
I am executing this over one single IP
because I don't want to make anything to
the network
well something songs sometimes fails
that is the Karma because I I know why
well that's just another example we can
execute any kind of comment to the all
network with with within a single comma
and the code is pretty simple is we are
using parallel SSN clients so um I will
release all this source code but i am
not releasing the password so if you
want get the finger start the password
and that's it so you can see in this
line we are reading the password from
other file to avoid any kind of leaking
this information because this is pretty
sensitive so at the end we execute a
clean a clean comment overall the
network just to you know avoid any
problems so conclusions and we were able
to locate this device anywhere in the
world also we are in control of the
device this is one mirror and the data
acquisition server basically anything
all the infrastructure there is not ssl
communications over the data finally
vendor splits called better and thinking
security that's it thanks a lot the
presentation
there's 15 minutes left so any questions
it seems the web interface is not
authenticated or did you use the
backdoor user for the web UDP adding the
streamer for the case of in this case is
not authenticated but well in this case
it is or look okay only not but as you
can see in the in the image that we have
in the last slide they are showing all
the template users so we can use any any
of them for example we have central and
this is a pencil central is the password
so does it and you can login so you can
see we are inside my unsuccessful okay
thanks welcome any other questions do
you know if these devices I've been used
in recent de dos attacks against obvious
well that's a common question but we can
do a do that but they are not good
strong for this task because in fact you
can set the target IP four and streaming
and if you control a fair number of
these devices and point to the same
target they will receive a huge amount
of publix and the details against Josh
was probably this kind of attack here
well the thing is that these devices are
not to a strong to create a de dos
attack so I don't think that will work
they are like they don't have enough
memory you can do added us over a single
device and he will die soon as possible
so i have a question actually could
determine the attacker
brick all of these devices remotely at
scale if they can a break home devices
at the same time yes of course with this
script they can do it for example if all
these devices are in the ocean bottom
and you create on the script and you
will disconnect the interface that's it
everything will be disconnected and that
means a lot of money a lot of money all
right if no further questions let's say
thank you to James thank you