yeah finally so tomorrow morning hi ever
talk at eight-forty-five it's got re in
the morning so I want to make some
teasing to help you wake up and at'em my
talk ok so for today so I will not go
into the details of bed meta brick but i
will show you what we can do with it for
instance here in the circle some people
are developing a tool to krys v cv data
basil locally stored on your computer
and so I did write some weeks to to play
with the severe search so in meta brick
when we want to play with something you
search by tag I want to play with
several search and you see you do have
two bricks which are speaking about
severe search so one of the first step
to do is to install dependencies for the
brick you want to use here I want to
install dependencies for apiic view
search so it has followed password and
those who did in it is installing some
open two packages and some perl modules
I said it I said the word it's burn and
so the rig is now ready to be used and
okay great what can I do with this brick
I just call her help of the brick and as
you can see you have a few bunch of
commands you can use we start with such
TBF oh so here in fact it's creating the
API available on the Civil stats website
so here we are online it's a REST API oh
no no magic here you can create a
vailable API for instance if you bros
you can get the list of vandor you can
suffer it because it's ultimately
automatically piped in the less stuff so
okay you're such a stuff what do you
have you see you of completion so if i
do tab here it shows me what which
comments are available i want to fetch
late latest addition to the base so it's
less last comment so you have all the
link all of that in fact is saved in a
variable which as the name of the run
command so you can play with it again
and couldn't the number of entry you
have because it's a hash not this one is
our okay so if i want to couldn't it's a
result one all right
ok so I have to look again at my
restructure its results with es ok so I
gather results ok now I kind couldn't
remember ok so the research results were
just for the day moment as you can see
once you have a result from the canal
you can play with the result of the
canal like two lights it's a Python
shell but it's a Porsche so you have
another database another brick for
severe such its database if you search
what can you do with it again you have
some commands you can run whenever then
is easy install there is a command to
use the source code of a break sometimes
maybe you may be interested in in seeing
what you have inside so in a brick you
have some properties which basically
defines some commands some attributes
and the required modules to run and you
have the needed packages to run it so
for civil search you have to install
python 3 by telling people to install
dependence and thanks to the insulin and
it's done for you there is a brick that
will just fetch as the git repository
three minute ok perfect and once the git
repository fetch it will automatically
call a peep tree install through to
fetch an installer requirements after
that you have command to in its database
I just followed the guide online on how
to install civil search on you will
local desktop and I will follow that so
it's calling a Python script once terms
of stuff you can update that obeys
repopulated at a base and of course
they're from some search so again I want
to call the damp last to see which were
the last addition to my local database
ok so we have a variable with stuff I
want to get more information on the sea
ezel I just consider search and it's a
number so okay I do have all the
information well that's how civil such
works you can create your local database
so there is no nothing new here but
maybe you are well that severe search
stores data in a reduced or MongoDB
database so maybe you just want to play
with directly with what is written in
the ridges database or just go program
you want to list databases ah it helps
me d tells me that I have to connect
first so okay I'm connected to the local
database I do have two databases and I
want to list all the keys of you have
you have to know that DB 12 if you want
to create it you have to call it 12 but
that's ready and now it dumped the
complete content of the Ready Set abase
you have whatever we want the same is
true for mongodb for instance because
some data storing a MongoDB database so
you use an ungodly stuff what can we do
help you have all the apps you want
again you want to list available
databases so I have to connect first and
you have three local databases in
MongoDB database as collections one
minute some collections so now I want to
list collection names from the CVE gb so
I have all the collections but I want to
dump the content of a collection so now
I call another criminal call get-get
database collection find all cvd be and
I will dump for instance NS so it takes
some time so now I turned the complete
content of what story in the MongoDB
database and it's safe listen to do our
random variable so you can play with it
again and do whatever
want with it let's meet a break tomorrow
morning 845 thank you