his Clarence thank you hi okay hi I'm
Clarence thanks for thanks first thing
for this talk so I just want to get a
quick poll of the audience how many of
you have used machine learning before
have played with it like taking classes
or something oh yeah it's good number so
today I'm going to be talking about how
to bypass machine learning systems
machine learning has been has been in
the in the news and in everywhere in
tech over the last two to five years I
did a quick crawl off RSA and black hat
the expo floor you know how companies
always have to publish some snippets
about what they do and I was just
looking for how many companies claim
they were doing something in the area of
machine learning or deep learning or
data analytics to solve security
problems so this is just a particular
instance of a company that claims to do
like deep learning for for mail or
detection and apt attacks that was
interesting so over the years you can
see the the number of instances that
companies have claimed to do machine
learning as in security i think is
pretty interesting from twenty twelve to
twenty fifteen there was pretty much a
6x increase and 2016 is it's a bit lower
maybe because people realize that it's
it's not that easy so this is a neural
network i I won't spend too much time
going to detail about what a neural
network does or how it works exactly you
can find it online yourself but
basically the idea is that you have a
standard infrastructure consisting of
input units and hidden layers and an
output layers and activation functions
which are each one
the small circles there and each one of
these units is connected to each other
by by a weight and so when you want to
find the output of a neural net all you
have to do is to check which activation
functions are actually activated and use
and then you would result the result
would be this output vector called
logits and then you would basically feed
it through a softmax function to get the
prediction and so neural nets are all
about distributing blame so during the
training of the model when you feed in
data when you get a wrong prediction
during the training phase you would
basically go through the model do it in
the process of back propagation to
assign blame to see which units were
were responsible for making this wrong
decision and so when you find a units
that make the wrong decision then you
would basically reduce the amount of
decision-making power that they have by
decreasing their weights and biases by
the upper body appropriate amount to how
much they contributed to this wrong
decision and of course you can do this
efficiently with optimization algorithms
such as stochastic gradient descent
which you may have heard of in other
machine learning algorithms as well so
the main focus on my of my presentation
will be how to bypass this if there any
questions about how this works at all
i'll be going to further detail this is
not just about bypassing deep learning
system it's also about bypassing just
any general machine learning algorithm
which i will go into detail later i have
a quick demo here on how to bypass in an
image classification and gene which is
one of the most classic deep learning
problems the the thing is that there's
this data set called the CFA are 10 and
what this is a stress 60,000 images that
are very small 32 by 32 pixels and they
each belong to one of ten classes so I
chose randomly two classes here a dog
and an automobile or a car so
what I have here is basically two kinds
of images than the normal and the
adversarial and so I pre-trained a model
that would well recognize this properly
so if I if I try to evaluate what this
what this image is it's a dog you can
see from the from the image on the right
that it is a dog but if you see here dog
f10 also looks like a top it's a little
bit more noisy but you know it still
looks like a doctor to you and me if we
actually run this through the same
evaluation algorithm it says it's a ship
so that's weird right and so this is
just a standard pre-trained model that
you can download from tensorflow and you
can see that you can generate images
that trick these models that are trained
using Google's own engines they have
been trained using gpus for thousands
and thousands of hours things that I
would not be able to afford on my own
AWS account similarly for the automobile
just to show you again it's a car I run
than the normal image it says it's an
automobile and I ran the other one it
says it's a Pepsi okay so you see it
looks it looks slightly different but it
says the cat so that's just some small
example we'll dive into each of these
images and see exactly what is different
exactly how we're generating this later
let's open up a Python console and let's
look into how these images are different
for each other
sometimes importing the standard
libraries i'm going to read in the
normal dog image just going to be a 32
by 32 x 3 vector because there's RGB
values so you can see it's nothing
nothing unexpected you see the shape is
32 x 32 x 3 and the minimum value is 0
and the maximum value is 255 as expected
so the values for r g and b brain from 0
to 255 ok so what we're going to do now
is to read in the adversarial image so i
want to read in the adversarial image
and ok so this is what ever it may look
like we're going to take the diff of
these two and see how different they are
same shape
ok so the tip is just minus 1 to 2
pixels difference and and yet we can
make the model make a wrong prediction
or a run classification so let's save
this diff and let's see what what the
diff actually looks like ok
and the difficulty shows up here so we
can see it it's just rubbish it's a
rubbish vector that we can add to an
image to make the model make a wrong
decision yeah so same thing for the
other one doc f10 is is another example
of an adversarial image that is
generated in the same in the same method
and the difference between da f 1 and f
10 is just how big the perturbation is
so how many pixels it differ from the
original image and the reason why we
want to change the amount of
perturbation between the original image
and adversarial images because when you
alter an image x 1 pixel for each color
value then it's not that easy to be
detected by by a human but if you if you
change it by like say 10 pixels then
it's more possible that the human will
be able to tell that something weird is
going on with it but the reason why you
would change you would change an image
by a larger amount is because it's more
likely for you to trick a machine
learning model that something is
actually different so as you can see
that the diff is is much larger now and
we'll go on so i'll go ahead and explain
how these attack works and and why they
work but first of all let's look at the
kinds of attack that you can have on on
machine learning models in general there
are three kinds of attacks you can have
positive attacks and exploratory attacks
closet if attacks just means that you
have access to the training the training
stage so in training a machine learning
model what you usually have in a
supervised case is you have a bunch of
input data and you want to train the
model to do something that is that you
do not explicitly program rules for and
this could be the example of if you have
a thousand images of ten classes as you
see as you see before then you have you
have 600 images of each class and you
would basically train the model to
recognize each one of these models and
recognize their characteristics the the
kinds of pixels that make up a dog and
the kinds of pixels that make up a shit
and then you basically go on and go on
to the training phase after the model is
strained after the model is trained to
go into the testing phase and then he
will feed it unseen data and see if it
actually generalized as well and makes
the right decisions the exploratory
phase is the export area text are more
interesting because you don't actually
have to have access to the training
phase so this is applicable in most
instances let's say you have a an online
Google Translate service that famously
uses machine learning models to to learn
from to learn from its past mistakes and
to make better predictions as time goes
on you do not you don't actually have
access to the training phase because
most of the time when machine learning
models are the plot in a while they
aren't they don't take in general and
public input in immediate training most
of the time you just get the results and
then the training is done separately
after the data is cleaned so you can
still attack models like that by just
crafting input samples that are more
likely to trick these models and then of
course you also have the other kind of
attack which is analogous to to just
DDoS attacks basically we're trying to
decrease the reliability of these
classifiers and to make them more
unreliable you want to make everything
for example be classified as a ship no
matter what it looks like so why can we
do this the reason that you can trick
machine learning models because they
don't learn like that like how humans
learn and this might be surprising to
too many people even those working in
the field even those who are very
familiar with machine learning when you
see that classifier successfully
predicts so successfully classifies
images within ninety nine percent
accuracy then you kind of think that
these classifiers are recognizing ships
and dogs and cats
the same ways that humans do but they
actually don't so what classifiers and
deep learning models do is they just
look for characteristics in the pixels
that happen to be common among among
images of the same class and humans
don't think like that for example when
we look at a dog even if the the color
of the dog were different even if there
were a large pixel differences from all
examples of dogs that we've seen before
in the past we're still able to
generalize well and look for certain
characteristics of the image there are
more high level that we're able to draw
general associations from and concluded
that is still a dog so this is this is a
this is an important thing that we
should take note off no matter what
we're designing classifiers for we
should make sure that the true positives
are real positives and there can be
false positives in any predictions that
these machine learning models make so
basically the intuitions for Hari
generate examples for adversarial deep
learning are you run an input model you
want an input sample through the
classifier model if you don't have
access to the classifier model let's say
you are trying to do it for a an online
malware classifier that you don't know
what models are using you don't know
what data they used to train the model
then you just have to use a substitute
model which are going to later the
second step is to based on the model
prediction derive a perturbation tensor
or vector or matrix that maximizes the
chances of Miss classification so I'll
go into more detail about how to do this
later and the third step is to scale
this perturbation tensor by some
arbitrary magnitude the larger magnitude
you scale this by the more chance you
have of tricking the machine learning
model the smaller magnitude you you tune
this by the smaller chance you have of
tricking the machine learning model but
also the smaller chance that human
looking at this input will realize that
something wrong is going on so the most
simple way that we can generate this
adversarial images is to basically
traverse the manifold and find blind
spots in input and what this means is
just let's say you have a 32 by 32
pixel matrix and you're trying to look
for misclassifications of an adult image
so what you can do is to just brute
force to change each each pixel one by
one increment each value from from 0 to
255 and just make small small
perturbations in the input to find out
which image of a dog with would be
misclassified by this model and this is
this is okay the people used to do this
in the past but it would take a long
time especially if you're looking at
larger images we're looking at malware
classification for example then
typically you have to change millions
and millions of bytes and it's just a
combinatorial explosion so to optimize
this search you can take the input of
the target with respect to that target
output class which is what inspired the
next the next method which is linear
adversarial perturbation so if you can
think of a neural network as basically a
black box when you have input and an
output and basically what you're trying
to do is to feed in inputs that would
result in a different output from the
previous input of the same class and
then you would take the cross the cross
entropy of the input sample and the
predicted class and this can be done
without the actual model as well but you
have to create a substitute model in
order to get access to the inside
parameters it's easily fun bye bye that
propagation and I have some sample code
on this on a repo that I published
online and you can play of it yourself
to find out how it works and to see if
you can generate adverse our samples for
arbitrary machine learning classifiers
yourself the last method is is a little
bit more complicated and the motivation
behind this method is simply to reduce
the amount of perturbation that you have
to add to a to a valid input in order to
trick the machine learning model the
basic idea is that you are you want to
try to find points in this in this input
vector that will allow you to make small
changes to the input but then result in
a larger change to the to the output so
this is a example
all salience II met which is what we
call the measure of how much each pixel
actually affects the output result as
you can see in the in the center of the
image you actually have the largest
salience II which means that if you
change a pixel if you change the pixel
in the center of the image by a value of
one it's going to affect the output with
a higher probability than if you change
a pixel by the value of one on the very
edge of the image which kind of makes
sense because of you if you think about
it just most of the time they contain
backgrounds most of the time it's not
important things that will result in a
difference in the classification so
we'll go on to the threat model
basically this is the different kind of
things that you have the two given the
different kinds of knowledge that you
have in each attack scenario the most
easy way to attack something is if you
have the model hyper parameters if
you're training a neural network for
example if you know the kinds of tools
that we use to Train it the the
frameworks that we use a train it each
value of the weights in this neural
network and the activation function
values the biases for example and then
if you have slightly less information
you only have access to the architecture
you for example know that this is train
of a neural network it's a three layer
on your own net for example and then
slightly less data you have only access
to the training data and even slightly
less examples you have it's basically a
black box so all you have is the ability
to input stuff into this classifier and
then you can see the outputs and we can
see that in this case you can still
generate you can still generate adverse
or examples so to trick these models so
this is just a study of what people have
done in this area in general the efforts
in a veteran machine learning have been
have been pretty having pretty scattered
there's not a lot of a lot of new
developments which is why I started
talking about this thing because I feel
like the security industry needs to look
at machine learning models since a lot
of the critical infrastructure will be
shifting to machine learning in the
future for example self-driving cars
medical devices and image recognition
speech translation all of the
are powered by machine learning and soon
as sooner or later we'll be relying on
these more than we would like to and the
thing is that a lot of these are not
very reliable if if someone were to go
in and try to temper of such a system
you can find that they can easily be
tempered some medical imaging devices
that try to find for example if a cell
in a patient is banana is benign or not
by looking at the x-ray output can be
easily fooled by something like that and
you can see that there can be dire
consequences they've been examples
online and papers published on how deep
learning engines used by self-driving
cars can be fooled by images that are
just held up by a person with a green
light even though there's a red light in
real life but the the models this sees
the green light or sees a red light with
a slight perturbation and things that is
not a red light and then it is proceeds
so you can see how this will result in
human loss of life or are other dire
consequences and this is why i think
that the security industry needs to
start to audit these these statistical
methods need to start looking at how
reliable and how tamper-proof these
machine learning models are so what can
you do with limited knowledge in most
real-world systems we don't actually
have access to the model parameters we
don't have access to how the model was
actually trained or what input was
actually used to this so a lot of the
time you can make good guesses and this
is kind of a black art but as you come
as you come into contact with more and
more systems that are using machine
learning you can you can make some some
good guesses for example image
classifications the state of the art
would be convolutional neural nets and
if you can guess that an image
classification is done by convolutional
neural net then you will be able to
generate adversary examples that are
more accurate speech recognition they
are done using lstm and recursive neural
networks a lot of the time anything
that's there's a do with temporal inputs
are trained using long short term memory
networks and recursive neural networks
if you're looking at more general
purpose machine learning frameworks like
Amazon machine learning or any kind of
machine learning as a service
then a lot of the time because they have
to generalize well you're looking at
very shallow networks since having a
deeper network will result in more
probable overfitting so that's if you
can guess but what if you can't guess or
you're not very sure of the guess you
can still you can still own it so I have
a second demo here to show captures are
one of the most interesting ways that
are most commonly used to differentiate
a human from a bug right so most
websites you go to if you want to tell
that it's a it's a real human that you
would put a capture there and obviously
there have been many services online
like that by capture that you can pay
for maybe a few cents for for a thousand
capped resolved to helped with your
automation but this is not very scalable
because like how many people are willing
to sit down at the computer solving
CAPTCHAs all day for for one dollar a
day so it's not very practical and it's
a it's a matching problem so excuse me
so there have been solutions out there
that use deep learning to solve these
these things and so this is an
open-source example it's called capture
crusher it's pretty good I didn't write
this this is this is just something
online and this is just a tool that I'm
using to generate captures pretty pretty
generic captures they are not the most
complicated captures but as you can see
the complication that the complexity of
the other captures doesn't actually
matter this is what the model actually
looks like and so I won't go into into
detail I cleaning the model but what is
basically doing is to predict the actual
is is to show the actual labels for for
this input and then and then show the
prediction and we're going to show that
this actually does solve captives with a
certain degree of accuracy in most real
cases especially since you don't have
access to how the captors that you're
seeing online are actually generated you
can't train a perfect model for for
solving something like that so
there'll be there'll be high accuracy
but but there will be still things that
you get wrong depending on what the
characters look like let's generate some
captors here we generate at ten you can
see they look like pretty generic
captors I think they're pretty
complicated and I might get some of
these wrong if I were looking at these
and try to type them out yeah there's
generated more so I'm deleting them and
I'm gonna show that you can actually
generate captures that trick this model
that solves captures using deep learning
so it's kind of it's kind of a matter
because what we're doing is there's a
deep learning model train to solve these
captors and we want to generate Capra's
that can trick this deep drilling model
so it doesn't successfully solve
captures so this was the training of the
model you can see training deep learning
models are our kind of they take a long
time especially if you're looking at a
little bit larger images I started on
July 12 at 553 a.m. and by the time the
model finish it was realized our team
from 9am so it took took a long time i
did this online on amazon GPU clusters
so it is cost up 120 dollars so it
better work well and let's try it out
and we're evaluating this model for now
from this 10 captures that that we that
we just generated just to see then it
may omit the right decisions okay it's
going to wait for it to dissolve it's
taking some time this is already pretty
fast i guess it's it is faster than
using like that i capture or online
services with a human behind the
computer ok so i predicted all of them
correctly this is this is lucky like if
you if you generate more more images
sometimes they'll be like point 9
accuracy so let's let's look at one of
them must look at the the first one so
the first one you see I actg be
and the prediction is right and so let's
look at this actual image it is I ECT gb
yeah so what we're going to do now is to
generate the adversarial version of
these examples so they're going to look
similar to the original image that the
this framework can solve very well but a
human is still going to be able to read
them correctly but the deep learning
model is not so we're going to generate
these images these are this the same pan
captors and what we're doing is we're
running it through a substitute deep
learning model that I wrote that is
different from the original capra
framework that's used to solve these
these things so this is a substitute
model is an example of a black box so
what this does is just five lines of
code that generates this that's a bet in
a code base that i'll be releasing
online that i've released online and so
you see this is the normal example and
this is the adversarial example they
look alike it's slightly different if
you look at the difference the first one
you can really tell at all which means
that the pixel differences are actually
in a white space and the human eye is
pretty bad at at differentiating white
and slightly off-white so that's
probably why and so if you do an
evaluation of the adversarial examples
you see that it doesn't perform nearly
as well as with the original examples
and let's just run these go to a couple
minutes
naw couple months couple seconds and so
it's going to give me a score at the end
and it's going to show me at each
position in this CAPTCHA there are six
there are six digits in each capture how
many got right so let's see a position
one it only got one out of the 10 right
president to only got two out of the 10
right at position 3 it actually got
seven out of 10 right so but the thing
is that we've captures as long as you
get one out of the 10 one out one out of
six digits wrong then you'd be blocked
so we can see that these actually look
the same to a human we'd be able to
solve them but it successfully tricks
the deep learning model so only an elder
in a presentation I mentioned something
about transferability I basically these
attacks are not only applicable to deep
learning models they are applicable to
all kinds of machine learning models
these are some examples of pressuring
models that have been studied for
example linear classifiers spectral
clustering algorithms support vector
machines there's decision trees the
thing is that and this is the one open
research problem as to why this happens
but adversarial samples are generated
using deep learning have a pretty good
chance of fooling a previously unseen
model even if it's a totally different
model train using totally different
things and in a totally different
infrastructure you can see that this is
a matrix of adversarial samples are
generated using one technique and test
it on a different machine learning
technique so on the y-axis you have the
the adversarial generation method and on
the x-axis you have the technique that
is used to test these adversarial
samples you can see that L R stands for
linear regression and svm stands for
support vector machines if you train a
adversarial sample on a logistic
regression and you test it on the
support vector machine which is totally
different in terms of instructor and the
math behind it even then you see that it
has successfully tricks the model with a
ninety-one percent accuracy which is
pretty good and the neural networks are
just a
easy way of training models since you
don't have the mettle of too many model
parameters and stuff and substitute
models are another thing that we can use
to train adversarial samples on a black
box model that we have never seen before
basically you want to treat the new
models input with the output labels of
the of the previous model and you are
training a new model based on the a
model that you don't have access to
which which is why it's called a
substitute model and why is this much as
possible so transferability as i
mentioned before is still an open
research problem the fact that you can
trick machine learning models is because
there are many blind spots in the data
when when you train a classifier to
learn something it is not learning
everything about a dull or it cannot
possibly classify every single image
that exists of a dog as a dog correctly
because there are certain blind spots
that this model learns so there's this
model versus reality dimensionality
mismatch and people sort the question is
this model actually not learning
anything meaningful at all so what this
means is that when you whenever you
deploy machine learning models you
should use with caution in especially in
critical deployments where there's where
there's human life at stake or when
there's large financial loss at stake
you shouldn't make false assumptions
about what the model learns and you
should always evaluate how resilient a
model is in adversarial in the face of a
visceral attacks and you should spend
efforts to make models more robust so
how the most straightforward one is to
basically generate adversarial samples
for machine learning models and then
train your model using these adversarial
samples basically are trying to iron out
any kind of imperfect knowledge there
are other techniques that can be used
like distillation which means you train
the model two times first feeding the
first feeding the original images into
into the first model and then you train
the second model with a with the output
of the first model and this helps to
distill the amount of information that
is stored inside a neural network this
was initially used to reduce model sizes
they can fit on your mobile phone for
example because if you train on a large
GPU cluster there will be many many did
you need many many dead units that are
not actually used in the actual
prediction and you can also use other
methods like using loss function and
regularization techniques so the honing
is say is a is something that I that I
release at Def Con this year and
basically it aims to be the metas plot
of machine learning so what it has it's
basically some some structured code on
how you can generate machine learning
some generate adversarial samples on
machine learning models and basically
you can input your own machine learning
models the with with your own
infrastructure and then use standard
techniques for generating adversarial
samples that these that is a framework
provides and it's pretty well documented
I think there are some links to data
sets and papers that are used and also
other sources of code that you can use
so please check it out just play around
with it and and if you want to help
contribute to it they'll be w it so I
think that a nutrition testing of
statistical models and machine learning
systems is it's important because as I
mentioned before more and more of the
time were relying on these systems and
we a lot of people don't have a good
understanding of how these things work
so having a good understanding as what's
required to really evaluate how
resilient these models are too
adversarial input and you should train
these models with adversarial samples
for increased robustness so please play
everything contribute there's this a
last interesting note that i think is an
interesting research area deep learning
and privacy is an interesting area that
has been up and coming in the past few
years basically there have been
researched as that's done that shows
that you can reconstitute training
samples from a train black box model so
if you can think about a facial
recognition
engine that that recognizes your face
and in my face and these models are
stored on in a mobile phone for example
researchers have shown that you can
regenerate the faces that I use the tree
in this model pretty pretty easily just
by access to dance with access to these
models which are distributed to every
month devices so can we precisely
control the learning objective of these
models can we train the model without
having complete access to training data
these are interesting research questions
I think have to be solved before we can
actually rely heavily on on machine
learning in everyday systems so this is
important because more critical systems
rely on it and we need people with both
statistic oh and security skill sets to
develop robust systems and evaluate
these infrastructures so in other words
things should learn it in the next five
years it's going to be it's going to be
very important and that's all I have
thank
hi so any questions they're there yeah
so the question is are there any
effective countermeasures that i have
found to be effective during the
development of machine learning systems
yeah so as i mentioned the adversarial
attack vector is only one very
particular attack vector against against
machine learning there are other like
system level vulnerabilities in many
machine learning frameworks that affect
how accurate the training is done
previously I did research in Fresno
component analysis poisoning which is
basically a poisoning during it during
the training phase so principal
component analysis is a technique that's
used to select dimensions it's used for
dimensionality reduction so you run your
your input through this algorithm and it
will tell you which dimensions can help
you make a better classification and
these these can be poisoned very easily
as well i think that the point behind
this is the same as any other kind of
kind of system you have to do some kind
of penetration testing because different
systems have different objectives and
the attack vectors for each of these
systems are different in some models
it's applicable that adversarial samples
should be should be protected against
for example if you look at the gmail
mail rare classifier which classifies
PDF documents for for for malware
different researchers that showed that
they can generate malware samples that
will actually bypass this and the prize
is that they actually get their samples
on to someone else's machine and it gets
past emails memory classifier which is
which is done using a deep learning
model so the way that you make these
better is to basically generate
adversarial samples and to train your
model with these adversarial samples and
basically it's like telling a child that
you made this you made this mistake in
the past but then I'm going to teach you
that this actually is a ship this is
actually a dog
and you shouldn't make the wrong you
shouldn't make the wrong decision again
in the future so that's just one of the
ways that they can be used and their
many other okay any more questions cool
thank you thanks