thank you very much yeah my name is
Matias teak and in the next couple of
minutes I want to talk about the
security of wireless desktop sets
wireless mice and wireless keyboards so
yeah a few rosabel mean I work as an ITC
IT security consultant for a company
called sis and yeah it still pays the
rent and I'm interested in information
security since my early days yeah and i
still have fun doing this I did this
research together with my colleague if
you have closed the meijer he couldn't
be here today yeah he's also very
interested in information security and
with it this research as i said before
together over the last couple of months
actually so the agenda for this talk we
have a few points at first I want to
shortly introduce you to the use
technology I will gonna talk about down
yeah I would mention the previous work
of other researchers our research is
actually based on then I will give a
short overview of our research talk
about the attack surface and a text
scenario is concerning wireless desktop
sets well as much polish keyboards then
the interesting part is the phone
security vulnerabilities there will
hopefully be also live demos I have one
set up here I hope it works and of
course there's conclusion and
recommendation and if we have still time
some Q & A okay so what are going to
talk about is wireless desktop sets so
you can see here on the upper side of
the picture of wireless des obsessed is
just a combination of wireless keyboard
wireless mouse and a USB dongle that is
working as a receiver and gets connected
to a PC on the lower side of the picture
you can see some of the devices we used
for our research purposes so I for
example use the heck are f1
software-defined radio later on we used
a crazy radio PA um Garretson specific
device using the same technology as our
target devices and nowadays you can also
do
these kinds of attacks I show you using
low-cost devices like a Logitech
unifying receiver thanks to the steel
networks because I found out that they
can you that you can actually reprogram
these devices they cost about 16 euros
16 to 20 euros and you can do all the
kinds of attacks you will see later on
using such a unifying receiver okay so
how do wireless keyboards actually work
what I'm talking about well you have
wireless devices mouse and keyboard and
yeah they're just sending keystrokes in
the case of the keywords to use be
Donell in the case of the mouse mouse
actions like novice movements or mouse
clicks and the communication actually is
not unidirectional but your golden bull
goes in both directions they are not
acknowledgments but they are not that
important here okay and our research
actually is based on the research of
other risks researchers as mentioned
before back in 2009 and 27 2010 there
was a kicker aqui in version one version
to this project targeted for example
microsoft wireless desktop sets and the
guys doing it from dream like a dream
life technologies also reverse
engineered some proprietary encryption
of the wireless keyboard and they were
able to attack devices back then in
2011-12 is good speed published a paper
on a blog article about sniffing using a
specific kind of transceiver nemidi NRF
24 and last year as part of the NSA
playset semi come car released the key
sweeper it's an improvement to the
research done by the Hickory key team
actually add in February this year but
still networks released several
vulnerabilities they called mouse check
here and we actually get something the
same so our research
started way back in April 2015 it
started as a customer project where we
had a look at three specific IES
encrypted wireless desktop sense but we
only had limited time and we were not
that content with the results and we
thought there must be more to it so we
started a research project over the last
few month it was a very fragmented
research project because there were
always more important things to do like
earning money okay on this picture you
can see the five devices we had a look
at it was money buys from cherry one
from Microsoft fujitsu logitech and also
perixx we have chosen those devices by
the project we initially did and then we
just did a research on emerson germany
to see what can we find if we type
wireless desktop site in aes and these
were devices we could simply by there ok
so our test methodology was three-step
actually first we did a simple hardware
analysis so we opened up the devices we
stared at the printed circuit boards
identified chips did a lot of reading
documentation yeah and then we try to
find interesting test points for example
for spy and we were also so luring some
wires to some interesting test points
next we did thermal analysis so we were
capable to actually extract firmware of
some of the devices under test and we
loaded it dumped firmware it was
actually an 8051 code of the
microcontrollers of the specific
transceiver to either and analyzed it we
stare at this assemblies we did some
more reading of fine documentation we
check the Nordic semiconductors software
development kit which was very useful
and we read some more code or wrote some
sample code and analyze this just to get
a better understanding of how these
devices actually work
and lastly we also did radio based
analysis because these devices are
wireless and this is the most
interesting part yeah how do they work
actually and what I personally did at
first I watched my gosh moans as the are
tutorials this was actually my first
project working with a software-defined
radio and I learned a lot yeah I did
some more reading of documentation
browse the web because we found out that
these NRF 24 devices are very popular in
the maker scene at least the
transmitters and receivers not a
transceiver system-on-a-chip devices but
many people are using these transmitters
for different stuff here and then we
also got started with a new radio and
canoe radio companion we wrote some a
Python scripts and yeah analyzed the
data communication using readily
available tools from other projects and
later on we changed our tools set to
this off still networks in febrile this
year because it was just superior to
that one we have used up to them and on
in this table you can see the
transceivers we were able to identify
and air four of the five devices as you
can see are using the Nordic
semiconductor transceiver and RF 24 kind
and we focus our research on these
devices so fujitsu it's still a work in
progress it's another technology and we
were just able to identify one
vulnerability in there I will show you
later on okay here on this slide I've
just compile some information about
documentation it's just very important
if you haven't done such a project
before to read all the stuff too yeah
just know what are you looking at and it
is also helpful to do some research
about available tools because it saves a
lot of time actually okay and on the
next couple of slides I've just puts
excerpts from the data sheet so this was
actually the device and this packed
package that we were dealing with the
NRF 24 different versions in the
keyboard and in the USB dongle and the
interesting pins for us were of course a
spy because while this serial interface
we were able to dump the firmware and we
could also reprogram some of the devices
this was the first interesting finding
because the anodic semiconductor
transceivers actually have a read back
protection but three of the four
manufacturers just don't use this
feature and so you just have to find the
correct test points and yeah you can
modify the device or you can just dump
the firmware for further analysis yeah
when when it comes to data memory it is
divided in two parts the non-volatile
data not all memory is accessible it
externally why aspire so for example for
the Cherokee word keyboard we had to
write our own firmware to extract all
the data that was on the devices so it
was not all externally addressable as
you can see here on this slide you can
see some information about the so-called
enhanced shot burst protocol that is
used for the radio communication we were
mainly interested in the payload and not
on the other stuff yeah but if you have
a look at these devices and do the
analysis you have to know how it
actually works was the preamble the
address configuration fields control
fields checksums all that stuff but it's
all well documented and what's also
interesting shown on a lower part is
that the non exami conducted transceiver
has support for hardware aes encryption
and it's actually used by the firmware
we had a look at so on this slide you
can see a microsoft keyboard or actually
PCB and what's nice from microsoft is
they have labeled all the interesting
test points for us so we do not have to
search by our own so you can see ya BF
oldest by
things mesial muzie chip select a clock
and we also have the reset and proc test
points there so it was very easy to
analyze this one and yeah that's an
example set up we used just a buzz
pirate that's a Cherokee board wired and
the correct sold at the correct waters
on the correct test points and then you
just can modify and read the things okay
and we do not only have a look at the
keyboards but also enter Donal's so my
colleague Alexander's first time did
this one yeah and so we were also able
to directly read the Donalds in this way
using custom eights breakout boards okay
yeah and concerning firmware analysis
what we did as I mentioned earlier we
just loaded tried a pro read the nautic
semiconductor SDK several times and by
having the SDK it was rather easy to
identify the interesting spots
concerning and friction for example so
we could annotate the code section dura
mainly interested in here and concerning
radio based analysis we start with the
new radio and radio companion and you
have some self made scripts just will
analyze what was going on over the air
using the enhanced shop first
communication protocol yeah and this is
just an example of our first rise using
the NRF 2040 coda we modified a little
bit and here were able to see the
encrypted traffic and some more
information concerning addresses p IDs
acknowledgement stuff like that so this
is just a raw communication here and in
febrile februari this year we changed
our own tool set a little bit because
but still released their own tool set
they used for identifying the mouse
check vulnerabilities and their tool set
was just superior to ours so we also
bought a crazy radio that
surely a remote control for a
quadrocopter and we used pastilles NS n
RF research firmware and some of the
tools and all the tools we have
developed so far are based on this tool
set here and of course there were
different problems during our research
project what I've learned personally is
that software defined radio really has a
steep learning curve so reproducing some
things at the starters were really easy
but later under when there are some
issues you really have to dig deep and
find out what's going wrong and we are
the error is but it's fun so I will
continue doing SDR analysis in the
future yeah and some things just were
more difficult than we first thought for
example simply replay attacks because
there is a channel hopping their timing
issues signal strength issues stuff like
that and what we also found out is that
correctly identifying chips is not in
itself because we overlooked at first
that there are also one-time
programmable versions of some of the
chips yes all we bricked one microsoft
device yeah that was not our intention
yeah and the other two points are rather
general if you have a development kit or
board where you can just play around
without breaking and damaging it yeah
you can save a lot of time and having a
proper tools yet makes a huge difference
okay so what actually is the tech
surface and what our attack scenarios
concerning wireless desktop sets and in
our opinion there are two attack
categories one with a whip physical
access to the devices and one where
you're remotely attack the devices over
the areas radio signals concerning
physical access what could you possibly
do as an attacker you can of course
extract firmware and menu platform where
extract cryptographic keys and many of
manipulate them
concerning attacks over the air what can
you do yeah you can exploit unencrypted
nano 28 unauthenticated data
communication you can perform replay
attacks if there is no protection you
can maybe perform keystroke injection
attacks and you can also try to decrypt
encrypted data communication so all the
devices we looked at were encrypted so
we only had a look at aes encrypted
wireless desktop sense here and here the
for the five security vulnerabilities we
found actually they are only four
because we play attack the solicitor
twice but what we found is that some
devices just have an insufficient
protection of code namely firmer and
data cryptographic keys so we were
simply able to read and also write this
sensitive data and as seen before using
spire then the second vulnerability we
found was unencrypted and
unauthenticated data communication and
we found this one in all the mice we
have tested so only the keyboards are
actually encrypted all the mice or
unencrypted and the next problem that he
was missing protection against replay
attacks so most of the devices had no
protection at all against replay attacks
and the microsoft keyboard had some kind
of protection zone that's point for
insufficient protection against beep
latex but there is still an attack
window you can actually exploit and the
last vulnerability is cryptographic
issues that allowed for other attacks as
we will see later on okay so the first
vulnerability insufficient protection of
code and data it's rather obvious one so
I will rush to the slides here you can
see sample from rarely used to eat
extract the so-called extended and be
flash memory from the cherry keyboard
because
in this way we were able to also get
access to the memory that is not
externally addressable why a spy and the
cherry keyboard for example stores the
AAS key in there yeah so you at first
have to dump have to reprogram a
Cherokee word our cherry Donnell in
order to actually get to the ASX in this
case concern the other devices for
example parex or Microsoft you can just
connect to the correct test points for
spy andrejs key from the device yeah and
here's an example of to dance from the
Jerry dongle and the Cherokee board as
you can see we have found the same 16
byte value in the Donald flash memory
and in the Cherry flash memory and this
is the actual key that it's used yeah so
yeah embedded flash memory of several
devices can be read and written
concerning a nerf and default on Seavers
there is a protection feature that is
not be used by every manufacturer so it
is rather easy to raise the bar for an
attacker having physical access if this
feature was used in the manufacturing
process and yeah what we also found out
this that it's also possible to
manipulate one time programmable flash
memory because you can change a 1-bit to
a zero bit but not vice versa so for
example Microsoft the microsoft keyboard
uses a one-time programmable version of
the transceiver but you can still modify
the key or modify the firmware in a
limited way yeah and what's also
important is that some wireless
keyboards for example Microsoft is
paired at the factory so you have no
chance as an end user to actually change
the cryptographic keys you just have to
trust Microsoft in this way we are still
working on a software where you are able
exploiting the spy access to change the
cryptographic keys if you don't trust
Microsoft but still work in progress
yeah and concerning the generation of
cryptographic keys none of the
manufacturers told us how they actually
do it so it can be simply random it can
be derived from some serial number or I
don't know what so it's just it's a
secret and you have to trust the
manufacturers that are actually building
these devices yeah and what does it mean
it means that non-technical is Alexis
can change the cryptographic keys and
the firmware and of course read it and
when I hear this I always have to think
of this picture that was released I
think three years ago yeah so anybody
who has access to the device for a
couple of minutes it depends on the
device so five to ten minutes can
extract the AES keys or it can actually
manipulate a firmware and here you can
think of some specific key logger
scenarios for example yeah we are just
extract the keys and then you're sitting
in the building on the opposite side of
the street or on another floor and just
sniffing the radio communication for a
couple of weeks and you're able to
decrypt all the traffic somebody is
generating using these devices okay so
the next vulnerability and the tech that
is possible our so-called Mouse spoofing
attacks because yeah as mentioned
earlier the communication of the mice is
unencrypted an unauthenticated so the
receiver cannot decide if it's authentic
or not and so you can just poof devices
and do whatever you want okay so i will
show you a small demo video hopefully it
works
because I was challenged by one of my
colleagues he said yeah but it's not
reliable exploitable in the real world
so we just developed a small Python
software to convey your active mouths
and I targeted in this proof-of-concept
attack a Windows 7 operating system and
Nia what actually did is I opened the
virtual on-screen keyboard of the device
and then you can just yeah do virtual p
presses there I sped it up so it's the
attacker is rather slow at least here in
my proof of concept too so I think the
complete attack has a duration of 3
minutes you can see a full demo on
youtube so i think a couple of days ago
or weeks two weeks ago we put a proof of
concept video on youtube you can just
watch it there yeah and what happens
here it's just virtual key presses it's
a default Windows attack vector download
and execute why a PowerShell and when
the tech is completed yeah now I slowed
down again and press enter now the
PowerShell command is executed and if
all goes well yeah melber just got
installed on the system this kind it's
just a mock-up ransomware yeah and it's
just a demo for remote code execution
wireless unencrypted mass communication
yeah ok so we've seen this here yeah so
the radio communication of all the
tested Myers was unencrypted and
unauthenticated so if you know the mouse
data protocol you can just do arbitrary
mouth action mouse movements on mouse
clicks here and you have control in an
unauthorized way over the mouse cursor
mouse pointer and this is really old
news so back in two thousand nine and
2010 the people
Dream labs the kicker Becky people they
also had this happens information in
their slides but actually nobody cares
because all people say it's not reliable
exploitable and it's actually true
because you need some heuristics to
exploit this in the real world so you
have trial and error educated guesses
but in some cases you have remote code
execution and heuristics concern they
had a layout of the screen actually then
the language settings you have to know
if it's an English keyboard or wall rock
or German for example you have to know
some information about the mouse
settings especially the mouse
acceleration that is used and you have
to know where the on-screen keyboard can
be found so it is also changed with
windows 8 8.1 and 10 but in Windows 8.1
and 10 you have a split screen keyboard
that you can also explore it rather
reliably I'd say okay and these are the
defaults I used in my proof of concept
just a default mouse settings using
enhanced pointer precision there's a
default Mouse acceleration curve in the
registry and the on-screen keyboard
actually has default position and
default dimensions if you haven't used
it before and moved it and saved it so I
think in most of the cases concerning
Windows installations or Windows Office
installations in companies it's rather
reliable and if you if you're not only
targeting one device but several
hundreds one is enough to get access to
the company network if the next exploit
is successful yeah and um what I
couldn't achieve was pixel perfect
control over the mouse pointer because
there is some more research necessary
because it's not that easy as I have
thought at the beginning here and
actually the mouse movement in Windows
is still handled in the kernel and there
is fixed point math involved and mouse
acceleration curves
it's more complicated than I actually
thought yeah and so the current state is
that we are using handcrafted mouse
movements that are actually slowed down
to avoid some issues concerning Mouse
acceleration yeah but it works rather
library as we've seen in the demo video
okay so the next vulnerability replay
attacks this is also rather obvious and
actually I was surprised that it works
on all keyboards i have also demo video
here but i will also try to do a live
demonstration in combination with
another vulnerability and later on so
yes repeat this one okay i'll pause the
video for a second this is just a simple
know what no I cannot pause it okay this
is just as a simple setup on the left
the laptop you can see the attacker
there's running new radio you can see a
software-defined radio and you can see
the victim system running Windows 7 that
is operated with one or both wireless
desktop set and what I just said is here
I recorded the radio communication on a
specific channel in this case and now I
simply do a replay of the recorded
communication and as you can see I can
unlock the window screen remotely yeah
so there's no protection concern a
replay attacks
yeah and in this case I attacked the
fujitsu keyboard and I don't know
actually the protocol of the 52 keyboard
so I did this using a black box approach
I just recorded the communication on a
specific channel and replayed it I don't
know what is actually going on but it is
easy to reproduce as you've seen okay
this was just a setup we've seen it in
the video yeah and actually this is the
new radio flow graph it's one of the
most simple flow graphs you can get this
can be used for recording and for
replaying by yeah activating
deactivating some of the boxes but
that's all it takes to perform replay
attacks and you can do this within a
couple of yeah seconds or minutes
actually it took me five minutes to
reproduce this on the fidgets to
keyboard okay yeah and we have also
written other software tools yeah simple
replay python script that uses the newer
toolchain the crazy radio PA and the NRF
research member and you can just perform
replay attacks using this and you have
them better output okay yeah so replay
attacks are rather obvious and simple
and all the keywords we've tested all
five of animals replay attacks microsoft
was special because it has some kind of
protection and there's a limited attack
window because only a specific number of
key presses should happen between the
recording and the replay if there are
too many key presses on a keyboard I
think it's about 1000 then the replay
doesn't work but concerning all the
other devices we were able to replay
communication we've recorded the day
before and it still works perfectly so
no protection at all yeah as mentioned
before simply player text can be done
without knowing the actual protocol and
you're more sophisticated text can be
done using the other tool set
and what can you do with replay or text
you can gain gain unauthorized access to
unattended screen lock computers as
shown in the video and if you can also
gain physical access to the u.s. be
Donell the receiver of your victim you
can just steal it and replay the
communication on your own device and
then you will get all the clear text key
presses in this way so it's another kind
of key logger scenario if you want it
that way so if you're able to replace
all the wireless desktop sets at a
specific facility cleaning personal
nobody will notice that you've just
replaced the original device and then
you can there replay communication you
have recorded the weeks or days before
and you can see for example passwords ok
and now the most interesting one the
keystroke injection attack and here i
will try to do a live demo all i have to
do a quick setup so
so I'm just preparing my whole week Tim
device but it's only for test purposes I
know I try to do some picture-in-picture
egg okay
so what I've here is well I'll make the
Pro running Windows 7 as a victim system
so it's not the ideal setup but I hope
that it works and what I have here is a
cherry keyboard wireless desktop set the
USB dongle it's just plugged in to the
device I will turn it on and just see if
it actually works such device is working
no I don't want to restart this okay so
now this device is connected to my
Victim system it's not necessary
necessary to see what is actually a
typed here it's more important to see
that something is happening ok so now I
will use a proof of concept to are
called Jerry attack and I will try to
live demonstrate two kinds of attack a
combination attack replay and keystroke
injection and i hope the demo gods will
support me in this one ok so what I did
is I just started to prove of concept to
and now I oh my fault i miss the most
important step my radio without this
well actually it should not work and as
you can see here could not initialize
young he also write it there so this is
on the crazy radio PA it costs I think
including the antenna 30 euros and now
i'm good to go
hope okay so here's my pick tool now I
press some keys here and as you can see
i found a keyboard this one is easy
because it doesn't do any channel
hopping and there are no timing issues
and you can also see there is something
going on concerning crypto and yeah now
I'm ready for the attack what I will do
now is I will try to lock the windows
system to show the first kind of attack
so now you can see the window system is
locked and now i just press one button
and now i will record all the data
communication of this specific device
okay so as you can see it was successful
the screen was unlocked now i will just
lock it again and try the replay attack
hello it works so that's the first one
the replay attack so you can simply
remotely unlock screen lock systems we
did not do any range test but the people
from but still did they were able to do
mouse check attacks I think up to 100
meters using some special antennas not
this one but yeah it's possible okay now
we have so this just a virtual machine
and what I try now is the other kind of
attack the keystroke injection and let's
see if it works yeah you can see
something is happening on the device
there's a command channel it's actually
a PowerShell I have all goes well
there should be some malware popping up
yeah it worked so that's the key stroke
injection so in this way a combination
attack you can remotely unlock a
computer system if you have recorded the
password entry at the right time and
afterwards if the system is unlocked in
an unlocked state you can simply inject
arataura keystrokes and do whatever you
want for example installing malware as
in this case okay so back to the slides
yeah so this is another tool keystore
conjecture I showed you actually this
one and this attack works for the cherry
keyboard we've tested the parry keyboard
and also the Logitech keyboard but we
did not found a vulnerability concerning
logitech bacillus just before us and
reported to logitech yeah and here you
can see an extract from the NRF SDK and
what we found there is that there are
differences between to an RF transceiver
versions concerning the AES counter mode
encryption and what we found out is that
there is not a counter used by the
random value and then we thought hey how
are the device is sinking and the truth
is they cannot sing they're just using
random values for the counter mode and
this actually is part of the problem um
yeah it's just a source code using the
pseudo-random number generator for
generating these five bytes random value
yeah and concerning the tested cherian
perixx keyboard we found out that are
using 128-bit aes encryption in counter
mode the counter generally consists of
unknowns number is once and a counter
and we also found out that the nons of
the cherry keyboard was only null byte
so we have 11 egg whites and five bytes
random value for the initialization
vector and by manipulating the cherry
firmware
were also able to find out some more
details concerning the release packets
so I released packet I mean if we
release the key of the keyboard a
specific packet is sent and we were able
to manipulate the firmware as mentioned
before using spy and analyze it using
either pro and we were able actually to
decrypt all the traffic on the cherry
devices we had and we found out hey if
he releases send it's just 11 non-whites
so and on the bottom of the slides you
can see how counter mode actually works
for all block ciphers in this case also
mas and what we know is all the
information you I've circled in red we
know the complete initialization vector
the nons we know because we did a firmly
analysis the counter actually is sent by
the radio communication in clear text
over the air the ciphertext is also
sending clearly not in clear text i'll
send over the air in the radio
communication protocol then we know the
plaintext at least of some packets
mainly the key release packets and yeah
due to the mode of operation of counter
mode we also know the keystream block
because something exclusive or zero is
still something yeah we have it on the
other slide here and what is also very
useful is this that there is no reply
protection so we simply have to find one
valid key release packet and modify this
in an arbitrary way so we have the
replay attack possibility we can do this
known plaintext attack and what we do
next is we do some simple math namely
exclusive or and then we can manipulate
this key Willie's packet arbitrarily and
inject whatever he is we want we also
found out that the Cherokee born also
parex and logitech are using the default
USB HID human interface device data
formats so we have eight bytes at least
in the case of Jerry we have some
modifiers null byte and six key codes
and here are some
your examples of well it well used for
these data fields and here's just a
simple example so we have an encrypted
release packet we have an exclusive or
with our plaintext packet we are fortune
in this case it's shift + a so we want
to keep it light and the injection
package you can see below and that is
all you have to do to have packet
injection unencrypted wireless desktop
sets yeah and here keystroke injection
in five easy steps you just have to find
the target device using yeah radio you
have to find a key release packet this
is also a heuristic but the last packet
somebody has pressed after all along the
pause for example two or three seconds
actually is the key release packet so
you can find these packets with high
reliability you do some simple math and
then it concerns modified cue release
packets as you want and repeat it as
often as you want and what you gain is
remote code execution as we've seen ya
on target systems that are actually
operated with vulnerable devices here's
an excerpt of the demo code of the demo
tool you've seen before it's just a few
lines of Python it's just an exclusive
or actually yeah that's not otherwise
we've built because my boss wanted to
have a standalone device so yeah we had
an old raspberry pi Ryan lying around
developed a small raspberry pi shield
here and put the radio in there and you
can do it attack also with this yeah
it's just a schematic you should not
take such device in airplane because
airport security yeah they have some
questions so my boss did last week and
he told me not to put it in the hand
luggage yeah okay and here's some
manufacture statement and feedback so no
response from parex at all Microsoft
they are still checking some of the
issues actually but some of the problems
that just cannot fix or not in the
products that are already out there yeah
concern
the mouse communication I said it it is
by design so no fix for this concerning
the physical access to say yeah if you
have physical access you can do anything
and it's actually true and we are
concerning his of keystrokes injection
replay attack they're still working on
this one yeah logitech just said yeah
thank you very much and we are working
on better products in the future fujitsu
yet i told us that these kind of replay
attacks are actually hard to reproduce
and you need special knowledge and stuff
like that yeah but I also doesn't they
will not fix this but in future products
they will try to do it better and cherry
they just relabeled their product it was
called unlimited be unlimited aes and
now they just don't promote it as a
secure wireless desktop set anymore and
they will also not fix these issues in
their product they are still selling
here okay so the conclusion is that all
the test devices had one or more
security issues in my opinion you can
exploit all of them in real world attack
scenarios yet a phone security issues
cannot or will not be fixed so one level
devices will stay one mobile in the
future yeah it's just a short summary
yet another summaries so what have you
found concern 25 wireless desktop sets
different vulnerabilities here and yeah
our all the single recommendation is do
not use wireless desktop sets with known
security vulnerabilities in security
related environments okay here are some
references and thank you very much for
your attention and I think we don't have
time for questions all right thank you
my tears