no problem this is better all right
thanks love and yeah I'm actually very
uncomfortable with that ear Mike because
it keeps falling off my my ears are not
very well aligned so I'll just hold hold
this thing in hand and give it a shot
yeah morning good morning and thanks for
thanks for showing up early in the
morning I I love hot glue very much it's
one of my absolute favorite events but
they always put me up in the morning
talk which is a challenge anyway so
thanks for being here this soft after
after about 10 years coming to hack lou
i decided i want to change up the theme
a little bit I've been doing offensive
stuff all all my career thinking of new
ways of attacking and you know figuring
out where we get blocked when the
defense catches up and then we kind of
innovate our way our way out and come up
with a new attack so I i started
thinking especially from my customers
viewpoint what a pain i must be to all
of them to to block me or to defend
against attacks that are coming and I I
started taking a higher level look at
infosec thinking okay you know we've
been doing this for almost 20 years
something needs to change and security
is actually pretty strange but while I
was thinking I thought we do have
actually in fact today we we do have an
opportunity to change the way we do
defense to come up with a more proactive
methodology for defense and actually
succeed while doing defense not to just
you know get blocked by the next attack
so my name is Alicia and the theme of
the talk that the thought process was
today's attacks succeed because
the defense is reactive we've we've
spent all our years chasing the
attackers tails we've seen a new type of
attack we've then scrambled to defend
against it it works for a while it keeps
the new attacks at bay but then the
attacks evolve and the attacks have
started evolving very fast way faster
than traditional defense can now keep up
so you're looking at a company that can
produce a box with blinking lights
starts pushing it out in the market it
gets installed everywhere to be used for
about six months and then it sort of
stays there the lights keep on blinking
and there's a process built around it
and then you go and look for a new box
this is no fun so what we need to do i'm
going to divide this talk into two parts
the first part is kind of okay how we
got here and the second part is all
right what do we do about it so if you
start tracing back from say 10-15 years
ago and look at where targets have been
targets have shifted when I started pen
testing it was all about servers they
moved the targets follow the path of
least resistance so as as one area
starts getting hard you open up a new
area you go to applications desktop
browsers and now the attacks follow the
the pockets you're carrying kind of an
attack with you wherever you go and now
of course there's a whole Internet of
Things thing he out there which which
also is vast attack carrier the
motivation of attacks a lot of people
have talked about it the motivation is
very clear it's all about the money
whenever you can figure out a way of
making money you have an attack
technique coming up for that and just
when we thought we had a handle on d dos
well here we go d
to the max again can probably take out a
whole nation with the kind of flood that
we saw from the botnet of things so
actually I had to update this slide
today's fashion is no longer breeches it
is terrible d dos but yeah this there's
a train every year there's a there's a
trend of attacks coming in this next
year there's a new trend breaches have
now become so commonplace that yeah used
to get really excited oh wow Sony got
hacked and they got owned and they got
like slaughtered through the press but
there's not enough press not not the
same magnitude of press about Yahoo it's
like okay we've become numb to it yeah
breaches will happen oh shit there goes
our passwords again and we kind of just
we don't bother about it we've closed
down or yahoo account and open up some
other junk email account to collect spam
i wonder if google gets breached or what
are we going to do but how have you been
behaving as far as defense goes over the
past 16 years we've kind of stride to
restrict everything somewhat like the
city of Gondor we've you know had walls
we've built walls in circles all the way
to the inner core so we first start with
the perimeter and then we started with
you know securing applications endpoints
desktop Sonja there are there are
creative Souls out there so yeah you you
got all your firewalls at ids and dep
and sank boxes only to be circumvented
by techniques created by smart people
and what we learn from this hacks happen
they will always happen yes there is
control so integrity checking yes there
is shadow stag yes there is you know CPU
level stuff that is being built in and
I'm sure some smart people figure out a
way two morrow how to get around it you
kind of keep going down the whole the
whole doesn't end the whole probably
ends when everything blows up and you
reach the core both attackers and
defenders die or when the matrix finally
swallows us
but going down the hole is not an option
you just you making it harder we're not
not really stopping the attack and I
kind of last year I did a talk on
steroid how do i encode a browser
exploit entirely on two pixels and
cannot make it invisible to eyes that
scan content it travels as a real
picture this this one is actually a an
exploit it is a browser exploit which
will trigger on ie9 it's painted on
Kevin mcpeek face you just don't see the
pixels I did this top last year at
hackle ooh and I've been working on this
for about four years and completed the
whole thing in the hackerspace in
Luxembourg so I decided to talk about it
but when I reflect back on to why stay
go slow it happens it's exactly the
reason you are being blocked so you kind
of figure out a new way of tunneling
attacks or carrying attacks on images is
find creative ways of packing things
together to make it succeed I read a
really nice blog on architecture and
somebody described this concept of
Nakatomi space this appealed to me very
much and in infosec it's exactly like
this nagatomi space is basically you can
traverse interiors in ways that they
were never intended to be traversed Hey
Bruce Willis can move up and down a
multi-storied building without using
traditional means of access and as
infrastructure goes complex there is
more and more Nakatomi space being added
into everything file formats networks
like stack memory wherever you think
there's some little gaps some little
ways in and out that an attacker can use
and traverse through it in a manner not
intended for for use and this is where
all the attacks actually come from can
we really try and block Nakatomi space
no it's a part and parcel of the
infrastructure it just comes
it's given you can't really clamp it
down if we look at how exploit
developers were like about 12 years ago
this is a photograph from sis is a
photograph from black hat 2003 we used
to write exploit for the laws as fun we
could own everything and then we could
brag about it today if you're going to
write exploits it's a huge effort
there's no publicly available exploits
around there's that the money has gone
up and exploit have kind of gotten
really weaponize and they've taken place
in like serious offensive tactics so
what does this mean for defense the
defenders tried to react against this as
well say okay we cannot find publicly
disclosed bugs and where we try to screw
over the researchers by forcing them
into legal battles so the researcher
said no more free bugs will not want to
tell you and they started using it for
themselves so what did the defenders do
they tried to buy back their bugs enter
the concept of bug bounties this is a
great start the thought process was was
was good it was designed for I mean it
came about for addressing a real need
and the real need was to credit the
researchers for their effort and you
know say thank you the problem happened
when they started escalating the stakes
so from being a thank-you game an
appreciation game it became a money game
and as with money the escalation started
pretty fast I am NOT going to rent about
bug bounties but I am NOT a believer in
the present form of bug bounties had it
retained the original thought process
yeah that's very good but you see that
bug bounties did try to fill a reactive
need and what's happened now you have
situations like this bug bounties have
not remained bounties in the true sense
but they've become sort of a trading
platform
a a weapons acquisition market if you
have 0 diem declaring a bug bounty for
iOS that's not really bug bounty the the
spirit of the bug bounty means a vendor
is buying the bug back I mean zero diem
is definitely not going to give the bug
to Apple not not after they played a
million dollars or now it's like 1.5
million and it's it's it's just getting
out of control you're acquiring bugs and
then using it recklessly this is not
what it was so my I mean my take on
everything reactive is that don't play
this game it's it's not going to benefit
you it's just going to drain you out of
money and time and publicity and you're
not really going to improve much I mean
Apple has now started a private bug
bounty only like eight or nine people
can contribute to it and they'll get
paid well that's sort of like saying
yeah we have an open bug boundary but
not really open because apple doesn't
really like anything open anyway that's
the subject that we can debate later
quickly cutting to how how users behave
and user behavior is one of my pet
points has sort of devolved over over
several years especially over the two
decades and the problem with user
behavior is where users have remained
the same and advanced technology is
advanced sometimes you don't know how to
use advanced technology and you you know
step into an Airbus and total it this is
what happens when users are given what
do you think happens when users are
given a smartphone with a camera they do
this yeah I mean why not this was this
was in August so how do you protect user
safety when you kind of enable the user
and made them feel good about tweeting
pictures of their debit cards and whose
fault is it the banks surely the banks
are going to get blamed but what do you
do
I there's several points that I you know
agree and disagree with Schneier one of
the points that I really agree with is
you give the user a choice about
security the users really going to make
the right choice about security they
will choose features fun and frolic over
security any day the pop-up is bugging
them from dancing pigs they will click
okay just to get to see the dancing pics
it's true so we've seen so far we've
seen a very reactive approach to defense
one of the things that has Orizon out of
this whole reactive approach of
Defense's old phenomenon called
compliance something happens in this
compliance being enforced in the name of
security this is a picture from my
hometown where we have a law that riders
of scooters and motorcycles must wear a
helmet okay this picture is compliant
but nothing to say about this person's
wife was riding behind and if she gets
if they get into a wreck she will have
to be scraped off with a spatula it is
it is compliant but it's not secure so
are these guys these guys are all
compliant they probably still are and
they are getting breached the golden
truth you and I know attackers don't
follow standards and certifications they
never have they never will and what are
we doing to defend in this manner if you
kind of go to a large conference you see
a picture like this so today's infosec
defense is kind of boiled down to three
or four major areas you sum it up all
infosec defense is all about rules
signatures and updates if we've learned
how to do this for two decades and oh
now we have this new thing called
machine learning thrown in as if it's
going to solve everything for us where
are we going with this is back to the
same thing it's it's about being
reactive I mean we know antivirus has
has its limitations I am NOT going to
knock it because yeah it served its
purpose frustrated me sometimes but we
don't we don't sort of learn lessons
from 10 years ago and we have more
statements coming up saying okay we stop
99% of malware attacks before they
happen well that's great you thought
about what the other one percent would
occupy it's it's the one percent malware
that really matters in today's age they
end up owning everything well then your
antivirus gets machine trained on this
then they'll detect it only to be owned
by the other one percent of malware and
this game keeps going on we've seen that
existing strategies simply do not match
attacker tactics all right so this is
part one we've you come to a conclusion
this this is not going to be the way we
are going to defend ourselves
something's got to change so what is
that change where are we headed in terms
of defense if you want to do it right
the one thing I known as we have a
switch our approach from being reactive
to being proactive and in a proactive
defense can only happen when you have
the proper intelligence gathered to
defend yourselves there's a lot to be
said about intelligence as well and so
many people say so okay you do you mean
that you should get threatened tell
feeds heck no there's like little maps
that shoot things against each other so
where you get your security intelligence
first thing look within you pretty much
have all the intelligence you want to be
able to defend your own organization
know yourself is the first approach if
you simply look at your
organization's data must be like
generating a phenomenal amount of data
petabytes of data these were all your
intelligence is the thing is what do we
do with the data we need to be able to
extract proper intelligence from it and
this brings me to my the rest of my talk
on proactive security testing if only
infosec learns from high-velocity
ecommerce and adopts the same process we
will stand a way better chance of
defense let me give you an example you
see you see a large retailer like Amazon
or a large e-commerce site not only do
they sell very fast but they keep a
watch on every transaction where is the
user looking how are they clicking can
we shorten the clicks are they using
more mobile phones are they using more
browsers what's the bottlenecks in
delivery can I can I shorten this curve
it's all about analysis and actions this
process is very well established they
also generate petabytes or maybe like
exabytes of data but they have the power
to analyze it surely we can as well when
it comes to defense so with this I kind
of thought of seven axioms of security
which I want to lay out to give you a
broad guideline of what what meaningful
defense is going to be and the first
axiom is collect everything by
everything I mean everything this
actually is a this is proven one of our
customers did it they started collecting
every HTTP request on all their web
facing applications they're a bank in
the United States they started
collecting every HTTP request since 2009
they have about a few petabytes of data
in a homegrown Hadoop cluster and
they've kept it
they just started with one thing we're
going to collect it and see what we get
and then they started running modeling
and analysis on it trying to detect
patterns frauds were happening and then
they try to look what led to the fraud
historical data is your biggest asset in
this case and from this historical data
they learned so many things that they
were able to improve their own homegrown
fraud detection by so much that the the
frauds our way minimized and the program
essentially pays for itself they also
and the cost it was like about 250
thousand dollars to fill up the hardware
and another similar amount like
three-quarters of a million dollar to
run this program year after year and
there is nothing compared to the kind of
frauds they say if they were saving
about 425 million in frauds simply using
this this this strategy and the strategy
was based on the security data warehouse
as they called it now that is the first
step to proactive security and that's
what set me thinking saying wait a
minute this is the way to go here and
look at Moore's law Moore's law has
proved that retention is cheaper than
deletion I haven't deleted anything from
a computer and over like five years have
just gotten a bigger hard drive and so
we it doesn't matter BB google code
every little bite you can it costs you
nothing to store it in fact it's like
kind of more painful to scrub it
properly and the more valuable I mean
the more aged the data collects the more
valuable it gets like a good vintage
there is i mean the the value of
historical data increases exponentially
with time whenever something happens you
can always go back and look and really
narrow down several root causes which
you never knew this is not going to give
you the answers for everything but it's
going to help you arrive at conclusions
really quickly
now what do you do after you collect
everything this the second axiom is if
you can't measure it you can use it this
thought process came from a talk given
by Marcus raynham is one of the guys I
respect very much and he was speaking at
IIT defense earlier this year in January
in mines and I woke up actually early
for his keynote one of the few key notes
that I attended and he made a point that
security is all about metrics what our
matrix matrix are nothing but measurable
units of info SEC or measurable units of
anything and it is is like we really
need metrics for several things to
either show that you're succeeding or
failing these are basically his slides
that I want to repeat over here and
essentially to take informed decisions
his talk was all about how to establish
matrix at a very high level so you look
through your process and make a note of
what's quantifiable measure it track it
if it's going up or down and the real
reason why matrix are very important it
is this slide which I like very much
it's what he called a battle of two
narratives and this is typically what
happens when decisions are being taken
like some wizard will come and tell you
that oh by moving to the cloud you will
save half a million dollars per year and
they're pulling numbers from thin air
they're pretty much you know what
nothing nothing more than a while
thought over a cup of coffee and they
they're going to make a business case
out of it the only way you can call
bullshit on it is if you have metrics so
if you don't this guy is going to get
his way and and your initiatives are
going to be sideways if you have the
matrix you can either credibly defend
against it or justify what you're
thinking of or maybe actually even prove
that they're right and take the right
decision in this case I love the random
statement is if you can't defend then
plan B is to come up with lies of your
own if you don't have matrix but
I have seen this with C source
throughout the years the main blockage
for security is somebody from marketing
comes and says oh if you do this user
experience is going to suffer there's no
way of measuring how many users are
going to suffer and I'm going to talk
about users in a little bit where you
actually measured and realize how many
users are going to suffer well go for it
there's always collateral damage we've
kind of become numb to it haven't win
today's day and age right the third
axiom is if you really want to test test
like an attacker I mean if you want to
do red team do red team thoroughly I
have several instances of me walking
into a red team engagement and the
customer kind of starts throwing
different rules like oh wait we got to
wait for a production release don't test
on production you're going to kill it
well that's the idea dammit don't
perform intrusive testing what's a
non-intrusive penetration test i mean
the the words are just conflicting
aren't they and then oh yeah this is out
of scope that is out of scope that is
out of scope so what do you want me to
do walk on the carpet and oh yeah this
is my favorite Oh test during off-peak
hours basically from 2 a.m. to four am
ok whatever you know so I asked them
saying ok who are you more scared of are
you scared of attackers or auditors and
make a choice if you're scared of the
auditor is a get a compliance report i
will give you one for free and go away
he'll be all green save your time siva
money don't bother me but if it is
attackers you're worried about all these
rules don't apply just do what an
attacker does coming to users this is
axiom for and this kind of was inspired
by a tweet debate between the grog who
is a very dear friend of mine and SP
it's like it's high time we paid
attention to user ratings we've always
talked about users you always told that
user is stupid no they're not they can
be incredibly smart and incredibly
stupid and there is this a curve we've
got to realize where we are with it
that's what's going to make a big
difference in our info SEC landscape so
yeah this was the the origins of the
discussion is the statement that user
hardening efforts have barely made any
progress compared to software hardening
over the last year's and it is time we
look at this really seriously from an
organization's point of view it's like
okay using metrics using data that you
collect who are your users who are they
what are they how mature are they in
terms of infosec practices and your
typical curve will always look like this
you have a lot of users on the low
maturity curve to begin with the moment
you start measuring you start seeing
this bell curve appear and then what do
you do here and of classify them you you
know there's there's a hopeless users
yeah there's uninformed users the pro
active users and the rock stars now
every user is different you cannot use
the same treatment for every user this
is the one big thing that organisations
are doing and failing if you try to
force me to change my password 12 times
a year i will start writing it down you
know it doesn't work that way you you
cannot apply the lowest common
denominator across your entire user base
so what do we do first of all the
hopeless users they're they're always
going to be an enigma you give them
anything they'll do something stupid out
of it leave them alone right on the
other hand you of the rock stars leave
them alone too because they are doing
the right thing maybe you want to learn
from them maybe you want to convert your
other Pro active users to be rock stars
too but your main target area are the
uninformed users this middle segment the
good thing about these people is if you
guide them they will end up doing the
right thing so your goal is to kind of
shift the curve take the slice of
uninformed users
and push him more proactive if you keep
moving the graph this way and you keep
tracking the metrics I believe you got a
very good game going and this can be
done through several things through
technologies from messaging sort of like
you know user feedback continuously AK
your updo using an old browser do you
want to update because if you don't then
where this might just stop working don't
be like Microsoft Clippy that that is
not call being proactive user experience
right fifth axiom is to set booby traps
and this was inspired by a dear friend
of mine her own mere who actually has
built his company on selling Canaries
and canary tokens I mean it's it's time
that honey tokens made a comeback you
know see where your money is going
market mark your data mark your
transactions and keep an eye on them I
have suffered three credit card frauds
in this past one year fall from Citibank
they showed me a new card every time and
then it something happens it gets
breached and i believe i am not a stupid
user something's happened now this
started i started thinking they issue
credit cards and batches what have they
end up retaining a few cards themselves
and these few cards will never be used
and just just program these credit card
numbers into anything that takes a
regular expression the moment you see
activity on these unused credit cards
even if it is simple lookup query be
very aware like okay what's happening
track down your process and you see you
see where this data is moving on the
internet you kind of catch where the
leaks were catch with the breaches were
and figure out something's happening
before it really explodes you you find
like one canary in the whole batch
invalidate the batch you know reissue
them proactively before fraud start
happening I mean this is a way of
seriously actively defending against
against these threats encourage you
highly to read read up about canary
tokens and see any youtube videos of her
own stock it's very very inspiring
sixth axiom is that analysis decides
actions corollaries basically you will
not take any action without proper
analysis so fair warning for this one
there's a few block diagrams ahead I
generally don't like block diagrams what
I am going to use them so the way you
want to do this and this is what I saw
with one of my banking customers the
guys would build thick petabyte
warehouse is every new estimate they
kind of first estimated what impact it
would have so they decided very early on
that we will not allow I six to eight in
our organization and they met with a lot
of flack saying oh you're going to do
this you're going to break so many users
and they came back saying no we're going
to break like about thirteen percent of
users let's break that that's okay the
rest of the eighty-seven percent will
not complain and we will manage this so
they estimated that they would have
about a week worth of customer calls and
customer support issues and they
launched the initiative they started
tracking it they started tracking it
over two weeks and found out that ok
didn't take a week it probably took a
whole month that's ok but then they kind
of went back to the feedback loop and
reviser process is a little bit
introduce some new initiatives and
started started pushing changes where
initially every change is met with
resistance here you have a proactive way
of pushing changes with proper effect
and tracking is where you need to go I
drew a basic blueprint for a proactive
security defense architecture it's
something like everything has to feed
into the security data warehouse every
application user activity perimeter
activity collect analyze and then
trigger actions wherever they needed all
right and that leads me to the last and
the seventh axiom of of info SEC which
is a hard one to solve hard as for the
last and this requires buying from the
top
this is where the most resistance
happens the sad part is that info SEC is
still a cost Center to most
organizations it's not a money-making
machine and because it isn't a
money-making machine it takes the
sidelines the approach is okay how how
much can we optimize spending infosec
and how can we like minimize his budget
and just get the job done just don't get
the auditors in my face and oh I don't
want to be on the press all over these
are the overall goals given to any C so
this is not want to change the the cost
Center approach is not going to change I
mean I don't know how info sex going to
start making money for you unless you
like tell your banking red team to go
attack other banks and steal money from
them but otherwise you know no make
money so what do you do I was then going
through the job role of a Cecil and here
is what a seesaw needs to do it's a huge
time suck with with today's today's
responsibilities on the modern seesaw
but then again you kind of find a little
optimization area if you can eliminate
ten percent of the tasks it's going to
free up ninety percent of the time that
I see so as to spend and this ten
percent you can't really see it very
well but in that little corner is
something that says compliance and
audits compliance and audits are not
enforced sick in fact if you want to
make an organizational change in the
organization create a new business unit
that gels just deals with audits sit
them in a corner pay them some money and
then tell them not to make noise do
whatever they need to do but please move
this functionality from under the sea so
and put it somewhere else because
honestly it's not their surface not
they're monkeys info sexy source need to
be creative and need to make something
not scramble to keep on complying and
fulfilling all the hassles from all
sides
this is going to seriously free up
ninety percent of the time and then you
ask your question is your info SEC team
doing something creative every day
rather than just responding to rules
signatures updates and compliance
requests so well that's pretty much the
end of my talk I just have to do this I
got this hat at 44 gone a friend make it
made it so it's time to make security
great again that's that's what it says
thank you very much questions any
comments any questions the security hats
you can contact Joe Fitzpatrick he makes
these really nice make security great
again he'll probably give him to you we
have a question in the back yes
objective method of communicating to
upper yeah so the objective metrics for
communicating to the upper echelons
first of all failure rates and show that
if you know failure rates can be
minimized attempts of attacks that have
happened user classification is a big
thing like okay here's here's the users
that we have and give you an example
about users we had 11 bank in India roll
out a fingerprint based banking
initiative and they made a statement
that okay with this we are going to get
rid of passwords forever and everybody
can use their fingerprints to log into
internet banking from their phones the
the fallacy here that was not backed up
by numbers is that very few devices are
touch touch ID enabled or fingerprint
enabled so for the vast majority
still going to be usernames and
passwords even for the users who have
the touch ID if they drop their phone in
the toilet and get like a cheap knockoff
phone then they will degrade back to
username and passwords so do the
attacker touch ID means just simply
degrading to a lower quality hardware
device and you get it so these once you
have these type of metrics put in place
you can make a very convincing point
rest of it depends totally on the
initiative that you want to launch you
think of an initiative like say a
browser upgrade or you know do you have
more mobile users you want to even
invest more money into web-based
applications reduce to start 10 killing
like still slowly start killing them
that's what it's going to be I i wish i
knew the the answers and maybe i can
make like some process and offer
certification around it and then drive
compliance no sorry any others yeah I
have one actually go ahead you said to
move audit and compliance away from the
sea so yeah move it where to another
department which department well you
know in Germany they started creating
bad banks that's you have to create an
audit department I guess marketing so
I'm very see so no no seriously it's
it's a I mean humor aside I'll tell you
this job is like a full-time job in
itself if you put the two together the
Cecil's never the the infosec
organization will never get an
opportunity to be creative the only way
is you got to move it out let order do
its audit job cesar's go to survive the
audit period but let's say I want to
budget at all right so if you look at
the whole thing there the mind map for
CISOs yeah the red box is my biggest
elephant to get budget without that box
my budget decreases and I have to fight
so much harder for any budget
budget thingies are here yeah use
metrics to get other parts of budget but
if it's a classic denim says I'm sorry
but in four seconds the cost center
right you said it is a columnist ases
organization still view it as such it is
a cost center until the bigwigs see that
it is stopping other money from
hemorrhaging the way many Caesars
actually successfully implement metrics
and show business value is by you put
numbers you put money actual monetary
values yet risks yeah and then a risk
reduction is a monetary benefit to the
corporation right but then you need to
have the risk and the compliance of the
audit and the gaps in security so that
you can measure and monetize on
mitigation risk mitigation that's I mean
that's true we are stuck in this the
thing is do you want to get out of this
loop or not there's a question we can do
this I mean that's fine we want to get
out of this loop I do something
different or just still keep on doing
this because after all that is a
reactive path and I wish I had better
answers I just don't yes I think I think
the risk analysis is not done only by
auditors can be done also in the axiom
where you analyze the benefits of an
action yeah yeah any last question if
not let's say thank you to sound meal
and go for a coffee break thank you