once say welcome to my introduction
about the new
I'm architecture about new oMG age 64
bit
a mic picture are my name is Thomas Ross
I do
in bed at 6:30 p.m. oh well security up
mostly in the direction of bootloaders
and so on and yeah we gonna take a
relatively short look at
what's new in the architecture and what
changed and how it does it make
my job different and how I'd doesn't
change the future of
I mobile exploitation
are for example put a breaks for
hyper I prime are either invasion and
Swan
think this is the basic
who wrote map of they just three of the
ARM architecture
it started with the with the relatively
old on b5
on the six I construction Southampton on
current mobile phones they're most
likely using
and armpits having peace process for arm
p.m. was obviated this I V eight is
basically the biggest
upgrade to the instructions at since it
was invented
I in and obviate we have stuff like
mandatory floating-point we have I
at fort here exceptional based
architectural hypervisor sands on and if
we look at most changes and arm
64-bit its really focused on high
performance applications
say one well the normal city to bed arm
I
is very good for small devices for
minimum power consumption devices
with on 64 we can actually really
do massive processing I love
the instructions contained stuff like
hymns for the
for pipeline optimization for caching
optimization
and so on arm we don't have the
the old CPU modes anymore we now have
so-called exceptional levels
we have virtualization burden I'm
and yet the the instruction are still 32
bit fix linked those so you're you're
not
doubling your coat size we have much
more registers
we have a divide instruction finally if
you've ever written
embedded for I'm Cody 10 what a pain it
was still
text would divide something new
bootloader with the comp and
and some construction and start-up
Mumbai and thunder
conditional sum each and every
instruction we can still
also on 32-bit up I'm code
save if we compared to the
old are instruction set third does some
main difference
a for example there's no more some vote
some
don't want to instruction set on arm
that basically was
the normal instructions such shrink down
to sixteen
sixteen-bit construction its was very
limited
but very small and onto very good for
compilers to generate because the
a it was so simple another thing
that's missing now are conditionally a
executing instructions on on 32-bit
each instruction could have I'm a
condition
in it so you could for example have a
block
instead of having up branches for
comparison and so on for its and tells
you could just have
a forbid in the instruction set
differently and it would
are compared per instruction
we also don't have a coprocessor anymore
which is stiffing that you use
on on I would seep use for it your a
menu configuration
for your and higher power management
setup where cashing at Swan
arm the the program counters not
writeable
anymore only by branch instructions but
we have
almost double the registers if you if
you want to get started was a bit of
on 64 development there are some
official home
have simulators as the iPhone 5s that
you can get
your coat execute 100 and there's the
visit Alex press which is basically in
fpga-based I implementation of the
on 64 and there are some other boats and
also very cool is that
chemo now house full support for up
actually since quite a long time full
support for arc
64 if you want to analyze final result
generate binary this
and want to reverse engineer existing
I'm 64k
most schools are already up to it I and
II the pro 60 months ago there was an
update that now supports
on 64-bit she says she can generate and
object them
I can disassemble the the code the
hopper disassembler which is a very very
nice and cheaper alternative to either
pro
house limited but working I'm sixty-four
support and if you want to debug
something I want to just chill could you
could just one in chemo and a
are in no time
already sleds talk about the the
architecture
at you from work is normal amplicor so
they will know that you had like
16 registers on will some of which were
bank
between the different in trouble levels
and so on and now you're
actually apps search for general purpose
registers
and also to search you first register
which is
you the dislike point to or as you
register depending on your
on your context on I'm
for the first aides who registers which
are
and intuitively at the bottom of the
slide up hope for me to stand with salsa
and their function sets and I never
bank between cause on the eighth is if
you return a pointer and you have
as some six scratch which is the sum sum
into procedure climate justice and so on
it's actually quite easy did one that
if you write exploits will you be come
for confronted with the most will be you
register 30 and 29 which is the friend
point and the link for just a
about yet basically everything
like before up accrue from you is that
you can
all registers can be used either in
64-bit mode
or in such a bad mood so if you for
example you happen in 10 shit
implementation we work with 32-bit
integers
it won't be slowed down by checks where
for example if you rotate
wrote it shipped something your you have
to copy over the the first half
I into the second because you you need
to such two-bit
shifting the instructions that has not
all that and and you also have
32 additional floating-point registers
which is
useful if you're into science stuff
sink the on the old I'm simply use we
have
I the different modes basically if
you're your applications were always
running in user mode
the operating system was a running in
the system mod
and and some parts of your system might
even run in the supervisor mode which is
a slightly enhanced system mode and so
on
it was very very difficult to build it
for
virtualization and so on because they
fear you only have
by one Haas interrupt handler and its
a dedicated CPU mode and so on ads was a
lot of
over had to if you actually did real
virtualization because a and interrupt
was firing you have to check what
who what BMI and and what what am I
actually supposed to do and you couldn't
have a real
hypervisor on money to promote on the
niece year
the guest operating systems without a
lot of overhead
on the get rid of that and I we only
have four months left
up we have the whips sorry
I'm up we we have the a
years00 exceptional 0 which is %um
privileged mode we applications run in
we have the exceptional the one where
you into be operating system you kinda
and Swanson
and we have a certain and exceptional
way a hypervisor for example your
when you're just a bit will be your VM
there or whatever runs and and then
underneath that we have another mode
which is called is seeking money to a
arm which managers the state switch
between the
in normal mode and these so-called see
just ate
at this this graphic shows the mid how
it could look on actual system you have
fewer applications and exceptional
0 basically didn't do you lower your a
the exception that the number is the low
I A privileges
and for on foreign normal summer system
for example could look like this that
you have a hypervisor which is
RVM go whatever KVM and then you have to
guess
which would bill a Linux and then on top
of that applications
and then also money to mod and the money
to mod can be called to switch and Hugh
as secure stayed up to sleep you can see
just ate
a its up to love it too is missing but
you can run as CJ operating system which
can provide functions
to your guests to your hyper visor for
example poquito graffiti
say up if even if you have ideas
owned your seat area won't be on because
that
it's entirely dedicated and separated by
this money to live here which is
quite cool and and quite similar to what
we do today with Swiss trust them
and I'm I'm quite excited to see the
presentations
from ap to the bottom and up again
on the right hand side be
right um each privilege level
except iight exceptional level 0 canned
said
what causes level change basically you
cut tougher
hardware button that causes the CPU to
jump into exception at three or you
could have
as soon as a as a specific date axis
happened yes if you can jump to
to such a level 22 hypervisor for
example to mention a
memory access was hardware whatever and
so on a turn to be you can also
explicitly
call down from the exception that just
never up so exceptional 0 could just
issue and has some see instruction and
it would jump into the
on into the secure money toward
depending on
on the exact configuration it's quite
cool because you can
very finally con Fuego what happens
with the different permissions of the
excerpts from exceptional see you can't
even the operating system level
can be very lockdown and very limited in
what it can do
which could be interesting poll if
you're hypervisors
like my pic or something arm
yep there are also three different
interrupt vectors for the
exceptional to each if such love the
house its
own intro Victor candidates own
interrupts and so on
and for example an interrupted that
happens while the CPU is an exception
level 0 could
go into the exceptional to but then
the such a lovely determines okay I can
I checked this
I interrupt I can give it up to the
operating system again because it's
nothing
they need to care about
I mentioned earlier the co-processor
which is switches
I use to configure your and then you
you're catching and so on this
on now gone it's basically not this
architecture
we have a separate co-processor in your
heart it's now all done
a yet dedicated a system management
instructions
which yeah it's it's quite a nice change
and it still
back what's comfortable so you can even
if we if we go to
is a slight you can even have guessed
that still run
in on 32-bit
but the hypervisor on 64-bit and the
second guessed
is arm 64 bit too so it's it's really
cool because you can just from the
bottom up
up change architecture however you like
so you could even go want one
a 64-bit on Linux oren 32-bit ARM Linux
and the
the old red just the bank thing that
happened before is now
met onto the new registers
alrighty I'm port-au-prince real up for
this republics levels we obviously need
to have
different memory translations because
each
yet we r on operating system must not
run in the same
at this pace is your second operating
system and say
in the worst case you missed three
staged for translation of a memory
addresses from
virtual to physical arm
which how does seems to be fast enough
and it's it's quite cool because you can
shifty a your full translation tables
around and
each operating system still without any
any penalty kick and manage its own
memory no no need to call you high
proviso for doing
all that stuff welcome
I yep the function prologue and epilogue
on on the up on arm
64th a bit different to to what happened
before
because be follow-on I'm city to you
basically when you
went into a function on the registers
you were going to touch you just
thank them into onto the stack yellowed
I we just on multiple register
instruction unfortunately
or whyever her this instruction doesn't
exist anymore
now you can only store load Parisa
registers
say to and the compilers evenly Lake
even right now compile is already
optimized lot in that direction so they
try to avoid using a lot of registers
even though they have a lot of of them
available because you you would have to
have a lot apps
stop hair instructions to store so two
registers
arm but yeah the basic a
the the basic product just stores
your up the link register and your
friend point
onto the stack contributors to stake
twisted -32
a to reserve a space for your local
function variables and Swan and the
a and the Reese the year appeal ok does
the same suspect wats
loads your lingering just again lets
your friend point again
at 32 by to the Taser to do by to the
stock
and returns the return instruction does
nothing like an x86 Red
pops addresses and so on return really
just sets the
program counter to the current content
of the linked
register so it's just then unconditional
branch it doesn't do any magic lichen
x86
soon if we if we look at some example
occurred to power up
very very simple arm sees of function
which just takes an integer close
another function dats
to the result of the function this would
me what
the currency since the resulting is
Asian to
said it stores the current up the
current limiting resistor and Frank
pointer
it moves these current stack pointer
into the into the
a from point A its doors the
argument that was supplied to the a to
the function
into up Alan today
up onto the stack Rd B-sixteen is
basically the of that
to the Prime pointer and then it goes on
call
who the reason we copied the argument
over is that we we can be sure that
up foo won't touch register 0 because
we're just as he was overseas
return values
say to for returns we could be the
return value into
register we load our argument again
this Casey compile up to Mason optimizes
a bitch
City we had them together and then
just up store again
I missed of rampant a link register and
return
its its that easy it's really
a breeze to read because the amount of
instructions you have to know
it's really though and its very very
comfortable to
frightened read I'm sixty-four code
early I'm no es very small demo of
up of how you can
run I'm sixty-four stuff on your
a computer a were
great say I have the money to don't know
if it's
but I'm basically weekend just you see
the cone chemo
just had has full are 64 support at
least enough to put Linux on it
and if you if you want to experiment was
a real
I'm sixty-four use the land you can't
you can just get the Linaro
harbors and run them in QM at some point
something this case
a all the stuff will be on my kids have
half that is talking if the
international to work today
and in this case we can just boot up a
Linux kernel
in up on 64 mode
and the scrolling works that would be
great
well
world
yep and now we can look in this is the
roots normally used by
add to to compile stuff for the
architecture and its easy we now have a
attest to the land runs in I'm 64 and
yeah really be easy to use
to looked at the reverse engineering
workflow I'm
have also prepared a small demo of the
hopper disassembler
I'm for example we
the too because I think
to a in this case this is part of the
code we have before just in this case a
a whole excusable
and I can now adjust are
take me hopper disassembler and love my
binary in there
and it will immediately were
I'll all screens but small
will immediately find all the symbols
that included in the code and I can just
may be difficult
and see that the code we we had earlier
is
pretty much exactly what apart health
facilities
now too so it's really really a breeze
to turn every day with the tools you
already have
up love them will will come I'm sure I
will
also have some IDA Pro stretched which
you can find my get up which allow you
to
up to basically automatically search for
on coat
I'm sixty-four code in a blob so for
example if you have a bootloader
and here loaded into the IDA Pro
you can run the script and it will look
for the function appeal oaks and
function
prologues automatically to see functions
in in binary blobs where you have no
idea if they actually
code or data and so on it a try society
to bed
up array
so um for exploits on on on 64
unfortunately we can't do in deaf
because of our time limitation but I
just 20
you very short overview on how its the
different form from homes for 22 in
regard to
the the steak offsets and so on
but of all a its on 64 has two standard
mitigation techniques so your contest
you don't just have a execute will stack
and heap on the operating systems
a return to Lipsy is not possible
because at least the first
8 arguments will be in registers and not
on stock
arm and yeah unfortunately
compared to arms 32 especially when
you're working with Spurs bootloaders we
often a very small functions
it's difficult to find good catches to
configure registers
a as you want it since then important
goal if you want to
be able to call random functions and not
just three-ton oriented programming
captured
Trevor a function which loads memory
into registers
because the load multiple instruction is
now missing
a most compilers don't generate nice
gadgets for something more
so yes sorry separate I'm oriented
programming is the way to go
as always at the moment and yup
a if we compared the EPL ok of the
often on 32-bit execute herbal and and
and
I'm sings for exit pupil function
we see that in I'm 32 the
a the program counter the instruction
point in the memory where where the
current code is executed
up was directly loaded from the stack
i'd is not possible anymore because
on the new 64 bit architecture the new
PC
the polling plan is not writeable
anymore are
and it can only be modified by
instructions like
the like branch instructions and return
instructions
this is mostly as I've been told by an
I'm engineer because up
pipeline stuff basically the pipeline
needs to be flashed on a
return instruction and so on and even
the return instructions
signals to the CPU that this is not just
an unconditional promise you can do
other optimizations because this is a
return and so on. it's it's quite with
making but it's it's just important to
know that
basically reload the link address and
the previous frame pointer from the
stack
and the return will jump onto stacked
three this is I'm very very
us from the simplified version of
code from was does the vid bootloader
which
already run runs on on 64 in the
basically
I gives you group yep to conclude
on that una a basically gave you the
chance
to up supply recovery script that's
booted on the first food but you have to
have some authentication to actually run
the do come on function and so on
by I was able to founders sector will
flow
and Boulogne itself which could be up
used by a buyer
accuse be protocol message we can just
have full control over the stack
and after while upon this
reverse-engineered stuff from the boot
loader which basically allows me to
execute whatever I want
on the system given that I can control
the recover
Sanskrit which actually come
so return oriented program growing
basically means that we
we want to return from one function to
another and we control where we return
true so in this case
I have we get bay over break from the
the on stapling bridges that we get our
code to jump to
the return statement here to you attempt
to cover the Jazz Age
which were returned the address of the
string
into register 0
and then we want to jump to the system
called because then we can immediately
execute the shell script mister the buff
I because nicely to get recovers
re script function computer register 0
very nicely for us was a past that we
can you can execute
so yet we we want to jump to the address
at
a set up the first instruction sue
up then we want to return be at the
stock be there
frame that's stored on the stock to the
system
and we have a root shell in this case
was a very easy case and its
on a quite interesting device but I
can't get into more detail said as we
are in
responsible disclosure am yet
suit basically what what we do you like
on
like me the on most divisive on most
modern
exploits we have a stake in the flu
about this we over Breitling register
we up we jump we we pride our own
frame pointer and after that we put in a
second
languages time frame pointer onto just
taxing
understate cover plays bass in PD done
what's growing stack
and we just configured all link register
to
up to point to the return statement of
to get recovery script and offering
pointer
which which will be loaded by the return
as the new link register
and the new Franklin to address offering
pointed
points3 stay cover flow control it
make bridges to said the return instead
of returning to whatever
whether we came from like to return to
the system statement
and give us the possibility to execute
whatever you want
a and thats basically it's just a basic
overview
over the on 64 instructor and said
I hope you have fun and thank you
I other any questions
only topic or just
but me later forever
thank you here