hello there my name is Jon butterworth
amor security researcher at The MITRE
Corporation I'm going to talk to you
today about a
some research to my colleagues and I
have been working on are specifically in
the realm of
firmware attacks and defense I'm gonna
show you today some
firmware some Vanderbilt easily found
which permit the bypass value wi-fi and
Windows 8 secure boot
technologies whose
so what we have here is I just organ
refer to for a little while as the
amount where food chain
up here if I can get my mouse there so
here we have the %uh BIOS firmware
this is what foods as soon as you power
on your a PCR platform
this is the bootloader which the biocide
hands of control to once it's done
initializing all the firmware and
hardware
the bootloader them searches for a valid
operating system in Boots it
up to this point where your OS now in
as a general rule when talking about the
platform
boot process are rootkits that are able
to execute earlier
during the boot process are have are in
a position where they can compromise
code which executes at a later time in
the boot process
on now way back when
in the olden days are just really a few
years ago used to be that malware
running with sufficient privileges
on the operating system could almost
trivially overwrite
the BIOS firmware and worthy bootloader
for example the he used to be that the
BIOS firmware is protected by typically
nothing more than just to check some
on nowadays all systems pretty much are
using
assigned for more updates which insures
that only
a trusted assigned for more image
is allowed to be written into the BIOS
flash however
a that can only protect that which
is located on the BIOS flash so
in other words I have provides no
protection to areas a
herbal components that are located
outside the house where such as a boot
loader which is going to be located on
your hard drive or otherwise pics media
arm so in other words you can prevent
things like food kits are evil made
attacks in such however
UEFI BIOS which is the successor to
what's known as a legacy by our server
compatible or conventional PC BIOS I
implements a security feature called
secure boot secure boo
when it's enabled cryptographically
validates
platform food components like your
bootloader
I'm before permitting it to load
and then execute however p.m.
um secure boot only checks during the
boot process
that's it has actually no way to protect
the actual bootloader itself from that
initial malicious right to an attacker
can still
overwrite the boot the bootloader and
insert a good kid
however its relied on for platform
security that upon next reboot
secure who will check in authenticate
that image that bootloader
and deny it the ability to load and
execute in summary a secure boot
basically secure approval verify any if
I execute a bowl
on or just have two component if you
will that's found
by the UEFI BIOS during the boot process
I know this all depends actually on the
secure boot
policy so what we see here
is the verification handler this the
determines secure boots actions that
will take
on he filed its attempting to load and
execute based on
the originating location above that file
for example
if it's a originating on the boot on the
BIOS flash
its permitted to our automatically
always execute now this actually isn't a
bad thing
because its relied upon that the most
sign for more updates
have validated everything that's on the
BIOS splash so
always excuse generally OK however for
the other
on a boo locations mentioned here
option ROM removable media and fix media
on
secure boot will determine what to do
with those based on the policy that a
retrieves from storage on the flash in
we'll talk about where that's where
those are located
and then the default policy is to deny
excuse security violation which means
curable
automatically check an authentically
everything else it doesn't fit one of
these are key statements
so what we see here this is the
disassembly
love this secure boot policy
initialization this is a very dull
e64 30 bio serve is in heat 12 just for
reference
much actually like the system's I have
right here
what we see here so little bit messy but
we see the secure who policy is defined
by tooth while it's defined by the setup
variable
if the variable exists and if it's valid
and which case the contents have that
setup variable or what defines a
security policy
otherwise then India results just the
policies just hard coded
now the year five variables themselves
which is where the
security policies toward one of these
variables
other typically stored on the BIOS flash
that bio spices the same by a splashy
contains a bias excusable code
which execute on boo so here we have
the UEFI setup variable and we can also
see its attributes
I'm this is this set a variable from
that same a Dell laptop
so here we have NV which means it's
located on non-volatile storage meaning
it's located on the flash
the BS here is a we don't really care
about that but that means that this
variable can be modified from the food
services
it's really just a requirement for the
RT here which is only really care about
our team insists variable can be updated
or modified from
from within the operating system
so it's accessible by what's called the
runtime services and I you if I world
so what's missing now is some attributes
that requires that any application that
wants to modify this variable
being authenticated application but as a
result to that I can show you
few attacks against care so
as a Windows 8 microsoft provides an API
for interacting with the with these
variables
a get firm firmware environment variable
set for more environment variable just
two
have those there are others as well
so the first attack is pretty obvious
since there's no authentication required
a we can simply a offers news when we're
looking at here
this is the setup variable again just a
little further down this is the secure
boo
on an off by TSO on is one so secure
boot is enabled
and if this were to be 0mb of on
here is the secure boo policy bite them
refers to the
firmware a flash a origin so in other
words a size zero means are always
execute
and his remaining force mean always deny
or deny execute on security violation so
on these would be for the FX media the
CD-rom in
USB I think the other one so
as a result though because because this
variable is accessible from
within the operating system week in a
modified
the firmware environment variable just
using the API which is a little bit a
privilege
required I'm to do so so we can use it
to set the security policy to always
execute
regardless of the origin of the media
the file that's trying to load an
Execute
so as a result even though secure boot
in this case is still unable because we
didn't actually disable it
on it's effectively disable however
because its permitting everything so
it's not really doing its job do you
think it's doing
I'm so things like food kitserver
drivers are
malicious option runs anything really
can just execute without any
verification whatsoever
so in summary this one's a little more
stealthy
but this one is a exploitable from usual
and to
disable the security policy or
effectively to say what I say
for make the permissive religious is the
right way to say it on
boot kits will function unimpeded and
secure boot however will still report
itself is running in functional
the us his way see this more stealthy
attack
this next one is a little bit I clumsy
but this is just something that we try
to see what happened
I so we tried deleting the setup
variable oh when you delete this setup
variable and
UEFI world did reverse the system to
what's called a Gaia
legacy I guess legacy boot mode so in
other words
cuba is effectively disable because at
that
and us good get some such can also
execute a secure boot is also disabled
however when you go to sexy a pursuit
secure who's running
it will see its not running so it's not
exactly stealthy implementation but it
is exploitable from usual and just like
the other
on and again boo kits works you without
any authentication
so the third one is really just kind of
an offshoot
at the second one because we found out
that when we do this I just pay secure
being I disabled from the OS when we do
it the actual reboot
the UEFI firmware before secure routers
even-par the picture
detects that the setup variable is gone
I'm and so what it does is it worth
restores
the contents %uh that set a variable
from another variable called standard
defaults
no standard defaults and forcefully
suffers from the same Malays
as does the set a variable it's located
on the non-volatile flash its only
problem with services who cares
but it is still available from the
runtime services without any of
indication whatsoever so
if you gonna modify the contents have
you set a variable but %um is also
modify the content substandard faults
unless you have a little more
persistence in your a
making your security policy more
permissive or something else a secure
policy
permissive
a so I'm how this is
fixed is actually pretty simple a you if
I
in there specifications they provide
other
additional attributes which can be
applied to variables one of these being
an authenticated right
access meaning that the application that
wants to update or modify this variable
must be authenticated and signed by
choice key located one the keystore
variables which I'll talk about a little
bit I'm
there's actually another authenticated a
access
attributes at all to record it 7 the
timestamp Zazzle's called timing based
authenticator write access but this is
adequate week usually see most of the
time
other summary this vulnerability
I is the what we call reported this with
Intel I'm this certain numbers here
and basically it summarizes this
vulnerability allows bypasses secure boo
on many systems as some keep in mind
because it's not strictly
result is delaware this model in fact I
mean just we first identify this
vulnerability on a Dell
e64 30 but it's not limited to the deli
in fact is not limited to Dell as an OEM
its across other additional volumes as
well
on and if we looked into the idea by
the UEFI reference specification also
called you know core
I if you will and we looked into that
and this vulnerability is not existent
in there as well
a block these variables down properly to
so which means that someone took the
reference specification
and at some point unlock them and didn't
remember to
lock them down again or should say
require authentication to modify them
so the it leaves basically one
hard who is responsible for this that
would be the independent bio spenders or
IV these
these are the guys like American
megatrends inside Phoenix
they're the ones the downloaden take the
reference specification and then a
modified the at a lot of proprietary
stuff
and they sell it to the OEM's like Dell
HP and all the rest
on so specifically who did it well
I'm it doesn't appear in the reference
specification a
vulnerability affects multiple OEM so
it's not tell it's not where the OEM's
they don't sell to each other their
competitors the vulnerability was
introduced by an IV V
based on our analysis it was a I'm
so in we've seen
how if I variables that her trivially
writeable
without requiring authentication I can
be abused
arm by an attacker now
not all here by variables of course are
non authenticated
I'm some of them require knowledge a
private key
in order to be modified I'm
ever authenticated variables such as
this a story very important
information on the system regarding
secure boot in other aspects of the
system to
for example like there's the accused or
that
basically contains a list above
whitelisted hashes
a VAP occasions and drivers which are
permitted to execute there's also a
blacklist
in there and then there's a a a listserv
operas keys
which the additionally witcha
applications attempting to loan execute
are allowed to be signed by
and gesture reiterate these a
authenticated variables
on the SPI flash are located basically
just alongside the BIOS firmware execute
a bull
which actually raises a bit of a problem
for the vendor's
my vendors in this case I really mean
the OEM's on
the Dells in the HP's insights so
basically what it boils down to
is at the SPI flash for the BIOS flash
just for simplicity
is getting pretty crowded it's getting
harder and harder to manage
all the rate ability requirements up
these
these variables I mean you have the BIOS
execute a ble which during runtime
should never change so that should be
read-only
but then you have these variables which
per UEFI spec
must be writeable during runtime they
must be sometimes the operating system
some them are arbitrary not that
important but some of them are important
but they all have to be writeable from
from the operating system during runtime
so the question is how can alway M's
securely implement
these a all these different read/write
permissions
a these co located a food all these
comps located components all these
variables alongside the
by 06 a cuticle so
Intel does provide some perfect
protection
mechanisms there which can help they
provide a a number of protections that
can help lock down the SPI flash
they can be summarized into two basic
group
to basic and it is really a there's
global rate protection and then there's
range
rate protection and it's up to the OEM's
to implement these
so we'll talk about the global rate
protection first this
is all managed by the this sings
legacy has been around for years and
talked about for years but it's called
the BIOS control register
what it does in a nutshell is a provide
system management mode the ability to
control
a the raid ability of the SPI flash
so what happens here ZF two bits the
BIOS lock enable
in the BIOS great neighborhood the only
way the BIOS flash can be written to
is if there by was right nablas asserted
so that's all fine and dandy there's
news the buyers Larkin able
that when it's when it's asserted it can
be dessert until the next review
but when it's asserted that means that
when the BIOS right nipple bitten
is also asserted in those two bits are
both asserted together
that triggers are generates system
management interrupt
no system is interrupt is one that
transitions
this CPU processor from protected motor
whatever long motor whatever was in
before
into system management mode I means all
other running processes are suspended
the system enters system management mode
executes the SMI Candler in that secure
memory space and a and then resumes back
and then the the processes that were
suspended
are resumed again after that now during
this time in system isn't known in this
case however
I wanna those checks it does is part of
its normal routine
is to take a look at this bios rain able
bit if it sees its asserted
and it knows it did not actually
initiate this rate
to the BIOS splash in owes its night it
should not be allowed
energy asserts this bit back to zero so
when the processor resumes back to
now protected mode on the offending
application I was trying to
assert this page here season 0 and
brought back seat thinks it's actually a
read-only bed
but it is actually read right so his
this to a step through the process kinda
so we have a the attacker process here
irony is rings 0 because it requires a
what you to portray or the ability to
Matt memory as we have bio's control
here with the BIOS lock
enabled as set to one so that when
the attacker whips there's a bit too
want to make the by a swatch writeable
generates Isis management interrupt the
Cebu transitions Asus management mode
BIOS rate enable is reset back to zero
in the system resumes back to the a
back to the attackers code for any
application for that matter that
attempts to set BIOS rate naval
with the BIOS lock enable set
and thus the bias remains read-only now
it's a important to know that the only
way in
out up system management mode is through
a system management interrupt I should
say
the only way into sis management mode as
fierce as to my sis measuring drop
the only way I would assist management
was be at the resume function but
instruction but that's kinda be on the
the point whose
so now we'll talk about the second
protection mechanism provided by Intel
was very briefly it's the that's called
the protected range registers
these basically enable the Year by host
the ability to program protected range
have the Flash and make you right to
rate protect the Ranger the flash we can
actually also said read protection to
deny reads beret protection is the most
practical
I'm and then to lock it all down because
as we noticed looking at these
here these registers are always read
writeable by you have to be a lock them
down to the wire some could just
remove your protected ranges so there's
this other or register
the sequencing registers it's a it's
after lock down to splash lockdown
and that once at was so once you have
all your protected Rangers said
the new setup lockdown was protected
ranges can no longer be modified until
the next reboot
so the challenge is just to restate the
challenge for the OEM's
is at what it boils down to is that the
year 5 variable region
must be writeable so therefore it can't
use those protected range registers
it has to rely solely on system
management mode to protect
that range those variables which is all
fine and dandy is on a system as remote
can always
run and reset the BIOS flash to make the
flash
to keep the flash read-only
however we found you can actually
suppress system management interrupts
'em which effectively bypasses
any in all protection mechanisms offered
to you by system management
mode from within system engine mod
the bio skin this bypasses those BIOS
control protections have the Flash
that I just talked about on it does not
require anything other than just a
little bit of privileges
executing from the operating system I
you don't have to execute any code or
anything like that from system engine
mod
you do this right from your OS and
suppresses my so
how to do this is via the SMI
enables control register it's located in
the power management
registers have the chipset on this is
just
the global assume I enable this disables
all different types
%uh system as manager apps however
that's part of a larger register that
contains other
bits that can be set to disable specific
kinds of interrupts if you want to go
fine-tune
which says mise you allow and disallow
I'm
but the point is I'm showing you the
global one because it disables
all system management interrupts
so if this register is not locked by
asserting
when I see you laters the SMI lock bit
when I say to present prevent this
as some eyes are disabled
with SMI suppressed we are allowed to
write to that
variable region of the flash and
effectively bypass
largest disable the protections provided
by the BIOS control and sis management
mode
on as a side note we've been serving a
lot over
machines like throughout our company in
a couple other organizations
and forty percent the system surveyed do
not have this bit set
and there's another note here which says
you can also technically downgrade most
bio says to
depending on whether sign in our weather
baseline signatures
and then you can also even if a a so in
other words if a BIOS has been patched
in as resolve this
if you downgrade the BIOS you might also
be able to re enable this vulnerability
in the system
so this is how it works when SM eyes
have been disabled
so again the attackers trying to set
BIOS rate naval
it's important to note that buyers like
enable is still set
I'm the attacker flips bit 1
it up the a BIOS flips BIOS rain able
thus
SPI flash is now enabled what would
normally happen of course is a system
which transitions system is winnowed
in that bill would be D asserted and
then the attacker wouldn't be able to do
anything with it however because I some
eyes are suppressed
the system never transitions to system
management mode and that by was right
nipple bit stays asserted
and the attackers now free to modify any
portion of the bio said he
can one thing obeyed I did mention
earlier about the protected range
registers
I'm with projected range registers in
place
the those don't rely on system
management mode so technically protected
range registers will also prevent
rights to the flash but as we know from
what I was saying earlier
that the variables at a minimum must be
writeable
so you can use a protected Rangers is on
those in
so much you can do to protect them in
this case
I'm so these variables like the setup
variable which contained in to find the
secure boot
up that of an authentication
settings I'm can now be modified in the
sole out revealed by passive secure boo
kinda like what we're doing we're
modifying the setup variable earlier
it's all pretty easy
stuff via demo video to show you
so
okay so what we're doing his words going
to demonstrate this is a UEFI system
this is the UEFI shell
now I'm basically it's like a edges
command line interface from here you can
know
go into every spouse systems that this
system is overloaded
and you can execute things like a really
care bootloader and such to boot into
windows and
whatever what we're going to do is we're
going to attempt to load
ASEM bootloader which is the attackers
Google Alerts
one that but a bouquet basically
benign to keep it yes so now what we're
showing you here
is that excuse me okay
so earlier I had mentioned those a
those authenticated variables these are
the ones that contain we see the
waitlist two passes
this is the waitlist year the DB is DV
databases the waitlist
passes so in other words if you have a a
if you harass
to gas up like a a unified drivers on
the road and put that ass in here
that will be permitted to execute I'm
we're just showing you these mbna is I
just sat there too
just to show you a that when we had a
new one it will be a
very visible as a currently the
permitted Chivers
I'm just gonna boot into the legitimate
operating system
so rate you're using flash from
to dump the BIOS flash to says a lot
about but
I'm sees this opens important
because so here to search just as a
warning to show
that I'm attempting to write to the
flash on
earlier can went by quick but this is
the BIOS
control registers located off-site DC in
what's called a low pin count
PCI device sir lacy device been there
for a long time but it's a
offset DC is that by was control
register I just lost it on here
I'm it's been disabled so in other words
a
the value of their so what it's saying
in a nutshell is that buyers lock is
enabled
and Assis manager Graham has a reset by
was writen able back to zero so that we
can try to it
so what we doing is we're going to I
disable
surmising this in the method I say which
civil script that does that
I'm which is in a we just had
do you sir SMI enable bit 0 in the power
core there
I was at the video
it's failed because buyers like a
neighbor said
I call you put this together college
stars
heard had to look it up to see what that
was
so
what we're doing now is we're actually
able to flash a bow so what we've done
show you a moment for you just projected
here
is a base with you Buy rating to the
flash we took their we took the hash
above are a %uh are shame
bootloader and added it to the DB
whitelist
so we expect that it should now be able
to boot
to go back into the approved we're only
going to leave because that's the only
way to actually with the mall but
I'm so now we see the the additional
these arc which is just how are you if I
names objects and such but
we see the new addition added to the
waitlist so
now we can do to the show we can again
try to
load a to Lodi rush im x64
which to see said my colleague wrote
this juvenile
the years
it's actually surprisingly easy to do
it's also easy to prevent no one seems
to know about it
so
in a that is very possible to pull off
in a
prevents us measure RAM for my being
able to protect your BIOS flash
on if you're interested in learning how
to lock it down
this is how this there's actually a
couple ways you can do it for starters I
mentioned earlier there's esmi
lock bit it's located in what's called
the gen
power management configuration register
up
also located in that core area where the
other ones were it so I'm
basically containing hiya that register
contains a big called as my lock
that when it said all the contents up
there SMI enable register
are locked in place so what the strategy
should be then
is that once Asus measuring is
configured by the BIOS
in that once it's all set and ready to
go that they have to ensure that
as some eyes are configured ready to go
and then assert this bed
to prevent any further changes to it
like a
someone wants to suppress system
management interrupts I'm
and then the second way to prevent this
is parade newer bit there was at it also
to the BIOS control register
as the one there's so much earlier that
lets as some RAM
decide who and what gets to rate to the
flash this bit
is a relatively new I guess is fuse old
so
I won't call new but it's a SMM BWT by
was right protect
our bus ride to sable I'm PSD is
for P is for disable on the I have
what it says basically is set the SPI
flash cannot be written to
and was all cores that the CPU are in
system engine mod
so even if a so what what that means
is a if this bit worser did this
requiring the processor
in all its course be in suspension or
before the BIOS flash can be written to
even if you did serve suppress system as
we enter ups
and then assert by was right enabling
the bass control registers
you could modify the SPI flash you can
modify it all because just mention
the CPU will never enters this mission
mode so it's kinda
nifty love chess move here this bitch
pretty much always be set
but again most vendors do not as you'll
see from our
research results coming up on
so the currency the protection is less
than great
over 10,000 system so far we've
evaluated in only would release 6
them have actually had the SMM BIOS rate
protective its set
pass rate Disable Bit set a about 40
percent of the system's measured as I
said earlier
a did not have the SMI lockset maybe a
table might have
SMI lockset I'm so
more vendors and this is really
responsibility though Williams but the
OEM's really need to be
aware of this and to to set their biases
to configure this
these bids to prevent trivial attacks
like this this is really easy stuff
we actually have for more talks in the
works coming about
also other ways to bypass secure boo
protections and such but
that's for another day but these are
like them
easiest to do so basically
in summary the secure boo
and is it is a good thing for the most
part it allows
it does provide your system protection
from a malicious or unwanted
executed wills from executing during the
boot process like a pool or something
like that
said kid I'm however it's defined
by variables located on the plastic can
be trivially overwritten if not secured
those variables must require
authentication to be modified
and then of course the underlying
architecture underneath that
in the chipset must also be configured
so that the systems
most important resources like system is
remote can actually do their job and
protect your system
from malicious rights to the flash I'm
his sister was have some related work
we've been working on as well till on
soccer bypass Windows 8 secure boot
arm and defeating signed by us and force
me to use
some intelligence to
rick martinez is actually will tell I'm
we did disclose all this
to them prior to her ever releasing in
such a course
I'm actually convinced
very quickly a speaking very quickly but
and it does anyone have any questions
anchors