and we are going to talk about crossing
River cinemas
this is a our agenda and that the peace
that we are going to talk about the
during his presentation so first of all
who we are Association am in a midget B
an imposition just answered with a
researcher at the light on who grew up
in security
I'm also upper beak for some you have my
blog
to tack on an email going to want to
contact me
no pennies per year competition there's
there's a good year said
and a nigger and this is a great
addition he was known
and the city's or a real and min
you wonder what that mean okay
what this book is about this turkey sub
out:
our research team backup servers and
white pickup service
will because we think they are critical
for companies
backup server some backup plans because
if you fuck
or compromise our pick up Sarah back up
claims you could
compromise hand in tech company also
because they are so let's get this over
so they should be secure right but as
you probably know
on as you would see during the
presentation they are not secure hope
then we start to use this backups are
releasing we could be a
as you can see in the right where we
come final at the fair
different backup for looks from
different vendors and we found
several a on their reducing at the
backup applications
here when work we are going to talk
about their respective because on their
knows a plan to pick up by the course we
found and under the and he's using other
products but we won't talk about them
because we don't have enough time
because of legal issues as well but the
important thing here is that
using these techniques that we're going
to talk about here you will find
venero this in a lot of other products
on this is for sure
okay so let's start this year the party
there on the fixes for the save money
reduce it that's way because
been thirsty and tried to contact us so
same we want to show you how we do how
we fund this kind of a issues
step-by-step and then you will find more
in other perks for sure
on that bike aprox least on we know that
I love you are with people on use these
issues with evil intent
on I'm of course we won't be responsible
your
you with a BS universal what I want to
allow these
not understand what up sir the summer a
place that we will use
in my nasa as you can see in the sum was
paid will have to do that
NC double 1 month ago through this bet
was solid
cement were as you can see the copyright
a in the passing of fun summer
these asthma corruption stuff but no my
buddies were report
seen 2008 so the season yeah it was a
report anyone ID
opinion these so much time a lot of rest
at me
there said women that there was a
request to respond using gonna be
but with gonna be a race it's amazing to
and he's
you can see that the property by some
weren't gonna be
weekend them play with almost anything
in this bizarre
on the left you can see there is if I so
would I'm on the right you can see
they're gonna be love
milieu have a7 o'clock and
to this but the Dixie the server but the
plane that this is the client
and English to listen you have to the
bus were I was never interested in it
too
you blame me so this message about day
and his day
the screen at the gonna be okay so
we know the plans have to send a
buzzword deserve it why because if you
don't mind but we're in the money box
others ever in once any bug so is
everyone now has the bus waiting anybody
said
but when the planes in the bus were okay
you know this
every these is better and went
when the client died to the server they
do up
it so the but they say by imposing
business Callisto and that they miss me
miss me if I this year
the is this another another bucket
that the claim send
the server and related but where is he
did decided is but the we gonna be
we realized that these bites the a the
eight
baby stuff unlikely but about that
so we're going to sue them for the
controversy innovate on the hollywood
a good a
in this case we use but points in their
previous and be fun since
and then go further in the debugger to
pick up with two
but the cumbersome as you can see here
in the the left
we have then put it back in the canopy
look
thank you have in the debugger and when
the function
victory is called around and we look at
the buffer we will be able to
to see attempted to pack it in the
memory dump as you can see here
okay you have their political heather's
and
and get it back so %uh so seen
the you see how r britt points we don't
find the functions
with under the so good we are looking up
for example in the read the packet here
in the first bite if we said have a
break point in the a bite
and when any instruction will try and
to read the writing these bite we the
debugger will stop
on we will be able to see what is going
on and doing these we found this
interesting function
which the group include the packet been
some
HR operations on
cue have the Tupac can de Maria
so the
our mingle here very now it's where's
the bus were in these they put it back
in now
as you can see here we were doing so far
this with the bus were test and the
password this one
on we realized that these up as
warehouse
Okies four bytes bus route bus warehouse
so for you
if we are able to the previous pocket
using an exploit and get the house
we will have upon their eighty you won't
be a really big
and primarily to get but unease air
it's ever going to start so we need
something think I'm reverse the whole
process here
and then we found three important
functions here and is it ok to call
these functions
now our mingled series how is the house
back at the grid because we want to wait
and explode know that to get the house
any plant in the sophomore then we found
this function
the funds from one and the scenes from
the calibrations for test the
she flipped she's right on or and so on
you will couple 84 bytes you seen as a
parameter
the following 32 bytes key this is dead
32 bytes key
and these key is the claim Burcham
that's the claim postname
Plessis that the key remember that the
time for some the time hostname
we we got this information from the
claim on this that the key
we found it in the barracks a constant
as you can hear as you can see here
South 32 bytes contact consent
and it's always the same their summer
fun soon the function to
as you can see here the cold a surreal
loops on
it with the four bytes from france from
one assignment you will generate
I want answered on 24 bite every as you
can see here and
in a memory dump then there's another
function the function 3
and with their last right from France in
two snowmen
you will create another a rate of one
person that for by the rate
doing some X operations between the left
or right from France into
on this wiki remember this cutie was the
camber simplistically
person employed that is that the key
then to find someone who will
it will be called a game and doing the
same legal abrasions
and using its not mean the last every
from France on three he will generate
another four bytes
then the function to he would call the
game on with the last
for rice from france someone he will
generate another and every
I'm finally the funds from three the
doing some extra rations between the
last every from France into
and include the packet you would agree
to buy gift okay
so as to marry you have this graph it's
pretty simple
we have three functions and they will be
called twice
and then on a very important thing that
we
really need here for all works but is
this Ricky here's a summary
every woman response to the study is the
key remember I think he's done but with
Liam Messam
the issue and the plane causing palace
at the key
but we found Nevada so we have
everything we can raise Brainerd
we were interested
rains bring her to the difference but
was running claimed so is not
do we just need to secure the funds in
1283 uneasy with the Panthers
day with work this is the
first packet that we have to send and in
the client respond with the plane was
handed
that we have to send this and I have
been but did
and these responds with these like
contain
he has so we're going to put all these
together an abutment
this is the by then go to the Senate and
they sell
on this simply go by the response and
one
this is fun to do is another
by representation of the same legal the
funds in due course
and is defined the funds in 30 days
another Michael
assembled festival have to so some
requirements
we don't mind the meal we just need to
send the packet to
to the client them have the same another
packet
basic unit monsoon I'm finally with the
house opening lines and to see you in a
team
cases the cold
is awkward respect and we went to secure
the
despite in this is the the key
and this is going to the packet
and into the provides the firm 21
great I was first therapy
this is the
purse by Kent and then the first they
claim fortunately I met him
after the signing up in bucket give us
and packet account in the house
on finally hours keep
have 20 it is the critical packet
I'm save you can get a this house
in this case you missus us
so
now we have the ability to get the house
to finish line okay
but what can we do with these hos as you
can see here
we have the house of the bus were tests
on the price of the password is one
it's always for Vice Haas on it sings at
all as you can see here
so he suffered bites haha so we have
four be impossible
unique bus course and a maximum of their
reducer respect but we're getting these
the
31 carter's on we can use moralist and
ninety possible characters
on this bus were so at this is the
number of their posture but between
application
which is really big on take back on this
number
on the for vice versa the collision
number is this one
which is really really because well even
more than atoms on their
so is really weak an ass you probably
could be thinking right now
yes this is her I need your love
vulnerability
by the press will try to go further in
these then that we found a house
function
I which is a fun someone we know more or
less some leaders have a response from
but will try to explain
more details and or the Fun Center in
the following slides
I on dysfunction would take us not mean
they're clear text password which is
in this case is best okay on
he will do some legal persons to see
fleshed seabright
on or then you will multiply a.m.
it will do I'm to be getting off the
cutter for the bus were
by itself and then he will do on annex
for a free sim
on when they're fun to use a stick
executed
it will generate the house of the bus
were as you can securely in the
yes register so with these
how come we fine a vulnerability here
our hong kong exploit these
Wellington through that we need to use a
mouse
you have to find someone else to go
which is easier for us to understand and
we have to look carefully at life I from
at like seven in line at seven we have
today
extirpation of their and with the
because not they cut their
the bus were by itself we'll talk about
the suppression later
but now we have to focus on line 5 where
we have this leaflet
operation they are very soon the sea
freight abrasion on the
on 3 operation here on three operation
we think that their developers try to
use
these and as a mask in order to protect
the beast during the rotation
but as you probably know three binary
and any on the bridge in with your in
the result you will have a zero and
that's where ABC's her failure
because if you want to protect all the
peace during their addition in this
particular case they must
should be seven because seven is 111
there's no sir
and you of I threw in the result you
have
the Telegraph where we have the
the 32 beats of the Haas or the 32 bits
of their resold variable in this cold up
before the rotation
on the because have the
how the British in works on and the most
important thing because of the
and three promoted is there a team and
in the first iteration of the loop at
they beat
to will be erased okay
and then the five and then the big
lemon and so on and that's what
we come bill a password with scarce in
Pasadena
easy way okay you have
this graph this graph we are going to
use is refered to
X exploit and explain how it works you
have
well and this crap sorry represents how
the beats
are erased in funds from one if you have
the 32 be tough for the house and
remember that we have the house
we have the lead to get the house open
again so we have to get the house open
again so we have lit
the beats he would have the 30 the
excellent of the bus when the
application which is
31 cut this so sane we will try tonight
a 3-1 length password which serves the
same house if you remember in fashion
when we have we have
and we have these and their operation DX
or
of them with the baton to cut their of
the bus or by itself
and that's why we will use carter's 2934
our new bus were
because Scott the two and three in
excess amount multiply by themselves
will have these binary numbers
and we will use the third law was
beating this binary numbers
let's see how it works for example we
have as ear
in this house bead in this particular
case if you want to start from the
let's cut the buzzword the number thirty
will have to use one
these two binary numbers starting from
hear from the lowest bid
I will have in this particular case will
have to put on
the same beat in the back is clear that
we have in this and a high-speed
so in this case is here will use the
Carter three and now we are selling
their house between this case
the following cut there's will use will
use the same
a logic but also we have to take into
context corporation
for example if we have here i won in
this high-speed
will have in to putting this back at
square beat
with the weeds doing an exhibition
between these be done
all the beats which are below are the
same column
their result has to be the same as this
one for example here would
jere XR between 0&1 they were so will be
one
so now here we we are answered in their
hearts beat
as well and the following potential uses
in late thinking they're gone
decks or person up this be done all the
beats with Harbhajan Singh column
again and again on in the last case
forgot their 0 will you sir and their
own unique
and because we have to fix or put two
beats
and that's why because if you remember
we have 32 has beats
on 31 Carter said in the bus were so
because of that difference that's why we
got
we have to to boot to beat
and also will use cutters in this case
two three four and six because
using those cart this we will have all
the possible combinations in the binary
numbers
for example if we have a1 a0 here
will have to start from here from those
bit like always
on a will have to put in the box where
be tweets
doing an ex or praise Him between these
be done all the beads which are below
are the same column
as you can see here in this weather
redline the result has to be the same
at this one I hear the same I'm putting
all this lady together in Argo tea from
we will be able to be in a password
which church is impossible
in a seaway the this is had the cold
it's pretty simple we are you seeing
Carter 2&3
on courtesy 6 it to 304
for the last case the car here but the
the best way to show you how it works to
the matter should be
but first full like always repairman
suite on the main the media as you know
we just need a.m. the house which we got
from exploit one
and we will be the bus were which has
the same house
on will use their respects her murder
trial version which is free
entree talk this to recline the city how
it works
okay you have the server we are up in
the plane
in the IP 69 and a plane is asking for
the password this is that a feud between
the claim them
the server and now
just approved will use the bus were dead
which is
that'll pass or of the crime just
disapprove
copy would be here
to cooking if you have the traffic
between the client and the server
and as you can see there are a lot
computer packets will talk about the
simply too packets leader
a hue have the counterpart of the guy
and we can pick up to lose
on everything's working that's okay now
we will to lead to the client and we
will at it again this AM
AP others AP 69 again
the Kings asking for the password on now
will use
our explode I'll will use the
on this from similar to calculated their
at the house of the bus were tested dust
has approved but
remember that we have to read look at
the house of unclaimed aren't we will
pass the house
to these minor and a binary will give us
a bus were 31 mince pies were with
sources him past
as you can see here good
copy you
to prove people have
as we're based
here okay
now here we have taken to open up the
Glen but if
we look carefully at the canopy look we
can see that did
servers trying to send an increase the
packet to the client and the client is
not responding so something's not going
work here
and if we click tools in the control
panel for the client
we will have this number error so the
finale
something is not going well here seaway
is a respected
30 the plant you senator belittle with
them
request/response response so is that the
thing that increasing numbers using the
brim
that made this possible as the as if it
was a big issue and you can see the bus
go to the client
okay do is understand we realize the
diana's personal information to the
server in order to this event has to
know the password and you scenes about
this
finally and this to pass course hey this
is a
possible we'd has the same house
as you can see in the screen but pasa
this for a vice
completely different so we know that
these that isn't the clay and we have to
set the password
as a willing to take wouldn't be much
client indonesia is your mind but they
will have to listen to me by slim
we realize how we see the san vincente
so upset about this possible that could
be interesting because he's we called
the first time that we going to change
the password
i'm following this month's human would
realize the
will be call the summer fun too because
blow is a key ingredient Lee
so we're going to lose the however Hall
what is the sponsor bed you have largely
depends on one
remain friends in well with it and
reappraisal home
and see right and so on the beach at the
we realized that he defines into with
many loops to and that would increase
the pension 3
with exploration on their own and soul
so is the day in the middle but
again I D somehow with the pain as
possible using our FEMA funds in 100
so into fine how these my bike generated
and we make at this at this with but
were tested
on we're going to see with you said
Howell
how these for my advice will be in the
80 you see me up bro and DB server
in
sorry okay
you have they the pro we are using their
debugger find a pro we have updated
their the line is claiming you seen
deliver GB said: DB server dealings
efforts between
on things asking for the first time
response were
I'm but we typed their taste buds were
and the phone someone
he will be called and using this moment
as you get here
in the cleartext password and Emery them
then
when he secured it will generate the
house of the bus were this is not new
for us
and then the funds into it will be
executed
and using this indictment the house of
the password you can secure in the
memory them
again this is not new for us
it will generate they want the sentence
for by director
on them
defines him three to scold
Creed
doing create using the sacrament
the the last every from France into of
funds into
undeclared experts were and this is new
for us
okay and it's important we'll see what
you will
generate another 1,000 in the 4-byte a
rare
I'm finally
defines him three which is the funds
from one again sorry the passbook
he will be
it will be executed using the time in
the last array from France in three
on when he succeeded
it will generate these interesting for
much but
180 defy simple so
the format to bite
I didn't read it with the house
underpinned experts were we have the
house
but we don't have the Pantech spies were
remember that we have the ability to get
the hassle from the plan and we have the
ability to be the bus were
password switzer system us we now have
they been to expose were
the real that a buzz-worthy of the kind
so at this point we thought that he was
pretty difficult to get something good
here
but the let's do some us again dust case
months and
for Megabus when you ready for the bus
were the house this is the crap
somehow how to make a bus will be united
me but that means there has the right to
with grated
is using the bus going clear: this and
that i won
and everyone is mediated using the house
and it doesn't last forever alone is
known to us
is that the is that value for us
possibly are there some way so we want
those entering for my son ray using this
form one
miss formula is a former have to use in
order to be there are 82
punching my result will be you know as
it was a good help these on either
so important that they do I have the
right one about why I think the way so
that i won
you have given it is gonna is rather
ever-present
the way that the beats will be rated the
gray area
is the I an area where they have its
will be erased so
is an important and then I heard that
the two until one thousand
3 I believe this is that they do but so
that
up there right so bisbee these bites
would be using it to play in a problem
because he's between I I want this entry
for
ira as a real is that the because
is not left the house day we only have
to take care of the spot
from okay and police party said
the solo tease love towers or got a
result
and gone to see I somewhat agree
this is the hardest and this is the
excess amount value
on the bus were tested if you saw I love
the constant between them
we get his number numbers is think so
the tree would be to get a buzz word
which says missing hot and also if
you're a bitch
characters between them we get the same
number good
as we have to store only been able
carter's on 20 27 and
we get 109 27 numbers
got it a so you only have two
brute force
the one hundred 100 these this is the
the bus were the we are going to create
so we'll have to
pick up okay because you're so I love
the cut it in then we got several 12
in this case in the case of dead will
have to take care of these numbers a
numbers thing this is they are going
that could make it possible you because
we didn't need us
for you okay a game
the explode 3 the prime in sweeping new
a game Miami then we just need to the
house which we got from split one
will be the bus were with says him past
and the same for multibyte
on a game will use ever disperse ever
tell person
see how it works
okay you have or binary super house by
nine
we'll will give to these binary the
house of the bus were
undefined there will give us all the 128
possible but worse now
hula playing a game
here
are using the bus were test which is
react well bus were asleep when
against approve click OK and
you have the country on a flight plan we
can keep
tools it's working that's ok so now
adding the clean again and now we will
use
our first bus tour from
hours split you
as we're could be the password please
here okay and knock you have to come to
power
but if we click to lose is not working
we have the same network error
so this bus were is selling the same
house but he's not certain that the same
for my two bites
as you body could be thinking right now
the worst case scenario here
is that we have to try it with 110 to
pursue a bachelor's
but the move don't worry about that
because the there because some
want to block you you tried with many
passengers
the peaceful decision upon so now
the will here with we know that there by
bus were in this case is
the number sixteen because we're
here
to prove now
here is the password okay now is getting
slower
screening for us you have the
conta bunny pana I'm finally forget
those is working
we can do a lot of stuff weekend they're
going to the clan
weekend do any and backup task over
start ask
we can copy any files of defy system
as you can see here we can connect to
the hard drive connect
and get any file and so on
so finger
so with this we don't have full access
to any remote client
anyone any sort we don't need
the main the mirror in Tina's we come
back up we're sorry the file
for example restoring and it'd except
David sounds good right we can execute
any except able after any backup restore
task a sec future of the application
so we can to promote call this a
gruesome because of this feature
underscores we tried with more
compressed password and test
we tried with the super secure passwords
you get here
and this is the house this POS were
on in this case there by the bus or will
be the first one
okay now we haven't thought about the
do this over other backup server is the
number to find a backup
it %ah a backup plan sobered by the use
bus home famous companies
such as CNN's Motorola breyer coming of
course
docs and
there on the put together by reducing
the spread at the scene
during our set so we decided to test it
Justin profession and then we found on
the 5th edition by bus
Anna crews permanent annual service
first we'll be there for the kitchen by
bus
and the first the like always will be.
understand the condition for the go
II's Jia the brassiere on
and where such house they sectors for
this but it also
with new for us and
so my earpiece always gonna be
everybody's going to
is great mayor in the 1991 Acer play so
I might be gone pretty
and is providing the way the team in
their celebrity so you can call
abrasions and he doesn't let you see
nobody looking up
it has many enemies you can see the gave
us we only
we have to publish the in this political
because he's the hip
that undercover use you know you've had
a
I'm hustlin site it is important things
services there Heather
I miss you decide these then has to be
named
the same name that you know that he
the we are proposing that the issue
because we love to break them to get him
with the government to get him back
attorney
it was realized that it was unclear at
this as you can see in the spring
okay at the next step will be
bus there from to get him back it in
this case you scenes will usually
framework
you have the to the template over there
education biker
you have different case a pirate on the
as you can see here we have here once
Acer okay
but when the winds here well the
geopolitical
in the soap work uses several chasers
for example
in the figures from packet use ssh to
for the user name
for the bus were and so on and as you
can see here we are only using one side
once a ser so we made a mistake
we found that while the vanity I mean if
you try to keep your
all the cases right you will find the
right their vanity as you can see here
we were fighting
and we were inspecting their requests
and responses in the canopy lover
and the responses from this everywhere
always 68 bytes
but as you can see here we have this
interesting man with two hundred and
eight bytes
and if we look at the packet we can see
that the user name on the bus were
are all zeros and we have a politician
within their backup server and
it's actually a position of the cell
number six
so a as you can see here Pfizer
are not only for grasses you have this
pretty self-explanatory
example but a the one maybe
her bleed you know about these course K
and undergarments with remind me know
we we using client in order leaders on
this great weather
and will have to change in at the to get
him back at the way I wanted to get to
my purse pocket
I'm let's see how it works up
it is that because you may pass pocket
missus then I was a funny look up and
we're going to
using gonna be there a no then dugan
in the all the on the rigors I'm on the
request to the server
interest and go to work
I'm willing to connect to their
tourism cabey's in the third
all the packets be seen as important
bucket going this is important but good
that contain under the cation
so we only have to change
aid by our indication my bus bucket
so copy and base it
they weren't looking
the half this is Ali says him
miss get your three we highly
to say whether the jury on a train to
them anymore these kinda buckets
on went to see how this works
after way to beat
they hear you you have for others to the
backup server well but first they were
good
but you can least Missy bathroom do so
many things
okay so you can do many things with his
banner ID
you gonna you have put up a stomach
ulcer do
to me but I'm supposed to apply and
resort operator plans
modify binaries it's a good common
after-tax as if you don't know because
you
as you can see music concert and finally
we
so solely to two million security
several guns that we've made for but the
display the article is the sea
just only approved because we have to
simulate earlier communication home
protocol and put him on the response and
its bit
have used us so we went to see aqui
demonstration
ABC's the proof
well and is accused eight-month first
we'll have to so sprite
it is old and as we wrote
get it done because you're my best
packet that we have to send
festival or their
on the request to respond I would have
to bar and Sen
final you contained
the San this letter to you by and
lettering on to so
and now the attorney path we're going to
secure it
okay I love it
I still need to show you
willing to abandon the sea but some
proof
on
you look at that we have
the find this km
fight this municipal so we are listing
their these
this is a important thing okay this is
gonna be no
you can see all the requests are
responding apartments in
an important thing he said this bike at
the gate and
209 length remember that and get him a
bus back at
and that's on okay
next the vanity will be there
permanently of service
and the last one the using for the
fussing with on the set
volatility a.m. I find that name for
task patina
really big desk name in this case on
when the biggest interest to start it
always crisis
courses not an expert double-cross but
the only solution
and the only way to solve these easier
it's understanding the biggest
conditional their way so
could be you really and I am on
the last them social media of our last
exploit
a game with on the main meal we come
brute force the use a number count on
the dust number will see
that mister should be there was these
and we go half
these numbers and ask for their servers
and in idea but it without any
indication
adding new to see what's it was the
scene interview
I'm finally we just need to send them I
suspect
see how it works
you have the server we have to be stuck
a simple created a
some simple will use again
cannot be in this case will use and they
were kind of going to be notice in the
Bakken
ok you have the packet on
as you can see here we have the disc
then
dusk name which is really big without a
face thank you have the usual number
on you're in the right the the dusk
number
on this values has to be right okay
so I am we come brute force these values
okay or we can a.m.
send a idea but it was her with helping
if in addition to the sever will give us
all their you to numbers on the desk
numbers: so we can
do both things if you want
and then you will send the packet
within the work line
on here in this case the Severus
responding with an error
and that's when he goes the the user
number in this case
is not right so sane so now
we know that use a number is 18
meetings is a number
I'm that we begun but forces are you
sure get these values
on this now there's a risk to respond in
with an OK and now they're because some
the graphic interface is trying to fit
the ask not name on it would press
and you try to open a game you know to
connect to the server it will press
Wilcrest Chris again and the only way to
solve the seasons and applications
could be fun as a conclusion
argument as ever plan
could be reused we found some about that
because someone is in April using this
Anthony
months and I'm the house with the father
by theme interesting you mean Sunday let
us
to buy more things than the so-called
amenities but changes hit worse
manage the Sonic progresses remember
honey backup for the issue my bus
the spam for us the minutes probably
you use so good diseases with them more
time
I'm really is a mod Liam Gallagher
service and they made us
promote cause the museum because it
houses
if you don't ambassadors to have more
security
because they are so pretty good palace
in our opinion
so thanks well I have been the moment
guys
things to him by his to my friend
and family and friends so the US team's
ago he
is there any question yeah
and it's not exploitable I will be worse
nine months ago against or 8
I'm not sure why if you wanna know white
snow mix but they will be gone
take it later but I don't bring her in
the hallway it's not explicitly
welcome thing
that's it yes with another
here
it appears that use on one issue their
ability to
be on security yet is it possible to
have an idea was a
amount of money move
I tell you later