ok excellent okay so looks like we'll
just start
right now why not um when when
I is in the back so we have our public
service announcements I think
a set up waiting 15 minutes we'll just
start the debate five minutes after
I think that's when the alcohol and beer
will be in so I will be happy or so
buddy okay so um enough about so
thank you all so much I'm Solomon sonya
and
it's a pleasure to honors a blessing to
be here in front of everyone
I'm here so I've had a good time working
on splinter and hopefully
I'm will be able to learn something as
we progress through the slides together
so first I to stop with the obligatory
disclaimer
just saying that some use the knowledge
I guess that we discuss or use knowledge
in hacking things
for good user for good enough for evil
so all that text just saying
as hackers please be nights because if
you destroy someone's computer system
although I built the tall are not
responsible because
1 I've your actually execute on the
computer system simply just be say
be set in the kinds of air fair we
okay alright I'll take that as a yes so
on this is what to expect in the
following
presentation for the most part I think
you'll be obvious what we cover
just as we go from like to slide but one
important thing is that bastard
I our live demonstration gremlin so in
america whenever we select a crossword
with excuse our friends
so if we're in France when we say excuse
my American
well well that worked %uh I'm not sir
but just in case some any of the live
demonstrations fail
I'm sorry it just happens for whatever
reason to get up to you try and do a
demo in things fail
but hopefully it doesn't and if so I
have a backup laptop hopefully
everything will go
I'm well from there so the research
motivation
as we know pretty much as everybody has
alluded to in the presentation that we
spoke about today is that
network security is still falling behind
to stay ahead of the emerging threats
so therefore in order to be able to be
stronger with a network security network
defense
pretty much if you want to be really
good at securing enterprise network
economy to know
exactly the in and outs of exploiting
this could this computer network so
that's why
I developed this botnet so if you
understand how to use a botnet
if you understand how to exploit
networks with botnets then perhaps you
have knowledge of what's a better look
for
in order to secure your systems in case
you see actually that's malicious
are active US index dipped love combine
infection so I'll
other talk about botnets what exactly is
this botnet I speak up well
this is our terminology that will use on
for today
all of this information is from the book
of Solomon I E
me so a botnet us pretty much
us another cover Thomas systems agents
their synchronized with the
command-and-control server
and which which Saint information which
stains commands and then we also handle
or remote
exploitation of those and systems when I
speak about the controller
the controller is us we are the
controller we are the botnet masters we
other person who use one
user interface to send commands to all
of our distributed systems
across the network or across the
enterprise the dropper
the dropper I'll we have a slight on the
droppers pretty much just saying
that's going to be one way up having an
entry points into that infected machine
and finally the implant the implant is
the listener
that actually establishes his connection
to the controller
executes whatever commands that we
receive and send that information right
back to the controllers now we have
arbothnott communication and then we
have other not at the bottom we want to
be as lightweight as possible
so we can establish a cell to the
controller whenever the controller sends
information
on my listeners side I simply
instantiate a new process
I executes the command that was just
received that I open
three streams on that process and/or its
execute commands the open your standard
out
a standard-bearer and then also a print
writers like correspond with that
process
any information that I get across the
standout understand that a run is
processed
I simply buffer that information and I
centre-backs the controller as a pretty
much how you establish a botnet
so I'm a visual learner I'm also a
teacher
so I kinda like to have diagrams
hopefully this helps less a lot of words
with my hands
but look at the pictures also who I know
understand what we're talking about
so I'm here we go right here we are the
botnet mastery other controller
if you understand using algorithms to
send commands to
wanna be infected machines received a
response from the infected machine and
send it back to the controller
if you understand how to program that
for one instance then if you can use the
same function to execute the commands
for the next incense and the next
instance after that then actually by
induction it means you understand how to
create
and how to control your button it okay
%ah very nice very nice
so where exactly do we begin if we're
talking about
establishing a botnet controlling
information: and controls and systems
well let's go ahead look at our anatomy
of an attack
most people are very familiar with this
you start with the reconnaissance
then you do you're scanning to
understand my entry points and the
vulnerabilities into the computer
network
and then we tryin penetrates that system
this is also refers was gaining access
on C one in the infected machines on the
Bonneville missy is that we were sad
access to
now after you gain access after you
penetrate that machine
and you stop you happy dance because
hacking is not as easy as as um you know
some people like to make it appear
so once we stop dancing cuz we just got
a shell into the computer machine
now we have options are we going to
escalate privileges
perhaps we're going to pillage and
plunder as mister della mister people
loose earlier
when I we have access to other sprinters
are any of those infected machines that
were talking about
or do we pay that do we actually try and
propagate I'm hour because from my
computer system
I'm now whenever I penetrate the network
I now have access to more systems
inside a separate network supply
continue to scan and then trying to take
more
more machines that way or perhaps I'm
going to just paralyzed every single
system
out there it all depends on-the-go love
your attack
and then after that we actually moved
down to stop the persistence and
covering tracks
other diagrams like to have persistence
and then cover your tracks what's up
with the other or covering tracks and
persistence
I put them side by side because it's
actually an iterative loop
and wits as I continued the attack I
like to try and yes still
as possible or I'd like to maintain
access so it's a
it's something that we go back and forth
is not just you do one and then you move
on
so that now that we understand are now
turning up the attack let's focus on
penetration
so earlier I alluded to the dropper I
really like the dropper implants
um paradigm whenever I'm technique
computer network so let's see
blew another pictogram so here we are we
are the controller
the controller we have access to a
malicious domain that we use
and her sis served additional malware to
infect computer machines
so what a dropper as soon as we have a
dropper dropper supposed to be as small
as possible
and the only purpose of the dropper
assemblies to break into that victim a
scene
and establish the environment there are
many different types droppers that can
exist I can use an exploit
I can use a malicious PDF I will be
using social engineering toolkit
um created by hacking Dave relic I'll
talk about that more
and a slice to come in which we actually
going to try and steal credentials to
gain access to a network
on that's the worst we have okay so
whenever I have my exploit my dropper
get into the infected machine
the dropper then reaches out my
malicious domain actually pulls down the
implant
that implant is what is establishment to
the infected machine now
and then it establishes his connection
up to the controller and from that
moment on the dropper goes away
and now I have my to wake a man to
control between the implant
and the victim a scene so now the
implant is connected to my controller
as we spoke about earlier stephan
persistence
that this is um what we call our beacon
but and the inspiration of this was
actually from Raphael much do we know
raffia much is the creator armitage okay
raise your hand if we use armitage
before by this we've heard about are all
good to excellent so there's a a pretty
good
I'm so can sort we're going to use
armitage is a wonderful framework very
very nice
origin is Metasploit Psalms actually
handle additional
exploitation the computer machine
Amplats at a
presentation that myself and Daryl I am
percent X we're at Packer Hall said last
year
and Armitage Raphael much he was talking
about sometimes
whenever you have access to a network
you don't just wanna have a
long-established socket connection
between a controller and then the
implant because this in and of itself
can be indicative that hey why is why do
I have one on my machines
having an a connection that lasted for
25 hours
I'm to another system why do you need a
connection established for so long
so instead he spoke about creating a
beacon but and you can use a beacon bus
to establish persistence
maintain access to a computer network
but without having a persistent
um a socket connection to control it so
what is a beacon but look like
haha so we have another pictogram here
we are
we %uh the controller on this site and
then we have our victim box
as soon as we establish our beacon on
the victim box
the beach in will wake up and then he
will actually stand a packet
to the controller your son the packets
the controller to register himself
saying I am live
I'm active on this infected machine the
controller acknowledges that
beaten request and then the beach in
goes to sleep
it severs that socket connection so are
whenever
up specified period of time elapses the
victim but then wakes up and contact the
controller
d have commenced for me to execute the
controller says no so what happens the
beach and goes back to sleep
then that beacon wakes up to have to
mess with execute he says no okay he
goes back to sleep again
he wakes up one more time do you have
commencement execute you say yes
okay no problem so what exactly do you
want me to execute to now we're checking
in
were downloading the command list in
this case the controller says establish
a cell back to me
in this instance the pecan woke up he
took the committee says you wanna sell
okay
I would give your cell and established
his back to the computer system
so um we are going to actually do some
interactive demos
so let's let's go have a look at the
Beacon but real quick
and so we can see what we're actually
talking about
okay so here we are are missus plan
services are but controller
on that we created it's available on get
carbon also um
on Twitter usually tweet about some the
access or how to get it
so on if you want to establish a
controller the first thing you do
you establish a server socket which
allows you to receive new connections on
to the controller itself
and then also an FTP site this allows
its which seems files and things like
that
so pretty much after that everything
else is supposed to be a simple
as possible and also you things as we
progress I'm throughout this
demonstration
okay so let's establish a beacon Satan
on see what it looks like
let me you
this a bit yeah this is it okay that's
going
hot
okay so if I do once established the
beach in the promise for the Beacon
I'm the first to say splinter I'm not
yet seen and if you do dash
eights I have a help option that I show
you all of the
options that you can use for this actual
implant so here we are going to use the
Beacon option so if we answer in Spencer
Daz be for the Beacon and then the IP
address to the controller
the IP address the controllers in this
case is one and it's 162 23
not one yes is right here and then the
port that we're listening for service
socket connections as a cross-court
eighty eighty
which is right here established for
sites to a space
8080 and then as going to the next prime
there will be my beacon interval
how often do I want the beat Kansas leap
before checking in
with mister controller and to see a are
there commence first exit you
i wills tell it six seconds i'm for now
that our press
answer okay that's my firewall that's on
the school hadn't
turn that guy of the kinda messed up my
demonstrations
don't do that okay I so it's like i RB
ken is connecting
over to a cell at this spot if we click
on the arm
I beginning agent command I'm terminal
best habitat actually see whenever
a beacon sex in it sex at the beach in
I'm second I just been received
and that's the beacons ID and at this
point at this but we don't have any
commands loaded foreign to execute so if
you do one its to execute commands
upon the next check in let me do this
okay to come over here to the right and
then say at command so
to commands let's do Who Am I
type right who am i
okay and then also as to the VM ICE
OS gets caption a kiss Aiden Ashley
cue up multiple commands whenever an
implant actually texan and then
to enable that you just click Enable to
the right it turned green and the sign
so the next time did so the next time
the agent sex and he dollars the
commands list and then provided the
response
so here I see that time work I'm
executing on Windows 7 Professional
machine
and also call my I'm list right now as
an admin PC
okay it now let's go back to the
connection status
and if you click on the active tab PC
that we have no active connections
and to the controller so the main
purpose other beating right was to say
okay when is it time to establish
I a s sell to us so I just disable
I'll be can commence the next time to
beat insects and he just said look it's
akin
0 comments established a key so if you
click on shortcut
I'm gonna say establish a cell and upon
the next time that the Beacon sex n
men from the second ago so he just
checked in I'm so the next few seconds
we should now see the Beacon is going to
return to sell to us
okay and so that's the cell that the
beach and just responded to us
and actually to have been sent
are okay so I actually built in
are a resolution which I can do I'm the
location for the implant that sex in
was just thinking it's sometimes nice
whenever you have many socket you don't
know is computers are so I actually
display a map to show you will this is
the
greatest or latest resolution aware that
infected machine actually is
so if you want to see that you click on
the Beacon or you click on the
connection here
and then you move over to google map and
then Google Maps actually display on
your
I'm using your default browser where I
believe that connection is coming from
at I'm connected since I I wish that one
would work might work in the next one
but I listen it will discontinue
continues at least
that was an example just a very quick
example using the beach in but it's
communicate with our controller check
and receive commands and then go to
sleep again
okay so penetration payload migration
whenever you build your botnet so
whenever you build a tool that has
command control and sockets established
I think one thing that is very important
is to make your tool extensible
or liking it so this two months ago
or so we released an update sponsor put
it on get hub
what if at that spot we had a beacon
that was established
unaffected machine buts no kidding two
days ago or whenever we flew over from
the United States over here I created a
new alarm payload
and I put into the system so how do I
know I'll get that updates
to affect the beginning agents that that
I've had running for the last two months
well like I see the new update I just
created today no he won't
so in order to have this feature
election update feature
or an extensible feature I created the
payload migration
a payload migration allows you to take
any binary or
pretty much any file migrated over to
the infected machine from the same
socket
executed and now I can continue
additional exploitation onto the
infected machine
so let's say uncivil Safi um I have an
initial connection to that effect
machine
and I want to run clear logs or Alex run
any other exploit sometimes whenever you
magically find a cell phone and fax
machine and then you say okay but I want
armitage
on and take Missy not sponsor well I
like to transfer over
pretty much any paleo that you have now
to that same infected machine
I'm using what we have so here's a
diagram up on what we're starting with
so we're gonna start at the controller
we already have an established
connection
so the infected machine and now we have
Metasploit we may also want misplaced
have access on fax machine still
so what happens many times I have
Metasploit I say okay
Hail Mary or do whatever you can to give
me access to computer machine sometimes
it works
sometimes it fails but let's say
whatever droppers was successful
to give you access a computer machine
let us now find a way to get Metasploit
months than fact missing also so this is
what it looks like
what we will do from Metasploit we'll
create amid reversed matar paneer
and then we will transmit that reverse
matar paneer from the control socket
on same sex machine then we'll executed
uninfected machine
and now will bring a socket over
armitage or overt Metasploit
if that makes sense hope it does if not
don't worry
we have another demonstration okay
okay let's let's do this let's do this
okay so here's armitage we have it
running and then we have our listener
established I right here listener this
is the IP address up the
Linux machine and the support that were
I'm listening on
on because of time I've recreated the
matar paneer I
reverse TCP but if you have any
questions on that I have a house to
I'm from the gephardt link on that will
show at the end so if you wanna see how
did I create that mean it's
is pretty cool or does Google matar
paneer reverse TCP in everybody and
their brother
much to write about how to use
Metasploit okay so let's go ahead and
I migrate the Paleo I'm what we want to
do now
let's use armed I feature from the
implant so this is going to be are
infected machine I'm Fort sitting
let's go in clear that also as well make
sure it worked earlier
let's make this large okay so
if I answer and splinter a kid s I now
Columbus establishing an implant
connection
out my controller and then the IP
addresses 192 168 up to 23
in this case one port is 8080
and then I have um this is optional and
optional feel that the ends this says OK
in case the current socket has dropped
house and you want me to wait before and
pecan to establish a connection
matter the control if you put t5 that
says connect immediately
so I just wanna make sure that I have a
persistent connection okay so looks like
that was successful and now I have two
machines
our windows is it appears to be Windows
Vista this cuz
I did go back and fix that resolution
but we have windows 7 which is the host
and then what appears to be Windows
Vista but it's really a a Windows seven
I'm machine that we've just infected so
this guy
now I the main purpose here was to
migrate payload so the click
right here on my great pay loan we can
now specify any payload that we want to
transfer over to infect machines
executed and then bring that sell over
to a different store which we're now
going to connect armitage
so at the spot there's no connection to
I'm it is a must
so this works okay solace in this guy
over there here
so I specify the people that I want to
transfer over
and the one that will be transferring is
this guy just reverse the CP
over to armitage from our sponsor
connection of the open
and then I also allow it to pre-planned
and then arm append any additional
parameters of a separate saw
has on prime others to execute you know
something he still had like 10 primaries
I do that option
at the spot and I think if you hover
your mouse to put a tooltip in that says
looking at yeah so it kinda does your
hands soiled and if you're not sure just
leave a blank
and see what happens pickin I clicked
sec options just to see where I'm going
to put it
I'm going to put it on the infected
machines temporary file temp folder
and then I at the bottom here you have
an option do you want me to execute
the payload immediately upon
transmission syntex machine
or do you just want to stay there and I
can execute at another time sorry to say
yes and no
and so will hit launched and if this
launch is successful
don't be so fast okay let's see if we
can get the connections armitage
so works OK okay good so um what you
just saw
was a separate armitage connection or is
just
any other program that I can now text
chains from my current botnet to allow
other people to have access and fax
machine as well so that's just a popular
migration feature
and I don't have to be omitted it can be
any execute a bill or any file
and then fax machine I just thought you
know whenever we establish a botnet
and go to allow additional tools I'm to
migrate from the infected machine
okay what's next of social engineering
okay this is this is this the favorite
as a favor mine
so if we can recall from yesterday
mister when spoke about the for that a
word that's the worst
on in secure into the computer network
right that was supposed to be the user
ibogaine also spoke about was that the
corona on the Sun flares solar
solar flares okay saw this we have two
really good things the users are bad and
solar flares
are just bad kind that everybody okay so
I what we're going to talk about now
is a DNS host file poisoning and the
credential harvesting and spoke USC
I don't think I have time for that but
if we have time at the end just
reminding
in we can show I this moving up the User
Account Control also
on when those missing so DNS cache
poisoning
the main purpose %uh establishing a DNS
cache poisoning
as let us say mister controller over
here he is the legitimate DNS server
okay or he's a legitimate website and
that's now say you sir are now the
attackers malicious website
I am now the attacker and the man in the
middle you now want to go to the
legitimate website let's say you are
Amazon or bankamerica dot com okay so
you want to log into your bank to check
your account
I'm now I can poison that DNS and sry I
can say no
don't go to him go to him who is a clone
abyss actual website
so you not knowing the difference cuz
they look exactly like you got the
militias website you can turn your
credentials i nasty you could still your
credentials
and I 42 over to the real arm website so
you don't really know the difference
that hey I just had the credentials
okay that's pretty much one of the main
reasons that we do DNS cache poisoning
so back in 2007 2008
we saw that WoW some really bad on DNS
cache poisoning was going on
and know what we do we actually patched
it so if I didn't want to poison
a lot of dr. main top-level domains I
believe that was the one that the
I'm attack worked in 2007-2008 and I see
that have to be very noisy
because I'd have to constantly poison
almost every single DNS
top-level domain and also the
authoritative domain servers
across the entire world and say no don't
go to make america here is actually here
again that's very noisy and has been
patched some at least most that's been
passed by now
so we're not going to do that cuz noise
and it just won't work well the next
thing we can do is a man in the middle
which I kinda explained
if I'm inside the network and said have
you going to make america dot com
I am now cast poison both view I say
okay you are now the router
you are now the legitimate website I am
the attacker you do not cause the
radical to me
any packet that you send I'm going to
force the router I'm not gonna tell
router do not said anything to him said
it's me
so now back and forth I can continue to
teach control every website that you go
to
this again is very noisy because I have
to continuously sent
gratuitous are packets in order to can t
that man in the middle attack and is
also very detectable
if you're monitoring the packets on your
network so not going to do that either
we're not gonna do that either
instead those actually manipulate just
one and three
at one entry to the infected machine and
then on by adding an instance in a
statement saying we're going to target
the Windows host file
actually say okay instead of going to
your main on domain server and then
handling all of our DNS
on request only go to one file if you
see an entry in the file what's that
on goes that location directly so if
that works a lot of people say
you wait a minute what is the host DNS
file okay good i'm glad you asked
so the host DNS pile on this location
with a host in this file
actually exist is pretty much an
important file that can be used
up to handle registries in locations
very quickly months because next like
running out of time
so on this is how it works let's say you
want to go to facebook.com
my computer system a similar thing is
going to work well I
will check its host of course the van
entry exists as an entry exists I'm
going to Paul
that IP address and then going to send
it back to my brows and say okay
you wanna go to facebook.com his
location on Facebook that you're looking
for
so go there instead this now means that
we've just on exploitation vector
if I can poison that hosts file I can
now directly to anywhere you want to go
base of the initial website
unless you're trying to go to so I'll I
and now for the attack more pictograms
yes
okay so here we are we are the
controller we have access to the
infected machine
all we're going to do is send one entry
to the in fax machine saying this
location
as the IP address on any site that the
user might have wanted to go to
then we're going to use the social
engineering toolkit very beautiful
I cannot say it's a warm fuzzy the
social engineering toolkit works very
well
wanted one other things that we're going
to use it for in this demonstration
as actually call on a Web site and then
if I can
steal the user's credentials I'm going
to afford it back to the attacker
and then I will redirect the user backs
the lid legitimate website that they
want to go to
okay so let's see so them a time let's
see if this is going to work well
hopefully this works well soco like the
hardest morning
I am so let's go back into sponsor
yes so this is the machine that we have
so if you first of what to look at
the registry file for the host in this
file click on your shortcuts go down
still grab
host file correct grab when those hosts
file okay so
you successful grab a file to say this
is where I say the location
I gave you a shortcut right here if you
click on open file hi
this is the and fax machine that we had
and then this is the host father we just
I'm grant from the system
so it's just a flat file no text file if
I look at it these are the current
entries on them picked machines host
file so there's nothing in there
that means if I want to go to pace with
dot com there's no entry in the host
file
hour then contact my local DNS server
that handles all the DNS requests
okay so let's go ahead and put in entry
answer that hosts file
so if you want to do that taken ashore
cousin is a a pencil when does
compost pile so what I'm using the
social engineering toolkit
on the Linux machine is to mimic a
website that we've all seen
many many many times and this it's this
website has comparison
okay so the IP address and I'll
mimicking on this site is going to be
192 168 8 20 3.1 forty-three
so I go to this website right now on my
computer you might even be able to do it
if anyone is trying
because I I'm connected to the incident
looks like arm so you might actually be
able to see the sights who
so on the Plano right before I got on
the plane I want to act in Paris website
I saw all
look there's a user login and a password
let's clone this site and see if we can
use this for so soon and talking
okay so what we're going to do now we're
going to tell that infect machine
the halls com the entry for the meantime
though that happen Paris
as actually located at this address and
if this works the usual go there and for
the credentials and I can check
on the social engineering toolkit
harvested the credentials the lessee if
that's going to work
hopefully this works okay so I'm the
first what we did we clicked on a pens
to Windows host file
on this I'm and then we answer in the IP
address that we want to
arm clone so right now it's house at 192
22 3.1 forty-three right I believe and
then
the URL the URL that we're actually
trying to redirect the user to
in WWW dot hack and Paris
dot com Obama talking too fast if I am
just raise a hand in all slow down
you that there's a lot to do and I wanna
snuggle okay so I
just a note saying the spear on with
administrator privileges
okay so right now the implant actually
echoed back saying
he disappeared as the host file and we
did not report any errors
on the host file now we just sit back
and went and let us assume that this is
the user now
on their machine so you have this up we
have the
I'm out but this intentional I haven't
implant that is not so
I'm any up went on inside a decide if I
want to go to
coming over to be dots hack in Paris dot
com
okay I had answer and hopefully
and does not look like on anything
ahold yet the user right now cannot tell
that's on you know
anything is wrong this is like the
correct website I'm trying to go
I'll let me just do this a case of
latency the
the otherness a kiss on now and it's
like okay well let me go ahead and log
in to happen Paris
the comment so assuming I have a
username let me just say user
1 and then a password was password safe
passage a quick
for a I love that one fluffy bunny
right bunny fluffy bunnies
okay okay so that's the answer doing
remember passwords why not
okay and
said sup so I think my internet was
working right this now would have been
the redirect from the
credential harvester redirect you back
to the legitimate website to try and
login so the user my to the HOA
well have this redirect if they even pay
attention if not you to santa hat
compares to come you try and login again
too much to say oh well looks like the
login failed well let us now go to
our credential harvester which is
I running let me go to the location
any file that we do receive from the
harvester will be saved and
far this week which
var BBW I'm directory
and then we should have a file I'll as I
could not save
I should I run the skin if this didn't
work if that works he would have seen
that they're the text ball save at this
location if you open the text file
you have seen that the users name and
their pastor would've been saved into
that file
looks like that live demonstration got
me there I'm not sure why I could try on
this one but
as a que will continue just right on
your own site everything else works
though we poison the DNS
whenever the user wants a cause that
legitimate website redirected them over
to the credential harvester
it the files have been there I i I'm not
sure why it's not there it worked
in the back trust him ok just did
just trust just just just mistrust okay
so um
besides that one less do I just one more
sore scorched-earth
source earth is kind of a term that she
is okay
I cannot gain access to a system or I
cannot have something I want
nobody will be able to access this
computer system right score system
burning everything
okay so how are we going to use scores
earth and the side
we're going to use it for denial of
service on the um
enterprise network so if I were to ask
you
what is the mileage service mean was
that was the dots if I was there was a
bus was in denial service noticing
was dial service yes
okay es Salaam
with us with a slight so if we read this
says Fensom
well I'd normally we're gonna sent
misinformation that the server can
handle
and many times the cause the server to
Kress right that's that's what we
understand
at the Palace service to be accepts as
the attacker as the programmer
I feel that definition is insufficient
to say exactly what
a DOS means because in my opinion the
definition of sentence misinformation
order to let the server crashed as more
and affected is more um I guess the
measure of effectiveness
if the boss is working so can access the
server know it has crashed the DOS is
working
instead let us refer to the book of
Solomon me
I am for a new definition for DOS
instead of picking up a DOS as senate
much information let's only consider it
to be
resource starvation if I can start the
available resources on a server or an
enterprise or system
then I can actually have a measured
effects such that access to the system
at a minimum is degraded and at a
maximum is disrupted
okay I think that's better so now I can
ask another question
as the attacker as we're developing his
exploits how do I start resources on a
server
well they're actually many techniques
many techniques exist
%uh and 1i developed two weeks ago
another 1i developed on the airplane
I was like a nine hour flight or so from
washington he was like wow let's see if
this works kinda hard dick
I can you know sometimes when you just
in the zone program you're kinda angry
at the world
but some we have a pink four things that
I learned from that process
and the first if we want to do a das the
first is to
analyze legitimate traffic so I want to
toss a website let me go to the website
and look at it with the packet analyzer
I E Wireshark to see what does it look
like if I wanted of the system
okay the next thing is to learn the
protocol and the structure
this is very important because a DOS on
a Web site
in a city website is going to be
completely different than the way you
try and awesome FTP server
and I learned this the hard way was like
okay to I just program the website dost
let's go ahead and do the same process
for an FTP server and those like punch
slap in the face I'm sorry
I miss refers to this RFC 959 to
understand how to first
authenticate with that FTP server and
then to send the command to start its
available resources
and in causa das okay so I think are
good
good that such that's our clue for da so
let's do this real quick let's do this
okay so I am also hosting
arm are hacking Paris website on a
separate IP address
this is at one 90 to 160 220 9.9
and everything is identical to the main
website that were familiar with the only
thing I
added was this I'm script at the top so
that if I refresh the page then you can
see that
you know the script is updating
appropriately that means whenever I went
over to the website and said to have you
index page
it's certainly the index page along with
the script my brows excuse a script
an agency that okay I just received
information from the server
okay let us now have a visual of what
that dos looks like
on the actual network how we had a bit
rate before
it for a place in no no okay only one
Wow either AP is incredible it's
incredible
so on what do I do with either a Peter
Aitken allow me to see various notes my
computer network
and also it how does a visual with some
with Evernote receives traffic
I can kinda see it expanding go big or
small base of love
its bandwidth utilization inside the
network so right now
F I worked soo move this over and this
is working okay
yet so you actually see that on this in
my system that sent the request over
and then this is the our server not this
my system and this is the server
he sent to the missile request over to
the server the server some low traffic
back to the I'm system and then it goes
away because right now we're not
exchanging information
so let us use in Swiss and if we are
going to execute a DOS
on that network when we expect this
suddenly appear on if you're excited to
allow traffic is being sent
at at once we've will pretty much expect
this to go completely red because red
as the protocol for HTTP okay so let
some visual what what what is that does
look like
let's see let's see okay so if you want
to execute a website das please again
use this for good enough for evil
house and we're going to use less I'd
ask for good I don't know but you'd
figured out ok okay so
if I come over here and to the shortcut
de dos website
okay then I answer in the IP address
other website you can also use abiam's
the Urals
I think I mean the program the for IP
address and what's best that way and
then
I went 62-20 that 139 right
and you can leave the port of its 18 mom
but others and million
so once I hit answer
%ah other issues one artist that one
implants
executed the holidays guy suffer hip
okay I'll get there goes
okay so what you're seeing is this an
are the west lies that
also what's missing is this implant I
just sent so much information so that
web service thing tonight the index page
give me a in that state's not only that
I instantiate about 10,000 threads
each person saying give me your index
page right now so if that is
arms its that a successful the website
might actually have too much information
that I can handle
and is going to crash okay so let's see
if the crest
a crest I'm so if I were to refresh its
all before
that refreshing the is gone so you saw
before that refresh the webpage so the
JavaScript that we wanted to or I can
see the time now I'm tossing that site
it's down that that's ever actually
crashed until will go back and restart
the server but even if we did we start
the server
you see that up how much time do I have
to help
23 minutes okay good okay so
but let's try this let's try this let's
see if we can make this look
right if up okay it does not appear
as as I wanted to but let's just say
right now you see that a just the kinda
sleeping
waiting for that server to come back
online so if I go back
armed services the are missing a host
the server also what I use for the demo
I use at this web server I'm to host
that website wanna go in
call the doctor that he's finished is
done for okay so if I just restart its
okay if I restart the server and then go
back to yep thought you see the implant
recommend %ah servers up till it
so gonna try television and
and now the server we try to bring it up
but some it happened so fast if I try
and reload the server is
is done for organ still down so they
just wait and wait and wait until he say
okay
couldn't stop the Bogside I think
they've suffered enough so if I want to
stop
the DOS army to go over here it's a halt
website boss
okay then your so I'm now the agency's
on the implants top
they will stop the bus okay so at least
I give you a halt Peter
the next on it FTP that when I whole
okay
at the you can tell I I like that one
i'd did on the plane
okay so if I want to go to our FTP
website I'm also hosting the FTP website
on 192 168
223 that 139 a kiss of I can lend
I'm not the part that you can see that I
have sought to establish from
about once a 139 that's on connecting to
and let miss
login anonymous nice but i right
I didn't cry akin you try that again
anonymous okay up to get logged in so
f'in sir
binary mode you don't have to do that
but
while okay are so high you can so that I
can interact with the FTP server
appropriately right the power to close
the socket
um call the connection in this log in
again I can still
login let me is the dacite so get some
logged in as anonymous so everything is
working appropriately
until we Dawson okay so on the so we
added we added the FTP
dos lemiux makers larger because they're
additional
I'm promise to answer in some things you
can just leave default
so right here the first thing will
answer is the IP address the web server
that we're going to dos
which is that right there and then the
next is the
defaults on port number for the
controller and then did
default port number for the control and
the default port number for data
investors
you know you know might have to pee
protocols on port 21 import 20
okay and then the user named I want to
use to try and login
I we will use anonymous for now I'm
going to add more to the speeches just
new that I think this is the most likely
at in and then just a blank password
makes you read the quotes intact
so we know on what the parts for the
password and then
I haven't added more to this gets but
eventually you'll be able to daisy-chain
additional commands that you want that
FTP server to execute
whenever you're we're trying to log in
and of that system but for right now it
works for one command
eats and I would just say list so this
means if this is working
login authenticate with the server and
then list whatever we have
but something I did what this does is
that it gets angry okay good
sup size agency are das it starts to
grow bigger and bigger and bigger and
bigger and bigger
so that on eventually what's happening
I'm spawning as many connections as
possible
after I try and spawn are many
connections I been tryin spahn as many
more so
this will go to about 20,000 connections
arm as possible
at the Cannes until eventually on the
FTP server
Wilcrest now on at the spot over here
I put a status this is currently how
many open sockets I have to the FTP
server
okay so you see is this going to
continue to grow and grow and grow and
then every 100
I did your status on this site their
dis- okay so right now we have two
hundred
open apps office and it's going to
continue to grow so
ice I'm going really fast I want to show
this let's see
I if I were to show the FTP FileZilla
is low his prime I'm going to um so
forth because it's
it actually freezes in fact the whole
computers reason for this reason too
much information
I open open open opened quickly
400 a kiss right now about 400 sockets
okay
so finally you can barely see is what I
cannot interact with this
I'm yes sauce is not responding because
our boss is being effective
0 finally look what happened ok I was
waiting for this
okay so let me come back to this side
real quick I like to give you status to
know whenever our dos actually detect
something
so we told you that the agents are
sniffing the network to see okay
any time that we have a website das EFX
my agents detect
that the website doesn't affect it
reports back to saying okay I think our
Das is good go and check it out
and hopefully the website is no longer
active das complete
and this case we have the FTP orbiter SR
da spot saying okay
we actually just received a status call
for twenty-one
and if we refer to the RFC 959 status
court
421 means on the connection has been
refused
and not only that the box report what
the server actually says
the server said survey says
that's too many users are logged in for
this account to try again later
in I don't like the looks on that so let
me go back
to a just on okay
if I were to try and do an FTP
connection again 192 168
one all that 223 not 139
FTP yeah so I want to login as anonymous
ok yes answer password and refuse my
connection
because it is saying that too many users
are logged in for this account
so you know we're gonna try again later
so was both of effective yessum
yes yes as affected do not let see I'm
so
we wanted look at the network again
they're still having at I'm so they're
trying to bust as much as possible
so eventually let me come over here than
this to be the last one arm
often difficult time if you say halts
FTP server
bus okay the agents report back the DAS
were hot in the boss
and now you can see no more traffic is
being sent as much as possible
that FTP server FTP server should be
working OK
so if I were to try one more time to
login
as early as before to the FTP server as
anonymous
password them they were so we can log in
again saw
at least thats I'm just a few options
that we added in onto our
are botnet allowed to do as many things
as possible
on this compact here
and I want to finish okay so we just
finished demo I we did the DOS
lasso additional features these are
additional features I did not talk about
but are built into the arm splint a
botnet I have
and then I also released tutorials on if
you want to do this yourself
how would you be able to do it because
my goal is for you everyone to be able
to
create their own but an exploit the
computer network for good
not for evil okay I'm say your things
that we do not talk about
over a payload clipboard injection USC
spoof if we had more time
I would've I'm so on a few I was really
learn
worse all I'm okay looks like another
time okay I next light
okay if you have any questions you can
um
this a why we can actually grab the
Colts are released the code
and also the implants that we have I
have new updates coming
like the FTP that we saw a just program
that on the airplane sauces I get back
home
on Sunday night you'll see the new
version that will be up uploader back to
get help and if you have questions email
just a minimal I'm pretty much always on
light will I'm always online six hours
behind
I guess or however many you know in the
US okay and then also um
if you have any question you can also
send me an question on
I'm get help yes questions
up
its as they want the question is is the
detail in one of the slides showing the
credentialing attack
and you said you had it all spells and
then you simply use that to the wrong
server and then just to redirect
actual server but when you do that if
the host file like we use a proxy or
according to the hope it's not okay
so your question was how does the
redirect really work if I just added one
entry to the host file
you but what do you do when you want to
really to the actual website because
you can because it's in the hospital the
was gonna go to the very IP and
to change the host but you have to
restart the browser take immigrant
because it catches this
so how do you solve this problem okay so
you're saying if I want to remove the
entry that we s
I'll okay I don't have time but if he
saw
when I did grab hosts file we actually
grab the original host of uninfected
Missy
so the next night you do is poison host
file again
and what you can actually download a
real upload that original host Paula
backs the computer machine
so now the host file goes back to how it
was recently in essence removed but the
brothers catching the information so you
have to restart the brother first
right and that honestly that's okay it's
me if the user has to restart the
browser we do it all the time
from so via yes oh that's
thanks to a question you any other
questions
I'll yes home about sun spots or
for the Wentworth I'm not that basic
okay
I was wondering if you grab a solar
flare out on it to us when early times
all okay yeah so the question was are in
our solar flare
added yeah how about numbers in infinity
plus one
okay then you'll see solar flare ok
anything else
anything else alright honestly thank you
so much for your time to question truth