hello and welcome to this talk about
fingerprinting all the things with
scanner first a few words about me so
I'm a security researcher in the Rd team
at Kooskia security I focus mostly on
network related security research some
say I do threat Intel but what I really
do is port scanning and fingerprinting I
block sometimes cut a lot big fan of the
command line interface and open source
software and here you can see like the
terminal this is where I spend most of
my days I wanted to have the black
slides but it wouldn't work out with the
black terminal so I had the light slides
so if you are here if you can answer one
of those questions but yeah by yes this
means you're in the right talk if no
then stay a little bit longer maybe
you'll like it for example are you
interested to know all the versions of
the DNS servers that are reachable on
ipv4 or much a specific pattern on all
pages of for example the alexa top 1
million top-ranked websites for example
to identify specific CMS or a web server
being used or even do you want to know
the assertion that is used on your
perimeter for example so these are all
question that can be answered using
scanners so hopefully on the end you'll
use it and you'll be able to answer
those questions the agenda for today
first I'm going to go through a little
intro to introduction on fingerprinting
what is it were the challenges and so on
they're the existing tools and what our
dog there are limitation
why don't they scale actually because
they scale vertically and why scaling
horizontally is a better way of doing it
and then I introduced kernel and do a
little summary yes so first let's start
with with fingerprinting but first I
guess you're not all aware of the
difference between between poor scanning
and fingerprinting so I'll do a small
recap port scanning is simply the
process of trying to identify the status
of a port is it open is it closed so
usually you send a packet with a
specific flag here sin and you you
monitor the response if it's a cynic you
know it's open if it's reset ACK it's
closed if you get nothing then either
you get lost
it's firewalls or other reason so port
scanning is straightforward pretty
linear but service printing in the other
way it goes much beyond so instead of
targeting of wanting to know the status
of a port you want to interact with the
server so you want to interact with the
service that is running behind that port
so you have to do multiple exchanges to
do that on the right side I know it's
too small that's the idea to read it but
this is a ssh connection establishment
so as you can see it's there's much much
more efforts to communicate with the
servers the the green try rectangle
there is simply the part that is doing
the port scanning so fingerprinting goes
way beyond so you have to be able to
understand the protocol and and talk
with the service in a way that that
provides you the information you're
looking for so like I said it's more
complex you have to understand the
protocol it's a much longer process
depending on the service that you were
targeting and in the end you don't get
like a status is it open is it closed
but you get the whole payload that is
being sent by the remote service and
since this is a payload that you'll have
to parse you have to endure some
unexpected data because it won't be it
won't be a single packet with a flag
being okay this is open but it will be
the whole exchanges now even more if you
consider running it on millions of
targets it will be a long very long
process
it might also impact
the network as those pro-gay is here and
you will have to answer question like
how do I enter the hole that I said in
the end how do i parse the data how do I
store that and and you have to be fast
and efficient because if if he takes
like weeks to do millions of targets
this this won't work as as we'll see we
will see so a few words on the different
tools that exist and and their
limitation the first idea for
fingerprinting is to do it by scripting
there's exist multiple tools for doing
that one of them is is Cappy a Python
library that allows you to forge packets
and in order to produce an exchange with
a remote host or also H ping which is a
UNIX tools that also allows by providing
specific payloads to interact with your
the service you want to to fingerprint
for the more most poor user there's
always net cat but I guess it's not very
efficient
so all those tools are give you a lot of
power but it's tedious and very specific
if you've done the implementation for
specific service fingerprinting which
Cappy for example you'll have to start
over again for another one again and
again this is my favorite slides I've
felt it here because I found this is the
most elegant way of doing fingerprinting
I was looking to have some smile yeah
there since so I'll go through it this
is just a geeky way of doing it
the idea is you declare your target so
the host and the poor there you open a
socket with a specific device on unique
file system and then you use UNIX tools
like echo and cut in order to send your
payload and receive the response it's
pretty elegant but of course this is not
very efficient but I had to put it
because I really liked that solution
so another solution it's to use tools
there's plenty of existing tools for
doing that one of them being an map and
it's NSC scripting engine that that
Hughes uses Lua programming language in
the backend and it has a pool of scripts
that are available to fingerprint a lot
of services so this is a very good to Z
group on the other hand is made by the
zmapp team which is also a tools it's
growing getting more and more service
available in it
there's SSH HTTP and all those most used
services around so those tools are
pretty flexible and very complete but do
the scale and how fast are they so I've
done a small test on the Alexa top 1
million websites so this is the 1
million top-ranked websites on internet
and I use a pretty decent machine so 24
cpus 190 gigs of ram and one gig pipe i
had tweak the the server in order to be
able to process that than many packets
so z grab the did it in like 48 minutes
which is pretty good I would say
nmap to be honest after 14 hours waiting
I canceled it it was only done at 8
percent so yeah not a great success and
like the picture says I'll almost die
waiting yeah so yeah just a few words 40
48 minutes you could say okay this is
pretty decent this is fast fast enough
for me yeah but that's only 1 million if
if I say that there's 80 millions opened
HTTP pour on internet doing that with Z
grub will take you three days this is
not very efficient and there's probably
other solutions to go much faster than
that so how do those tool scale the only
solution is to scale vertically by
vertically that means you'll improve the
other where you will
better CPU you'll get more Rams you had
a better network card and so on it all
depends on the bottleneck that you
eating if you're hitting a bottleneck on
the CPU then you improve your CP this is
all nice but at some point you'll hit a
limit you won't be able to scale
indefinitely on the same machines also
scaling vertically so adding a better
hardware on the single machine has also
drawbacks you'll be limited by the the
routing devices on the path to the
target like those poor ships there for
the back diseased ships so the idea is
that you would be sending from a single
host all your packets so if if it passed
through a device that has a smaller pipe
than yours then you'll be blocked there
also you're using a single IP so you
might get blacklisted by your ISP or any
other instances out there that are not
happy with seeing all those packets
coming from from your single IP this is
also a single point of failure if your
hosts crash then or get blocked then you
lose all all your results or part of it
and it's also expensive having your
machines with 24 CPUs and and and that
many rams is a lot is a lot but even
scaling even more than that is also a
lot so now we get so why is scaling
originally a better solution by scaling
horizontally this means simply getting
your own army of minions and
distributing all your little tasks to
them so that all those little minions
will process your tasks this uses the
cloud and it's no other is pretty cheap
to have VM so this looks like a pretty
good idea also it has specific
advantages like its stealthier since you
are having multiple minions you have
multiple IPS you would all then less
likely to be blacklisted since all your
packets will go from different paths
it's also fair because you won't hit the
same route Iran your path to your
targets but multiple ones its resilient
one of your minions die then you only
lose part of your results but the rest
the rest keeps on doing and should be
faster by adding more minions you use
you get faster and your scan takes less
time but distributing an application so
with minions with VMs brings also its
own issue if you've ever played with
multi-threaded application and unlocks
and mutex and so on and you apply that
to distributed application then you know
it's it's a big mess and a nightmare
also how do you handle the communication
between all those little minions you
have to answer a question like how do i
distribute the tasks I'll do end all
failures in case one of you millions die
and and you have to restart it or how do
you do that and in the end you will have
to you'll have all those minions with
the results I'll do you a grenade that
those results at the same place in the
end system so that's where Erlang comes
to the rescue
I don't know if anyone is familiar with
erelong but it's a pretty good
programming language it has currency
available out of the box it's Jewish it
provides distributed application and it
uses a nice mechanism which is message
passing for communication so instead of
using Lux for example it uses mailboxes
that the buffered message being sent so
you get the the master node for example
that would send message to all the
minions and those message get buffered
into the mailbox and each process is
able to just check when he wants or when
it is able to get the message and
processes so this is a very good system
in order to avoid all those issues with
distributed app or so it uses the
reactor model I will go deeper in that
in the next
it's resilient so the idea is you know
one of your minion might crash
so get be prepare for that and and set
up all the different stuff that you need
in order to keep on scanning and keep on
doing what you need what you're doing
also scanner has very small processes
it's not we don't call them processes
more erelong processes but it's 300
words so that's pretty small it means
that you can have more than one hundred
and thousand processes on a single host
so that sounds good for fingerprinting
for example what is this actor model so
like like in object-oriented programming
where each object each everything is an
object here everything is an actor like
this nice guy here so each process is
isolated from the rest it has its own
mailbox and receives all the misc
message thread and process the message
as as long as its life and all all this
make it a very good model so our long is
based on that model which makes this
make makes it really good and powerful
programming language now how do we apply
that to fingerprinting so let's say that
each target so in each for example of
those 1 million top-ranked website is is
a minion so is an actor you would spin a
new Erlang process for each of the
target each each process will
communicate with with the remote host so
establishing the TCP connection sending
the payload receiving the payload and at
the end return the results and and die
and another one will be spin for the
next target so this sounds pretty good
and I guess you see where I'm going so
this is where I'm gonna introduce
scanner which is based on all those
little principle so you still here guys
right that was the boring part now comes
the fun part so here is the the design
of scanner
so on the left side here you get the the
master this is the part that is doing
all the tedious task like parsing the
arguments getting the targets starting
the different nodes here and so on all
those boring tasks the broker is the
part that is running on the VM so this
is the the the part that receive a list
of targets and we'll spin new processes
for each of those targets and at the end
we get those actors that are actually
one actor per target so that means that
the broker if it received 1 million
target it will spin 1 million process so
the design is is pretty good because it
allows to scale a lot also all this
process of creating the the broker and
communicating communicating with it is
all transparent to the user so all you
have is your host with scanner running
on it and access to some VMs ten hundred
VMs and all the the process of creating
the the the brokers sending the the
target to them and then spinning the
different actors is all transparent you
don't have to do anything so of course
this this allows for infinite scaling
yeah that that's me being a little bit
optimistic but the idea is that you are
able to decide the number broker you
want so the number of VMs you provide it
to scanner and then you decide the
number of actors or wrong processes you
want per broker and you get the whole
process going and you should be able to
scale indefinitely so this is all good
and nice so the design looks good but
finger printing like I said at the
beginning is specific to the protocol to
the service that you want to access and
communicate with so the the core
provides all those basic blocks of
parsing starting the VM on the remote
host and so on and we've added two
modular elements the fingerprinting
module and the output modules that are
easy to integrate into scanner the
fingers fingerprinting much
is the part that is running on the actor
path so that's the little minions that
is communicating with the servers and
the output modules is the way you want
your results to be filter or aggregate
or pores before they get outputted to
any kind of of output so I'll got a
little bit deeper in those two modules
to give you an idea who it is and it's
not that difficult
so the fingerprinting modules is
actually allows you to to perform three
types of communication TCP UDP and SSL
sounds pretty good so far and and
there's a mechanism of callback so that
actually the whole scanner process here
on the Left will be handling all that is
the transport communication so
establishing the TCP connection or
sending some payload receiving some and
your module on the right side we only
have to respond what is the next step to
do so for example after the connection
is made the the scanner will ask you
module so what I do next
and you will provide some payload that
will be sent to the remote host and then
when the response come back you get to
parsing and so on and so forth until you
happy and you bring back some results so
this allows for easily implement some
some modules without going into whole
the network layer stuff that is
sometimes a bit more difficult so this
is how it looks likes if you've never
seen functional programming or or long
bare with me
I'll explain that it's it's really easy
so like I said you have to declare that
the type so the type you can change it
in one line so for example if you I
implement a module for for TCP like for
HTTP for example and you want it to be
applied to HTTPS you will just change
the TCP in SSL so this is pretty
convenient also as it's it's functional
programming the same function will be
entered depending on the argument so
this is the same different steps we've
seen in
Graff before so the first function here
we enter where we when we start so when
the connection has just been established
with the remote host and here you'll
provide some payload in return so this
is what will be send to the remote host
the second one enters if nothing's come
back for example the the remote host as
an answer or is not running the the
service we expect it to be running so
here you would answer you will return
some some kind of error like like a
timeout for example and and the last the
last part is where the the interesting
stuff is going on so this is where you
get your response you get to parse that
and and and format that in the way you
want so depending on what you're looking
for and the results that you put here
will be sent back up to the master node
which will aggregate all those results
so as you can see this is a simplified
example but it gives you an idea how
easy it is to just implement a bear
module for fingerprinting a specific
service for example the output module is
is based on the same ID with with a
callback
it has also some two functions in E and
clean in order to setup and manage the
output let's say for example you want to
write to a file in the an e in E you
will set up your file descriptor so that
it's ready to be processed and in the
clean you will close the file descriptor
or flush the data to the to the fire and
and this way of doing allows to format
or even filter or reformat the data the
way you want it for example you could
you could want to output that to two to
standard out like print that to the
console some save to a file even push to
a database or stream to another host so
anything is possible here since you have
control over all results that are
provided provided back by the
fingerprinting module this is how it
looks like so in E and clean this is
an example is pretty straightforward but
the output here is where each results we
will go through before getting input
output it so here it's simply writing to
standard out but you could think of for
example sending to some elasticsearch
node for example for post-processing or
save to a database sequel database or
whatever anything is possible and and
this freedom allows to to pre-process so
to say the results so that they're
formatted the way you want it in the end
so how does it look in practice here
before I'm going into how fast is it
how good is it so a few lesson learned
about using a scanner first
fingerprinting like we've seen at the
beginning will bring back a lot of data
not only the studies of app or like port
scanning but the whole payload that that
you asking the remote host so since our
long is is running in the virtual
machines you sometimes end up with the
heap overflow so you have to increase
the ramp we've also added a few option
in order to control that but you have to
be aware that this is something that
could happen also the bottleneck is not
we would think in the actor side so the
side where we we connect to the remote
host but more on the saving process so
it means that it's not always the
perfect solution to have more minions to
to process much more faster the targets
but more how do you handle those results
how do you save those results for
example to a fire it's also pretty
difficult to debug a distributed
application if you've done that you know
what I mean internal communication will
impact your network too so not only the
communication with the remote host like
the the service you're trying to
fingerprinting but all those which
retrieving the the results back managing
all your nodes also on and like I said
before it's everything is transparent
but you still have to provide VMs for
Scannell to use so you have
to set up those VMs the dependencies are
not high it's only setting up a few
option for along and installing Erlang
but still you'll have to set up those
VMs you can use any deployment tools
like ansible for example to do that but
it has to be done it in anywhere one
thing you have to do when using scanner
2 is to give a lot of love to you season
means because using a tool like that
that scale pretty large will impact your
network and will mostly likely break it
here we can see a contract table on a
firewall being hit so once the contract
contract table is hit and you don't have
much more going on right so I don't know
if my season means are here but anyway
if they are thank you guys because I
broke their network a few times and
they've been really nice so yeah you
have to be aware of that it will create
a lot of parallel connections and and
might or will break your network so now
we get the performances so I took the
same target as before so Alex at top 1
million top-ranked websites I tried to
be fair although the comparison is not
very fair between a distributed
application and still a known
application but still I use 20 VMs each
with one V CPU and tookies of ram
against those 24 CPUs and 190 gig of the
rams anyway so the grub donated in 48 8
minutes and map wasn't that and scanner
one was done in four minutes so this is
a 10 factor
it's pretty nice and we've only used 20
vm so what if you scale even more so
I've tried with 60 VMs and we come down
to 1 minute and 30 seconds so this means
that here like I said at the beginning
if you want to target all those 18
million targets like Z grab would take 3
days to do that here with with a scanner
you do it in two hours with 30 VMs if
you double the number of VMs then it
gets probably down to one hour so this
is pretty good as you can see we've
tried several protocols of course all
that is SSL related world where you have
more overhead of
due to the communication it's a bit
longer but still you can still you can
scale and and the idea is that you
should be able to add more VMS in order
to be more more performant so yeah
pretty good results so now you say so
how much does that cost well it's it's
free like in free beer although it's a
bit early but it's open source on github
and and there's already a few modules of
available there but we are releasing
more especially related to ICS and SCADA
so if you haven't yet go have a look
clone the repository try to play with
the tools and see how it works out with
you for you and if there's anything not
working feel free to open an issue or
come discuss with me we are happy if
people try using it because I think it's
a great tool so what are we gonna do
next first idea is to package for big
Linux this distribution like Kali for
example for pen testing Ubuntu we've
seen it it's already a package for Arch
Linux which is pretty good I haven't
done it so I found out the other day so
that's nice we want to increase the pool
of available modules by getting the
community involved
the idea is to yeah get get more of
those modules being implemented I'll
have to improve the documentation it's
not the perfect task and the most
interesting one but I have to do that
too one of my wish would be to pour it
to ipv6 it's not under plan and I don't
know if we'll do it but I think it will
be a great challenge and especially
since everything is moving towards ipv6
today this this is a kind of tool by by
using scaling that could allowed to do
large research on ipv6 and of course get
a fancy logo so if you have any idea
come talk to me I was thinking of a
scale or something but I guess marketing
won't agree
so with
so a little summary so scanner is fast
as I've shown because it's distributed
it's flexible so you're able to
implement your own fingerprinting module
and your output modules to handle the
the results are you want it to be it's
open source so it's free you can get it
as it is it enters TCP UDP and SSL and
is able to target IPS or even domains so
independently of both and it has very
few dependencies because only along is
required to run it so yeah so that's it
for me I was fast I think I've put the
link to to the to our github if you want
to try the project and to our blog where
we publish some of our results if you
want to go have a look and yeah thank
you for your attention and don't ask
tough questions
[Applause]
any question did you try to run it in a
cloud and you know some cloud providers
but allow you to spin up some VMs and do
scanning yeah I tried it wasn't very
successful because I get I got a lot of
abuse yeah usually cloud providers don't
like all those activities of scanning
and so on so you have to check all those
little chars at the end of what you sign
know what you register for before doing
so I tried it wasn't a success success
because I got blocked but I got a nice
slide for that you you can okay I'm
sorry I'm not a Windows user okay I'll
go first through that you can build your
own cloud and that is by simply getting
raspberry PI's and you could run
scanners on different raspberry PI's in
Iraq for example and you get your own
cloud right since since you were able to
control the number of process yeah but
as proof Austin yeah the thing all right
any other question
you you are talking about TCP pulling
are using anything similar to cowboy or
something like that - well - cowboy took
over she's one one very unknown I mean
TCP pulling tool for TCP okay similar
also to Moshe web something like that
yeah no no nothing yeah it's well known
things in Everland
so what is it the vulnerability scanner
no no no it's not the venerable I'm
talking about just the the part of a TCP
liar why we have to build everything
because there is already things already
develop it so in term of air long there
is a lot of things done in terms of TCP
oh okay yeah this is why I'm asking the
questions
it's for me it's exactly 100 it's
similar in there the back end like one
you are for example using actors or you
are scanning to do for example there the
HTTP connections like so this this
abstraction layer no I've never used it
and I didn't even know I'll give it a
look thank you for the pointer go boy
it's okay no demo I don't want to break
the club right yeah in fact I have two
questions first question is did you give
a try to mask on just not for this test
I've tested mask and in the in the past
not here but mask and as far as I know
you can provide a payload for
fingerprinting it was mostly for
challenge the question was to understand
yeah if you try and why you didn't reuse
- okay
the thing is mask and for me is mostly
oriented to port scanning and not
fingerprinting and
so this is the whole idea had with
scripting if you have to always provide
the whole payload and stuff and do some
geeky stuff around that and scrape the
whole thing then it's if even after that
you're not able to scale what's the
point of that so this is the whole idea
of Scannell is to try to scale
horizontally so distributed on on
minions and in the cloud and my last
question it was just to be sure that I
understood when you mentioned that you
launched an actor every time you have a
target for example if you want to scan
like 65 key ports are you able to launch
an actor for each spot I'm asking this
because you mentioned blacklisting and I
think it might be interesting to have
many actors not in order not to be
blacklisted I don't know if you have
this granularity yes yes so you can
choose the number of the words our slide
for that you can choose the number of
brokers so that means the number of VMs
so you can think of a broker like a
process on a VM or you can even think
multiple broker on on single VM and then
for each worker you can choose the
number of actors is spinning for example
if you say okay I want just only one
hundred parallel processes or
fingerprinting processes running then
you can provide that as an option and
you can also not limit it limit it but
the thing is then you'll break some
networks like I've shown before but yeah
you have that granularity and that's all
options you have when when launching the
tool
yep okay any question left
there is one there is one actually just
a little question so everyone is
laughing because we are working together
just a little question did you try to
run it on the big big ass machine to see
how good it compares on on a single note
compared to the other tools you comfort
that's a good question
so I haven't directly on this machine
there but the thing is I've done is I
experiment that using multiple brokers
on a single VM or single machine is
usually not good for performance it was
better to have a single broker and and
and double the actor instead of doubling
the the broker and having that separated
in the to process so that's from my
experience I haven't tested on that
machines but yeah you should definitely
use one broker per VM okay last question
well actually there are like three
questions first there is a there is a do
you have any result that you can show
about the fingerprinting that you have
done the second one is that have you
been detected as do s generator and the
third one have you been contacted by
soda or any other fingerprinting
searcher or using your stuff
okay so first question yeah we provide
our results in this blood maybe it's too
low I got like a full page here so yeah
if we publish something it's older go
have a look we publish laughs a lot of
results that was for the first question
second one yeah of course we get abuse
letters this is something we're used to
because when you perform port scanning
or fingerprinting people get angry so
yeah we do that and we usually answer a
person into each person that has
requested us to stop or that is not
happy with what we do and last question
was how should I know we haven't been
connect contacted by shodhan or any of
those scanning platforms okay
Thank You Adrian thank you