under them pacer we are we already know
spare me 10 10 estas Alice tan Bonita
mara-vee-oso a cartel area tango I love
it Quincey demas cream Oh sacré de como
plateaus patrocinadores platino yes
Athena ther Janos patrocinadores sorrow
because consider stay on your Abel's
Capgemini Avery's orange peel SS a
prayer Waterhouse Coopers Aristotle oye
que telefónica una plaza para ellos que
nos permit
thanks for this wonderful environment
this is a talk that is great for the
place we're in they're going to talk
about film we have with us
Francisco Jose he has computer and
masters in safety of the information
technologies and since a 2017 works in
Monica and the team crazy ideas and
collaborate with Luca in Nevada he's
also a research journalist he's a
co-founder of a journal such as how to
fulfill one magazine wanna carve another
media and right now he works with a
great team in the publication of rebus
Tasik who's a leading
welcome oh I want to think that for
offering us this space there's a great
honor to participate in the 10th your
birthday party and we're gonna talk
about movies and hackers film can be
considered hacker technology to the
extender it creates an intuition or
something that doesn't exist and it it's
a passion for us and it fills us with
curiosity and it surprises us the fiber
history of the large of the big screen
us those of us would believe about
cybersecurity
much I choose these films our
expectations about the cyber Paducah but
before we start we're going to spoil do
a lot of spoilers I'm also gonna have to
put up with a lot of a pixel you never
saw something films are a bit old in the
last 30 years and the spoiler effect
won't be so serious so here we have
August and lewiston yeah we believe they
are the first hackers in history to
achieve a dream that's a lot of people
had had before which was to give
movement to image 20th of December is
the first day of the history of film
they projected in a coffee and a coffee
in Paris a film entitled frame coming
from today is that look so simple to us
made viewers run away in terror thinking
that there the train you say driving so
the first effects of
century discovered that the Revere
invention could be consider more than
attractions but a great art of this
screen with these trained will feel our
heads and our homes and we'll end up
living in this virtual world of film
came about in which computers is one of
them whether it was white computer
almost like best based on mechanical
machine from child fathers and if you
know that it's connected with a Don
Lovelace computer Polly was at the
beginning and absolutely necessary
because the argument is that a meteorite
is going to you collide with Earth and
the government says we can't quite
believe that in both entrepreneurs
decide to launch an airship to try to
save as many people as possible and
calculate the trajectory of the
meteorite they used a computer it was a
differential machining they gave it
which was the one that Ada Lovelace was
trying to promote and computers not
becoming more popular not only in
societies because at that time they made
I was using it
also very common in the missile nuclear
missiles and one that popularized
computers were say with Catherine
careful and Spencer Tracy who weren't
and are famous unable to become later on
in this human that's cassette where a
computer was trying to get the job of
hard rehab who was librarian came about
and it's one that you all should see if
you haven't seen it which is fantastic
voyage that tells or explain how an
engineer part of making miniatures of
things to the extent that they manage
for submarine to be small enough to be
introduced in a person's body at that
chance that the Russians and they start
fighting to see who can do that until
creator suffers a brain problem that can
only be resolved by entering his body to
save him so what's funny about the next
year if not the highest from the biggest
computer ever manufactured
they were showed the IBM a NFS qu7 it
had 16,000 void her tubes it was
destined to the control of the a cold
war between Russians and Americans it
waited 245 talent that was the computer
and talking about the Cold War those of
you who are interested in AI hacking
computers this is a film
that was a milestone it was called
Colossus defecated project and it says
that the United States had Russia in
delegate all control of their missiles
into artificial intelligence but the
problem is of the artificial
intelligence detects that the people in
charge are not responsible and both
machines the Russian and the American
one agree on gun control from people if
this is the decoration at the end of the
movie where the machines right that they
are going to take charge because as
humans are to destroy each other
this was that perhaps was the first one
to talk about artificial intelligence
depth so when I will begin to do the
hacking whether the kind hacking come
along well before that you have to tell
you that computers have been great
protagonists of all films and this page
is interesting you have the link there
you need to have time for that
what it does is it takes all film and if
there is one single screen frame with a
computer and it will it will listed here
and they you know ghost chaser the the
computer is only there for a couple of
seconds the crazy police academy this is
the computer you see what about hacking
why are they in cybersecurity really
come about well probably with this film
it's a film that's actually accommodated
no no drama no trailer it was considered
the best comedy concept of hackers there
is not quite like the one we have right
now
[Music]
also the detective of a heart attack
this is a thief that realizes that
through computers can sail and can steal
a lot of money and he's there so much
money that he he then has to run away to
Brazil with the secretary and I like to
say that this is the first time that
there is an unauthorized incursion into
spectra 7 and 50 but this is this is no
intelligent artificial intelligence at
all in cybersecurity we always say that
I wanted to be very careful with the
insiders who generate 70% of the
disasters in many companies well already
discuss a problem but society at the
time that made people laugh and it was
rifle that I feel and and they were
picking and that was also the beginning
of the image do you believe that hackers
in movies much hackers in real life
blocks everything and don't just care so
in the car
much yeah we have in the last one we
have supper area but this is the bond
hammer in your life so have these
hackers and these computers have also
built great protagonists of this
phenomena matrix and in the last example
perhaps is not the greatest film but but
it's still very popular hacker doesn't
make any sentiment connected to the
search of the origin of the hacker world
this is where it all begins
it all begins in the MIT this is a poem
written by a scientist of MIT in 1960
and why is there a train but at the time
the MIT was experimenting with a train
models and they they it were something
spectacular for the time but they were
missing some and components I want to
have a traffic light here or or a
junction that I need this part box
material that they needed and they not
use it for their model place and that's
what that's what that was a hack
when you were able to take something and
use it for something else than in turn
original in original indictment so Dobby
she was a hacker and there are all sorts
of hackers but what happened here this
is a murder this is a real picture of
MIT and what happened one day a nature
too many electrical business away from
the telephone boxes and they left at all
without phones electrical fuses from the
phone box this is the article printed at
the time explaining that this killed
broken of the of the hacker world as it
was originally and to try
to clean up the term we have invented
the term black hat hacker and white hat
hacker and that comes from the movies in
the western films the good guy always
dressed in white and they got the bad
guy always dressed in black and they
matching hats that's why we have these
white hub hackers and black hat hacker
although perhaps there's a better term
yes cracker would be a lot better it
says that my promoted and he said stop
calling
but guys let's choose another word
cracker it's been used a lot in the
ideas but it's so the question is if
this pejorative meaning of the word
started with this film because in Spain
we have this habit of translating titles
it happened with the greatest spoiler of
raspberry baby baby which in Spanish was
translated into the seed of the devil
I'm sure you've heard about this feeling
1995 I have mixed feelings about this
but there are people living love it and
the technical people like it because it
it touches upon important topics but
look at that their crime is curiosity
and the second one is that in Spanish
they translated hackers computer pirates
and at the top it says you thought your
secrets were safe while you were wrong
so
to see the film everything was spoiled
for you so what is a hacker so the film
has its charm because the main
characters be collecting IDs and writer
this prim writer just they are a lot of
people in the sector around but and
sometimes even wrote something that
actually made sense and there are two
books that you have to be familiar with
things but the static say history but it
is true that attack it talks about the
hacker culture which in the freak
element which has been part of the
culture ever since and the was quite
nice and it has been copied many times
have been in in mediums with beautiful
and Hawk the planet it's an interesting
concept yes and it identifies they they
save the planet sort of at play on those
words
there is one went forever because I was
a child of my first communion day I was
a suppressor and taken to see it I shall
feel very popular at the time wargames
1983 this film had a great impact in my
childhood because I wanted changed my
school scores with a computer I didn't
see the film but I was given the book
and from the I read it and the kid was
going to school and he would stay - in a
game being there you know that we spent
a lot of time in the game in arcades and
everything yes here is the time which
was were dialing you ring phone
Tennessee if a machine answers and then
if it was a machine you could use her
protocol of the time and and that was
something that was really off and it
done yes that was done in United States
because you could you had a flat freight
and not in Spain you would have gone
bankrupt if you did that or so and here
the character or the computer to the
right has not monitor and the keyboard
and so but they
they just robbed us there being any
computer of the time that they lose
their person and they manipulated their
voice so what they did rather than
recording all of these entities they
would sort of scramble it in human voice
to make it sound machine like if there's
somebody who hasn't seen more games
everybody has seen it okay so you know
the genius with this a the film is also
based on this goes back like the first
ones today were a cold war this is the
second Cold War later on in the 80s and
here they introduced artificial
intelligence without noticing they are
talking about enhance the learner which
is a machine learning technique because
they were training the machine against
itself so that the machine should reach
a conclusion they didn't know but they
were actually starting from a base that
is now pinions which is enhanced
learning and a final metaphor which is
quite good the one over here the best
move is not to play because just
realized that with Cold War there was
going to be no winner whatsoever and the
dead cop this is the first time I saw
this term death come one two three four
that later on it became very popular
well this was probably the more the
flagship film of the eighties but it is
the dictator started again with the
comedy film a film that also showed
cybersecurity in a much more mature away
because one person just enter in the
system of somebody else trying to defend
this was teamwork very well organized
we're talking about these things they
sneakers are only 98 92 sorry
I like this more because it's it's
yes it is a rat team no doubt
their works
these are different experts in Swiss
market whose electrode who is an expert
in in piracy and at the center is the
red team boss yeah that actor has to be
the boss here it's a penetration team
that panel testing and then their real
hacker the technician and a woman at the
top charge of the management of former
FBI agent and and who did social
engineering and then there's some who's
based on this person the applied expert
Steve but for instance love him because
he got into the hockey area in security
and and it even founded April Apple with
Steve Jobs because they did this film
and when take care of the whole freaking
community of the time and Dave's they
said that this guy could actually
generate by blowing the right frequency
to reproduce the sound of the telephone
yeah it's a wild film the other tape and
we were preparing the tall guy I showed
the tried it no trailer to my 12 year
old son and he said when is this one
coming on but it's twenty years old and
you'd be surprised if you see it now
because of how contemporary it is and in
fact it closes with the quotation the
bad guy in the film who became famous
because of the Oscar that they receive
but then they stall better and worse
they replace the bad guy in Iron Man 3
shall bake a slave in place the bad guy
on this fear in the end
Thank You Slee supposed to go against
rather bad for a start and they started
feeling being a couple that are trying
to steal money from the banks to pivot
to charities and this film what they
have a box that have a reference a
stolen and they wanted to use to bad
stock and it's a box that allows you
with cryptography to have access to all
code and then kiss me tell him that
scheme is not this is not just about
money this is not just about power but
what it says here the world isn't round
by weapons anymore or energy or money
but it's run by little ones and zeros
little bit of data it's just electrons
it's about who controls the information
what we see and hear how we work what we
think it's all about the information and
this is 1992 and we're still there and
the fear was also supported by experts
he was one of the advisors of the field
so it has a sort of a very solid
scientific based basis and as to the
Machine it was able to decipher any
cryptographic code here I am that
suggests to me quantum cryptography
yes but the pocket quantum cryptography
a great film anyway but of being a bit
of kind of cheated here in the first the
x-files film for a few minutes you get a
team what these guys the longer legs
guys like teamwork sneakers are
appearing on The X Files
and there's a series they're not my
people have seen he's in a speech I say
it's been off from the x-files I'm going
to save you telecoms expert social
engineering expert and then the idea is
just amazing is really it really is
amazing
so technically do read of the real
things so let us go back to the hackers
movies here we have another one between
TV option suppose we call this picture
you see one of them is working the other
one I was working of course the real
Apple genius he was one doing the work
to see if Jobs was looking at things
but why pirate first of all pirates
sorry can remain that off because they
didn't have any geographic environment
apple or Windows they install it to
Zurich Palmer who operated one day Steve
Jobs Bill Gates got ahead in publishing
Windows 1.0 okay so what happened very
angry he called him up and said hey
don't you so from now know Bill Gates
was the only person
has been proven between a name Stanley
Steve Jobs said hey I haven't done
anything I say I know when to steal from
a neighbor and I saw you are you won't
just leave it before and he said it's
not probably not in that way without
conversation it exists so when you look
at things you did happen Steve Jobs
imperative about theft then on the other
hand it was quite common Silicon Valley
you have a pirate flag in teams who is
something innovative affect my sick jobs
done we need to be smart or maybe have a
permit flood and here we have pictures
from the film when this picture is part
you know sting and you're saying yeah so
Steve's looks great today yes so it's
our security there's a level of
awareness three two one
it is a funny thing how many bows for
the Raptors not you know a cyber
security needs to pertain to everyone
especially hackers is ability to admit
point that is right it's hard for same
time to make it well sometimes we
advanced is worthless if you and enough
put this here underneath of Apple
foundation
Steve what look so that he hadn't done
anything because Irish that was just
warehouse well he's doing easier based
remember joy bubble who was in front of
cereal box and inside there was a
whistle that little joy bubble did 600
heads and they bond to make three calls
use them at university but they never
really sold them maybe some expertise
working my kids they begun with this and
we'll get his machine he was trying to
make a call with Tommy and Hughes
see also stoner free Chima that he
fought near deal but he got paid with
little food and I'm not taking the
Marriott offer Steve Jobs he had the
world of business great vision and he
knew how but he does talk about I love
hate relationship of safe gates of Bill
Gates and Steve Jobs
well Microsoft towards the owner of
nearly all of our people who are whether
you not see Bill Gates that was cremated
lunch and then job said let's see my new
partner and Bill Gates appeared and
people were moving because he had always
been Chris a simple guys but he
eventually won
we'll help those there's a whole
long-standing relationship between its
called transpiration
is really scary remember the Publix is
not just like in here all executive
doing commerce on signal Valley however
behind he is sitting software for
programmers and masking really Phillips
are and if t realize is that different
people are dying strong circumstances
yes is lost a set of circumstances like
there's some interesting concept is by
some McCarthy that the founder of it's
obvious that I wasn't with those two
so she virus security and through a
front she discovers one of the software
problems of the government of the USA
he's using has bugged all the pretty
much everything : way to say the same
thing he'll office absent a fire sale
so she's guilty number disappears she
knows her circular but the e key part
the in part of a she finds a virus
greater
this is a king of the world
now the management machines
talks about
he's just good because there are some
mistakes such as they own a machine
human manufactured he was picture here
manufacturing hitting a gallery junkies
song but it was a undermining the
chronic machine he didn't yourself when
a machine even managed to automate this
de touhina process you see the
university barber is just inverse
engineering trillion remember he was
opposed then all of a mansion here so me
too well
you probably expect I hated this we have
one ship of the virus and once I saw the
extended version expand it to make sense
right in lucky 150 there was a spaceship
15 years these have been
I stopped in the food network computers
so the phase which is beginning Facebook
so Lincoln very active database nation
yes it kind of expands out can you see
there's a realistic full of cinema
[Music]
for my ears she's like this
well he made me say to American systems
selling information so you are some o2
others but do something with each animal
[Music]
consciousness
when I'm 15 again too much fish might
face what it is was a secret it was a
code it's not reality
there's another thing here like a Seco
18,000 monitors with possible just
mechanisms trace of a gimmick you teach
English for a hunter I don't think
how are you doing
there's actually
so KP 1 you saying
but there needs to be something
ok so let's give the hospital rules
[Music]
okay
can you since we don't like security
firms in Spain
fix wasn't too much does anyone have one
question for the speakers I think I said
when we go to detail where they should
be really short and quick by the way
well you might not like it but here miss
Peng apparently some films are being
made with a snail do you have any
reference open windows for example yes
he's actually not played by a very open
windows a little suggestion yes we're
just gonna fit it like one time so much
better
Lutie 2020 with all the things we have
well thank you very much guys thank you
pleasure
[Applause]
unagi Mufasa a and is one lasting by the
way you will love cinema hackers I think
also music so you have creative Expo
file it's called cinema versus 2019
there you have many of them were big
things