thank you my name is Mariana Bellomo I
am malware analyst of antal gene a
low-tech system who have changed the
name now its security systems and I'm
working in reversing but where analysis
and when you see the beautiful thing bad
guys do you are interested in knowing
the dark side the other side of the coin
well my email is here and you can get in
touch with me if you'd like to sell it
feedback or a beautiful picture well
look nice and we're going to start now
with this malware analysis and the
reverse in lab we're going to have
reversing or malware analysis workshops
in order to analyze all binary and CTF
environments or what's equivalent and
the daily analysis we perform we have
here a graph where we have the way I had
organized my daily analysis lab it is
what I do to get connected to CTF
systems and here I have the virtual
device virtual machine I use the
software virtualization malware because
things that are good and they facilitate
things and tasks are easier I'd like to
show you that I've connected this to my
host and I have a series of rules
applied for the traffic to be redirected
towards a proxy proxy proxy in
transparent mode in such a way that with
a certificate of the user I can I can
break I can breach the HTTP for traffic
and see requests clearly for this to
work I have to tell the device
we should use the DNS of your host the
domain and system I use of DLS mask with
this configuration the domain server of
the host I have this mask here and you
can copy this directly and you can have
your own lab you would like to start
fighting malware and on top of this I'd
like to say that as we work with a
virtual machine then they know this the
bad guys know about it and there are
ways to contract this because they are
traces their registries there are
footprints things that easy to check
with programming tools and if we don't
want to have patches all the time to
pass the tests we can change the
configuration of the device well we can
then refrain from doing cumbersome tasks
and as I said before this could be
perfectly done otherwise and are things
I'd like to say as we saw the CPUID
instruction and their symbol if we put
the register EXA one bit at one that
sends us if it is a it's sent to the
instruction it means the instruction is
taking place at Virtual Machine the
configuration file add this line you see
here if you add this first line the one
on top of here then you get always a
zero from the instructions in the
configuration in the configuration file
you can say that your virtual machine
will be a cloning of the manufacturing
of yours the virtual machine is a clone
of the host of a CPU ID when you use the
other parameters you'll get a string
that is used to compare and to see a
virtual machine so you're checking and
you're as you see here skipping the
test so then there are ways perhaps you
will see here in small print but there
are some MAC address that corresponds to
VirtualBox or malware software's and
virtualization and a configuration in
this card you change this configuration
and you put one that looks like your
host when they check the hardware like
the amount of RAM memory you have or for
instance the size of a hard disk and
this capacity the number of processors
when you create a virtual machine and if
you don't have lots of resources you put
something that is not very ambitious and
useless for tracing also there are some
programs some software programs that are
free al qussair and Pasha's they have
implemented the normal malware
verifications to detect virtual machines
and as those are open software's you can
go to the repository and you can see the
code that's checking things so you can
think how to turn it by the way and to
see everything green everything is good
when they execute the software once you
have implemented the suffer machine you
have to give some tools to a machine
facilitating our analysis tasks I'd like
to split this into different categories
and I have here rapid access from the
bar but each one of you can do it your
way
do it your own way I have several
decompilers too for languages like
dotnet or another software the decompile
flash router it and there are debuggers
like immunity I have
the old one that it's good still frost
and the Model X 32 t BG X 32 d BG the
modern one of course I have what you see
on screen the graphic user interface
that's also useful and hexadecimal
compiler we have the 0-1 editor that is
able to have a string inaccessible and
you can't copy and paste and for
instance you have a binary coded in
hexadecimal you copy directly and you
have the binary and such ready for using
it and executed then a normal one HX d
or the one that down there that allows
you when you have a memory memory part
use you can look for it and you can say
clean it clean everything to have MZ
header and also the other part can be
cleaned debugger to analyze the binary
structures are seen here as we see for
instance to detect the version of a
compiler the compiler that's been used
for generating the binary visual C C++
or dollfie or whatever and also for
instance there are programs like
multi-purpose programs to see different
things like piece to do and people to
see resources from executable they want
to dump it and keep it's executing
to reconstruct very poor table a
software like Excel our incorrect are
useful many times as we use the vector
for entry there what they use is the
videos or the USGS that are interpreted
by the window script the mother and
there are some debug rocks included for
us to know to this text file those are
text files and we have some points to
add to be executed in other cases web
another program that was created by one
of my co-workers to load to the file
there and you have it's you play and
[Music]
it's quite easy to use user friendly and
that was done by one of my co-workers
obviously we need to know what happens
with the operating system when we
execute here from Microsoft it's very
useful the internal things and there
this program also were the capture of
all the keys all the registries from the
system and you can do whatever you want
to do you executed a sample and then you
compared to see the keys modified what's
been deleted and so on so forth and also
there are tools like the one you see
here to analyze documents in the case of
Microsoft Office it is what we can give
to the machine or to start upload and
let's talk here to Athena
Antonia platform Athena who knows at na
Athena who's played with all the
challenges you've taken the challenges
to first channel is Athena
is safety information technology safety
and security platform we have several
challenges like cryptography stenography
exploding networking reversing and what
we're going to talk here is reversing
and there's Athena platform they created
a school Athena Athena school for those
who are starting security and
information technology there are some
courses were the theory and tutorial
courses with the challenges but the
difference is that you get solutions
here you can compare if you are in the
right track if you're doing well or not
so where to start with reversing in the
school Athena School in Reverse in
Category we have a computer architecture
we have the Intel's syntaxes we have to
know all the act active on norman
characteristics we describe here the
binary format of Windows we define the
portable executable format from
Microsoft theory of D and sample
compiler d compiler and the MST and so
on and the challenges from Athena I was
told to analyze have seen challenges in
front of you and those are old
challenges out of those for reversing
challenges I'd like to say I'd like to
revise with you I'd like to elaborate on
the simple ones for those who are
starting and just to get a flavor and
with that we're going to talk about
another Matuschka the Matushka
it is one of the most difficult
challenges of the platform of reversing
challenges and was totally the first one
that cracked me if you can't crack me if
you can and distract me the challenge is
to obtain the key that is of a code that
will appear when the binary is executed
in the proper way
[Music]
two out of five stars and we get the
binary and the hash tag whenever we see
a new binary I like to explain how it's
been done on what has been used to do it
because you can get an idea of where to
go which tool you should use and about
the next steps to take and then here in
this case for instance we check the file
of God is an executable and 32 bits for
Microsoft Windows and there is a tool I
have described which is detected easy D
I eat to see the compiler in this case
is a visual C C++
that's the Edition 2015 version release
414 and then it seems here the entropy
of the binary and you see that it is not
high this entropy so they haven't use
sort of blaring methods so when you want
to take the D compiling and the
assembling of the program you see the
real code that was created by the
programmer and then we take this and
crack me if you can knowing that we are
able to see it as such we upload at D
assembler it is first of all I prefer
the static analysis to see in the
program flow as it is visual C C++ was
subscribed by our colleagues previously
when you conduct a program
and visual C++ the entry point is not
the main that was created by the
programmer the compiler man puts a lot
of code and beginning but with the
experience and good of idea a bit of
idea you can see this is Hydra software
Hydra software that's an open software
nowadays with Hydra and in this case we
upload the program and we see and the
left inside the entry point look for
this and the decompiling with the
assembling once we have the entry point
there we see decompiling on the
right-hand side and there is a function
to which we give two parameters and in
this case we have two pointers but in
general and the truth is that this is
the main because you have here the
arguments and you have here another way
to get to the main would be to look for
strains of characters in those strings
of characters I mean strings of
characters and to look for something
striking and this binary web CCN
container CCN container and then you
would look for the string of characters
and here you could tell of a system
where was a string used and then it will
take you to the d assembler where it was
used and you could go up levels to get
to what you think it's the main it
should be a function there will be
visual c c++ that array of characters
and one figure so we see here the
representation of c dacoit code created
by hydra on the main of a program and
what you see here is that there is an F
condition that's each if it does not
comply with this that goes to zero and
finished that's it what in this f there
was an F condition sin equal nama for
the program to go on to go ahead and
then what let's see what happens there
and I would like to say that what we see
here is parameter 1 and it should be
more than 2 bigger than 2 the main
function parameter parameter responds to
the number of parameters we have here
given to this binary it should be higher
than 2 so we have two parameters to the
program and we'll see which two
parameters are there are there is
another function that will give back
another variable boolean viral role that
instance really into figure as you see
here it's different from 0 so we see
that we have to compare two parameters
and that let's see what the function
does the function if we see here the D
compiler and the D assembler of such
method we see it uses they create to
help 32 snapshot that as I said before
if you go to MS which is the reference
of all the ones of the operation
operating system it's used to capture
the process that are executing on the
machine at the moment when you call the
function and then with 32 first and next
you see you go long the snapshot and you
do whatever you want with it
if you look in detail the code of what's
been done there is a verbal to which has
been compared which is an array where
the string of characters I don't know if
you see it in grey its renamed here and
then
strange chinga tu white shark protocol
analysis software that is going to be
used by the analyst the software
analysis analyst and it checks it's
trying to someone is trying to spy to
see the program and then to overcome
this you could have a breakpoint here
and you could make the opposite in the
case you would have one of those but
let's see how to overcome this you have
to take a look at net to have one of
those software is open whenever you are
debugging or you are cleaning the
program the software once the function
is past its function there is another
function down here part of the program
where there is a parameter a parameter I
don't know if you can see it here the
parameter is the first first string that
goes as parameter into the program
knowing that this is the first parameter
given to the program and what you see
here is you have a call of the API of
get computer name instruction you have
to be too clever to know that we're
seeing the computer name but you can go
to MS D and to see what the parameter is
the one it's that's God and then you
compare what is given back to the
parameter the first parameter you have
to convey is the name of our computer
computer name and in the case they do
not get what is to be expected then it
is going to create another flow and
another flow and this flow calls a
function that is showing directly the
window like as such and this crack me if
you can if the name is
that's unexpected someone could think
that's a key or the code or something
but there are other conditions and other
tests to pass curiosity it will look for
the string of characters in Google with
the search for this this is part of the
Neal Stephenson's book and perhaps you
get an idea on this challenge into what
is related to parameters we'll see
number two parameter and what's the
function here in the program program
comparing comparing as it was the case
the first parameter was given to the
first one now the second parameter is
given to the second function and there
are some operations going to the left
and so on so forth and this is in this
case of a hard-coded string hard-coded
string of characters
once they operations they perform the
operations and if they compare this with
the parameter and they coincide this is
going to be used as a code for
deciphering deciphering code it is in
order to whatever here for instance hash
data will have the code or whatever it's
decoding clearly it's decoding
deciphering and that decompiling does
same clearly but we see the version of
the dissemble and we see that what is
given back by the function goes as the
local verbal here as an input and
there's a local variable and you see
that it goes to the one receiving the
code proved crypt create hash and the
code is what stems from this function
what goes out of this function once we
have the code we can have a program in C
language implementing the same thing and
to execute the program or or knowing
that we have an idea and where it goes
we have a debugger the x32 dbg and with
the debugger with a debugger now we're
good to have breakpoints at those points
to check that the analysis and static
analysis dusk respond whether what we
believe it is and then in this item at
this point where we have the defi
deciphering of this who have another
breakpoint comparing this with the
parameter that was conveyed and then we
send randomized parameter first we see
the characters and
we know here we get the second parameter
of this I have a video where I have done
this and I'm going to show the video to
you video on we have the entry point
then I have another one in this main the
main one look at this have another one
here then we skip again we'll go towards
the part where it's comparing with a get
computer name we'll see what's back from
this it's a name of my computer and it's
compared with commando who know which
was the one the name I gave at the
beginning we check because we know the
first one we change the name we swap
we'll put the first name we accept and I
don't know if the video is a bit blurry
or not but then we video again we see it
again we execute again we see that now
it passes the test and here it's
comparing with a string of characters
and I think the video is not time we see
what's been generated the comparison
have accelerated to see the process
let's speed up then note block where I
have included all characters and in the
end it is Neal Stephenson was a string
that appeared there and then we swap it
put lunch gain the program and now we
see
we have a follow break point we see the
comparisons will coincide now and it is
the side we wanted they are comparing
now the string of characters and then
yes let's end this okay the and is that
we get the flag of challenge to you if
you have a time you know what to do and
please go ahead and I wanted to tribute
curiosity you have to create a virtual
machine and to play a little bit with
the virtual machine and now another item
and this is what I wanted to say but I
think that you're not you following me
you're following me yes if not during
the Q&A session can go back and see
things and now we're going to talk about
the Russian Russian puppets with Madonna
Trischka and we're going to find out by
the flag and to overcome this challenge
that is specially difficult this is
matreshka and then on top of this and
this challenge to have a clue that we'll
see we're going to use this or not is to
think about the true ciphering and that
the zip code is infected there is
something and it it is a five star
difficulty it's a we'll see if it is
that difficult let's continue now we get
a zip where we have a binary code inside
we have hash tag here and we just
extract the zip and we see the binary
and now the first thing striking me is
that the header the header is bit odd
strange it's not the typical ones note P
whatever you see the one will you have a
sword and know it is sort of making us
think that the compiler is not the
standard wall not a well-known one you
know the one I've seen till now one of
those have seen two now or they have
used to a type of pattern let's see the
tech TDC so they moved to detected AC
and receive entropy of the binary system
is at a very high level seven point nine
nine nine so it's almost a ninety nine
percent the spidery that we've been
given is packaged so the Packers the
commercial Packers most of them have
been analyzed by the community and they
create created some signatures equally
there are programs where you have a
binary system that could be packaged and
on the basis of these signatures or on
the basis of the execution they tell you
whether the commercial package the
Packer they tell you the the commercial
part of the refused with this detector
may be the Packer that they've used is
Mac code compressor so we know that it's
packaged and in order to see the app
code as the programmer is done we'll
have to apply some transformations we'll
have to stop an execution
it's a executing the binary we'll see
how to do it in order to see the app
code anyway just for the sake of
curiosity were on launch it to sources
and the app was this it was a padlock
that will ask us to type some kind of
combination and depending on what we
type in we will keep on moving so we
know what my code compressor is
and as the community has worked on this
if the first search that you do in
Google is my code my code compressor in
pack you'll see five or six a great
bunch of videos of people D packaging
binaries that have been packaged with
this Packer and the way of packaging
them as well you watch the video news
here you say well this exactly one so
let's see how we can do it so in this
case it's quite similar to upx and we
get to the entry point we would continue
through ESP in the uploading and the
address that we have well we would
include a hard word break point we would
last the binary execute and we would
come to the jump before the original
entry point just before the original
entry point and this is the entropy of
the original program before being
replaced by the packet okay so we would
tamper the binary we would look for the
importable of this new binary and we
would fix it so that the binary can be
executed from the disk and here we would
check that the binary has grown from one
point six megabytes to almost five point
and megabytes and it's still executable
so this way we have been able to
retrieve the most similar things to the
original code of the app and we've have
we have something to see it and with a
static analysis so if we have a look at
this detector of this binary refer
detected detect it easy we see that it
has been done with a Delfy and we see
that the Anthropy has been reduced to
five point 35 so we're almost 100% sure
that we'll be able to include some some
code some codes and we'll be able to
play around with it
so looking for correctly characters or
strains we've seen that we have had pad
we have buttons or so button to
one-click button to click these trends
were quite curious were quite curious to
me and I saw that they were defined in
an structure were above every strain
there was an offset to a function so I
saw how the graph graphic interfaces in
toughy work and this well these offsets
are the functions that are dealing with
the pulses of every button so here they
are the appearance button one button two
and we have numbers but we have to to
see that button one doesn't match number
one so in order to see what every
function does we need to see the length
between button one what button it really
is in the interface so for this what I
did was to upload the application in the
debugger and as we have the opposites
here I included a break point as every
offset so that it stops here to launch
the app for example I click on a and I
see what offset I've stopped so if this
offset is the one that I have here okay
so button one is a repeating this with
every with with with every button we see
that one side - is e etc etc so this
already we can see the strain and a
function that is called fun create this
function initializes the logic of the
graphic interface to initialize
variables all the logic that the
programmer has created for this
interface so if you have a look at this
function we see some variables that have
been renamed but initially you see that
these are variables as you can see on
the screen and if you keep well if you
follow the program areas where these
variables are used you see that there's
an increase of these of this variable
and this is included in a button code
specifically this is included in button
a so these are counters of how many
times you've clicked on these buttons so
there's a counter for buckling a 1/4
button II another 1/4 button 3 and
another one for button C ok and what we
can see afterwards is that this is moved
to a local variable and after that to a
specific offset that these ones where
you can see here I know them down
because they are retrieved these is
retrieved from these offsets to compare
to another function so just to know or
to note down that button a is 980 the
other one is 900 and 984 etc and this is
this on one hand and if you keep on
seeing character strains on this binary
you see that on the one hand this these
strains are some of these strains are
quite big and one of them stays starts
with 4 D 5 a header this is the
equivalent in ASCI I to NZ that is the
header of our windows binary so it could
suspect that in some way we would say
where this has been used we see that
there's a function where it seems that
there is another variable and after that
this variable moves to a function where
there is a right and there's a
okay so everything seems to indicate
that there's another binary round that
will be written in the disk so when
something happens on the disk if we keep
on looking we see the variable as being
Coppedge that has been renamed marine
and s is at part one or chunk one we see
where it is used and we see that we are
moving to other functions and if you
check that these are variables at the
same time that they are following this
order so I guessed and I saw that that
was the case that this was the order
that the binary building was going I was
going to follow so chunk one check two
chain three and after that I renamed all
these asked all these functions and I
renamed the function as part one
variable to you as part two and I looked
at where these functions were called and
if you follow them we can see that both
parts one and two and what I do in the
functions come in a row and they are
called in the offset code that manage
the lodging of paten a if you do the
same for the other parts which well you
see that beforehand there are some
requirements that we'll see but if we do
the same with the other parts well see
that for part three and four and five
and six are on the bottom okay
and seven and eight are on the bottom C
so it seems that these are the partners
that will participate in our pad and the
ones that will have to do something with
if we have a closer look to the code a
code the button a codes are in we see
that agree comes the variables that we
considered as counters before and
they're included in another local
variable and after that there will be a
comparison of that with other values
that have been defined
[Music]
that are fixed in the code in this case
these are four and zero so we see that
it is recovering it and when we click on
it was the function that way that
executes when we push a button so it
checks how many times this button has
been clicked and it compares it with for
with button Ian is compared with 0 and
button see with zero so if we click on a
four four times at the fourth time this
condition will emerge and we'll see that
there will be a file on the disk with T
dot TMP that contains the two first
parts of what is considered as an e MZ
if we click on OK it has the safe one
and after that the other one on the
first one well these counters are global
ok they do not change so it looks how
many times Buckner has been clicked we
don't have to click on a more times
before clicking on our K how many times
we've clicked on e zero and one for C so
clicking on a four four times and
clicking on save for one just once we
would have the part three and four do
you get on long more or less get it well
each Eklund same happens for the second
part a has to be 5 times C 1 one time
and we have the next parts and with the
button see you have the same the same
checks with the same value with the
other values and in the end it has a
code but it just renamed T dot TMP to a
dot X a and each launches the binary
okay so we could launch this on the
debugger and as far as we know the
combination we've been cool breakpoints
in those offsets that we had to check
that this really case
and we could include a one last break
point before the binary executes so as
it's written on the disk we will have it
as itself as such and we will have to
see what we keep on doing with this new
binary so we'll do this and once we
recover this new binary that is a dot XA
we repeat the process the same again we
have a look at it to see what compiler
we've used to created in this case I've
used this XA a info that tells us that
maybe it is a visual C++ we look at the
Anthropy and it doesn't seem that it's
packaged so we upload it again and we
perform another static analysis of this
new binary as it is with visual C++
Visual C++ sorry we would move to the
entry point we threw a strain or having
a look at the D compiler code we would
look we would find the main function or
through an API that could call your
attention you would move to the part
where the main code is the first
instruction that we see is a get console
window we see the windows versus
executing ad and if we have looked at
MSD DN MSDN it says that it should be
hidden I don't know the prefix but the
program as soon as it executes will hide
the window where it is executing the CMD
or whatever so after this we'll see a
stream of operations that you can
include you see loops you can do things
and eventually you see that with all
this it doesn't do anything it it's
stored in the variables it releases them
it reassigns them well if you compare
with the P with a PI calculation
algorithm it was this
I mean it's code to delay the execution
so you have to stop here of course you
have to lose some time
or if you are if you are very good and
you see it you see you say oh okay
that's fine but after doing this the
next step would be something a little
bit more relevant and it's a function
that is called with a new thread with
create fur and this function makes a
hook to the dbg you remote breaking API
this API is called when you have a
binary that is executing a Nutella
debugger to attach to this process to
debugging so what it's doing here is to
have a look where the API addresses and
it is telling it to write down what that
API is to jump to exit to exit processes
so that when you attach to the binary it
calls exit process and it's done it is
an anti attach measure and here we can
see before and after this API if you
keep on what the API is you see that
normally speaking space and some
references and once this code section
has been executed you see that it jumps
to exit process okay so to skip this
debugger you'd have to note this call or
to to know the write process memory call
for example in order to avoid this hook
from happening we continue there are
there a small code then that makes a
different verifications and what it
checks are the permission stars that
this binary has to be executed and it
does it with this IPRs with a certain
information to a stroke with token
elevation as a parameter so we can see
whether the program is being executed
with the permission token and that's
telling us that the banner will have to
be executed with administrator
permission on the other hand it's true
that we could skip this but maybe this
check is being done because maybe the
administrators need some some time of
permission so it's for free so we can
execute it as an administrator and
that's fine on the other hand as a crown
previous correctly did it uses the
create to health to the two structures
API to make a snapshot of the processes
and it goes through them and it checks
in this case that processes father so to
speak should be process with an end CMD
dot X a it doesn't mean that it has to
be CMD dot X a from Windows we could
rename our debugger as CMD on X a and
this condition would be fulfilled or
including a breakpoint and skipping it
after that more checks we see or it
verifies that the Windows version that
we are using to execute this well it's a
little bit tricky here because it's a
live and sometimes it chance where we do
not want it to jump so it has to see
that the Windows version is a Windows 7
on and after that it has a new thread it
creates a new thread with other a
function that we'll have a look at right
now out of this thread a variable is
assigned or allocated and we very far
the not of this variable so that we need
to verify that this variable is set so
that it doesn't care get into the lift
because we don't want that because this
moves directly to a protection that
would delete the executable
so what do we have in this new threat
and this new threat
we have called together saying get a
sign he state and we have a look at MSDN
this is to lock the keyboard pulses and
what does it do with this it has a
counter at the end it checks that it's
different from 12 and it increases every
time we click on an on a key so when we
click on one key for 12 times it will
get out of the scope we do not know what
the key it is but we will have to see
what it does with it if this function
the 14 17 F 0 that has the reference of
what the user has just introduced says
that everything is correct we would
write the next 6 characters in a
registry key that would be current user
software interact
it sets the variable that we were saying
that we want to set in 1 to make the
comparison later on so what does this
function do to compare the value so as
happen as has happened before
we have a jet of code a code jet the
well these are base operations with a
variable defined on other side equally
we can either try to copy this and make
or create a program in C on Python or
wherever you want it but in fact thing
you have to be careful because this is
roll on roll 1 it's taking the lowest
part of the registry so you need to use
these variables or to use more faces too
or masks sorry to to do it if you don't
have time you can do it on C or if you
even have less time executable you have
to launch the executable and you have to
include a break point when the
comparisons is done
between what you've taken out from here
and what we've just included so apart
from all of this you have to verify that
the variable that we've passed it's 12
we know that it has a life of 12 and you
should check the six first characters of
it so that executing this function and
doing these breakpoints we'd be able to
know what's our other six first scan of
six first characters that the binary is
expecting so this is what I've done here
I've stopped just before calling this
function and now I'm going to get in and
I'm going to have a look at the
comparison and dramas so we get in we
see the operation stream the operations
flow we put a breakpoint right here we
execute it and I'm still uploading
memory of this variable that will be
writing down initially it's this so now
I'm going to perform to promote
transformation you can see how it's
going to be executed we execute it it's
a little bit start but well you can see
and it is Atari and if you have a look
at lexa this is the space here's the
first six first characters are Atari
space r2 this
there are more checks it checks whether
you are doing it in a virtual machine in
this case the verification is through
registration registry codes when you
install the les éditions in a machine to
make it compatible with the screen size
to make file copies these leaves the
trace in Windows logs that are these
specific codes so if we make a check and
these keys exist these goes exists we
know that we are executing it on a
virtual machine after this there's
another anti debug measure well we have
the reference here we can see how we use
it and it's calling an a ent DL API
there's another debug measure that we
could skip changing registry and that's
it so after all this we would have the
file writing with P name that you can
see you can see there you have you have
the buffer of what we were going to
write so we're at this that it seems at
64 strain it looks like a 64 strain and
it's going to write a P file with this
content on the other hand well I saw
this before but it made more sense to
input this and this part because it is
when it is used it has resource with the
name 666 and after the OTP it creates
the resource and it takes it to another
file with the name one dot ps1 so if we
do not make some of these replications
of binary we'll make pink and with this
land would call bail and moves this and
passes this strain that is the name of
its executable so it's deleted so it's
not a measure that may
analysis is more difficult because we
need to have a copy and we need to do
this so okay what have we got what do we
have we have a P and P dot ps1 so we
would execute it we would see the
different conditions will you write down
Atari they say that we're going to make