here we go thank you all for being here
I know it's complicated to be here after
lunch however I see thing I see people
still coming in first of all the name of
my presentation is meat non-words make
environment and virtools this is what
meat stand for me-80 so the idea is to
create tools in order to make auditing
process more agile and approved this is
what I'm what about discussing with you
here today so the topics for
representation is first of all an
introduction then auditing for mobile
devices I'm sure that a lot of people
here have any the mobile auditors I'll
talk about how auditing are conducted
and then I'll explain testing
environment which is most specifically
for the tool were created and some
conclusions let me introduce myself for
those of you who don't know me my name
is Paco Ramirez an IT engineering I have
a master's degree in cyber security I'm
a PhD candidate for mobile application
security security at university of
seville I work for in Noatak they gave
me the opportunity to be here with you
today actually so thank them and I've
been working in pen testing for four
years and I might cut it for mobile
devices but also for website hardware
hacking red team and also analysis of
devices Internet of Things Bluetooth
with Wi-Fi etc my researcher and
professor at the university of seville
so i'm working with students
[Music]
have several certifications that were
awarded to me and also responsible for
Oba Seville which is an association at
the world Association and we are we have
the chapter in Seville is led by me and
we teach what we do to different people
for this presentation we're not going to
talk about vulnerability or exploiting
or anything anything sensitive but I'm
going to talk about tests and things
from an academic point of view so no
failure analysis has been conducted for
that so that's the disclaimer
so auditing for mobile devices I like to
do this because probably some of you
have conducted mobile devices auditing
some people may may have not so let me
talk about a wasp you a wasp is a world
organization devoted to security they
started with a web application and now
we're working on mobile application so I
was like I said before is a world
organization that provides us with the
tools for auditing processes and to
implement security controls for our
applications so as you can see here is
the top ten of the tools so the ten most
regular applications and they are
updated by hours these are the most
frequent devices or tools for this kind
of applications so for those of us
working in hacking and pen testing etc
one of them guides to follow was testing
guide that is published its fourth
edition as you can see they talked about
control and the control categorized
cookie sessions etc and each section
allow us to see how control
for example if we have kind of control
for cookies for example or the kind of
sensitivity of the cookie I can get
information from cookies this is
presented by our wasp in this kind and
this allows us to see how this control
can be organized also as you can see in
the screen on the left I'm sorry on your
right says the speaker we call black box
testing so a wasp specifies the kind of
auditing you're conducting and according
to the type of auditing how you will
complement the control what is
interesting for us and we which is more
updated is the mobile security devices
Hamas started studying websites
everything today is moving to the mobile
world and for that we also have the top
10 so 10 most unknown units for mobile
applications the same guide for website
this guy is a little bit different
because in most mobile this section we
have different categories of control we
have the first year the basic level
which allows us to conduct certain
controls of the application the second
tier is more demanding in terms of
security and then we also have a level 4
reverse energy engineering things I'm
sorry so depending on the kind of device
we are auditing we should be applying
one set of controls or or or another for
example applications to know where ATMs
are or the institutions that are closer
to me or so that demands in terms of
audit audit in control and
and control and etc will be not as
strict as applications for the banking
system so depending on the kind of
application we are using we will be
applying some kind of controls or
another one so the guide you will find
two columns and the columns show you the
kind of controls to be conducted so you
can have a tick on the right column and
depending on the level of application or
the kind of application you will be
applying one kind of control or the
other
these are the main controls but I would
like to focus on five kinds of control
why is that if one application has these
five controls it will be difficult for
us to continue auditing because the
auditor will have a lot of obstacles so
first control is SSL pinning route
detection anti tampering debug mode the
detection and obfuscated code and also
anti tampering anti tampering is a
verification you need to verify that a
unit will not be modified obfuscated
codes means something simple it is to
say I have an application I have it
closed feature and instead of naming it
in an obvious way for example see the
key with the password this will be
replaced by letters ABCD to prevent
hackers to attack me so if someone wants
to attack this application and this
feature numbers and letters the code
will be more difficult to decipher then
we have route detection for this section
why this kind of controls are applied
when we have a rooted device the ammos
meaning
is the set of files where the
application is being activated is like a
box and we are not we don't have this we
don't have a root in the mobile device
we will not be able to analyze these
files so if we if I only have a root
detection control if I don't have this
root detection control I will not be
able to access these files also debug if
I cannot have access to this but if I
can debug the application to see how the
application evolves and its registry I
will be able to see how it works so if I
don't have the debug taxes tax are
easier and lastly SSL pinning which is
actually the most difficult for us our
attacks because at the end of the day we
need to apply them the Divine's the
static code but we need to see what the
communications are and we have to make
it go through a specific point so we
need even if we have a certificate in
the application meaning according to the
scheme if the attacker I'm in the middle
Chilly's be application and say I can
break your communication if this
certificate that arrives in the
application which is a malware that I
put in the middle if the application was
able to really underlies the certificate
and if it were possible for you if it
was possible for the device to see this
is not a good certificate so
communication will be stopped this is
the scheme multiplied so I establish
communication and once I verified the
first communication if I verify the
certificate and the certificate is not
one I haven't stored communication ends
and lastly in terms of anti tampering
which is also related to integrity
checking or something like that this is
used by CBS or ATMs actually if you open
it everything will be erased so anti
tampering uses a similar concept if you
run an application under Android you
should have a signed certificate verify
this developer certificate and this
certificate is not exactly the same as
the one that was the original I cannot
continue using the application this is
very difficult because either I modified
the function or I still the certificate
from the developer which is extremely
difficult and this is how we are going
to conduct auditing kind of controls to
be applied and we were talking about the
five most important ones
the idea is to optimize things why is
that let me give you an example of a
chart of an oddity I have five tests for
auditing a mobile application estimates
are half day to prepare the environment
two and a half days or three days for
testing and then I will have one more
why don't have more days or two days to
come up with a report that's the ideal
case for a five-day audit what happens
in reality so you have an auditor and
you he or she will be preparing the
environment for one or one and a half
days so one and a half days two days
four controls and then the report cannot
be touched upon because and the report
will be the same as before but what is
the problem quality and time you devote
time to prepare the entire the
environment for audit but control I mean
you will have less time for tests you
will only have one a half days so one
happy
place to prepare the environment and
then 1/2 days tests so the quality of
the item will be reduced because I will
not have time to verify the other
control in my experience in my
professional experience why does this
happen
this happens because each application is
a world in and of itself so we have an
application using the CRM system some of
the libraries are used only for REM or I
can say or I can see that certain
version the application doesn't run for
6.0 and this application will only be
used for 7.0 version on each application
is a world in and of itself I need to
prepare the environment for that audit
specifically so this was the
introduction of my presentation because
I wanted to focused on how we prepare
the environment I've been working with
customer for seven years for several
months so we have other things one of
them a week and we need to optimize time
but sometimes the problem is that you
need to use time not to optimize
controls and everything but to prepare
the environment this is when my
application comes in place make
environment Android tools meet m18 so we
are able to create an environment that
will be adapted to the application we
want to audit so this is the test when
we run the tool this is the home page of
the two we have two options when we
start start the audit or do something
else so we want to start the audit so
the first thing we are asked is the kind
of environment we want to work with if
we want to continue an emulated
environment
environment or a real environment and
depending on the kind of application we
can raise Android say six seven or eight
we can use this and so we are allowed to
decide what kind of environment we want
so what is the environment we will be
opting well it depends depends on what
it depends on the kind of applications I
have like I said before our application
have libraries that are run in RM so we
need to use a physical device but we
might have depending on the version of
our physical device is six point seven
zero so the application is for the
following version so we need to use an
emulated environment so you have
emulated devices or physical devices so
everything is possible with our
application
what is the following question we are
asked if you want your application to be
parched with freedom so let me give you
an introduction of freedom freedom is a
hooking tool what is cooking cooking
cling to a process to process with this
hooking tool I can modify or cling to
the process and modify the function I'm
interested in and change its results to
do that we have a tool widely spread
widely spread the tool called freedom
which allows us to enter a process
modify the process to obtain another
result so now for you put in order to
show you demo let me show you an
application when once you open it you
will get a message root of detection
what I want to do is to bypass this root
detection so when I open this up a
message pop in and with this message
the application will shut down but I
don't want the application just to shut
down or exit but I don't want to exit I
want to continue using I want to hook in
this function how do i hooking this
function I open a terminal and I say
Frieda Frieda I launch a JavaScript in a
file and I said feature click instead of
system exit I asked not to do anything
because the features changed
I launched Frieda and I said okay
unclick was modified so because this was
modified I can go back to the
application you detect this and you can
continue this is hooking the process
using freedom so what happens Frieda is
very useful tool but with objections so
but this vacation has been in a terminal
for example skipping the SSL pinning
function with this objection the
application and why this apk I mean not
the application I can patch the apk I
have a root device I can even launched a
free the survey process for the cooking
but I need to have the Rudi device
before if the and the device have good
detection no long nothing can be done so
we can use a library that is injected
into the application to be able to
execute this allows me to patch this ap
key ok and use other option debug or
network security office or something
else
add this so when the minutia asked me do
you wanna patch the application with
Frieda and in stall objection and use
cooking for the application yes or now
but also I would like to add network
security conflict because from version 7
have a nindroid
to make an application to go through the
book superseded if this is not included
in the application nothing will be done
this was implemented by Google Android 7
version on but this is not very secure
actually because the idea is to within
the Android manifest our main file
application and we security setup our
application the following thing to do is
to add this file and this is the example
given by Google for you to add this
security is specificity and we need to
indicate with certificate use for each
activity the problem is that we can
modify that we can say that the file is
gonna be this and take all the
certificates of the user system so this
is automatically done by the application
what else can we do we can activate
debug in order to debug and the
applications are never TIF the debug
flat is not activated this function will
not be activated either so if I select
this option they add android tobacco
equal true and they say if the tool the
tool ask if I want to setup the apk
within the device device and launch
objection
so and at the end of the day what I'm
doing in an audit is next next next next
step by step that's how I have an
environment to start editing in only
five minutes and like I said before it
will launch objections in the terminal
we delete completely delete the
verification of SSL paying for the
application and lastly you can raise
aprox proxy because if we want to
analyze the application we have
objection for hooking the patched
version but we can stop the
communication of this application so
proxied is raised
this is a public tool so we don't have
them establish setup so you need to
start this at the beginning for this to
listen the different phases to the
different so this is the basic process
of an audio but more functional
functions or features are possible
static analysis with the Mara tool I can
also have the opportunity to the device
and to launch itself that will allow me
to have access to the terminal and the
terminal will be in the end also Rudy so
this is a virtual Oba for you to see how
we can have access
Oh okey it's um
I mean it's behind me it's gonna be
difficult but okay so we have the
terminal here and we have to launch the
meet command
so there's a very interaction here and
then like I said before you have these
two possibilities from the beginning
delete or other options so I asked the
system to see the first option so once
the other starts the question will be
what do you want what kind of emulator
do you want a physical okay so we will
use Android tix enter here we are with
that with the terminal with an Android
terminal now what happens then the tool
will ask me if I want a patch the
process I want to add it with freedom
these apk another security feature for
proxy yes do you want debug this
application as well yes and then the
question is what kind of application or
what application which application
sorry I couldn't see that very well
because it it's behind me so I have to
start over again
sorry about that
okay so here we are terminal has been
shown so following steps are not made up
until the device and absolutely detects
that the device is connected to the SSL
system so if so this should be activated
because the application takes the
architecture of our device to put the
apk so depending of the kind of reading
we will have it will take one part of
the other so so using frida catch a yes
so configuration having time I mean
setup Frieda yes so I have the mega mega
five setup and it is patching things it
takes a little while and then after
patching things the question is do you
want to setup and install the apk in the
device
but but I okay it's next screen shows up
meaning the apk has been patched so you
need you want to install this apk in the
device yes and to avoid failure and then
and stops it again and then they launch
it and why is that because now the
question will be if I want to check
share after patching ap Caid of the
Egyptian it starts to think and wait
until it sees that everything has been
connected even with the objections and
the only thing to do is indicate Android
SSL pinning disable okay if you high
[Music]
Molly yummy thing annoys me
did you need to send that process so
long to process they say yes sorry
skipped the bird comment ow a temple
community a community reach oh this if
you have should change save changes but
I open project and I just need to tell
proceed in options
to listen it all interfaces
you are going to be
in fact right here test test and I go I
have escaped there is a pinion I have
everything activated and it detects oh
well but then it shows up here
maybe there isn't internet connection
right now
because indeed I am without internet
connection
I will not type in a Wi-Fi password in
case anybody start with the car already
I'm sorry
so if I get that connection
[Music]
to see the that device do you want to
emulate so I have to
I have a proxy and I can do that
five minutes rather than a day and a
half that auditors may need to generate
the environment back to the presentation
[Music]
both in the emulator
they're everything II think that's it
that's all for my talk
thank you very much chuckles questions
state law questions very shy room here
one Daniel middle of Ohio I think this
let me bring in people to is somebody
embarrassed about coming walking on the
way down to microphones to ask questions
okay thanks very much Michael