speaking of the use of infrastructures
in particular of domains why not take
charge of these methodologies of
analysis because it may be that there
are times that you have to do
investigations on domains and host infrastructures
or other both for thirty reasons so
well test analyze everything  what is
behind an
ip address domain name to our other or even
homes djibouti so if your company
or job principal told me
to drive data buying pepper
understand how extensive infrastructure
how much internet with  who are you going to look for
points to 3 points live have analyzed
the bumps infrastructure
one of the cases the application 1 of the 19
of the positive things in this when
from the playfulness in this case is that
contact is not made with infrastructure
so a good part of the tools
used on directly  so guide
the small structure there will be
no direct interactions as in our
part of the reservoirs of ozil la  second
thing is thought an analysis will be needed to be
carried out
which however is not related to the
tempo lieutenant so it is not the infrastructure as it is
now but perhaps as it was
45 years ago if we use the classic
bale noses methods of the subdomain in the
mx depuis we will only see that  that now
so that's why there are certain sites
that allow you to also make
historical analysis of these data and this is
extremely important if you want to make
a tv gens of analysis
and cognition that is not in the same moment
we are back in time
therefore  evident this presentation
divided into two parts the first part we
will use all the
free web based tools upon registration
the seco we will not go right on
the technical part seeing the classic
tools that we can use the
dot
anywhere in your
favorite solution most of these tools
do  some things that are in common
with others so we will see that there will be
d  and the data that is also repeated in the
other tools but then the tool that we
will use will have a little piece of
data more this is important the analysis
of the multiple sources that were at one
image are complete of the thing
let's start with the first then at the end there will be
also a little treat related to the heat
meniscus a thing that in collaboration
with doctor bertoldi
back and this must leave for later
then
let's start with the first site the
whole presentation what we start
from the public website
the first one i show you and respect
[Music]
by  selves closed like
mac starting from a bit a stream or something
else that can be seen in this case here I'm
using libero.it for the site they didn't
go available marx restaurant and between
we see the classic data of how
star headquarters 10 set the first time that  was
last seen in 2010 and let's
start in the evening what resolution
of the host the network the screen is part
of nothing new
the bus at the current time quin  of italy
online on the high there has been a good part of the
contacts the resistant technique which in
any case are hidden because now with
speeches the speakers or in any case with
privacy a
large part of us are caught and this is
one of the strengths that we will see
later from the historical basis
I hope we manage to be a little
student, however, I made a mistake,
the analysis of pickles is available here
without using tools or
dictionaries or denis bruteforce. We are
analyzing all the domains that are part
of it
.  'infrastructure, as you know,
I underline the beautiful analysis, it can be easy to
get the two on TV, maybe it's true, I try to
understand between the heels
what, in short, the name of any
subdomains, other times by touch,
dictionary, however, always launch
a request for our company here
instead we are analyzing everything
that has been collected by someone who city
same thing as our anch  and here we see that
there are all the
bmx spf and
server dns records
[Music]
among these is also therefore we see only
a part of
this again to imagine that
now you are making a
mental map and then maybe an ancient one can be
mapped directly on the screen
but let's imagine that we started
from an honor anyway that we are
gradually mapping our various not
the various bits and pieces of information that
can be super multi-spin rules
other than that they are giving us an overview
of what we are monitoring
a thing  nice as usual in the
reconnaissance phase in order so
considered in my opinion is the analysis of the
https certificates in the certificates
we can still see
the certificate issuance activity which many
times can still be an email to
a person's name and therefore here
starting to send  also in the analysis
not only of the services of the servers and
our in connected to this happens
this name but also of the  the people who
then if some on the other remove desert and
rose from the analysis of the certificates
here too we can see something
nice so here too they have
been collected by the bushes plus all
these certificates for the
fixed tps we have one
we will see that  however, below there is a part of
the host names
so in this case how much ravaldino
punto libro.it consumed height kg
whoever registered the picture registered
a series of other information that
perhaps a
normal dns analysis cannot find
and this is the first of  sky closes
the second
herbert suisse
then this here
goes off to the room alone starting
from a dindo numerous domains let's
go back to the other registrants such as
other names ial registered the
organizations and everything and therefore also
here let's understand
if this
register or something else is connected  to other
companies this case we are
analyzing italy per year other so
we will still see a large number of
names if you think  I like to instead create the
domain of a company that has uploaded us
on which we have to carry out an analysis a
survey we see less anyway
but even here we are able to map other
companies that perhaps through the same
register the same name of registrant
etc. have created  other luini and
therefore here too we
add little pieces to our
investigation
where an immigrant here instead begins to
go into the
investigation part which does not stop only at
today but also saw a little something that
had been recorded in the past
boiled monarch york therefore at inter
on the web it was successful  however done on
other data which may be of those
that he has seen of a now in the first case
the classic thing that happens to me and voices
first race since in
nico's bois you point all the
personal information and in the obfuscated state
almost managed to see it instead  let's
see that following the latest
update here we can keep the
name of the person who registered
domain and here  then also this year they
begin to identify no longer on the
systems
but also on the connected people
in particular and
the historical bulls for example I will give a
practical example during a
three-step competition it happened that
we had to investigate the name of these he
did not say here that the  press say a
disappeared for months anyway and that I
found this
site which is one of his activities in the past
problem this site the expired so
it had not been renewed and the other not to be
reviewed bulls there was cassi complex of
bought di mineo top
going on  site have instead always
managed to go back to years
before when the name
of the person was indicated but also the
housing service and this was an
important slice because it sanctioned the
building of his home via health care this is the
data which was this beautiful  a
few points as well as helping to
find again even if I write this
girl
let's go on like
this framework this here no hours
slide class  and you already know it is a
container of all the famous friends sites
divided by category that concern
a sinuous one that can go from the
analysis of metadata
terrorism on transport
therefore speech from this aerial speech
doctors to internal
telephone numbers social number of this one
good a starting piece when
maybe we have to do the investigation on a
theme
an area and he doesn't know yet maybe not
damon has explored we have to do
our tour boss to start
similar to the first one we saw
that it was from sky more if chances
this too  here in similar mirror
therefore it allows us to do the analysis of the
ssl certificates to pull together a
flood of data
and in addition to this some banner born site friends
which also includes the domain in the nile
of the person who maybe gets possession
of this site  another
extract practically from the chapters page
also here we can still see
part of the
part of the ssl
and ad certificates  straight
this is a test that we can do
if we use this yes
search string service irs certificates di
studi libro.it
we see that even of the various subdomains
dave the host of libero gives us the e-mail address
of the person who posted
this certificate and  that therefore
reassured city therefore they arrived
anyway earlier and prepare a
tall clean man here instead we are
also actually recovering
thousands of
people what do we need this for besides mapping the
whole group of people anyway one
of entities connected to this domain
you know better  therefore we can
use day camps to see if
this person is registered in other
sites if other data in other companies
etc. however we have identified won
the day
usually also identifying
the initiative of a month first person
from the site and here of the
company and therefore  not only
rizzi's classics out of use else
we can also understand the template for
creating the emails so no  n is full
name surname and first name and
initial surname or something else we need this thing
if we are leaving maybe we
need to identify if another
person has contact with this company
here is part of this company or something else
has not found it on the internet  on
linkedin, for example,
simply approving by
smtp, seeing if you need to answer
even 15 shores by saying some people's
name and surname exist in
our database and we know that this
person could be part of that
company or in any case contacts that this
thing here  even if we started on
Monday another person
after our went into detail but as
you can see I'm keen to show even part
of the nfp the location of services open
to everyone understand about yes
but I'm a little bit from now on the
survey quite serious  For
example,
Russi is another site that can give
you
the historic month of the domain in this case, so
let's go to libero.it and
click on chaos  at the bottom
we will see that here we have a series of
data that did not previously appear in
both of the sites that we have seen
not even in the other initial one where they
identified the person here and no one
buys data and moreover with the date on
which  we have been accused
before
same speech in the plis
we can do it other dns records
so going on dns history we see
that on the book all of us are see
now by nxp
rule come on all the rest of this
moment here instead there are all those
who have been analyzed by  how much
this summarized analyze them in
particular with all the dates on which
they were detected so even then
we can do an analysis of the back
I say and the infrastructure evolves it has
been modified other since for
example liberalized liso
a single record of the mix has begun  which then
gradually resumed 12 46 adding
everything
that can help us in the analysis of
subdomains and dns damster in this case
that this  a we will
always find data i see
same
dns server itx of records but we see
there is no couple more here the status of
fashion though pf indeed google
inspiration of google
this is a graphical representation
of beijing
the thing  beautiful of this site and that there
will be it will give us a created map of the
superstructure analyzed by
disposable dyes so there is an understanding to do
what we should do with the morning
that is our tool to understand
what is behind all this this
Monday  domain
even which
free internal sql server or other have come out
so maybe they would have
needed a little more in-
depth manual investigation to get there we
found ourselves already well mapped various relationships
or other
surely this event vaio
after this
other site that there can be  help to
understand the relationships with the host of
nas is having how the site was created
do you want to know if they are inside and in
particular the mods  bulls averse to the best
thing he is using as number of
s the first because it is multi life
this in which he simply analyzes
by analyzing the
source code of the pages with which cms
was made the two servers that responds
something is being used the crisis  of
fair as new band itself has a
task tracker other is using google
public safety of we know they are tv
of google services in dissent to
do the advertising part
and more
in particular by google
adsense
we will see why it will be important later
because also  these people were to
trace the relationship between this
company and any other companies that
maybe now we have not identified
with this general domain
al qaida thorium
a belt i was whatever you want to call
it we talked about it before it is exactly
what we feared with
lewis historical records and now what else
we see precisely on the weight so we go out to
see not so much the current status of the
site or domain  that maybe an
expired page has been renewed or something else
but its evolution over the
years
so for example maximus are
book pages for 14 June 2006 at 41 having
proposed 6 snapshots that day we
see them that apart from this
slightly old feeling we manage
however identify
ok
not so much as ravasin has once the
news and believed but even here
possibly some companies had
exposed themselves to grasp his
company name
the contacts he had the times that maybe
have changed have been removed or other
and this for a serene and  therefore it is a
very extensive mine of information
let's go back to the first speech google
analytics this because
analysis of this therefore allows you to
insert the trek with coutinho
or side and always identify
through open ended through second
which other sites are using
this free this tracking this which is
not  allows you to do in certain cases to
identify which web agency has you
made the site made the other sites
but in the case of a company maybe that
develops from another site it allows us
to identify
other companies social names that are
using the same analysis code
for google
google analytics and possibly if I
'm not mistaken in the preparations  sense here we see
more book for example used some
ends with 76
also used on three others
in this case it is the only tool that
replenishes the partial results not for a
fee however there may be some
female athletes reason is my my concern to
show you also  this technique of
samo reverse search any
the connected to this domain
let's go on
ok now let's move on to the part
of analysis using command line tools
the first and hamas now let's pass
these tools here we don't know how to give
ourselves more appropriate to a third party silvio  parts
as before from open sources but
actually have an impact on
an infrastructure, therefore usual speech
pn framework or if it
is a judge if we have mandates here we
cannot touch
infrastructure management this is not the
first the first choice to make
[Music]
however let's start with the nas which in
this case here to allow us to do
the analysis of different conditions
so now you dominate
passively here in this case so still use
the
side database to try to modify
without going directly to the
unitary infrastructure
so what is the possibility saab recommend so
command if but
here they are
we see that we found
through this too I am taken by
passive questioning therefore by
contacting directly lost but through
the names on the left you see
blister happy fan I agree other we are
questioning others similar the only
case however we see that we have already
found the series the subdomains in this
case here I think how much
book allowed registration  of
sites
are said to pedal goods user data
latera la tempes  ta of times gone by
we found another series so
sunday aired another another
still pine photo in this
case using joker
dot allows you to identify not
only under saying by means of other but
also of which ones that are present
all  'inside the page what is the
community of our being records
for example here but extracted directly
to 33 records
tixi and 34 domains of addresses
internal links therefore steps are moved
not only from the analysis of the records but
also of the links of this phase  from here
[Applause]
in particular this painter of the
hips how many other data can he
therefore find in which series
the new inspiration for interior instincts
all the various writings uses the
subdomains
and also any files that are
present for example also on the subject we will
take later  because we will see
how freely downloadable files found within a
domain
can be
extracted in bulk and used for
analysis
tls types track  I'm not ok but then
another one who does a series
of things also this allows
us to distract from what we
have seen before with my big
bags yes
external terms
this that even the loop that joins
in the default maps cannot be
also see the doors even if it is therefore not
ours
[Applause]
in our case the investigation we talk about
them however soon we believe
wars cloudflare another that makes us
the common extraction the
the tool we have seen previously
in which each
each file contains various data
which we see part of the records
I saw before
here we see box of
course here too I see
an instrument made a bit of what
the other was doing adds a little bit
we gave less between my idea is
that on the basis of the cases  that you have visible
already there to see then what is so finished
results in your best environment
for the speech instead
of identifying mail or other in this
case here also in this case via of
col  ester theater his name
can see that in this case
the Swiss are here he is not the arm
so he is looking for this case the
file or other available less on
search engines bing a goal
yandex
we believe that the result
[Music]
but immediately if the  things
the sisal games
the 8 ungrateful assists
interesting under
other faces of hosni on foot final
a post
the iphone has not returned
[Music]
and if they are present it also provides stars
a part of eni can be found
within the web pages
[Music  ]
yes
ok
going back instead to the tools that
cost to be performed from the
command line or even online by marking
concludes I can also from one of the most
complete you can also interface with
abidal who felt everything from a shoulder
[Music]
in this case we mean an analysis  already
made on spike from spider food that
the disability of the novel but yes you can
then redeem yourself so at least in this
case I'm using its shortcomings
of the hijacking is s  tata the team
closed at the same
and can see that he found the 4,723
tactics at the site of the end this
domain of which 3,800 are enemies
of that most are
online identity leader projects
certificates and web protocols
this here in my opinion if you want to
use a tool  that it's a
little bit of a framework that does many
things together
and 1 of those
helped me of the most common served
so yes
[Music]
knows because if we see
what david tried to
give us an indicator of the risk of
any Calabrian results and it is  also excellent
for finding the addresses
linked to this video we see that when
they arrived quite a few
and the nice thing and that already
in its search
forwards other divas present
the usernames it found on social networks that
are the same age
as this one  know
yes yes
no
and the first band of
babel also this here set a saab the
jump another let's see what he did
a little credit and science
victor ques  whether or not it is that they were
monitoring on which they had found
effective some references to libero.it
automobile by sealand they had your
book which are
part of this which I say on the left you
can see therefore it can also be useful
when we also have to understand
the  'exposition of grisi leader or
any data that has been linked
the last nice thing before going
on the collaboration with
bertogli
no
here are shops for the other not on the
premier side who are developing a
city to start a bar very similar to
skype
at the moment i still haven't found so
many plugins or transports negative to
render
to do it in person to render really
useful in my opinion because i structured
languages
a one of the tools to say
before we said these
tools can help us also identify the
files we need to find it
identify files pdf word documents
we have seen things here we have two
half funny tools from them exit
pool pays for it  the climate allows us to
screen all the files in these cases
so dfx and the doc protect by
the domain because then what we will do we
will use the exit pool then the various
filters or other to go extract the
metadata contained within these
do  here therefore the name of the creator of
the software for the
particular find the
machine documents must be pulled well in the house or even
the inter the gps coordinates for the
sepe design part we found exif data
and we see that in this case
I don't remember here I don't  'I did up to the book
punto.it but also on another domain
so much smaller limited however
let's get to the data you found
they are not bad so we are identifying
the software that was used
to create these documents
the various feel a possible
used numbers but above all
rino gandini has now been identified
any connected people
the simple identification of some sails and
here instead they are identifying the name  and
user of the pc from which these people
acted on these online files so they are
already beyond the question of infrastructures they
are sacred data they can help us to
triangulate or understand here too how
these sculptures are created in a garment of terni
which went online also  from here
in case if we want to understand it is
structured with the brief we can go
to the various link sites and see if these
usernames have associated mings and
then try maybe which one can
express not even a step that has already been
identified to try to enter or
understand here too  the tools that this
person is using on which peter that
perhaps by giving a user we have already
identified also what is the name of the
pressure
perhaps to carry out a phishing attack
knowing that
one of these software paintings that we are
the last of life on a body with
the  absent roma
believes and
we've gotten quite a bit of
information here as well that can
use our will like it
as a  we then have all this
information that we have identified
in the tools that you prefer relative
i.e. it is not that when fiscal mud
to download an asset all of it is
initiated in the transforms started in the middle
of the automatic private individuals started
outside a series of data for which you have
number of  information especially with
large data so
in my opinion it is my first it is one of the
methods to see certain information but
I prefer the part that the spinals as
you can see that the free one
can also be used commercial quaestor
that allows you to trace all the
connections  among the dunes of host people
in this case here and he saw me and is
connecting book.it love forced
below I put other records
made to our map without
automatisms but by mapping
graphically all
receive information that there are
significant results from the game  and already
president we have therefore made
an idea unmapped map  all of you and then
try to understand the interactions
however we will not leave software in terms of
mapping everything and then from going to
dozens of its various forms because in
my opinion at least for how
[Music]
last thing
in the case
[Music]
now
in particular field  the last if
we have to understand how to protect
the infrastructure can understand the risks that
this road is running out and that
of the oranges that can be done and
that south squatting or
domain registrations with numbers
words
political sounds similar to the domain we
are seeing that we are  analyzing
that they can then be used for
phishing attempts trying to make people
understand by
screening gunnar and making the person
who complains which arrives in any files
or other and of the site that we are the
one of the tuf apart but
job was changed and one on the  r4
to do the reconnaissance
part here too
there is a tool called that can
be seen in this case and
used two  ways one to understand
which domains that have these rules that
can be used in rigoni in
the shake park have already been registered and
therefore maybe block them within
the now I said sure we are
analyzing can actually in the case
of a foreign priest adro see what they
are  it is possible to generate that could
deceive the end user
the case of phishing or other in this
case I have used the summit to
see donations that have already been
registered
so you will see that
now he is calculating all his
presentations and events top
left
inaccurate
latina  34 seconds
these are the sites that inspired the
cookies because they have been
registered
libero.it libero pdl punto libro.it
to syria in things and by
re-entering none of these possible here
I can reveal the ending is and associative
of the attacks of the alleys
to this we arrive at the  little thing
he found alessandro bertoldi said to
say never had this serious sotis a
65 usually the stage stalking name scotti
that you use lett numbers that
look like however almost what to say a
difference if not for certain they say
whose name was some Russian characters and or
other the other policy which however have
been banned
in the long distraction at least from the
in the  european other comerio then
register cards only with that
policy or registers with the policy
now let's see normal
the only thing was found by him
a vulnerability a real bar
but an attack vector that office 365
if you eat an email from  a dns that is
registered from a forward domain
with capital letters he doesn't make a
lake of a new arcade of characters
when
these things arrive it means
thought the n is also mine how many times have
you not figured out which title
maybe the  re money in the duty between
writing something on the dot I'm going to
copy paste
aside coincidentally the domain of the
company in the company where I work lost the job
ndata fits very well to make these
attack texts
so what happens the domain
of the work company you
need security it's called person went
online
I registered the domain towards a given
point.it therefore where of assistance here
stf record registered
therefore from a hymn it results  as spam with
by nadia tomalino what else happens to me
but me forever as lost a capital letter
date is identical as you can see here he lost
a hand in this case a mail to first
is that for now we have not found an
artist or office 365 himself who could
identify this is all the jury of
children will be dino
and therefore nothing
the final gem linked to overcooked factors
has spent them
it seemed nice to present a repeat
the gimmick alessandro bertoldi in
you can yourself nor the sea is a
small thing but
as of sites also having the  time has
passed by anti spam
paralyzing
park analysis scott hicks focuses on the
classics uncle capital d  re associated along
that the boulders uppercase and lowercase characters
we actually didn't find in the
controls and designers so
difficult attack for the Florentine is a
criticized
[Applause]
via I finished I hope
this thing intrigued me
[Applause]