i'm alicia wandles i run the uh
partnership for countering influence
operations at the in carnegie endowment
for international peace and i'm going to
be sharing a little bit about what we've
learned and looking at this topic over
the last couple of years this is not
going though
so what i want to tell you is share some
of the things that we've been
researching um
first thing is what's the problem
democracies around the world have been
struggling to
address an immediate existential crisis
in coronavirus
um
and there would be a lovely slide here
if it goes yes what's the problem okay
where we're going i'm gonna start so
democracies have been struggling to
respond to coronavirus which is an
immediate existential crisis
how do we expect to actually address
climate change when we are having
problems with public decision making and
why is this the case
mostly because we have a polluted
information environment in which people
can manipulate things and public opinion
the information environment is the space
where humans and machines produce and
share information to make sense of the
world
information can include things like
ideas songs codes images and it moves
through the information environment
through different channels that includes
social media but also television radio
print websites and in person
and little is really known about how
that information environment actually
works as a system
now savvy actors as most of us know will
attempt to influence audiences and
outcomes through things like influence
operations
and this tends to happen in a cyclical
model with the ultimate aim of engaging
audiences to become participants in that
and spread the propaganda as well
enter the pcio so we are an
international multi-stakeholder
community of about 31 partners of
academics industry
government and other donors and our aim
is really to foster evidence-based
policy making to counter threats within
the information environment
since 2020 when we launched in january
we started out by conducting a bunch of
meta studies to really understand who
was doing what to counter influence
operations and how much did we really
understand about their effects and the
efficacy of impact of interventions to
them so this is very brief on what we
learned first defining the problem is
hard olga will appreciate this very much
a lot of definitions are used mostly and
consistently from field to field and
even in the same field sometimes
it's a big emerging field we identified
460 initiatives last year
majority are focusing on fact checking
or supporting journalism or some form of
research
and
okay
the experts do fortunately agree mostly
on next steps and that tends to come
down to sharing more information
regulating tech companies greater
transparency
and platforms are making more tweaks but
these tweaks to the platforms tend to be
focused on redirecting users to better
information or content labeling
governments have also seized the
opportunity with covid yes and i've got
five minutes uh to um to implement laws
to counter aspects of influence
operations so what are the gaps
first up we talk about a whole of
society solution but we don't really
have the glue bringing it together there
isn't an obvious field to speak of
there's no key leading institute that i
could recommend that somebody would go
and learn about the information
environment a lot of the convening is ad
hoc and if you look at the different
stakeholders who have to come together
it's difficult they don't trust each
other and they're not really talking
just to give some example in the
resources that are required we take an
8c step to change and that involves
building that community convening them
and finding answers and moving that
forward
one of the reasons we don't have this
clue is because operational funding is
lacking and the community tends to agree
with this a lot of it's project-based so
we get a lot more case studies than
anything else and there's a lack of
diversity in the field the majority of
it is in north america and europe
most of the proposals that come out
don't have the details for industry or
government to implement so this is also
problematic we don't really know what to
do
and little is known about the threat so
we don't know much about the effects of
influence operations mostly only in the
context of mass media very little is
known about the long-term effects using
digital media and we don't know much
about western populations we know even
less about the efficacy of interventions
eight percent of the interventions we
looked at that companies disclosed only
eight percent mentioned efficacy with no
further details of whether it worked or
not
um that leaves massive gaps in things
like what happens when we de-platform
people what happens when we do content
moderation why do we know so little
down comes down to a lack of
transparency reporting researchers just
don't know what research is available so
they don't even know what to ask for
we don't have data sharing rules so
nobody really knows who should have
access to what data for what purposes
and who gets to decide that and then on
top of that even if we had those things
worked out we don't have a mechanism for
longer term research to facilitate
knowing more about interventions that
would protect the independence of
researchers so what to do
a networked problem needs a networked
solution so every stakeholder really
needs to come together and do things
civil society should be convening to
come up with some of these answers to
determine who gets access to what data
and on what terms academia should come
together instead of being separate
centers work on having bigger
infrastructure to do
bigger testing like on interventions
government should be regulating
transparency reporting and data sharing
rules obviously civil society should be
giving them some answers there but they
should also look at funding something
like a cern for the information
environment something that is
multi-stakeholder industry can fund
donors can fund and researchers can go
and learn more
platforms don't have to wait for
governments they can start to do greater
transparency reporting today but they
should also be continuing to work with
researchers ideally on good faith
maintaining their independence and
finally donors can support that glue and
that multi-stakeholder need that we have
to have a whole of society solution
and with that i will not have any more
tech failures thank you