hello everybody so the talk of the day
will be about consent for third party
tracking which as you know might be
quite a pricing basis practice but the
thing with that topic is it also
encompasses both aspects of computer
sciences for the technical part of the
analysis and also um aspects of law so
the regulatory aspect of it and that's
the reason why we've teamed up together
with copyrighted men like many other
co-authors that are mentioned
to look at that issue from a very
interdisciplinary perspective
so
the team conhad is computer scientist
team and we're very happy to present
very briefly some of the uh
the outline of our research
so the first uh question that we were
wondering was just do you actually need
consent because people talk about
consent quite a lot and usually consent
is seen as really the golden standard
and that's something that you should
achieve uh when you're tracking and yeah
content is essentially you know
everywhere on the web right
well yeah exactly and that's that's part
of the solution and and i would agree
actually as a lawyer i would say consent
is probably the only viable option that
you have and the reason for that is um
yeah it's combined reason actually
because you have the deep privacy
directive that people might know about
already that says that if you want to
actually access or store data on the
user's device which you definitely do
when you are engaging in dirt by
tracking
essentially consent so there is there is
actually very little way around that
when you're actually accessing storing
data
and that's the reason why consent is
really one of the most important
option that you have when it comes to
tracking and what about what about gdpr
you know the massive privacy law in the
eu yeah gdpr is definitely relevant as
well um and gdpr also lays down rules
about the actual validity of the consent
and the actual lawfulness as well but
there would be a bit much for today's
talk so uh yeah if you're interested i
would really encourage you to read the
paper because we detailed that there uh
but the short answer is consent is
mandatory that's mostly due to uh the
privacy but what we're most interested
in was really the absence or uh the
presence and you'll tell us
that now of consense mechanism in apps
so whether there was any kind of
consensus mechanism implemented there
yeah yeah sure um so what we did to
learn about the presence of concept
mechanisms and apps is
uh
a
representative sample from the
google play store of 1 300 apps
and we opened every single one of these
apps
looked at whether these apps ask for
consent and at the same time we
monitored their network traffic and um
analyzed well where does data go to what
companies
and what we found is that while more
than 70 percent of apps
send data to
uh tracking companies and that's even
before any user interaction
um well even before clicking on the
accept button for instance you know you
just you just you know you just open it
and your data goes out there to facebook
google
many other companies right at the start
yes that's right and well less than 9.9
percent of apps actually ask users for
consent
so that's a huge discrepancy that's that
that's quite worrying you need
especially since we didn't look at the
quality of the consent as well so we
just look at whether there was any
type of affirmative action required by
the user of the app not even whether
they were sufficiently informed clicking
accept for instance so that's also
another another issue yeah well actually
only 3.5 percent of apps
allow users to refuse consent otherwise
apps would just quit so that you know
which is which is really worrying
actually and
app developers even supported in the in
their efforts in implementing consent
for instance or are they left or on
their own uh without without any kind of
guidance as to how to do it um yeah well
what we did is look at 13 um trackers
and their online guidance to just find
out well
why do
developers and so much numbers don't do
the right thing don't uh you know
fulfill the legal requirements and what
we found is that the
guidance provided by trackers was just
you know
[Music]
while very mixed
we found lots of outdated or broken
information as you can see from the
slide
with you know google facebook other
companies
um so overall just not a pleasant
experience of
trying to implement content
to tracking in apps
so wrapping up now um it doesn't look
very bright right because while consent
is actually necessary it's not really uh
done in practice there is no incentive
very few uh and if you're motivated to
actually implement any kind of consents
well the guidance that you'll find is
actually very scarce and not really
available or even accessible
so it's kind of a dark picture isn't it
well you know i think it's changing but
you know change is slow
you