hi my name is anastasia daniloba from
the university of bonn
me and my colleagues conducted a study
with freelance developers on password
storage to provide new insights into the
task design of developer security
studies
when investigating the security behavior
of software developers researchers often
ask their participants to write
code so to complete a programming task
however programming tasks require a
large amount of participants time and
this results in high costs
and small sample sizes
therefore we tested a new methodology
for security developer studies we
investigated how participants review
code snippets in an online study instead
of writing code
after that we compared our results
with a study on password storage where
developers needed to program
[Music]
the task on their own
in our study we asked freelance
developers to write
code reviews for password storage code
snippets we wanted to find out how
freelancers behave in an online studies
if they are asked to review code instead
of writing it
and prior work showed that developers
often tend to focus on functionality
first and security later similar to end
users by the way
therefore we prompted half of our
participants for security
that means that the prompted group was
specifically asked in the task
description to make sure that the
password is start securely
we recruited a total of 44 participants
from fiverr.com which is a freelance
platform
and each participants got one of three
java code snippets
each snippet contained password storage
methods which were not secure
and the methods were
plain text base 64 encoding and md5 all
insecure methods
so with the prompting and the code
snippets we had a total of six
conditions in our study
let's quickly discuss some of our main
results
the majority of our participants
reported to have reviewed the code
snippet manually
also our participants needed a median of
83 minutes to complete the whole survey
and our participants stated when they
looked for
functionality
logic
maintainability
performance
and error handling issues when we
reviewed our code snippet
so regarding the password storage issue
13 of 44
found the password storage issue and
commented it in their code review
only two of these 13 were prompted
and even though our sample was small
prompting for security had a significant
effect on mentioning the password
storage issue in the code review
our password related issues were
password validation
password encryption
sql and jar injection
or the complexity of password storage
finally our findings suggest
that code reviewing studies could be an
interesting approach for conducting
security developer styles
for the future work we recommend testing
a hybrid between code reviewing and a
code writing developer studies for
example a participant could receive
functional insecure code and be asked to
write the review
and if necessary to correct the issues
within the code this could combine the
advantages of both methodologies writing
and code review
however it might also increase the time
of solving the study tasks for the
participants again
so
although the freelancers in our study
indicated that they feel responsible for
security our results showed that they
did not focus on security now in their
code reviews if they are not prompted
and even
in a security critical task such as
password storage not all the freelancers
were aware of security
if you are interested
in finding out more about our work you
can find more details in our paper and
feel free to contact us
for further questions
thank you very much for your attention
you