hi everybody my name is dan bailey and
thanks for tuning in to our talk i have
no idea what they're trying to
accomplish enthusiastic and casual
signal users understanding of signal
pins
signal is an end-to-end encrypted
messaging tool that is privacy focused
minimizing data collection from its
users
offering not only secret messages but
also contacts and other metadata
when signal adds new features the goal
is to maintain this standard
signal traditionally relies heavily on
device local storage to reduce data
stored on signal servers
this introduces significant challenges
when transferring a signal account to a
new device
signal added a backup restore feature to
make this easier but that means storing
some data in their cloud obviously it
would be better to encrypt this data
somehow
additionally signal has relied on
sms-based authentication to verify
accounts but if they'd like to tighten
the security of this they can add
another authentication factor in order
to address these issues signal added the
signal pin
our research questions were as follows
are participants aware of how and why
in-app pins are used in signal
how effective are pin reminders in
assisting participants to remember pins
we won't be focusing on arcu2 very much
in today's talk so we can focus on
research question one and three
how do participants choose and compose a
pin for signal and does their
understanding of how these pins are used
affect that choice
pins add another layer of security to
your
signal account or so the prompt says
after some feedback from the community
the prompt expanded and added a few
sentences about what the pin is used for
this led naturally to our research
question are participants aware of how
and why pins are used in signal
under the covers the pin is used to
derive an encryption key for storing
encrypted backups to allow easier
transfer of accounts between devices
in addition the pin is also hashed as an
additional authentication value checked
during account registration for a given
phone number this prevents sim swapping
by adding an additional knowledge check
however an attacker with knowledge of
the pin can effectively both sim swap
and also decrypt contact information
metadata stored on signal servers
this larger context of signal pins can
be difficult for signal to effectively
describe and be understood by signals
users and this is what we explore in our
paper
we conducted a user study with 235 users
recruited from reddit signal community
forum prolific and snowballing the
survey reached many different signal
users with different backgrounds and
technical understandings
in order to gauge comprehension we asked
in your own words please explain how
pins are used by signal as this would
illustrate the effect of comprehension
on other security related behaviors
fifty six percent of the participants
were able to explain something about the
pin and we dubbed these enthusiasts
forty four percent were not and we
termed these casuals
enthusiasts tended to say something
about backup encryption contacts or
registration which as we've seen are
obviously all part of the signal pin
feature
by contrast casuals tended to say that
they just don't know what signal pin is
being used for with substantial numbers
of them thinking it had something to do
with unlocking the app or protecting
messages which it does not
to illustrate this disparity one of our
enthusiasts said it protects data like
settings and group membership and signal
contacts that will be stored on signal
servers using svr
nothing in the prompts that i just
showed you says anything at all about
signal servers or about svr that means
that this enthusiast was getting
additional information from supplemental
sources over and above what is in the
app in order to understand the signal
pin feature
by contrast our casual says i have no
idea what they're trying to accomplish
and explains why
from this we can see that for at least
some participants the in-app prompts are
not successful today in conveying the
right information
so our research question three how do
participants choose and compose a pin
for signal and does their understanding
of how these pins are used affect that
choice
so when you see the prompt on the screen
asking you to create your pin there are
two nudges to the user one is that the
pin must be at least four digits and
another is that the user can create an
alphanumeric pin
enthusiasts tend to pick long
alphanumeric passwords even though by
default the app is displaying the
numeric keypad
casuals on the other hand tend to just
pick a numeric pin using the keypad and
they don't tend to create alphanumeric
pins
so in conclusion we want to say that the
encryption and additional authentication
are only as good as the pin if we aim to
protect against snooping by signal we
need hard to guess pins
additionally if i can guess your pin and
do a sim swap i can recover your account
in order to extend these protections to
casuals we really need better
communication about the signal pin and
its purpose so we suggest calling it an
account recovery password because this
might encourage longer and better
passwords
in summary casuals tend to be confused
about the signal pin casuals really need
better communication and casuals need
more help in picking better pins my name
is dan bailey and thanks for coming to
our talk from supes twenty twenty one