hi everybody my name is khadija and
today i'll be representing the paper
replication effective media on the
mental models of technical users
users with technical background have a
much larger role to play in online
security than those who are
non-technical
all technical users have an influence
within their job on security and also
serve as informal advisors for
non-technical people amongst their
family friends and
for this reason it is important that
technical users have accurate mental
models of security
how computer systems work methods of
protection and risky behaviors
one of the ways these mental models
might be influenced is through media
cybersecurity depictions in media are
often fast-paced and dramatic with the
use of several tropes
and previous studies suggest that it
might influence fuser viewers mental
models
one such study is that of fulton that
else
titled the effect of entertainment media
on mental models of computer security
fulton study confirms that non-technical
end users often turn to fictional media
and its tropes to fill gaps in their
technical knowledge
given that the study did not control for
technical expertise we replicate it with
users who have a technical background
we had 23 participants in our study
during each study session participants
completed an interview followed by a
questionnaire that asked about general
demographics media consumption and
technical background
data was then was then analyzed by
inductive thematic analysis
and each transcript was analyzed by at
least two researchers
in the second half of the interview
participants viewed six video clips and
discussed what they found realistic and
unrealistic about each
the video clips chosen by fulton cover
common cyber security concepts like
hacking and password usage
we will focus on the portion of the
interview related to the video clips
we will go over some details of what
made us seem realistic or unrealistic
and focus on the aspects that overlap
with the original studies results
our new dif our new findings or
differences will be highlighted in
orange so results that match the
original study will be black
when faced with unplugging a computer to
stop a hack some of our participants
like those of the original study agreed
that this would be an efficient way to
do so
others however noted that this would be
ineffective when the network was
compromised
participants were also faced with a
scene in which users were alerted of the
hack due to a multitude of pop-ups on
the screen
while the original studies participants
found this accurate our technical
participants distinguished pop-ups to be
a feature of malware feeling that a
hacker would remember to prefer to
remain undetected instead
[Music]
most of our technical participants felt
encryption to be secure and hard to
break
this is in stark contrast to the
original study where the participants
felt encryption to be easily broken
when discussing intended targets of a
breach there is overlap between the
original studies participants and our
technical participants both believed
that specific important targets were
likely to be attacked
some of our participants did however
acknowledge that not everybody is an
intended target
both sets of participants agreed that
suspicious links should be treated with
caution however our technical
participants were particularly
unforgiving of victims of importance who
they believed should know better
similarly both sets also agreed that a
breach probably takes longer than just a
few seconds
our participants further elaborated that
this would only be possible with the
help of an insider or due to lack
security measures
most participants did however expect the
systems to be heavily defended
methods of assessing realism were mostly
consistent between the technical and
non-technical participants both using
their technical knowledge personal
experience context and cinematic cues to
do so
while our participants had a more
nuanced understanding of cyber security
concepts there were gaps in their mental
models even amongst those who
demonstrated reasonable knowledge
the paper provides numerous examples
our study results provide educators with
insight on the nuances and depth of
misconceptions held by technical users
in addition to the recommendations
offered by fulton at al we suggest the
development of a more holistic thorough
cyber security curriculum
we also suggest these misconceptions be
included in fact-checking websites and
emphasize using media as a tool to
increase awareness of cybersecurity
concepts
thank you so much for listening five
minutes is just a sample so please do
read the paper and feel free to send me
an email for follow-up questions