hi my name is dan hastings today we're
going to look at solitude which is an
open source privacy analysis tool you
can use solitude to inspect your
favorite mobile and web applications to
see where the data that you put into
these applications goes when you use the
apps
solitude has a couple different ways of
running and configuring which you can
look at on our github today we're just
going to take a look at a mobile web
application and see how
it's used with solitude
we're using the strava app there aren't
any known privacy issues with strava
we're just using strava because it's a
good example and it has lots of
different types of data that it collects
and uses within the app
so when you boot the app you can see in
the background the different types of
data that either comes searches that
come built in such as internal ip
addresses or
different types of data we've configured
to search for within solitude
such as that's dynamic that we've put in
as we use the app
so one example of that is we're going to
take a look at the profile here and
we're going to add in the city that this
user is from
already pre-configured this but while
you're using the app you can actually do
this in solitude and you can go into the
configuration settings here and add any
different types of data you want to
search for as use the app
so
in this case we're looking at the city
herndon which we've titled our hometown
we're going to close the settings and
then as we save the profile we can see
that the city heard on the hometown is
being sent to strava.com
we've given the permission of
our contacts
accessed strava access to our contacts
and so we created a fake contact which
we're going to then see if that contact
that fake contact in our contact list on
our phone is being sent anywhere and
solitude has found that it's being sent
to strava.com
lastly when we foreground the app
one of the built-in searches that comes
with solitude is looking for gps
coordinates
and we can see that the gps coordinates
are being shared with mapbox.com
and that's a quick tech demo on how
solitude works
if you have any questions if you want to
contribute you can check out our github
at github.com ncc groups solitude or you
can send that send an email and reach
out
thanks and i hope you enjoyed this tech
demo
you