hi i'm liaison kennedy i'm an assistant
professor from the university of
waterloo stratfor school of interaction
design and business this research is
done in collaboration with sonia chozon
from carleton university
in this paper we explore general privacy
perceptions and self-reported knowledge
of businesses data collection and usage
practices towards consumer data in
canada
we like to share the moral code we
identify that consumers rely on to
assess privacy violations based on four
core moral values
so for for those of you who might not be
familiar with the canadian legal
landscape our privacy law is known as
the personal information protection and
electronic documents act also known as
pipita
our participants describe their
understanding of their own privacy
rights and their interpretations of 10
privacy scenarios describing corporate
data privacy practices
that we adopted from real privacy cases
published online by the office of the
privacy commissioner of canada
this data is collected through a survey
with 300 canadian residents and
follow-up interviews with 32
participants using grounded theory
analysis
so i want you to picture this scenario
your cellular provider notifies you by
mail that the company intends to use
customers personal information for
secondary marketing purposes
now you could have your name removed for
the marketing list by contacting the
company otherwise it will assume your
consent
we could argue that company in the
scenario has implied consent complying
with pivotal
because they are using existing
customers information and by signing up
for the service customers give implied
consent to receive marketing material
however when we asked whether the
company acted appropriately under the
law our participant deemed this approach
to be within the boundary of the law but
highly unethical
for example one of our participants said
do i think that they acted appropriately
under the law i'm hard pressed to say
that's illegal i mean i could be wrong
on that one but i don't think that they
being particularly ethical
i don't like the optics of it but are
they being unlawful to my knowledge i
don't think it's unlawful
these responsive sets a stage for a
grounded theory where we propose that
participants understand em perspective
follows a moral code for data privacy
we base our model on the identified
codes and sub-codes and the
relationships between concepts
identified in the analysis
we refine the results into four core
moral values that consumers use to
navigate their information disclosure
these include trustworthy organization
transparency of the organization
feeling of control over personal
information and access to privacy
information
our participants moral codes suggest new
insights and expectations of privacy in
canada
based on these expectations we suggested
an improved consent model more control
and access and the developmental privacy
ethics assessment tools for helping
organizations align their privacy
practices and policies with consumers
moral expectations
however a key problem lies with how to
convince corporate organizations to take
these steps
our view is that this issue requires
increased governmental regulation and
oversight but studies such as this one
help to increase awareness among
stakeholders and provide
supporting evidence to those in position
to pose for change
in conclusion we suggest that
understanding users privacy ethics could
offer rich insights into how they engage
in online privacy decision making
if you're interested in learning more
please take a look at our paper and feel
free to reach out to me i'm a co-author
for any questions
thank you very much