[Music]
all right
hello and welcome to b-sides delaware
2020.
in true 2020 fashion we've had some
technical difficulties and we're getting
started a little bit late
but we are excited to have everybody
thank you all for coming this year thank
you all for coming the last 10 years
and uh thank you all to the speakers
staff
volunteers and past sponsors
since we don't have any official
sponsors this year um
without you we would not have continued
this long
and without all your creativity we
wouldn't be what we are today
so thank you i'm going to turn it over
to josh
thank you honey uh we started this
conference
many many many years ago in order to
build a really wonderful place for our
children to play at
and of course that means that this year
i dropped off our
kid at my in-laws because
it's not really a conference for kids
this year for little little tiny ones
for bigger kids yes
like like me uh this is an amazing
conference
every year we've shown that every year
we've done it better and better and
better and this year we're going virtual
so we're going to do better in a
different realm
and i want to thank all of you
volunteers staff
sponsors crew board people who we cry on
their shoulders
because we do um you're amazing
well without you this would not have
happened without uh zach and spam
and jason uh without uh patrick and his
incredibly dry sense of humor
uh terrifyingly dry sometimes and car
breakfast sandwiches
oh oh oh oh dude if
next year when we were back in person
please god uh
you must check out patrick's breakfast
sandwiches he makes the most disgusting
awesome concoctions known to mankind
we have speakers coming in from india we
have speakers coming in from all over
the world we've
participants from all over the world we
welcome you we hope you have a great
time
and enjoy everything that this venue has
to offer including the
uh the chance to have some some very
strange friends to make
and it's it's wonderful just to give you
a little idea of the demographics
without personally identifying anybody i
know that we have people from at least
three different time zones
so when you go outside at lunchtime
today
it may not be their lunch but
everybody can find something common
ground to talk about
and that's really exciting and we have a
wireless ctf
we have a spawn camp we have a dead
pixel sec has sponsored a chill out
space
uh we're gonna have some fun let's just
enjoy ourselves
2020 may have been a very very strange
year
uh but there's a light at the end of the
tunnel things are gonna get better i
promise
and to talk to you a little bit about
and risk and communication we have spam
as our keynote speaker
so we're going to clear out of here and
let spam get to work
you