helping with the world again they feel
cut off you know they're the same as you
ride the they have the same
I goals and aspirations and they have no
limitations in their brain they just
have limitations from their bodies
so all of them are extremely excited
very happy
they want to move again I mean that's
that the greatest goal is to move again
and we have to be very careful course
not to promise too much I C well
a of course our audiences intensely
interested in codes and cryptography
and your cracking one of the most
interesting codes in existence it in
your own coating the brain
I'm to talk a little bit about your
efforts in constructing the current
generation
a brain gay as you work on future
generations
%uh what is the frontier where did the
challenges lies in the matter
love on the scale of the problem
or other actually qualitative
differences as you begin incorporate new
features
well it is an immense problem you know
it was one of those things it was an
easy problem we will figure out how the
brain worked a long time ago its it's a
very complex problem
and we don't no up really what the
spiking signals
actually me they are the brains code we
r
developing as a kinda encyclopedia
no run by your honor what they do how
did they get involved in hearing or
seeing or moving
and we know that they have common
features but we just don't understand
the way that transformation occurs from
integrating
huge amount of information into some
kind of spike train we have
just beginnings have that understanding
well
brink it restores lost capabilities to
patients who
are suffering from it from a dysfunction
on
but as you've shown it's possible to
control more than artificial limbs
showed for instance the ability to
control a cursor I'm
can you envision a day when
on healthy patients have implants that
this sort
to supplement their functionality in the
world I don't know
implant that help people stick to their
diets or control devices for a third
armored and something along those lines
so
so there are many people who think about
these kinds of things that they they
want to be able to
extend their capabilities so the first
thing that this is a medical device
we're trying to develop something
or individuals with disabilities to make
their lives better
I the biggest barriers this does require
brain surgery
so we don't take that lightly it's
something that you know is always raises
a concern
I am where we will go with this and how
we will use it I think will require
serious debate serious discussion
but as I said I think the barrier will
always be
the surgical one that we we will not in
the Cavalier
implant able-bodied people I'm to
to have consider frivolous functions and
the other hand
we have many things already available
that her aides will have smartphones
that carry around
that are substitute for memory is again
telephone numbers and thing so we have
many many devices and so it would have
to be clear that
at some point we would outstrip all of
the available external technology to
ever even begin to think about
enhancing us by implanting something in
the brain well
have you in fact been approached by
industries or companies or government
agencies who
are hoping to exploit bring gate for
purposes other than the strictly medical
one
I wouldn't say exploit I think that that
I mentioned
this EG like signal that is available
from outside your head
so there's a lot of people interested in
whether how much control can you get
from that
and in fact it is a very noisy and very
hard to manage signal
and it's not very reliable so a there
are number people who would like to see
bat signal be as good as the one you get
from inside your head
it's not going to be I think if you
could want me to do is one place where
it's actually being
there's a great deal of interest in that
isn't it toy industry I you can get a
little bit absurd have are you
thinking are you more rows are you happy
or your little bit more relaxed you can
pick that signal up with a very simple
toy like device and sold for gamers
this'll be a fun toy
and that there are couple companies
already making devices I think we'll be
out this christmas
so could that that had something that
will be around
well or are there frivolous or dangerous
applications that
you're afraid if up seeing I
well the the use a brain gate requires
the participation
%uh the user so if you don't want it to
work
you it it just it won't do anything you
have to actually participate in use
so we're not too worried about that but
as I said there are
a the people are always trying to say
where will this go and I think they draw
from that this
science fiction movies as I said the
kinds interfaces that you see
in in Pickard for example that kinda
integration up the machine
in the human is really extremely far as
we just week at
tapping into the nervous system is very
difficult and taking singles out we
don't understand
so we have a extremely long time before
work where
a level like that so it may be a little
early for me to
asked this question but I'm as the
technology evolves
what person that the first ethical
quandaries that that you foresee
a in in terms of the patients a you know
one thing
these are not being ethical quandaries
it's about paying for them
they can be very expensive we have
models love
how to pay for expensive devices but how
do you decide who gets them
those kinds of things so if there's a a
person who doesn't have the means to pay
for it
and a person who does then who decides
who gets those
the technology well
let me ask her some questions that may
relate to the technology
as it will appear in 10 or 20 years
but on well actually let let me ask a
a question about what what you could do
today if you were given
ample enough resources so free if we
gave you $10 million dollar grant and
failing
liberal surgical access to patient up
could you build an infallible
lie-detector
meant that is that within the realm of
possibility no because we don't
understand the basis of lying
and those kinda was ok we're looking at
very simple functions like left and
right
you know their very simple kinds of
control so we can understand those
there there are few places in the brain
where we can get some insights into your
thought processes but they're really
only
a guess so we were so dim guessing and
sometimes were right but we always
whenever we tap into single neurons we
were all we always have some probability
being
wrong and we had nothing like what up
well i
you know we have no concept of what the
neural representation II would even look
like
so as I said it's hard enough to know
we're working at what is a neural
representation in the spotlight look
like what is a representation uva
wholeness sound a word we is beyond our
but currently I what is the neural
representation
a movement you heard little bit what
that sounds like but putting it all
together the assembly problem is the big
one
that's a huge barrier and where I think
what we need is this is where science
plays a big role where
for the first time listening into the
human brain thinking acting human brain
were actually able to
ask you know what's going on in there we
can actually asked the participants what
are you thinking about
and we can get some clue about what that
activity is
interestingly if you ask Matthew what is
he thinking about while he moves the
cursor around
who make up a different story every day
it's sort of the same kind of story
that if you said to a little kid who
gets up and brushes their teeth
what did your brain tell your arm to get
your toothbrush to go up to your mouth
they don't know it just works you know
and so pretty much that's what happens
they somehow think about moving
and the first to remove the events
unfold
and we've even found that people begin
to come up with to
crazy a strategy that it begins not to
work so well
they just have to let it flow naturally
on
one thing I would I would love to see
would be a
an external projection of dreams as it
were the movie
a movie rendering is that simply of the
books or is it conceivable
of them they will be able to do that so
see you are you are actually
bring up but an issue that something
that is looked at some it is known that
if you
do something I'll give you a sense of
how primitive our knowledge is
in rats if you have a rat run around the
room there's a little part of your brain
so deep buried on the inside
that unfold a map of space and what each
little neurons says
I'm here I'm in the next bite him in the
neck spot and when the red goes to sleep
and dreams
it replaced the sequence somewhere and
so you can actually predict
if the rat ran across the stage he ran
out the door any replayed it's been you
can actually reconstruct
that from from the from the activity
that they have in their sleep
but that's a long way from projecting at
your dreams of whatever you dream about
a out into the solving
cryptography or something you know yeah
onto a projection screen
might bring bring in the line of
questioning and perhaps a little closer
to reality
I'm sure many in the audience were
wondering about the application of this
technology to information security
I'm for example to think that brain
waves art
distinctive enough to identify
individuals to computing systems
could they ultimately serve as a
replacement for biometrics
fingerprints for instance yet that there
are
I think the the the variability is so
great and
it's also the reliability of detecting
the signals as you can just put your
head in a
you know dome and get in a simple
structure and get
get a get a good signal that is it's
very sensitive and exactly how you set
it up
so there's a lot of variability just
from that and then an individual's
arm I think it would take a pretty
sophisticated system
to see whether there is a a neural
signature but we do know already for
example there are some people that have
a potential in their brain
it's called a p0300 but it's a surprise
potential if I show you something
something pops up new on the screen
you have this little electrical
potential it pops up you can record it
even from the outside
but it's not that reliable and about 15
percent people don't even have it