my pleasure to introduce to you doctor
john donohue
a doctor donahue is the director the
brown Institute for brain science
on as you learn he's not a security
specialist
rather he studies the way that the brain
converts
saw into motion and develops tools and
techniques to
eight patients were suffering from
paralysis he was invited to speak
at the arse a conference simply because
his work is it so important
and so intriguing that it kills
naturally to technologies have all
stripes
i think is is also the type remarkable
work
that's likely to intersect with our own
industry in the future
in unexpected ways abducted on who is
going to give
a slide presentation and once he's
concluded the presentation
you know I will have an opportunity for
a short question-and-answer session
please join me in welcoming doctor john
donohue
skies
the
well thank everybody for coming in thank
you for the invitation
on I am a bit unusual for an audience
like this but I thought it would that
show you something about the %uh the
kind of work they were doing to
connect the brain to the Internet so
what you're looking at here
is a young man playing a video game it's
called he managed to hit the targets
that our treasure chest and avoid the
goblins this is something that is
I you know not so surprise except to say
maybe is not doing a great job except
this young man who's in his twenties
name is Matt Nagel is completely
paralyzed
he cannot move from the neck down due to
an injury in this
spinal cord and he's controlling that
person with his break
he has a tiny sensor implanted in his
what's called the motor cortex its where
his hand commands are generated they
come out
and they're being decoded on the outside
through a series of computers and those
brain signals are being used
I had to control the cursor by him
thinking about moving his hand
so this is a device for developing to
help people who are paralyzed
but it is it's been called the neural
interface system or brain computer
interface in all these other things we
just call it brain gate
and the device itself I'm gonna tell you
about
how this device works and I gotta give
you a little bit a background
love why that device could actually be
developed how could we possibly go from
the brain to the outside world
I with with the cable basically in a few
computers
and then I'm gonna try to give you some
perspective on how all of this
might fit into our world in the future
so
one might ask what why would you want
that even build such a thing and that
one reason is that
there are a large number of diseases
that lead to the condition of paralysis
in which
people's brains are able to think
they're
cognitively intact but the message is
from the movement areas
to the outside world can't beacon are
connected their broken off
that common one that made you probably
know spinal cord injury
and what spinal cord injury does it
basically interrupts the cable from the
brain
to the outside to the spinal cord and by
interrupting at the commands can't get
out
so the there are millions of people who
are paralyzed from this bear
variety of diseases that I've listed
here and I won't go through some other
were just
jammers too many view they all share in
common the
up the feature that the brain functions
in the body does not
so we need a way to get from the brain
to the outside world
and this is the system that we developed
it is %uh this is the brain gate
it consistent this tiny sensor I its
a that the little black sensor with the
little hairs coming out of it
is there something the size of a baby
aspirin four by four millimeters
it has 100 here the electrodes coming
out a bit that are sensors that are put
into the brain
is put into this was called arm area of
the brain
currently in its sorta crude pilot for
men has a plug on the head were all
those signals come out
the crackling noise you hear is signals
from one of them and I'll tell you more
about those in a minute
and the the signal is then processed
from front through a cable that goes
through cable through an amplifier
through a cart full of computers and get
converted into basically what a mouse
control
so that's the system that we call brain
gate that we develop it was actually
develop
up based on a number of years %uh work
handle in my laboratory in other
people's laboratories to show that
these kinds of things would actually
work in humans up but we didn't have the
testing in humans
im so here here's just a concept diagram
of how we thought through the problem in
lead
from something that was that an idea and
had its basis in
in basic science research but had to
really be tested in humans
so in this condition the brain is
disconnected from action
I and we're trying to build a bridge
from the brain to the outside world
the brain signals could be used to
control computers
I'm that is directly plugging the brain
into the internet through computer
potentially
to assistive technologies that is
anything that can help people
to robots say assist the robot that
could help an individual who is
paralyzed
to artificial limbs that is people who
have lost their limit you could make an
artificial limb and then connect the
brain back up to that women
and move it or even back to the muscles
themselves so you could
reanimate the muscles but the brain
reconnected back to the muscles and and
allow movement to happen again
so most people say how the heck could
you possibly do that and it is a big
and complex problem and these are some
of the big questions we had to answer
what what area of the brain
would you even selected get signals say
to move your arm which is the kind of
signals that we targeted
and what what are the signals you'd even
look for what are the brain signals that
give rise to commands what are they like
what's the sensor you would use
are you just saw the center and I'll
show you a little bit more about it
about
what is that what could you use to pick
up his brain signals
and for possibly leave them there for
say 70
eighty years how did you code so it fits
in with the theme at this conference
we don't have a reserve a stone in
neuroscience we have to figure out what
the brains
coding scheme is and try to understand
it and finally what technologies and I
just showed you the kind of technologies
we might connect to
so I just what we're going to do now is
have a little Nora 101
and just give some background
information I think that will %uh have
some interesting
parallels to the the to computing
internet and
inmate generate some interest from
those if you're interested in security
up but also I think it's a
fascinating to get some overview of how
the brain works a little help you
understand
how in fact weekend build brain gate
build it a connection between the brain
and the outside world
so the blue thing there's the brain the
outside is the cerebral cortex
I it's the part we think is the
intelligent part of the nervous system
world the smart stuff goes on it's
covered by this rind
business is so if you slice through it
you can see that sorta grayish looking
stuff
there's a i a sheet about the size of a
large pizza but it's all crumpled up
inside your head so it fits
at about two millimeters thick robust
because an orange peel and basically all
the computing for your
thinking and speaking in hearing is all
going on in that
there about 10 billion neurons and
neurons are
brain cells their spidery things they
have perfect things you can see in that
wonder on
are recipient parts have the neuron they
receive inputs
they have about 5,000 have them there
most them are very weak
connections that converge from large
numbers of other neurons
and they emit signals they sum up the
signals and they fire these
electrical spikes I which are actually
called spikes
and they're about a thousand the bus ok
second long impulse and that's the
communications system that neurons
neurons are very sophisticated
computational device is the take
a lot and we can put in convert them
into pulses I'm
and those connections that they have
with other neurons are called synapses
just
was shown there so there's a
interesting parallel between the brain
and and other real-world phenomena
including the Internet
so those of you who know about small
world nets are those about other kinds
of admiral networks
the brain is I'm on the left there and
on the right is actually a
a the Internet and its connection
a connection diagram above it internet
and personal looks a little bit like a
brain but its the brain is actually
wired like this
and that the parallel is the brain is
wired with lots of local connections and
a few
largely just a few long-distance
connections and by that basically
everything is connected everything else
but functions tend to be clustered in
areas
so if you're trying to find an area I
say for
connecting to something that will
control arm movement we know
it's basically from a hundred years have
nor science that I
functions are localized so in the back
of your head which is to the right there
is seeing just above your year there's
an area for hearing
and there's a strip that goes from the
top of your head out to your job own
about half an inch wide called the motor
cortex it's a stripper that
cortex and all in your movements are
generated
or funneled through that area and its
subdivided so that the middle third
controls your arm
and in fact now is good for you I'm just
control the army the other side of your
body
so we know where to go in the brain
that's the area that we would target
that's the place the generates
commands now what it what are the
signals
and brain signals are extraordinarily
complex there are basically two kinds
once called field potentials in one is
called spike so I like a computer which
just has
basically you know a diode that goes up
and down zeros and ones
the the inputs the cells the broad
currents flowing around in your brain is
one kind of signal
which is this FPR feel potential and
you can see one running across the
screen there and it it is the most
familiar example is the EGFP electrical
potentials you can record on the outside
your head
it's due to all the currents flowing
through all the neurons in your brain so
it's sort of a smeared function