you in a coma are you alive those kinds
of things
but the other signal below is
are the spiking that's the spy cam one
nor on their their impulses
and that is this the code that computers
that
sorry the composed that neurons use to
communicate to each other that is the
language of the brain
and it's our job to crack that code
understand what is that syriza
pollsters mean in terms it's a 12 so
you're listening this is what North
physiologist do all day long they listen
to those crackles and try to figure out
what they mean
I so you actually listening into the
brain I
and the problem with the signals which
are the information-rich signals on the
on the brain if you want to get access
to them the only way to get to them
is to put a microelectrode in the brain
microelectrode is basically a very
the in needle I you can see one next to
a hair here
and it's a it's introduced into the
brain and basically the tip of the
electrode is a sensor
and it has to be noted that very close
to the cell the sellers like a broadcast
power and
for short-distance it generates these
impulses and the problem we have is not
only do we have to put electrodes in the
brain but we have to have a lot of them
because we don't want to listen to sort
one conversation we have to listen to as
many as we can get
and the way we do that now is we
we basically invented this 100
microelectrode array
as they said it's about the size of a
baby aspirin and it is implanted just
into the surface and the cortex that
peel on the outside
and as a as you can see there the little
plug on the surface that goes through
the skin and brings that signal to the
outside
and this is the device that we developed
in my laboratory
I just to give you a sense have the the
scale it's actually quite tiny that's a
penny so barely covers Lincoln on the
any
now the other big problem is knowing
a how to make sense and the signals you
heard that was actually a movement
related signal you would never guess it
just sounds like a crackle
basically what happens is you can see
here
I trade have many neurons spikes coming
out to those little tick marks or spikes
and basically at its maximum flow rate I
if you're listening to a hundred neurons
are recording a hundred neurons it's
like getting a hundred
bit I information stream at one killer
hurts
that's about as fast as it goes it's not
real fast but there's a lot of
information there
in our job in decoding is trying to
relate
something like a kinematic Vale variable
like the velocity
to a the spiking and we use techniques
like linear regression or other more
complex techniques to map
what is the relationship between the
spiking we see and something going on in
the outside world
the rather than spend half an hour
explaining the math I thought I would
try to give you just some intuition at
the approach we take
so you can imagine you had one of these
microelectrodes in my brain in my
arm area motor cortex and we're
recording while I made
small movement say to the left or to the
right my arm
and every time I moved to the left that
nor on May 7 at the spikes
every time I move to the right it made
to the naked have a decoding scheme 7
means left to means right
I went behind stage and all you heard
with the pulses if you heard seven you
would guess I had just moved to the left
so that's fundamentally the way we we
look at this code we count the number
spikes in a small time interval
usually about 50 milliseconds the
problem is is that the code is not that
reliable
the number of spikes every time I move
say a little bit to the left
is not the same sometimes it's fewer
sometimes it's more
so what we have to do is average across
many neurons and by averaging that count
over many neurons in these behind in we
actually do get a very good
estimate where you're moving your hand
in space so
with all that background knowledge some
some knowing where to go to get
arm signals knowing what that signals
look like and
what kind of information they had all
done from basic science
we we then I applied to the FDA and got
permission to test
in a a small group of people the
feasibility of
then using the signals to actually
produce movement in
so there have been five people implanted
the two you see they're called s1 and s3
actually Matt Nagel and Cathy Hutchinson
Kathy and Matt I'll call them
and if I want talk II won't show
as many videos as I'd like to show but
if you wanna see more Kathy she was on
sixty minutes
I where they told her whole story and
and are you so they bring a technology
all other people with implanted are all
paralyze the cat with their arms and
legs
it's a seriously debilitating condition
where you rely on
others completely for anything you do
so what are the big issues for us was
you know
could what's going on in the brain after
its been disconnected from the world for
years in every case our patients were to
an in cathy's case
nine years since they had actually moved
a limb we were concerned that the brain
would be shut down
or even if they thought about moving
nothing would really happen
so what I'm going to do is let you
listen in on Kathy's brain
and you going is that the pink thing you
see there is one of those spikes spread
out in time so this is what it looks
like but it's only 1.6 mil a second in
time
or if you look slightly to the left to
be to see a lot of these pink spikes
going by
I'm and those are the that once cells
I signal going out basically just listen
to it you can hear
the activity and what you'll hear
technician do is ask her to imagine that
she's
opening your hand closing your hand or
relaxing
and what you can hear is you'll hear her
thinking about moving and those
clicking the spiking noise you hear is
listening to human thought about
movement
and you'll hear that when he says open
your hand it'll be very active in which
he closer and it'll be almost silent
act
talking in your hand cadillacs
closer and relax
open hand kill you you're listening
21 brain cell and its signal about
movement and I think actually it just by
listening to the sound you can tell
there's information there
this is what we capitalized on and we
were very excited because we knew the
brain remained active even though it was
disconnected and
and cut off from the outside world so
week we could build
are using all the neurons in all the
information from different neurons we
could
up build a decoder and here you go to
see Matthew nari
his own early use up the system so here
you can see him with the technician
I'm he's got the connector on his head
is sitting in his wheelchair
and he's going to do two things that
he's going to narrate himself the first
thing is going to do is open and email
program by
just drag your cursor over an envelope
it's a real email program is one we made
up
and he's gonna try to draw the world's
first neural 0 is gonna draw circle
with this just using his mind so you get
to see him do that
you can see him there there's a
ventilator to
is a little bit quiet because the
ventilator is he has them support to
brief
okay without panic that up way like
depressed all
my email okay p
first-line you know the first class its
graduation June 21
I get sec
email okay says hi
toss
great half-naked back to the by Haaretz
I the one that
excellent a trials in a draw circle
of for this is just a little inkwell and
he tries
three times and you can see him get
better as he practices for yeah
right player
up
here high in the air is at hand sir
like to avoid okay the dow we try to get
a few minutes later
extra now just try I we just witnessed
the world's first
up drawing a minnow using only your
brain
so we were interested you know given
these that then that was an early side
a being able to control a cursor but
with that some improvements we were
asking
well what can we demonstrate that you
can actually do that would be a use for
these individuals
so so here you see Kathy doing two
things with the computer interface
on the left she's using a kind of
smartphone by typing
where she's pointing and clicking at
letters and I asked her what she thought
in the technology and she's typing out I
love it
I and secondly on the on the right you
can see her using just basically what is
a
TV remote control but she's now using
just thoughts to guide the cursor to the
TV channel or the volume and and be able
to select what she wants to do with the
TV
in addition we wanted to know
is it feasible for people to control
real-world objects these people really
want to be able to interact with the
world
so we asked met with that Matthew up
with this prosthetic hand
it's a motorized and it opens and closes
usually driven by some switcher some
muscle
here he is fucked up to to from his
brain directly to the handle is the
first thing that he controlled in years
directly with his with any output and
here's that you can see his reaction
know you can listen to it
once we start this video 0 hold
should all and let's set will run it
again because it usually get
but I think it shows the impact so can
you back up in
and do it again there 0
school share 0
so though obviously it important