a so we have to start thinking about you
know innovation
innovation in both disruption
and Prevention so one of the things we
did Microsoft as we look at a particular
botnet
that was responsible for a lotta
nefarious activities
this but that was the top 10 botnet in
39 countries
hotmail along blocked over $650 million
connections from infected computers
the Malicious Software Removal Tool that
we run is part of what
automatic update cleaned almost 200,000
infected machines so knowing that we had
this problem
it was an opportunity to innovate about
both disruption
and to start thinking about innovating
about prevention
so had we think about disruption
well one of the things we did as we turn
to the courts
as I said we always have to align not
just social political economic an IT
forces
but we need to use social mechanisms and
political mechanisms to reinforce values
if you think this behavior is wrong in
society should do something about it in
a structured way
so one of the things we did is we use
the court process
we went did a court filing it was
supported by industry partners in
academia
we got temporary orders to sever the
domains we notified the people to
domains were affected
we waited 14 days and then we could
terminate
basically the head up the botnet now
it's an interesting idea as something
that we will continue to pursue is
appropriate
I don't mean to suggest this is a remedy
for the botnet problem medicine
the point is that just like we do
defense in depth in it.
we have to do defense in-depth in
response
we have to think about technical
solutions such as cleaning machines
and we need to think about social
solutions like using the court in
getting
people involved so to me of course this
was an interesting
way to proceed but Utah so
raises an obvious question this is
reactive
what do we do proactively to change the
problem so we've started to think about
this
I actually think that the health care
model
particularly related to the World Health
Organization and the Center for Disease
Control
in other countries have similar
organizations and authorities
might be an interesting way to think
about the problem with medical diseases
we basically educate people
and sometimes if you fly into certain
countries else can you for your
temperature you get off the plane
if you seem to be infected your
quarantined
and you're treated the question is why
don't we do this
for consumers why don't we think about
access providers who are doing
Inspection and Quarantine
and cleaning machines prior to access to
the Internet
now in the region has become so
important
is if you look back at the end ten trust
paper which was actually written a
couple years ago there's a line
in it it says who's the CIO for the
public sector
the reason government in enterprises can
manage the botnet
risk is because they have protect
professional IT staff this is their job
they manage this risk is much more
complicated in the consumer space
me when the things I love to do is just
look at my own life and when things I've
done is
the I have three children and I have my
mother whose fortunately still healthy
as someone at the sandwich generation
and that the mom
and I've got the kids and every now and
then I Jux the post my four-and-a-half
year old
with my eighty-year-old mother in part
because
baby he is so much like it just the
stands me but let me tell you one way
they also behave like my 4 1/2 year old
has learned to navigate without my house
as just great to watch enough to get to
the house
up pops a security dialogue he can read
he doesn't understand it he clicks okay
then I go to my mom she's got a PhD in
education
she gets the dialog pops she can read
she doesn't understand that and she
clicks okay okay
week we can't do it that way anymore
the attacks are happening at light speed
we have to respond lights be so we
should think about Inspection and
Quarantine other some obvious questions
why should we be doing this to people
will people accepted socially and
politically
well we've done it was smoking people
use to smoke and we said look you're
gonna kill yourself but if you wanna die
go ahead causing cost to the health care
system
will eat those costs go ahead and tell
yourself then
of course the EPA comes out a second
hand smoke certainly smoking is banned
everywhere you have a right to inspect
and give yourself illness you don't have
the right to infect your neighbor
well the commuters are the same way we
told people run anti-virus
catch back up your data but if you don't
do that stuff and you lose all your
stuff that's a risk you can accept
but today you're not a just accepting it
for yourself
you contaminating everyone around you
right and we do this another is like
vaccinations if you have kids to go to
public schools they get vaccinated or
they don't
the whole we do those and enforce
and then there's the question of who
will pay for that well maybe markets
will make it work but if not
there are other models to use taxes for
those who use the internet we pay a fee
to put phone service in rural areas we
pay a tax on our
airline ticket for security you can say
it's a public safety issue and do it
with general taxation
and there's also a good role for
government here if access providers are
gonna scan for content what content
can they scan for if you want to protect
networks in yet the limit the activity
to network protecting active
not worry about copyrighted material
speech other kinds of things
but we do have to innovate and this
example gives you
another reason to constantly think about
alignment how would you get social
acceptance
political acceptance find the right
economic model
and have I T which does still of course
things like that happen act today
how to use it. to achieve these
objectives
so we have some interesting
opportunities here now let me talk about
the cloud because the cloud is the big
thing for sure let me
make sure we're talking about the same
thing you know the National Institute of
Standards and Technology has done a
great deal
and talking about cloud definitions
there's infrastructure we just rent the
hardware
there's the platform when you get the
operating system Microsoft has ensured
that on the platform
and then there's the total outsource
model infrastructure
operating platform and applications
right
and they'll be different kinds of class
of the public clouds private clouds
hybrid clouds
to be clear these models are not
completely new
people have outsourced in the past and
put their data with third parties
consumers are used to things like
Hotmail which is a Software as a Service
but what is different about this class
what makes this different
is a couple that tribute still be some
new platforms like the operating system
for the clout that dynamically allocate
resources
there will be global elasticity you'll
be able to participate in various places
all over the world
on the fly again might not even know
where your data is
and there's Co tenancy I talked about
you know Coke and Pepsi would wanna
share the same hardware but there will
be co tenants in the cloud
and as a result that that create a bunch
implications for those of us in the
security and
privacy space the first has to do with
the shifting shared accountabilities
so in the box product well we develop a
product we give it to you and then you
go out
and you configured and patches and do
that management work
depending on which cloud model you use
you take on
more or less responsibility in the cloud
and they'll be challenges for compliance
because the fact that to date is in the
compliance
in the cloud doesn't mean you don't have
compliance obligations
moving all the data together in the
cloud can create which targets
for bad guys to go after and they'll be
the question is how you do shared
investigations I'll talk more about this
in a minute
to be a lotta information aggregation in
the cloud
and questions about what the cloud
provider can do with that information
and they'll be questions about
jurisdiction which I'll talk about to
so if we think about the cloud
implications that I can start to think
about the end and trust vision
and how it impacted by the class first
is more important than ever that we do
the fundamentals right and that your
cloud provider do the fundamentals right
because you're increasingly gonna be
relying on that third party if you're
using a platform was that platform
developed with the security development
life cycle on Mon
can you you know ensure that the cloud
providers using the same way good that
you would use
is one of the things to think about we
have to think about privacy centric
models
so how does the cloud provider what
rights if any do they reserve to use
your data
and how are they going to respond to
threats in the class
the trusted stack becomes important as I
talked about
we need to route to trust in hardware
but it's gonna be virtualization
that is the key to keeping the tenant
separate
so how we gonna make sure those
virtualize compartments a secure
as we move up the stack from the
hardware audit is going to increase in
importance as we try and figure out what
happened to the data
and how we gonna do forensics
investigations and the clap
you know not long ago there was a
hospital that
not contacted by a bad guy who said they
had stolen data and if they want
paid money they would release the data
and they shared some of that data to
show that was really a compromise
suppose that data had been in the clout
the hospital cause a cloud provider and
says we think you lost a day