they're doing it and but but but you see
this is the problem of course with
Einstein 2 and Einstein 3 another
you know government initiated network
detection methods
you know to their the you know
recognition I'm in Sparta their mission
that
that's part about the NSA i suppose to
do they're supposed to a
locate that content but if you put them
in the security business and they're
looking for malware
you cannot put on Thursday things to the
businesssave looking
at things in the United States gonna
throw line
go find somebody other than that I say
we have to move the Burton
to the ISP's and other places you know I
think or else
but there's another issue here which is
what what can government do we're all
afraid of government regulation and
government in your privacy
what can government do to help solve
this problem that doesn't raise these
these these hairy issue and one thing
you can do
is relate to other governments right now
cyber crime pays
let's just be upfront about it
cybercrime is not script kiddies anymore
it's very sophisticated international
gangs that work
with the connivance support the
government Russia and the government of
China
and we talked to russia and China about
a lot of things
we don't ever make this a big issue and
we've never tried
to structure an international solution
getting other countries involved as
we've done on money laundering and so
many other things
we've never done it on cybersecurity and
why is that will because I think people
in the government don't understand this
issue
to a very large no I don't think that's
part for I think I'll
the big problem has been attribution hi
something emanates from a particular
country now we have the attack since
Tony we take action Georgia
I let's assume first two more with the
server which appears to be
genesis in fact hi not just in emission
third party it's been hijacked even show
you have to ask a question
if the government for security the
government turned a blind eye to witness
the government simply
incapable of dealing with it is when
it's hard to prove is a way of solving
witches have an international treaty
that put an obligation on every country
to police its own cyberspace and so you
don't care whether was the government
or whether it was some hacker club that
the KGB
refs be didn't know about it so they
could be such a thing you know we have
to get over our government
hang up on having arms control in
cyberspace we've got fiber Warner
alright because this fiber command with
weapons a four-star general
and we have no strategy that anybody
knows about and we have no arms control
well we there is no Arkham cyber warfare
yet there is no
military college teaching this kinda
stuff nonetheless
are we carrying out cyber offense
against other countries first-year
say more no look if you think that the
the story was true that the
China or somebody has lace the US
electric power grid with logic bombs
me I think you have to be naive to
assume that we haven't done that
China yeah and what's ordered situation
is that with backup
what if that Wall Street Journal story
and said plastic explosives were found
on the high tension
distribution waters throughout the
United States and we have reason to
believe that the people who put them
there were Chinese agents
no we wouldn't the congress would go
crazy
they wouldn't serve Chinese food in the
cafeteria you know all
Chris all the usual going to stop
freedom charmaine freedom tournament
with her
the but you make it a larger
bomb and nobody notices but I i get i
think im you know
party the problem here is it is the
difficulty of proving
wear something competition we said that
every country is responsible
for policing with its within its own
borders and then it turns out someone
from another country has hijacked
computers in our own country who
and then the question becomes Marco
relate to this
sure the US government has now an
obligation to shut that down but but wat
tam was going to say that violates my
for him and privacy right
so other countries are gonna turn to us
and say well you got an obligation to
shut this down
we don't care but the fourth amendment
do it that's what makes this a very
very well you know I it's not that hard
but let our company let me just come
back to richard's point cuz I don't
think it's true
that at this point the United States is
ignoring
the international dimension in fact I
think secretary Clinton's recent speech
on internet freedom was almost a direct
response
to the Chinese hacking incident
involving Google now she had to walk
a careful line there in part because of
the attribution problem
nephew not absolutely certain about what
you can say at least in public
you're going to be cautious but the way
in which she elevated the issue and if
you read the speech
I think it's fairly clear that she was
saying to the Chinese government listen
we're aware of this
or not going to ignore so that pieces
and have a cheese on willing to engage
in cyber arms control well that that may
be the next step but let's also say that
the united states you know through the
Council of Europe
pushed very aggressively to get support
for the cybercrime convention over the
last
you know five years in russia didn't
sign it and there's no sanction
yes but your criticism was that the
United States government wasn't doing
enough to read article
arms control and I think we're beginning
to see the government
take those steps up from the privacy
perspective look we don't have a big
problem with promoting sensible policies
and people working together we're gonna
have concerns at the point that someone
comes along and says
now we want user authentication and now
we want some other
you know technique that's gonna you know
catch everybody's a
online activity even if you don't like
to eat welcome back to the fourth
amendment
so the attack the russian attack on
Georgia
in part emanated from a server in
Brooklyn
and once you can establish that
you can go toward the you their service
level agreements are also two ways
you can go in and stop there's no the
fourth amendment
variability do that rapidly and the
Billy
you that in every instance is going to
be a potential ops
I'm not disagreeing by the way I think
that there should be I think there is a
commonality
interest to some degree for example
every country that use the global
financial system
i has its stake maintaining the
integrity that system
something that corrupted trust in the
financial system globally would affect
Chinese and the Russians at in the same
way that affects the US
so I think it your art areas where there
is room for this kind have
incremental movement second thing I
think we need to do is
and this is part of a cybersecurity
initiative which we in ordinary a couple
years ago I think I spoke to this group
about it
a couple years ago and now finally it's
been at least
summaries been declassified a couple
days ago party that is to you
really think through the strategy in the
21st century for cyber
attacks that as we thought through the
Cold War and
and nuclear deterrence and that means
doing almost another project solarium
when you bring together people
who think through what are the
architectural problems legal problems
diplomatic problems I do we need a clear
policy
retaliation you need to say what their
red lines or
what we do in this case you're in that
case hard issues
we may disagree but I we've got to start
talking about this and we have not
really gotten very far and
definitely going to be a public
discussion I'm because right now it's
all classified top secret
and the public doesn't know about it
media doesn't know about that the
congress doesn't know about it
and that's a recipe for making mistakes
as grueling as all that might be
we have precedent ways of handling it
you know we had attribution problems
with a brush fire wars in assassinations
we took care of that
we had the various ways oppressing
people to change your
with mutually assured destruction and I
assume there some cyber version
that I'm not sure there is but okay
maybe there's a version that but there's
a whole other half for the problem
away from great powers and their gangs
a North Korea tax you all what you gonna
do go after the 10k pros they have in
that country
you know what it was that will you
counter that small states that harbor
criminals so exactly so pardon the
the reason deterrence doesn't work in
cyberspace
is attribution number one but number two
you could be attacked by a north korea
we know north Korea has engaged in
cyberattacks
on South Korea and on the United States
on the last fourth of July
there was a major North Korean attack on
systems in the United States
they launch those attacks from China
because they have so little collectivity
in their own country
meaning but to say you can have mutual
assured destruction
there's nothing to attack yeah
we're going to rio need to move forward
well you know but cyber
cyberwar against cyber war you they need
to have cyber systems
when we went into Afghanistan in 2001
I asked dennis et to develop a plan to
attack
Afghanistan also with fiber or check
ready came back to me is that
what they should do you think we're
going to attack yeah
well but actually have reason other upon
which we haven't discussed
a certain Elmander strategy obscene
vulgar question a deterrence and how you
deal with
people who attack department is
resilience its building the capability
to deal with the fact that your cyber
assets may be impaired
and I you know sometimes you its
mechanical
fix something you need to be able to
shot of something if in fact
someone get into it in cyberspace
sometimes its redundancy sometimes
frankly
and maybe hearses say this year it is a
low-tech response
I mean you know I find if I have a
really important document I printed out
I know that's really kinda caveman staff
but you know
no one can hack into a paper document
even show sometimes using different
levels of Technology
I introduce Islamic resilient either in
cash to be part of a strategy
there was a guy who said if you don't
want if you want to keep something
secret don't put it on a computer
there she met and so you know there's
something to that there are some simple
thing