some love you or your tower
right now I but we
need we need it this is a huge
public interest for our country and we
need the brass
best brains a that we can bring to bear
on meeting the challenges so
%uh in addition to consolidating within
the department single chain of command
we also I have a
for three important pieces are cyber
strategy
that fulfils are goes toward meeting
our mission the first is the continued
development feinstein as a critical tool
in protecting our federal civilian
agencies as you know the US computer
emergency readiness team us-cert as
where we consolidate our intrusion
detection incident analysis
and cyber response capabilities to
protect these
systems in the past year we've deployed
the second phase a
I it's time to 11 federal agencies we
will grow to twenty one by the end of
this year
and we have forward-deployed I N Stein
to to the poor management trusted
Internet Protocol Service Providers
this deployment in fact is ahead of
schedule
and it is allowing us to better identify
malicious cyber activity
and improve cybersecurity support across
the federal government
so now we're testing the technology for
the third phase
appliance time and intrusion prevention
system which will provide the Department
of Homeland Security
with the ability to automatically detect
malicious activity
and this able attempted intrusions
before
are is done to our critical networks
and systems let me a at a critical point
here even as we are working
in developing and deploying I'm stylized
I find to now I signed three week
take very seriously the protection of
privacy
civil rights and civil liberties so in
the cyber area
we have established an oversight and
compliance officer
I in to to work from the outset
on the technologies that we are seeking
to develop and deploy
and key US certain personnel
receive specific training on the
protection of privacy and other civil
liberties
as they were late to computer network
security activities
so even as we move to prevention
detection a on
malicious activity prevention preemption
in a way
we want to do it in an atmosphere that
respects those core
privacy values as well so that's why the
first
major major areas that we have
undertaken activities in his past your
second we're developing
the National cybersecurity incident
response plan
ensure up I which is being developed in
for collaboration with the private
sector
the ensure will allow us to Mel a
national
response to a significant cyber incident
a response where all aspects of our
society would have an important role to
play
from the federal government state and
local governments
to the private sector now much of the
government side have such a response
will be coordinated
I love the new national cybersecurity
and communications integration center
and kick are and we're looking forward
at the testing other plans I
that we are making with ensure been and
kick I
this fall in September when we will also
conduct the cyber storm
3 exercise again was full participation
up the private sector so as a secondary
the third area
I wanted to discusses that we have made
significant progress
are helping to secure the automated
control systems
that operate elements of our critical
infrastructure
now private industry owns and operates
the vast majority
on the nation's critical infrastructure
and cyber networks
so therefore we work very closely with
the private sector
to conduct vulnerability assessments on
six
commonly use control systems components
and networks we have then develop
training manuals
for workshops for conferences and for
other venues
to educate the control systems community
on the risk control systems cyber
attacks
as well as mitigation solutions
now since its inception the control
system security program has trained
fourteen thousand plus professionals
for both classroom and web-based
instruction
and we now conduct monthly cybersecurity
conference calls with the primary
manufacturers
of these control systems so bringing all
of us together
we establish the industrial control
systems cyber
emergency response team which is
really a national resource to recei
to managing to respond to incidents and
vulnerabilities
that affect our nation's control systems
and again nations control systems are
important
for protecting and securing the nation's
infrastructure
goes right to the heart the mission the
Department of Homeland Security
so these are key efforts already
underway
at DHS but as I've suggested
we need to do more am we need to do it
faster
so within the Department of Homeland
Security
we're committed to better aligning our
cybersecurity and physical
infrastructure protection
missions nearing together a strong
resiliency
component to make the Department a
clearer focal point for cybersecurity
with in the federal government our goal
of course is to be able to ensure the
continuity of government
and private sector services and
information
while protecting privacy but also
providing
the ability to bounce back even more
quickly should
a large-scale attacker really an attack
have any size
I a car a part of it is prevention
reaction prevention but also resiliency
around the nation now
it's important I think on to pause here
and say
that we are not about duplicating
capabilities that exist
elsewhere in the government we're past
the point
where stove pipes in the government make
any sense whatsoever when I fished old
pipes
what we mean is we're things are and
vertical corners like this
stove pipes but there's no wars all
connectivity than ever
reach out are they and they do not
organized to communicate talk plan
strategize
with each other I so within
this department by having all these
missions and strategies and one place we
are able
to break down those stovepipe said
existed
prior to this and bringing all national
capabilities to bear while we continue
to
organized and to build a the cyber
cybersecurity aspect of the civilian
side
are United States government on
you know last week the I was testifying
in the congress
before the Senate Appropriations
Committee
are and I described our efforts
I as really not being a a
a duplication or replication for what
the Department of Defense is talking
about doing
because I think in some respects we we
are much further along
but it's really a recognition the
massive effort we need to make on the
civilian private sector side
if we are truly going to exists in a
secure cyber environment
in this century so are we want to make
sure your
a and part of this now will go to Mb
I think discussed within the congress
but within the administration
with the congress are we want to ensure
and make sure
that the Department of Homeland Security
has the legal authorities and the
financial
resources we will need to execute our
mission
successfully and two attract maintain
and retain the top talent that we need
we're going to work with the private
sector to build resiliency here
I and we are going to be pushing forward
as I said as fast as we possibly can
let me let me turn to the human
dimension aspect
up this and get beyond kinda
governmental organization and
and kickin ensure but and all that let's
talk about the people
because be on the technological and
governmental side of cybersecurity
I can't stress enough that really a
a secure cyber environment is as much
about people
and habits and culture a as it is
about machines cuz even the most elegant
technological solution will ultimately
fail
up