ladies and gentleman please welcome
FBI director Robert s mother the third
and afternoon everyone
I'm sorry about that between the marines
here because he had to stand up
they told me that they had music
introduce
the speaker by I said no you gotta be
kidding
they say what do you want and i'd
joshing Lee said well
the Marine Corps hymn hoping to up
spider
or two up push everybody back and lo and
behold
they did up I'm glad to be back in San
Francisco
and glad to be back talking to this
audience I can tell you I always like to
be
a little bit different and I'd venture
to say I'm probably the only person
in this room that is wearing a tie I may
well I
be the only person the room knows what I
is I
but as I say hey it's good to be back in
San Francisco
recently I read a new story
about a tailor in Bogota Colombia
a tailor who makes bulletproof menswear
he will design the garment to your
specifications
and line with Kevlar sufficient to stop
a bullet fired from a .38-caliber pistol
at point-blank
range some may question whether this is
necessary or extravagant or both but the
world has become increasingly dangerous
this man was merely combining the need
to stay safe with the desire to look
good
at the same time course my first thought
as well was for the brave but polish
volunteer who were these clothes during
the testing phase
my second thought over
however was that we could use this kind
of ingenuity
to safeguard are computer systems in the
early nineteen nineties we marveled at
the potential at the Internet
the risks seem to be a world away and
the dangers were largely limited
two teenage hackers and identity theft
but today the power and the
pervasiveness
on the internet are evident in the way
we communicate way we conduct business
no way we learn but the risks are no
longer a just that possibility they
write their doorstep and in some cases
they are already inside
the house and unlike the Colombian
Taylor we are not bulletproof
nor can we make ourselves so we can work
together
to align our networks with the
equivalent kevlar
and we can work together to find them to
stop those who are taking
shots at us and to prevent future
attacks
almost twenty years ago here in San
Francisco I read the book
entitled The Cuckoo's egg many have you
I'm sure know it two-story other by
Cliff stall
a Systems Manager at eight Berkeley
Laboratory he noticed an accounting
discrepancy
I've just 75 cents any ultimately track
track that describe the 28 German
espionage ring tapping into
our military networks met a story to
several FBI employees to illustrate the
Aleutian
cybercrime asked if anybody had read the
book
I one replied did Stick Micro
younger employees said with a but look
like a smirk
I haven't read it sir I was only 10 when
it was published
I responded thank you for reminding me
of how old I am
I'm sure you'll be very happy in the
FBI's office in Yemen
coming around a large office agent
though it
agent though it may be the story
up this tall illustrates how far we have
come and how quickly
today we'll talk about what the FBI is
doing to investigate and prevent cyber
crime
talk about the power partnerships touch
a touch on what we must do together to
prevent cyber crime from becoming
endemic
to our businesses our economy and our
national
security as begin with cyber threats to
our national security
as you well know a cyberattack
could have the same impact as a
well-placed bop
today terrorists have not use the
internet to launch a full-scale
cyberattack
but they have executed numerous denial
of service attacks
near the face numerous web sites
including congress' website
following President Obama's State of the
Union speech
a group known as the Iranian cyber army
claimed responsibility for this attack
and while the damage may
have been limited such groups attack for
both publicity impact and becoming more
adept
at both in the past 10 years
al Qaeda's online presence has become
as potent as its physical presence
extremist are not limiting their use
the interment internet to recruitment a
radicalization they are using it to
incite
terrorism thousands of extremist website
promote violence to a ready
in the willing audience they're posting
videos on how to build
backpack bombs bioweapons and they are
using social networking
too late terrorist plotters and plants
Accorsi internet is not
only used to plan and execute attacks it
is a target
in another itself Osama bin Laden
long ago identified cyberspace as a
means to damage both our economy
inner psyche and countless extremists
have taken this to heart we in the FBI
along with our partners in the
intelligence community leave the cyber
terrorism threat Israel
and rapidly expanding terrorists have
shown
a clear interest in pursuing hacking
skills and they will either train their
own recruits
or higher outsiders with an eye toward
combining physical attacks with
cyberattacks
apart
apart from the terrorist threat
nation-states may use the internet
as a means attack for political ends
consider what took place in Estonian
2007 and in the republic of Georgia in
wave after wave data requests
shut down banks an emergency phone lines
gas stations grocery stores even part
a beach countries government the impact
that these attacks
but this all aware of our
vulnerabilities
mister promoted to
counterintelligence intrusions and
economic espionage espionage want
pitted spy versus spy country
a against country but today our
adversaries said on
fiber-optic cables and WiFi networks
often unknown and under undetected
they may be nation state actors are
mercenaries
for higher rogue hackers are
transnational
criminal syndicates the attackers
actively target our government networks
AC car technology our intelligence
our intellectual property even our
military weapons
and strategies and in short they have
everything to gain
and we have a great deal to lose there
has been much discussion
%uh late about which nation-states pose
the greatest
danger a cyberattack to a certain extent
that discussion baby irrelevant may not
matter who the attacker is for whether
the Notre
motivation is political ideological
or financial the information may be
bought
and sold by anyone anywhere in the world
weather friend or follow and the end
result will be the same
we will lose our data we may well lose
access to our own information
and we mail may well lose our security
in recent years we have witnessed a new
trend the collection have seemingly
innocuous information
about a company and its employees from
email addresses
to PowerPoint presentations to note for
meetings
the state it not only provides inside
knowledge up research and development
business plans or quiet negotiations
it can provide entree to a company's
network
hackers are using this data to Spearfish
employees
sending emails purportedly from
coworkers
with content often to loring or
realistic
to ignore and just one reach
is all they need to open the floodgates
we'll see not only a loss of data but
also corruption and that they did
we as you were concerned with the
integrity of source code
if hackers made subtle undetected
changes to your code
they could have a permanent window into
everything you do
the same is true for those with access
to hardware and software
in the global supply chain