defeating Germany was built on a united
front we stopped playing defense and we
push back
day by day there is no one country
standing alone that could have ended
that war and the same is in some ways
true today in this new context
no one country no one company
no one agency can't stop cybercrime a
bar the windows in both the doors
mentality will not
totally insure our collective safety for
churches will not hold forever
walls will one day fall down and we must
start at the source we must find those
responsible the only way to do that is
by standing together
together we can find better ways to
safeguard our systems
and stop and incarcerate those who would
do us harm
for only we face the same threat we both
you and I serve the american people and
we must continue to do everything we can
together to minimize and stop
these attacks now before I
a finish up I one last word my good
friend I understand Janet Napolitano
stood on this stage couple days ago and
encouraged
those have you in the audience to sign
up with the Department of Homeland sure
Homeland Security I also
want to send out an imitation those have
you in the audience
you would like to serve the country to
join the FBI and if you'd like to join
the FBI
then perhaps I can encourage you to join
the Marine Corps
thank you Brad may God bless you take
care