thank you and good morning everyone like
to extend my own personal warm welcome
to all love you too
iris a conference 2010 know this
gathering
%uh hours gets more importantly each
year
because more than just the occasional
story
on the database preach the magnitude in
volume
up cyber vulnerabilities
and attacks have become mainstream
topics
in the media as never before
underscoring
the criticality the situation this week
you'll be hearing from
Secretary Napolitano FBI director molar
White House cybersecurity coordinator
Howard Schmidt and a host I've industry
and government leaders you know
it it really never gets easier for us
says
practitioners and then there's does it
malware
at pandemic levels a global economy
struggling to recover in a straitjacket
of cost controls
and a new wave of computing struggling
to take hold
cloud computing but it could get easier
how up by leveraging the technologies
enabling the clout to secure it sounds
heavenly
but as my father used to say p
everybody wants to go to heaven but
nobody wants to die
to get there and because cloud computing
represents a challenge
as well as an opportunity we have to be
careful
we don't end up in security hell so
whenever I feel locks ten by big
challenge like this
I like to look to history as a reminder
the boundless creativity of the human
mind
its ability to completely reimagined
aspects of life
that others seem unchangeable and we
don't need to look
any father then the recent past and the
man we honor this morning
with defeat as well as our own
Rs and a for this kind of creativity
in the area managing have crypt agassi
these are people who see what others
before them cannot
no matter how hard a look and from there
insight
they build a new vision sometimes
quite literally consider another
inspiring example imagine what it was
like
to be a blind person in the three
centuries
following looking birds invention the
printing press
the printing press represented a
sweeping transformation up the
information infrastructure on the time
it changed for ever the way thoughts
knowledge
and information was shared and yet
if you are blind you would have been
locked out this new world
recorded knowledge then
in the early eighteen hundreds along
comes Louis Braille
blind since the age up three
as a 16-year-old he envisioned and then
devised a system that would enable them
blind
to read as well as right his curiosity
led him to a form of communication
used by soldiers on the battlefield at
night
when they needed to send written
messages to each other
but didn't dare light a match
real adopted their grill %uh raised dots
but
dramatically improved and simplified
their system and that process till today
as one historian put it braille was
the gutenberg on the blind so
how does this relate to our industry
and our situation today
I believe we in the security industry
even what elevated an expansive vision
connected to the uge wave %uh IT
transformation that is
underway right now cloud computing
think for a moment about why cloud
computing is so powerful
in animals businesses to leave their AG
inflexible
and costly IT infrastructures behind and
moved to a new
Pay As You Go model characterized
by choice and agility
and not a moment too soon because
organizations are spending as much as
two-thirds of their
IT budgets just maintain their
infrastructures
and applications keeping the lights on
cloud computing can dramatically alter
this two-thirds one-third ratio
so that much more energy and investment
can be directed
toward real innovation and competitive
advantage
trouble is something's holding back
the full realization love this vision
and that in a word is security
CIO magazine recently published its
stated the CIO study
and get this fifty-one percent of CIOs
surveyed
more than half cited security as their
greatest concern
surrounding the adoption up cloud
computing
and if you are suffering from cloud for
T
alright tired of hearing about it let me
remind you
other than MIT Media Lab's visionary
Nicolas Negra Ponting who said in 1997
that the internet was the most
over-hyped
but underestimated phenomenon in history
mark my words the same will be true up
cloud computing
cloud computing will complete the
transformation a
IT infrastructures unleashed by the
Internet
organizations will demand it because
they must
absolutely must get faster and better
returns
on their IT investments so we must play
an essential role in making cloud
computing
a reality so here's the skull
about challenge an hour opportunity
as I see it the challenge is to ensure
that safety is designed
and built into the cloud so that
organizations a every size
from the smallest merchant are agency to
the largest
government or multinational can make
broad use in the cloud
fully confident that their information
and transactions
are secure are industry
needs to deliver security solutions that
ensure
levels of protection in the cloud that
surpass
what physical environments offer today
in short people must everywhere be able
to trust the clout
even if they literally and
metaphorically
can't see thats
our challenge what about our opportunity
the answer is that cloud computing
is going to make your work more
important and prominent
then ever before cloud computing is our
opportunity
did to change the way we deliver
security
inside out I say that
because the cloud will force
organizations to pay serious attention
to this security management process ease
not just their endpoint dead endpoint
security technologies
we have for rare opportunity for do of
to be present at the creation n roll out
on this new wave of computing with
security
built in from the get-go
we can't be on the ground floor to
create and infrastructure
that is actually more secure and more
enabling
%uh innovation then today's physical
infrastructures
that's my focus today how together
we can make the cloud inherently secure
compliance and governed in a way in a
way and manner that ensures
confidentiality
integrity and availability about
information
in other words security that enables
business
like never before
so where we start in the world of cloud
computing will need to enforce
all the same identity information
infrastructure policies
we have in the physical world but it
gets trickier
because ritual infrastructures decouple
your software environment from the
underlying hardware
infrastructure so that you can aggregate
many servers
storage systems and networks into shared
pools and resources
as we consider how to make the clouds
safe I think it's best to begin with
people
process and technology just as we do
in other aspects a business and security
so let's start with the people shelling
in the physical world
all these are siloed separate groups
focus on
storage servers networks and points and
so on
in the cloud many of these operations in
roles
will converge for example
world