the prion or miss topic to try to figure
out
you know what are some other security
issues are the impediments to getting to
a success and I think that if we
basically take this issue and we start
looking at it from a couple different
perspectives
for example we think about the
perspective the
end-user we look at the the IT expert
really
the the community of IT practitioners in
an organization
we also look at the provider community
as well I think that's going to be very
important
because he's maybe a lil bit high for a
lot of hype right now in the market
space and so we need to learn from
providers as well as end-users terms of
what's really happening out there and
is in fact security a major driver
inhibitor
is it exacerbate the kinds of problems
that you see an on-premise technologies
either to some other things and I heard
today hey
on now you'll notice there's a beautiful
picture the cloud
thank you for that are working you'll
also notice at WWW
that pondimin Dow toward slash our essay
we r
looking for the best people in the world
we want you
to go to our website and register for
this
absolutely terrific survey so if you do
it here's what I promise you
I promise that we will see provide a
summary I
we will not violate your privacy and we
will
share that information with you and
and I think it's really important that
we learn from you have
being a talking head here we need to
spend time understanding what's in your
head in that
the survey will be very helpful to I
sell hopefully everyone will participate
I really appreciate that you know to
celebrate email address or anything
we get that second there that now dole
you don't get good I was checkin
yeah I thanks larry in it thanks
gentlemen are
I weaker German do the survey dizzy it's
a it's a great thing it's it's larry is
working I legacies a world renown in a
stable work in research in anything will
give a great back to you as soon as it's
available the early in May
it will publish it back out so I really
encourage you to do that
so it's a wrap up I think that I started
talking about his security inhibitor to
cloud adoption and
and I i really don't think it is i think
the based on their knowledge and
intellect to the people in this room in
in the in the security organizations in
our company's
but I really think that we can stop
being looked at as an inhibitor
but I really truly believe that we all
can be enable others to help
organizations take advantage of this new
technology as it continues to evolve so
I like to thank you very much
I please enjoy the rest the conference
and I'll kiss you again next year
thank you thanks guys thank you