the afternoon and thank you for joining
me today
this is my third consecutive RCA
keynoter am very excited to be here
I it's a fantastic conference and we
really enjoy
be a big sponsor here today we want to
explore
be the challenge are is security
really an inhibitor to using the cloud
in a cloud adoption
if you read the press and the journals
in everything you read about today
you'll see that securities generally
identified as the number one issue
security compliance privacy
for people to really adoptees great new
services
so that will be exploring today in my
role prior to running CA security
business unit I was the CIO the company
and our chief security officer Bill
toppers in the audience today as well
if we go back three or four years bill
and I had summer challenges like we
wanted that
and evaluating you Software as a Service
we wanted to use remote host
applications
we started experimenting with Platform
as a Service
all very successfully we we've all been
doing this for a few years
it's not that this is all that new and
sometimes I think
we fail to communicate effectively that
we actually can do a lot of this
and maybe we need to the bong the myth
the legend that security is really this
inhibitor so today I am
we decided to go with the a
distinguished panel the really dive into
this issue
and the panel is diverse they come from
different backgrounds
someone panelists our cloud providers
summer cloud consumers
and summer both so we're gonna get their
insight
and we'll share that with you so afraid
I'd like to introduce our panel
first we have Tim Chrisman from axiom
next we have
Steve Riley from Amazon then Kurt obably
from Lockheed Martin and last but not
least
doctor Larry Parliament from the
parliament Institute
thanks guys so
I wanna turn it over to
Larry to kick things off larry is a a
very distinguished researcher
but well-recognized world-renowned misty
told me that in our interview
and yeah I I wanted to kick off the
dialogue by sharing with you some other
work in research that he's dime
and gotta start the juices going and
then we're gonna diving with the panel
with some
interesting questions the discuss and
debate so larry and thank you Dave
appreciated
and good afternoon everyone thank you
for staying late in listening to us I
think we have
I have some really interesting
information to share with you on
just and you know where in the repin a
min Institute Larry pondimin here
we basically do research very boring we
focus on things like information
security and we're very interested in
cloud computing security we're doing a
number of studies myspace
but is kind of interesting walking
through the exhibit hall
I saw on a hundred we counted that
scientifically after we've missed a few
but 127
different security products supposedly
dedicated to security in the cloud
so that I think it leading indicator
that we're onto something here that it
must be important
herein are both I was only in there for
I 127 messages on cloud computing
security
so but i wanna do is this sign tattoo is
it is like one picture is worth 1000
words he said that it was a
confucius said that but was kind of
interesting is that if you look at this
and you're on the high when you see this
sign you can have a heart attack because
he's just too much going on
and really when you think about the
issues that are keeping us
up at night from our cloud computing
prospective is really how insecure is
the cloud isn't as bad as people say it
is
or is it more fide appearance there in T
and doubt and so it's
just another security issue but not
worse than any up the gazillion
security issues that we have to deal
with every day another issue
can not cloud computing actually not
just diminish but
enhance the security posture that
organization is that possible
in a bit maybe very possible I'm how do
we had negotiate privacy and data
protection issues you know they heard
the privacy word
throughout this conference does it
become harder to
enable privacy to ensure compliance with
data protection was specially european
allies your data transfer
lies who is responsible for security the
company the vendor
on the IT gurus in an organization are
they
do we become less important ways it
really an end-user
responsibility how do we respond today
to live to date if after data breach in
the cloud
we have more make it data breaches
because we'll have more data
that can be lost or stolen I what
security trumpet
technologies transfer in the cloud and
what technologies are going to be left
behind
because they don't transfer to the cloud
is security as a service
is it is a big one is it economically
viable I mean we think it is but it will
it actually create enough
positive economics to now find
investment
in better technology and less than but
not least in this map here
is while protecting the cloud leave us
vulnerable to other areas
I mean are we gonna nor other important
pieces the security puzzle
so hopefully we'll learn a panel
discussion will answer most these
questions
actually next five minutes great thank
you larry take that from me
on so when we look at
II the the panel had not Steve here from
Amazon and an Steve that runs around the
world be in an evangelist for security
and for at
a Amazon Services and ec2 is it is a
great
service you guys offer I know we use
every many things like testing were
doing there
on so do you think that security is a
bear ears the for people to adopt those
services
I think people think it's a barrier a
mostly from
just not having a complete understanding
love how a cloud
environment might look a lot like the
existing environment they have and how
it differs from
from traditional IT environment so a
large part of my job
is to help people understand what we're
doing
to protect the infrastructure to protect
customers from each other to
provide high degrees have compute and
storage isolation
a.m. but in many respects I i think that
much of what we've all learned as
security practitioners
overtime applies to the cloud as well
simply giving up ownership for the
infrastructure does not mean you have to
give up on a ship that the data
and with appropriate controls like
encryption
right security standards and things like
that we can still maintain that
that that ownership for the information
right and that's what do I think ski on
on the transparency is is key
transparency Eagles trust
and one of the things I think we could
all help each other out with this kinda
demystifying this whole cloud where
I think there's a general perception
that there's this big a more precise
cloud that doesn't really be you know
isn't really cable cuz my
anything but there's private clouds and
public cloud and hybrid cloud
and there isn't anybody that would ever
offer up their IT security
order compliance properties to say one's
gonna put up in the clouds I think
there's a
a bit of an educational that to you guys
transparency Eagle stress I think
more transparent cloud providers can be
you'll see more more customers adopt
that's great not Kurt down you run that
an amazing center in maryland the the
NextGen cybersecurity center
that protects love the infrastructure
the US I
lucky margins is really a global
security
leader and you miss a lot of customers
you're managing supporting
defense customers watch their customers
what's your reaction
in from the federal government site and
how they're adopting things is there a
fear from the federal government to the
hide of so many services and use them
what are your thoughts on that so we're
very very customer focused a
in their customers have a diverse set of
missions they understand their missions
that they have
you can see whether some concerning
clout right but when you look at
certain missions they have like
confident facing
missions on EPA Eric and get on a a
cloud over the PA
you can find out all kinds information
to be about you know
buyer knows where you are right in one
of our customers
I've been working with remains proud
example week
but I secure cloud private cloud inside
the printer
and when we looked at certain workload
it makes sense to keep it there
but another workload they had some
interplanetary imagery that unlike whole
week
to do what they needed internally right
but when they
went out to the cloudburst to ec2 over a
weekend
about six hours they got the same thing
done and that was dated that was going
to happen in the public so
you understand average profile then you
can start managing that fear
excellent Solari did a little research
on are different groups whether the
federal government to keep their
commercial markets
on what do you see news is there a
difference in the responses from
the government people versus the
commercial sector folks that's kind of
interesting we just had a steady and
involved executives in the
federal government its final government
is federal government departments and
agencies
and we were fun we we found some
uninteresting
findings with respect to cloud computing
I think we were not dazzled by am
as we work a little surprise that cloud
computing as a security risk
rain before and have 12 it doesn't mean
that's not in it thats
that's still suggest it's really
significant but there are other issues
that were viewed as much more
pressing a much more important will have
another study
look that folks who are at a lower level
in the same governmental organizations
here
we call people folks in the trenches
folks like unis
these people looked at the same security
risk in actually put cloud computing in
a much higher level so I've year
the wrong where they know something that
the Chiefs the senior-level
folks are now where okay