at these are safe and in fact you know
when you think it through its a
it's really a good thing because what's
that wants one of the role of government
the role of government government is to
protect the nation on one hand at this
is a subir warfare
and you had before that you know
discussion about it and the second one
is to protect the individuals
and today as we all know we all have to
go onto the internet
and a the risk of being mad
is quite significant so i think is very
well coming to have the government for
him to be
for really very serious
at you know and being here so or that
problem so for those who have not had
the opportunity to
here the the Keno the for our new
cybersecurity czar
very happy to eat to introduce Howard
Schmidt in our digital world
the information technologies we depend
upon everyday present us with both great
opportunity
in great danger for national security
public safety in our economic
competitiveness
as well as our personal privacy our
lives have been rich in callus ways by
technologies
arnelle part over the very fabric for
day-to-day lives
our dependence on these wonderful
technologies continue to increase with
each new innovation
as does our shared responsibility to
protect our security
in our Privacy indeed as president Obama
has said
the cyberthreat represents one of the
most serious economic and national
security challenges
we face as a nation as such I look
forward to working with our leadership
from congress
industry federal departments and
agencies state local and tribal
governments
as well as our international partners to
ensure that our economic
and national security interest are
enhanced are combined cybersecurity
efforts
because ultimately no one not government
not the private sector that individual
citizens can keep us safe and strong
alone
when it comes to cyber security our
vulnerability shared
and so is our responsibility to ensure
that our networks are secure
trustworthy rezoning so as I told the
president
I'm committed to bringing all the
stakeholders together around a new
comprehensive cyber strategy it keeps
America secure
in prosperous thank you howard and
if we look back to the these videos
that we have the in this neck so there
is a is a common threat to love them
and these are one
as we discuss that the technology is
really moving very fast and it's
becoming
totally unpredictable to understand what
is going to be it impact the second
thing is that that
obviously requires that we think
different I
we cannot continue thinking the same way
and think he is obviously not enough
a we need to act and I
different so were clearly
on RB crossroad up these are not going
to you
get better soon but I believe you have
the hope of making them better
so as I mentioned earlier I think the
opportunity is really
for all of us together to have that goal
in mind
a building the security into the very
fabric
the cloud and in doing so making it
practically
invisible and what I think it will
require
it would withdraw a toward it different
I did June between the security vendors
we as security vendors up to return
out to Cooper out to me to collaborate
together
at creating true integration between
out-competing solution if this
what it takes because one company cannot
do it
anymore I'm sure you recall some of
these a
up speeches made that because we have
sold millions up sensors
we know all that great landscapes and
therefore should buy from me
you're going to be protected so that was
probably true
two years ago it's not true anymore
there is also some fundamental building
block
have the clout that we have to make more
secure
we need obviously a more secure browser
we'd also what I call a single
the secure single sign-on so when we go
into the crowd you know we don't have to
managing all these different passwords
and so forth that's
another problem which needs to be sold
so this is going to require the
commitment of the individual which are
working at that to really
thinking more than just the leader
interest %uh their companies that we
start to understand that this is a
bigger problem here that we want to
seoul
and I think if we tap into the community
which is as we very well know today
computing us change it's not anymore I
they used to call the priest the
up for technology in direct contact with
the God of technology providing
technology to the mortars
today communities are extremely savvy
very knowledgeable
I think there's a huge report unity to
hap into the F
effort other communities if individuals
and I do believe today that community
like the ice is said many others will
have in fact more power
because now they can really influence
and push
you know the vendors whether they are
the traditional security vendors are
worthy of the cloud computing vendors
to centrally go at fulfilling that
agenda
let me give you your a few links that
there's many more by the
I was like to recognize the Jericho
forum
and for the very simple reason that good
G that the jerk off or members which was
about a group for
food C-one hundred large companies which
were
trying to influence the vendors
to change the way they were doing things
they were criticized a lot then simply
because they had the vision
before many many of us that the business
requirements and the technology combines
where century a foresee it but
forcing us to up in a bow networks
and therefore making the security in
that environment
harder and harder and harder as we just
discussed earlier
and that's what they call the
parametrization and then they've all
to start to understand that after all
the end goal is
collaboration in the cloud and how do
you make collaboration into the plot
secure their old quite a few
interesting papers about that and then
most recently they aren't you lucky you
can if in a self-assessment allowing us
to try to find out
if all cooperation before doing you know
the room
right these enough you know to
isn't removed from that transition to
securing ok
all current network to the new word I've
leaving if you prefer in the cloud then
you're no the Cloud Security Alliance is
have also put the paper that Alex Tomos
a
with put we publish that on our website
that i text that most
a created because
it awaits it's scary should go and look
at this paper when I look at it the
first time I saw my god
this is a lot so I told him I said extra
duty divided into pieces
one which is the seventh these you need
to do and then
a the second page the other 25 of 30
things you need to do
its mindboggling to see the complexity
the number of things we need to do do in
fact
be immune to some degree to attack like
or are so welcome you to go to see that
paper
there's another book which had input
here that out
really recommend that you read I forgot
the name of the author at my age you
know you start to forget a few things
but I i remember the name of the book
this good
this cold thinking the unthinkable
and this is the book all about that
acceleration of technology
and that we cannot really predict in
fact trying to give use
give us you know some mentor if you
prefer
techniques a so we could start to
think the in the cover and be there for
much more ready to adjust to changes
for those who believe that we are not in
and I threw should have changed let me
give you another
personal example example have my
grandmother
my grandmother was very nicely
educated by the by the Sisters
finish school at 16 and a half years old
because she was considered very smart
sensor the finishing up thirteen years
or
the giver three more years a free
education
and my grandmother so in one life
the first commercial bicycle and the
first man in the moon
right that you today technology is
accelerating
even faster so without
I would like to leave you with a very
strong message of hope because
if life I believe for the IT people is
not going to be fun because I meant to
be dislocated be
time thanks of cloud computing so for
them they will have to readjust I think
from the security people is a unique
opportunity
because security people find them a tour
or as you all know
its obviously about to very far
this is our job to make sure