good afternoon it's a real pleasure to
be with you today that thank you for
coming
so before a we start discussing about
how
cloud computing a is changing security
as we know it may be
let's go back to a few RC sure recall
the days when
it was about the said defending network
it was about large companies
which will govern up all of these point
solutions to provide
can afford one shop word would be
significantly
is your to go to to secure our networks
it was the day where
worms and a hikers where
roaming happily out there
if we just one year back
that was the year where almost every
security company s an entry by them
by the magic of marketing become a sauce
company
everybody wanted to be
cloud computing the security
professionals were
pretty leary because obviously seventy
thinking that the data that we
spend so much time and energy to protect
was now moving into the cloud
was indeed frightening we also so
virtualization new technology coming out
and we could see
a matter where starting to
raise its ugly head and at that time
also within wanted to have to do
anything with social networks
because we knew that that was a very
dangerous place
so let's look at where we are today
the theme far as said today
is cloud computing becoming
rear and in a bid to burn
it's about matter where I have been
become a century pandemic
we social networking whether we like it
or not we're all doing it
and we have seen
doubt Arthur is significant
participation above the government
with our new cybersecurity czar
with the director the if the I'm
Janet Napolitano and contributing
significantly
you know did you the discussion so that
there's ice that something as really
change
and this is what we're going to talk
about so then meet
go back gain a little bit a year ago for
those who
assist the I doubt talk I discuss about
the inconvenient truth of security which
today we know exactly what it is the
fact that
securing on that work has become harder
their neighbor
if not impossible and
obviously that we know now as I discuss
a year ago that
drug computing is extremely is very as a
very disruptive nature
in itself which you know many whiskers
is or so
room since then i thought id been more
about the disruption
and what I realize is that in fact its
even more powerful than I thought biko's
it reminded me if we go back few hundred
million years ago
to the Cambrian period where we so the
explosion of life
and we saw the exposure of a fly because
there was
enough building blocks of life that this
started to be on themselves and creating
very very different ecosystems competing
against the
each other's so across technology is
concerned this is exactly what is
happening
technologies building on his on itself
faster and faster and faster and faster
and there's plenty of examples that that
in June 2003 as I'm sure you all recall
the Apple Computer the iPhone was now
most
banded poo-poo d that you can if a
gadget
three years later where more than 100000
ap on that device on which is really a
platform
and these applications are changing our
very lives
and even the way we do business and
three years ago
bukar and operator were good friends
essentially trying to for
pushback Microsoft together
now today they are competing
in a battle which is very reminiscent of
the upper and micro sim batter
the up in platform versus the more
clothes
platform and then few weeks ago
a we had that new announcement
the iPad and again same story all over
again
the banded pooh-poohing doesn't have
these doesn't have that this is
that's a troll the reasons why this is
not going to work
but when you start to think about it
that device
leveraging a lot of technologies which
has made now that devised possible as
well as the
delivery mechanism that I judy's
seventy I believe is going to change
again
our lives especially the live the
executives
as well as the life of my you three
years old
lil girl why
because as an executive seventy with
that
device I can read the newspapers
I can read my books I can do some email
again just some notes as you know
executive
done that very productive we just
consume information
sometime we do something about it so
and my little girl she's already and I
touch
fine and she finds that the the the
keyboard is too small
you know the so she's going to be
delighted when a giver
and iPad which I can because it's only
£5.95
so would you think that a man dove 65
years old would share the same
technology that the three years old
your arm so that's the world we are in
so we've got to be ready for the change
and that change is becoming almost
unpredictable so this is where we are
whether we like it or not so
I discuss obviously about our that
phenomena which is got computing and
cloud computing is nothing more
then the Internet due into the I pick
industry
and two the security industry in
particular
what he has already done for the
publishing industry
this is all these internet biz
technology
coming at disrupting the way we do
business
so I discuss a year ago about the fact
that unique opportunity that cloud
computing was giving us a security
professionals biko's
it gives us the opportunity to build the
the security E do the very fabric of
cloud computing
today the problem we all obvious that we
have to secure his enterprise network
which means corporation f2
by the infrastructure via the servers
the database is installed them by the
application integrated application and
then
with the security on the BB which is
obviously becoming absolutely impossible
to do
so we have that opportunity to
essentially put our minds together
and really do the right things and beat
security into the fabric
of for computing so
obviously this present different
challenges in an opportunity and
we're going to look at one by one by
taking some segments what's the chance
for their of cooperation to do that
obviously the corporation are facing
fight with a billion with the most
difficult problem
because on one hand large proportion St
to continue maintaining the security of
the current computer infrastructure
and they have also to start you know to
move into the cloud and learning that
new
and varmint which obviously present a
certain number of challenges
so let's hear from the
the CSU 12 the largest global companies
I'm very happy to up
the sea is rough G grady summers no
which countries speak about his abortion
issues and challenges the moving into
the cloud
edgy were enthusiastic about the cloud
for the reasons you might expect like
the scale we like the
flexible provisioning of course like the
financials about what we like the most
is where the innovation we love the fact
that cloud provider can take all that
scale and leverage it toward a single
application or single
infrastructure platform really
innovative much faster pace than any
large or small company could on their
own
I we see a lot of opportunity for GE
companies like us we've we've had some
good success with
with storage in the cloud in backing up
to the cloud some good success stories
with security services in the cloud
I'm as well but we think most at the the
big opportunities are going to be an
applications as a service you know the
CRM
the personal productivity applications
in latex and moving those haps to the
cloud
that said we've got a real challenge
with security and compliance and privacy
on you know ironically many things you
love the most about the cloud
I make accounting from compliance
perspective we love that bass recycle
but on the other hand were bound by
regulations are required to document in
and test every release extensively
I love the fact their users can access
data from anywhere in the world on any
device but if the cloud provider can
tell us
aware that date is sitting or sure is
that was duly able we tried to delete it
that's going to be a problem so
ultimately I think this