coppersmith and others came in with
comments like that calming the flurry
never got happy again it wasn't that big
a deal the attack did not work
as specified at that time very argues
the
that makes you think a little bit let's
go back
and review the process again remember
that
session the first 15 giving their talks
in from dying in laying on the floor
had demanded came up with the BF attack
later on Randolph then in the room on
that day and stood up and said I have an
attack
have these huge array a linear equations
each term representing quadratics me a
este looks after
and i can tell it all down in Bangor got
your variable you're dead
I believe rendell would have been dead
laying on the floor along with others
and would not have gone to the final
five would not have emerged as the
winner
and I do believe it was the most
performance in widely acceptable and
performing
process in that part we would have lost
a good thing
that a process fall because a black
of time to verify for their technical
verification of claims made in a public
session
alright just kinda cool off a little bit
as: had the great for being the women
had time to cool a because it's too
frightening to throw it away
so they finally be down the BF attacking
it survived we have really the key
attacking talked about now I D way they
did mention that require related keys
was real question where you get those
get a megastar nevermind and
but duke it out an experiment with
taking him back and get ahead ed Rendell
there's another twist to it as well as
well as having a possibly detrimental
the concern on the second quarter round
she had a had his favorite way to be
brief
well that first when buyers of Africa
scary enough
but a go back to their first-round again
and look at the other candidates that
were disqualified are known to be dead
to some of them deserve a resurrection
was a possible they were shot with
blanks
the way ABS almost worked who is another
favorite could be examined on the
process to the lie in their graves
with respect or should they be
resurrected already
that left on the end of stuff and I
think I did what would be the
implication for the shuffling
competition %uh
as well to save my time here but lied
about the nope this do that now
the SHA three is running thank you and
happy said very much
on making
hash codes in my mind and I think most
of the audience is much harder
than making a codebook okay we got
then another reason he s was a fun thing
to do because it's pretty easy we should
have a winner
I'm not convinced we're going to have a
winner with the hash function a contest
running how do you make sure
you do good processes to do that it
started with fifty-some-odd thirty-some
I can do this that and the 15 now
I believe the process is to run for a
while looking at those in the mouth
a winner I think the field is too large
still I think they should pick
three winners not one as semifinalists
alright and run another one to two years
looking at those intensely
to really make sure another work has
been done for a wise decision
and not risk the hearty are foolish
consequence overlooking something
to seoul for the study has been done ID
like slot for study
thirteen years Amaury a little stories
about that we can't wait that long
but it needs more than the currently I
recommend extending the shop process
begin 31 is not one and studying longer
before announcing the final winner
the cave has pulled out there the
problems but they're far more robust now
to last longer for that process
than the AF process they have had to run
fast cuz theres
that was already dead in fact you should
replace many years before
apologies for that we can not make that
mistake again
if times are free to do it more safely
thank you
thank you just add something to what I
said you come in every day and work on
it impossible problem in about every 180
have a good idea
cool but a fall would be excited on day
one hundred after days 1 $3.99
produce nothing I mean cuz initially the
eighth and probably work on a day when
100 looks no different
from the others and that's something
that every meant at
that it's important to get excited about
that
10th or 100 idea even though it's
foolish to do it we have no chance of a
tactic so this looks like all the others
white light
why try it and you'll never get anywhere
K
wilhite like to take advantage of the
present so far special guest here
ask them pointed question I'm sure the
audience's
burning to ask you all kinds of things
like go when it is that the NSA
managed to break the RCA algorithm at
that quantum computer in the basement is
coming along
adamant uninstall the eavesdropping
software in our iPhones and so on and so
forth
but I I'm going to refrain from those
questions let me ask something a little
tamer
thank you mother is so please
so some years ago it was certainly the
case that the
Cryptologic know-how in the NSA
surpassed that in the academic community
to what extent do you feel that that's
the same case to what extent can you
comment on whether that's
the case today it's a more nuanced
last year you have to take a look at the
range of things and if he is interested
in and the Rangers thing
commercial sector is interested and they
do not have the identical
overlap as a prince that we care about
that you don't have a range that we care
about that you don't
things we care about nuclear command
control I don't think you care and want
to play in that area
okay things that we don't care much
about but that you are very interested
and
there are some and I really shouldn't
because then if they never confesses
were not interested in from the
cryptographic that many terms that
are not as thrilling for us lower
forgive me
of them their own knowledge doesn't will
be able to get has
if more value in peer to peer Mitchell
suspicion relationships among suspicions
partners
military systems are credit roll top
down the general says they were shut up
girl
you don't negotiate back and forth so we
have less interest
in some areas and you may be better off
in those areas that famous for your good
but let's take a look at the area were
you both overlap and we both have
something at stake
what's going on there we cheat we get to
read what you publish and you love to
publish it gets you academic prestige in
that promise
we do not publish what we study shame on
us
joking you know national security
we have to maintain but it is an
advantage this pragmatic it's there it's
real
class we have a very good budget a very
aggressive very talented staff 102
mathematicians PHD's
on stair doing nothing but good quality
that's a nice
Department those most universities can
you know
afford that in their schools so
unnecessarily I think we're going to
have some advantages here and they're
not as a give us a better
actual knowledge base more stuff then
you had
I think if you take a the way to do it
is not the best
how to compute that metric so let's go
to on various different specific field
and I can do this in detail
but each little piece that we might
overlap on there are so many different
people in Britain research papers and
stuff
measure in each case who's ahead plus
and minus course by some
manner and did a weighted average over
all of them come out with that number
to see who has the most they can on
average by defining averaging function
I do believe the NSA is still ahead but
not by much
small him to love years on average some
dramatically so others narrowly so
possibly even behind you in that pool
but on average due to resource intense
the admission and focus
I'm going to have the extreme hubris
adding him politely say
I think we got the age still but I do
believe that in the eighties it was a
huge gap
you guys picked all the cheap inlet
low-lying fruit real quick got
grown-up real fast and I got closer and
closer and tighter so the
exponential curve coming up but I think
will always be on a curve slightly
ranting and we're very close together
and both of us are moving slowly in a
fairly mature feel
so I can be a tighter race over the
years and sort of urgent met each other
shows method
so it makes no sense for me to issue
VAD Lee differing opinions in this and
the foolish in England do it anyway
a at first time this part A that I don't
think nuclear command and control is a
particularly good example something
that doesn't interest %uh the public I
the public about the first happen some
papers on that subject some up in
question outside an essay but inside the
government
I inspired by Gus Simmons which anyone
who's working on nuclear command and
control
I don't think that's outta bounds what
use outta bounds because
is there are a whole range up problems
that are inspired
by doing real signals intelligence
and you really this community can't do
that
the minor point almost irrelevant point
is that
you know would be illegal but generally
for us to do that a more significant
barriers the
expensive but the critical point years
it really would be unbounded leave
frustrating to attempt to do so signals
all real offense Eve work
in public if every time you reading
their traffic
you go publish a paper and rub their
noses in it they'll do something about
it
I and she'll work because you know will
you think I these workers frustrating
up that's what they worry about down to
Fort Meade you know we'll go
blows some source and then a bunch of
people have to work hard to several
years
to recover it and so that is the portion
the work
and when you're doing production
cryptanalysis
you are never satisfied with the results
I
you'd like to do it on the basis of less
traffic in the Pleasance a higher noise
get the results out quicker spend less
on the computers
no he into practical issues you have a
product that product is going off to
your bosses
were effectively paying you for and you
have to sharpen it up just as much as
you possibly can
a brief pushback I'm not