is in this decade of smart will embrace
service management what smarter security
as the foundation for their business
processes and those that do so
will be able to see did new
opportunities to innovate securely
and cost-effectively however
you can't move to a paradigm like
smarter security by yourself
it's just too big a job need partners
who can help you get there
partners who can deliver the technology
the business expertise
and the global service capabilities to
achieve
smarter security and that's one of the
reasons that we're all here today
share ideas share insights
that will help us achieve strong
security
because I think the lessons of the
Rosetta Stone have taught us
I that and we've known this but
thousands have years
with strong security will come strong
prosperity
I wish I love you great prosperity
in a safe journey home wherever that may
take you thank you and have a great
afternoon