laws in particular in war are
under siege from two sides that is
the prevailing laws of war the Geneva
Conventions are so old that if they were
people
they would qualify for Medicare and
actually were trying to apply them to a
21st century technology
like a Reaper drone it's been utilized
again to 21st century
have the Syrian war like an insurgent
who hides out in the hospital or school
or home
because they know that's what they're
not supposed to do
the taking advantage of the Los I
remember being at Human Rights Watch
and asking to move the officials there
what law would we turn to in these kinda
been since
and 1 I've they got an argument from me
and one of them said with a gene
conventions like we've always turn to
you
and the other one immediately yelled
back at him nah nah nah Geneva
Convention won't work in this
what we should turn to is the star Trak
prime directive
it's kinda funny but
the point is this are I love track i
cant
call captain kirk as an expert witness
in a
real court of law that is it may be
inspirational but we're talking about
real technology right now
and real legal dilemmas and this leads
to
what i think is the last ripple effect
that's important ethics I dove of this
now when you talk about robots and
ethics people say oh you mean awesome of
laws right
wrong there's three problems with
Asimov's Three loss
the first is their fiction how would you
program how would you turn Robuchon not
harm human
into a series of 0's and 1's not that
easy
the second problem is their fiction as a
mock created them
as plot devices and all of the stories
they try and follow the laws but end up
violating them as the poster for the
movie version put love I Robot put it
rules were made to be broken and then
the third problem
is were deliberately violating these
laws you don't give a robotic system
a .50-caliber machine gun or a Hellfire
missile if not to harm humans
that's kinda the point of it or I don't
want a system that takes
orders from any human like they would
under are some of los I don't wanna
robot to walk up to Osama bin Laden
and he can reprogram it easily enough
most importantly
is that that's a bit over misdirection
it's not the ethics
on the robots that matter it's the
ethics the people behind the robots that
matter
think about these questions what kinda
robot should we build what kinda
software should we design
work on actual future they have what
should we not
what organizations and individuals
should be allowed
2009 UC system's which one should be
prevented
what kind of training our licensing
should they be required to have
who is it ethical to take money from in
research and design
who was it not ethical to take money
from who should
own or be able to access the information
the unmanned systems are
always gathering about the world around
them who should be prevented from that
all these are innocence ethical
questions but they're also
legal questions because ethics without
accountability is empty
the problem here is this if you were a
young software programmer if you were a
young robot assist
you wouldn't have a code about six to
turn to for guidance and assistance
like you would for example what you were
doing medical research and the broader
field
has a challenge right now that it isn't
pushing is kinda ethical dialogues like
other cutting-edge fields are for
example the field
genetics is pushing discussions about it
impact on society
and most disappointing to me
wasn't email that I received after our
talk a lot like this
and I give a talk at an engineering
school and a professor chastise me in
the email for quote
troubling his students by quote asking
them to think about the ethics of their
work
so in ending
it sounds like I've been talking about
the future
but notice how every single picture you
saw
every single example I gave you was not
from the future technically
it was from the past the war and so it's
up to challenge
for all of us well before have to worry
about your room by sneaking up on you
its the fact that what is unveiling its
of right now
looks like science fiction feels like
science fiction
but it is already part OVR reality
and go back to those examples I gave you
have passed technologies
many of which came out in the realm of
science fiction whether it was
flying machines or the atomic bomb
which HG wells was the first one to
conceal up even gave the atomic bomb its
name
we didn't wrestle with the implications
the science fiction like technologies
until after the fact and so we kinda
laughed at the mistakes they made back
then
like having the person walk in front of
the automobile with a flag in firing of
where our future generations going to
laugh at us the same way
so unending what I'd like to do is
actually jumped into the realm of
science fiction for a sec
a couple years ago the AFI the American
Film Institute
did a survey up all the characters that
it
ever been in hollywood movie over the
last century have movies
and how to follow those characters which
ones represented
humanity at its best and which ones
represented
humanity at its worst that is which were
the top 100 hollywood heroes
and which were the top 100 Hollywood
villains
I've every single movie ever made only
one character
made it onto both less up top 100 heroes
in top 100 villains
the Terminator a robot killing machine
and to the point here is this it
illustrates the duality
a bar technology it can be used for both
good and evil
but I think it also do illustrates the
duality of us
the people behind the technology its
human creativity
that really is what distinguishes us
from all the other species
it's our human creativity that invented
fire
it's our human creativity that took our
species to the moon
its creativity that don't work so are
literature and architecture
to show our love and appreciation for
beauty and now we're using human
creativity
to build this incredible technology that
if you believe both the scientists and
the science fiction writers or
the Battlestar Galactica fans we may be
literally creating an entirely new
species
but if we're honest with ourselves
really doing it because we can't push
past
that age-old human need to fight one
another
and so the ending question on review is
this
is it the technology
or is it us that's wired for war thank
you