here comes a block away yes it is
welcome everyone hi everyone and
everyone out there in the break room
come on in it's the public policy
consultation I know people are
interested in pretzels and public policy
hopefully so yeah so we should
eventually get some people very good I'd
like to welcome everyone I'm going to do
a little introduction about what this
session is about and then we'll actually
start going through the discussion of
the open policy proposals amazing thank
you I thank the comic relief team okay
public policy consultation this is an
open discussion of the internet number
resource policy it's held by Aaron and
it facilitates in person and remote
participation we're going for both today
it may be held at our we hold them every
time we have a public poll every time we
have a public policy meeting we do a lot
of consultations but we also hold them
in other forums that we think are
relevant currently the only list that
we're willing to try this out right now
on is nanog and we've done one before
we're doing this one we think that this
is a good community to be at we think
the cross-pollination is helpful so I'll
give a couple of quick things with an
update on the current policies and then
we'll go through each of the draft
policies that are out there and this
includes the interim our transfer policy
proposal then a 3gp network IP resource
policy proposal the RIR principles
policy proposal and the lir isp end user
definition proposal welcome remote
participants do we have remote
participants yes okay there should be a
webcast like to thank the people for
whatever measures it took to get that
back up for this should be a live
transcript
it's someone else at the end of the
remote webcast whose transcript ting it
and putting it out there so be
understands a little leg but there is a
transcript downloading meeting material
file you can get online there's a chat
room which has an on record virtual
microphone and a hands up show of
support when we ask for sure with
support you can be counted okay the
chair in this case vice chair Paul
Anderson will moderate the discussions
of the actual draft policies so everyone
can speak and all can be heard please
state your name and affiliation each
time you're at the microphone please
comply with the courtesies that are in
the discussion guide if you're in the
room there is this handy-dandy
discussion guide if you didn't get one
as a bunch on the table over there but I
also see Susan passing them out very
good okay at the head table Paul
Anderson myself Kevin Bloomberg build
art who's our Java monitor Scott library
who's with the AC and John Sweeting is
the chair of the AC so John sweetings
gonna give the update on the AC council
activities all right good afternoon
everyone John sweetie and AC chair going
to give a quick quick update on Advisory
Council activities so as John said we
have four draft policies that will be
presented today what we're looking for
is feedback and input on whether you
think the policies are crafted correctly
and and what we can do to change them to
make them more effective and if n if you
support a more fee against it of course
we're always interested how many people
we can get supporting these policies we
also have two policy proposals although
it says newer items one isn't really a
newer item one is believed 182 einer
kind of changed his lines okay let me go
to the next okay so there's the draft
policies John already talked about these
we've got the inner rir transfers of a s
ends the 3gp network IP resource the RIR
principles which is the 2050 debate
that's going on on ppm ppm l right now
today with a with a lot of good
discussion hopefully we can keep it up
at a level of good discussion and keep
the the bad remarks out of there just
respect everybody on the list and put
your opinion out there and let other
people put their opinions out there
please and then the lir ISP and end-user
definitions oh so proposal 186 section
eight dot to real organizations this
proposal when the AC looked at it it
seemed that it really what didn't need
to be a policy draft up recommended
policy that had to go all the way
through the process so we posted it out
on PP ml and asked for input if there
was any objections to us handling this
as an editorial change to the Newark
tuden nurple and that period ended I
believe may 29th or 30th there were no
objections noted so the intent of the AC
is at our next call to vote to recommend
this to the board of trustees as an
editorial change to the nurple the the
real reason that that we believe that
was because Kris grundman who ended up
rewriting ate that too for a earlier
policy actually you know said oh i just
left that out by mistake his intent was
not to leave that word out so we're just
actually putting the word back in that
was there all along prior to that change
in that erin was still following that
guidance even today so that proposal
will most likely be eliminated once we
make that recommendation to the board
and then there's erin proposal 189
allocation of ipv4
and ipv6 address space to outer region
requesters that is an ongoing we just we
got it in like the day before our last
call so we couldn't do much with it at
our last call so it's still in the
proposal state and that's it I would
like to put in a good word for the AC
the AC does go out and support a lot of
community outreach functions the errand
on the road and several others and also
as you can see we're here supporting
this PPC here at nanog yes Lee my name
is Lee Howard from time warner cable
room i think you and i may have met once
right i think i see you some difference
I think he used an acronym that maybe
not everybody in the room is familiar
with I don't know if you spelled out
what nurp um means yeah I can I was
going to another resource polymer
resource policy meant I could it has
passed what John just whispered network
is it was there it is in touch
errands errands policies the other
actually but I also wanted to ask do you
want to is there is this an opportunity
for discussion of the proposals that you
just disgust or those not up for
discussion right now and you want to get
to the draft policies draft policies are
the priority for good ed so we're going
to go through them first ok thank you ok
I'm going to do the introduction for the
draft policies under the discussion the
first one we'll discuss is recommended
draft policy 2013 dash 1 this has been
recommended by the AC they found it
properly formed and it is a candidate
potentially to go to the Board of
Trustees after its or a go to last call
in preparation to go to the Board of
Trustees this is section 8.4 change in
Terraria our transfer for ASNs the
history
Rosalynn 2012the a sea Shepherd Scott
librarian of rob c strim was presented
at nanog 57 was promoted to recommend a
draft policy in 2013 it was presented at
Erin 31 in april 2013 at our barbados
meaning it's on the AC socket the text
is available and in the discussion guide
both online and in the discussion guide
staff summary would allow the transfer
of a SNS along with ipv4 address space
in an 8.4 in Terraria transfer it
applies all the same criteria current
listed for ipv4 to a SNS no similar
proposals or discussions that's
something that we considered is without
similar proposals or discussions this
requires a matching policy proposal at
the receiving rir because it's an inter
rer transfer policy so we're if this was
adopted it would be one hand there need
to be some other are I are doing
something else I don't know how much of
a priority is one way or the other and
the other rirs staff legal assessment
the policies clear and can be
implemented as written it would be a
minimal resource impact and it poses no
particular legal issues previous
discussions very little communication on
this or conversation no posts for or
against on the public policy mailing
list and with 102 people in the room we
had seven in favor and eight against a
Terran 31 and when asked should the AC
work on this eight and favor 12 against
so it's a fairly lukewarm policy no one
particularly loves it or hates it from
what we can determine and I'm going to
now turn it over to Scott to do the AC
presentation program okay apparently i
get a cue alright so this policy
proposal is quite simple SNS are already
transferable within the region not
transferable out of region so this would
allow that if another AR AR or
interested in doing so
the benefits of doing that obviously i
delay SN resources could be recovered
and used the registry can be updated
when a SNS are transferred because of
business needs of various sorts when
when many of the actual use cases that
we've seen so far are not people selling
addresses to someone else there oh I'm
using this address in this other place
for this other reason and I need to
update the records and a 8-3 transfer
has been the easiest way to do that in a
lot of cases so this would allow if
another region participated in a dot
poor transfer to do similar things and
it allows for some parity between the
policies for in region in inter region
most of the folks who have spoken out
against this have done so on the basis
that this isn't really necessary for
several reasons one might be that they
don't think that SN transfers were
necessary to begin with another might be
that there simply is no shortage of them
and as John already mentioned without a
similar transfer policy allowing that in
another region there is simply nothing
that this policy proposal does in that
situation so our questions as the AC to
you as the community are is this
necessary and useful and should we move
this forward or abandon it as you saw on
the previous slides we had some lukewarm
response from the community because most
of the folks who spoke up in favor of
this policy proposal were from the nanog
community I felt it was important to
bring it back here and hear from you
guys if you really think this needs to
move forward I'd like to hear from you
guys at the mic and or with your hands
up when we asked the question in the
absence of any interest then I'd like to
hear people opinion on whether we should
just go ahead and abandon this as
unnecessary so one way or the other I'd
like to get your input as to whether we
can make a decision here
thank you Scott so as pointed out this
is the audience participation portion so
if you have any comments or questions on
this proposal again as Scott stated
we're really struggling because we're
just not getting a lot of support so if
you could stand up now if you're in the
room and come up and say state your name
your affiliation and whether you support
her do not support this policy here let
me model that behavior Lee Howard Time
Warner Cable opposed mildly I don't
think it's necessary I don't I don't
know that it's useful but I did want to
ask a question because I believe that
this would modify or be affected section
eight dot for right of the policy manual
so there's specified transferring
ar-ar-ar transfers which says that the
who they take may only take place via so
maybe take place only by our ours who
agree to the transfer and share
reciprocal compatible needs based policy
do we have needs based policy for a SNS
you have to demonstrate that you need an
asn is that correct and do other rirs
also have needs-based sm policies mr.
Kern um so recognize that that we don't
preemptively mail people postcards with
random a ascends on them they have to
actually say they want one that for
purposes of a SN is saying you have need
and it's the same in the other area so
we recognize such as a need space policy
the level of rigor varies by our iron
some rirs you actually have to say I'm
tending towards multi-homing or some
equivalent statement and so it is not
necessarily HR ir determines what is
appropriate there though can I infer
that you would read the other rirs needs
based policies as compatible when
another rir passes a policy or proposes
one that's similar I will stand in their
form and tell them whether it's
compatible or not which I've done for
all the entire policy so far so okay
but no I can't preempt that I even less
useful right thank you others that have
a view on this policy ask you to
approach the mic or we also of course
have remote participation so please feel
free to start typing madly if you would
like to ask have a question right here
by our jabber monitor yeah John go ahead
and lead I wasn't trying to be flippant
but i wanted to be very clear right now
the current asn policies of the other
other IRS may or may not be need-based
at all to mean it that the level of need
is hard to discern it varies by rir
someone while proposing a policy for in
Terraria are transferring another are
might say for purposes of transfer is
the need based test just like in the
right region they may eliminate need
assessment for ipv4 as a general thing
in their policy manual that doesn't
preclude someone introducing one a
policy that introduces needs assessment
simply for transfers so we really need
to see the specific policy proposal
before can comment other comments or
feedback on this proposal again we're
we're really struggling when you
feedback as useful even if just to come
up and say you're in support or against
center microphone stacy hughes TW
telecom i will vote to abandon this as
an AC member because it's irrelevant
thank you thank you for that feedback if
we don't see in any other people
approaching the mic and any jabber
comments yet we have one queuing up Jeff
handle Louisiana State University i'm
very new to this space so well got a SNS
were unique in global why do why are we
talking about transferring from one R&R
to another John um and I have no view
and I mean I'm the staff I have no view
in favor opposed whatever you decide
folks decide makes sense we do have
cases where people may have a business
unit that's moved to another location or
they may
have some sort of change that they've
gone through and they find themselves
able to update the records for ipv4 but
they may not be able to indicate that
that business is now in another region
in another rir for example because our
policies say once it's assigned to you
you can use it or you're going to turn
in it we don't recognize and we do
recognize transfers within the Erin
region even though someone can come get
a new asn why would you transfer one you
want to update the records accordingly
because it's been moved to a new
business so if it's moved to new
business in another region that
presently is no way to officially
recognize that it's left the building
does that make sense I'm not sure if
that use case comes up very often but it
is a possible use case fajr rear
microphone yeah Jared watch NTT if I
want to update a record and provide you
a valid address and it's not in your
region will you update it even if it's
the correct address so the organization
if the organization is in the Erin
region then you saying you're changing
the organization record to reflect its
now out of region because the
organization moved maybe my mailing
address is out of region we've had that
happen I mean we there's no invocation
there's no enforcement of that per se
but there are people who want to reflect
the fact that the business is broken up
into pieces they're still here but that
piece is now in another agent go ahead
okay so I think what it sounds like is
that this proposal may not be necessary
because you will update the records
based on the resource the request of the
person for whom the resources have been
allocated to even if they're outside of
the region
right Kevin Bloomberg so one thing I
wanted to clarify each region was given
blocks of AAS numbers so that's why you
get nice to be done I believe that was
part of the intent of your original
question I believe one of the benefits
of this is to allow both IP space and
asn numbers to be transferred at the
same time through 8.4 whereas right now
what you would need to do is an 8.4
transfer of the of the AAS number sorry
of the IP numbers and not be able to
transfer the AAS number but probably use
it but not necessarily know where it's
actually being used so if you know I
don't know if you can do an eight point
to transfer out of region which would be
a merger and acquisition so if you're
selling from one unit to another you
couldn't necessarily do it out of region
so this would allow for some out of
region both you know basically transfers
and sales no just John I want to clarify
because I guess the previous question
was about maybe the policy is rough not
relevant because he was talking more
about address update but this policy
would also allow to transfer to another
organization all together correct we
would not do without this policy right
of region president I in region but not
out of region presently a party could
say I have more IP addresses that i need
i'm transferring these numbers for
parting an AP Nick that has a reciprocal
party with it with Aaron and you could
transfer ipv4 addresses if you then said
I also have 5a s numbers and I'm I want
to get rid of two of them and I'm going
to sell them to the same unit over there
in in asia-pacific region we would say
that's not possible we literally will
not allow that transfer now you could
you could they could use them we don't
enforce routing but if you actually
wanted to sell the a SS that's not
actually possible per policy thank you
for that to clarify rear Mike Jeremy
Schmeichel from my BBS so basically from
the way I'm understanding of this policy
is one of the main use cases I guess
from what I understand is if say my
business is located here in the United
States and its purchase
by a larger company or larger entity
that happens to exist in another AR AR
and you know the v4 address obviously
could be transferred under this policy
but I would have to apply for a new
autonomous system number if let's say
all the resources were moved however if
I still have a network footprint here
the majority of the network flip earnest
here in the Aaron region would even if
the company lived in another rir or say
like the mailing address for instance
was in another AR AR could we
technically keep the autonomous system
number without any issue could you
repeat that last question that last
sentence if the majority of the network
footprint is still located within the
air in region even if the company let's
say corporate headquarters is in another
AR AR is that is that an issue no that
happens today quite a bit actually
that's what that's what I thought so in
my personal opinion I don't know that
this is entirely necessary at this point
I was gonna say are you in favor against
turn no opinion opposed at this point
opposed thank you next question hi Amy
Potter Hilco streambank I just have one
sort of hypothetical situation that may
be okay about maybe you won't um
bankruptcy estates that are selling
their IP addresses via inner rir
transfer if they also have AE essence if
as faulty doesn't exist then those daya
sins are sort of left in this in the
green space I don't know if you care
about that if they're enough that that's
not an issue then maybe not necessary to
have this so as a point of clarity my
understanding of policy today in a case
that you spoke that they would be able
to transfer it to other organizations
within the region and what this policy
if passed would allow them now to be
transferred to other regions with like
pulse similar policies presently that
can only be accomplished within the
region and so if you try to transfer it
to a party unrelated outside the region
we would not allow it we would say you
literally cannot sell your i guess so i
would sit in that situation you would
you'd be left with a sm
just I'm sorry could you speak slowly
and clearly sorry i would say that in
that situation if you ended up selling
your addresses to someone in the
asia-pacific region and the bankruptcy
estate still had several ASNs they would
sort of be wasted just ending up in
never-never land well there is no one's
gonna I'm not as a broker I'm not going
to go through the trouble of finding
someone to transfer just a sense too
because there's not a lot of value in
that brass so you're just gonna end up
with these essence that don't go
anywhere I don't know if you care about
that so I think I've understand your
comment you're just reinforcing and I
think that was one of the reasons this
policy was proposed by the original
proposer way back is that there's an
inconsistency in the current specified
transfer and that it covers v4 resources
but did not cover ESS for inter ir yeah
yeah basically i mean i'm just saying
that there's a hypothetical scenario
where you might end up with all sorts of
a SMS that don't belong to anyone and
right with the circumstance that happens
is that the receiving party it doesn't
get the they remain with the
original register on that can cause all
sorts of interesting issues several
years later if it turns out the original
register doesn't care the party that's
the recipients using them anyway the
databases don't reflect that so i don't
think we have a lot of demand for for
our fur asn transfers but we said the
same thing within the region and we've
had half a dozen of them occur so there
are people who make use of these
policies hard to tell who and when and
for what it's worth I've had people
approach me trying to get essence so
then I would take it that you're in
favor the policy is written I'm just
playing devil's advocate I'm not sure
that's really necessary if there are
enough essence out there that there's
not like a shortage issue okay thank you
other questions or comments before i
close the microphones both remotely and
here in the room this is your last call
bills there anyone feverishly typing
so going up my supposed to mikes after
this comment go ahead sir Derek Waldrop
integrated broadband I believe
inherently that the ASNs don't really
hold much value and that it just seems
more likely that they would be removed
most of the purchaser v4 addresses from
a different region you know that's
what's the value to you know I would
think and that they already most likely
have their own autonomous system and so
I'm opposed to the transfer i think it
would be more cleanly for them just
basically return and then in some case
that they needed one just apply for a
new one within their own region okay so
you're not in favor okay so we will now
the question I would ask is where the
again the audience participation time
I'd ask those a remote and in the room
I'm going to ask a question of whether
or not you support moving this policy
forward this will be advice provided to
the Advisory Council so I would ask for
all those in the room who are in favor
of moving this proposal forward to
please raise your hand nice and high
anyone who can hear my voice is allowed
to put their hand up and our counters
will count I think I think I got it
there's also the remote obviously and
those that are opposed to moving this
forward
please keep them up until I ask
are they able to put their hands down
there Susan okay you can put your hands
down I don't suppose for the sound is it
possible to get the mics and thing a
little bit more in the front it's just
hard to hear some of the questions I
don't know ok just a moment I'm waiting
for the envelope
Thank You Susan on the matter of policy
2013 one in Terraria Ras n transfers
regarding moving it forward in favor
zero against 12 those in the room and
remote 51 this input will be provided to
the air and advisory council right now
for their consideration thank you
everyone John ok going to move right
ahead and next up is policy Rob 2013
dash 2 which is the 3gpp network IP
resource policy it originated in March
of this year Scott librarian and rs of
the Shepherd's Robert seized from it was
presented at iron 31 in Barbados and
there was discussion it would lower the
utilization threshold for additional
ipv4 allocations for the 3gpp networks
there's no similar proposals or
discussions at other rirs it was it's
still in development by the AC so we'll
perform when they told us it's ready to
be reviewed and now I will invite Scott
who's coming up for this one or Scott I
will invite Scott up I ask the people
when they come to the mic speak slowly
and clearly somewhere out there on the
end of a webcast someone is doing a
transcription think of that person when
you speak okay so i always like really
slowly and clearly something to keep
that up you
so I'm back this one is a little bit
less simple the original problem
statement here in summary of the
original proposal was that there is at
least one mobile network operator that
is having some trouble getting enough
global unique addresses for their needs
so someone from that operator put
together a policy proposal to help
address that issue and that this policy
proposal would basically relax the
eighty percent requirement in certain
situations that would allow for well
I'll get into that in this next slide so
they're using a number of non ra are
assigned address blocks internally to
provide addressing two handsets behind
their Nats RFC 1918 is not large enough
for some of these large networks RFC 65
98 the / 10 doesn't help either so they
have a number of otherwise unrounded
blocks that they have been using
historically as that space is brought
back into service via returns
Reclamation's transfers etc it becomes
problematic to have those numbers also
being used on the inside of a large
mobile network so they have been going
through the effort of remembering into
global a unique space that requires some
addresses from Aaron to do so the there
are some technical details that the
author provided about the way their
network architecture works which I have
in an appendix and we could talk about
if anybody really wants to we talked
about those fairly extensively at Aaron
31 but basically what it comes down to
is there failover architecture it
requires what's essentially fifty
percent utilization in that one region
needs to be able to pick up for another
region if
is an outage so that conflicts with the
eighty percent utilization requirement
in the current policy so we did discuss
this at Erin 31 in Barbados there were a
number of folks who felt this problem
was very specific to a single customers
needs and was not more general one of
the questions that we brought to the
community was is this a problem for more
networks there were some folks that felt
that this was a broader problem not
necessarily for mobile networks that
have similar architectures but just more
generally there are other networks that
for various reasons it might be useful
to apply a policy that's slightly more
relaxed others felt that there was we
needed more information to really know
if this was a problem so obviously if we
do address this issue it does fix the
problem for at least one mobile network
operator and probably other operators as
well it will allow them to reduce
excessive use of NAT and address
conflicts obviously making it easier to
get ipv4 addresses if we're able to do
so through the policy cycle before well
they're still here is going to
accelerate ipv4 depletion it's unclear
as to whether as to how many networks
this policy proposal would apply to and
help it's also unclear as to whether
this is the appropriate solution or if
there's a architectural or technology
fix that could be applied and of course
there are deck tears so I wanted to
highlight some of what I thought were
the important discussion points that we
should talk about here one is the very
obvious one is this an important enough
problem to solve the feedback at Erin 31
was somewhat equivocal on that and I
think what it comes down to is are we
going to have a broad enough solution
that it's going to apply to other
networks I think there are a number of
approaches to solving it one of which
does exactly that which would be to
broaden the residential market area
section of the policy manual to cover
existing devices as well as what it
currently covers
our homes this is the portion of the
policy manual which I recommend you to
pull out and read or i can bring it up
on the slide that basically says for
residential ISPs that are serving a
number of homes in a region and have to
assign addresses to their equipment they
can assign those based on the number of
homes served by their infrastructure
whether or not those homes are actually
currently using their IP services so
this is classic cable policy the
approach that the author was wanting to
take in his original version of this
policy proposal i think is to do exactly
this to cover folks who have devices
many of which are feature phones or
smartphones that may not happen to be
using an address at a given moment but
if those devices are present on the
network that they would be able to apply
the same sort of fifty to eighty percent
utilization ratio that the cable
networks can apply so that would be one
approach to solving this problem there
may be others we're still interested in
feedback from folks who may have ideas
and we're also interested in the
question of whether we should move this
forward or abandon it so this is the
existing in RPM text which is also in
your discussion guide and then I think
I'll leaf the leaf this on a slightly
modified version of that which would
possibly address this and then I'll hand
it over to Paul so I think is a I shall
go back if I can find it I'd ask if
anybody has comments on this proposal I
think the most the first point is this a
problem that the AC should spend time
trying to solve and if you have a view
on the approach that would be useful and
I think this is one that we definitely
need some discussion on so don't all
rush up at once there's only three
Mike's I know you guard much from NTT
you won the race go ahead sir perfect
this this seems like a provider having
very short range
in how to architect their network coming
to Aaron and asking them to change
policy to work around their own
brokenness and I do not think that this
is something that we should encourage
people to do and therefore I do not
support this not supported so first if I
may I gonna let Scott respond if you'd
like no okay that's why and second thank
you very much the some people that is so
much better here on stage to hear I
appreciate that next speaker Jeremy
Schmeichel from integrated broadband um
agree with the previous sense of and I
believe that especially since this
happens to be one mobile provider that
was mentioned I'm sure there are more
that are impacted it concerns me that
we're looking at changing the policy for
everyone just to fix you know one
person's issue especially when we're
already so close to the end of the line
for IP version 4 as it stands today I
think that you know the eighty to ninety
percent number yeah that that's probably
you know pretty fair i like that
suggestion there but instead in turn we
should be you know pushing these
multiple providers and the people that
work with the mobile networks that are
having issues you know as Lee you know
presented earlier Android and Apple that
do not have ipv6 support yet properly at
this time it really does need to be
rolled out in order to not necessarily
fix the problem because we all know that
dual stack is the way to go and it
doesn't even you know fix everything but
you know I think it would help alleviate
some of the issues so as it stands today
due to this being such a small focused
problem I don't know that it's
necessarily a good way to proceed so
opposed I'm opposed to yeah thank you
sir next speaker or on kamari Google oh
and probably what's the first I actually
agree with Jared so I take it you're
posed yes it's all right love thee let
it be recorded he's opposed I'm a picker
yeah my pound said to Phileas they I
like mostly to this i'm i'm opposed
because i don't see the point in doing
something like this first to bring up
the the cable subscribers issue that
that was done for a a specific case
where we had a segment of the the
industry that had no come
troll over its own architecture and we
did that fruit because income incumbents
were forcing other organizations into
the incumbent architecture and it was
the others that we were trying to solve
a problem for just because you give me
the questioning look there we were
trying to solve a problem for people
there who didn't have control over their
own architecture these positions do have
control over their architecture you know
that they can find a better way to solve
this problem I think so opposed yes next
speaker Lee Howard Time Warner Cable um
but you know it's great not being
subscribed at ppl because I can come
here and talk about policies and and
it's I'd forgotten how much fun it is to
the point sir to the point oh thank you
the I was struggling to read the
discussion in the discussion guide or on
the slides for some specification of
which version of IP we're talking about
it seems to me there are trillions of
addresses available IP address available
and I can't figure out what the problem
is mr. Lai brand I think he needs
clarification proves that we intended to
apply this type ev3 okay well I'm going
to take Lee that you were also opposed
to this policy if there's anybody who
would like to speak in favor of the
policy I'd ask you to approach a
microphone now or start typing so that
build art can echo your words here in
the room Kevin Bloomberg Kevin Bloomberg
I'm gonna be speaking on behalf of the
wire which is my company who dates back
to the dial-up days and you know to me
this is a dial-up problem in some
respects they would like to have one IP
for their customer and one IP for that
failover node for that customer as well
give them two smartphones whatever the
case may be it's not a well architected
concept and my concern is that it is
going to bleed out I don't really care
about the ipv4 run out that's going to
happen
but this is going to be an issue we
always have to look at it now in the
post run out as well and this will be a
bleed in the post run out it's a
completely inefficient use and I would
have loved for more providers to have
come up and I have not seen those
providers come up and say this is an
issue so you're opposed your post this
is a a call to close the mics I would if
there was somebody would like to speak
in favor I would urge them to come
forward he or she to come forward now
are you approaching a mic server finding
a seat seat got it anything on the
remote sorry we'll close the mics if
there are no further questions or
comments seeing none we'll close the
microphones we are now again just if you
can raise your head for me you know for
just a moment and just participate in
this one question the only question I'm
going to start off with is basically
does this community feel this is an
important problem to try and solve if
you believe is a problem we're solving
I'd ask that you raise your hand now and
of course participate remotely I think
once again I can assist the counter on
that one that's got it got it you can
put your hand down if you r do not think
this is a problem that the AC should
spend time on solving I'd ask that you
raise your hand now please keep it
helped just for a moment
again if your remote please signify your
Pole now you may lower your hands now
thank you just a moment the last errand
update John was between you everyone in
coffee on between you and beer I think I
got the short end of the stick on this
one
Thank You Susan on the question of
whether this is a matter of which the
advisory on on 2013 to 3gpp network IP
resource policy is this a problem that
the Advisory Council should solve zero
in favor 19 against 51 people
participating this feedback has been
provided to the Advisory Council for
their consideration thank you John okay
I'm going to continue moving right along
okay draft policy 2013 dash for our our
principles it originated just a couple
of months ago Aaron proposition 187 the
Shepherd's are crisp randleman Kathy
aronson and I went along it was adopted
it was made draft policy in April the
text is online in your discussion guide
it hasn't yet been discussed this is the
first real chance to discuss it in a
policy forum from the problem statement
the guiding principles of stewardship
are not currently being carried into RFC
2050 biz for background RC 2050 which is
a 15-year old fountain foundational
document of the RIR system is being
updated in the IETF that foundational
document has some goals in it and it
also has some allocation policy from 15
years ago in the revision of it the
goals have been revised and the
allocation policy which is 15 years old
and and replaced by the RIR system per
se is means that when we look at the new
document that maybe concepts that people
believe should still be followed by the
rirs and in particular by Aaron that
aren't in the revised RFC 2050 biz so
the policy proposal takes the the
principles that are perceived as missing
and suggests that they go into the
number resource policy manual no similar
proposals or discussions that other AR
AR
first legal staff assessment still being
developed by the AC so we haven't done
one yet and I'm going to now turn it
over to build dark who will give the
presentation from the EC thank you thank
you all build art here so I'm not one of
the shepherds for this policy nor am I
the author Jason chiller was the author
of this Chris grundman was planning to
present today but had to leave meeting
so I'm standing instead the original
text as John said of RC 2050 described
the registry system for the distribution
of globally unique internet addresses
and rules and guidelines and principles
for those distributions of number
resources that current work that John
referenced has left some of those
principal terms out at this stage of its
development and so in Barbados at at our
last public policy a meeting there was a
suggestion that perhaps there ought to
be a policy that recodified or
reintroduce those concepts in into the
number resource policy manual of Aaron
so that's what it intends to do to
express those same principles that were
codified or expressed in 2050 into the
NR p.m. specifically it would create a I
mean at this stage of the process by the
way at this stage of the process were in
discussion only that's what a draft
policy does is help us make sure that we
have a clear policy statement so the
principles and goals of the internet
registry section zeroed would be
included in the NR p.m. efficient
utilization based on me
that covering the principle of
conservation that was in 2050 with a sub
a bullet of documented justified needs
that there is needs basis for allocation
and assignment of number resources that
there would be support for hierarchical
aggregation that again supporting the
2050 goal of route ability and
uniqueness through a registration
process again and all of this is wrapped
up in a concluding statement about
stewardship this is what stewardship
means so that is what would be included
new in the number resource policy manual
if this policy proposal this draft
policy were to mature gain support in
the community so according to Aaron's
public policy or excuse me policy
development process we're at this point
of trying to assess whether there's
community support or not for moving this
specific proposal or or or not or
something different forward or not the
crux of our need as with the other
presentations you've heard today is to
get your support or your comments
whether you support introducing this
language so that everything I mean
basically the NR p.m. the number
resource policy manual has been founded
upon these principles in the past
everything that we do in the way of
allocation policy you know has been
predicated on these things but if a
policy like this similar to this if
language is not introduced into the
policy manual then the authors and
others in support of this so far have
said then there will be no place to
point we won't be able to point back to
ooh 2050 because it will be updated
there would be no place to point and say
that our processes and policies are all
founded in these principles so that's
the whole point of this so any
discussion that you would have upon
whether these kinds of principles that
were originally expressed in 2050 should
be expressed in the current public our
number resource policy manual I will say
that the discussion that's been on the
list and there's been some hot
discussion on the list a lot of that
discussion has been around whether there
is a needs basis anymore whether there
ever was a needs basis in the past I
think you know there is a lot of
discussion that is tangential to this to
the point of are these principles still
the principles that we operate by and
should they be expressed somewhere we
can point to those foundational
principles when people ask us how we run
errand and make policy and allocate
number of resources thank you Bill thank
you again for standing in for Chris on
short notice as well again this is as a
bill pointed out it's earth this
policies earlier in the process so the
AC is just looking for feedback on how
to move forward with it and fall so as
always I would ask you to not as you
have previously rushed to the
microphones just take your time don't
then I'm can I make it first you did you
may go first there as long as you member
state your name and affiliation yeah
Matt pound said Phileas yeah i agree i
think that these are definitely the
general principles we've operated on and
they should continue to be i think it's
probably more important
post run out when we're trying to deal
with transfers and things like that when
it's that much harder to get address
space it's that much more important that
that eats basis and things like that be
maintained so yeah I think it's a good
idea to do this thank you hello Matt
Matt if you could come back John had a
question for you can I ask a question um
because this is being predicated on the
change from 2050 to 2050 biss and that
change there's goals in 2050 and there's
goals and 2050 bits the language that's
in this policy proposal is not just the
goals what's called principles in here
but as actual allocation policy from
2050 and I guess have you looked at 2050
bits to see what more since that's
what's causing this change have you
looked at the differences between the
two I have not done a comparison of the
two RFC's now okay that's what I was
curious I assume you have though
disclaimer I am one of the co-authors of
RFC 2050 bits and I'm familiar with it
yes other comments or questions Scott
Scott ly brend Aaron AC so having
watched a lot of the discussion and read
over just the gold section not the rest
of 2050 biss I am a little bit skeptical
that what we have in this initial draft
of the policy proposal is the type of
thing that is really necessary let me
rephrase that the goals in 2050 bits I
think capture most of what he is
captured here I think what's left is
more a description of current allocation
policy than it is a statement of
high-level principles there probably are
a couple of higher-level principles that
we don't have global consensus for any
longer because of the the move away from
complete ly needs based policy in the
face of ipv4 run out that might still be
relevant for another year or so in the
end region but i'm not sure that those
are things that we want to codify in the
way that this policy proposal seeks to
do so i am approaching this skeptically
i think the the general approach of this
may have some merit but as evidenced by
the heated discussions on PP ml and
other things i'm not sure that we're
there yet so i would encourage everyone
to go back and reread all of the
relevant documents and start thinking
about ways that we can actually do what
I would call a gap analysis and find
what actually is left that still needs
to be described and then have a
discussion about what whether there's
actually consensus on those gaps because
I see a lot of the areas that are not
described in 2050 being the contentious
ones and I'm not sure that we have a
community consensus on what those should
be so I'll be interested to see how that
plays out and I'm looking forward to a
lot of editing and discussion on this
one I don't think it's ready yet so
skeptically a support over the direction
a I am skeptical of the current text and
we'll see where it goes from there okay
other comments that would be useful to
the AC we're again on this one I would
think that we will probably just pass on
the verbal comments and not take a show
since its new and seeing none in the
room I'll just check with mr. Dorrit if
closing the mics three two one closed
thank you very much we'll provide that
input to the AC thank you okay thank you
and coming up on draft policy 2013 dash
five lir ISP and end-user definitions so
back in May this was submitted the AC
Shepherds Kevin Bloomberg Owen DeLong
and drum spre draft policy was adopted
as a draft policy of the AC meaning it
was understood what it was trying to
solve the text is online and in your
discussion guide it updates the
definition of LIR ISP and end-user
there's no similar proposals or
discussions and the other regions it is
still under development so we haven't
done a staff legal assessment on it and
I'll turn it over to Kevin I presume to
do the AC presentation back forward so
here are the current definitions of what
in li RS or an ISP and I are that
primarily assigns address space the
users of the network services that it
provides Li are generally Internet
service providers end users and end-user
and is an organization receiving
assignments of IP address spaces
exclusively for use in its operational
networks now the draft policy is trying
to help define what an Internet service
provider is and this is what I really I
wanted to talk about isp the word isp
the word lir the meaning has changed
over the last 15 years and so the
question is does this change that we
have here actually change anything or
does it just make a couple words look
nicer and not solve what the original
issue was so I'm going to go over that
in Barbados which was actually cooler
than it is in New Orleans right now the
we had a staff report that was done that
brought up this issue there is no term
is P in our in our
newer technologies don't necessarily fit
into the word is P it's kind of hard to
define what an end user is or who an ISP
is and what really the crux of it is is
we have policy shopping so what's gone
on is over the last three to four years
an end user is still at 12 months an end
user has a / 24 is their minimum for
multi-homing requirements they have a
much simpler time of it because quite
frankly and users are smaller there are
less of them they don't come back very
often they have simpler needs they don't
have to assign to their customers as an
example and what has happened in the
inverse is that ISPs in the ISP
definition have gone from 12 months to 3
months and we're running we're going in
to run out things are getting more
difficult so by having a very vague
definition which has worked for many
years it allows people to say no I'm an
end-user but you're giving it to your
customers to use but based on the
definition I'm an end user and what this
what we're looking for or what I believe
the author is looking for in this policy
is to help clarify so that there is less
ambiguity for staff and for the
community as to what is an end user and
what is an ISP now we could do it one of
two ways we could try to define what an
ISP is and I've having spent enough time
at nanog I would be very interested if
we had 50 opinions on 20 people in one
isp is but the question is for the
community as I see it is what is an end
user can we define end user and leave
the rest to the other category would
that be acceptable that's one question
opposed to close to the group the other
question is if we do this we're going to
be making some subtle changes to what
people have expected for many years web
hosting company potentially that might
have been fine in the end user policy
might not anymore they might have to be
in the ISP and vice versa so the the bar
will move will shift and what might have
been one way will now be a little
different and this will be both in again
our current scenario and down the road
that will have an effect on the the
transfer markets as etc so i guess i'm
going to open this up to the floor
because really what we're looking for at
this stage is as much feedback as we can
get at what the easiest way of and what
the community wants in this area is
thank you Kevin I think it's also worth
pointing out you know this definition
not not all sit only affects the policy
under which an organization would under
but also affects fees because we do
charge different fees there and whether
you are an end user or a lower isp so we
posed that there some questions here
opposed I'd ask again if you could
rapidly approach the microphone since
this is our last proposal so we might be
able to wrap a bit early and Jeff handle
Louisiana State University I thought
into the category of I don't know what I
am I'm a university assign IP addresses
I have a lot of users but in your eyes
and my am I an ISP or mine end user yes
may it depends on the day so hold on one
second you're an end user right now okay
if you ask me you we would say that your
registration is an end user you pay
lower fees than I asp's by the way for
very very very similar services it is
also true that there are some criteria
that are different for end-users and
ISPs for obtaining initial and new
allocations as we get towards the run
out of ipv4 in the pool people will self
select which criteria is most favorable
to them and that's fine as long as the
community expects that to be happening
it's also true that someone who can't
get additional space could be asserting
to iron
my business model has changed by pure
coincidence you happen to be running out
of this fête dress space but my
business model happens to change and now
i'm no longer an ISP so can I have some
more numbers and so we have the question
of someone claiming do we worry about
that or do they self declare which they
are got it does that clarify it a bit
more any feedback on the questions that
are posed or actually I do think this
would be worth clearing up to see what
you are especially ask me as a
university thank you right sir jeremy
Schmeichel from integrative broadband
you know in my industry I actually we
work with you know a couple hundred to
two and three cable MSOs you know
throughout the air and footprint and me
the way that the policies written as I
read it you know currently it's
basically defining an end user as
someone who doesn't let's say I'm
assuming you're meeting us and slipping
certain amounts of address space to
subscribers and behind your network is
that correct as I understand it you're
saying the current definition of isp
sorry not the current the proposed
whatever it is a little proposed god yes
that's a pretty good summary okay I was
just making sure so let's say that I'm a
cable is P and you know I get an
allocation from Aaron and all of my
address space is simply be hcp to the
cable customers in behind me and I don't
have to swim any address space would I
then be an end user John how would you
interpret that under the under the
proposed policy great if all you did was
provide Internet services and st.
Andrew's an organization receiving
assignments few cents at work and does
not register anyway assignments so so if
you do not register any reassignments
then you're an end user okay now it just
was wanting clarification on a thing
right I think actually I had Scott did
you a question or you okay for Mike
Garrett much ntt though the one thing
that I noticed is that in this booklet
that I was
handed and thanks and thanks to the
staff who put that together by the way
they do a lot of work to provide in
section 2 you have a definition section
yes we do you do you intend to define
what is P is as an acronym that you use
throughout as you do similar acronyms
here as part of this because I don't see
the bootstrap problem right yes I think
that is a good takeaway for the AC to
decide if they need to pay for I think
it's a good point out oh I'll see if I
can address that the acronym is P
expands to internet service provider
that's in the text of the new 2.4 yeah
it is right before sure I understand
that but I think the question is
defining the end user sites the
university who's not quite sure are
there in isp because they may have
departments or other people they may sub
assign things to and what not would it
be valuable to put that there and it's
it's a question that I don't feel needs
to be answered but it's just a question
of whether or not it makes sense to
enumerate that further to provide
clarity so people don't try and drive
trucks through holes I when I ask a
question that make sure I understand the
proposed text functionally defines the
difference between an ISP and land user
you're suggesting enumerated certain
types of organizations are one versus
the other you're suggesting a ISP
includes a university universities are
ISPs and community colleges are ISPs I'm
suggesting that through the community
feedback process you it may be valuable
if you further document that and and
what I'm saying is that someone would
need to suggest text as to what
organizations end up in that enumeration
sure thank you over to Kevin Bloomberg
first so just a quick question sorry you
sat down is it easier to define ISP or
is it easier to define to end user
because my concern is that is P is a
very long term moving target that we've
seen some I guess my question for you is
is end user and easier
term to define then ISP or the six of
one half dozen of another thank you
Kevin next Mike Matt pound said Phileas
I think that if an organization that
provides internet access is not defined
as an ISP under this text that Miss text
is broken and so in other words the
interpretation that John gave earlier
you feel is suggest the text is broken
yes so okay I would agree with you I did
not intend for msos to be classified as
end users by the way Scott library and
Aaron AC author of this text um simple
in full disclosure so my first off as
mentioned in the policy text rational
whatever it is my organization is
neither an ISP nor an end-user by strict
reading of the current text because we
are not primarily providing internet
access and we are not exclusively doing
it to our own equipment where some of
both I think it's important to clear up
that I'm neither thing I think it's
important to tighten up these
definitions a little bit I do not think
it is important to lock down every
single possible edge case as either one
or the other while there well Aaron
staff likes to have things cut and dried
in policy so that they can do their job
more easily I am inclined to put more
work on them when it benefits the
community and I think having policy that
is a little bit flexible in this
situation might be good now in in the
well-known innumerable cases like
universities msos I think the text
should go ahead and be clear enough to
make it unambiguous what those are but
for some new cloud type service that is
sort of like an ISP and sort of like an
end user I'm not personally opposed to
having them be able to choose which
policy applies to them and if the
policies are so different that
everyone's
was making the wrong choice by some
definition then perhaps we need to look
at that distinction and tighten that up
but that's kind of where I was thinking
as when I wrote this text I think it
does need to be tightened up a little
bit but I would like to hear feedback
from the community as to whether you
think we need to explicitly define
everything or whether it's okay to leave
some ambiguity in here I think I've
heard a lot of yeah we should work on
this steps so I think wow it's valid to
hear the community I think it's as it
was pointed out earlier in the
presentation you know I think this
proposal came out of a staff report
that's given it each one of our regular
Erin means that staff have had struggled
with this so I think if staff are
struggling I think it behooves us to
discuss it because that means they're
having a problem doing it and their job
is to execute the policy that you know
the errant the community passes I
believe the farm like was just like John
did you have to add something my
apologies um so actually we can do
whatever the community wants and so if
you want loose definitions those are
great and those work fine if you have
two very clear definitions that says the
world is made up of a and B but you've
defined a and B very tightly you may
find out there's a lot of sees that
don't qualify for a or b so you need to
decide the philosophy here okay if it's
that they can choose then it's pretty
easy to have some light definitions of
either we don't really care they can
choose if it's that you want a hard line
to either be qualified as an end user or
to be qualified as an ISP that also
works as long as there's only one hard
line that we're enforcing if we try to
enforce too hard lines we actually end
up with organizations that are a or b or
i don't mean either and that's the
problem you face so the philosophy of
what the community wants is very
important before you decide which
definition structure you want to have
far Mike first it was just a quick
comment Jeremy Schmeichel from
integrator brought man I didn't mean to
necessarily introduce a loophole it's
just you know dude
the work that I do I work on behalf of
several you know cable MSOs that are
smaller and so that is the first thing
that springs to mind it's I want to make
sure that we have a clear definition to
a certain extent obviously because we
don't need to introduce all the Seas but
I think that this is a valuable
discussion and that we should definitely
work together as a community to help
come to those definitions Thank You
senator mike was next Matt pound said
again yeah I I kind of feel like that
that doing it by defining the end user
might actually not be the easiest way to
do it because the the thing that I think
we're concerned about is the workload on
staff and the resource usage of isps
there there the the larger resorts train
right for both for both workload and and
for number resources so that I think
it's ISPs that we are concerned with and
I think so it's probably easier and so I
think that any organization that shows
some isp behavior even if it's not all
of what they do should be an isp so I
think it's probably easier to define
that then then to say people who do this
or this or end users and everyone else
is an isp map I'm actually really
impressed with that little snippet I'm
gonna have to use that is P behavior
rather than a specific definition yeah
that that actually I think for me really
embodies what what this is about and not
we be able to take that we don't know
who you are sorry Kevin we broke the
wire Aaron AC so I think so I mean we
can probably get it down to a small list
of things right people who provide
Internet access to other organizations
or two or do individuals right p and
people who swip resources i think i
think even just those two things would
probably cover 99% of them you know
there might be one or two other simple
things we need we would need to throw in
there Ivan a lot about it for very long
but but I think that might be an easier
approach is to say that here are things
that are eyes that our isp behaviors
anyone who does these things is in isb
everybody else is an end user thank you
and fairness
just check with remote participation no
I'm going to be closing the mic soon and
so that you're not thrown off there
won't be a poll question as we've had
previously so if you want to input even
just to say get your two cents and
please approach a microphone now closing
microphones once twice three closed last
question comment to you sir so Jake not
clear from dying my my hesitation with
what Scott said is while it's very true
you want to be flexible confusion and
frustration don't lead to flexibility I
guess by what I would envision is an
applicant having to choose with the
acknowledged of interpretation and then
your staff this is back and forth where
it's kind of like so who's interpreting
what so I guess my question would be to
you especially directed at like staff
interpretation is I'm guessing they
probably want some some examples maybe
maybe to Jarrod's point maybe and
there's some kind of separate document
that just gives examples and that's not
tied into the to the bylaws or what
whatever formal documentation work you
know where we're solidifying here so
that you have flexibility to adopt that
over time thank you John yes
okay so I think that's a very good
suggestion regarding having examples
when we get to the other end of this and
we know what the rules are it would be
nice that's an example so someone could
say oh I'm one of those and that's
easier I'm going to raise an aspect now
and this might be worth this might
reopen the topic it might encourage
people to come to the microphones
recognize that the Aaron fee schedule
for isps is significant recurring annual
fees for your number of resources and
the fee schedule for end users is a
small maintenance fee each year and this
has been the practice since Aaron was
found with its inception so this means
that parties you know if two parties
have a both of them have six / sixteens
and ones that end user and one is a isp
the ISP is saying several thousand
dollars per year for eight thousand
volts per year and the end user is
paying this fee of a hundred dollars per
year generally if people have a choice
of paying several thousand per year or
hundred dollars per year as much as
their altruistic they choose to pay the
lesser amount and so this means that we
need to be careful because if people can
self-select we could find ourselves
having to face the financial
consequences of everyone saying I'm
actually getting the same services and
I'm just going to pay a lot less money
so people who feel that the answer to
this is normalize the services normalize
the fees people who think the answer to
this is differentiate the services
please come to the mic that would be a
helpful aspect of this we talk about is
P versus end-user social selection
conveniently somebody has approached the
mic Jerry cared much ntt I am probably
an ISP and hopefully we pay our fee
is is this that big of a problem or if
the fees are aligned is that going to
present a significant budgetary
challenge for Aaron when you say line is
if is if Wi-Fi if if the fees converge
such that everyone is pain and
relatively the same amount it depends
which way they converge I guess but a
lot of end users would become very upset
and would look for the person who
submitted that suggestion and hunt them
down if yes but if it were to go the
other way or did they won't it can't I
mean end users are paying a hundred
dollars per resource wat record no no so
anyway I have no idea how the air and
budget stuff works perhaps that's
through my own ignorance and because I
don't pay a lot of attention to the
process if all the ISPs stopped paying
their fees or start paying the end user
fee well that how will that impact Aaron
eighty percent of errands revenues or
ISP fees okay so if the ISPs count fees
come down to meet the end user fees it
would get interesting okay i think as
treasurer i would have to say that would
put us in a serious position yes okay
other people that would like to approach
on this topic center microphone i have
to raise it a bit guarantee you speaking
for myself just i was sitting here
thinking about the future of enterprises
and end users subsequent allocations you
six requests reporting requirements and
that it will probably evolved over time
and users will probably require more
resources from air and maybe you should
pay some more fees or maybe not and that
reporting might require things like
slipping enterprises and end users might
start looking more like ISPs though we
should i would suggest we are careful
about language in what looks like an isp
means
as we as a community have absolutely no
idea what an enterprise is going to look
like over the next 5 10 15 20 years
thank you that's a good comment I will
close the mics again on this topic and
second we have about ten minutes left in
this session so we can potentially skip
a bit earlier going once twice real
participation check nope so old thank
you very much for your involvement elite
turn over to John to finish up thank you
thank you I'd like to thank everyone for
participating in this session I remind
people that we're going to be talking
about these same things at the next iron
meeting which is a joint Aaron anode
meeting and that's coming up in October
in the meantime if you have views on
these policy proposals they're all
online they're actually a mailing list
that gets a couple messages each day
called the public policy mailing list
you're welcome to join it there's a
active discussion of these and your
views are more than welcome if you have
any comments particular to these your
advisory council your elected Aaron
advisory council the folks from the
community are the ones you should seek
out and you can express your views or
help to ask them to help explain aspects
of this that may not have been covered
thank you everyone for coming and enjoy
the rest of your evening
gunfire heavy and welcome to the podium
exec heart