so we've heard about cgn sucks we've
heard about this for a while now right
certainly kind of beat the drum that we
need to deploy these there we need to
employ these 60 v6 is the solution to
not having to replace the GM but we all
know that that isn't actually the kit is
the case to some extent but we're gonna
need a bridging technology right so cgn
is the bridging technology and so we
should talk about how we actually can
deploy and what effective methods are so
talk a little bit about how Rogers is
working on that right now
I almost feel dirty talking about this
now after Lee Howard talked about v6 but
anyway on we go
a bit of an introduction so we kind of
just kind of two things that we looked
at or when we looked at this issue
generically one was there give me some
folks that for whatever reason I've
decided they want to get it you know
they're gonna look at CG net how do I
deploy how do I actually put it into a
network there's a lot of operators out
there particularly mobile that have been
doing this or at least translation maybe
not
for most carrier grade NASA may have
been may be using enterprise level
translators etc but they've been doing
translation for many many years now and
as their customer base starts to
actually use internet services they have
smartphones etc and that starts to cliff
rate they they wind up there doing a lot
of this I'm moving forward now this
presentation is not about you know why
you should do carrier grade nat it's if
you've decided to it for whatever reason
now what are some of the integration
techniques or what things you can do to
try to get this to actually work
correctly now as a bit of a level set as
I'd mentioned this is not about it's
good it's bad in fact I actually don't
really like NAT per se I'm actually one
of the v6 guys back home but I'm also
responsible make stuff work so off we go
and have how do you make this work when
required what I found is a lot of
discussion about
is it good is it bad but there's a lot
not a lot of discussion out there in
terms of how do you make it work when
you decide you need to do it or even if
you have translation servers in your
network is there any way to make it work
better
ie the mobile space the other item too
is if you have a running Network with
native v4 running for most your
customers you want to add in care grade
nat how do you that without impacting
your customer base to the best extent
possible because what you don't want to
do is add a care great NAT technology to
your network and then disrupt your
ongoing customer base and make their
service worse for any reason at least
that's not a that's not a good decision
I would think from an operator
standpoint and then you know look at it
from a practical and pragmatic approach
you know how do you do architecture
around carry great NAT or how do you add
it in another thing to look at is like
I've mentioned earlier most mobile
networks already do translation for most
customers I mean there's a little bit of
you know public addresses assigned to
some endpoints but for the most part
it's all translated and that's growing
pretty fast
not all wireline networks are gonna have
enough efore addresses before they can
get everyone on to v6 only so they're
gonna have to as mention do some type of
bridge and by the way none of this
replaces your enthusiasm to try to
deploy v6 get it working and move to it
as fast as possible this is by no means
a replacement for a v6 strategy this is
what you do as a bridging technology or
bridging capability for v4 the other
thing that I'm not addressing here is
some of the business issues related
around translation this is not this
doesn't fix or nothing I'm going to
present fixes the problems with care
with translation so if you do if you
have to identify customers for certain
types of service access etc this is not
talking about that is about how do you
make transit how could you get
translation to work in your network
effectively or one version of it now
when we looked at this and we you know
said okay what are the high-level
considerations for adding care great now
some of the things we looked at is well
how do we minimize impact to our running
state native v4 customer base seems
pretty self-evident we would want that
another item we looked at is can we come
up with a flexible model where we can
change things over to
without unduly impacting our operations
in injuring folks you know try not to
make them go through more effort than
required and can it scale based on the
changes of our carrier grade nat demand
overtime and what we found you know as
one of the pictures shown on the slide
there is that might mean that you're
carrying out resources change position
your network from a more centralized to
a more distributed position over time as
demand goes you might want to scale that
out subscribers on traditional v4
services normally acquired direct or as
direct you can connectivity the internet
so for most of our customers today at
least on the wireline side you want to
get them to Internet as fast as possible
the good news is that's good from a
performance perspective for them the
good news for us is also cheaper right
you have fewer links to upgrade and a
little less network to have to pass them
through the issue with carrier in our
customers is their next hop is not the
Internet or their next point of
reference in your network is not the
Internet it's actually get to a
translator so the fundamentally
different path you want them to go than
the rest of your customers that couldn't
particularly already exist so the
question is how do we deal with this
coexistence how do we get both you know
there's categories NAT customers added
in if that's what you're doing
and how do you not impact your your
mainline customers so you know the
question here is in terms of from a
solution perspective is CG CG and
placement becomes a big issue is we
don't want us you don't want to
overspend yourself in the beginning
saying I need to distribute category NAT
for the future so you might want to
change where you place your career I
need care good carrier-grade NAT
resources over time and that might
actually change though the arbitrary
topology you see there you know between
where I might have some peering than
where I have my access routers that
position might change to be more
efficient and be able to distribute it
to take on the additional load the other
component we know we were looking at
would how do you try to keep the
configuration and the complexity of the
environment as low as possible
throughout this now it seems a little
bit utopian that you know I want a lot
of flexibility but
want a lot of control over the
complexity and amount of changes I have
to go through within my network so it
does sound utopian but we think we found
a reasonable middle ground there and as
mentioned earlier how do you get that
going going back to the you know
placement over time we found that the
place and the optimal placement of care
Gradney carry regret carrier grade nat
I'm not doing that well today resources
throughout the network is going to
likely have to change to be optimal now
a particular issue that we had which not
everyone else has is you know we we kind
of see the world as both a wireless in a
wireline world we have both and so they
both grew up from two very different
places so Wireless is pretty much all
translated for most people not just us
and wireline is pretty much there's
pretty much no translation right from
the onset so the question is how do you
come up with an architecture or a way of
doing something where you can apply the
same methodologies to both and then if
this is your problem space converge them
later on now obviously if you're only a
wireline provider you're not converging
much and if you're only a wireless
provider you may not be converging much
but a lot of people out there or there
might be some partnerships that come
into play later on so you might want to
think about that now
the other thing that we looked at from a
solution requirement was how do you do
CG and bypass do you have a lot of
services within your network that you
may not want to translate before you get
to your own service at least it is you
have it you have an opportunity to kind
of avoid that problem so to avoid that
issue you know we want to save costs we
don't want to buy translation services
for things we don't have to buy it for
so how do we get a get a bypass
technique working that was one of the
one of the mandates from a solution that
we need to look at so on to what we
looked at actually doing so that was
kind of set at the stage of what we were
thinking why we were driving down this
path by the way this does not replace v6
strategies so what we decided to do was
leverage MPLS VPNs as defined in RFC
4364 the reason why we looked at this
was its well deployed I mean we have a
lot of experience of MPLS VPNs we've
been using for a number of years
traditionally for business services so
our operations folks know how
I know how to deal with it or injuring
folk our engineering folks know how to
deal with it we know I designed an
architect around it so we thought that
seemed like a pretty good idea and just
to pause there you know when we first
had vendors coming to us wanting to sell
us equipment of course you know they
were giving us all kinds of crazy
techniques as to how to make care of
great network policy be routing etc
etcetera etc and we're like well this is
pretty complex we don't do much of this
today and we don't want to add in all
this additional complexity hence back to
the what are we already do and how do we
leverage technology technologies we
already have to do translation and the
other thing about m+ VPNs was it allows
us to overlay this onto an existing
network without actually changing the
underlying topology and the service the
services that already exist within our
network we can add this in on top and
not affect anything underneath that was
one of the major advantages to doing
this so to kind of put a little bit of
pictures in here the way you know kind
of we looked at is we can loosely define
cgn zones you know groups of customers
that need to be translated to get to the
internet and we threw them into vr af-s
on end points and then used LSPs to kind
of get them over to wherever the
translator was now the location of the
PE in this particular case in the
translator is irrelevant to the topology
that can exist literally anywhere and
that's pretty dynamic if you happen to
be using the LDP in your network could
just you figure out the other endpoint
just kind of works and if you move that
translation endpoint well just magically
LSP magically moves over somewhere not
magically dynamically moves over and
regular customers wouldn't even see any
of this pre translated traffic is inside
the VPN post translated traffic is in in
our particular case in the global
routing table or the same routing table
where all our inner traditional Internet
customers are now from AC gen bypass
perspective it was actually pretty easy
to make this work within this model
effectively if you put your services
into a services vrf all you basically do
is import export statements or extranet
your own services to your customer base
so what that effectively does is it
means that your services are not
translated to your own customers would I
be your DNS server or something very
basic or other services you might have
and this is all within the standard MPLS
VPN model and look at normal customers
don't see any of this and for your
traditional customer base is irrelevant
that this is all operating over on top
another good thing about here is there
was no traditional traffic engineering
wired to do this it just worked pretty
fluidly and it worked pretty well
another look at this is you can then
join that same set of services too as
not as many of the cgn zones that you
want so if you have multiple cgn zones
because you want to be able to segment
your customer base over time to be able
to scale that in the future and put them
towards different translation resources
you can basically extranet the same set
of services to each one of those zones
as you please and each one of those
translation zones will go to their
relative translator for to get to the
internet or they will go to the service
directly to the services for their
various services
the other interesting thing here is this
doesn't have to just be for internal
services you can extend this to business
partners and other other folks who can
be placed into that same zone I mean the
servers in that zone can have public IPS
and they can be exposed directly to the
your global table so you can feed
content into those zones as you want and
effectively you can then stream that out
to the customers obviously anything in
there has to be aware that you were
gonna potentially see private addresses
or you know in deers the shared address
space range the 164 range so though you
have to be aware that that piece that
gear is operating this environment but
as long as the equipment's aware or the
software's aware it works pretty fluidly
from a dual-stack perspective obviously
we looked at how does we how do we add
this into a dual stack option in terms
of being able to give someone v4 and v6
and that also worked out in our favor we
you know we have two methods that we
were able to do this with one was we
could land the v4 and v6 connectivity to
different vr af-s one could be the
global table and so the v6 travels just
like any other traditional traffic would
flow and your care grade NAT traffic or
your v4 connection lands into a V RF
that goes off into a translator and
those are managed separately another way
of doing it is on the source side or on
the access side you could just leak
those routes into the table and then you
know just becomes IPS available at that
access router so that worked pretty well
so from a dual stack perspective you can
make this work so there's nothing
inhibiting you from then incrementally
going to to add v6 in for this customer
and then in the future you can just turn
off the v4 piece if you need that
customer becomes v6 on the other piece
that worked really really well was yet
you know our view of the worlds we had
to make this converge between our
wireless and wireline properties so the
nice thing about this architecture was
we could basically ignore all the
complexities of what goes on in our
mobile network and effectively just
check you know attach those V V RS or
VPNs from our mobile network attach them
to our larger network and use the same
common translation infrastructure for
both wireless and wireline so
effectively it's a common way of
providing a service that acts
differently between both and again
because we're using different cgn zones
which are represented by different VRS
and VPNs we can segment that or converge
those at different parts throughout the
growth cycle as we see fit
you know the mapping of a given
translator or translators to and number
of of CG and zones can change very
dynamically all of you doing is
effectively for those who do this
configuration themselves you're just
changing import-export statements on
edge boxes and they pretty much done
there's there's very little
configuration both of the care grade
outside and on and the rest of
configuration the access side that needs
to change to do all that remapping it
also helps you know fix a lot of
challenges because there are a lot of
problems with translation logging and a
lot of other things have to
they have to occur and so that can
happen pretty fluidly as well and you
can offer the same set of services you
have whether or not they're wireless for
wireline customers where they're coming
from when we're looking at other
considerations so this goes back to why
we kind of looked at the NPS VPN option
versus some of the other options I mean
we did look at policy based routing and
we found that would be really really
ugly I mean we could have said you know
based on your source address go this way
and but you know for everything else go
the other way we found that it's a lot
of change we know we don't want
engineers and ops people like literally
tapping away keyboards changing
configuration all the time because that
normally translates into problems the
fewer the fewer times you have to have
someone actually change configuration in
a box the better for us it is just it
typically works out the other you know
item we looked at was MPLS to eat we
thought well we could traffic engineer
this traffic over from one location to
the other but that's a lot of overhead
that's a lot of work that we would have
to add into the network for something
that we didn't want to spend a lot of
time on at the end of the day you know
one of the original goals is how do we
use technologies we already have that we
really operate that we already know well
that don't require a lot of ongoing
maintenance but provide a lot of
flexibility so traffic engineering yeah
it would work it could have worked but
we found that it was just way too much
complexity to to put into something that
will live and hopefully die in the
not-too-distant future
and there's other things that we looked
at in terms of multiple topologies and
putting on you know putting in all kinds
of crazy techniques to kind of separate
our customers but we found that the
other the other options again a lot of
time a lot of cost for a service that
again you know it's not really worth
paying too much time on if you can avoid
that last time we spent all this for us
was the better we wanted to spend our
time and other things like v6 from a
general experience perspective it's it
works pretty well now it's nice not our
experience we've spoken with others that
have both use it based on our input we
have a draft out in the ITF that
describes this model some others happen
that comes a similar conclusion and the
feedback we received is that for me
adding in trends our carrier grade nat
this architecture worked pretty well and
it works pretty fluidly it's easy - it's
reasonably easy to deploy if you already
have experience at MPLS VPNs if you
don't have experience with it it might
be a large bat to use to get this
working so I don't necessarily advocate
this option if you have no experience
with that but if you do it's actually a
pretty it's pretty easy to add it in
because you're ready familiar with all
the techniques if they actually didn't
have a huge initial cost because there
was no changes to the actual access
network that we had to put in the only
cost that were born at the end of the
day were the cost of the actual
translators so those are costly and in
the future if you have to add IPS on
your global pools that will cost money
but from an infrastructure perspective
there wasn't a lot of costs most of the
capabilities that are used already
inherent in most of the access nodes and
their various other components within
the network at least the network we have
and we have generic routers and switches
as most of you will have from the mobile
side it works there as well we were able
to bridge us into the LTH SP environment
pretty well your P gateway GGO sends
have the ability to take ap ends and
attach them to VR FS and we can attach
different APNs of different VR VR s as
we want so we have a lot of flexibility
there so this work both in a Docs is
cable world it worked both they were
also working in a DSL world and we had
this work on the mobile side so it kind
of worked across all their various
access technologies that we need to need
it to work across and it you know
separate their traffic well and what we
found was our traditional customers
flowed nicely to the Internet as they
did before and for those few that need
to use this and in the mobile case the
most of them that had to use this it
worked you know they went to a
translator and we were through segments
that as necessary now one thing I didn't
go through too much within this DAC but
when we we had a larger set of
requirements that we had looked at
originally when we looked at translation
so we looked at do you want centralized
versus decentralized location of
translators so the answer is well we
said we wanted both we want to be able
to move it around and the answer was yes
we could do that with this architecture
we wanted to be able to say you know can
you coexist with traditional IPV
services without impacting them and the
answer was yes we could do this
it doesn't impact your your an
underlying customer base the other thing
we looked at is can you do cgn bypass
and the answer was yes we could do this
and you could bypass CG ends pretty
easily it's all within the MPLS VPN
framework
another thing we looked at is routing
traffic can we do traffic control with
this and this yeah we can you know we're
sending our translation traffic one
direction and arrests our customers in
other direction the other thing we look
at is well do we have flexibility can we
split our translation zones as the
actual demand grows and then contracts
later on the answer is yes we can remap
the number of translators to the number
of CG in zones as very easily throughout
the lifecycle of Kara great net the
other thing we looked at is is supported
well within both the wires and wireline
properties and the answer was yes it's
technologies that are available and all
our access gear that we already have
today if there's nothing magical about
doing this in terms if your traditional
operator that operates MPLS VPNs another
thing to look at you know what can we
can we work with overlapping address
ranges in the answers yes if we don't
have enough private address space or
enough shared address space you can just
overlap between the seat and VPN so the
answer is each VPN could have the same
address range if you wanted to the
caveat there is if you're extra netting
services into those cgn zones you know
have to have instances of those services
because you can't have literally the
same server talking to the same IP
multiple VPN so there's a there's a
caveat there so you can do overlapping
address ranges but then you there's a
service impact doing that but it does
work if all you care about is getting
customers translated to go to the
internet there's a work with the dual
stack operational the answer was yes we
can make this work with dual stack
operation so there's no it doesn't
inhibit us from adding v6 in as time
goes on for those customers and does it
help out with you know the logistics of
what do you have to do when you add in
something a carrier it not in the
answers yes log in connection management
that can all be done and the nice thing
is it can be done in a standard fashion
and we don't have to have different
deployments for different kind of
properties we can kind of have a common
deployment for both our wireless and
wireline networks and it works pretty
fluidly across both so based on the fact
we were over time I kind of try to
concatenate that bit and leave a little
time for some questions so that was the
end of my slides I guess at this point
talking pretty fast was there any
questions to us again I feel kind of
dirty talking about carrying that but
did anyway
Lee Lee Howard Time Warner Cable is this
architecture based on operational
experience let's say do you get my
question
so you're saying is the architecture of
how we used impose VPNs based on
operation experience or how we're doing
translation let me ask the pointed
question did you just say you're doing
cgn well on the mobile side we it's
always been cgn right well sorry it's
always been translated traditional
translation occurred might not be very
great correct well I mean it you use
what you had 10 years ago right any
other questions okay thanks