okay so we're gonna go a slightly
whimsical here and talk about something
in a little bar in the work life
situation for a lot of us so I
personally work from home for a
significant amount of time a decent
amount of my team does as well recently
there was a bit of a dust-up in the news
about one of the companies he's actually
usually well represented here changing
their work from home policy and mr.
Underwood and dr. Prairie here decided
that they wanted to explore how they
felt that was working in the industry in
general and so Todd you know has a lot
of experience here Beth is a
gynecologist and so you'll find that
that may not be directly relevant here
if any of you do need a gynecologist
though I highly recommend her if I'd
like to think if I ever needed a
gynecologist I would call Beth
thankfully i don't think i will need one
and todd is an SRE which in this case
will stand force and removal engineer at
Google so Todd and Beth technology are
we on yes yes thank you very much for
that great introduction pumpkin we
really appreciate it we're happy to be
here today excellent so um what was the
company that you were referring to oh
well have to get into that in a second
so uh we wanted to take a look at a
touchy subject this is touching in the
way that claiming that not everybody has
to travel business class all the time is
touchy because people who really want to
do the thing they want to do feel
put-upon when you tell them what works
about it and what doesn't but in
particular we wanted to look at what we
actually know about how this stuff works
and specifically we wanted to figure out
under what circumstances it works for us
here geeks and technologies
technologists as workers but also for
the infrastructures and the systems that
we build so once your new some
terminology will try to convince you you
care if we fail to succeed
we convince you you care to start the
break early there's probably coffee and
they've been sending out the food early
so feel free to wander out we don't
really need you anyway we can talk here
without you you guys are entirely
superfluous we'll talk about our biases
we'll talk about what we know about
remote work and what we don't know in a
few counterintuitive things will try to
do a brief survey of what a bunch of
companies do and then we'll look at some
strategies for making remote work
successful so just to go over the
terminology really quickly so work from
work is what we all know you have an
office desks and if you're really lucky
you have a coffee machine working from
home is really two cases you can be
local with the same city same time zone
same country as your team or you can be
remote in a different place then there's
work from remote which is working from a
different office of the same company but
remote from wherever your primary team
is distributed teams are where there's
no office for the primary team at all
everybody's either working from home or
working from remote the really important
thing to remember especially when we
talk about the data in this is that
people don't differentiate well between
work from home remote distributed teams
and everything else so when we talk
about this remember that all that people
really mean when they are presenting
data writing papers doing research is
either you're in an office or you're
something else and that's going to be
important as we look at these cases
because you lot are going to try to
distinguish but ah my team is in the
following way the data don't distinguish
that and one of the things we're going
to find is that the data are less good
than we wish they were so why do you
care the main reason you care is that
there was recent contrived media
controversy or controversy for the Brits
among you that's probably actually the
only reason you all care but why you
should care is that smart people want to
work wherever the hell they live right
people like being productive companies
like smart people who work for them to
get a lot of work done and be cheap
right and people are cheaper in Detroit
than they are in santa clara and this or
in jersey city knows
a little bit more expensive than Detroit
okay that's fine um and this impacts
technology workers primarily a lot of
the research on this is about
salespeople is about call center but
this we're specifically trying to look
at technology workers and the other
reason you guys cares that the
infrastructure for work from home has
been changing pretty substantially you
know ten years ago people are like IRC
aim and a phone call and now you know
there's virtual meetings there's
gotomeeting there's virtual desktop
sharing and presentation sharing some
people use google hangouts or skype
right and the bandwidth requirements
keep going up and the technology
requirements keep going up so let me
talk about our backgrounds so that you
know our biases one of the reasons I
think Dave and the program committee
were happy to have me involved in this
is because I've done all sides of this
so when we lived in New Hampshire I was
chief technology officer of a new
mexico-based ISP so on the like systems
and network engineering side that was
awesome because IRC and that's fine
right on the executive management
business and product management side of
it it was downright abysmal like people
are like how did you not know we were
gonna sell that product line to this
other company we talked about it in the
hallway of two weeks ago like that's
fantastic so that part was mediocre
overall at Renesys I was there for about
six years the most of the team was
distributed so although the headquarters
was in New Hampshire the teams that I
work with the systems engineering and
the network engineering teams were in I
don't know five countries and nine
cities or something and it was fine
right because IRC again because I RC but
the executive management saw again was
fine when I was local when I moved to
Pittsburgh it worked less well Google is
a very very different circumstance and
it's been widely reported google has an
almost universal work from work practice
that's not the policy but the practice
is almost everybody works in the office
almost all the time but really really
great offices some people have crappy
commutes I'm not
them because I live in a sensible City
and you too could live in a sensible
city so that works Oh Joe's cranky sorry
yeah I make Boston suck it's not my
fault oh um or California so so that
works that works pretty well but it
obviously has some downsides I'm back on
the other hand has noted that gynecology
is not particularly amenable to remote
work it's not clear to me why that's the
case but Carnegie Mellon has some good
robotics engineers working on pieces of
that so we'll get it I'm not kidding
like the remote surgery stuff is going
to be amazing because they start with
like the surgeons in the adjacent room
and it's going to be the surgeons in the
adjacent time zone not terribly far from
now there's some latency things that i'm
working on a lightning talk for this
afternoon we'll talk about the latency
impacts of that so um the research stuff
so Beth does a bunch of research I'm
like research it's about reading things
and thinking and writing that can be
done anywhere right there's all these
pieces of paper and they're all like we
have these pieces of paper we have to be
with our paper it's in a place in a
drawer and we open it up and take things
out of it it's really weird but anyway
that apparently is not amenable to
remote work as well I'm confused as to
why so here are just some sort of images
for you to think about when you think
about what people's work environments
look like this is my work from home
research environment um you can see I'm
behind my castle there are some boxes
there that are full of my pieces of
paper to which I'm very attached and I
just have a simple little desk not a lot
of distraction there's an elliptical
machine I have a nice few of the trees
out of my windows the key element here
is the castle in you too could have a
castle at your work environment but the
castle does not come decorated you need
children to decorate it for you but
those can be rent we can provide those
yes indeed so working from work gets
productive right it's great this is my
work from work environment I walk on a
treadmill because why wouldn't you work
on a treadmill I need to wear headphones
because I need to defend myself against
my co-workers conversations I need to
wear eye protection because I need to
defend myself against my co-workers nerf
guns to be fair I did buy them those
nerf guns so it's difficult to complain
too much there's hand sanitizer there to
defend myself against my co-workers
viruses and other
the Jews and a towel because of course
the towel so so what is it that we know
or think we know now that we've sort of
covered the terminology and some of the
background I'm what we really wanted to
do with this talk was give a summary of
the data of what is actually known about
the conditions of working from home as
opposed to working from work and I'll
tell you right now that the take home
from this is that the data are thin on
the ground and a lot of them are
methodologically flawed and so we don't
know as much as actually to be honest we
ought to know as we begin to really have
work forces that want to work from home
so what we do know is that everyone
wants the holy grail for an employee
fast cheap and happy everybody wants the
great employer who's high paying with
low friction and good work-life balance
so business schools corporations who are
employers and social science researchers
have been attempting to determine the
methods for achieving this holy grail
but as I said please bear in mind that
the research is not at the level you
would really hope for so always start
with the epidemiology which is who gets
the disease that you're worried about so
the definitions are a varying quality
nobody laughed that was a joke I was
like you just called my desired
lifestyle disease that's how we roll I
um so as we pointed out with the
problems even with the term work from
home the definitions are problematic
when you look at who are the people who
are working from home as well so in the
US the bureau of labor statistics the
most recent data they have on this is
from 2004 you know very recent your tax
dollars at work ladies and gentlemen I'm
fifteen percent of all non agricultural
workers in the u.s. worked from home at
least one day per week and that's flat
since 2001 of the people who worked from
home sixty-six percent were business
management or other professionals which
is you all not me and twenty-five
percent had a formal arrangement for
work from home in 2010 so the US Census
asks about this at every census but they
get coarser data and the finest data
that they have are those data from 2004
so as of 2010
ten percent of people were work from
home in the EU the most recent data or
2005 so there you know a year ahead and
they had seven point five percent of
their population worked from home at
least twenty five percent of the time so
again hard to compare those exactly so
when people are working from home what
are they doing are they working so um
this is a survey this is
methodologically not a great survey but
there's actually not a lot of data about
this and if you think about it it's hard
to get somebody to self-report
accurately what they actually do so
forty-three percent of people said that
they watched TV or movies and twenty
percent played video games and just to
be clear if you were a parent of
children you were more likely to answer
that you did those two things while you
were working twenty-four percent of
people had a drink a quarter of them
took a nap more than a quarter of them
did household chores and almost thirty
percent made dinner it's still probably
a good use of time dinner has to be made
it's kind of boring you might as well be
working while you're doing it we know
that interleaving or pipelining tasks hi
it's latency and almost everyone works
when they're cooking dinner anyway both
were there any questions on that survey
that you would have had as a
gynecologist there were other things I
would have been curious about people
doing while they're working from home
but those were not asked those questions
were not asked to be fair so this is
that this is one of the slides that I
worried people would think we're bashing
on working from home let me be clear
among this list these unlike reading
from the slide these are the things that
I've done at work watch TV and movies
played video games had a drink took a
nap I've never done household chores Oh
12like phone calls to make a dentist
appointment for the kids all the time so
like it's really hard to squeeze the
work in at work so yeah it just to be
clear all of that doesn't mean people
were not productive at home it just
means all that other stuff is happening
too so so does it work this is actually
one of the most important and one of the
most robust studies that's been done to
look at this and it's pretty famous if
you use a search engine on the web and
you are looking for data
you will come across this study and it's
not really a fun study to read so I will
summarize it for you so this was a group
of Stanford researchers who study
Chinese call center workers and the
study is randomized although it's not
perfectly randomized and it is a
crossover design so they got 10,000
science terms you're just confusing them
they use 10,000 Chinese call center
workers who volunteer to be randomized
to either work from work or everyone had
been working or work from home when they
randomly assigned them they found that
the people who were assigned to work
from home had thirteen percent higher
productivity they were more happy they
were more satisfied they had a nearly
fifty percent lower promotion rate after
they did that the crossover design was
to say okay now we've randomly assigned
you everybody choose so when people get
to choose half of each group choose
chose the opposite of what they were
originally assigned to so that's really
interesting too and when people were
allowed to choose whether they worked
from work or worked from home they
increased productivity by twenty-two
percent so there are a couple of really
important take homes here one of them is
that there's it seems to be true that
people can actually make good decisions
about what the work environment is that
works well for them and that we should
think about letting people have that
choice because even when people who
wanted to work from work worked from
home that was a less happy environment
for them then when everybody got to
choose I'm as an aside especially for
people who live in the more congested
areas of the u.s. that they are
interesting community effects that were
noted i mean 10,000 people in a small
city in china is not an insignificant
number and they were able to document
lower vehicle emissions but increased
sprawl so as more people got to work
from home they drove to work less but
they started moving farther away from
work and expanding the city yeah and
we're going to come back to a couple of
the other findings from this as well so
there's a you guys may not have looked
at this but there is a widespread
we believed adage which is people are
productive when they are working from
home but creative when they're working
from work and those are a little bit
overloaded term so by productive I mean
when there's a set of defined work or
defined tasks people it is believed that
people are more efficient accomplishing
those tasks when they are working from
home in general with some caveats about
choice and some people hate working from
home in the Stanford Chinese call center
study and that people are creative and
by creative I mean they are more likely
to invent new products patent to new
ideas develop new approaches to solving
problems when they're working from work
this is believed there's some data
around this and the data around this are
very weak and confusing so the first
thing around the is that I need to
mention and I know this is an
uncomfortable topic for this audience is
that human beings are complicated
there's another thing that's a little
bit difficult for this audience to admit
culture matters so most of the work
that's been done on this has been done
on Americans that's awesome but
Americans are actually very particular
first of all they're individualistic but
they get tension and creativity out of
working in groups this is a weird sort
of set of cultural predilections that's
not universal so for Americans Americans
do appear to be more creative when
they're working in groups optimal
amounts of creativity are when you work
with people you know well enough to
trust and that that group tolerates
dissent and tolerates friction so
there's a lot of data around diversity
for example that people come from
diverse backgrounds gender diversity
racial and ethnic language diversity
diversity of professional background
diversity of professional experience
difference in approach to solving a
problem that one of the things that you
see is that that those differences
bubble up in tension and conflict and if
the group is able to tolerate that
tension and conflict creative approaches
result out of that there's a this kind
of creativity and this kind of tension
is less likely to occur in the work from
home environment I don't want to speak
to your relationship with your family
because I'm certain that there's plenty
of tension there and perhaps maybe even
tolerated maybe not that's you and your
shrinks problem but I think that it is
less likely that you will encounter that
kind of tension while working over a
remote channel so understanding these
dynamics what are the dynamics that give
rise to this kind of tension tolerated
dissent in order to create creativity is
an interesting technological challenge
we're going to look at that a little bit
oh there's one interesting thing to
mention what was the interesting thing
to mention there oh that no no that's
fine we'll deal with that later okay so
this goes on to dr. Perry gets a coffee
machine so Lily got a coffee machine so
there's this a pretty famous place in
Pittsburgh the makii women's research
institute they get like eight point six
million arse tons of NIH money and they
do all this research and they didn't
have and you guys those of you who work
in education know this like there's no
common space there's no nice lounge
there's no like coffee machine there's
no espresso machines there's no snacks
there's just like offices and dank
hallways and like a water cooler that
hasn't been fixed since nineteen sixty
seven or something right and like the
money and research is like bleeding out
right now so there's no money but these
guys are serious about the science so
they looked at the set of papers done by
a famous biomedical institution in
Cambridge that's not MIT Harvard and
they looked at the geolocation of
authors positions in space and then they
cited the significance and significance
is pretty easy in really rigid academic
communities because you can just say how
many people cited their talk right and
that's a pretty good metric of like was
it important it's not perfect but it's
decent and so the talks that are the
most important are the talks with the
highest number of intra building
collaborators and there were some
buildings like individual buildings that
were just like producing all the most
significant papers because they had the
most collaboration within the building
so the magee-womens Research Institute
saw that's not like all right we just
gotta pony up for our coffee machine and
they got a coffee machine it's pretty
good thanks Harbor so the last thing I
want to point out is so there's a widely
stated study so there's this
set of evidence that looks like in
general most people are more productive
at defined tasks at home most people are
more creative and innovative at work but
not universally with some exceptions and
then there's like the business press is
full of this particular study that says
AHA it's not the case people can be more
creative at home to on under these
circumstances the reporting so not
surprisingly in the social sciences the
reporting about the study is bad but the
study itself is pretty bad too so it's
kind of a wash as to whose fault it is
that this doesn't make any sense what
the study actually shows and this is
really important is that less structure
and by structure we mean organizational
structure and communication structure
promotes creativity and in the
particular groups that they looked at
they the people working from home happen
to have less organizational and
communications structure in their work
environments while they were working on
tasks that involved innovation or
creativity and so there were more
innovative and creative but it doesn't
actually when you take those same kinds
of less structured communication and
organizational environment so you put
them on work from work then those people
get creative again also so it turns out
the study is useful but not for any of
the reasons anybody who has been
popularizing it say it was um so I want
to go back to one of the points from the
Stanford study on the Chinese call
center workers which is like so you kiss
your career goodbye remember that they
were fifty percent less likely to get
promoted when they worked from home and
I am really genuinely sorry to tell you
that this is one of the single most
robust pieces of data that's come out of
this research in that everyone who's
looked at this without exception has
showed the same effect so people who
work from home and remember again though
that these definitions vary across
studies do not get promoted as often
when they do get raises their raises are
smaller than comparable people in their
organizations who work from work and
words that turn out to be important when
you're being evaluated include
dependable responsible and committed and
people who worked from home had people
evaluating them use those specific terms
and terms like them less often
this presents some pretty significant
management challenges so work from home
necessitates specific objective results
oriented measures of performance but
even that may not be enough to counter
feast I'm bias and I know that a lot of
people kind of feel like that facetime
bias is because my boss is it is a
dumbass right like my boss just can't
understand sort of a good way to rate my
productivity or do what needs to be done
to deal with work from home and we're
going to talk about some data that say
unfortunately it's not just your boss
there is some special sauce and there
are actually researchers across a broad
range of disciplines trying to figure
out what that is about us physically
meeting each other and physically being
present in the same space so there's a
really good meta-analysis out there that
looks at these data all together you
know a meta-analysis is when you take
all the papers you do actually pretty
fancy statistical measures on all of
their results to try to figure out
what's a true way to interpret all of
the data together using math weight like
math math it's like math it's just like
my here um so work from home did have a
persistent small beneficial effect on
certain proximal outcomes reduced work
family conflict and people said that
they felt more autonomous I'm job
satisfaction performance and turnover
intent but not actual turnover are
improved with work from home and roll
stress which is this really specific
sort of sociologic measurement were
improved and then people who worked from
home greater than two and a half days a
week had more challenging co-worker
relationships and the data so at the end
of a meta-analysis you kind of get to
say like the quality of the data that my
results are based on is like good
mediocre or bad and these data are
mediocre so basically it's a wash so
given all of that so we're at the
situation where we think there are some
advantages for work from home people are
happier in some ways they may be
slightly more productive
if they're given the choice to work from
home and want to work from home but
relationships with coworkers are more
challenging and creativity and
innovation might suffer but some people
still really want to work from home so
we decided to say okay set aside the
data about what works and what doesn't
what do we know that improves the
chances of it working well so this is
like the this is available in the data
and all things outside of your field can
be learned at a dinner party so we went
to a dinner party with David Anderson
who's in has friggin a bunch of you know
him and there was Justin castle who does
the human she's the head of the
human-computer interaction Institute and
Erica Fuchs who does research on
innovation so we're like this is awesome
since we don't really know anything
about this which makes it pretty
questionable why we're here talking to
you but anyway bygones um we're like it
was really good freaking fantastic good
wine there were a little cute little
baby to look at for a little while as it
was really entertaining I'm sorry you
guys missed it actually no in any case
we're like so tell us what you know we
got a bunch of pointers and we looked at
the research so um here's the things
that work much much better having a
policy and we're going to talk about who
has a policy a initial impersonal
traction doesn't look like it's a good
idea it looks like it's more or less
essential for two reasons one of them is
that it significantly improves trust and
Trust is something that you need in
order to tolerate dissent and dissent a
disagreement is something you need to do
anything innovative or creative so you
got to have that but the other reason is
that and we all don't like to admit this
relationships that are initially and
primarily electronic are easily
discarded people actually we just don't
care about them that much there may be
people that you've chatted with daily on
IRC for ten years and if you stop
talking to them it really won't hurt
your feelings that much and you might
even forget that you used to talk to
them a lot and it's this feature of us
as human being so that looks like it's
pretty important good communication and
good communication needs frequent
communication in different modes of
communication having objective
performance metrics that one's pretty
obvious right shared interest with
different skills we're working towards
the same thing but we have radically
different ideas about how to get there
and radically different approaches and
strengths in accomplishing that there's
this really amusing there needs to be
perception of balanced effort but you
don't actually need balanced effort you
just have to convince everyone that
everyone's pulling their weight and that
sort of management jujitsu you just do a
Jedi mind trick in your like we are all
equal and then it's fine which is weird
and you need the right people so some
people and this may have been like one
of the impacts of the Chinese call sign
our study some people may just be a like
home organization or constitutionally or
attention wise incapable of working from
home effectively and so some people are
obviously better at this than others so
I are okay work or home gotta have a
policy right it's good to have a policy
uh so we said well like who's got
policies because we know I'm like buddy
show of hands how many people here work
from home at least two and a half days a
week alright see you so like you guys
how many people here work for a company
that has a policy describing how you
work from home see that's what I'm
talking about like this is like it went
down to ten percent by the way right so
we're like okay who's got a policy
what's going on here right so we started
looking so there's one pretty large
company that famously changed their
practices although it's not clear what
their former policy was and it's not
actually clear what their current policy
is on working from home and that's sort
of what started people rethinking about
this stuff Google fairly famously has
very few people working from home but
some people do there are actually a
small number of of people who work from
home and there's a pretty medium sized
number of people who work from remote in
other words they work at a Google
facility but they work primarily with
people that are not at that facility so
it's difficult to judge where that fits
in in the data um Cisco I mean just
don't know it so Cisco got a bunch of
stuff about this and like love them to
death but all their stuff about this is
about selling gear they're like I'm
selling software and so it's really
difficult to get any value out of
anything they publisher because you
should buy some stuff from us and it'll
be great and like of course you should
buy some stuff from them as long as they
keep sponsoring now you should just keep
doing that but there's nothing in the
stuff that they publish to help you
figure out what works or even exactly
what their policy is IBM has been
claiming for about 10 years that they're
on this aggressive everybody worked from
home all the time they're like claiming
carbon credits stuff about this they're
claiming forty percent work hours
are done remotely that's awesome but
they roll in their entire sales force
into that number and so now I don't know
what to do with that because if you had
a bunch of people who were never working
at the office anyway because they're
outside sales people how much of a
change is this really it's awesome that
they have good technology around that
but it's not clear that they're taking
traditional collaborative you know
technology and engineering tasks or
management tasks and moving them
remotely but the punch line though is
almost all of the technology industry
lets some of the best people they like
the most work from home with no policy
and just kind of calls it good until
it's not and that as we've shown is
pretty mediocre so concluding you want
to cover conclusions sure so people who
primarily work from home seem to be less
likely to get promoted like I'm really
sorry to deliver that news but that
really does seem to be true and clearly
we need to do something about that but
they also seem to be more productive at
least when they are Americans they may
have less creative solutions and if
anyone's interested in those data those
studies are fascinating I would be
totally happy the studies are footnoted
in here so you could go read them
yourself or you could ask me about that
or anything else at the break lot of
food um they seem to be happier with
family but they're not necessarily
happier in general but the data are kind
of crummy and so we don't really know so
what are the like real things to take
home meeting people in person is really
important and we don't know why and your
boss needs to see your face if you want
to get promoted you need excellent
excellent communications infrastructure
to do this diverse teams still do way
better and explicit policies are
probably a good idea but very few people
have them just a quick clarification um
in case people are confused this is not
what diversity looks like I just didn't
want anybody to misunderstand that all
right irrational exuberance questions
that oh good Wow Oh rock and roll or
cordless
I should fall off the stage got so
excited about this oh hi this is wil
hargrave with a british airways
architect executive gold and hilton
platinum so there's a there's a subset
of people who who obviously we've
established do not actually have an
office to work from have you done any
research or work on the people in this
industry who are doing actually have a
home to work for magic work from their
primary work Modi's work from conference
or work from airplane this is a specific
hat tip to Martin I don't wish to
comment on that ah no I know no one so
let's be clear the actual data here
don't even distinguish between people
who work from an office without with a
different work group and people who work
from an office with their own work group
so no but I would say if you're gonna if
you're going to work from your airplane
you should show your face to your boss
once in a while you should try to have
coffee with people on your team once in
a while even if it's out of conference
yeah dude Joe provo from a travel
company well please continue working
from the airplanes and everywhere that
you work from the please book your
flights and oh how would we booked our
flights there's this lovely Joe provo
idea software but Google there's this
lovely atul matrix and actually this
beautiful integration of flight stuff on
maps blah blah blah blah blah anyway
promotional thing out of like you sping
the promotion you had hinted that there
was additional data other than just call
center drones that did not get promoted
by not being seen by their 19th century
meant factory mentality managers is
there actual you know relevant to this
crowd data or you know to hinted I
didn't see any of the fun notes so it
depends on what you consider relevant
like not not to be obnoxious no no truly
I we could not find any data that
actually looked at you guys so if there
any graduate students I don't know in
the audience where are the graduate
students I definitely wanted to
encourage doctor / to continue this work
because not the least of which because
then we get to see her more often and
let it be awesome
and another variable that that's
worthwhile considering is in the work
from work thing other than the you know
other teams open plan versus a standard
office space would be an interesting
variable to include in this future work
that's a great idea interesting talk um
who are you Ted ceiling sprint sorry
Dave is there any data from this that
shows by like industry type or sector
whether it's fortune 50 fortune 100
where this how this worked from home
thing distributes across those guys
because I'm curious you know this is a
text industry centric thing that you're
looking at or is it across the board I
appreciate the fact that that you guys
are giving these researchers a little
bit more credit than is actually due to
them no I really that I mean right very
obvious question I wish we had the
answer no so that it's a mess these
studies are a mess because people don't
have consistent definitions they're not
consistently looking at the same worker
populations but I will tell you there
are a couple of papers that are cited
that are looking at professional workers
but none of them look specifically at
you know IT workers but i think that the
professional worker ones are sort of the
closest you can get and no they don't
break it down by sort of fortune 50
fortune 500 the problem with that in
part has to do with the way business
school research and employer sort of
research gets done so there are for
example white papers released by
corporations who studied their own
people you read those and you think like
I feel like you didn't tell me
everything right and I think they
probably don't so the data are just not
that great in terms of what's out there
now again a call to the graduate
students in the audience wherever you
are thank you networking if I was
juniper one of the things I have to
question is medical collusion is being
bad
we'll work from home are not necessarily
is promoted as much know if we go way
back no to a book called Peter Principle
know that people tend to get promoted to
their level of and competence and one of
the things that can be observed for
people that are in industries that can
support working from home is that does
that company have or have not a
technical track versus a managerial
track because typically what promotion
means after a certain point most
companies is you get pushed up to
management and that's not necessarily
where people have no their skills and
where they can do the best job yeah
that's it it's a it's a sound point we
did not mean to imply that either
getting promoted or making more money
were universally desired or positive the
point is to is to highlight that this
appears to be a fairly firm outcome of
spending most of your time remotely if
it turns out you're happy with your
salary and you live somewhere like cheap
and it's good for you and your lifestyle
and your family you don't feel the need
to get promoted then like full
disclosure you're all set right so yeah
no it's a fair point and we should have
hit that harder thanks my pound said
Phileas justify your crack smoking there
first no yeah I keep telling we keep
trying to get rid of them baby please
succeed so there there are a couple of
studies out there that are sort of might
be peripheral e related to this that
I've seen that look into constant our
problem solving and creativity as
related to a concentration and
interruption and met so my own like
personal experience from this is that
working from home I actually get a lot
more creative work done because I don't
get somebody wandering by my desk every
10 minutes to say hi or to ask a random
question or whatever those stuff that
stuff all goes into email and when I'm
done solving the problem i'm working on
then i can go and check on that and and
i find that that type of stuff becomes
way more productive when i'm trying to
figure out a problem in some code or do
a design work or
anything like that and I'm kind of
curious if you guys came across anything
related to that when we were when you're
working on this that was to be honest
that's part of why although the pictures
that we put in of where we're working
right now are kind of funny that's part
of why we put them in actually if you
look at my work from home environment I
have many fewer distractions than todd
has his work from work environment and
that's true i would tell you and the
answer on the creativity thing is a long
answer and i'm not going to like delay
everyone's coffee with the long answer
but i would love to talk to you about it
because the the data on the creativity
stuff are fascinating and so yes I and I
can tell you having been an intern and a
resident that there's robust data from
studying us about interruption and the
way in which our capacity to
problem-solve goes right down the tubes
when you interrupt me every 15 seconds
my pager goes off right so that is true
but the creativity part is they really
do those pagers I'm not kidding sorry
you said pager and they're like what she
says or what is a pager sorry going um
but the creativity stuff is a little bit
more complicated but I'd be happy to
talk to you about that in detail he
likes the only other thing to point out
and to remember and this may be obvious
to you guys is that intra-group
differences massively outweigh the
intergroup differences human beings are
complicated and there's a huge range of
behaviors this is like when people look
at gender differences in though I women
are X and men are lying you're like
there's a one-percent different set the
peaks and massively overlapping curves
right this is just like that there are
some people for whom this doesn't apply
and your anecdotes will fit into these
curves somewhere Randy with the last
question Randy bush iij um this was
really good thank you but I've got to
say something which is I'd like to ask
David in the audience why they find the
profession of gynecology more amusing
than router geek and why people laughed
at broad I thought was a rather
obnoxious comment
I am NOT in the audience and I'm not
Dave but I'm gonna say i think
gynecology is kind of funny like I've
been a gynecologist for I'll just say a
long time now and we all kind of think
it's funny I think it's good to have a
sense of humor about what you do for
living and to be honest I sometimes take
care of people in life-or-death
situations and at the end of the day I
have to be able to laugh about it or I'm
not going to get through it Randy I have
an immense amount of respect for the
work that Beth does and for all
Gynaecologists around the world for that
matter I consider her a friend and I
apologize if our playful banter was
offensive but that was in no way meant
like that thank you thanks for your time
folks thank you
real quick a couple of