so I'm really excited to see this
presentation you know this is discussing
distributed mesh infrastructures with
all of the tumult and turmoil that we've
seen around the world one thing that we
know is that you know the network needs
to be resilient and finding new ways to
interconnect people you know aside from
what we just think about of you know
fiber is is critical and so I'd like
Sasha and I guess josh king to come up
here and present on this thank you thank
you how's everyone today silent
seriously thank you all for coming out
here I'm actually used to speaking in DC
to a bunch of Hill folks and white house
people in State Department people and
I'm used to being kind of the the geek
geekiest person in the room and now I
feel like sort of like a lilliputian
nerd compared to the knowledge and
expertise that's here and this is why
I've actually asked my technical lead
Josh King to come in because for all
that I know about our work he knows far
far more and I have a suspicion that
some of you may wish to dive into the
weeds far deeper than I wish to go most
of my work in DC is as a part of a push
this once or
and you can see I just go next to
technology and it breaks so I I work at
a think tank called the New America
Foundation where I'm vice president
there it's about 150 people and about 50
of us are part of the open Technology
Institute which I run and you have to
imagine a place DC is completely swarmed
it's overrun by lawyers and more
importantly it's overrun by lawyers that
wish to play technologists and so if
you're wondering like why do they keep
making these crazy decisions in DC it's
because honestly most of the time they
have no idea what they're talking about
when it comes to tech policy and so into
that space the open Technology Institute
was created five years ago with a fairly
simple plan which was to bring
technological acumen into discussions
we're all too little of it existed you
can see our mission statement there and
so we have sort of the traditional
think-tank arm of our work this is sort
of the juan curi these are the people
making white papers and holding
conveniens and working with people
inside the beltway on developing policy
these are the people that are going up
onto the hill and banging our heads up
against various brick walls for fun but
also and unlike any other think tank in
this area we have a field operations arm
and the field operations are more the
folks are out in community deploying
networks now the project we're going to
speak about today very much lies at the
center of these two areas plus the tech
development the work that we do in-house
to actually build open technologies of
various sorts and we have sort of two
big research development tech projects
one is called measurement lab which is
available measurement lab net this is a
another network
measurement platform that I founded with
Vint Cerf back in 2009 I guess it would
be and we just actually surpassed about
700 terabytes of data all licensed under
Creative Commons 0 license so anyone can
use it and I for one I'm definitely
going to pick up an atlas probe and plug
it in at the office and see if there's
other ways that we might collaborate
because I see this all as a mechanism to
inform key policy makers with empirical
data which is a very radical notion in a
lot of the circles that I work but I'm
not going to talk about measurement lab
today because in fact what we're going
to be talking about is commotion and
commotion began in essence about 13
years ago in my living room where in my
utter technical naivete I invited a
bunch of local hackers and system
administrators and super geeks while I
was looking in urbana champaign over for
homebrew and pizza and thought this was
going to be a summer project to develop
some sort of distributed ad hoc mesh
system that we could all build over a
large geographic area well as you can
imagine it's now 13 years later we're
still building it but it has in fact
grown far outpacing the size and scale
of my living room and now has a global
R&D capacity and whereas we began this
project looking at it through the lens
of how do we bring affordable
connectivity to those that are under
unserved and this would have been prior
to the prior to the new millennia that
we were beginning this today the
number-one interest from folks like the
State Department and US aid and radio
free asia is this notion that these
exact same technologies have a different
facet to them which is distributed
secure communications in places where
censorship surveillance monitoring is a
major problem or where the internet
itself
munication systems like your cellular
infrastructure have been shut off
entirely so that said josh king it's
probably one of the smartest
technologists I've ever met I first met
him probably in in my living room or at
the urbana-champaign independent media
center in urbana and luckily enough I
was able to convince him to pick up and
move halfway across the country to join
me in Washington DC there are few facets
of this project that he hasn't had a
direct hand in and there it's no
exaggeration say there are few people on
the planet and maybe no one on the
planet that knows more about this
project and a wide swath of different
open-source mesh technologies than he
does so I want to bring up my longtime
co-conspirator to then take you through
kind of an overview of commotion and
what it means and what we could do with
these technologies what we're working on
today and what you might be interested
in helping us with as we continue to
develop the commotion project
okay hi presentation tag-team style it's
actually the back of a pickup truck and
I think yeah so the commotion wireless
project is something that we've been
that's based on a lot of work that we've
been doing for years in the community
wireless networking and open source mesh
wireless networking space and sort of
building on a lot of the technologies
that we've worked with a bunch of other
developers on over the last few years
and where I see the really valuable the
really valuable purpose of this
technology is in being able to push a
sort of education innovation about
network technology and into the hands of
communities and being able to make the
edges of the network as you know as
redundant and fault-tolerant as we try
and make the core of the internet and
there are a lot of really great examples
of networks that are built kind of from
this grassroots level up like there's
the Athens wireless metropolitan network
that has that covers most of
metropolitan Athens in the surrounding
area and has eleven hundred and twenty
nodes and 2900 like client relays or
queefy net in Barcelona that has 31,000
nodes and 36,000 kilometers of links
obviously I got tired of drawing dots
and lines long before I got to 31,000
but why don't we see those sorts of
networks like those networks demonstrate
a lot of opportunities for the sort of
technology you know as being test beds
for things like delay tolerant networks
being served
dynamically disruption tower and being
able to route around problems in in the
networks and as test beds for local
applications and new use cases for
networks that communities come up with
being able to use applications that
exists only within they exist and
operate only within local community we
worked with communities that come up
with ideas that if they had their own
local infrastructure what would they use
it for that some of the examples that
we've had our people who want to build
wireless air quality monitoring networks
because they they live in a polluted
neighborhood or they live in a
neighborhood that's underserved for
connectivity and so they want to be able
to host their own local maps and
community calendars or they have a need
for an event or a protest or something
where they need to be able to
communicate amongst each other and
distribute information but no such easy
use infrastructure exists and
distributed networks late like that can
also be extremely tolerant to different
kinds of disruption but either like
natural disruption or you know two
takedowns or two other sort of
influences that might cause different
parts of the network to fail they're
able to dynamically route around those
sorts of problems but if we see those
sorts of networks in places like Athens
or in in Barcelona why don't we see
large scale community networks
distributed networks like that in the
u.s. that are get built up from you know
just interested community members well
there are a number of challenges
involved in that like the overall
technical complexity of building a
large-scale network dealing with
scalability issues a lot of these
networks are based on Wi-Fi and other
unlicensed wireless technology that
doesn't necessarily scale that well
beyond
a couple of dozen nodes and most of
these networks are built by people who
are I mean they're mostly built by a
bunch of german hackers who only use
command-line interfaces for anything and
don't make any sort of interfaces that
are very accessible to to make it
possible for a community that's
interested in creating their own their
own infrastructure what that's an
activist community or just a
neighborhood here in a city in the u.s.
there are no real like documentation or
entry points for them to be able to
build a network like this to be able to
start learning about networks and what
they can use them for in order to add
value to their own to their own
communities so what the commotion
project does is to try and take a bunch
of these existing open source
technologies and build their
interoperability build cross-platform
interfaces for them create planning
tools like this is a community mapping
tool that we've been working with some
developers in brooklyn on on creating
called tide pools that enables
community-based mapping and planning of
networks and interacting with with their
networks and resources on the network in
their communities that allow them to
take just installing it on a few devices
installing mesh networking software on a
few devices in a room in order to build
a small network and being able to take
that from the small scale to the large
scale so that networks like those that
exist in some of the examples that i
gave in europe are are more attainable
by engendering those sorts of those
sorts of tools and those sorts of
planning skills in the communities that
we work with and allowing them to build
local applications that can run on the
network and be utilized for local
purposes
so that in the event of disruption of
internet connectivity or for purposes
that are purely localized the owners and
operators the community that runs the
network is able to have agency over
those applications that operate on the
network so where we are now with that
project is that we're engaged in lab
testing of the software the software
that we have is is designed to run on on
consumer grade and commercial grade
routers on linux mac and Windows desktop
machines on android and iphone mobile
devices to allow people to get their
hands on networking technology to be
able to learn about it and to be able to
plan out these networks as part of a
learning curriculum that we developed
through our work with domestic test beds
for further testing of the software and
through a program called digital
stewards which is a train the trainer
program that we operate in a lot of the
communities that we work with digital
stewards is a six-week training
curriculum that teaches non-technical
users everything from how networks work
different kinds of antennas how to
install software on routers how to plan
networks how to you know install them on
rooftops and in buildings and by the end
of the course they have the basic tools
that they need in order to be able to
learn about and implement these
localized community infrastructures in
their own neighborhoods and then we're
working to select new sites where we can
work with with new neighbor like new
communities and new neighborhoods
internationally so that we can roll that
into our our training program and our
documentation
and build use cases for our for our
software so that we can get better
translations and make it more applicable
and continue to extend its reach as far
as training and ease of use to everyone
to outside of the US sorry wrong button
so thank you if you have any questions
where our websites and email addresses
are up on there or if anyone has any
questions any questions
it tell us a little bit more about how
this could be used in you know I make
sure mentioned earlier stuff like
current political situations well one of
the one of the things that we're working
on is sort of making this a useful
platform for for people to be able to
build out their networks for Internet
connectivity and local communications so
that in the eventualities at that in a
political situation you know in Arab
Spring kind of situation or something
like that where network connectivity
gets shut off that infrastructure is
already in place and allows people to
communicate locally even if traditional
means of access to the Internet aren't
available and also to be able to make it
easy to use things like mobile devices
to create sort of smaller ephemeral
networks so that just being able to pass
messages and photos and and things like
that and you know sort of a smaller
gathering or in a protest or something
like that so that things like that can
get distributed amongst a large number
of people in a delay tolerant fashion so
that if any one device or any one person
you know losses or gets confiscated
their device that their their
communications there my pictures and
media can get distributed anyway I'll
just add to that that you know after
Hurricane sandy when all communications
was out in the neighborhood where we had
one of our testbed sent then became the
mechanism the way in which people are
able to communicate locally and so we we
accidentally if you all had sort of a
real-world test case of the disaster
scenario where this kind of distributed
mesh could exist and be useful to local
community members we obviously
you know the State Department's support
that we've received is specifically
focused on what happens in say in Egypt
to where the main infrastructure the
main internet connectivity or cellular
structures turned off is there a
mechanism one can use in order to enable
people to communicate in a distributed
manner locally and continue to swap
information swap media etc we s just
last Friday if you go to our website
we're talking about sort of what I will
call the the bart scenario whereby we
were testing interconnection amongst
devices on a subway train that did not
have any internet connectivity to see if
it was possible in that kind of
environment to have communications in a
distributed manner and you have to go to
our website to see what we found out but
those kinds of use cases abroad and
domestically or exactly what these kinds
of technologies are incredibly useful
for uh Keith Mitchell ENSO art I think
the objectives of your project are
commendable oh man it is great to see
the progress on it I am however very
concerned about your IP addressing
architecture is my understanding correct
that you are reusing address ipv4
address space that is already been
assigned elsewhere on the Internet yeah
that is the case the but we're working
to change that so the reason for that is
that at its outset when I started
developing the firmware that would
become one part of the commotion project
was that we had a need from one of the
communities that we were working in to
be backwards compatible with an
open-source mesh routing firm were
called Robin and that was the routing
scheme that the Robin firmware used and
so that's what we ended up using not
writing seeing sorry the addressing
scheme that the Robin firm were used and
so that was what we ended up with as a
default my understanding is that the
reasoning behind that on the part of the
Robin community was that at some time
those addresses may have been
you know sparsely utilized I don't know
if that's actually like a a valid
reasoning but it's something that we're
actively working to change and it didn't
make it into our most recent release to
change that as the default addressing
scheme but we'll make it into our next
point release to move to private
addressing space we'd like to move in
the direction of you know using all ipv6
on the back hall of the network it's
going to require some additional testing
just because we are any like one of our
mandates is to support so many different
operating system platforms that is a lot
of different networking stacks and a lot
of different software a test and ensure
that it's compatible with ipv6 but at
the very least we're moving the
direction of changing to like a all
private address space for the next point
release because yes there's a problem
okay thank you Chris kundiman um I
understand the challenges slide cost
wasn't one of the things that was listed
and I wondered if you'd tell us like the
examples in the European cities how are
they funded how do these things come
about uh they actually come about in a
bunch of different ways depending on the
network so it's it's really interesting
a lot of the different networks have
extremely different models of
organization and extremely different
models of of funding as the organization
both from a standpoint of people and
from the standpoint of like how the
network itself is managed for instance
the network the Athens network is almost
entirely completely ad-hoc collective
where individual participants all
purchase and own their own nodes and
it's there's a loose sort of like
Congress of no donors that that form
broad network policy but it's
largely unmanaged but there's sort of
the network itself sort of the ethic
behind is to engender a strong sense of
personal responsibility behind that and
mostly any uplinks that network was
actually founded before there was a
cheap available broadband access in
Athens so it was originally founded
almost as entirely as a local network
without any sort of dedicated source of
uplink stand so that wasn't necessarily
a requirement for their funding model to
fun up links to the internet now they do
have up Winx I understand mostly like
donated or they're funded through
donations but there are other networks
like one that I didn't mention because
it's just in one city and so it would
just ended up being like one big dot but
there's the funk for a network in Vienna
Austria has about 600 nodes that cover
most of downtown Vienna and a lot of the
surrounding neighborhoods and they
actually have a very tightly controlled
and managed network that they they
manage through a close association they
are whatever the Austrian equivalent of
a 501 C 3 is I believe and they fund the
operation of their network by running a
micro colocation facility through their
main fibre uplink and they are they're
actually able to make enough through the
colocation fees to fund the upkeep and
operation of their network so they're
extremely varying sort of methods for
funding the networks and something that
we have a strong focus on is just in
trying to build a toolkit of technology
and documentation that's flexible enough
that can support a lot of these
different organizing models because what
we find is that different models of
funding and organization and network
management different models work better
in different communities and so we just
want to be able to support as broad a
swath i would say that generally
speaking you know hardware wise and
operationally
the costs of deploying one of these
networks is probably significantly lower
than deploying like enterprise-class
gear and trenching fiber but it's I mean
there are trade-offs there too because
you don't have gigabit capacity
generally speaking either but yeah so
different for different networks I guess
sure thanks and kind of a follow-up
question to that you had like a next
step slide that went into you know we
were working on the software obviously
and then looking at kind of pilot
projects to develop a summer with and
then the training where are you actually
out with that you have like other pilot
networks in the u.s. that are doing this
and are there people that have been
trained and yeah where have you actually
gotten on that so we have pilot networks
in detroit in brooklyn new york in
washington DC we have spoken with a few
other people who have started up small
networks just by downloading our
software off of the website they the
platform that's for this long right now
is the routing firmware so it's in that
sense it's kind of traditional community
wireless network stuff like fry funk
stuff but so we have small testbed
networks to in Detroit to and DC and one
in Brooklyn that are all running our
software and are being managed by
community members in cooperation with us
so we're working with them in order to
build out the network's the digital
stewards curriculum training program
we're currently running that I can tell
you like if we've actually completed the
first course of digital stewards but
we're running it in Brooklyn and in
Detroit thanks I Greg Dendy with equinix
you may have just touched on my question
I understand that your technology helps
support the occupy DC movement are there
any successes or challenges around that
you can discuss definitely some
challenges one of the lot of the biggest
challenges there
were just practical deployment issues
and I was largely around the fact that
at that point I mean still the the
router base platform is kind of our
flagship platform and some of the other
platforms like the desktop clients and
Android and all of that kind of aren't
quite as far along in their development
cycles but because of that we deployed
routers in like you know we donated
routers to occupy DC but mostly the
problems there were just around
electricity because we didn't have the
it was kind of a spontaneous thing and
we didn't have like batteries and solar
panels and they were you know plugin p
OE routers the burn watt power and they
weren't really like designed to main
problem was that they were running it
off of a generator that frequently went
down because they ran out of gas and so
the network was just too unreliable for
them to really make use of but we got a
lot of good feedback and from people who
were able to use the network when I was
up and it shows the need that we need to
since then we've focused more on both
the mobile clients and enhancing their
capabilities doing some upstream Android
work to support that and also focusing
more on like power consumption on solar
and battery powered hardware platforms
things like that
let me also add the first week of
October that'll be sort of a global
gathering of people from the community
wireless realms if you point your
browsers to wireless summit org I'll be
in Berlin first week right before
oktoberfest for those that might be
interested in such but good to fir in
germany in that month for sure any other
questions
thank you thanks