okay next up you up Snyder's are you
here there is okay we've got you over
speaking about hearing DB accuracy hi I
want to talk a little bit about how
accurate the data is empirically and
what that might mean for you as a
network operator when automating the
hell out of your network I'm job
Snyder's I work for our ATO shadow as a
lot of peering and it is in this slide
that I became inspired to some research
in this area I also recently joined the
peering to be admin team and I do suffer
grouting originally clearing the B was
conceived by the Illuminati to crack
down on big transit and gift a little
man a chance of finding each other and
set up hearing this eventually evolved
into a website based on PHP and on that
website I've heard of what you could
call critical a SMS has registered some
kind of information regarding their
network now critical a Zen is a very
loose definition hearing to be in my
opinion was a real game changer because
it made life so much easier than
scraping CSV files or parsing HTML to
find out what the other guys IP
addresses are appearing to be is run by
volunteers there are some people in that
men team that are truly dedicated and
they spent hours per day munching
through tickets and helping users to get
this running the data itself similar to
Wikipedia is one hundred percent user
submitted there is no import from other
databases like your IX or internet
exchanges themselves this is all user
submitted data an example peering
be record might look like this in the
upper right corner you'll see a listing
of internet exchanges and next to it IP
addresses and then Bend with information
you can lie all you want nobody will
check this information and in the left
side you will see various nuggets of
information like which I are our record
could be used or the company name or
phone numbers anything you want it's
your record and you can fill it peirong
DB offers various interfaces for
automation you can talk a sequel against
appearing DB server I don't really
recommend using this because it tends to
be a little bit slow also every night
around one or 2am Standard Time dump of
the sequel database is published on an
HTTP URL and you can import that on your
own sequel server and hammer the hell
out of that and then of course there is
the web interface which I showed in the
previous slides in the future we hope to
offer restful api swith kinky keywords
such as jason or maybe even if xml and
but but that's the future we don't have
that today now what we're going to
discuss is the big question how useful
is to use the submitted data in peering
leeby can i actually just import the
data and really run my tools against
this and use it to semi automatically
turn up HP sessions to address this
problem we figure there are two useful
data sources out there one is the data
source or data set that we want to
validate clearing the beat the sequel
dump and the other one that is very
useful as actual show bgp summary
outputs from real networks will throw
this all together in one giant cocktail
and then go over to brazil
it's to collect those show bgp summaries
i created a small website research top
hearing the be calm and last week i
emailed that around to people i visit
this website submit your data and help
out assessing the accuracy on the
website there was a big input fields
where you could just copy paste from
your cisco brocade iOS XR and juniper
and a gigantic monstrous regular
expression would go over that input and
figure out what the clearing sessions
look like so from this example you'll
see quite some established sessions and
those are of interest and there's also
one or two shutdown sessions and we
throw those away because they mean
nothing in this research you press
submit and the website would give you
feedback is this what you want to submit
and the website would try and figure out
which sessions are actually on IX piece
and which are not and discard everything
that is not relevant so information such
as how many prefixes you send or how
many you receive it doesn't matter the
only thing that mattered was to remote
IP and a remote ASM and by submitting
data on this website you would confirm
that you have seen an established
session with this IP and asn quite some
networks contributed data to this small
work among some white some big networks
also a lot of small networks it came
from all over the place in total 33,500
bgp sessions were submitted through this
tool and a my opium it was quite a good
number it was spread over two hundred
fifty six individual submissions and
this is ran for like seven days so not
too shabby so data source one are
peering DB data set that we want to
verify today in peering the be there are
roughly
4700 networks registered and that
represents about ten percent of the
default free zone in those records there
are connections are describes at the
bottom you see such an example it is our
listing of tea cakes Frankfurt and what
we do is we list our IP for address in a
record and in a separate record we list
our ipv6 address there are about 15,000
of such records in the peering DB
database the IP address view in the
current bearing DB implementation is a
far char 128 it has to be unique but you
can essence put anything you want there
and I've noticed they're quite some
people use this freedom to describe
impossible garbage I especially like the
second IP in this list because I think
the guy was trying to combine the best
of ipv4 and ipv6 and stick that in one
string well but this a lot of this is
Commons which is ok I mean if you're
leaving an exchange or going to an
exchange at some point that could be
useful for people to know but there is
points on just just you can throw that
away after say fifteen thousand entries
in peering the be about ten percent is
not possible if you don't do a little
bit of scrubbing and with some very
light scrubbing here's a small Python
example it's like two lines you already
recover like sixty percent of that
impossible IP entries in this case the
scrubber strips leading and trailing
white spaces it removes everything after
a slash and the remaining part it tries
to parts as an IP address object in
Python and if that works cool it must be
an IP address if it doesn't work it's
useless data if we use this this small
scrubber and look at what's in the
records sixty nine and a half
of the user submitted data in peering TB
is possible they are valid IP for and
ipv6 addresses and see be honest I felt
this number would be much much lower but
only 680 entries are useless and we can
probably hunt down those users and ask
them to rectify this and make something
more useful now the second data source
is are what I call ground truth the
actual sightings that networks report
regarding established btp sessions that
they have seen in wild as i mentioned
earlier 33,000 sightings were published
twenty eight percent of those were ipv6
sessions and seventy-two percent were IP
four sessions the 33,000 sightings were
about 11,000 unique combinations of ipm
asm so that means that for a lot of
records we in essence on average got
about free confirmations whether it was
up and correct or not out of those 11
thousands I matched it again against
appearing DB database I XP operators can
describe which prefix is they're peering
and prefix so I matched all the sessions
against that list of prefixes and
roughly 9,000 unique tuples remains that
we could identify as something that was
known in appearing to be database 67,000
bgp sightings could immediately be
confirmed with the peering DB entries
this meant that from all data that was
submitted 75% of it had some
corresponding entries in the peering DB
database this another take on that
number is that we validated forty-three
forty-four percent of the entire data
set in peering to be so in my amp Ian
I'm not a scientist this represents a
good portion of the data there so we
don't need to do very complicated
extrapolations only 64 IP addresses
resulted in what I call a conflict where
what was seen in the wild deviated from
what was registered in peering to be
alcione zoom in on those 64 IP addresses
fifty-seven of those were IP four
sessions and I I went through all 64 of
them to try and figure out why what was
seen in the world did not match the
peering DB database and I concluded that
sixty percent of those entries that were
in conflict were actually IP addresses
registered by some company in the
peering DB database the company left an
internet internet exchange and the
internet exchanged and recycled IP
address and gave it to a new party and
you could kind of figure this out by
looking at the dates of when the last
update was done to appearing the be
record or a look at which ASAS number
was higher or lower so old still data is
something we as admins need to figure
out how we can pursue people to to
update it twenty-six percent of these
conflicting sightings were actually
networks that have merged or we're
migrating from one as2 another and I do
what I think is the local ass trick to
to all clearing sessions where maybe
they cannot reach the other peer but
they want to keep hearing so they'll
just give up and use local ass to keep
that session up and running fourteen
percent was just typos where to where
people would just flip two digits in the
a s number or something that really
looks like oh i fat fingered this oops
and about eight percent I just had no
clue why what I saw in the show bgp
summary data was deviating from keyring
to be it
the sixty percent still data most of
those entries were actually the Moscow
internet exchange did really stood out I
don't know why but that was it so let's
look at what this means seventy-five
percent overlap between the peering
leiby data and the sightings in the
walls forty-four percent of pier going
to be has now been verified as correct
this means that ninety-nine percent of
the data impairing Leiby is actually
correct and a flabbergasted because I I
thought it would be seventy-five percent
so that's why I included the next slide
ninety-nine percent guys it's awesome
this means we can really use peering
Libby and everybody should use it the
fortune in essence is about it percent
so if one out of every hundred peering
sessions that you set up go wrong that's
a very good score it will lower the
burden on your knock surface desk keep
in mind that scrubbing the data that you
get from keyring to be is worth the
effort you'll easily yield a few hundred
extra IP addresses from appearing to be
and if we would optimize the scrubber a
little bit I we could even make it into
something where we salvaged seventy-five
or eighty percent of IP addresses that
have been mistyped in a way well as
admins will talk about whether it is
acceptable to force a little bit of
scrubbing on this should it be well text
or not or should we make a separate
comment fields and a separate IP feel
which can never be anything else than an
IP address we'll figure that out at some
point how can you keep improving the
data in peering DB how can you ensure
that will keep the number high as it is
I recommend that in the current peering
to be set up
one IP address per entry I've seen quite
some people that try to fit both an ipv4
and an ipv6 address on the same line
because they feel it's cheating to list
the entry twice and then double listing
the bandwidth as well for a fee 674 I
don't care about bent with at all if I
want to appear with you I want accurate
information that's the only thing that
matters to me so to accomplish this I
really urge you guys one IP address /
field don't enter comments don't add
subnet masks don't only IP addresses in
terms of automation and the steal data a
number that we saw an option could be
that in the future of peering maybe you
will add some some freshness factor
where if you request through this
beautiful JSON API that will really
arrived some day in the future we're not
committing anything here where you could
say like give me the most the entries
that were updated most recently and this
will be a nice feature because you can
have the old records from networks that
left internet exchanges you don't have
to touch their data but you allow new
commerce that got that recycled IP
address and they update it more recently
so it's probably more accurate we could
do stuff like that maybe it's worth
while maintaining this feedback loop
where say once every half year we ask
networks like submit your show bgp
summaries so we can verify the current
state of peering to be we could make a
periodical thing out of this if the
community would appreciate that and keep
scrubbing data that you pull from
peering to be really do some sanitizing
on what you expect and then a lot of it
is workable like ninety nine percent and
this concludes my short presentation on
curing the bees a curious
and I was wondering are there questions
that you would like answered Lou I'm
Patrick from let's call the peering gb
today so we looked at your dad I'm we
actually talked about this sorry
everybody else that we're talking about
something we discussed but I think it's
important to the group we talked about
this and you for instance notice that
Akamai had some data that would
mismatched because we were locally
asking some peers do do legacy stuff
where does that fit into your data and
with if did you look at how many people
were doing something like that did that
make you a higher or doesn't matter
because the ninety-nine percent kind of
washed over that anyway well so for
instance the Akamai entries were in the
64 conflicted IP addresses so the
ninety-nine percent is everything that
really where the real world correlates
with what peering Libby States in your
particular case I think a nice feature
in impairing they'd be would be that you
could list maybe legacy asns for a for
an entry and it you could say well our
preferred a s for this IP address is our
new a s or the big is but you might
still have sessions somehow with this
this and this is but these are actually
corner cases given the low numbers thank
you
all right anybody else I mammoth from I
can and you mentioned that when you're
typing the IP address is not to use
columns or anything like that in the
stead I think it would be useful peering
DB to allow those who are just want to
let others know that they are in the
exchange point but they don't
necessarily want to display an IP
address there i think there should be
somewhat like an option there where no
that is possible right now that i know
that some people are using columns like
me that's basically my policy i just
peer with the route servers but it will
be good to have that option so i am in
the exchange point but i don't
necessarily want to show my IP address I
I agree one of the strong things about
appearing to be is actually the fact
that you can put in whatever data you
want and I originally I was like no it
all must be strict and we must force
people to enter IP addresses otherwise
my script doesn't work but others
pointed out well it's maybe your few but
other people like you just want to list
at their present and not necessarily
disclose more information than they deem
needed so in a new appearing to be
iteration I think it would be good to
make all kinds of data optional but that
you could classify what the information
means so instead of having a mixed IP /
commons / empty field you could have
something like don't publish my IP
address or this is a comment regarding
the connection so it would be easier for
parsers to figure out what the data
means yet keeping that freedom of what
you want to enter into the going to be
Kevin Bloomberg the wire you mentioned
much of the croft with stale data data
as the recycling of I exp eye peas
from the people that have the stale data
or in many cases not in this room is
there a way to really push getting the
feedback to them on some of the simpler
stuff automate it and in some cases just
doing a cleanup day once every two or
three years or to get the people who
aren't in the room getting their data hi
I'm going to take that we're working on
ensuring that the data from the I exes
is correlated correctly the issue is as
it was saying earlier it's all user
entered data so we don't want to just
displayed it we don't want for instance
nixa the wire has this IP address
without your say-so but we also want to
be able to say if you put in an IP
address that the i-x confirms that's
your IP address and if it changes it
away for the i-x to notify appearing to
be not your IP address etc etc etc so
that's all being worked on we actually
have a meeting tonight at six to deal
with it so it it'll be more than
scrubbed every three years hopefully
it'll be scrubbed in real time right
thank you another option in this space
that we have is to try and reach out to
the listed email addresses and the email
address that we have internally and see
if the email bounced if the emails
bounced and they keep bouncing then
after three months we might maybe
conclude that the company doesn't exist
anymore and will maybe flag it as
inactive or we should reach out and
start nagging users that we feel have
incorrect data and peering maybe and try
and convince them to change it instead
of us forcing it upon them okay anybody
else going once going twice okay job
thank you very much thank you for your
time
you