coming up next we've got Larry Sandberg
with BT I Larry morning I'm going to
talk to you today about some advanced
development thinking that we're doing
which really means sort of describing an
alternate universe advanced development
is strange there is still an analogy
from from one of the sessions on the
first day it's it's a matter of trying
to skate to where the puck is going to
be and and you don't always know where
the puck is going to be I will also note
that that over the course of my career
I've had the opportunity to come up with
lots of neat names for products and lots
of neat acronyms for products and some
are pretty good Sock'em is not high on
the list of names but i can assure you
it's better than the previous to that
i've had for this so it's a step forward
so this really comes out of the the fact
that for most of the last 10 years I've
been working as a technologist and an
architect in companies that build
optical equipment packet equipment and
and more to the point packet optical
equipment and I've been distressed over
the course of all of that time that that
packet optical usually means packet and
optical not really packet optical the
the the coordination between the packet
layer and the optical layer has been
either non-existent or my opinion very
poor and a lot of this is clearly due to
the capabilities of some of the optical
hardware more than the packet Hardware
in my opinion and this is driven people
to design networks in particular ways
and and the biggest problem is that
there has been no standard or calming
control infrastructure and this is the
area that I've been focusing on in my
thinking and then I'm going to talk
about a little bit over the next few
minutes so
the problem is that that optical
transport is still thought of as wires
we don't really think of optical
networks yet as dynamic entities at
least not in the way that we packet
people think of packet systems as
dynamic entities and you know part of it
is just sort of the time scale we think
of when we're doing packet processing
and packet switching we're thinking in
in microseconds in milliseconds and
seconds with today's row domes optical
infrastructure we can think of making
changes in days and months fixed optical
was months in years and you know people
who put in telephone wires were thinking
in years and decades and maybe even
centuries so there's a different time
scale in the thought process and again
that thats related in the case of
optical optical equipment to the
capabilities of what's out there today
but with with the advent of some next
generation Rotom hardware that's that's
coming down the pike right now for for
what are called CDC Rotom zorkon
colorless directionless in contention
lyst Rotom 'he's i believe that things
can change drastically so today packet
switches are topology driven people put
in their optical networks first they put
the transport network in place they run
the fiber they light wavelengths that
could be either with transponders it
could be with rodents it could be with
embedded colored optics in the routers
and switches but the point the point is
that that the fiber is run and lip and
then the packet switches are connected
and they see these connections that are
already lit and they talk to each other
and they determine the Jason sees and by
the way everything here is is I'm trying
to be agnostic to packet switching
technology i mean we build switches but
these could be these could be LS RS or
they could be routers they could be
switches that that's really not not the
tenth of the discussion the point is
that the packets which is see each other
over an existing link and they develop
adjacencies then they develop their
forwarding paths they build their
forwarding tables or their their routing
tables whatever and then the services
are defined so you know to some extent
this is like building a road between
pick two cities Boston and New York and
two possibilities one is you build the
straightest possible road between Boston
New York merely to find out that thirty
percent of the traffic all exits at one
place and travels ten miles on back
roads to get to a Depot or alternatively
you build a road between new york and
boston polygamy between 20 cities merely
to find out that 10 of those cities
never have any traffic exiting neither
of those are efficient use of resources
they they both cost money and to some
extent building the optical network and
building the routed network before you
know where your customers are going to
be putting their services falls into a
very similar category so all packet
switches draw their spanning trees
across accessible switches and the
operative word is accessible I mean if
there's no light then there's no
adjacency of course new paths can exist
you can light up a new wave length you
can connect it to your routers and lo
and behold the routers are going to
create new adjacencies and update their
routing tables but that's not something
that the routers did it's something
that's somebody else did and the routers
just discovered so an alternate vision
of the universe in terms of how we deal
with ethernet services and Ethernet
services or the area that I primarily
focus on today Ethernet services are
static monolithic and long-lasting you
know you basically sell a customer 100
megabit service from point A to point B
it's expected to be there all the time
it doesn't come and go and sometimes
it's used sometimes it's not used I
envision the world
a few years out where where they're
dynamic where they're granular people be
creating smaller services but more of
them and they'll be ephemeral they'll
come they'll though you'll create a
service you own creative service I could
even envision a situation where
application libraries you know Python
libraries or C libraries actually have
primitives that let you create an
ethernet service within some
infrastructure like like like you you
can do with AWS to create a variety of
resources and basically say I need I
need 100 megabits from this port to this
port now create the service give me this
qos transfer a bunch of data take the
service down that's not the way services
are today but I believe that as time
goes forward that's that's a way that
people will be using III III net
services if the infrastructure would
would support that but to get there we
really have to turn everything we know
upside down we can't assume that
services are going to go where the
bandwidth is just like we can't build a
road blindly and assume that we know
where the exits are supposed to be we
need to figure out ways of putting the
bandwidth where the services are so that
requires a very different kind of
thinking so imagine if the connections
didn't exist a priori what if if you
started the network as a blank State you
had your your Odom's and your packet
switches and you wired them up but you
didn't really light any wavelengths up
except maybe some supervisory channels
for for letting the rodents talk to each
other for their equalization for letting
the packets which is due LOL EP a-- with
with each other to determine who's out
there and what the topology is but you
didn't actually light any data channels
and then the packet switches and the
optical switches could work together to
figure out where to create paths as
needed as services are created then we
can configure the network dynamically we
could figure out where the bandwidth was
needed we could put the bandwidth where
it was needed and
and we wouldn't we wouldn't have to meet
be guessing about where customers are
going to be placing bandwidth or find
that we've got plenty of and within the
network but not between the two points
where where a particular customer needs
it so Sock'em this is a presentation
about Sock'em and this is basically an
idea for network control system that
uses external control entities to
simultaneously and dynamically allocate
both optical transport paths and dynamic
Transport has ad service initiation for
for dynamic ethernet service we press
the button so basically the way it works
is that you get a request for an
ethernet service now that request could
as it does today come from a management
entity you know as a network management
system or some other management entity
or as I noted earlier it could come from
applications and this probably falls
into the category of what people are
often calling today application-aware
networking so a request comes in for
service and the Sock'em infrastructure
will basically look at that request it
will allocate an optical path and that
optical path could be a an existing
optical path it could be a new
point-to-point path between the two
endpoints or it could be a concatenation
of existing and new optical paths that
are packet switched at intermediate
points a priori it's it there's there's
no right answer there the the decision
is based on on a variety of parameters
and states so there's what are the
existing ports and the existing
wavelengths for that are already
allocated in the network what are the
current instantiated pads what
wavelengths are lit up and we're where
are they going what are the bandwidth
requirements of the new service that
that's a big one you know obviously if I
have a wave
between point A and B that's a 10g
wavelength and I've got a 4G service on
that wavelength I can't add another HD
service to that wavelength so that's
that's an important point quality of
service if this is a low latency service
then I'm more likely to want to have a
small number of hops or packet hops
maybe zero pathan hops between them and
if it's a best-effort service I might be
willing to just so go from hop to have
to hop what are the protection
requirements because you may or may not
want to set up a protection path the
protection path may may need to be
diverse it may not need to be diverse it
mainly the same bandwidth requirements
or the same qos requirements so that's
all part of the decision and and I think
you can envision that there are a
variety of other parameters that you
could enter into the equation again this
is an advanced development project so
this is this is not something that I'm
taking orders for right now it's
something that we're thinking about and
and and doing some prototyping on so let
me walk through through an example so
first of all in the beginning there are
no services and paths there's your
optical network which in this pictures
is shown by the road ohms there are your
packet switches your packet switches
connect to the road ohms for the network
side and there are user interfaces on
the outside now one of the things that
differentiates this right off of that
from the way people do things today is
that that today people tend to populate
their network ports with with
transceivers as they decide to light
them so you usually don't buy a router
and by transceivers for all of the
network ports and hook all of those
network ports into your optical
infrastructure and anticipation of using
them in in this network you would be
doing that I mean maybe not 24 of them
but maybe a half a dozen ports on each
router depending on where you see the
traffic and what the needs are and you'd
basically
neck them up front to the optical
infrastructure but you really wouldn't
be lighting any pads now what happens
when the first service is defined so
customer wants to get a service from
from the top left to the top right
packet switches what will happen is that
the system will say okay I need a path
from packets which a the packets which
be I don't have a path I'm going to
create one and I'm going to use a blue
wavelengths from Rotom ada Rotom be and
there's a rules database that goes along
with this that defines rules for many
many things including what order to
allocate wavelengths on so maybe the
rule is that that you you allocate blue
first and then you allocate red as an
example so I'm going to allocate I'm
going to build the wavelength from the
left-hand Road them to the right-hand
Rotom and then I'm going to program the
packet switch to say okay this service
has a uni on port of Port one it should
be forwarded to two and an i won I
should tune the transceiver on port 12
blue and tunable transceivers are common
today and that's part of the requirement
and then similarly on be I do the same
thing I defined that there's there's a
uni on on z I say that the N and I for
that is on port 5 and now i have my
ethernet service and i'm using exactly
as many wavelengths and and exactly as
many hops as i need to support that
service so what happens next if i add a
couple of months services so I'm going
to add another service between the top
two routers s2 and the system is going
to note that i already have a wavelength
between between those routers the blue
on the two services will fit on that
wavelength so i don't need to create
another wavelength so we just have to
program the packet switch to forward
from the unies to that that network port
on
both of the packet switches and now s1
and s2 are both traveling over that blue
wavelengths between between the two
packet switches I will note again sort
of in the name of being agnostic that
I'm not proposing any given language for
programming these packet switches you
know there's a lot of a lot of open flow
going around and this could be open flow
that that's being used here again it's
not really relevant to the goal of the
solution so now we have one more service
ss3 and that's between the upper left
switch and the lower right switch well
clearly we need another optical path
because we don't have an optical path
today between those two switches so we
have a choice we could either
concatenate two optical paths so we
could go from A to B and then B to D and
packet switch across that path that's a
pretty common way to do it and if
there's enough bandwidth on to you might
want to do it that way or because these
are Rotom networks we could simply
create a wavelength directly from A to D
and if the parameters of the service
were such that that was a reasonable
thing to do so for example if it
required a lot of bandwidth you know if
this was an eight gigabit service you
probably wanted to write its own wave
length anyway or if it was a low latency
service you probably wanted to have the
fewest possible hops so there are there
are a lot of reasons why you might
choose a concatenated path versus a
direct path but in this case I'm showing
a direct path so now we're going to
light up the the red wavelengths we're
going to drop it at packets which a and
we're going to drop it at packets which
d we're not going to drop it at packets
which be we're going to route it
optically at packets which B and now we
have a service from A to D that's direct
and can service s3 and again all three
of these services now are
our by some definition optically routed
in terms of use of resources and and the
requirements of the service themselves
so looking at some of the practical
issues and and and where this really can
provide assistance this is one of our
customers networks this is actually
pretty prototypical network there are
probably a million networks out there
but we have a customer that's replicated
and infrastructure sort of like this in
a bunch of cities so they have a main
ring that is covering a metro usually
has six or eight nodes on that main ring
and then off each of those nodes they
have distribution and access rings and
that main ring I think in their biggest
Metro today has for 10g wavelengths on
it some of the smaller ones are our two
and then most of the distribution rings
are single 10g although I think there
might be a few now that are 210g but
effectively what they've done optical
networks tend to be deployed most easily
in ring architectures for a number of
reasons and what's happened is because
the optical architecture is deployed as
a ring we tend to deploy the packet
architecture is already which means that
effectively most of the traffic goes
from hop to hop to hop to hop around the
ring and this is really a waste of
resources and and it doesn't optimally
route many services that that really
want better service than that the
problem is it's hard I mean the nice
thing about Rotom zyzz it lets you take
an optical ring in turn it into a packet
mesh but to do that on a case-by-case
basis is really complicated as the
number of services go up but even what
happens if if you have a service that
needs to go from there to there and it's
a nine gig service well you know it's
it's going to need the wavelength of its
own on that ring at least between
between the the two paths on the main
ring that
it goes through and today you deal with
that on a case-by-case basis well you
know this customers buying an eight gig
wavelength will light up another
wavelength on the main ring for him and
and do it but in my world in the vision
that I put forward a few slides back
there are lots of those cases people are
creating and destroying services you
know second by second you know
eventually you know the way they do
tcp/ip sessions today there are just a
lot of them you can't route them
optically if you're using a static
architecture like a ring it just it just
won't work and and and you need a better
way to do it and that's what what what
this is all about and the other the
other capability that comes along is
something that we've been calling
wavelength defragmenting you know if you
think about it for a second let's say
you're creating 3 4g services now
obviously you're going to need two
wavelengths for that to carry all three
of those but what happens now if you
delete one of those 4G services in
reality you end up with an extra unused
wavelength now it could be that the two
remaining services are already on one
wavelength in which case you could just
eliminate the first the second one or it
could be that the two remaining 4G
services are on two different
wavelengths but now if you can migrate
one of those services to the other
wavelengths you can reclaim the unused
wavelength you know just like
defragmenting your disk this basically
is an important aspect because what it
does is it frees up wavelengths and nni
ports for more services so a big piece
of the ability to do this dynamically is
the ability to optimize the resources
there's also a power savings because you
actually don't end up having to light
the transceivers that that you're not
using so you effectively can turn on and
turn off your network ports as you need
them to support services that are being
or eliminated so what are the components
of of a solution like this well as I
noted the most important component is
the CDC Rotem the ability for a packet
switch to turn on a transceiver to tune
it to a particular color and then to
have the network program the Rotom to
route that port to a particular degree
dynamically with with with no contention
on other colors is an important part of
the solution you can get these today
they're there they're not real cost
practical to deploy broadly today but
they are happening they effectively need
another wavelength selective switch in
front of the road in order to be able to
direct direct reports you need a packet
switching infrastructure and as I said
right now this is completely agnostic
these can be VLANs they could be pseudo
wires it doesn't really matter how those
services are being carried it needs
tunable transceivers in the packet
switches those are there today we ship
lots of tunable transceivers in the
packet switches they are not real
effectively used today I mean today
honestly they're primarily used as ways
of eliminating large inventories you
know rather than having to own to
inventory spares for 30 different
wavelengths you inventory a few tunable
spares and you can tune them to the
wavelength that you need that's not
really exploiting the power of what you
could do with with tunable transceivers
and then you need an external control
infrastructure and this is this is the
part that needs to develop this is the
this is the hard part and the
interesting part and we basically are
envisioning a system that looks sort of
like this at least from a prototype
point of view so there's there's the
controller and the controller basically
knows how to create optical paths and
how to create the the service pads there
are the Annie's at the bottom which are
the three things that have an optical
and and the packet component there are a
few databases that that drive it there's
a rules database and then of course a
database of services and then there are
people on the right side that are
creating and destroying those services
applications and management
infrastructure and these pieces conspire
together to to create the the dynamic
packet-optical infrastructure which is
sort of my goal important three-letter
words now you can all write checks
because everything has to say Sdn on it
but realistically the the power of SDN
in my mind is that is not that it lets
you do existing things cheaper or better
or in a in a vendor independent way but
that it enables you to do things that
are impossible to do without it or it
facilitates doing things that are just
hard to do without it doing the kinds of
things that I'm talking about with with
Sock'em are really hard to do with
combined data and control plane in the
any because it really requires an entity
that can look at the packet
infrastructure and the optical
infrastructure from above and coordinate
them together I leave that that the
power of SDN is to solve problems like
that not just to sort of do the same
things that we do today and that's why
I'm excited about the advent of SDN
because I think that it will allow us to
solve problems that we can't solve today
so Sock'em puts the bandwidth where the
services are that's probably the most
important aspect today we try to put
services where we've already put the
bandwidth that doesn't work in my mind
for the long term what's important is to
try to figure out how to allocate the
bandwidth for where the servicers are
getting put this requires an external
entity it requires modern modem
technology and it basically configures
the network based on services and flows
this gives you better utilization better
response to changes in load and less
manual configuration less guesswork and
hopefully a better network thank you and
we have time for a few questions he's
either asking a question or going to the
men's room okay okay thanks