hi everybody
welcome to my presentation today we're
going to be talking about using
behavioral psychology
and some analysis techniques to protect
systems
so my name is nikki robinson hello
i am a security architect with ibm by
day i am also an adjunct professor by
night i teach at capital technology
university
i currently have a dsc in cyber security
i was studying vulnerability chaining
and scoring
in depth so if you ever want to hear me
babylon for about three or four hours on
vulnerability chaining just let me know
uh and then i'm wrapping up a phd in
human factors i have defended
my topic which was vulnerability
chaining blindness where i was studying
uh sort of integrating two different uh
phenomenons together uh to determine if
this phenomenon of vulnerability
chaining blindness exists i'm hoping to
publish that before the end of the year
so i do hold some certifications
industry certifications like cissp and
ceh i really specialize pretty heavily
in vulnerability management but i love
continuous monitoring risk management
research analysis
statistics i don't know you name it um
but specifically in the cyber security
world i really like to focus on
vulnerability management
but the last year and a half two years
i've been focused on this human factors
research and that's what's really led me
to th this presentation i i started
seeing some of the
you know the same problems that we see
over and over again uh phishing attacks
um you know you name it the same types
of attacks happening over and over again
and i started to really ask why why are
we still seeing these these same types
of attacks conducted and in the same
ways and how are we not able to to
protect against these things we know
that they exist
and so i really started to to try to
understand how
we could integrate some psychological
uh sort of well-known
uh phenomenon well-known and defined
terminology and and sort of concepts
into cyber security to help us sort of
start to solve these problems
you know one of the things that people
talk about is process and technology and
people or technology process in people
but we don't talk a lot about our people
we talk a lot about the security tools
that we need we talk a lot about you
know processes and policy and frameworks
but we don't always talk about how our
people interact with security whether
that's our users our management
uh even our security and i.t
practitioners so as someone with an it
operations background who's been in
security for for about four years now
you know i'm really trying to to help
understand where those problems are and
uh hopefully by discussing some of these
things
we can sort of start to solve those
problems
so quick disclaimer all thoughts
feelings uh views expressed in this
presentation are my own they do not
reflect my employers
so we're going to be talking about a lot
of different things today but
we're going to start with talking about
i want to lay some of the groundwork for
blue red and purple teams um sort of who
they are
why they're important to this
conversation
before we dive into cognition
perception
cognitive limitations which i think are
really important and then perception and
intention so um
we're going to sort of lay the
groundwork here and then get into some
of the the really fun psychology type
terminology
and another quick disclaimer i am not a
psychologist i'm not a licensed
therapist or anything like that but i do
a lot of research and i think that there
is a lot of merit to
doing some of this academic research and
and trying to blend it into what we do
every day as technical practitioners
so our blue teamers so i can you know i
can say i'm certainly on the blue team
side
as far as network defense goes i you
know our blue teamers they really do a
lot of of different tasks when we talk
about blue teams everything from
continuous monitoring to
actual network security and defense uh
incident response
coming up with different types of
defensive measures security secure
configuration
application hardening creating baselines
all of those kinds of things
even up to
log analysis and correlation so actually
going through those logs and trying to
figure out where are the issues where
are my problems at what what alerts do i
need to configure so so really technical
and hands-on and usually blue teamers
work very closely with other teams um
they work very closely with with
management with it maybe with red teams
as we'll sort of get into in a minute
but
people that work on blue teams need to
have
a lot of different abilities not just
technical abilities but they need to be
able to communicate effectively they
need to be able to communicate to very
highly technical
people that they work with maybe admins
or engineers but they also really need
to be able to help management understand
risk so they have to be able to
effectively communicate into a technical
audience as well as a more of a high
level management uh to help them
understand where the risk might be and
what needs to be worked on so
prioritization and so that's where we
start to have the conversation about
where psychology plays in uh people who
work on the sort of continuous
monitoring side you're probably working
with system owners like i said admins
and you know you have to sort of be able
to tell that story of what
vulnerabilities need to be remediated
and why
to really help people understand you
know not just hey i'm here to tell you
you need to implement 300 controls but
here's why
or here's what we can do instead here
are some mitigating controls that we can
implement instead so the ability to to
work really cohesively with other people
is is an important skill to have on the
blue team side
um
and on the red team side you know uh we
talk about psychology without really
talking in psychological terms which i i
think is very interesting
because social engineering tactics uh
really are behavioral analysis
understanding how people use social
media what information can you find out
about them online do they like dogs do
they like cats um do they like long
walks on the beach you know whatever it
might be but you're really going in and
trying to determine
uh who who your target is and finding
out information about them to help you
gain access basically to their accounts
uh you know with fishing
if you're calling from the red team side
you know trying to get a hold of someone
who might give you some information
about other users or about
email addresses or account information
something like that you're going to be
calling and trying to
uh you know use some techniques to
get someone to feel comfortable talking
with you and that is psychology 100
uh the idea of this hacker methodology
so
the idea that
you know you're really using this
methodological approach to gaining
access into systems there's a lot of
persistence that's needed a lot of
determination that's needed a lot of
sort of this will and this general
curiosity to be able to actually get
into these systems and i think that it
takes a special type of person to have
that sort of determination that will to
say
well i couldn't get in this way i'm
going to try another way and so it's you
know
certain personality traits or
experience or interest that sort of lead
into the ability to sort of be you know
really great at um pen testing
um understanding your targets so from a
psychological perspective you know are
they
um
you know am i trying to target a
disgruntled employee am i trying to
target someone who is in financial
distress they might be an easy target
for me
if i'm trying to gain access into these
systems
and then what information can i get from
them
so really trying to understand you know
who your target is and what valuable
information they might have and how you
can get it out of them is it an email is
it a phone call is it a text message is
it an amazon
uh delivery email that
is spoofed but it you know it looks
legitimate or
is it something with urgency so really
trying to understand who your target is
um is certainly uh behavioral analysis
techniques sort of you know very very
much
so and then purple teams i wanted to
highlight this because i do see some
people talking about purple teams but i
think it's important to highlight here
there's this really great relationship
that that can occur if you have
depending on the size of your
organization that you could have between
red teams and blue teams where you have
people sort of on this you know
remediation or network defense side and
they can really work with red teams to
um have this sort of continuous
iterative process where vulnerabilities
are being found and they're being
remediated this takes a lot of effective
communication so then we start talking
about emotional intelligence the ability
to have empathy the ability to
understand and comprehend you know sort
of what someone else's objectives and
goals are and how they align with yours
and how you can work together and
collaborate to really improve security
in your environment
so i i love the idea of a purple team
sort of ecosystem where you know you
have your defenders who are finding
vulnerabilities and potentially you know
helping to categorize and find those
high risks and maybe interacting with
the red team and saying hey i found this
vulnerability are you able to exploit
this is this something that i should be
really concerned about then your red
teamers can go out there and say yeah
absolutely let me go see if i can do
this um you know and vice versa someone
on a red team someone who's actively
doing a pen test might be able to uh
exploit something maybe they can conduct
a sql injection or something that nobody
noticed and they can go back to that
blue team and say hey i found this
vulnerability are you able to see this
in your security scanning software so
that we can go back and fix this really
quickly
so i felt like it was really important
to bring up purple teams just because i
don't hear them being talked about as
much but i think this can be a really
big benefit and a great way for for
people to work together
all right so let's talk about cognition
so
when i was doing this human factors
research i started to uh really when i
was reading a lot of psychology books
you know behavioral psychology
and even some of the you know i had like
a law enforcement component and so i was
studying sort of behavioral analysis
techniques um you know when they're
looking for criminals looking at
profiles things like that and so i i
started doing a lot of research into
cognition and perception and what i
really found is there's a lot of
information there you know psychology
this field has been around for so long
and there are so many uh terms and ways
to help describe phenomenon that i think
could really be beneficial from the
cyber security side so cognition is
really uh conscious reasoning
but i i love to equate this to chess
because i'm a chess player i've been
playing for a long time and this really
analogy really made sense to me when i
was studying this you know how do you
determine what the best move is if you
are playing a game of chess against an
opponent you're not just going to think
one move ahead you're not just going to
think okay well if they move there then
i'll just try to move here
wha what really great chess players do
is you want to be thinking 30 moves
ahead probably at a minimum if i move
here would they move here if i move here
would they also move here what other
possibilities could occur on the board
when i make this move it's about
implications you know if i move here how
do i think my opponent is going to react
so sort of that the way that we make
decisions
and there are a couple of different ways
that we make those decisions
you know one of them is uh fast thinking
so using our intuition
uh if i'm playing a two minute chess
game versus a 30 to 45 minute chess game
i'm gonna be playing those very
differently if i only have one minute to
make decisions on a full chess game i'm
going to be using my intuition and my
my knowledge what i already have with me
to make those decisions as quickly as i
can versus slow thinking where if i if i
have an hour of time in a chess match
then i'm going to probably play that a
little bit differently i'm really going
to take my time to make those decisions
and say you know is it really worth it
to lose my queen here maybe maybe not
whereas in a fast game you might need to
lose that queen and just keep moving
and the the final note i wanted to make
here was on metacognition so
metacognition is
the
idea that we are
thinking about thinking we're really
trying to identify how did i make those
decisions
why did i make those decisions why did i
allow my queen to be taken in that
moment
so you're really analyzing
how you have made those decisions to
help make better decisions in the future
figuring out where our limitations are
what we can do to sort of improve those
or maybe find better ways to deal with
those limitations so there's really this
sort of this understanding of how we
make decisions and in cyber security you
know that is very very essential
um
so
tying cognition back to cyber security
for a second
i wanted to bring up security tools
because you know that's really
especially from you know either side the
red or the blue team side or anywhere
you might be in cyber security our tools
are sort of our greatest assets we use
them to help us with alerts and logging
and monitoring um
how are we using them how are we how how
are they created to be used for us
um and and are we using them to the best
of you know the the best that we can are
they configured in a way
that helps us do our jobs better are we
missing things by having them
misconfigured um
so how are we actually analyzing and
looking at the tools that we use
uh on a day-to-day basis because we're
not using those tools effectively we
might be missing you know a big a big
piece of the picture we might be missing
vulnerabilities if our security scanning
software isn't configured properly
um if our credentials aren't configured
properly things like that so uh
considering how we use those security
tools i think is like a really important
a note here
um how do we prioritize risk management
is it an important component
how do we make those decisions how do we
decide what risk that we accept
is it based on our business and our
strategy
is it based on our business proprietary
data is it based on a certain number of
assets what are we basing our risk off
of uh so that brings that back to that
decision making component
employee turnover and burnout so uh
am i considering you know my sock
analysts who are working around the
clock they're constantly looking for
alerts and
you know working really hard um am i
considering maybe moving them to another
group where they don't have to you know
be on call all the time that they can
sort of
have some breathing room um because you
know if there's too much turnover that
can actually lead to security issues as
well if you constantly have this
turnover in your in your sock or or in
your security teams
which i know is pretty well documented
in in the industry right now when you
have that turnover it's really difficult
to establish sort of these you know this
constant sort of steady state of
security um you you have more sort of
fluctuating security and every admin is
going to sort of manage and monitor
tools differently so uh you sort of have
to consider that as well that there may
be that learning curve when new people
come on board
and then predicting malicious behavior
again it's where we talk about
psychology without really talking about
psychology where uh whether it's a
inside threat or an external threat
how are we able to predict and determine
uh what a malicious insider looks like
to us
um how what are those indicators
because depending on the industry or
depending on you know what their job is
that behavior may look differently
and so i wanted to touch on uh
perception next because
uh there is some debate in the uh
psychology world on whether cognition
and perception are sort of the same
thing
um
i personally believe that perception is
its own thing uh cognition you know it's
really based in decision making and it
is based on you know our past
experiences but perception is the idea
that
we may interpret or handle a situation
or experience a situation differently
than somebody else based on our
experiences so
if me as security engineer
you know i've had a
uh you know a bad experience
um with maybe a tool like i've had a
i've had a really hard time configuring
it i can't use it properly i may say you
know what my perception is this tool
doesn't work it's terrible
but that's my perception maybe in
another environment it's configured
properly and it works great but
that limits me on my beliefs on that
tool because based on my own experience
so um that's sort of where that
perception ties in
and it really comes from this sort of
sensory information that we've received
so it could be how we see something how
when we touch something how it feels how
we hear something so really based on our
senses
and there's two different ways that we
process uh information in in this way
bottom-up processing and top-down uh
processing
so the bottom-up processing is that
sensory input that i was just talking
about that if you go to the beach and
you touch the sand that you know what
the sand feels like and when you
remember or you think about the beach
that's what you think about
versus the top-down processing which is
how we interpret these sensations but
they are influenced by our experiences
so if i walk into a door and i stub my
toe
um
i'm going to probably remember what that
feels like because i remember that
sensation of me stubbing my toe in the
door and wow that really hurt um so it's
it's uh really interesting to sort of
see the different ways that we process
this information and how it affects the
way we perceive situations
so tying that back to cyber security
how do our past experiences influence
our decision making this is one of the
most important notes that i want to make
from this presentation is something to
take away and consider in your own
environment in your own world in your
own organization on your own team
how has past experiences influence
security and decision making in your own
uh environment
so for example if
you had an experience with someone that
you know you were constantly trying to
make something happen you're trying to
constantly make a project happen and
you're working with someone and maybe
you know they're not responsive or
they're not getting back to you or
something might be happening
where you're not getting those responses
that may influence my decision to work
with that individual again i might say
you know what they weren't really
responsive last time i'm not going to
ask them to help
but what might have really been going on
is maybe they were overloaded with other
projects maybe they were having
technical issues maybe they were having
personal issues and they were really
just out of the office
and just hadn't really talked about it
or some any other number of things but
that perception uh will live with me
because i'll say yeah gosh you know i
don't i think i'm going to consider it
before i work with that person again
and this other idea of being able to pay
attention
so
if i'm looking at alerts all day if i'm
staring at you know a dashboard all day
how much can i really stare at this
before i start losing interest and start
losing information so if i'm staring at
alerts all day long alerts alerts alerts
they keep coming through
at some point i'm gonna get bored and
i'm not gonna be looking at them as
effectively as i probably would be at
the beginning when i was really looking
through alerts so
how long do you have stock analysts
looking at alerts is it all day long
that they just constantly are reviewing
these things and looking at dashboards
or are they able to take breaks are they
able to you know do it for 30 minutes
and then take 30 minutes and do
something else and then come back to it
for 30 minutes so think about where the
how long somebody's able to actually
ingest this information um in a
a really good way
because we all can only handle so much
uh how does the organization perceive
security so
and not just from a top-down approach
but how do users perceive security how
do they perceive the security team do
they know who the security team is
is that maybe part of why they don't
care about security or they're just not
as interested in it
so how do
how does hr perceive security how does
you know finance perceive security so
thinking about how other teams might
actually think about the security team
or maybe not know them
and then uh
you know thinking back again to when
we're talking about cognition
how do we properly configure our
security tools so
that perception that i had of that tool
that i couldn't get working right and i
i just couldn't get it and so now i
don't like it but maybe it is a really
great effective tool maybe i need to go
back and say hmm what did i do wrong
with that tool maybe we can try it again
and see if it wasn't the tool that was
the problem maybe it was me
the practitioner that didn't understand
the tool well enough you know to to
really configure it properly which is
fine right we can't know every tool so
uh so i think that that's sort of uh
what is my perception of the tools that
i use and how do i use them
so cognitive limitations and this is
sort of where i was getting at with the
how many alerts do we manage and monitor
a day uh
we have only so much that we can take in
and keep and store in our memory and our
attention there's only so long that we
can look at something and do something
before we lose that that really great
focus and intention um attention on what
we're doing
so
this is a pretty well researched area of
psychology and even in technology where
you know there's only so long we can
stare at a screen there's only so long
that we can really sit and do a task
before we have to get up and move around
and then how do we actually visualize
a different scales of problems so am i
able to understand and comprehend and
perceive
a situation
in the same way that somebody else might
so
uh let's take for example solarwinds
because we all know that one right
um
we all probably perceived that well a
lot of us perceive that as a pretty big
threat right that that was a pretty
serious
uh concern and making sure that you know
what what do we have this in our
environment where is it in our
environment um
but was i able to
you know could i perceive
the overall sort of overarching big
picture threat which was that you know
it's not just solar winds it may be
other tools in the environment there may
be other things going on that i'm not
aware of yet and i need to be prepared
for that um as a as a security
practitioner so sort of understanding
the scale of those problems
and then uh thinking about
uh the complexity this is one of those
things i talk about a lot but
because i think it's important
our systems our organizations and
security is really really complex
the amount of vulnerabilities that are
released
daily the amount of you know experience
we have to have with different tools and
you know networks and configurations and
cloud platforms and sas and all of these
things that we need to understand as sec
security practitioners you know it's it
gets very complex and there is only so
much information that we can ingest
so
uh it's one of those things that i i've
liked to bring up from an awareness
perspective that you know when we ingest
so much information that we're probably
going to forget some things too
because we have to constantly be taking
in all this new information on threats
and vulnerabilities and systems and
working with people and all of these
things so uh just understanding that
there's quite a bit of complexity within
those within those systems
and then uh intention versus perception
so
this is something that i think is uh
it's something i i really want to study
more i think that there are
there's not enough data out here
specifically in cyber security and i
think we we need this data to understand
how intention and perception can create
an insecure environment basically
so
if i intend
to
have a conversation with someone and i
provide them you know
i need you to fix 30 vulnerabilities
okay well how did that interaction go
was i
did i provide enough information or did
i say just fix these 30 vulnerabilities
just do it
or did i provide context and say well
there's 30 vulnerabilities that need to
be remediated but these are the top five
that need to be done today the rest we
can discuss and make a plan for and talk
about and so did i work with the person
or did i you know just sort of give them
this and say just go do it so uh to
understand from sort of that perspective
well did i
provide them enough information enough
context how did they perceive that
interaction
did that interaction go poorly for them
have they had security people in the
past tell them you know hey you have to
get this done and there was no
context or information
uh that could really change the
perception in the way that that person
works with me in the future um and it
may make them not want to fix security
vulnerabilities either uh
what if
they've changed settings in the past and
it's broken their environment maybe
they've gotten yelled at by management
because they made a change that security
told them to make and then it broke the
environment uh how you know their
perception of of changes to the
environment is going to be a lot
different because they understand that
their functionality
and operational environment might go
down and so they they're going to have a
different perception of sort of fixing
these vulnerabilities and so it's this
sort of
give and take where
we have to sort of figure out how does
perception actually affect the secure
and security and secure configuration of
our systems so there's a lot more
research that i'd really like to do here
and and sort of dig in to understand
um so what can you do about it uh i i
think it's really important when doing
sort of a presentation or talking to
people to
uh give a really good idea of what you
can actually do with this information
um i do think that we don't talk enough
about security within other fields
you know think about um like biology do
they have a cyber security course i
don't i don't think so probably not
but why not a biologist is going to be
using a computer just as much as i would
use a computer so why do we not teach
you know cyber security in undergraduate
programs um in all fields of study
we're all tethered to technology in some
form or fashion
and uh
even healthcare you know how
are nurses and doctors receiving
any sort of cybersecurity education as
part of their programs they use
computers and tablets all the time with
patient information and phi so um so we
should consider having cyber security as
part of everyone's education
uh awareness
uh so just doing some research i think
that's the best way to sort of
understand how psychology and
psychological principles might help
better protect your systems really at
the end of the day um there are so many
you know i only touched on a few but
like cognition and metacognition and how
we actually process information i think
understanding those principles and how
they might affect our security teams
could help us understand our team
members better it could help us
understand the security of our
environment better
and and really sort of mature our cyber
security programs because that's really
what should be happening is we should be
working towards maturing our cyber
programs and i think by integrating
psychology integrating some human
factors engineering sort of principles
uh can certainly help us do that
uh consider hiring someone with a
background in psychology
um i actually know someone who
came from cognitive
psychology into cyber security uh dr
margaret cunningham and she is a
phenomenal researcher
she is such great insight and so i think
that having having more people with a
background in psychology and cyber
security is only going to help us
understand the problems a lot more um
and then really understanding cognitive
limitations and i think from
a practitioner standpoint understanding
what our cognitive limitations are so
sort of understanding okay how much
information can i really digest versus
how much information uh you know am i am
i taking in and then actionably you know
putting something towards and then from
a management perspective understanding
that you know
practitioners we can only ingest so much
information at a time and trying to
figure out the ways to augment or
automate uh some of the ways that we
look at alerts and and that we handle
some of our systems to sort of help cut
down on the the sort of that fatigue
that we get
um and then thinking about human factors
and design and how that plays into
security tooling
so
it's not always you know i hear this
sometimes it's like well this tool isn't
doing what it's supposed to be doing and
we need to replace it and get a new tool
nine times out of ten doing that
uprooting an entire infrastructure just
to integra implement a new tool is gonna
be really expensive
and chances are the tool could
potentially be configured in a better
way not always um that's not always the
case but it is possible that the tool
could be configured in a better way
re-architected in some way instead of
ripping it out and trying to put
something brand new in there um
so so that's always an option uh to sort
of cut down on budget and things like
that but i always think about it from a
you know how can we sort of
make our tools better that we use and uh
so i think thinking about what tools you
have in the environment maybe even
consolidating some tools because that's
the other thing if we have 10 tools in
our in our toolbox and it we have
cognitive limitations there's only so
much we can look at in a day it's very
possible that we run out of time to
actually be able to configure these
tools properly so so think about the
security tooling you have in your
environment and what's really necessary
and what's being used and is it being
utilized
to the best of its ability
um and so that's it for me uh that is my
conclusion here um please feel free to
reach out to me on linkedin i'm happy to
answer any questions uh share my
research
or anything that i've been working on uh
thank you so much for having me today uh
and i believe i'll be in the q a uh uh
part of discord answering questions for
you guys thank you guys so much