hello everyone i'm randy parkman
and i'm jean-francois
and we're going to be talking to you
about our research and development
efforts around
red teams attacking logs and blue teams
defending against them and trying to
bust the ghost in the lots
yeah i thought this was very awesome and
i think it all started when we presented
both at unicom
uh we started talking to each other and
i was
under the premise that i wanted to see
from a red team's perspective what was
going on if like all the worst things
could happen to a blue team
and i wanted to to know randy because
randy's pretty good at his job wanted to
know his opinion about how you could
potentially
defend against that and you're gonna see
what we're talking about in just a
minute
um let's introduce ourselves just a
little bit um i work at binary defense
where i
work in threat hunting for a lot of
different clients
trying to find
new advanced ways to detect
the
attackers and all the techniques that
they use and prior to working at binary
defense where i've been for the last two
years i worked for 15 years at the fbi
where i worked on cyber crime
investigations and digital forensics
incident response
following that up that's
quite some big shoes to fill there so my
name is alfred zomas i work at
trustedsec
and i'm also a sans instructor i teach
the 699 course there
i create open source tools
primarily red theme based and i'm also
the creator of red teamer.tips which is
a help website for red teams with some
field notes uh just a quick cheat sheet
there if you want uh if you're stuck
somewhere and you want some help
uh feel free to take a look at that as
well
so there you go as i already mentioned
the preface of this is actually
how adversaries can mess with defenses
and how
defenders could potentially react to
this if a worst case scenario would hit
and what do i mean by that well
we all know the saying that defenders
have the home field advantage it's
something that has been said over and
over again but is this
really true though because
defenders do have the home advantage
they do know their environment they know
which servers are there they know which
defenses they have but adversaries
also know about the common technologies
that tends to get them caught such as
edrs such as sysmon suggests log
forwarding to seams
so those things are very very similar in
almost all environments adversaries know
this stuff so they can start dampering
with this stuff as well
and defenders however are actually
fighting the unknown yes they do know
their own environment but they don't
know what's going to hit them there are
a billion threat actors out there with a
lot of ttps most of them or at least
some of them are mapped on the mitre
attack framework but there are
definitely nation states dtps out there
that don't have a mapping just yet
and to illustrate this even further
there are over 90 over 87 different c2
frameworks actually locked on the c2
matrix which is actually a website that
is dedicated to try and map all the
different
c2s out there so there are over 87
different c2s out there and as you can
imagine yes they share they share
similarities but they also have their
own uh nuances as well
and as i already mentioned various
strategies each with their own ddps
so on what do these tools rely right so
edrs they can rely on user mode hooks
and they also have kernel callbacks
sysmon typically relies on etw events
which stands for event racing for
windows we're going to talk about that
in just a minute
and the event log service and then of
course the log forwarders and what do
they rely on well they rely on actually
having
reachability to the target they are
forwarding the logs to
so
what are user motoks if you haven't
heard about this before allow me to
quickly illustrate what we're actually
talking about here
so typically what we can see
um is
every process that is running in your
computer at one point or another um
calls ntdl.tll which is um the gap
between user mode and kernel mode so as
you may know the operating system has a
kernel uh that's actually the thing that
is responsible of running the entire
operating system and running the
processes on there and the processes
that are running in your operating
system need to have a way to interact
with each other of course and that is
what the kernel is responsive for
responsible for
so ntdll is actually the bridge between
the two and you can recognize
ntdl functions because it's typically
annotated with nd for example nt virtual
protect anti-allocate virtual memory so
all np functions belong to ntd level tll
and all modules at one point or another
will call ntd level dll so this is a
primary example for edrs to actually
inspect right this is interesting
traffic because everything goes through
this and they want to inspect what is
going on so what typically happens is
as you can see in the
first stop of this slide
this is actually an example of a
disassembled goat of anti-allocate
virtual memory and this is how it
typically looks like so it does some
move instructions
it does a compare instruction it does a
cisco and it does a return
now on the bottom half of the slides you
can actually see what a hooked function
looks like and you can see this is
actually quite different because here
the first instruction is a move
instruction and here the first
instruction is a jump instruction to a
different memory address and if you
would follow this memory address 99
out of 100 you will end up into an other
dll which most likely will be the dll of
the edr that is trying to inspect your
traffic
so what can you do as an adversary
well
it's actually very simple what can you
do as an adversary you can um try and
subvert that because you know that nt
functions are actually always following
the same instructions there's always a
move instruction there's always a
comparing section there's always a cisco
instruction you can actually craft your
own function and call that instead and
and try to evade hoops that way but we
will get into that in just a second
let's talk about the event lock service
and etw first so the event lock service
relies on etw and etw stands for event
tracing for windows now what does this
actually mean here i am once again
talking about kernel it's actually a
tracing function that belongs to the
windows kernel it exposes different
providers where processes can subscribe
to some of these providers are very
interesting from an edr perspective once
again such as for example the kernel
provider as it can actually gives you
information on when a process is being
launched and also even threats so when a
threat is being launched and this is
very interesting because then you can
actually um
correlate threats that are being spawned
in a process and try to hunt for process
injection for example so if one process
is injecting a threat into another
process you will see that a new threat
is being spawned from a process that is
not the same process as that threat is
running on so that's very interesting
and a cool open source tool uh that
allows you to play with this stuff is
silk etw by ruben bonan aka fuzzysec
really cool uh open source developer as
well it's a really smart
researcher and this silk etw allows you
to either lock etw events to the console
and it even has capabilities to actually
lock forward it to a lock stash for
example or to a splunk
so that's a really cool thing if you're
in interested in learning more about etw
and their providers i highly recommend
you to use this middleware if you want
to
so there you go
then line of sight with a seam i guess
this is no surprise to anyone
your end points collect locks
if you want to forward those locks
you'll have to have some kind of process
that is actually collecting all the
locks your endpoints has and ships them
to another target
and of course it relies on line of sight
if you can't communicate with the end
target of your lock forwarding then the
locks will never arrive there so that's
interesting to know as well
because we're going to dive into that in
just a bit
so as i already mentioned multiple times
here we are not just assuming breach
we are actually assuming worst case
scenario so this research was conducted
from a very simple idea what if an
adversary
completely blinds you so what if he can
bypass really all the security measures
that are in place in order to try and
prevent an attacker from actually doing
malicious stuff what happens
then and i created some software
it's called purple power and i'll link
to it
in the discord as well like the github
link to the project so you can check it
out if you're interested in the code
and what does purple power actually do
well it's actually capable of bypassing
etw and bypassing um c mc is the malware
scanning interface of windows so it
bypasses those two things
it's written in c sharp and it's
leveraging the d invoke framework for
cisco generation so it actually bypasses
the user mode hooks again i'll talk more
about that in just a second it can nuke
the event look it can also load a
malicious driver in order to completely
stop etw events from being written in
the first place or it can inject into
the event lock service and use java
rules in order to
make smart decisions whether or not you
want to lock an event or you want it to
be blocked
and finally but not last but not
less important it can sink all
communications to seams
so bypassing user mode hooks as i
already mentioned hooks are things that
edrs for example like to place on things
so how does that work you're a regular
user you're spawning a process that
process needs to communicate with nt dll
and an edr will hook that ntdl page for
you now
i am malware now and i want to create
some malicious stuff i want to do some
malicious stuff well guess what
i too want to communicate with the
operating system so i too need to
communicate with ntd level tll which is
hooked so my malware is going to call an
empty instruction that is actually
hooked by the edr so the edr will see my
call to the ntdll function it will
inspect it and it will do some
processing logic whether or not to
decide if i'm malicious or not if the
edr deems that indeed my call is
malicious it's going to block and it's
going to send an alert or if not it's
going to let me pass
now how can you evade that well as i
already mentioned
nt functions always follow the same kind
of
assembly instructions it's always going
to do a compare it's always going to do
a syscall it's always going to do a
return so we know this we can actually
know the function prototypes of this
stuff even though it's undocumented
there's actually a lot of research
already out there there are
entire websites uh dedicated to
undocumented function of microsoft so if
you want the uh the function prototype
in assembly you'll definitely be able to
find it
and the invoke or dynamic invocation is
a c framework that actually automates
this process for you so you don't have
to do it and what does it look like well
again you are a user you're spawning a
process that process needs ntd allowable
dll so it's going to load it into its
process memory that is still going to
get hooked but now i'm going to do
something different from a malware
perspective i'm not simply going to call
the ntdlr.dll function anymore i'm
actually going to ask
a clean
ntdl.tll
file from disk so i'm actually going to
manually map a new ntd a level dll into
the process memory which will not be
hooked as edrs typically place the hook
on process start and the process is
already started so the ntdl dll page is
already hooked i'm going to just simply
map a new entity level dll in memory and
i'm going to call the nt function from
that newly mapped ntd level dll instead
which is not hooked and which will not
trigger any alerts so happy days for
adversaries
so etw shenanigans i already said that
purple power actually has three
different ways of messing with etw the
first one is actually just simply nuking
the entire etw
lock service so that's actually
the most impactful because i'm just
simply nuking the entire thing
it's also the loudest
uh so what does that look like well
you may or may not know that event lost
service is actually running as a
privileged process on your system which
is just
svchost.exe there are a lot of svc hosts
in there but you can actually use wmi to
query uh
the exact process id that is hosting the
event of service so as you can see here
on the slides i'm basically saying look
i want all the services but i want to
fill this um event and i want the
process id of that so here i see that
the process id is
and if i use process hacker and look for
2056 i see svchost.exe if i inspect the
threats in this svc host.exe i will see
[Music]
w-e-v-t-s-v-c svc.dll which is actually
the dll responsible for the event
so what i do is i'm actually going to
suspend all the threats that are running
event log
and this is actually a snippet that is
uh used from irat.team which is another
retimer website out there and you can
see here um the the uh the threats are
being suspended and here you can see
that the first command is actually being
locked so audit success but the second
command
it's not being locked
nothing happens and that is because the
threats are suspended so nothing can be
looked as there's nothing to look
anymore there's nothing that can
actually do the law hang anymore it's
suspended to spend it in place
so that's really interesting that's the
first bypass
another bypass is actually made by
batsack actually the the next two
bypasses are made by betsek he's a very
smart researcher as well um offensive
tradecraft and he's actually very young
i think by the time of this presentation
he's 19 or 20 years old so it's really
amazing uh really smart guy really young
as well and what he found out is he used
wendy bg which is a windows debugger in
kernel mode
and he actually started disassembling
functions and he found that there's
actually an empty function called nt
trace events
trace events event tracing for windows
etw so the correlation is not that hard
to make this event
this function is also responsible but
from kernel level
for etw event rights so what happens
here is he actually patched it in memory
with a very simple return statement
and what he found is once it immediately
returns the event look is not writing
anything
again
now this is a kernel function and this
is not something you can typically
manipulate from user lands
as there is protections in place that
use it even if your local admin can't
just simply start messing around with
the kernel that's just simply not
possible so
a vulnerable kernel actually needs to be
loaded in memory
and there are a ton of them sorry to say
but there are multiple vulnerable
drivers out there that are signed
um even intel has a vulnerable driver
out there as well so there's a project
on github called kdu which is actually a
well a collection of vulnerable drivers
and it allows you to sideload your own
driver which is unsigned which is
typically not possible because you're
exploiting another vulnerable signed
driver that has kernel read write
privileges you are allowed to sideload a
unsigned driver and that inside driver
is called ghost in the locks and ghost
in the locks will simply patch the nt
trace events
function and it will immediately return
so that means every time the function is
called it's going to return so it's not
going to do anything it's just going to
say okay i did something but in reality
it actually didn't do anything and that
also bypasses um the event as you will
see here in just a moment
so once again
uh here you can see event log actually
running
and there's going to be a powershell
prompt in just a minute
just give it a second
the powershell window spawns
and normally you would suspect that a
process id one will be registered in
sysmon process id1 is process create but
in reality there's nothing there why not
because ghost in the locks patched that
function and simply didn't write
anything to the sysmon event log
and then the third one
is actually um the sneakiest one in my
opinion and uh randy from the blue side
will definitely agree with me there um
this one isn't simply nuking anything
it's also not simply patching
all of the functions this is actually a
very
very sneaky
thing botsa came up with and he actually
used jara which is typically a blue
teamer's tool but he uses it offensively
so what um
etw event mute
does is it's going to inject
a new threat into that svc host that is
running the event block and it's going
to just simply listen for new events
if
an event
is actually hitting that event look
service and it matches
a jararu it's going to drop it so it's
going to do that return it's going to
drop it it's not going to lock anything
if it doesn't match the jar however it's
simply going to keep writing so it's
only going to take very very specific
attacks based on java rules and it's
going to make decisions based on that if
it's going to get hit it will discard it
if it's not getting hit the event block
will just resume as normal which is very
very tricky for a defender to defend
against
so same calling communications to the
seam that one is actually very very
straightforward
because here i'm actually cheating a
little bit i know that sentinel is being
used in our environment as a seam and
it's well documented by microsoft uh
there's actually a command line
that you can use a powershell script to
enroll yourself into
sentinel and here you can clearly see
that health service is being used for
this
now if you're familiar with cis internal
tools you know that cis internals
actually has
a tcp view package
that you can run in order for you to see
every process that is running on your
system and whether or not they are
creating a connection to the internet so
here you can see how service
and my first train of thought was i'm
just going to um
blacklists a specific ip in the firewall
but then if you look at this screenshot
you'll actually see it's not just the
227 but also the 228 that is being
contacted by health service so then i
was thinking okay i can just blacklist
these two ips but then i started talking
to randy and randy actually linked me
microsoft documentation again of all the
ips that azure
are using and there are a ton of them
and i didn't want to go through the
hassle of actually creating black
crystals for all those ips because not
all those ips are just sentinel there
could actually be other services running
in azure that you still want to
communicate to so instead of using
eyepiece i just went for a very very uh
dirty approach and i just blacklisted
the entire binary
and how did i do that well there are
actually two approaches that you can
take you can either use the nutshell
command so that's a utility that is
living in every windows operating system
using the adv firewall command you can
actually manipulate the the local
firewall
so you can add a rule
based for example on a binary or you
could also do it in c plus plus you
could also do it in c sharp and if you
want to use c sharp there's actually a
very nice
package already available to you there's
a binary a library to use and it's very
very simple and just a few lines of code
as you can see here
you can blacklist uh whatever you want
honestly so that is what i did i created
a new rule see a nerds and
you can give it an arbitrary
binary to blacklist and in this case
we're obviously targeting that
howservice.exe
so
this is some some nice ascii arts
because no tool is a complete without
asking
purple power it's available on github as
well as i already mentioned i'm going to
drop it in the discord the link if
you're interested in checking out that
goat
but without further ado let's just
do a very very short live demonstration
so you can actually see it in action
and in order to do that i need to go
into my remote desktop
i will need to sign into my domain admin
account
don't do this by the way in production
don't just log in as a domain admin
everywhere
i don't want to stay up to date i'm
sorry this is
a outdated operating system by design
so here we have the purple power the
help menu
well it's a bit messed up sorry about
that so i have nuke i have mute i have
ghost in the locks i have backdoor i
even have cobalt strike which will
inject a predefined cobalt strike
beacon so don't use this if you're
pulling the codes from github because
chances are that that global strike
instance is down but in the off chance
that it's up you're giving me a free
beacon on your system so don't uh run
the the cobalt commands unless you
modify it yourself with new shell codes
uh but yeah without further ado let's
just for example uh nuke
the eventblock
and let's add a backdoor
to our system
so what it's going to do it's going to
patch
omc it's going to patch edw then it's
going to reflectively load
a other c sharp binary which is uh
called sharp event log nuker something i
created
some nice ascii there again
here you can see that the nuke actually
found the svc host process with process
id 1596 it suspends all these
threats it nuked it successfully it
created a new invisible backdoor using
sharp invisible back door which is
another binary i wrote once again some
nice oscar there and it's actually a
dollar sign user with passwords backdoor
123 which was successfully created and
added to the admin group obviously all
this stuff relies on local admin
privileges so this purple power binary
needs to be
ran as a local admin if it's not local
admin you won't be able to manipulate
the eventbook service and we can
actually i haven't um
haven't checked this prior to the uh to
the demo so i hope it worked but let's
just
verify whether or not it works
using a process package
so
svc hosts oh yeah that's not going to
work i need to use process hacker as
local admin as well sorry about that
come on
give me my keyboards okay it doesn't but
it's in the recent so it doesn't really
matter
right
there you go
one five nine six that's svc host there
you go
and i hope if we check the threats yep
there you go
the threats are indeed all suspended uh
all the threats to
that uh dll that is responsible for the
event look so there you go proof that it
works hey
very nice
uh so that's a demo of uh purple power
obviously you could use ghost and locks
as well or
mute if you want to feel free to check
that out
if you don't believe me that it works
i need to start the presentation again
there you go
so that was the demo and now i'm going
to give the word to my esteemed
colleague
randy for his sites
so he's going to talk about the blue
perspective here randy take it away
thank you so much john francois i really
enjoyed working on this project with you
and i think everyone in the audience
seeing this so far if they're on the red
team side is probably already excited
and maybe already downloading
your github so that they can start
messing with us everybody on the blue
team side is probably freaking out like
oh my gosh what is going to happen
if somebody uses these tools there's so
many different ways to bypass my logs to
hide things from the edr what am i going
to do
and the approach that i'd like to
recommend
is that in any case when you're looking
at
red team tactics um think about these
worst case scenarios and instead of just
getting stuck think about what you could
do what what can you do if you can't
trust your logs um that's not to say
that you want to give up logging like oh
it's it's no good because most of the
time that's exactly what you need to
catch most of the threats so we're not
going to give up logging but we are
going to add an additional approach
um
and
when you're thinking about
an adversary blocking your logs you want
to start looking for what you cannot see
or looking for what's not there
there's actually a really great story
from
many years ago in computer security
history that cliff stoll wrote about in
the book the cuckoo's egg i don't know
if you've read that before but if you
haven't i really recommend it it's a
great story about how a system
administrator at uc berkeley
caught a very advanced russian
state-sponsored hacker who was going
after military secrets
because he noticed that there was a
difference there was
an unexplained
difference between
the logging time that the unix computers
reported that they were being used and
another system that was keeping track of
administration of amount of computer
time that different users had used for
billing purposes noticing the difference
between those two logs
told him that there was something
happening that was not being reported
the way that it should be
so um as we were approaching you know
this idea of how would you spot somebody
who is a ghost in your own logs
i thought of really the same sort of
approach what if you had a different
system something that the attacker did
not know about that was auditing the use
of the system in another way now the
most straightforward approach would be
just have a second a second sim that has
uh log forwarding going to it you know
maybe some secondary logging but there's
a couple of problems with that one is
the attacker is probably going to see
that as well if they're going after your
logs they're probably going to
see it if it's too much the same as what
you already have
and whatever method they use to block
that probably will be used to block
your secondary system as well so that's
really out but the second reason you
wouldn't want to do that is purely
economical if you're going to take a
second copy of all of your logs you're
probably paying double for whatever
service you're paying for in the first
place and nobody on a security team
wants to get a request hey could i
double my budget for next year just as a
backup right you don't want to be doing
that so
again
i decided that the right approach to
solving this problem would be to develop
some new software and i will also drop a
link to the github project where you can
download the software for the blue team
side um for fun because we were talking
about battling ghosts in the logs we
decided to use a ghostbusters theme and
the the software is called thinkmen
there's all kinds of references to
ghostbusters in here that i recommend if
you're going to
use this software
in your environment you change all of
these things because after attackers
have viewed this presentation you don't
want them looking for vincent on your
systems
so
let's talk about the goals that we had
we want to detect if the log collection
network traffic is cut off if your log
collectors no longer
receiving events
you also want to detect if locally logs
have gone down and then um
stretch goals if we could we wanted to
see if we could detect
that really really sneaky situation from
bat sex software if the event logs are
just being filtered if most of them are
going through but just some of them
aren't that's really hard um and then
the last goal that we have is hide
vincman so that the attacker doesn't see
what's going on
don't get caught otherwise your backup
system is going to just become a
liability as well
so thinkman is also designed in c-sharp
using.net
it uses
event tracing for windows etw
and i implemented this as a dll because
one of the things we wanted to be able
to do to hide bin from the
adversary is to actually use a red team
technique and inject the dll into some
other process that you wouldn't think to
look into
there are some requirements for that
process it does need to be running
not as the local admin but it does need
to be running
with a group that
has permissions for um
subscribing to etw events
and i'll link to some microsoft
documentation about what local group you
can set up and what the permissions need
to be
vinkman needs to and in fact it does
with the implementation that we came up
with um check the running processes on a
regular base basis um you also have the
opportunity uh when you've got the
running processes to check all of the
threads that are in there this is not
something that i've implemented yet but
it's a future design to do some basic
checks to see what are the threads in
each of these processes and is there
something going on that uh maybe we
might want to alert specially on
then going through each of those
processes we want to count
the number of events coming through etw
for each one of them
we're not going to log all the details
of those events though this is the trick
to try to save us some money and save us
some resources we're just reporting on
how many events of each type for each
process we're seeing
then we need to send those logs not to
the log collector we don't want to send
them to the same place that is being
blocked by the adversary perhaps we want
to send them to some place inside of our
network that the adversary is not going
to want to block communication to so in
our test lab we just sent them to a file
server
that was on the domain controller so if
their adversary is blocking traffic
between the workstation and the domain
controller they're causing themselves as
many problems as they're causing
everyone else and they're going to get
caught right away
so we wanted to
send the log someplace that wouldn't be
so obvious and wouldn't get blocked
one of the things that we also wanted to
do with this is to be able to change the
configuration on the fly like where are
you sending the logs which etw
events are you subscribing to
and so i implemented that using dns um
dns has a lot of different record types
one of them that is very convenient for
red teams and blue teams both is the txt
record type you get just like four
kilobytes of text that you can
respond to dns queries with and so we
use internal active directory dns txt
records to tell the vinkman client where
to send the logs and which etw
subscribers to
um to hook up to and then every 60
seconds it checks in with those again
and if they've changed if you've made a
change as the administrator
all of the linkman clients across your
enterprise will get the change within
the next minute or so um change the
config on the fly and then anything with
ghostbusters
themes uh needs a pke meter or an
aurascope
so
we use that just as far as naming
conventions but we had a lot of fun with
this
so we've really already talked about
what uh etw is um so i won't go into
that a whole lot but i just wanted to
show you um a couple of the dns txt
records
that we use um so
the
um
uh the dns name that i chose for this is
uh vinkman dash etw dash providers dot
and then whatever your local domain name
is you definitely want to change that so
that the adversaries aren't looking for
linkman in dns records but you can
change that just with a config in the
software very easily
and then
as the value for the txt you simply put
the names of the etw providers you want
separated with a pipe character so
that's it
you can change that on the fly and all
the vinkman clients will be updated
next i thought really hard about what
log format
we wanted to use for this because
obviously we need to report all of these
details
at first i thought we wanted to use json
as a format just because it's easy to
parse it's very standard the problem is
then that
repeats the
[Music]
the names of the columns throughout
every single record
and it ends up being very heavy as far
as the logs and if you're paying per
gigabyte of logs ingested um you
definitely want to keep your logs as
lightweight as possible um so what i did
instead was use a um like a csv format
with a pipe character as the delimiter
and then every so often
when the column names were updated i
would just repeat out into the logs a
new column header
and this worked out very well ingesting
these logs into azure sentinel which is
what we used for all of the analysis
next slide please
so um let's take a look at what actually
happened um here is here's what these
charts represent
we
ran queries
for
uh time intervals of every two minutes
and looked at in each of those two
minute uh time intervals how many sysmon
events did we get how many security
events did we get from the endpoint that
was under attack and then we looked at
the same time scale um what were we
getting from vinkman and the charts that
you're going to see are the number of
processes that vinkman recorded
i'll show you at the end the difference
between the processes and the number of
etw events which got more complicated
but this actually is the simpler way to
do it and the research showed this is
probably the easiest way to do it that
is also the most effective so you can
see at 10 33
utc time um jean francois attacking the
system uh ran the event log nuker um
using sharp event log new nukes um you
can speak to this if you'd like and also
block the
the
firewall use a firewall rule to block
the log collection and you can see it
absolutely worked like there is a big
blank space in this time when there were
no security events and there were no
cismod events
and then at 1057 the machine was
rebooted thinkpin was restarted the
firewall
rule block was removed
we do have some more research to do
because we found that there were some
logs that slipped in
at a time when we didn't think that
there should be um we've got some
theories about this that maybe there
were some logs that kind of got queued
up um somehow and then they got
forwarded to the sim later on um after
the system came back up uh but
we're definitely looking into that it
also could be that our clocks were not
quite synchronized and we just noted the
the time a little bit wrong but the good
thing to notice here is that while the
security logs and the sysmon events were
not being recorded at all by the sim
vinkman still was it had an alternate
path it wasn't being blocked it was
recording a different way and so we have
this opportunity as the defender to see
that
something is not right because there is
a difference between the accounting
system thinkman and our logging system
in the sim that is showing us there's no
security and no sysmon but we can see
that there are events and there are
processes running from this machine and
it's still on
next slide please
this is using the next um
technique for
purple power which was ghost in the logs
from bat sec
and um you can see this also worked
really well um i'm going to show on the
next slide how we we're still getting
security events which is interesting we
weren't expecting to see that but it did
block sysmon events very well again we
see that there were a few events that
happened
a little bit earlier than we expected
them to come back so we need to look at
that but that big spike in sysmon events
that is the system reboot right there um
so i think it very well might be that
the the clocks between sentinel um in
azure and our local clocks might not
have been quite in sync but you can also
see during this ghost in the logs
minkman saw all of the events just fine
um it still saw the processes running
and it was still reporting in this whole
time that the logs were off
next slide
um i wanted to show uh this is the same
experiment as the last slide but instead
of sysmon events we're looking at
security events and you can see that
those didn't go away the whole time so
while ghost in the logs was running the
security events did not get blocked and
that's also going to require some more
research but this is good information
for blue teams to know sometimes the
tools that red teams use don't work the
way that they expect them to maybe
they're working just fine but uh though
the thing that you think that they're
going to do
they don't quite do all of those things
so it is useful to have multiple event
sources that you're monitoring and
multiple ways that you're looking at the
logs next slide this is the last
experiment
this is using event mute and the
firewall block at the same time and
again you can see the same pattern that
both the sysmon and the security logs
did not come through to the sim during
this time period we did have an another
unexplained little spike of events come
through right at 1pm and then they went
away again and then you can see the big
spike when the system was rebooted um so
uh once again we'll be looking at that
but the great news is that finkman kept
reporting in the entire time and could
see all of these events
next slide i think there this spike
sorry to interrupt there i think that
spike is an update of a java rule
so then it actually starts the uh well
it's going to allow some
uh events uh back again based on the
java rule whether or not it gets hit or
not
so i think that's the uh that's the
explanation for this one at least
okay
um thank you i i appreciate that and i
think out of all of these different
attacks
that last one was definitely the
sneakiest
because you can see we're relying on
uh the logs from sysmon and security
going away while we can still see logs
from finkman
to be our indicator that something is
wrong so if there are still event logs
happening if there's still sysmon
there's still security uh that would be
very difficult for defenders to detect
um i wanted to show you what a baseline
of normal looks like this is a period of
24 hours when no attacks at all were
happening
and we can see
in the green
that is the number of etw events that
vinkman was recording and in the purple
squiggly line you can see the number of
processes
that vinkman was seeing these are in two
different uh scales otherwise uh the
number of process counts would just
disappear on the x-axis
um so the the green uh events uh the
number of event counts is a scale on the
left and the purple one the number of
processes is on the right uh this is for
five minute intervals and the important
thing to take from this is that normally
when a system is just running normally
and there is no attack going on you can
expect that the number of processes is
going to stay within a fairly expected
you know range it's kind of going to be
bounded
when you look at it in five minute
intervals
and then the number of etw events is
going to vary wildly like it's all over
the place there's these huge spikes that
happen um at different times and that's
just because sometimes the system is
incredibly more busy there's windows
updates there's reboots
some processes when they run just create
a massive number of events um so one of
the things we were kind of hoping is
that we'd be able to come up with like a
best-fit line
um on number of events and detect
anomalies that way um but
this sort of pattern makes that very
very challenging to do
next slide
this is just for the period of time that
we looked at for those three experiments
when purple power was being used on this
machine and you can see once again
there's some wild variation in the
number of events but the uh the number
of processes stays within a fairly
bounded range and is uh you know none at
no time do either one of these things go
to zero the closest thing to zero that
looked to me like it might be there was
in the number of etw events and still
that was like you know uh four and a
half thousand
next slide
there's also a nice uh homage to botsac
there was a good the batman kind of
thing oh my gosh i didn't even see the
bat ears that is awesome and it's purple
that that works out well
um so i wanted to show this is a very
simple query in kuso query language kql
that i set up as an alarm to tell me um
if across the environment there are any
hosts for which in the last five minutes
we're seeing events from venkman but
we're not seeing anything from the event
logs um if that ever happens then it
raises an alarm and notifies me and i
say oh okay here's a machine that i need
to look at a little bit more closely and
then maybe i can use my remote ir tools
to pull memory from it or you know do
some
do some ir
tasks to preserve what's going on on
that machine so that i can tell the
truth what is really going on rather
than what i'm seeing through the event
logs
so now we have time for questions and we
will be happy to take your questions in
the discord thank you very much