welcome everyone
today we are going to talk about
ransomware in factions in cloud
databases
first of all i am very thankful to texas
cyber summit committee members for
giving me this opportunity to talk about
this research
i'm also thankful to all of you who are
attending this talk
i hope we are going to have a great time
during this talk
let's get it started
before we move further this is some
disclaimer i want to talk about
the basic purpose of this research is to
share the intelligence with the security
community
and the target is to strengthen the
efforts
to build strong
prevention and detection solution
so that we can subvert these attacks on
the internet
and we strictly believe that it is only
possible when the security community
comes together and work collaboratively
in order to do that we have to share our
findings we have to share our research
and that is the basic target
for the stalkers
a little
brief breakdown of mine
i've been into this industry for more
than 13 years now
i've written two books targeted cyber
attacks and empirical cloud security
you can check for my background more at
the portal here
you know you can connect me with twitter
as well
but the basic purpose to highlight
the background here is to show that what
we are going to discuss we know what it
is all about and how we really need to
go ahead and solve those problems
so what is the agenda today
at first we are going to look into cloud
databases threats and attacks landscape
very important to understand
what are the new trends and tactics that
attackers are opting to target cloud
databases
we will look into some of the root
causes of why ransomware infections are
happening in cloud databases
we will look into some of the real world
examples
after that we are going to talk about
two tools that we have developed
and we will demonstrating those tools
against real
and live targets on the internet to show
how we can detect
ransomware infections
and then we'll have our questions and
queries down the line
so this is one of the most important
and essential artifact in the
real world these days
when i say real world
in the world of digitalization we are
talking about
the internet
the ransomware attacks are rising
exponentially
and why that is
the reasons are as follows
because data is a new currency you know
everybody wants to control the data
so as the attackers
second is
why to launch attacks for free
if the attackers are going after
subverting the integrity of internet
and compromising systems
they really want some profit out of it
which means they want monetary gains
combining these two factors
attackers are going after the
technologies
exactly how the data is stored
processed
and transmitted
one or the other way they want to
control the data
and the main reason is data is a new
currency
in the world of digitalization whoever
controls the data controls the money
flow and that is the reality
well that also
enhances the
security challenges for the
organizations as well
because attackers are very much focused
and whenever they design a malicious
code they run designing in the form of
ransomware
basically we're going to infect your
systems we're going to install
ransomware
we're going to control your data
and at last you have to pay us the
ransom
in order to get your data back
so i control your data
you pay me the money
and then is all
as well
that is the reality of the
attacks on the internet
that's why ransomware attacks are
increasing
at a rapid pace
so let's look into some of the cloud
databases
in this spot you can clearly see some of
the
media titles that i have picked up
related to elastic search
you know how elastic servers are
compromised how attackers are launching
attacks against these
services and more importantly deploying
ransomware in the elastic search
instances
basically they are going to control the
data they are going to control the
search engine capabilities that
elasticsearch provides
so that you won't be able to get a
access to your data
and ransomware is actually is not the
only one
attack that these cloud databases are
encountering these days there are many
more
but for us we are going to focus on
ransomware primarily
and you can clearly see you know
hackers are targeting elasticsearch a
lot these days
and this is one of a severe problem as
well so categorizing elastic search into
cloud databases
is nothing new
now
on similar
note
we have another cloud database
threads and attack landscape if we want
to look into is the mongodb
again some of these
titles and news
headlines actually highlight how severe
the problem is
cloud databases are under attack by
attackers
they want to control the data as we
discussed earlier
and once they do that you know they are
in full control
so that's why these
adversaries or attackers they are going
after
cloud databases
so if you just look at from the
technology point of view both
elasticsearch and mongodb
databases are nosql one you know in
elasticsearch we have an unstructured
data so that they can query it
efficiently
similarly with mongodb you know
json-based documents are stored
with proper collections and you have to
search through these collections
to do the interaction with the database
so if the attackers control that
collection in mongodb
you know they are going to control the
data
and of course they are going to encrypt
it so that you won't be able to recover
it
and which we'll going to see
in some time as well
since we have seen the threats and
attack landscape for elasticsearch and
mongodb
which means
in this particular talk
we are going to focus on ransomware
infections
that are targeting elasticsearch
and mongodb
our focus
will be these two cloud databases
highlighting
how ransomware are going to exploit
these
and how we have done definitive research
to detect infections
in these two specific cloud databases
so as a part of this research
we'll be discussing in detail about our
two different tools
but let's first understand
what are the root causes for this trend
severe infections
primarily targeting cloud databases
there are many reasons for that
let's go through some of them to
understand why this is a problem
here i have listed couple of reasons
which actually initiates the ransomware
deployment in cloud databases which
means how attackers are going to
compromise cloud databases what are the
reasons
they are able to successfully infect
these cloud databases with ransomware
one of the main reasons for that is the
exposed database administrative
interfaces
during deployments administrators
not pay much attention to the security
and as a result of that
the configuration stays in secure
which actually result in exposing
database administrative interface
whether it's on different protocol
communication channels such as http or
https or others whatever they support
they are exposed on the internet
and if they are exposed on the internet
you know attackers are in a very well
situation to go after fingerprint them
and try to exploit them
it makes
the situation more worse
when administrators use weak and default
passwords as well
or maybe running the interface in an
anonymous mode
so attackers can easily launch
credential cracking and try to gain a
complete access to the database
administrative panels
another way attackers going after these
cloud databases because they are running
on specific network services these
services are not secure in itself
for example tcp based services that are
sporting the communication with the
mongodb instant are exposed again on the
internet
attackers what they do they try to
interact with this network service try
to fingerprint what are the inherent
database software
is being deployed
and they try to
map that and try to figure out any
vulnerabilities that exist with them and
of course they are going to go after
exploits after that
to exploit any inherent vulnerability
that is present
and then take a complete control of the
network service and at the end and
itself is the cloud database
another reason that adds to the
compromise of cloud databases
is via indirect channel
which means attackers first you know
compromise the end user system
to in fact the cloud instances
you know we have standard attacks like
drive by downloads you know and then
many other ways
phishing attacks you know
their attackers are able to install
malicious payloads on the end user
systems
and when these end user systems are
interacting with the cloud services
they try to control them
through lateral spreading
or other different techniques
but in this case is that
attackers are going after end user
systems first and then targeting cloud
databases
again as i mentioned lateral movement is
the most important
technique
that is being used here
because once the malicious code is
running on the end user system it
becomes way easier for the attackers
to exploit
or map other systems in the same
environment
and that actually contributes
further to the
compromise of cloud databases running in
the cloud environment
as we discuss social engineering attacks
of course these are indirect way to
compromise end user systems and taking
that route to target the cloud instances
running on the
environment
so the these are
most important
ideas that we really need to understand
here how attackers are kind of going
after
cloud databases
in order to install ransomware
attackers can go after any
technique
but as a security
researchers
or engineers
we really need to be cautious on each
and every front
so that their appropriate security
controls are deployed to circumvent
these attacks
but that is a reality
now since now we have understood how
exactly ransomware is deployed in cloud
databases how attackers are exploiting
the integrity of network services
in order to control
now we really need to understand
how infections look like in real world
let's move forward
so what we are going to look right now
is
how the infectious
are being triggered in cloud databases
and how exactly
ransomware
infections
are mapped into these databases
we are going to take a look into two or
three different examples here
since we are focused on elasticsearch
and mongodb we are going to look
into examples
of infected elastic search
and infected mongodb instances
with ransomware
i try to understand
how in real world
these infections are triggered
so let's take a look into first example
so this one is an example related to
elastic
search clarence dance
the highlighted details here reflect
if your elastic search instance is
infected
how attackers are leaving ransom
messages
in the infected instance
in this case you can clearly see the
message
highlights all your data is backed up
as we discussed earlier data is a new
currency
which means like the attackers have
taken a backup and they have actually
encrypted the existing state of the data
and they are asking for the bitcoin
in a specific time period if you want to
recover it
if you're not able to provide that money
you're not able to recover your data
which will significantly impact
the running services
and in fact
the brand of the organizations as well
if you are they're not able to control
the data because it will substantially
results in
security breach
now take a look into the another example
here
so this example is specifically for
mongodb
now you can clearly see
it is talking about a one specific
database
here
and what kind of different collections
it has
so the collections
are named as system.indexes as well as
readme so the most important part here
is the readme
and the database name project like
readme to recover your data
so what's inside readme is the key here
which we potentially map it to as an
again a ransomware message
but
subsequently you can figure it out if
you scan the databases
that are available in mongodb and
related
collections in it you will able to
understand
where exactly the ransom
message is being
left and what the demands of the
attacker is
in this particular case this actually
suggests
that how
brand severe infections are occurring in
mongodb instances
and with the previous example you will
see how the similar
infections are happening in
elasticsearch instances
since we are focused primarily on two
databases
elasticsearch and mongodb
so we really need to come up with the
way to detect
the ransomware interactions on the fly
which means
we really need to automate this process
so let's move forward
to talk a bit more about it
in this sections we are going to focus
on
two different tools
that we have designed
the tools actually allow us
to detect these infections
running on remote
instances of elasticsearch and mongodb
on the internet
and we can
use this for internal research purposes
as well as building some strong
prevention solutions as well
but these tools gives you the capability
to just detect
it even as a part of your vulnerability
management scenarios or vulnerability
assessment or even a part of penetration
testing exercises
to detect
whether these instances running in your
environment are infected with ransomware
or not
so these tools
provide a great capability and that's
what we are going to discuss right now
so the first tool that we are going to
talk about is traffic
so stratfor tool provides you the
capability to detect
infected elastic search instances with
ransomware
so you can clearly see the
how the tool looks like what kind of
modules it support and you can clearly
see there is a one module related to
ransomware which will going to
map the elastic set instance
against any potential
infections specifically to ransomware
and we are going to see that
in some time
so the first tool is the stratfor one
for elasticsearch infections
the second tool is amphilate
it is focused on
mapping the mongodb instances whether
these instances are in factoring severe
or not
so if you can look at the different
modules
it's for different modules so it's not
only related to the ransomware
mapping
but it's also related to other infection
scenarios like meo board as well
you know you can check for admin access
privilege escalation you can dumps
different set of information you can
verify the authentication
configured
but our focus is only on the ransomware
in the stock as we have discussed
earlier
both of these tools
will provide you the
power
to run the scans in an automated manner
to unearth infections
in elasticsearch and mongodb instances
running remotely
so let's see how it looks like
so the first example is the stratfor one
ex
exactly the staffer is an action here
it is detecting
in an automated manner
an elastic search instance which is
infected with run severe
and how
it basically scans
that exposed interface
and using
built-in heuristics and signatures it
maps rather the system basically the
elasticsearch cloud instance is infected
or not
as you can clearly see
it is able to detect
that the remote instance is infected and
what kind of ransomware messages being
left there
and that's pretty cool because you can
just use this tool run against
elasticsearch instance and then figure
it out
if it has been compromised or not
another example is of anfield
this one is targeted against
a remote instance of
mongodb
if you look
in the
here the output reflects that you know
it is run against the tcp port 27017 and
the module that is enabled is intrusive
checker and server
so it's going to perform a very
intrusive check here
what happened in this case is dumping
the identifiers for all the databases
which means well are the available
databases
it is readme to recover data admin
config and the interesting one is the
readme to recover data
so what the tool is gonna do right now
it is going to
scan this database for all the available
collections
and try to dump
and check against
the logic that has been embedded in this
tool for detecting
ransomware infection
and you can see that it is able to
detect this ransomware in faction
highlighting
what is the content of that message
what is the ask of the attacker and how
it looks like
so overall
previously you have seen stratfor
now you have seen anfilate
these are some of the examples
but let's see how these tools act in
real world
now it's a time
to go little bit detail
into the demos
the first demo that we are going to talk
about
is the stratfor
in the real world
let's take a look
so right now we are going to see
stratfor in action against the real
world in stance
it has many modules
but this one what we are going to use is
the ransomware one
so let's see
so the tool successfully detects the
infection here
if you can clearly see this is the iep
running on a tcp port 9200
and it detects successfully the
infection in real time
because the remote elastic search
instance is infected
so what you can do here
you can download this tool
and you can check for the state of
elasticsearch instances on the internet
you can even create a batch script you
know provide a multiple
inputs for different elastic search
instances that are exposed on the
internet and run this
tool you will be able to find out that
you are
that those exposed instances of
elasticsearch are infected with
ransomware or not interestingly you can
clearly see there are several patterns
are mapped here bitcoin index readme
data backed up
bitcoin
account identifier and so on
and once it just calculates a logic
it scans for
this particular message
and try to
reflect that
the existing state of that elastic
search instance
so this demo highlights
how exactly staffer provides you a
strong capability
for checking the security state of
elastic search instances
now
let's move on to the next demo
in this particular demo
we are going to run a very intrusive
check against
remote
instance of mongodb
infected with ransomware and you will
see how amphilate
helps to detect that in an automated
manner
so let's first take a look into how the
tool
operates different modules
export
and all that
so first one we are going to run
potentially a basic check
for ransomware
let's take a look into that
so if you can clearly see
we are utilizing here
27017 tcp port which is being consumed
by mongodb forest network connectivity
and now what you can see here that we
are able to detect initial fingerprints
and it is a potential way that this
instance is infected so the tool is
saying run aggressive analysis and let's
just run the intrusive check right now
and see how it reacts
so what the tool is now gonna do
it went inside into the database and
check for the available collections
and whether any of that collection is
infected
basically the attacker has control that
collection
and left over some sort of ransomware
message
and now you can clearly see
that
the remote mongodb instance is infected
with ransomware
so we are doing a rerun here right now
to highlight how it works first it was a
basic check
it shows that there is some potential in
faction
and then we are running the
intrusive check
which means that gold detail into it
figure it out what it is and then show
me whether this
mongodb instance is infected or not
now you have seen then a real world
example and a demo of
detecting ransomware and factions
against mongodb
so just imagine you have these two
two different tools available for you
stratfor for elasticsearch
and
inflate for
mongodb
you can utilize it for a security
research purposes
generating threat intelligence
launching mass scans for potential
ransomware infractions and even
conducting penetration testing analyzing
the security posture of your
cloud databases which in this case
are elasticsearch and mongodb
so this is an automated way
of conducting scary assessment
specifically
highlighting if
these instances are infected or not
with ransomware
so we develop these two tools
that you can utilize in your regular
work environment
to reap benefits
now
what is the inference here
so we strictly believe that subverting
ransomware infection in cloud databases
require defense and depth strategy
and continuous security assessment in an
automated manner
we need automation
the reason for that is the scalability
aspect of it whether it's vertical
whether it's horizontal
you know with that
with exponential increase of
clouds
and
are moving towards cloud technologies
they really need a strong infrastructure
to support that for that they have to
scale and if they have to scale so as
the security has to scale
so in order to conduct
and build a strong security posture we
really need to go after continuous
security assessment and that is only
possible by automation
in this particular talk when we
discussed about how ransomware
infections are
geared up
and attackers are targeting cloud
databases
which are basically the lower building
blocks for any kind of different sas
applications and other variety of
applications
protecting and securing these cloud
databases are of utmost importance
and for that
we really really need to go after
assessing the security postures
of these cloud databases making sure
that these are not being compromised by
attackers
as a crux of the stock
we really need to detect these are not
infected with ransomware
and that should be the target making
sure our data stays secure
and we preserve our e-currency which in
this case is the data
so with that
you can download and fill it and
stratfor tools from these github
wrappers
it's open source you can utilize the
source code the way you want it to be
and consume it accordingly
so both of these tools are available
on github
go ahead fetch it
use it and share your feedback how you
like it feel free to enhance it as well
love to get your feedback on this
thereby making sure as a security
research community we learn from each
other
and that is
our
target should be
so with that
any questions and queries
we can discuss of channel
you can connect me as well
you can visit my portal which we have
discussed earlier or you can connect me
by twitter as well
i would really love to
have your feedback on this one
so that we can take it from
there i hope
you enjoy this talk
and we learn from each other
and you are going to use this
research
and intelligence
in your regular work environment
thank you very much
i really appreciate that
again
i would like to be very thankful
to texas
cyber summit committee members
for
giving me this opportunity
to go after and discuss my research with
you all
and thanks for
creating this conference it's amazing
i have been there earlier as well
and i hope
this research talk
gives you the valuable insights
on how to go
detect
and circumvent
ransomware infections at cloud databases
with that thank you very much