okay thank you everybody for joining to
our presentation and thank you texas
summit for letting us be part of this
amazing conference
uh today we're going to speak about
different vulnerabilities that we found
last year in the 2020 uh that will allow
ultimately an authenticated attacker to
basically compromise full compromise and
sap system so hope you enjoy our
presentation
uh who are we
my name is pablo artusso and today with
ignacio photo we both work as security
researchers at the anapsy security
research labs we're both from argentina
uh and yes we enjoy our day today
basically doing vulnerability research
penetration tests
from time to time
and at the bottom of the screen you will
find a link to our github or team github
where we are gonna publish we we are
gonna be publishing our latest
advisories so if you are curious about
them just
i recommend you go there
this is our agenda for today first we're
going to start with an introduction to
acp world they will go in deeply details
about the different vulnerabilities that
we found last year
uh we have a special chapter talking
about threatening delicious campaign
that we were part of
last year and is really really
interesting and finally some conclusions
so let's start with introduction
why sap why we keep insisting on oacp
security
well acp is one of the largest companies
in the world and the solutions that sap
develop basically are business solutions
are being used by the most
largest companies
in the world so if you go to the fortune
500 oil and gas for example companies
all of them are using sap for the daily
business
acp manages resource financial resources
human resources information stock
resources um
what else business processes so a lot of
different
important and critical
information of a company related to the
business goes through an sap system so
that's why we believe that acp system
should uh
take
should be taken more seriously when it
comes to security
um
today as i already told you we are going
to speak particularly about a layer
that is part of a hundreds of different
solutions
of sap which is called the sap netweaver
layer
this layer is a base layer for
a lot of different solutions and this
means that a lot of sap solutions are
built on top of this layer right so they
share this layer in particular the
subnet wheel layer could be found in two
different ways
developed in java or developed in app
today we're going to be focusing
specifically in the java network layer
right and here for example we have a
very well known solutions of sap like
the solution manager the landscape
manager
the enterprise portal
these are some of the solutions that are
based on the subnet revert java layer
from an architecture point of view this
is how an application server a java
application server looks like right
uh we can see there that
we have two different type of instances
within java we have what is called the
java instance and the central instance
right
the central instance is unique per
system so every system we have only one
central distance
and we have a particular processes
running in that central distance and
besides that we have multiple java
instances as many as you want right
inside each of the java instances we
will have some different processes in
particular as you can see in the slide
we have the icm which is basically the
http server
from um
from this from this sorry from each java
instance
and this means that the way to
communicate to these solutions or to
these uh systems basically is through
the http protocol which is really well
known protocol on the other side if we
were discussing out avap application
servers we are going to see
different binary protocols and custom
protocols which is a little bit
different here in java
uh besides the icm we have what is
called the server process so within the
java instance we have the i think that
is the the the smallest unit of
processing which is the server process
each server process of the java system
has its sound cluster manager as you can
see there on the right
so i just want to mention this because
we're gonna
go back to this in a couple of minutes
another interesting
feature or characteristic of the sap
java
systems is that they are usually exposed
to the internet this means that
sorry they are not usually exposed but
if you grab all the systems that are
exposed to the internet to the internet
the acp systems most of them are sap
java systems and basically from my point
of view this is because they are
http based so this means that they are
easily
being exposed but besides that there is
a particular solution based on sap java
netweaver which is called the enterprise
portal the sap enterprise portal is
basically one of the solutions that
um was brilliant was developed by sap in
order to be exposed to the internet and
allow
sorry allow external users to log into
the system through the enterprise portal
so we are gonna
uh
go back to this again in future chapters
uh because this is a crucial and
important information for the rest of
the of the talk
next chapter is about our findings 20 20
20.
so let's continue with the first of the
lunaries that we have for today
motivation so
why we decided to start looking for this
bug
uh in the early 2020 on march 2020 um
together with a friend ivan we
discovered a bag that was really
critical in the sub solution manager
we finally combined this with another uh
vulnerability and we delivered a talk in
blackhat usa last year i really
recommend it to you go there if you are
interested in all these topics because
we finally got root shells from every
sap server that was part of the acp
landscape so it's really interesting but
besides that the important thing was
that the there was a bug in a sub
solution manager that was basically
a web service exposed without
authentication
so
after that we started asking to
ourselves okay
are there more web services exposed
without authentication what about the
web services that are exposed at the
subnet we would layer because this one
was specifically from the sub solution
manager but the subnet layer also
exposes web services
so
i start like
creating a tool capable of at least all
the web services
decide if or designer check if they have
they need or not authentication
and of course this in an automatic way
because it was a tool after a couple of
weeks or months is i finally got the run
in the tool and
once i run it
uh it gave me a lot of different web
services that were exposed without
authentication
and among all of them there was one that
was called ctc web service si which is
our main uh
topic for for for this analysis
so this endpoint is a soap endpoint so
for those who are not aware about soap
it's just a really interesting protocol
based on xml that allow uh basically
executing co accessory executing methods
remotely
and if you can see in the middle of the
screen the first image we have all the
methods that are available to be
executed or to be used uh
through exit through calling this
soap endpoint
and among all of them there is one that
is called execute which seems to be
interesting on the right side of the of
the slide you have
the
let's say the body of the of the packet
that you should send in order to execute
that
that method and
also you have all the
parameters that they are needed the
identifier context messages and resource
so at this point i didn't know how to
use this
but what i did know was that is all this
is developing in java and
java is easy to decompile right
so i decompile the code and initiate
from a
more box sorry more black box um let's
say strategy to a more white box one
and i found implementation of this web
service
in particular you can see there the
execute function having receiving the
three parameters that we were talking
about uh before and what we have there
are the data types of each of these um
parameters so this is this was really
interesting and really helpful because i
started looking for that data types in
order to find the definition of them but
instead i found
um a piece of snippet of a snippet of
code that was actually
creating a resource identifier
and it had all the different parameters
that this resource identifier
constructor received
so
this was really useful because i could
just grab these three parameters and use
them in order to call uh through the
through a stop message uh the execute
function right
so you can see there the body of the of
the packet of the
of the soap message that i had to send
using all the three um parameters that i
grabbed from the snippet of code and
once i send that
i receive an idea as an answer
so i didn't know
what this idea was but
after playing a little bit with other
methods like events available or read
next event i saw that they were asking
for a parameter that was called session
id so i did a
i think i did some synapses synapses and
i realized that maybe this id was
exactly this that session id that these
methods are asking for
so i started looking for that number
that particular number in the os of the
sap system and i found a log
that was talking about that about that
specific session id and when i
realized that log was uh related to the
configuration with our application the
confirmation with an application i
didn't know what that application was i
knew that was part of the network
administrator panel so i entered to that
as you can see in the images
and within the running configuration
task section i found
a
seems to be a task a configuration task
that was running over there and had the
session exactly the session the same
session i did the right if she was an
answer
so
just just to recap here um i didn't know
what the confirmation wisdom was so i
look for it and i have a quote here from
sap documentation which the most
important thing is that it says it makes
the technical settings in an automatic
way
sorry so it seems that
um
it does really interesting things right
like the technical settings and also in
an automatic way so it seems like
somehow related to scripting or
something else
some part
if we go back to the image we can see
that there is a task name over there
right that is the create users so
somehow it seems there are more tasks
more possible configuration tasks and
some part of our
message that we send through soap
decided that we have to use that
configuration task and if you see if you
pay attention to the parameters you can
quickly see that most probably the good
candidate it was the last parameter
also that parameter seems to be a path
right so i went to the operating system
and tried to look for that possible file
and i found it it was there it was
exactly in the same path that
that that parameter uh said
so it it was really interesting because
okay now i have the file in order to
understand what a ziprock is and what uh
what basically that file is
but besides that i look for that
extension cproc and i realized and i
found that it was more than 500 c
products so at this point i didn't know
what a ziprock is but i know there are a
lot of them but seems that
dc proc the spc user management is the
one that basically decided what
configuration task to run
so i opened that file and i found this
basic
of course as you can see it seems to be
something
xml based here we can find the
description that is the create user the
thing that we appear in the image we can
see some tags like for each inbox
service input that makes the idea that
is something related to scripting
we i found also these which is a message
something that will be
helpful uh later on um
that is called user delays and if you
can see in the first part of the of the
file uh we have something commented we
have user details and some information
that i don't know what it what that
means and finally we have within the
expression tag
we found like
some dash user dash java or raver
user dash username
and if we can see here inside the user
details tag we have the same four tags
so it seems like somehow this is
accessing the data which is over here
so what we can think is like the user
data is like kind of the parameters that
we have to put here or to provide to
this kind of scripts and here
in the pink uh squares they will be
grabbing that values from the parameters
these are just an ideas
so what we know about cprox zipworks are
xml days
there seem to be scripts and there's
interesting parameters how well
if you remember the symbol of the
snippet of code that i already told you
besides that behind that sorry um
the the code also was creating a ctc
context message
with the
with this basically with this string
that is the same string that we were
talking about before this uterus the
user details
and
all this piece of information that was
part of the commented section
so this was the way to provide connect
to provide um parameters to this script
and here as you can see they were
executing with the identifier that we
had before and the input with this
ascetic sorry a ctc context message
um data type
so now we have all things to test this
through the soap endpoints however i had
some issues there uh trying to to make
that work so what happened finally was
that i shift to a more simpler c product
i found another one that was much more
simpler uh it has a message that is
called delete user here we can see that
we have access that this um zip is
accessing the root username
um
tags within the parameters
and it seems that this cproc is deleting
a user right just providing this message
so now we have the knowledge on how
ziprox works at least basic knowledge
and then we have the c product so let's
try it
so i craft uh first of all i create a
new user in the system that was called
this recon user and then i craft the
soap request that is that we have to
send
with the corresponding of course um
parameters here we are choosing the c
proc
task that we want to use
the delete user is the name of the
context message and the content of that
message right that remember it has to be
b6 uh basic c4 encoded we got an id
and this id says that it does well it
has almost the same amount as the other
one it
finished successfully and when i went to
the system to list all the users test
recon user wasn't there anymore
so what happened
so specifically the script executed
successfully and we deleted a user but
in more general terms what we finally
did was we were able to execute a
configuration task without any kind of
authentication and if you remember we
have 500 more configuration tasks right
so at this point i say okay now it's
time to look for the most critical c
proc right
so in order to do that i had to learn a
lot more about c products i had to go
more deeply in details about all the how
they are build what that means i mean
the nature of steps i mean each zip is
based on steps they can have 20 50 50
steps um
they
clearly are our scripts you can uh skip
some steps if they are not interesting
for you
and also in order to talk and to
understand how the process is going
basically it's working you can you can
there is a
a lot of things like um not a lot of
framework uh event driven that i had to
learn how to read an event how to
provide a new event so
after a couple of analysis after a
couple of days doing some analysis i
found one of the
maybe one of the most in critical c
perks that at least from my point of
view
it was really really interesting it had
more than 20 steps but within the first
two steps it did all the critical things
that we needed
this was the code
of the cproc the name was create java
users
in the first step you will create a user
with a password that you provided and of
course the username and in the second
step you
will assign a role to that user and
which role well the role that you
provide also as parameter
here is the template of the message that
we can send the user the password and
the role that we want to that user
so stop talking please
go directly to the demo so here we are
gonna see
um
a demo of this first of all the attacker
will try to log in to the system with
the texas admin user this user doesn't
exist yet so it will actually it would
fail
perfect
um so now
what is the attacker gonna do is uh
basically execute a script that is
exploiting this vulnerability
called recon
has to provide of course the host the
port the username and the password of
the user that it was that he had that he
wants sorry to create and
the administrator role that is one that
is the role that is going to be assigned
it is basically hard coded inside the
script
so as you can see here is it executing
the c pro the create java users and we
only need the first two steps then we
can cancel the execution because we
don't need anything else right
so now we are going to try to login with
the assist with that user again and this
time it works because the user was
created
uh now just uh just you to to
to be sure if we list the user roles we
are going to see that it has
administrator
assigned
so
what happened here
basically an unauthenticated attacker
with access just to the http port of the
sap java system
was able to
grab
an administrator user and potentially
fully compromise the entire sap system
so let's talk about the protections and
in particularly when we talk about
patching
sap releases the patch
within the first month after we um we
submit the the vulnerability right so
this talks really good about the appears
art psrt team because
i'm not sure if you all are aware about
this but sap releases security patches
for their solutions every second tuesday
of every month and
and yes they they released the patch
within the first month so in the next
possible patch day
the the patch was already out so this
was really quickly and well it talks
really good about the the ps rt team and
of course all the developers that are
involved
um but besides the patch sap also
released three different
notes talking about x-informational
recon explaining to their customers how
this
vulnerability worked where it was an faq
talking about how to install the patch
explaining again uh the different
questions are the most simple questions
that could arise
and a third note that talk about
workarounds sap knows that sometimes um
it's
not easy or not so quickly to implement
patches
in sap systems so they also release a
workaround that is busy how to disable
the application in case you are not
using not using it so yeah for sap uh
this was really important and they
address it really well in terms of
protections
talking about extra protections besides
the one provided by the vendor um
also the community office north uh
created a rules for that and the most
well-known ips is on firewalls develop
new rules to to address this this
vulnerability from an apses
we develop a free assessment tool that
you have you can download it directly
from our github or you can also use our
cloud version from the from our web page
in terms of publication
well this attack was in some
of the most important resources in terms
of news like cdn and upgrading but the
most interesting thing is that different
countries different certs from different
countries issued alerts
about this topic and primarily because
there
there were a lot of companies
within their their countries like that
uses this
software saps
and in terms of public exploit well we
have
three of the most i mean these were the
three most common
uh tpeak i think it was the first one
that releases the
working exploit and sir stainer is a
really well known 33 researcher that
usually he developed
metasploit modules so i think that
within the first or second week
they already had a fully functional
working exploit within the metabolic
framework
and now i will let patel actuary ignacio
continue with with the talk
thanks paolo hi everyone i am ignacio
and i'm really glad to be here today
speaking about the cluster manager
peer-to-peer communication research
and the reason behind this research was
first at all that an sap system is a
software platform
which means that it's made of several
components which some of them highly
couple each other and exchanging
messages or opening ports for external
connections for example
but also as pablo said before the sap
java system are more frequently exposed
on internet becoming a really
interesting product to analyze
so we decided to see what is open by
default
with a list of services that
has open ports and waiting for
connections in all interfaces
and filtering out those that we already
know what it is looking for the fresh
target
we establish a connection with the
remaining ones and one of them gives us
this sap cluster manager banner
for us was quite new
and not a lot of documentation were
available at that time
so we decided to interact a bit more
with this service
playing with different payload size and
also sending back for example
the
the banner that we received when we
started the connection
and for this last case
the behavior of the service was quite
different
it keeps waiting for more information
after this banner
checking the processes calls we realized
that what it seems to be a two-step
communication because first the service
try to read up to 47 bytes which is the
same length of the banner that we get
and after that more data is required
also analyzing the logs reaction to our
different payloads in the first case we
have an exception when we sent a puree
payload full of a payload and
a
handshake java class
and another supporter protocol version
is printed out in this log files
but if we send the banner we send back
the banner that we get when we establish
the connection and append some a's at
the end
another java class
throw an exception
about a character header and a checksum
so we decided to take these two java
classes as our starting point for this
analysis
and we were able to identify all of the
fields that make up these messages
on the left side we have the hand check
which is 47 byte as we as we tell before
and after that we have
the header of the message
48 byte which was new for us
in that moment
and
as we can see we have a variable length
body
for this message
and this body will be processed by
different kind of
services
this is the role of this service id
field in the header of the of the
message
the service id will pick the listener
that will be in charge of process or
handle our request
and this internal message listener is an
interface and we found around 40
implementation of this message listener
some of them we highly critical and
privileged action as we will see as
follow
here we have a scenario in which an
attacker which has direct access to this
cluster manager
no authentication authentication is
required here so it can interact with
any of these service ids or any of these
internal message listeners
first we will talk about
the sld listener
which gives us information about the
system or system properties for example
the username that is running
this
sap system and also the global directory
and version about the java about sap and
and
other info
about this system
but also we found this database manager
listener
which allows us to modify some
connection parameters for example the
max connections allowed to be
established so if we set this value
for example to one
only one connection will be available
accessing the available connections for
real users and leading to a denial of
service for example
and the last one for today
is this gmx listener jmx is a java
technology is not an sap thing
which allows to be short basically to
register and invoke dynamically some
something called
m bins
it is a java bean
with some specific characteristic for
this technology
it's not
really interesting for our analysis
today
but
as we can see here we can invoke and
query all the
m bins that
were available
in this
sap system
and we found around
m bins
registered by default in an s and clean
sap installation
and some of them with high privileged
actions
or critical actions
and we will we will see the effect of
these basically of these three march
bins and this met and its methods
the first one is the single sign-on
which allows us to add a trusted ticket
issue
this means i can register myself
as a single sign-on ticket creator
with my public key and after that with
my
private key i can create my own
single sign-on authentication tickets
and authenticate in inside the system as
any kind of user
and pablo will talk about this
configuration in the system about create
http alias and enabling enabling
directory these things
um
this kind of configuration can be
performed also this through this cluster
manager and its service listeners
now we will show you a demo
about these jmx listener and adding a
thruster a trusted system to create
single sign-on tickets
here we are gonna start from already
logged in user just to show you the
configuration that can be achieved
through this cluster manager
as we can see no trusted system
is available so far
so first the attacker check the
connection is possible to the cluster
manager
and after that we'll try to inject its
own system on its own publicly as a
trusted
first the script will try to
identify the message id that is required
once we get this
we'll try to identify the service id
which is running the
jmx listener and after that as we can
see here now we have a new
trusted system to create logon ticket
for single sign-on
about protection measures to this
service sap releases a node
basically adding authentication to this
cluster manager service
but also it's a good option here to
first configure the message server acl
to allow connections only from ip
addresses
of this
for instances of the same sap system
and also end users
usually don't need access and interact
with this cluster manager so firewall
restriction
dropping connection from end users only
allowing from
as i said before instances of the same
sap system is a good option
next pablo will continue with the last
vulnerability for today
so yes thank you ignacio and let's start
with the final
vulnerability of today
first of all motivation so either with
the cluster manager or with recon an
authenticated attacker is able to grab a
user an administrator user of the sap
system right
however administrator users are not able
to execute os commands and as securities
researchers when we start looking for
vulnerabilities we want to follow the
pre-op remote code execution right
so in order to achieve that goal let's
say uh
we have i mean we have half of that goal
we already know how to without
authentication grab a user of the system
and of the system sorry and not any user
but an administrator one
so the we have to
fill that gap you know we have to find a
way to
execute commands but being an
administrator users which is something
that should not happen
but it's most probably to find it
that finding a pre-op remote code
execution from scratch
so we start our search
uh with the netweaver administrator
application this application holds a lot
of different and
and
sever i mean several applications within
this application um there is part of the
sap netweaver java layer and allow you
to control a lot of different stuff from
your sap system you can control
connections you can control
configurations regarding um
applications you can control
connectivity like give authentication to
some part to the other part etc in fact
the configuration with our application
the one that is related to recon
is
inside this nwa
another application that is part of it
is called java http provider
configuration and within this
application you can configure several
things related to the http server for
example you can define application
analysis application analysis are
basically a path a short path in order
to relate an application so if you want
to define um i don't know what dash asd
and you would every time that somebody
enters you asd
you're going to write
it to an application to a particular
application that is running on your
system you can define that you can also
define aliases
aliases are the same thing i mean you
can define an alias like the previous
one dash acsd but instead of related to
the application you will relate it to an
open operating system path so you can
for example link it to a temp
directory
um also you can define virtual hosts of
course the cache usage and you can
activate directory listing so if you pay
attention i mentioned directly listing
analysis right
combining those two things what you
could do is basically you activate an
alias in order to
uh
link a particular
um
asd for example a particular url to an
os directory or
ios file
and then browse that file because you
have the directory listing activated
is that possible yes it is possible and
with that an administra an administrator
user already will be able to read files
from the os
but
if we want to execute commands we need
something else right and one option is
to upload a web shell for example place
it in the os and then reference it with
this technique
but how we can upload a webshop
well we started looking for ways to
upload a web shell and we finally found
a candidate application this application
was or basically allows you to upload a
configuration file
uh inside a zip file
but
if
the file that you compressed and upload
doesn't follow certain structure
after the compressing the application
will read that file will fail because
again it doesn't follow the correct
structure
but it will never delete that file
and moreover it will return an error
saying hey
the path where i decompress it and the
file is doesn't follow or this file is
not uh found there blah blah but
important thing is that it also gives
you the path
so with those two things what you can do
is basically upload a web show and then
grab that path and use it as an alias so
the full exploitation will work like
this first of all log in as
administrator enter to the nmu
application activate the directory
listing
upload this configuration
web shell over there
inside the zip once it fails the
webshell will remain over there and it
will give you it will return you the
path where this website was uploaded use
that to create an alias
of the system and you can reference your
web shell and finally you will be
executing
commands
as the sad adm user
so demo time let's see this in a video
how it works this video will be a little
blurred because there is not a public
exploit about this so it's
better to keep some things private still
so here the attacker is activating the
um
directory listing now is defined in the
alias the alias will be named java
underscore rse underscore poke
here is checking that the
basically
that directory or that alias
is
is an empty directory so far
now we are going to blur uh but here
what is happening is the attacker is
uploading the web shell to that
particular uh
directory and here we have it devops
shell.jsp
so now it's a matter of executing the
command that we want for example who am
i and this will return the sad adm user
that is being used by the system in this
case rd1 idm
so this basically means that um
a user with administrator privileges was
able to execute os commands of course
abusing this vulnerability and if this
winner is combined with recon or with
the cluster monitor issue then it will
be a fully functional exploit of a
pre-op remote code execution
let's talk a bit about protections um
about the patching again sap patched
this monarity in the first patch day
possible this means within the first
month we we submitted that uh
vulnerability and within the first month
it was already patched so this talks
really good about of course the psrt
minority technical steam involved in
developing the the protection
but it also talks really good about sap
in general because uh it's clearly how
they have
been improving in terms of security how
they are putting effort into protecting
the your customers and and of course
make creating or developing a more
secure software in fact we can see that
uh
we see that really often
uh because each day is harder and harder
to find a new vulnerability so yeah
really
really good for them
as an extra protection besides of course
applying the patch uh an extra
recommendation will be also to keep
firewalls and all the
your security um
endpoints that you have updated because
we are dealing with http issues so here
for example if you have a firewall in
the middle maybe the firewall will have
detect
the
reverse the web shell and will blocked
that attack so it's always a good uh
advice and good recommendation to have
all those uh
security endpoints up to date
now i will leave in asia to continue
with the with the following topic
forecasting the implication of these new
critical vulnerabilities that were about
to be published
most of them targeting potential
internet exposed solution i can mention
for example the solution manager or the
sap java stack system
along with some previous vulnerabilities
really all vulnerabilities that are
still being exploited in the while
nowadays and apps decided to take the
lead into this threat intelligent
campaign
as we mentioned before the sap system
are mission critical systems
which means that manage or handle
financial records uh transactions
customer records so
very important information from the
biggest companies around the world so
sabotage tax and spinach attacks are
everyday threats for these kind of
systems
but beside these
targeted attacks or from expert attacks
we found some other interesting reasons
for example cryptominers or bounty
hunters or botnets which are
more
automated attacks and massive attacks
that could lead to a security breaching
in our sap systems
these new rules in the technological
environment for example
anonymous payments and anonymous
networks and
some
bps in the cloud
services
that give the feeling of anonymity in
the in the
internet connection
bring new players uh to this game
so not only expert attackers
has
are
actively exploiting or trying to exploit
these vulnerabilities
also internet tech indexers
give the information about
sap system exposed to internet
joining all this information together
imagine that there is a lot of people
trying to
break into this kind of sap systems
we have kept track of seven thread
vectors
and as a result of our threat
intelligence campaign we have evidence
of
more than 500 confirmed expectations
with more than 100
with the attackers with their hands on
the keyboard trying to access the data
or exploring the system
and as a key tca takeaway is an
implication the three actors are
actively targeting and exploiting
unsecured sap applications and some of
them possess a lot of expertise and
capabilities to carry out really
sophisticated attacks
besides that the window to defend is
getting shorter uh for instance the
exploitation for recon started in less
than 72 hours that sap
released the patch
and also a new sap system that were
provisioned in the in cloud environments
has been discovered an attack in in
about three hours but the attacks are
not only targeting missing sap security
patches but also for example
misconfiguration as could be default
credentials or
misconfigured acls
and finally these three not only
represent a cyber security risk
they also could have some compliance
implication in
sox or gdpr
well some fun facts during our thread
intelligent campaign was for example
that after exploiting recon and
successfully creating a user the
attacker applies a workaround to protect
the the sap system so i think that maybe
not all here were capes
but someone else that was able to
execute os command of using a really old
bernability did it just to run a mono
crypto miner
and finally
we have evidence that some vulnerable
endpoints were tested around three
months before the exploit was publicly
available
and concluding this presentation for
today
i want to share with you the list of
vulnerabilities and patches but also i
want to emphasize that combining some of
them for example
recon with the java rce or cluster
manager with the java rce is possible to
perform and authenticate the remote
common execution
and as a conclusion in itself
we have that critical exploits are
becoming publicly available
and maybe because of this or the public
attention on the new technological rules
that we share with you during this
presentation attacks on sap systems are
getting more and more common
and on the other side we have that
finding bugs in sap is getting harder
this is sample as
how important the the security is for
sap and also along with this sap patches
are being released faster and system
getting stronger so
and sure but you need to ensure that you
have your system as updated as possible
and i want to thank you and i hope you
that you have enjoyed this presentation
bye bye