hi and welcome to our presentation uh
entitled securing over-the-air firmware
updates for industrial internet of
things devices
the reason we
selected to do this presentation is we
believe that it's representative of a
lot of
iiot
connectivity
um
we're specifically from the water sector
and we'll talk more of that as we go on
my name is kenneth crowther i'm the
product security leader for xylem's
applied water systems and america's
commercial teams
and my name is radhika
i'm a product security engineer here at
xylem
so so let's get into it the first the
first thing we want to establish is we
want to make sure that we don't scare
anyone
by talking about
cyber exposure about cyber
vulnerability and so we want to we want
to remind everyone why iot is emerging
why connected digital systems
so
in the water sector
we believe that we're super lean
we can deliver
a one ton of clean water to every
household in the united states for
example
for three dollars a ton
and uh and then we can reclaim
those tons of
material
uh for uh within that same price right
so we're delivering and reclaiming a ton
of material all for three dollars a ton
and i don't think any industry can claim
that leanness and yet it's not good
enough right three in 10 people still
lack access to safe drinking water six
in 10 people still lack access to safely
managed sanitation
and digital
solutions are a key to making a
transformation that can make
our sector even more lean
and so just as a reminder of uh where
we're coming from there's an example
from south mid indiana that's that's uh
uh informative in this in this case
so south bend in indiana they had this
big problem they were dumping about a
dozen
olympic sized swimming pools uh worth of
some of sewage
into the saint joseph's river every day
and uh
this was resulting in
concentrations of uh bacteria like e
coli
growing it was reducing the the ability
to use that water for recreation um and
uh and it was starting to concern epa
among other organizations
they estimated what it would take to
rebuild their their wastewater system
and it was going to cost on the order of
800 900 million dollars right just just
shy of a billion dollars for a small
town like south bend indiana
that ends up being something like um ten
thousand eleven thousand dollars per
person which is just unaffordable
and so what we did instead was we
installed 120 sensors
these are flow meters
level sensors
and uh this helped us to understand the
condition of the wastewater system
and
what we realized was that there was a
lot of unused capacity and what we
really just needed in terms of
concrete
was a 200 300
uh installation in order to make this
uh
infrastructure more navigable
in the end this saved over half a
billion dollars in capital expenditures
these sensors then became part
integrated in into this control system
where the sensors are basically kind of
like bidding for downstream
capacity so as flow as level is rising
as flow is increasing they're starting
to value that portion of the wastewater
infrastructure starting to value that
downstream capacity more
and it's now bidding for this downstream
capacity and the result is is that we
can use the infrastructure that already
existed
more successfully
and
and even and with this operational
technology they're now saving 1.5
million per year in addition to the half
a billion that they saved in
capital investments
this is reducing overflow into the saint
joseph river by a billion gallons a year
it completely eliminates overflow during
the drier
seasons of the year
um and reduces it by like 70 or 80
percent during the the wettest seasons
uh e-coli concentrations have dropped by
and all of this was made possible
because of connected digital solutions
um
in fact uh
the the gateways and the cloud
processing still happens on our site
where we're monitoring and uh and
helping to continuously improve what's
going on and securing this
and so i want to make sure that we
establish this upfront because as we
talk about iot and we talk about some of
the threats and attack vectors and stuff
like that i want to make sure that we
remind ourselves why we're doing that
so the second thing is that connected
digital infrastructure
does result in
additional exposures and emerging
threats and so
uh
we're monitoring right now in the water
sector seven threat activity groups that
have specifically
exercised certain tactics and techniques
against water technologies
and and we're watching out for other
threat activity groups that have
techniques
and procedures for attacking industrial
control systems
and so
for example uh dragos released this
report and they talked about these two
groups magnalium and raspite that are
specifically targeting
safety systems
um
and this is something that we're aware
of and as we
talk about uh attacks and protecting
um
controllers uh for these over-the-air
firmware updates um we're acknowledging
the fact that these tactics and
techniques exist and in fact these
techniques have gone into informing
what we
want to protect against
and so this this example shows an
activity by raspite um wherein they
masqueraded as this trilog.exe
um program
they
were successful at overriding parts of
the firmware
in this schneider electric triconic
system
and
while they probably intended to do some
worse damage it successfully shut down
the plant
and the plant shut down multiple times
before they realize that
that there's something something is
going on something is fundamentally
wrong with the
the product
and uh
after going to schneider electric
realized that this was malware that's
targeted to modify the firmware of this
system
and so as we talk about over the year
firmware updates we're specifically
paying attention to these kinds of
things
and this is representative of a problem
that we definitely want to avoid right
we don't want anyone overriding
the firmware particularly
to result in any kind of unsafe uh
activities
so but this this is part of this larger
problem uh
we
uh
recognized that there were
a trillion dollars a trillion u.s
dollars in losses last year because of
various kinds of cyber breaches
the average cost of an incident was 500
um
in the water sector there were reports
of over 150 products having some sort of
vulnerabilities
the water wastewater sector is the third
most targeted sector of all
16 critical infrastructures that are
categorized in the u.s
we're right now tracking seven activity
groups um that have tactics and
techniques that are or have been used
against
uh water or wastewater
facilities or water technology
um and so on and so forth right this is
this is the cyber summit and uh
you guys recognize these kinds of things
and they exist in the water sector as
well
and so
so why have we picked over their
firmware updates as kind of the focus
and
how do we believe that this can overall
help improve the security of
um critical infrastructure as we move
and transform our infrastructure to
become more digital and more connected
um
so
the first thing is to to recognize that
there has digital
connected digital infrastructure is
starting kind of a
transformation
um so on the left side of this
shows the traditional purdue model
and in this model the utility owns all
of the utility or the plant or whatever
right the operator
owns all of the infrastructure
and down at the bottom are their
physical processes their sensors
actuators valves drives
they have intelligent controllers right
or just controllers that have been
programmed with logic
above that they have their supervisory
controllers their scada systems their
hmis their historians right this this
overall constitutes the operation
um these then are are
a part of an area network or a plant
network um where they can pivot across
what they need to for the purpose of
operations and control
there's usually some kind of a gap a
demilitarized zone
a
some kind of logical segmentation
then
a connection to the enterprise
where they
use this information to start scheduling
logistics billing
doing the
the business side
and what we're starting to see
if you move over to the right side of
the screen
is a fundamental shift in how this
architecture is working
and we just pull out two examples um in
some cases there is an industrial
gateway and that industrial gateway is
owned some kind of a jump post or
something like that and it's owned and
maintained by the vendor
and
it then allows for
exchange of information back to a cloud
environment
because because that data is now in that
cloud environment it allows for
continuous improvement constant
monitoring new features
more rapid implementation a realization
and adaptation to what customers need
across various types of systems
all of these
features that we've been talking about
with respect to digital twins and things
like that
and what we're starting to see is a need
for this additional communication which
then results in these added exposures
the utility no longer owns all the
infrastructure but
it also means that there needs to be a
partnership
in how we
execute on cyber security
and so
what we're going to talk about is how
firmware over-the-air firmware updates
um provides a like a case study to look
at this uh
communication back and forth between the
utility and the vendor
and um
results in
uh a concept or a set of concepts on how
we can protect
this uh additional exposure that's
created
um and then it and then it reveals some
things that we would like to conclude
with about
partnering uh across the industry for
the purpose of cyber security
so
so this is our rough sketch of uh
firmware uh over-the-air firmware
updates which we'll refer to as phota as
we go
and
i'm going to let radica talk about the
details but i want to point out first
that
there's three
different environments
that were that were spanning right the
product maker environment where we're
developing and experimenting and testing
the firmware
the cloud provider environment that's
providing the infrastructure
and
the
the storage and the servers and the
capability in order to make connections
out
to these iiot devices
and then there's the the operator site
right the industry site where the actual
operations are happening and where the
device sits
so with that i'll turn it over to
erratica to talk about some details and
and some threat uh modeling
so looking at this picture yeah
the firmware update process over the
year goes something like this
it starts with the development
environment
and
the developers test the firmware updates
and gets them ready for the build
and then once they merge the code with
the master branch
that triggers an update process the
firmware is compiled
and
using the key management server from the
cloud they sign the
firmware packages and then store them in
the cloud
there will also be some kind of
configuration files that specify the
firmware versions the compatible devices
the rollout methods and so on
once these firmware packages are ready
for the gateway
there are two ways that the gateway can
receive those updates
they can be pushed to the cloud to the
gateway or
the gate we can keep checking for
updates and
once it gets the updates from the cloud
storage it will send to the device
now on the device end you'll verify the
hash of the package and then try to
upgrade
if there are any errors in the upgrade
process they'll roll back the changes
so this is kind of like a data flow
diagram or a dfd for the firmware update
process over the year
notice that for the gateway
and the key management piece there's a
orange outline
we're trying to indicate that they have
a shade responsibility
within the bigger picture
when we try to make sure that the entire
process of
photo is secure you have to make sure
that each of these individual pieces is
secure
and
to manage that security of these
components there is a shared
responsibility
the gateway or the mobile device that's
on the industrial side is owned by the
site but
the security of the device and the
firmware update
are managed by the product vendor so
there's a shared responsibility between
the site and the product maker
similarly for the key management piece
that's
sitting on the cloud
the cloud service provider and the
product members have a shared
responsibility
the key management solutions are
provided by the cloud service provider
and the management and the rotation of
those keys and all that is handled by
the product maker
next slide please
connect so now that we have a dfd we can
do a threat model
this involves identifying the threats in
a very structured way
and then listing out the security
controls that address those threads
the threats we see on the right side are
based on a stride model which stands for
spoofing tampering repudiation
information disclosure
denial of service and elevation of
privilege
these are some types of threats that we
can look for in the solution
um
notice that we don't have to use stride
but it can be any kind of threat
modeling process
it might be
miters common weakness enumeration model
cw or my test attack framework or
anything else
stride is just one way of standardizing
this process
and then
once these
threats are documented
these are mitigated by enforcing some
security controls within the process
these
security controls become part of our
trust model of the
solution the trust model is generally
built on security principles like
authentication integrity non-reputation
confidentiality availability and
authorization
these security principles
will ensure that
the firmware code is handled
confidentially
that it implements access control on the
code
and it ensures that there is no
tampering of the code and also that all
the useful details are
locked
we can do this kind of threat modeling
and the solution for photo
next slide please scan it
so here in on the slide we have listed
some threads
for
all three buckets the product maker
bucket the pipeline and the cloud are in
the operations of the industry inside
using the stride model we can list out
some of these threads for each of these
packets this list is not exact
exhaustive but it gives you an idea
one of the threats
is
an attacker spoofing a developer's
identity and being able to publish their
own firmware
this disrupts the product maker's
publishing process
or we may have a spoofed quota server
that is serving
malicious firmware updates
or an attacker may be able to
tamper with the firmware in the
development environment
or have tampered updates available on
the
in the cloud for the endpoints
are tampered on the way to the devices
and when it comes to reputation
we can have some updates that are not
tracked
using proper login and
that can happen either on the cloud foda
server or on the devices
you may have some counterfeit
firmware available or a man in the
middle may have may be able to get a
copy of the firmware and then make some
changes
there may be some denial of service
using flood of requests or very large
update packages
or when it comes to elevation of
privileges
you may have some admin users doing some
anatomized operations or someone getting
unauthorized access to data in cloud
these are some threads that we can list
but let's see how they can impact the
photo
solution let's pick a couple of threads
as an example and walk through this
let's say
in the cloud storage there's an
elevation of privilege issue and an
internal user who has access to this
storage server
is able to access other servers and
other people's data
because of this issue
they may be able to
spoof the
firmware publisher's identity
and
maybe alter the firmware updates
stored on the cloud server or they may
be able to break the firmware updates
configuration and control process
so because of that
can you go to the next level
now we have these two threads that we
are focusing on the internal users
getting innovation of privileges and
being able to spoof a developer's
identity
if a user is able to spoof and get
elevated privileges
it means that there are no checks to see
whether
that user
is authorized to do those
privileged auction actions
they're able to get some admin or super
user privileges to access those
resources that they're not supposed to
or another way is to
make some lateral movement or some side
channel attacks and being able to access
those resources
to prevent this
we can have some role-based access
control on every operation performed on
the photo server
and
admin operations
can also be authenticated using some
multi-factor authentication
to ensure that they are who they are
multi-factor authentication will also
reduce the risk of
threats from weak or shared credentials
network segmentation in fire volume will
also help in preventing that kind of
lateral movement from of users from one
server to another
and then the
product makers side
we can also add some protections to
prevent a spoofing of a developer's
identity
if a user is
able to spoof the
firmware publisher's identity they can
corrupt the firmware con
configuration and control process too
so to prevent this
user access to the build process must be
strictly controlled and monitored
and
the approval process to merge the code
into the master can include more than
one person so
the idea is that
spoofing one person's identity might be
easy but spoofing two people at the same
time be way more difficult
so even if you take just two threads
listed here we have some of these
security controls that we can put in
place to prevent these two threads
similarly we can
come up with these threads and uh in the
end synthesize all these into
actionable
measures that we can think
let's take another example
um let's say someone is able to push
rogue firmware updates to the cloud
photo server
um
it's possible that
the firmware updates are not signed by
the developer then
you may be able to craft these up from
your update packages
load on
because there are no checks on the
endpoint to verify the authenticity of
the update package
in that case a very simple test case to
crash the endpoint is by sending very
large update packets
because
even if there is signature verification
on the end by the time it downloads the
entire large firmware update package the
gateway may become unresponsive
potentially draining its battery
this can lead to a denial of service on
the in the industrial side
next like this
now let's consider these two threads
rogue firmware updates and really large
updates
if an attacker is able to push rogue
firmware updates to the cloud server
it shows that the cloud environment can
be dampered
so
apart from controls like authorization
and firewalling and authentication
controls
signing the packages by the firmware
publisher will help in reducing these
threads
on the
receiving end the end device it can
verify the signature of the publisher
before upgrading
and then
to mitigate the risk of having very
large update files
if the firmware update is really large
in size
when the gateway downloads it without
checking about the size the battery may
drain because of excessive
processing load
or it can use up all the storage and
break the gateway
let's say instead of a gateway we have a
mobile device and
probably it has more storage then it
won't be a problem on the
mobile device
but then
when the update package goes to the end
device it may have the same problem you
can use up all the storage and then
brick the device
so to prevent these threads
we can have validation checks on the
file size before downloading
and then version tracking to make sure
that
the end device is
receiving the firmware updates that it
is compatible with
and then logging all these operations on
the photo server
can you go to the next leftness
this way we can document all these
different threads and then come up with
all the different security controls to
prevent these
and then
we tried to synthesize all these
protection mechanisms into four
different buckets
and this will help in building some
cyber security into the further process
securing fodder process
requires what we call a multi-barrier
approach or defensive depth
we'll give you water waste water as an
example
in
water based water monitoring system
there are different
layers of security built into the system
we start with the legislation have
making laws governing the water
treatment and monitoring
then
when it comes to the local monitoring
authorities
all the neighboring
monitoring authorities share data among
each other
and the
local monitoring authority will make
some decisions based on the data it is
receiving from the upstream monitoring
authorities
and then they make adjustments as needed
and then
the water treatment facility
even that one has several layers of
added for redundancy and
approval process
for this water treatment and the process
is monitored to make sure that the water
is safe for human consumption and then
it goes to
the end users
throughout this process
there are several layers of checks and
approvals and monitoring
we will apply the same principles of
multi-barrier approach to our foda
cybersecurity
looks like this so
um
before we go to the next slide i just
want to emphasize that
um
that this multi-barrier approach is not
only on the backs of the utilities
so
even though the utilities are the ones
actually doing the treatment
and frequently owned the transport and
delivery infrastructure
and there is a multi-layer tech stack to
do that
this is a partnering effort between
other utilities that uh provide that are
also using a similar source
between the municipality or the
community
and uh
and so we're to start realizing that
some of these
partnerships are necessary to secure
iot
in our case
so
so we're going to talk about these
different layers the first thing to talk
about is
that we want to ensure
that the device can verify the
authenticity and integrity of the
firmware
and there's two key principles um
that
that all the security of the device is
based on
the first is the idea of the root of
trust
and the second
and this has to do with
how the
the chip sits on the actual
board itself
and we'll talk a little bit about that
and then the next is the chain of trust
how that route of trust is uh
helps to make sure that we have an
authentic um and an untempered
bootloader and how that bootloader helps
to make sure that we have an authentic
and untempered firmware and how that
firmware then has built-in procedures to
make sure that
the update uh
component and the communications
components
are constantly secure and that the
features that they need in order to
establish secure communication or to
verify the authenticity and integrity of
an update um
are intact
so
the first thing is this idea of root of
trust
so the idea is that when
when there's a reset function
there's a very limited amount of memory
or capability
that that a chip
can deal with
and because of that
it provides some inherent
trustworthiness that we need to learn
how to take advantage of
in some
architectures um there's only one
function that it can run and there's
some immutable rom boot loader
but even when there's this immutable
boot loader there's typically like a
segment in there for
or a slice of memory in there for
verification
and while the default might be some
basic crc checksum
that
that set of features can typically be
replaced with a public key and a sep and
and some sort of uh
verification algorithm
uh in order to verify the firmware
in other cases uh where there is this
basic uh
immutable rom bootloader it provides an
opportunity in the architecture for
establishing a secondary bootloader
where you verify the integrity of the
bootloader the bootloader then has
public key and advanced uh crypto
methods for verifying signed firmware
and the firmware then is able to
load a validated and verified update
process and communication driver
and is able to access
certificates and other things that might
be involved in
those exchanges
um so this is the idea that there's this
root of trust
um and that at each layer in the the
loading of the firmware
you're carefully
assuring
integrity and authenticity and then
loading the next loading the next
feature
there's also
uh a becoming more and more popular
are these uh additional chips trusted
platform modules
where they've already thought through
all of the
uh
root of trust
and uh crypto excel uh crypto uh
requirements
uh tamper resistance redundancy
resilience of uh uh of install and
rollbacks and things like that
um and there's a a special set of
functions that uh exist already
on these uh
these
chips that can now be established
independent of the
[Music]
the basic mechanism
so
underlying all of this
though is
um
a
a a
cryptological schema which uh can
be across a number of algorithms
hopefully
we're looking for ones that are approved
by or consistent with fips 140
dash 2 or fips 140-3
preferably maybe even validated
through that fix 140-2 or dash 3
process
but even if the algorithm and the
process and the architecture is all
revealed
the
process can still be safe as long as
we're protecting
that private key that's used to sign
the bootloader or to sign the firmware
or to
a counter sign a certificate
request
and
so in this process we need to pay
special attention with how we're using
third parties um if the third party
develops our firmware and then hands
over the firmware with their private key
now that key is not only do we not know
where it's been and we have not have
control over it but now it's been
transferred through some kind of sharing
mechanism that was established
and so
as
as product vendors we should get in the
habit
of making sure there's enough
agility in the way that our product is
architected such that when the product
becomes ours we can generate our own
private key
we can export
the public key and encode it properly so
that it can be involved
in the bootloaders verification
processes
for loading this firmware
the last piece to think about is that
sometimes things fail and sometimes they
fail for unexpected reasons um and so
the last part of security of this device
is that we want to make sure that we
don't accidentally brick our device
through some kind of
firmware update process that goes wrong
in an unexpected way and so on the one
hand we're going to be doing a lot of
testing but on the other hand we want to
make sure that we have rollback and
fallback conditions so that we can make
sure that
if if firmware does load and the
bootloader rejects it
or if it's rejected in a verification
process before it even resets or reboots
we want to make sure that that doesn't
disrupt the operation
of the device
so so one last thing about
verifying the high level firmware
is
we need to get in the habit of making
sure that this chain of trust goes all
the way from the bottom to the top
and that means that uh
we need to
assure that we're
not using obsolete uh function
functions
many of these obsolete functions
are not careful with buffer or with
memory or with the way that
elements are transitioned from the
transceiver chip or the uh into this
update process into the firmware storage
um and we need to make sure that
every aspect of the firmware
is being
tested through
a component analysis or through a static
analyzer that's consistent
with the
uh
the whatever the function set is that
the that are being provided to us by the
chip vendor or that are consistent with
the architecture that we're working with
and so
so this is the first
uh
or at least one important layer of trust
and this is completely under the control
of the product maker right the product
maker we can decide on the architecture
we do work with the chip vendor in order
to make sure that we understand
boot loader firmware where we can stick
in verification how we encode the
public keys in order to make this
verification work
we might need to work with manufacturers
so that
we for a communications driver for
example we might want to make sure that
the private key
for that establishing secure
communications is generated on the
device itself
um and then it generates a key signing
request we send it over to our
certificate authority to counter sign it
and now that way we have a
chain of trust and communications that
then sits in the on the device in the
form of a certificate
and now we don't have to give our third
party manufacturer for that
communications piece access to all of
our basic uh development systems
um so this is the idea this root of
trust and a chain of trust
and now we have a device with firmware
that is is ready to start accepting
these kinds of over-the-air firmware
updates
but that's just that's just one layer in
this multi-barrier system
next one deals with
cryptography
encryption and
integration of tls into the
communication
this will ensure that the firmware is
protected from the time of compilation
and signing
and then stored secure encrypted
in the data storage
and then transmitted securely using
encrypted channels of communication
to do this
we start off with a very hardened server
we remove unnecessary ports and services
and have a minimal attack surface
and then
we include the database that is used for
storage
access to this storage service will be
restricted to only those
people that need it
and the communication says channels
between the one component to the other
must be encrypted using tls
only the latest and greatest encryption
standards like aes and tls 1.2 or higher
with strong ciphers are used here
and on the endpoint side we have the
chain of trust established with the
product developer using secured like
cannot explain
it has the public key of the developer
in a protected memory that can be
tampered with like a trusted platform
module
and then once the device receives the
signed update package it can validate
the authenticity and integrity of the
package and then proceed with the update
this will ensure that
the
communication channels and the data
storage are encrypted
so
the next piece uh so so now
now we have a device
that is set up to be able to verify
authenticity integrity
we have this root of trust in this chain
of trust
and we're changing that trust all the
way across the
the communication pathways
so
now what we want to do is we want to
take the humans out of the loop and we
want to take the variability out of the
loop
this makes it then much more
simple to protect
from the standpoint of
we're going to log everything that we
can
and we're going to be able to make sure
that
nothing unusual is going on and we're
not going to have humans coming in and
doing the unusual things um
and this this requires us to kind of
zoom in just a little bit
because the thing about building
firmware
is that sometimes we need a chip
specific
toolbox
sometimes we need a specific kind of
compiler
sometimes we might need
something that the vendor
the chip vendor has helped create
in order to encode things properly or to
take advantage of some kind of
architectural features
and so
unfortunately with a lot of these
firmware builds
we're not just going to be able to take
some kind of pipeline off the shelf
and apply it
but
but there is value to doing this
automation because we're taking humans
out and we're taking out a lot of the
variability and so the first piece has
to do with how we build this uh this
build container
so
in this pipeline we can have uh
some kind of a merge to master
a
kick off some kind of automation process
and what we want to do is to make sure
that
this build environment is not going to
be persistent
we also want to make sure it's going to
be built on a stack that is uh
going to be
up to date at the very beginning so
we're not going to necessarily want to
create one image now
and then use it six months from now and
then use it ten months from now we're
going to want to maybe go and get
ubuntu
the latest version that's still
supported with the most vulnerabilities
patched
we might go and get something like
segger and um
have it set up to
have the correct toolbox for whatever
the
chip vendor and the
special tools that we might
want
and it's now only going to be temporary
while we're building
signing
packaging
and then pushing this package and then
it's going to be
blown away everything except the logs
so the second thing that we want to
think about is that if we're going to do
it this way
we're going to need credentials to push
and pull
the information that we need we want to
make sure those credentials are not
going to be stored
in the pipeline automation script and
we're that they're not going to be
stored
in the container that gets built
and so this means we are typically going
to need some kind of a separate secrets
manager
there are some secrets managers that are
available through cloud vendors and
there are some ways that these can be
built in in a separate way for
common pipelines like like uh
bitbucket and things like that
um the key is that we want to make sure
that these are in separate places so
that they're called for
when they're needed
they're utilized in a way that is not
logged right so that the transfer of
these we want to make sure we're not
echoing printing cutting whatever
these these credentials uh if we're
you're doing that during debugging
we need to make sure we remove all that
and then what happens is we're able to
now
uh separate out this so we have a
container that's temporary
that's uh standing up doing the
compilation and and so forth um and then
we have these credentials that are
separate
the next thing is we gotta think about
how we're gonna protect that private key
remember that's the
that's the most important piece um for
our entire device security
um
and so
the rule of thumb is that ideally
wherever we generate the private key it
never moves
and ideally wherever we generate the
private key has layers of protection in
place
to
keep that private key safe
but that also might mean that we need to
have a little agility in how we actually
do the signing of the firmware
so
for a medium assurance process
it's possible that you might even grab
that key temporarily just use it and
then make sure that you can have a
deletion process
but for anything that's uh critical
you need to make sure that you're
adjusting that process so that for
example
you can
generate a hash of the firmware send the
hash over to the key management device
have the hash signed
return that signature and be able to
append it to the firmware in a way that
the bootloader verification algorithm is
going to recognize it
so as we move further over
one of the things that we talked about
and this becomes important for
automation
is that we don't want to put everything
on this device
sometimes these devices are going to be
remote sometimes they're going to have
very little bandwidth sometimes they're
going to have
they're going to result in operating on
a battery
um
and
so to the extent possible we want to
think of where the best places to do
this verification is um typically
in a secure boot uh
architecture
you load this new firmware into a queue
and and then it's not verified until the
next time that you boot up and that time
that way you don't need multiple
verification
programs in memory and if the bootloader
doesn't verify the firmware it just
loads the common firmware and clears the
queue
if it passes the verification it loads
that new firmware um and uh
and eliminates the existing
firmware clearing up that memory space
um
but somewhere along the lines we want to
make sure that we're not putting
everything on that bootloader so that it
doesn't necessarily have to get all the
way down the line
and potentially hogging bandwidth and uh
and using up uh using up more power than
we really want
and so that's in some cases this might
be done on the gateway in some cases
there might be a
shadow
configuration that's on a cloud service
and
where it's doing some verification
before it even replaces that
kind of shadow configuration which is
what helps say to the
the gateway and the device that it's
ready for an update
um the final thing is that on september
22nd uh
department of homeland security
uh dhs cesa
um they published these industrial
control system performance objectives
and one of these objectives was this
thing called crypto agility the idea is
that at some point in the future you
might want to swap out the algorithm
that you use you might want to swap out
the keys that you use
and so
this now
as we're running through this pipeline
as we're running through this process of
trying to automate this pipeline
that
starts to
bring to surface a couple
of features that we might want to start
thinking about
the first is do we want to be able to
swap out the keys
if we want to swap out the keys remember
that that means we might have to modify
the bootloa well we will have to modify
the bootloader right because the
bootloader contains that public key for
verification
um
and uh and that's the case if that's the
case we need to make sure that our
processes are set up for
being able to do that bootloader update
and not just the firmware update
and
the other thing is that
there's this question of whether we're
going to at some future date want to
swap out the algorithm
and we don't have a lot of experience
with swapping out algorithms
we have a hard enough time getting
everything to work just right
with the way that it is
but that is something that we should
probably start putting in our mind is
how much agility do we want to give
um
to our devices uh in the future
um and do we want to be able to
uh
to have uh some some level of crypto
agility
um the last thing i'll mention about
that crypto agility is that typically on
the cloud photo server
is going to be some kind of
configuration file
and we're going to want to make sure
that we understand the compatibility
right if we change the boot loader
because we're swapping out this uh
public key
uh
and then we're gonna start signing
firmware with a new key we need to make
sure that there's a compatibility uh
chain
um so that if there's an update that has
to happen
that uh the new firmware is being loaded
on the correct bootloader
because after our installed base is tens
of thousands
we don't want to necessarily have to
keep this in an excel spreadsheet
and so we're going to want to put that
in this configuration file and we're
going to want to test against
these compatibilities when we're doing
that testing on the development side
before we do the merge to master with it
which then basically kicks the humans
out
out of the loop
and the last thing just to emphasize
because it fits into the next piece is
that we're gonna be logging all of this
stuff
um and because the human's not in the
loop and because it's automated we know
what we should be seeing we know what
should be happening
and so so this is this is the third
piece is uh
taking the human out and automating this
uh firmware pipeline
finally the last piece covers all the
rest of the security measures that of
the strike threats
like role-based access control for the
build and sign process
access should be restricted to only
those people that need it
and even to those people there should be
granular access control read only versus
read write something like that
and then the firmware update must be
compiled and tested properly
merging a code branch into the master
branch must include two or more people
in the approval process
to make sure that there are additional
eyes on the testing verification process
where there is an admin operation or a
super user privileged operation
there must be multi-factor
authentication
to make sure that there is a reduced
risk from shared credentials or weak
credentials
all the photo operations must be locked
again like we talked about earlier
all these must be locked so that
given the logs one can easily
piece together what happened who did
that and when and why and
what the status of that operation is
but we should remember not to have any
sensitive information in the box like
like the passwords right
on the device side there must be
verifications
to check the versions of the update
so that um any incorrect firmware update
won't corrupt the device or bring the
device
and so by having this process we can
automate this so that
as new firmware packages are added as
new versions are added as the keys are
rotated
there won't be any downtime or any risk
of security threats and
by implementing all these security
measures we can have
a fully automated build pipeline for
firmware updates
that go from the firmware vendor to the
cloud and then get pushed to the devices
looks like this
so so we've talked about four
big topics
um
and uh just to kind of recap right first
we talked about how important connected
digital systems are
because they are the things that are
going to generate value
and help the water sector become
increasingly lean
the second thing is that we did talk
about how there's these emerging threats
um and that this is creating new
exposures
we went through this threat modeling
process that generated
dozens of attack
attack vectors
with
multiple dozens of controls
and then what we tried to do is
synthesize it into these four main
pieces the first one is the device
you've got to have root of trust and a
chain of trust
everything needs to be signed
with uh with private keys that you
protect
uh somewhere outside of the device
um
and that will help to maintain the
authenticity and integrity of everything
and then you have a chained up to that
that
update process
the next thing is protecting from source
to destination right these communication
channels
the third thing is automating this
protecting it from people
making sure that we know exactly what's
supposed to happen how it's going to
happen
taking the humans out of it and then
logging everything and finally we need
to make sure that each
piece of this process
is hardened
and uh that privileges are separated
that there's multi-factor authentication
right that that everything uh can be
hardened at each aspect of this
um and this is how
over-the-air firmware updates happen
and this enables us to have this agile
uh
infrastructure that now we can continue
to deliver additional features
um and modify things in a much less
expensive way
but in a way that then results in this
kind of shared responsibility
um
and that's where we kind of want to end
traditionally so we've viewed cyber
security kind of within these four
buckets secure the product on the left
hand side secure the deployment right
the architecture of the actual
operations network that's on the
right-hand side commission it's secure
secure then monitor the security and the
health of the system right install
patches updates maintain it
and then at the very top monitor for
incidents and respond to them
appropriately
typically the product maker has only had
to exist over on the left hand side make
secure products
worry about let the integrator worry
about secure deployment let the operator
worry about health and monitoring and
response
but what's starting to happen is with
iiot
the product owner is now having to take
care of a lot more of this
and this is an important piece if we
want to have this digital transformation
work
we as product owners and vendors
we need to make sure that we're doing
our part so in this case we're now
securing the product
we're establishing an architecture for
secure over-the-air firmware update
deployment we're making sure that we
test and validate each of the controls
across that entire architecture
we're then monitoring the firmware
transit we're monitoring the firmware
update process
and we're keeping our uh and that and we
we we have our uh you know product
security operation center our psoc
for doing that and then we're monitoring
our product our product health the
vulnerabilities in our product we're
making sure that we can respond and send
these updates quickly
and we're participating with our
customers when they have an incident
response when they have an incident that
involves one of our products
and
that takes
that's what we use our pcert for our
product security incident response team
and so we're now starting to have to
share that responsibility of this
security diamond
with the the the customers or the
operators
and i think that is
the direction that things are heading
and i think that that uh that shared
responsibility will become a good thing
and help us to solve uh solve these
problems
that we have in water with secure
connected digital infrastructure
so
we're available to take questions we'll
be online i know this is a recorded uh
this is a recorded session but we're
available to take questions
or you can contact us
through our email addresses that are
listed there we'd happy to collaborate
and do anything that we can to help
promote this idea of
secure digital infrastructure
we would be really interested in your
comments
part of the reason why we put this
presentation together was to
i mean i know it didn't go into every
technical detail of actual
implementation
but we would be interested in
anything that we're missing anything
that we haven't thought of
and uh or collaborating with anyone
who's also trying to think through this
process
with that we
thank you for your attention and glad
that we could be part of this texas
cyber summit
thank you
you