hello there and welcome to the stop cat
fishing how threat actors really see you
presentation
my name is ken underhill i'll be your
presenter for this session
many people in the industry probably
know me if you don't i've basically
helped a lot of people and i've won some
awards
i started my career in healthcare i t so
i actually worked as a clinician i
worked as a pediatric nurse for a number
of years
moved back into the i.t realm i was in
it many many years before i was a nurse
and came back into it worked in network
engineering network security around that
moved more into the cyber security or
quote unquote cyber security type of
roles it wasn't called that back then
but uh from there i've worked a variety
of roles worked as a pen tester and
other things i'm currently a an
executive for a startup
as well as running multiple companies
myself i also have a tv show and that's
what you see depicted in the top right
there and like i said i've won multiple
awards i'm up for some others et cetera
et cetera
that's enough about me long story short
helped a lot of people and that's what
really matters
so what is the problem we're going to be
talking about today well
we've got this issue out there and if
you haven't experienced this yet you are
very very lucky as an organization but
what a lot of places are finding is that
their cyber security premiums are going
up and they're literally going up in
many cases overnight
and we're seeing man it's crazy we're
seeing like a 5x 10x increase especially
for like your small medium-sized
businesses and so for a lot of them that
type of increase that that puts them out
of business they can't afford that
insurance
and why is it happening well
one of the main reasons is all these
supply chain attacks so
insurance companies just like with your
car insurance or anything else
they focus on risk
and traditionally
cyber's been kind of ignored as far as a
risk standpoint and saying well okay
there might be a breach or something
like that no big deal so rates have you
know pretty been pretty straight
stagnant over the years
for the most part
but
with all these more public
attacks insurance companies are saying
whoa wait a minute here what's going on
is this company affected well that's a
big risk so even though you as an
organization
haven't been targeted well you
realistically have and you and you
realistically have been hacked as well
but
even though you're not in the news
of saying hey company x has got a data
breach
you're still a risk because
other companies in your industry have
been hit
or just the fact that there's all these
supply and chain attacks out there going
on and it's a risk now for these
insurers so again just like your car
insurance if you get in a bunch of
accidents if you drink and drive
anything like that or even if you're a
male versus a female when you're younger
there's a bigger risk that you may be
involved in an accident
where the insurance company has to pay
money and so because of that risk your
premiums are a little higher so we're
seeing that same effect here in cyber
lately especially for the small to
mid-sized organizations and
unfortunately a lot of them
can't afford that now the other side of
this
is
because
the insurance rates go up
the companies a lot of times are just
canceling saying well we can't afford
that
not able to do that
and then what they're realizing is oh
wait our contracts
require us
to have that
and so now they're in violation of their
contracts with their clients
and there's
a good push from a lot of financial
institutions right now
that are basically saying in their
contracts look if you don't have the
insurance if you don't meet the
if you don't also meet the minimum
security standards that we require as a
financial institution to be able to work
with us and be a third-party contractor
of us then guess what you're not getting
paid until that happens
and we're seeing more of that as well
right there can the
different organizations are controlling
in the contracts where you have to have
the insurance you have to do some
minimum security standards
which are really just best practices
right so that's kind of the main problem
there is that rates are going up
companies can't afford the new rates
what do you do that's what we're going
to talk about today
but before we do that let's talk about
the root cause of all this so why are
the rates going up we talked a little
bit about the risk factor there right so
really
what are the insurance companies looking
at
because they're not there every day with
you they're not sitting next to you your
team at on the computer they're not
sitting with the accounting team and
seeing what's happening there they're
not sitting with your security team and
seeing what's happening there so what
are they actually looking at well
they're looking at things like the
security posturing right and they're
looking at the external view that's what
they're getting a look at with things
like security scoring
i want to share a story with you
and
way way back in the day in my younger
years i had a different life right and i
was a medic in the military and i
volunteered at a boy scout camp with you
know variety of age ranges i think the
youngest was like six or seven whatever
the youngest in boy scouts is up until
teenage years and
one of the things i found is working
volunteering as a medic at that camp
was
the first couple of days the kids were
out there and they would be out there
for about a week and so the first couple
of days would be out there
all sorts of issues right especially
like on day one and day two like oh my
oh i got the stomach virus oh the pain
oh my arm hurts i've got this headache
that just don't won't go away et cetera
et cetera
and what i learned
is
that was just related to the fact they
were
homesick and once i realized that right
once i realized root cause i was able to
find a solution which in this case
was lemon drops and that's why you see
the lemon drops pictured there so what i
would do is every time a kid came oh my
stomach or my arm or something like that
and i would assess them of course and
say okay the vital signs are good and i
don't see anything wrong with their arm
and so i would be able to determine that
okay the actual cause here is just the
fact they're homesick they miss mom or
dad or both or or their friends or
whatever and so i would pull out my
magic pills is what i would call them i
said oh these are the these are the
magic pills and the magic pills
would help take away any pain you have
uh but you had to take one a day
don't double them up you might get sick
if you if you double them up you might
get sick even sicker just take one a day
and come back in a couple of days let me
know how you're doing and you know we'll
go from there if we need to send you the
hospital or something we'll do so then
now
when i started this at that camp
a few of the kids actually
they didn't realize these were lemon
drops so they were like oh this medicine
tastes great this is the greatest
medicine ever you know uh the problem
though is that the the kids would be
there a week and they were recycled
through and new kids would come but a
lot of the kids knew each other because
it was boy scouts right so
the next week kids started knowing that
the lemon that these were actually you
know just lemon drops and so
it still worked though the kids
understood that what i was trying to do
a lot of them did at the end there of
hey it's not a big deal right yes you're
away from home
but
this candy makes you feel better and
for those of us that eat candy we know
candy makes you feel better for the most
part on everything so
long story short there figured out the
root cause find a solution in this case
a delicious solution
but you can't always find the delicious
solution in the cyber world
so how are we doing things now well
guess what this is the magical
compliance checkbox and this is really
how the vast majority of organizations
are doing things because
board members are saying hey what are we
doing for compliance insurers are saying
what are you doing for compliance
your third parties and the your clients
are saying what are you doing for
compliance check the box check the box
check the box and that's what we're
doing
great at least we're doing something
right but
here's the downside of that let's go to
the threat actors
hey i'm a threat actor i know that your
company is just checking the compliance
box well guess what i know exactly how
to attack you now because i know exactly
what you're doing
and yes you might be doing a few things
outside of that but realistically i'm
going to get it in
so that's how we're doing it now let's
change that and this isn't focused on
you as you're in your organization you
might be doing awesome things but this
is a broad statement here that let's be
realistic a lot of companies are just
checking a box
so we're going to briefly talk about a
couple of case studies near the end of
this presentation and really just
talking about some of the things we
should be looking for so bank of ken
which by the way gives awesome loan
rates you can find the loan rates on the
dark web so just go search around there
you'll find that and click every link in
there and then meow hospital because
many people that know me
know i love cats and they love cats too
so i had to throw a cat picture in here
so meow hospital you can also go there
as well i have heard that
their
the the entrance to the hospital is
covered in litter so just fyi on that
so when we talk about the insurance
companies and we're going to focus this
a blended approach on this presentation
of insurance companies and the threat
actors so when we talk about insurance
companies what are they looking at right
they're looking at your security scoring
and there's a number of places that do
this security scorecard is one and
that's one that i i actually use and you
can sign up for a free account over
there and just get like a simple report
and monitor on
your organization you don't get like the
deep dive i don't think with a free
account but you can at least get some
insight into what your company's scoring
is right now or a company that you're
interested in
i will say that you basically it's one
email address to one account so if you
want to have multiple accounts this is a
workaround you could technically i'm not
telling you to do anything you could
technically create a few email addresses
and technically sign all of them up and
technically monitor different companies
so just fyi on that
again not telling you to do that but
that is a possible workaround that you
may try
so they look at security scoring and as
part of that again that's an external
view right so they're looking at things
like your third parties are there any
attacks going on with them so for
example if you were contracted with
solar winds and they're getting hit are
you at risk then does your risk go up
because of the third party contractual
agreements they're looking for external
vulnerabilities it might be things
you've already patched right and we'll
talk about what you need to do in that
case a little later also any any uh
hacker chatter and i put criminal hacker
here because hackers as we all know
there's a big
misperception in the media and stuff so
i don't like to jump on board that train
so criminal hacker here but that really
covers any nation state all that stuff
as well with that the word criminal that
i'm using there
so these are some of the things you're
looking at again the big thing to take
away here is the external view is really
what they're looking at
so what can you do
well know your security score i mean you
got to start someplace right you have to
know what they're seeing on their end
and then you can determine what you can
actually do about it
you also need to identify the pathways
to critical assets critical data your
critical services
because that's what the attackers are
going after they're not going to get
jimmy's excel spreadsheet on his desktop
unless that's something critical right
otherwise they could really care less
about that it's not a good use of their
time most attacks are usually
financially motivated or intelligence
gathering from nation state or state
sponsored groups
you also need to identify security
controls right so once you identify the
pathways to those critical
assets you also need to identify what
controls do we have in place right now
and what are we missing
right
and once we identify that then it's a we
have to go through a process of okay
we're missing these controls now what
can we put in place
and we have to basically do a trade-off
right we have to say okay yes this would
be the absolute best possible control we
could put in place but
man that thing's really expensive
or it takes a lot of
human resources to implement or it takes
a lot of time to roll out and we need
something quicker so there's always a
trade-off when you're assessing
different controls it could be a
financial cost could be just a resource
cost
could be the the ongoing cost right
maybe it's pretty easy to set it up and
get it going but maybe it's a long term
cost right maybe it's very expensive to
keep maintaining
that particular control in place maybe
it's very resource intensive to keep
maintaining that control as well so
there's always a trade off there that
you have to go through when you're
thinking through different security
controls the other thing there is
how can you maximize control right how
can you maximize security controls what
do i mean well once you have identified
the pathways where
where's a good spot in that pathway
right where where maybe it branches off
so thinking about for example like your
active directory infrastructure
where
does do things branch off you know from
your forest where you know where the
force is connected where do things
branch off and can you put a control in
place there
so it has maximum impact right so if i
put a so think of it like a a city with
roads right and so i've got all these
roads but there's only one way in and
out of the city it's across this bridge
so i could if i was trying to catch a
bank robber i could try to put a police
officer on every single street and try
to catch a bank robber that way
and you know assuming again that i know
the bank robbers
leaving trying to flee town or i could
just block off the bridge
right and that's maximum use of my
controls and i maybe i only need a
couple of officers to do that so that
way not all the officers are taking up
stopping the bank robber so that's what
i'm talking about there is once you've
identified the pathway and where the
threat actor may go
then figure out the maximum bang for
your buck so to speak on security
controls and implement those right and
again that's that's going to depend on
your organization and what you have set
up so that's something you actually need
to take away from this presentation as
an after action item to make sure that
you sit down with your team and you
start kind of plotting this out right
identify pathways to the critical assets
data services etc
then also from there identify what
controls you have in place to protect
those right now
and what you're missing and then from
there you can go through the activity of
prioritizing and doing the trade-off
analysis of those security controls
once you've identified all that stuff
and gotten all this stuff in place now
it's time to sell yourself and i don't
mean like go sell yourself
you're going to sell yourself your
company your security posture basically
to the insurance companies and say hey
wait a minute here yes this is a score
you're given trying to give us this rate
but
this is what we've done right this is
what we've we're this is what we've
recognized right
these are the things we're doing well
these are the things we're going to do
in the next 30 days 60 days 90 days six
months you know year 18 months whatever
you basically want to give them a
roadmap right show them like okay we're
doing this stuff now
we're patching these servers now for
example and we're going to patch that
web server that was showing some
vulnerabilities and then on top of that
30 days from now we're going to do this
or six months from now we're going to be
doing this and we're also doing this you
know 12 months down the line 18 months
down the line whatever you want to show
that roadmap because that allows them to
reduce the risk right just like if i had
a car
and i had a really bad insurance rate
quoted to me and i said but wait a
minute i have 12 letters of
recommendation
from
people i know that say i'm the best
driver ever i have video evidence
showing i'm the best driver ever and
what i'm going to do immediately is do
these things and and you know make sure
my hands are 10 and 2 and all these
things
and then from there in six months i'm
going to make sure that i've gone
through some additional training on
driving safely et cetera and then maybe
in the year in the year time frame i'm
gonna
get my
license to be able to drive semi trucks
so i've got additional training on
driving and safety and things like that
you're right so i'm just giving a road
map to the insurance company now i don't
know if that's going to work with the
car insurance you can try it let me know
but for these purposes
that's what we're trying to do for the
cyber security insurers
and as part of this process there's a
secondary benefit right of
being able to stop a lot of the threat
actors because now you're improving
security posture so you've identified
the pathways to your critical assets
you've identified how the threat actors
are likely going to go down those
pathways to get stuff and you've
identified controls you can put in place
well guess what you just stopped a lot
of the attacks that were going to be
happening on your company as long as you
actually implement things that you've
identified
so it's there's a secondary benefit here
in addition to what you know the board
and executive team would care about of
in reducing those insurance rates in the
financials the secondary benefit here to
the organization itself
is
now we have an improved security posture
we have a roadmap of things we need to
be doing and we can actually go execute
on that roadmap moving forward and that
will reduce our risk overall of threat
actors
getting in right we're just you know
again we're not going to keep anyone out
completely if someone wants to get in
they're going to get in but if we make
it more difficult with company a then
they're going to go over to company b
and bother them right and that's a whole
goal here
it's very similar to
you live next year well you obviously
live next door to your neighbor but
you let's say you have a fence you have
you know a couple of really big dogs you
have a security system alarm system you
you have a bunch of guns you have
cameras whatever right you have all
these things you have barbed wire all
these things and your neighbor has none
of that stuff right
if i'm a
person that likes to break into houses
whose house am i going to break into
well i'm going to go to your neighbor
right because that's easier that's path
of least resistance and that's most
threat actors want the passive path of
least resistance out there because a lot
of the these attacks are financially
motivated
so let's just talk quickly about the
bank of can and then meow hospital and
some of the things you should be looking
for so if you are a a bank or financial
institution
some of the things you should be just
kind of thinking about that might be
possible uh parts of your pathway right
so bank of can and this is just kind of
a real real life example that's based
off uh real real events just like a
movie but i i'm gonna change like ever
just about everything aside from the
fact international locations just so i
don't give any indicators away of
actually who this was but i worked with
a financial institution and it wasn't
actually a bank but financial
institution
that offered a software solution to
banks and other financial clients of
theirs
uh basically a cloud-based solution and
so that was one risk area significant
risk area that was getting flagged uh
international locations so they were in
an international and had actual physical
offices around the world and dealt in
different areas around the world
they stored a lot of sense of data in
public cloud environments which actually
is scary if you kind of think about that
and it was not secured properly so just
some of the things they had to keep in
mind when they went through the pathway
and security control activities
but
here's what happened with them initially
their insurance rates went through the
roof and after going through the the
process that i shared with you
previously
they were able to reduce the quotes and
everything and and uh you know working
through
identifying or at least last i knew
working through identifying the best
policy for them right but their rates
went down because they were able to show
that their security posture had improved
to the insurers and that was a critical
part on top of that they were able to as
part of the activity actually identify
some vulnerabilities they didn't know
about they had some say they had some
web servers out there they didn't
actually know about and so they were
able to secure their improvement improve
their security posture overall
and then meow hospital and this is also
based on on real life events so mia
hospital
uh was actually a healthcare
organization that was hit with
ransomware
so when
we see a lot about okay patient records
system systems are locked out they can't
treat patients they can't get the data
whatever that's one facet of these
healthcare attacks but there are many
other aspects that probably don't make
the news so much right so obviously we
know the emr ehr systems and that's
electronic medical record systems or
electronic healthcare
electronic health record systems so emrs
you usually see in like doctors offices
and smaller organizations usually
hospitals use ehr and really a lot of i
mean these days things are just kind of
blended right you're just it's patient
record system essentially there's some
different features on both which we
won't dive into
patient data is one aspect that a lot of
people think about like okay all the
patient data the doctor can't see what
happened with your blood pressure last
week but
what about the employee data in these
events right it doesn't mean that the
data for employees is not going to be
compromised and in fact with the
ransomware attack i mentioned the
employee data was compromised as well
right they literally got like everything
and this was an organization still
running like some windows 2000 windows
95 stuff yeah i know that's scary right
and so naturally of course they were
an easy target
and the other thing here medical devices
so not just like pacemakers
defibrillators i've actually
uh with testing many years ago when i
worked as a pen tester in healthcare i
actually turned off a defibrillator
remotely and this is back when they were
just starting to do the remote
monitoring of pacemakers and
defibrillators nowadays it's commonplace
but
i showed how you how i could turn off
the defibrillator feature
where it would just be a pacemaker and
show the vendor that and so the vendor
went back and uh fortunately for them
and kudos to them for fixing the issue
in the code but medical devices and not
just pacemakers defibrillators but
infusion pumps
your x-ray equipment all sorts of
equipment in the hospital
if you've ever gone to the even the
dentist office there's just so many
things to play with there's just so many
things that you can attack it's just
crazy
the number of devices you can attack and
most of them are extremely vulnerable so
when we when you're healthcare
organization you really need to consider
what are all the entry points here not
just what's the typical entry point of
you know susan in accounting clicks a
link in an email but how else some might
somebody attack and what's the actual
impact financially as well as the human
life
because if you turn off a defibrillator
on someone and they need that shock to
take them out of ventricular
fibrillation which is basically just
where your heart's like
you know all day long type of thing
and it's very dangerous and that's in
the lower chambers of your heart
but if it's if it's fibrillating like
that and you don't have a defibrillator
to shock you back into a normal rhythm
for your heart the person can literally
die
they literally in some cases may dr
essentially drown
their heart may drown in in blood
and so
these are real things these are real
things that can happen and these have
been vulnerabilities around for years so
that's another consideration and the
last one here that people seem to forget
about is communication
so what happens when someone attacks
communication of the hospital so code
blue is a code called when
it's a life and death situation in the
hospital and so somebody may be going
into cardiac arrest or
or it may be suspected that they are or
something
and so that basically calls a special
team in most hospitals where they come
running doctors nurses etc as well as
the local
team and by local i mean i just mean on
the unit itself so there's a number of
people that come running to save the day
but what happens if they can't ever get
that call and you're laying in the
hospital bed or your grandma is or your
your other loved one and
you can't they're calling cold blue on
the floor but that communication is not
going anywhere no one's able to hear
that guess what grandma dies that's
unfortunate but that's reality so the
communication is one other thing on
hospitals that a lot of people forget
about but that's a key one as well what
happens when people shut that down so
all considerations you need to think
about and these are just a couple of
different use cases there
now that particular healthcare
organization that this use case is based
on
uh they they wasn't around cyber
insurance or anything but it was around
the throat actor angle and so they were
able to actually improve their security
posture over time
and
mitigate a lot of future attacks because
they had they really got they really got
pwned they really really got prone with
that organization
so i just want to open it up now to any
questions throw those in the chat so
kind of a brief presentation here but
the main takeaways here are
go look at your security scoring if you
if you don't have that already just
again security score card is just one
but that's the one i like to use
personally
go there sign up for a free account you
can usually get a free account just pull
up your company
it usually free account won't let you
deep dive it'll just show you the the
very ten thousand foot level but take a
look at that identify kind of the major
areas and say okay let's go let's either
number one pay for a security score card
or another service and and see the
deeper dive or let's just take this
information on these top level things
go back to the drawing board and start
working through the process of
identifying what are our critical assets
critical data services etc
in these areas
and then on top of that what are the
pathways to those
how might a threat actor go go through
those who are the threat actors
targeting us usually based on our our
type of industry and where we are
geographically in the world and then
what controls do we have in place right
now to protect against attack
and then finally
with that part
what controls will be missing and then
you need to do that trade-off analysis
this is not a hour-long process by the
way this is something you need to take
back it's going to take you probably a
couple weeks at least as an organization
to to go through as a team and get work
through these things
but these are the things that you need
to be doing and then once you've
determined that stuff then you can work
on
with insurers if you're trying to reduce
your rate or whatever you can work on
positioning yourself better and saying
okay this is kind of our roadmap of what
we're going to do and even if you're not
trying to improve your insurance rates
let's say your rate stayed the same
you've been fortunate that's cool this
process though will help you improve
your security posture overall and so
you'll be able to finally have a road
map essentially to go take these to the
executive team and that also helps you
with budget right we all scream about i
need more budget i need cyber security
budget we don't get enough budget blah
blah blah well that's great how are you
positioning that to executives right
they only care about the the numbers
right honestly i'm an executive i'm
telling you i only care about the
numbers
and so you need to communicate that and
this is an easy way for you to do that
if you're a more technical person
more practical more practitioner type of
person and less political business type
of person then this is a great way to
show
exactly what you need to be doing and
the cost of everything and the cost
financially resource-wise etc
and you just present that information
to the the stakeholders the leadership
and say hey this is this is kind of the
plan
and we need your input and if you want
to do some of these things you need to
give us more money right you need to
give us some more money i need more
money pay me right
so it allows you to go get more budget
and everything as well so there's a lot
of benefits to doing this process
and you need to do it right because
again as we talked about
in the beginning
most organizations are checking the box
don't be like them
if you're just checking a box right now
then go through this process
again
this can benefit you multiple ways it
can help secure your organization a
little bit better it can help improve
insurance rates and reduce rates on that
it can also help you land contracts
because if other businesses are seeing
that you're
doing the things you need to be doing
and your competitor isn't
i've actually won contracts before
because of that and even though my rate
was higher i won the contract because
they noticed that the competitor wasn't
doing what they need they should be
doing so all this stuff can benefit your
organization this is part of pivoting
the mindset out there that security is
just a cost-centered focus
we're trying to pivot the mindset here
to where it's a financial benefit for
the organization to improve that
security posture
so again if there's any questions at all
throw them in the chat real quick here
and we'll get them answered for you
thanks everyone for coming out today
hope you've been enjoying the conference
love this conference i wasn't able to
make it in person this year but
absolutely love this conference it's a
great one so be sure to come back next
year if you're attending virtual this
year then by all means do your best next
year to come in person to the conference
you'll meet some really really awesome
people
at the texas cyber summit