thanks for the introduction my name is
Aaron dubrovsky I'm a PhD student at the
technical university in Vienna and
researcher at SB research in Vienna so
for this talk I'm gonna simplify like
take file format data formats protocols
treat them all as a language they are
describing the data and the file is a
transmission as a data stream is one or
more packets conceptually from the
length sock point of view they're quite
the same and when we look at the typical
input path we have some machine that
takes the data interprets it decodes
posits does some computation and output
something that we like to see maybe it's
a spreadsheet maybe it's a picture
basically depending on on the data that
it was fed with in the worst case from
the length sack perspective this machine
is Turing complete this is all just a
part of the picture then usually these
machines are nested concatenated or
stacked in some way for example you
could have like a very simple machine
that is a synchronizer in front that
detects where the data starts and then
you have some error correction or
decompression and then the final machine
that reads your data and does something
so the different possibilities why we
nest or layer the data and these
machines and in some cases we have
another simple machine in front of it
that is in dissector which classifies
the data format and usually do returns
one power for one option how to read
this data this is very common sense
usually we'd like to have
the nice thing about standards is that
there are so many to choose from so we
have like the picture program has to be
able to read multiple picture formats
and so we typically end up with an even
more complex machine or array of
machines so let's talk about that the
dissector a little bit more we can play
tricks with the dissector by building
binary polyglots there is this
tremendous work from albertini that user
uses different file formats like PDF zip
and g pack and stuff them so together
that they are actually valid for all
free file formats about and yeah and you
can open it with different programs and
it shows two different content this has
already security implications the famous
ambiguity is in security paradigm
imagine an antivirus firewall that does
not know how to treat this violent with
my treatise file as one type scan for
malicious content but the user that
opens the file treated as another file
so let's picture this a little bit we
have our piece of data and we carefully
interleave these different file formats
together maybe even reusing some of the
bytes for both and some bytes are only
for one or the other file format the
other thing I mentioned briefly before
one of these machines could be an error
correction correcting machine so an
error correcting machine is something
that is heavily used for example in data
transmission or in storage for example
digital radio broadcasts of different
kinds radio and video and telephone
networks with GSM UMTS tetra whatever
you named Orion with storage on hard
disks on in rates in cloud computing and
also with barcodes as kind of in between
between transmission and storage so
forward error correction is basically a
technique that cope with arrows on an
unreliable channel without having a
return channel and it uses some kind of
redundant encoding there are different
types of these error correction
techniques very simple like parity and
hamming codes or complex one with like
read Salamone or trouble codes for this
talk we can treat them like a black box
they just correct our data within a
certain margin error margin that usually
can be configured so it transforms then
data into code words and vice versa as
long as this error margin is not
overstressed we can or the transmission
channel or the arrows can override parts
of the data usually almost everything
except maybe for the ECC header itself
and a synchronization signal in front so
basically we can now stick both things
together and make include a foreign or
alien data into this data packet or file
or transmission because the error
correction will transparently for the
one data stream will transport Lee
abstract the foreign data way on the
other hand the foreign tater is still in
this packet the difference to
say the packet in packet attack from
from Travis good speed at all is that in
this case we do not modify the user data
the user data after the error correction
remains the same we just included
another packet inside of it and both
packets are actually correct it's also
not like a hidden data channel because
we can actually put in very valid data
in there that is then correctly picked
up by some decoder by some standard
compliant decoder we can sometimes we
also include these packets includes a
kind of byte sequence header or magic
value or mark or synchronization pattern
and even that one we can include inside
of this alien data in yeah so these as I
told before this is used in several
transmission techniques like radio and
story or in storage and it's also used
in barcodes so we put up a simple
example based on barcodes so you can
build up sorry so you can take one
barcode and in a bit embed another bar
code into it and both are actually
standard compliant and it's based on the
implementation of the reader which one
it will decode so the the nice thing
about barcodes again is there are so
many to choose from we can stuff
different barcode types into another or
we can stuff the same power code type
into it this is just a quick overview
about different but 2d barcode types we
focused in in our experiments on the
barcodes with square pixels so we picked
up QR data matrix and at stake code
and tested it with certain decoders the
most popular Multi multi standard
barcode readers for iphone and android
and a professional symbol barcode reader
that is used like in point-of-sale
installations so just a quick few
examples like in this one we stuffed an
extra key code into a bigger QR code and
you can see some decode the inner power
code sum decode the outer barcode
sometimes it's indifferent and the
decode one or another based on pure
chance we did this with data matrix as
well you can see that for example neo
reader only prefers the inner barcode in
this case the data matrix barcode other
ones are either decoding the inner or
the outer one with this example of QR in
QR we can see that for example the
symbol reader strongly prefers the inner
one while most other readers decode the
outer run or sometimes to come none but
it's highly implementation-specific and
the implementation basically is as
follows we have one very computational
lightweight machine that tries to find
synchronization markers in the picture
and determine which kind of bar code the
user scanning and then we have a
computational more complex code that
then decodes the data and once choosing
a path then the the decoder runs down
and just returns one of these codes so
yeah and while the standard for a
particular power code
while they exist there is no standard in
in a sequence how to dissect different
bar codes so is it just harmless fun or
are there some practical implications of
it so with QR codes we know there have
been several vulnerabilities like these
ussd codes that can wipe your phone into
effect and make a factory reset they can
generate premium rate SMS messages or
they can trigger exploits in the web
browser and with the knowledge that some
readers and some phones or some decoders
a prefer one coat or another I can
actually distinguish between different
platforms and readers and then tailor
exploits for specific users or maybe do
or just probabilistic exploits like
divert a small number of users to
transfer money to a different location
since QR codes are also used like why
people and Bitcoin so for their for the
bar code domain we can think of
different countermeasures like and
string and decoding order or presenting
the user with different options as soon
as the reader software finds more than
one code but this would include the
reading software actually tries to
decode all possible codes regardless
which one it found first however for the
generic case when we go back to the more
generic transmission example from before
it's kind of hard to spot multiple
synchronization markers in an
asynchronous data channel and verify
that their belonging to non overlapping
overlapping data packets and this might
also to clue
include decoding and verifying all
possible interpretations of the received
data so one so application-specific the
decoder could either drop the other the
data or it can escalate it up towards
the user and let the user choose you
could probably think also of other
heuristics like choosing the data stream
that has the highest data density but in
either way it's a kind of guessing and
ambiguities in security so to wrap
things up the main conceptual problem
with countermeasures in this area is
that ECC's are error correcting codes
are designed to transmit Lee hide any
modifications from the process sing
layers above and as the host data data
as well as the parasitic data are
actually valid and conformed to
specifications so having ja in in in
some application domains a stringent
language description that includes rules
for the sexting multiple languages of
standard might be a solution but this
will not work in the general case so
this was a dad yeah my talk and I'm
happy to take questions let's take our
speaker
questions yes Jacob would you say this
is somewhat analogous to the row hammer
bug where you have closer to the Phi
level a ambiguity that's trying to be
that's propagating through and actually
creating an application-layer
vulnerability you can definitely see it
this way thank you anybody else