hi there and welcome thank you all for
having me here at besides athens as
virtual as it is i hope that next year
we'll be able to do this in person so
i'm dave lewis and my talk today is
security debt and running with scissors
and we'll get into what that means in
just a second
so i've been in security now for the
better part of 30 years and i have done
pretty much every role along the way up
to and including being a cso for a power
company and i have always been of a
hacker mind uh when i got started back
in 1983. i
hate that i can say that um i was really
having a good time you know duping video
games telling my kids in school that
sort of fun stuff
and well time has skipped ahead on us as
it always does
and now i'm a pretty much grizzled old
graybeard and a rather frequent coffee
drinker
um
and it's been interesting over the last
couple years during the course of the
pandemic
i got into a couple of side ventures of
being uh involved with a whiskey
distillery as well as a soccer club here
in canada
and it's been uh it's been really
interesting to be able to you know try
different things even though we have
been and for a large part of it locked
down
but now hopefully we are coming to a
better place i want to believe i also
would love it if this virus would just
go away
so i am canadian uh so sorry about that
um it is you know running joke here in
canada
um
and you know we have to keep our wits
about ourselves because you know so many
times we have issues that crop up
and we often forget about the human
element so we have to be very cognizant
that we are taking time to take care of
our own mental health as well as those
around us so
having a good laugh every once in a
while doesn't hurt because we have far
too many soul-crushing meetings and you
know what you know we have to be very
cognizant of that because
there are better ways to do things and
over the course of the last couple years
we've actually found that we can be very
productive as security professionals in
this climate so that has been a real
bonus in that regard
so i myself identify as a hacker and
that means that well most of the world
is not a big fan of us
hackers quite literally for me is a term
of someone with an innate curiosity
about how things work
how we can take them apart put them back
together again and the criminal side of
things is something that i refer to as
the attacker so we have to make sure
that we are owning our own lingua franca
because otherwise the media will spin it
for us
so back many years ago i got my first
apartment back many years ago
and the first thing i did after my folks
drove off and it was just my roommate
and i was i grabbed a pair of scissors
and i ran around the apartment and my
roommate thought i had completely lost
my mind and wasn't too far from
incorrect he wasn't too far from the
right
you get me um
so i i just thought it was an ultimate
act of rebellion not taking into account
that this could have been a rather
unfortunate accident if i had tripped
and this is really how i like to frame
security debt now for me security debt
is a technical debt that has manifested
a security issue and we'll talk about
that a little bit more later
and it is very much akin to running
around with a pair of scissors in your
hand
seemed like a good idea at the time
so we have to make sure that we're
looking at how we're doing security or
in our environment and you know just
because something's inside your firewall
doesn't mean it's necessarily secure
because i have worked in an organization
in the past where that was actually said
to me by a cio and the problem here was
that you know security wasn't part of
the equation it was a flat network
and the phrase that was said to me was
that we trust everyone who works here
which is all well and good because you
know ransomware trusts everybody too
they trust us to make mistakes
ransomware really is the debt collector
for security debt and we have to make
sure that we are not making it easier
for attackers to be able to get their
job done
another thing here too is you know we
all like to be environmentally friendly
which is a good thing except when it
comes to passwords now i stole this from
my friend karen elzary and you know what
this is a great idea here because we
have to make sure that we are not
recycling passwords we are not reusing
them on multiple sites from our internet
banking to you know whatever it happens
to be because the attackers know this
and they will go after sites and
compromise them and then reuse those
credentials to try and escalate their
privilege so we've got to make sure that
we are not making their jobs any easier
because as a security professional we
always feel like this or at least i do
and hopefully we can get to a better
place so we are not feeling like this
constantly
so when we're born into this world we
have to understand that we are
defaulting to trust now malcolm gladwell
talked about this in his book talking to
strangers that when we're born in this
world we are looking for food we are
looking for shelter we are looking to be
safe
and as a result we don't have an innate
understanding as to what it means to be
you know securing our environment and
making sure that you know attackers
can't cause us undue harm we are just
reaching out and hoping for the best
now
this does not translate into the modern
uh world and when i say that from the
perspective of computer security we want
to make sure that we are trust but
verify and verify again because we can't
just accept at face value that someone
is who they say they are we have to make
sure that trust is a absolute factor in
everything we do but it's established
trust because trust is ephemeral we want
to make sure that we are not just saying
oh i trust frank because frank is
somebody i've always known
because frank might not be frank behind
the keyboard anymore frank might have
lost control of his own credentials so
we have to always keep that in mind
because in the last couple years we've
really seen that our security paradigm
has shifted our threats are different
i've been very fortunate that i've been
a home office user for many years
so a lot of this was old hat for me but
too many people have you know really had
a hard time adjusting because before the
pandemic we had folks that would say oh
i'm going to work from home on friday
which was code for you know i'm going
off to the islands or i'm going off to
the cottage or whatever it happens to be
in your respective jurisdictions um
and it has really changed how we view
the world so
in addition to the threats that we have
to deal with you know cats running
across keyboards dogs chewing through
cables
kids tapping on computers when they
shouldn't
we have to make sure that we also
understand the human element as i
mentioned before because the human
element really does factor into security
debt as well because we want to make
sure that we're being aware that you
know people are in a different
environment they are really trying very
hard to get their jobs done in a safe
and secure manner and they're they're
worried about you know how are they
going to be able to pay their bills so
you know attackers know this and they
tend to prey on this using uh various
phishing techniques and things to that
effect so we want to make sure that
we're giving them tools that are going
to help democratize security and keep
them safe and secure at the same
time because security debt as i
mentioned earlier is really it's about a
for me is a technological debt that has
manifested a security issue and i really
like to do to make that absolute
distinction because i have been in too
many environments in the past where
you know security debt really had become
a wide open problem you know os2 warp
systems running hvac that were attached
to the internet um all sorts of really
odd things like that
an old
polycom device that was configured to
access the internet
using default credentials and also with
the ability to change that to allow ssh
through it into the network
these are kind of things that you might
not think about at the time but they do
manifest as a security issue once the
attackers find them as absolutely but we
want to make sure that we're managing
that risk to our environments
because things like heartbleed and log4j
these are going to continue to happen
because when organizations are using
open source software and to be clear
there's nothing wrong with the open
source software but they have to be able
to manage the risk associated with it
because at the time you know harpley's
ssl or sorry the ssl library rather was
being used by e-commerce sites to plant
all over the planet like everybody was
using it but at that point in time there
was about one and a half people
dedicated to maintaining that particular
library
thankfully that has been remedied and
they are well financed and the rest of
it but
it's just one example of many
there are all sorts of open source
libraries that find their way into
commercial software that may not be
properly maintained so we want to make
sure that we are keeping on top of that
and not introducing undue risk into our
environment
because there's different ways to you
know handle risk you know do we avoid it
accept it reduce transfer
the thing here that really bothers me is
far too often i see organizations just
accept the risk they sign it off and
move on and
it's forgotten you know that piece of
paper ends up in a desk drawer or it's
you know filed off in some obscure part
of your computer that you never look at
again
and that's a problem
because
there's also the pieces you know who is
accepting that risk who has the ability
to accept the risk in your organization
and what's your plan to deal with it in
the future
because things like this are going to
continue to happen i've seen this in far
too many environments where a beige
desktop was in production
running mission critical code written by
a summer student that nobody knew how to
port it off and they couldn't afford to
shut it down
because it was running a critical
function
this is just one example of many that
far too many organizations have in their
environments
last couple of years i've been doing
sisa roundtables roughly about one per
week
and this has been a topic that has come
up over and over again you know these
old deprecated systems that we're
running that are not maintained not
patched
but it's okay because we have a firewall
it's an unfortunate notion that
people put a little bit too much
investment into the idea of a
traditional perimeter you know the
castle wall the moat and all the rest of
it really that has been a deprecated
notion for many many years
we want to look at the access perimeter
is or rather the perimeter as being
anywhere an access decision is being
made and we have to be very clear on
that
so just accepting the risk is not going
to help you it is going to buy you time
and it's usually driven out of a it
project you know the project manager
just wants to get the end of job so they
accept the risk they move on and the
risk is
forgotten so
this can't continue
because
when we're looking at it from a
project-based perspective there's
usually no sunset provision for that
particular project so when that project
is built
it could be meant to last for three
years five years whatever it happens to
be but then in most organizations it'll
limp on for 10 to 20 years
and this is a real problem when they're
not being patched not being maintained
not being configured the people who
installed it didn't properly document it
and have now left the company
these are the kind of things we have to
make sure that we're keeping on top of
on a consistent basis
and when you're looking at security in
your environment rather
you want to understand what are those
business priorities for your
organization you know running around
with your hair on fire saying oh this is
really bad
has extremely limited utility you want
to look at it as you know what are the
outcomes you're trying to achieve from a
security perspective in order to satisfy
the aspirations of your business
fundamentally that's it at its core so
if you don't understand what it is
you're securing in your business you
know you're not just saying you know the
answer is no
um
you're going to put yourself in a bit of
a disadvantage you want to make sure you
clearly understand what the mission of
your organization is so that you can
best protect it
and from a business can you know context
you know what is most important what are
they like i was talking about what are
they trying to achieve but we also have
to make sure that you know we're not
negatively impacting systems or in our
environment
we have to be able to facilitate that
conversation with the developers with
the business units so that they don't
just stand up in application hope for
the best
in the past i was dealing with one
organization who built out a web
application and put it live
somehow bypassed security altogether and
the very first day it went live
they came to me and said oh we need a
security review
nothing like being timely
the problem here is the first thing i
did was view source on the web page
and right there commented out in the
code was the username and password for
admin and password
i wish i was joking but this was
actually a thing what was made it worse
was the particular manager for that
development team looked at me and said
you've hacked our application
i had to take a moment's pause
that was a very difficult moment for me
because i wanted to scream and pull my
hair out but
that wouldn't have accomplished anything
i at that moment realized that there was
a failure on my part and my team's part
that we didn't clearly communicate to
the organization what we expected from
them from a security perspective
and they clearly didn't have any
understanding of that so rather than
vilifying the users i had to find a way
to have that conversation to better
impart what security issues we needed to
take care of so that this didn't
continue in the future
now we talked about project managers and
how sometimes you would see you know
risks being accepted by the wrong people
but you know within your own business
ask yourself this question who has the
ability to accept risk
typically it ends up in the c suite but
not every organization understands that
and far too often i'll see organizations
that are accepting risk that are
individuals that have no capacity or
authority to accept a risk
one organization that i was at and i
left shortly after this was we had done
an entirely entire rather vulnerability
assessment of the organization found
absolute
plethora of
organizational issues
vulnerabilities configuration issues
imagine a flat network that spans the
globe
and we presented them to the head of i.t
um wasn't even the cio who's the i.t
manager
or director rather for that particular
part of the organization and he said
that's okay we'll just accept the risk
this was very very difficult to
wrap my head around at the time because
at no point was he doing anything to
mitigate the issues
and
it was really a trivial exercise for an
attacker to breach that particular
organization i sincerely hope that they
have long since fixed these issues but
it was um
not something that they were really keen
to take a
serious look at at the time
so when you're looking at you know the
various security issues within your
organizations what those risks are and
when i say the risks you know i mean it
from quite literally an expectation of
loss if this particular system goes down
how much is that going to impact the
business and how is it going to impact
the business you know how can you
quantify that and how can you improve
the process in order to make sure that
those risks are being dealt with
so you know do you have a risk register
um are you tracking these risks to end
of job are you able to clearly
communicate this to the auditors when
they come calling and wow they come
calling
pardon me take a little water break
so we want to make sure that we have a
clear you know defined repeatable
process on how we can address this and
reduce the risk in our organization
fundamentally
because if these risks are not addressed
over time they compound
and when you add in new systems add in
new projects over time you end up with a
layer of digital detritus that really
can cause an
unbelievable number of issues and if an
attacker is able to breach one system
all of a sudden they have the ability
and capacity to pivot from one system to
another and we don't want to make their
job any easier than it already is
we want to make sure that we are not
allowing you know these issues to
languish we have because you know
fundamentally that danger does grow over
time and if we have a lack of action on
our part
it just presents targets of opportunity
rather
for the attacker
and when we layer in things like iot
the risks explode
they are
many and many many issues that come with
this and i'm not talking just simply
about consumer grade croft of you know
the baby monitors and the wireless light
bulbs and things like that but you know
control systems that are being used to
do manufacturing to handle
control systems for power water and so
on
all of these things if they are not
properly maintained
we have a real problem and there is an
adversarial relationship that i've seen
historically between ot and it groups
within organizations that handle these
systems
we have to find a way to build that
bridge to make sure that we're avoiding
these security issues because as these
things crop up they're going to add
greater and greater levels of complexity
in order to what in order to
try that again
to for our systems that we need to
protect and we have to go through that
lather rinse repeat
and as we add in multiple systems that
becomes far more difficult to address
we can't just be that flaming sword of
justice is running down the hall and
saying the answer is still no and we
have to make sure that when we make our
slides that the color of the letters on
the slide are the right color so you can
actually read it which says the flaming
sword of justice so that refers to
somebody that i knew many years ago who
really his answer to everything was no
and this does nothing to improve
security for an organization
that's an old-school old-school dated
approach and it's really ineffective you
know if we are not taking time to
empower the organization to help them
better understand how to secure the
environment
it's doing nothing to improve matters
because that perimeter is not what it
used to be
it's everywhere anywhere an access
decision is being made
because data breaches are happening and
they're happening all the time and it
really does seem in a lot of cases like
you know everybody wants one
so we want to make sure that that is not
going to continue as a trend back in
2012 i started tracking data breaches
and there was a few here and there you
know i think the biggest one at the time
was six and a half million records which
was pretty huge back then but nowadays
we're dealing with orders of magnitude
of billions of records being compromised
we can do better
when we look at it and we see that a lot
of the breaches are handled or rather
facilitated through weak credentials
like qwerty password123 things like that
vilifying the users isn't going to help
we have to give them better tools we
have to give them better ways to protect
things because if it's a weak unpatched
device that's on us if it's a bad
password that's also on us and i don't
expect non-technical people to be
computer savvy so we want to give them
something that is going to help protect
their organization
and make it as easy as possible for them
to be safe and secure so they can you
know concentrate on their core
competencies
continuous trusted acts is a great way
to do this i mean some people say zero
trust i like it this way because
a lot of times i've heard people spit on
the floor when they say zero trust
xero trust really is fundamentally about
reducing risk so if you say continuous
trust and access is making sure that
you're going through and approving all
the users devices and applications on a
continuous basis because as i said trust
is ephemeral
this will help improve matters in the
longer term
and you want to make sure that security
is part of your mission overall
so just saying you know you're one
little security group running around
terrorizing you know people in your
organization saying you know do this or
bad things will happen isn't going to
help improve matters we want to make
sure that security it becomes part of
the fabric the dna fundamentally of your
organization
because as a security professional i
shouldn't have to exist this should be
part of the overall structure but again
going back to when we're born into the
world as malcolm gladwell said we
default to trust and we want to make
sure that we are helping organizations
better understand this because you know
security people are a little different
we have to get away from the bailing and
bailing wire and duct tape approach to
putting our systems together we have to
have clear strategies in order to get to
that better place
and we do that through having clear and
concise planning
you want to trust but verify within your
organization you need to establish trust
in your user identities devices
applications we've got to sanitize our
inputs and outputs for our applications
i mean sql injection has been on the os
top 10 since the beginning it's still
there still one of the absolute biggest
ways for attackers to breach systems and
we have to make sure that we're patching
things we can't just we worried about
you know the zero days i'm more
fundamentally worried about the 100 day
the 200-day vulnerability that hasn't
been addressed
that
database service pack that has not been
applied for three years these are the
kind of things that keep me up at night
so if we go through it and we look at
zero trust or continuous trusted access
however you want to call it it's about
reducing risk so fundamentally you want
to go through establish trust and user
identities
evaluate the device
look at enforcing policies and make sure
that you know dave from canada is not
suddenly showing up in mykonos attaching
to your systems when i'm not actually on
that side of the planet these are kind
of things you want to make sure you're
on top of
securing the connections to all of your
applications because you don't want me
sitting at a coffee shop here in canada
accessing your email systems when i
don't work for you
and you want to make sure that you're
going through all of that data you're
collecting and looking for anomalies
because they will continue to happen
because attackers are going to always be
looking for ways to get into your
systems
so here's a real quick flow user
requests access to an application we
establish trust on them using say
multi-factor authentication or
passwordless you know these are ways to
do a better job of
authentication uh looking at the
trustworthiness device is it running
windows me
um
in my web blogs for my own site i have
actually seen that recently it wasn't
when it was windows 98
somebody was trying to access my website
and i'm sure that was a horrible user
experience for them
enforcing policies on user device
combination make sure you know that dave
is in canada not in mykonos or something
or athens for example
and making sure that you then build in a
secure connection to the application in
once you've done all of that go through
and look for those anomalies
so if you take nothing else away from
this talk today i need you to go and
look up web authen it is a open standard
that really is about passwordless
authentication and this is a way to make
it easier for the users to you know
access their systems we want to make
sure that we are making things that are
going to democratize security
making it as easy as possible for people
to get their jobs done
we've learned a lot of lessons along the
way the problem is putting those into
action we want to make sure that we are
facilitating a better conversation
because as security practitioners we
have really gotten to that place where
we are now at the adults table we have
we're being taken seriously so we have
to make sure that we capitalize on that
opportunity to better secure the
environment by being a champion for the
environment
of our organizations to better secure
them
there are a lot of problems out there
we've got to make sure that we're not
worried about the sharks that are
patrolling the waters we got to look at
the ocean
the ocean is really
the bigger threat and often overlooked
we want to make sure that we're building
a safe and secure future and you're
using multi-factor authentication using
password lists making sure that you are
reducing security debt in your
environment are all ways to better
improve things because
we don't need to cause ourselves
problems we got enough of them to
contend with as it is
thank you very much for having me
besides athens hopefully i'll be able to
do this in person in the future
if you want to drop me an email at
gattica cisco.com or find me on twitter
at gattaca it is truly an honor to be
able to be part of this again today and
uh thank you and
see y'all later bye