[Music]
all right good all right I will try to
make this good I know this is the last
presentation between you guys and some
beers so trying to make it good my name
is Ken Weston and I'm from Portland
Oregon I'm going to be talking to you
guys about some things that I did prior
to my job at Splunk I actually worked
and developed various tools and
technologies to actually track criminals
I'll talk about some of those cases but
also talk about some of the theory and
some of the things I learned as well
actually doing some of these
investigations so I've been doing
security for about 18 years training to
both defensive and offensive security if
you want to follow me on Twitter there
if you want to send me eight mail and
death threats
there's my gmail account so I developed
a number of tracking technologies and
tools some of them are actually I got to
Pat so we're issued I actually had a
start-up as a result of it it allowed me
some freedom to actually explore and
actually start to develop and leverage
some of the technologies the hackers
were actually using to do malicious
things but actually turn the tables and
actually leverage those technologies and
actually help people to fight crime to
help recover your devices if they're
stolen and through that process I
actually learned quite a bit I actually
built another search engine that
actually tracks and looks at image
metadata you heard Sarah talking earlier
about dark web and some of the things
you can do with access data I actually
both a search engine they actually mined
a lot of the information and I'll talk
about how that actually came to be and
how we actually use that information to
solve crimes
I ended up assisting and training law
enforcement and how to use open source
intelligence for investigations when
they get data like we would collect from
devices how do we make use of this
information so I ended up kind of
holding their hand through a lot of this
stuff as you can imagine sometimes law
enforcement is not particularly
savvy when it comes to technology and I
tried
to help bridge that gap it was a little
frustrating at times but I feel like it
isn't good work there I ended up putting
a lot of bad people in jail probably
about several dozen people actually the
with the data that I actually collected
actually led to a number of convictions
not only did I recover stolen devices
but usually I would also identify other
crimes are being committed we would
actually unveil large organized crime
rings particularly in Portland Oregon
there seem to be a lot of organized
groups that are tied to Russian groups
and I'll talk a little bit about that as
well will actually go into some of those
cases
I'm currently it's Blanc and I focus on
helping organizations with security
analytics I love data especially when
we're talking about hunting and things
like that I really enjoy it I do a lot
of work with insider threat actually
about two years ago I presented up here
different location for a V seismic
Coover I talked about insider threat
with my friend or fawn and I just kept
kennel you guys know - a lot of this is
my own independent research it's not
tied to my employer especially the
things I'm going to be talking about
these are things that I did will before
my employment all right so all right so
that was a charge watching right good I
actually did this presentation some of
the material at Def Con 23 and I got a
lot of media attention
I was actually called a professional
cyber stalker it's not too bad I got
called the the real-life mr. robot that
pissed me off Oregon was a little nicer
as I called the organ business Maggie
called me the good hacker so next year
going to be doing a presentation about
how to make yourself a target for being
doxxed and that's that's how it started
so these are what I call my wallet shame
these are actually photos were captured
from devices or people that actually
recover their devices and results from
the technologies I used this is just
some of the ones I can actually talk
about I blurred up the faces to protect
the guilty and we'll talk about some of
those cases and why I actually do that
some of them aren't blurred out not
everyone likes the work I've done I
thought this was kind of Awesome
actually I actually applied to speak at
blackhat a talk about this stuff and one
of the reviewers said I think you should
reflect on the ethical implications of
the technology you're happily
distributing and it's important that you
know that kind of hurt my feelings right
because um
what I wanted to do is actually take
this technology and actually help people
with it not only help you recover
devices but also help people understand
that these are the tools and
technologies the criminals are using to
track you right
so that was my whole goal with this
stuff so anyway it made me a sad panda
but I got over it and I presented at Def
Con that year which was way better so
some things you'll kind of see this
pattern is when Raphael was up here we
talked a lot about machine learning and
leveraging data science and you know
artificial intelligence and things like
that
when you're dealing with criminals
they're something you need to take into
account right we need to understand that
there's also real stupidity right not
artificial intelligence but people will
make mistakes and these are the three
things that I find that usually leads
criminals to get caught and the FBI law
enforcement they rely on this as well a
lot of times they don't know how to
solve a crime but then they get lucky
because someone screws up so it greed is
the main one usually when someone's
committing a crime and they start to
make money from it they're going to
start getting sloppy they're going to
start taking additional risk and with
that it's going to lead to additional
mistakes pride a lot of arrogance
sometimes is people just having a false
sense of security of that hey they
haven't been caught yet there's no way
they're going to be able to track me
another is just being lazy alright we
see that not just in criminals but we
and some of our environments in our
corporations right with our users but
but those are things to remember so if
you are considering life of crime just
take this into account
so a lot of the work I did I was always
trying to understand you know what is it
I'm looking for there's sort of this
underlying theme and there was a guy
named Evan Lockhart and he's a French
forensic scientist he was actually one
of the first forensic scientists that it
was a lot of the things we have this is
even before fingerprints and things like
that yeah these sort of theories and it
sort of led to all things like we saw
with DNA and fingerprints and things
that are actually used in forensics and
crimes and of course he was talking
about physical crimes the idea is that
when you commit a crime you take
something with you and you leave
something behind and it's referred now
as la cartes exchange principle and I
believe this actually carries over into
the digital world as well the trick is
being able to identify where that data
is and how to log that information and
sometimes it's in places you would never
expect and
talk about that and some of the
investigations so we talk about data and
there can be little pieces of data it
can start with the social security
number we can look at IP addresses we
can look at device IDs we look at phone
number geolocation there's all these
little pieces of data and a lot of times
that data on itself by itself doesn't
mean anything doesn't actually identify
an individual it might defy a device but
some magical things happen we start to
do correlation when we start looking to
all these different data points that
actually make that up we can actually
start to actually develop a profile of
an individual and we can actually even
identify who that person is and
sometimes we don't have all the evidence
but this can be saw enough for probable
cause to actually dig deeper into
investigations and I'll show you some
examples of that so we look at all the
different things we talk about our
laptops or devices we hear a lot about
Internet of Things and people are always
worried about oh they're going to hack
my refrigerator or maybe your microwave
right because they're doing surveillance
on us now but I think the bigger problem
here is the information that has
gathering that data is being gathered a
lot of times it's being stored in the
cloud and a lot of times it's these
companies that are actually developing
these tools and they're not actually
taking security seriously and there's
all this information that's actually
available so if it does get breach there
are ways to draw these correlations and
actually start to identify patterns and
behaviors things I've actually
identified it could be everything from
you know what you like to do your
running patterns and things like that
all that information can be useful if
someone's actually trying to profile and
identify you so these are called crazy
walls anyone act watched CSI probably
seen these right so the whole idea here
is that you're gathering evidence and
you're doing it over a time line and
you're drawing the connections right and
so that's we're doing in the virtual
world and we talk about machine learning
to insecurity that's really what we're
just trying to help leverage that
technology to actually help us identify
these patterns and data because that's
what it's all about it's identifying
patterns and if you're a hunter and
environment or if you're doing this type
of work you sort of have this innate
gift of actually identifying these
patterns and maybe seeing things that
other people don't see and that's
probably why a lot of you were in this
field um just to give you a little
example me and uh one of my peers we
actually got tasked on
national TV show called crime watch
daily they said there was a six million
dollar smart home that was unhackable
challenge accepted we we were able to
hack into the home because the Wi-Fi
password was actually the guy's cell
phone number it's the people that set
this up they didn't actually set the
Wi-Fi password he did but once we got
inside we found that all everything else
had default passwords we were able to
monitor all the different devices and
everything was still using the default
passwords so I got into surveillance
camera as we did all these different
sorts of things and then for dramatic
effect you guys want to watch the video
I'm not going to play here but um we
actually they had a party that night we
had 24 hours to hack it we got
everything we into it we could and then
we started fucking with them we we
turned the lights off which we lowered
the curtains we projected the security
camera footage on to the TV we started
showing all the people's faces that were
at the party scaring the crap out of
them and then we piped in some audio too
it was a computer-generated voice mr.
robot ish that talked about how we
hacked them and stuff like that it was
fun but but it just goes to show there's
just a little piece of information right
and we even talked about things we could
have done there - I had access to his
computer like I got to do his file share
was able to access some of his
information that's where we stopped we
said we're not going to go any farther
in there we told him about what we could
access and we didn't leave that
environment until we actually made sure
that it was secure so so we talked about
the interactive things a lot of times
one day to get to collected so there is
needed is created by us and this is data
that we actually have control of right
so information that we're aware of that
you know we can delete emails and things
like that and we feel like we have some
control of that data but as we do that
there's also data that's created for us
so your stock portfolio when you access
your medical records when you look at
any sort of analytics tools right this
is generated for us we don't have a lot
of control of that we may be able delete
some of it but you know how far can we
go
then there's data that's created about
it and a lot of times we don't even know
about this right I actually talk a lot
with the FBI and investigators they say
people think we collect all this
information about people it's like no we
go to companies the marketing department
they're the ones that have all the
information about people so when we talk
about breaches of that kind of data
right how important is security to those
organizations they're trying to make a
quick buck they're trying to profile
people they're using
machine learning they're doing all these
sorts of things but how is it
information protected usually it's not
secured at all and then it gets even
scarier what I call boogie data people
can't talk about data exhaust things
like that and this is where you start
looking at it may be logged in it may
have some information that can identify
you
it can also consist of breach data so
information that you may not even notice
in breach this actually being sold in
underground markets and things like that
we talked a little bit about darknets
earlier Michael Myers gets thrown there
scary so give you an example just one
thing I want to say is what do you guys
think is the best way to secure your
customer data amen
stop fucking collecting it right we
don't need to store it if you don't need
to collect it information there's no
business purpose for it don't collect it
and if you do need to collect it you
know a cryptid hash it do something you
can to protect that information not only
are you protecting your customers but
you're also protecting your organization
from liability if there is a breach of
that information when that gets out if
it was that part of your privacy policy
where people aware of your collective
information right a lot of times people
in business they may not even understand
how the information can be used against
people and it may not be that data if
you correlate that with additional
information like your your your flight
information with your medical
information your histories OPM anybody
right how can that information be used
against people just something to
consider I'll give an example Ashley
Madison I actually helped an
organization with an investigation they
actually had some suspicions about a
particular executive in the organization
and then someone was searching around
and they found that hey our company name
is actually in the data file and this is
one particular individual he made the
mistake of using the billing address of
the company he used the email address of
the corporation and then dump should
even use the debit corporate debit card
right so usually the company wouldn't be
able to do anything right and it's hey
whatever you do is it's your own
business you know legally we can't do
anything here hey it's between you and
your family but the fact that he was
using this information or corporate
assets that became a bigger issue so we
were able to look at things where they
had billing address they had the last
ajiz the credit card number and there
was even a defense where
I can say well someone used my email
address and they registered as me
problem is we also had VPN logs were
actually logged as IP address the Ashley
Madison date also had the IP address of
one that actually occurred so then you
also have the time stands to go along
with that right busted so we're able to
correlate IP address with vpu + n and
there was also some endpoint logs
he actually had created a shadow
corporate account he was kind of a
pretty savvy when it came to Finance
almost kind of white-collar that's a
fraud and he was actually had a lot of
other expenses so this led to a larger
investigation they got board approval as
well they found that he was actually
using this account to pay for golf he
was paying for bar bills all sorts of
different things a lot of other things I
won't even go into but just to give an
example of when that gets breached right
actually managed and they even told
people that hey working to delete your
information he even tried that the last
transaction he tried to delete the
account right but this information was
still there so that's a violation of
trust
also I helped with another thing it was
actually a
telmex it's the largest provider in
Mexico they actually acquired a company
called prodigy which it was one of the
biggest email providers at the time but
they did not keep the servers past they
didn't configure things correctly and as
a result a lot of the emails they were
in this one particular account we were
actually getting indexed by Google so I
work with the organization to clean up
this configuration and I also helped
make sure that that information got
removed from Google but a lot of the
data we actually pulled from here you're
finding like bank statements a lot of
other information and it's kind of scary
and place like Mexico where some of this
information can be used against people
right so you never know when your email
provider might make a Mis Mis
configuration your data can all of a
sudden be public so it's just something
to think about so I'm going to change a
little go back into some of the actual
tools that I built focusing more on the
endpoint and recovering stolen devices I
got really interested in USB based
Trojans I actually developed a website
called USB hacks you can actually
download some of these tools I'll talk
about go on USB hack zip on the USB tax
com
you're going to get an error of course
it says it's malware because it is just
so you know I have to put it out there
because people say like hey I get to
weird alert oh shit but there's a number
of exploit tools that are available
there you know these are sort of old
like 2008-2009 when I was experimenting
with these but I was really interested
in how these were actually being used
I'm a lazy hacker like trying to hack
from outside that's really difficult but
if you're inside an organization holy
crap it was so easy you know you can
deploy all sorts of malware to the
organization you can download data all
these tools just made it super simple
and so what I did was actually I worked
on my my Master's dissertation where I
was like what if I can take some of
these tools that are have malicious
purpose and actually you know make them
a good thing so what I did was I took
these USB based surgeons and I made them
a happy little Trojan right so you plug
that into a device if let's say that
device gets stolen it hijacks the
computers connected to it then sends
information out to a remote server so we
replicate information like IP address
name of the person that's logged in and
some other data just start out as an
experiment I didn't think was going to
be anything I offered it for free you
know back then it was dig calm for you
Millennials that's like reddit but back
in the day and it got dug to death the
site went down because it was on a share
toast but I got a back up and running
you know modified it some more and
actually found and actually used that
data that was bringing in to identify
all the different types of devices that
this would actually use basically
anything they had USB mass-storage I was
able to to track and I developed a
start-up around this as well so this is
pretty simple it's taking advantage of a
vulnerability within Windows you can
actually download the source code for
the initial USB client that I developed
if you want to actually pick it apart
since P plus plus but it really
leveraged a lot of the autorun
capabilities I also social engineered it
so the file would also look like a
passwords file and things like that so
some want to be more likely to click on
it but again this would hijack the
computer is connected to again careful
when you download the code I'm not I'm
not going to repair any of your
computers and so you think that USB is
you know it's you know that's that's
kind of old and done with but you know
we've we've seen it again the Stuxnet
virus it was initially delivered via USB
it's particularly when you look at
industrial environments or you look at
the medical environments to they're
still
to Windows XP systems that are still
there still vulnerable still a target
and we've still seen this even today
even in 2017 we're still seeing this if
you guys are familiar now with bash
bunny con hack five I have mine on order
it's being shipped should be there when
I get home but basically the
commoditization of these USB hacks and
there's a number of them that are
available there's a lot of really
interesting things you can do with these
types of tools for 100 bucks right so
you know your people that are gonna be
targeting organizations have access to
these tools as well so it might be good
for you to kind of play with these tools
within your environment see if you can
detect them so there's a problem with
the IP address when we were doing these
recoveries a lot of times I we get the
username of the person so that would be
helpful evidence but you know if you
have an IP address it required a lot of
work from law enforcement that's all a
lot of paperwork
it's no identity so it doesn't actually
put the person in front of the computer
probable cause is also a big challenge
it's not always accurate it takes a
really long time legal process and law
enforcement is generally apathetic or
they're busy with other things more more
violent crimes for example so the first
iPod recovery I had we got a connection
and you know the username was kalapa cos
family and there was only one person in
that particular organization that
actually had that last name so that was
very simple one just gives you an idea
it's like if you have IP address you
have additional information you want to
collect as much as you possibly can then
I got approached by a company that makes
thermal imaging cameras and they had a
problem because these devices cost
anywhere from like five thousand to
three hundred thousand dollars they also
had issue with these devices because
some of them were export controls they
weren't allowed in certain countries and
so there what we did was we built a
special version of the software that
would actually rewrite itself so if for
example they they removed the SD card
and they put a new one in the firmware
would see hey this is a new SD card it
would redeploy the Trojan right so if
someone does connect that to a camera
then we're able to get the location we
got some interesting things some devices
showed up in the Middle East that
shouldn't have been there were some
ideas that we also attached to that as
well so we can identify the distributor
right so there's some interesting things
you can do there as well that's that
organization lost their business
also disguised the Trojan as a thermal
image itself and that's the one I use
right there my cat his name was Nabi
still going to go on a quick tangent to
is like well you know these are all
windows what about Mac when I actually
worked on this presentation for DEFCON a
couple years ago actually found some old
source code and I brought it back out
how you can actually develop the same
similar tool for for Mac products so I'm
going to talk about how to build a USB
Chodron for Mac so I used AppleScript
why because it's trusted Apple script is
trusted by all the different
applications in the operating system
I'm also an incredibly shitty and lazy
coder I'm not going to learn objective-c
or Swift or whatever the hell it is now
but Apple script you know even though
it's a real pain in the ass to work with
at least I know this trusted inscripted
and I can easily develop tools for it
and one thing I found was that OSX has a
little security thing where if you put
it like a dot mp3 it'll throw a dot app
on the end to tell people if like this
isn't an mp3 this is an application so
what I did was there's these things
called homo glyphs all right nobody
chuckles all right you guys are all over
12 so so I think use this character
called an organic it's a Turkish
character looks like a period with a
little tiny tail but users can't see it
if you threw that on the end in through
mp3 then it wouldn't throw the dot app
on it so I told Apple about this they
said it wasn't the vulnerability so I'm
now publicly talking about it but this
is kind of what the contents of it looks
like somehow I was able to actually take
that script and make it useful and
here's the actual code and if you guys
want it you can't see it I'm sorry
because it's kind of small here but it's
on my github comm flash Kwest slash
Apple razor and you can actually
download the actual code you compile it
out but the idea here is I'd actually
use sift info object some other things
that actually have available to gather
information about the system the user
that's on that system I got really
frustrated because I was able to open up
a web browser and I could Excel data
through the query string but it's really
obvious to the user so I'm like hey
instead I'm going to use iTunes right so
that's what I do here is I tell
application iTunes to activate and then
I wanted to open up this URL and in that
URL I pass all the data through the
query string and then that when it does
that hang out
then it responds back with an mp3 file
so they think when they clicked on the
mp3 they're actually loosing an mp3 and
usually I know when people are actually
downloading this in the presentation
because I used the rickroll song right
Swee someone starts playing with it in
their audience and yeah anyway but uh
yeah and then down here you can also do
shell scripts you can call a lot of
other things too so this is actually was
an exploit when I release this Def Con
for Mac they can do some some nasty
stuff but just be careful with it and
people will ask about gatekeeper yes
gatekeeper will block this now but back
in the day they didn't have gatekeeper
but a lot of times I found users don't
always have gatekeeper enabled so that
might be something you can leverage or
take advantage of and I've also heard
that there might be a bypass so so kind
of getting back to this when I started
actually doing a lot of recoveries you
know it's not just the the Machine data
itself but we had one device that was
singing out we're getting IP address for
AT&T but then we also got a connection
to a computer lab at the University of
North Texas just the flash I was
actually belong to a professor he has a
bunch of research on it and it got
stolen from him he wanted to back that's
why he had our software installed on the
device and so we tracked into this
computer lab and then we talked to the
campus security and we found that okay
well we have a timestamp of when that
device was plugged in we also found out
that the organization had a number of
laptops were stolen so they actually had
required a student badge to be swiped in
so we had badge information in the log
data as well and then we also found that
they had security cameras as well so we
were able to sync that with the
timestamp and we're able to identify who
actually had that flash drive when we
got it back for the professor so just an
example of a lot of times you need to
think about all the different data
sources you may have available to you
when you're doing these types of
investigations um if you get stumped you
know just ask around see what other
information might be available so after
that I actually thought about how can I
actually use this technology to actually
recover stolen laptops themselves at the
time there were a number of tools they
actually can do that recovery but a lot
of them I didn't trust because they
provided a backdoor into the system and
I was real nervous about that but I said
you know it's my device what if we can
develop a tool that I can track that
so what I did was I was able to leverage
the web camera which wasn't particularly
new but when we combine that with
geolocation so this is around when the
first iPhone came out and it was using a
skyhook wireless it was actually using
Wi-Fi to get location so I approached
them and I got access to their API and
is able to use it for stuff recovery
into a tool and it gets us within 10 to
20 meters which is perfect for over
we're trying to do with def recovery so
we would capture a photo of the person
that stole the computer we look at the
locations of them and we would send it
to them every 15 minutes or so so and
we're able to monitor that the activity
of the device so a lot of topic got
stolen
you know we could actually identify you
know who actually had it and at the time
I didn't want to build the
infrastructure at the backend so I
actually just attached into Flickr so if
you had a Flickr account you would have
your laptop it gets stolen you activate
tracking and then that data would go
automatically into your Flickr account
is private and then you could provide
that to law enforcement and it worked
really well so we used the wireless now
in which every device has location-based
into it you can actually access it your
most api's and those scrips so you could
you could home grow this now even the
Google Maps API you can get location
data from that as well here's the first
recovery I actually had it was a it was
an iMac that was stolen in New York
along with a bunch of photo equipment
and you'll see in the background there's
all kinds of really other cool stuff
this guy has he has a lot of really cool
toys the police went in and I swear to
god the police officer he'd worked with
some of these other tools he was like
great now I got to do all this paperwork
and he's calling me is like you got a
you know I have to get the information
like no I have location look at the
report you have the location and he
didn't believe me you know and so I said
no believe me
Princip photo out go to the location ask
around if anyone has seen this guy and
he's like don't tell me how to do my job
all right
and but then he did it you know and he
got the recovery and this guy he was
actually a tattoo shop owner and this
was like his back office and he was
actually fencing a lot of other stolen
property and after that then they were
like you want to be my best friend and
next time I'm in New York we're going to
go see a baseball game or something so
what's cool another one we had was in
Portland Oregon
all of a sudden a lot of the schools in
Portland were getting hit a lot tops
were getting stolen
so I actually approached them I said let
me help you guys out we deployed our
software on a number of date laptops
that weren't in the that weren't locked
up
it was weird like they would get stolen
they would replace them and then two
weeks later these people would come in
and steal them again it was just it was
it was crazy so we did started getting
connections from one of them we got the
data and then we actually mapped it out
it was actually in a house in Vancouver
I had to work with the police on this
one in Vancouver and it was frustrating
because they gave me a dress it's been
10 to 20 meters to go to the location
and the guy the police officer knocks on
this guy's door and the guy opens door
he knew it this guy is the guy that
works on his roof and he's like this
guy's not the criminal your technology
doesn't work I got pissed off I'm like
fuck you yes it does so I drove out
there and I started I had my laptop and
I was looking at the Wi-Fi networks
verifying that the data I had was
correct and then I swear to God out of
the door there's a guy this guy right
here he walks out of his door he
deflects right next door right and
there's a the network we had was it's
Russian pride something or other and on
the bumper of his his car was this thing
about Russia right so I'm like great so
then I called the police they came out
and you know and they said yeah this is
great you know now we can actually
follow it up it's like it's a good thing
that you know he didn't see you because
he's got his friend across the street
that lives close by and he's bad news
I'm like what do you mean yeah he got
out of prison he almost tried to kill
someone I'm like all right thanks guys
was awesome but anyway I learned a lot
from that like don't get to at all
another one we had was Victor there was
a laptop that got stolen we didn't hear
anything from it for like two weeks I
got really pissed off I'm like great our
technology doesn't work you know there
may be the reformat it for parts or
something like that and then all of a
sudden I started getting pings from like
Missouri of all places and it was this
guy and I was tracking them all over I
saw him in McDonald's he was in a hotel
with some girl in the back doing
god-knows-what
he was everywhere and we had a lot of
information on him the nice thing that
he really did I'm going to step out of
my box sorry is that he changed the
username in his full name so remember I
talked about the vulnerabilities the
stupid and that's that's one of them
right so if you still a laptop don't put
your full name into the user
okay alright so from that I was able to
go to MySpace
you know I saw he was a really big Scion
car fan I found that he's a username
mapped to a bunch of car forums so it
was really cool to is I also had his
license plate number that was really
nice of him to take photo of his license
plate for me he was selling a lot of
parts on eBay for cars so again what
kind of business is he involved in and
then he ended up he's a nice guy he sold
the laptop along with a stolen bike to
his friend and what happened was is that
his dad is actually the one that gave
him the laptop and what was happening
was they were actually loading up a
bunch of stolen property into a van in
Portland and then they would ship it to
Missouri they would then load up a bunch
of stolen property their ship it back to
Portland because if your stuff gets
stolen where's the first place you're
going to look Craigslist right so that's
what they were trying to do and they did
all this thing and it was his birthday
and his dad gave him a stolen laptop
yeah that's sweet really sweet and a
criminal record thanks dad we had
another one what's more violent it was a
carjacking to Brazil it was actually a
veterinary student and these guys put a
gun to them and they said get out of the
car smash the guy that was the driver
his friend broke his nose and they took
off and they bought the laptop with them
we're able to get these photos provided
the information to the police and they
were able to get the laptop back this
was a good one too because he was a
veterinary student you know he had a
bunch of his final work on there it was
his final year he didn't have it backed
up so I feel pretty good about this we
also you know got the guy that broke his
french nose so then I looked at how can
we apply this to the mobile side so the
geolocation became a lot easier we
looked at mobile devices the IP address
is a little more problematic because it
keeps changing with the different
carriers we then also wanted to do photo
and contact back so the devices we find
that people don't really care about the
value of the phone they can get a new
one but they care about the data but I
didn't want to have unencrypted data I
was really nervous what if I get hacked
I'm very paranoid right what does I mean
for a customer so we actually developed
technology where you would install the
software you would enter a privacy key
the only you know knew that would then
encrypt the data and when it gets
uploaded you can download it and then
you would enter that encryption key and
it would decrypt the data
so that way even if FBI came to us and
say we need all these guys photos
here's your encrypted blob now you need
to go and you know go talk to them about
getting the key we're hands off and if
we do get breached we wouldn't have
these sort of you know the fappening
types of situations where backed up
information becomes compromised and I'm
going to talk let me play a video here
hopefully this works
this is actually this technology got
deployed to a number of wireless stores
they actually deployed them to their
demo units and so let's make sure this
works of course it's not going to work
try it again
where that helping track them down
they've generally spent each have spent
the past two days with police and
investigators on the trail of swiped
cell phones he's live outside the
Washington Square Mall with the theft
took place at well the main years of the
audio are here in Washington Square bill
basically it's the Washington we're
talking saw or is actually a miles away
guy here went into and slower onto their
demo but they ended up writing you an
arrest they stole several thought this
is a felon with this wanted out wing of
a 150 dollar kind of a parade to it I
display Kramer course Oman held to del
phones you're in store at Washington
Square we also have a security footage
without actors in the video self
employees mom and then they were able
act like we're back telephone stolen
phones we were able to not only find the
GPS location of the individuals about
how much took loan cost we've been able
to it looks like Donnelly there happen
to a lot of us are wired LAN tourism
activity area adopted my office shoes or
someone else shortly after the same
thing is a can photo sometimes police
admit right so bravely soldiers I know
phones one girl told to send back
pictures once you're strong I can I get
not only on the fact one of the
interests of our that went together
photo during their experimental two
actors were able to get points to be
very sure credit holders information for
Salalah what I know the Portland creator
of your software cracking up Thatcher
says I can the police are on the right
track it's an awful fees I definitely
know who stole it and if you look at I
am don't you'll see in the window and
Oregon temporary are very smart Philip
I'm today with the help of a gadget
trows estimator on phone we had a
religious : I'm anything else you just
ask there we found you a robbery permit
and please are full enough work a camera
a man she called Peter that was a girl
except it's totally over a Saturday
evening but says she knew nothing about
the phones right I get attractive second
cell phone but I go to beautiful black
about eggs locks away we don't have an
exercise Samsung Epic Games okay you're
the other for it but these were here
yesterday looking for anyway I'll skip
so it just gives you an idea is that you
know we have the surveillance camera we
had a lot of information for whatever
reason the phone it wasn't sending the
location data as we need it but we were
able to still get the location data from
the photos themselves because that XF
data in it so we have the GPS
coordinates of where the phone was taken
in a time stamp that was really helpful
for the investigation of course you know
having that as well the trip permit
that's just that's just gravy
the ended up getting these guys and
there was about six or seven people that
were actually involved in this
particular group and they give me
recovered a stolen car this wasn't the
car that we do cover but one of these
guys has already had a warrant out for
his arrest so again we unveiled a larger
larger crime ring and so when I was
doing this to is there's a lot of data
associated with with that are actually
embedded in images you know it's not
just within cell phones where you have
GPS coordinates you have timestamp I
also found it in higher end digital
cameras it would embed the make model as
well as the serial number of the camera
right so that was really interesting to
me and I was like what if those away
because I could search for the serial
number of a camera to see you know
identify all of the photos that were
taken by a particular camera and I
actually found that these are all the
different makes and models of the
cameras that actually will embed the
serial number of the camera in the exif
data
a good example was I report or actually
reached out to me you know when the when
celebrities had some other photos a
compromised Scarlett Johansson I had to
download the images at the research
research research people keep your clean
keep it clean media was saying that the
phone was hacked when actuality if we
actually look at the exit data it
actually reveals that the it was from
multiple phones over the course of
several years and it was actually the
point of compromise was email with this
guy Chris Chaney he's now serving 10
years in jail because you know he was
guessing the passwords the passwords
weren't particularly complex and that's
how I was able to get access to the
images um so then I thought you know
there's got to be a way to mine this
exif data so at the time i was working
with a friend of mine who had a startup
was called CP usage and they actually
have sort of like the study at home
model right so instead of volunteering
your computer time we would actually pay
you for your computer time so i access
to lie
500 to 1,000 computers so what we did
was we got around Flickr I was trying to
use just the the API of course that
limits how many requests you can make I
got this stuff I'm like there's got to
be a way around it that's what I want to
mind so I use those 500 computers from
all these different computer labs from
universities and other places all around
the world and then we started mining the
Flickr data and we were able to do I
think was like 5 billion images within
about 2 or 3 weeks we were able to grab
it also from other sites like 500 pics
panoramio Twitpic I found that Twitter
will actually scrub the exif data from
engine images you upload but a lot of
the profile images still have the exif
data it was really weird you'd find
these tiny little thumbnails and they'd
just be tons of exif data including GPS
coordinates and serial numbers and all
sorts of interesting things so we mined
that as well just for research so the
way it works is we would mine these
sites we would actually download the
data we would have this information we
then put it into a database and then
again I launched as a free product you
could just do a quick search and of the
serial number and we'll show you all the
different photos we actually found that
were actually taken with that particular
camera and we actually started getting
recoveries it got featured in New York
Times and The Economist and some other
publications imported refers heard about
it this one guy John Heller he had a
camera stolen about a year prior he did
a search and he got a hit on Flickr we
then were able to map that username to
another account on Facebook and it was a
guy who was also professional
photographer who just happened to have
photos of all of his gear and there was
his camera he was like that's my camera
he contacted the police they got
involved what happened was he was at the
Egyptian theater and somehow like $7000
of the camera equipment he was on
assignment for Getty Images and he
turned around to talk to someone turn
back around all his gears gone right
that's that's for an independent
contractor six $7000 of camera equipment
it's pretty scary so the guy stole it he
then sold it to someone on Craigslist
and then he sold it to someone eBay and
so what we were able to do is actually
trach this guy who had it on Facebook he
bought it from someone on eBay the
police went to that guy on eBay about it
from a guy on Craigslist
okay what was the address they went to
that guy's address this is a year after
the camera was stolen they go back to
this guy's apartment and they find all
kinds of other stolen property right so
he got busted bad thing is the guy that
had it on a rig at the end there he
would didn't commit a crime but he was
in possession of stolen property so he
did have to hire an attorney just to
make sure that all the stuff got worked
out but first recovery was kind just
using a little bit of data
EXIF data right so this put people on
notice that a camera can be tracked
right if it gets stolen a year two years
three years later and that guy got
arrested there's a copy of the receipt
so so we had a few of these other ones
another one guy a guy tried to sell a
camera on Craigslist and you know he
looked it up and there was a case where
he was showing someone the camera out in
his garage and then this other guy drove
up in his car the guy he was showing it
to popomon face knocking to the ground
took the camera ran off and then so
we're able to identify who had it and it
was this guy
and we had his name identified his
business he was a professional
photographer and DJ he had addresses we
had some domain registrations able get a
cell phone number from his ads as well
identified all the social media and
photo sharing accounts he had about 12
different high-end cameras that he would
get every 12 months so we actually mined
all of his images that he was posting so
he so he was trying to like do this with
girls like hey if you want to be a model
I'm a professional photographer that
sort of thing but he had tons of photos
if some photos he probably shouldn't be
taking so you had photos of his
marijuana he had a photo of him holding
a firearm up to his his head there there
wasn't a license there was no registered
firearms under his name when we talked
to police you like to take photos of him
and his friends smoking marijuana as
well as going to a concert I think was a
jay-z concert or something they were
smoking weed on the way looking to date
stamp and just a note if you are going
to take a photo of yourself smoking weed
make sure you don't take a fit photo of
your speedometer going 110 miles an hour
because then we had geolocation time
stamp and everything that was doing so
the police really like this one we gave
them all this information right all
sorts of probable cause
interesting things you learned about
people and so this technology was
actually I was approached by ice and
there was a Child Exploitation
investigation unit and they wanted
access to this via API the idea here is
that you know Joe sicko
he's taking photos of kids and he's
uploading them to darknets right so
those images may have exif data still in
them with serial numbers and we'd be
able to match that up with maybe that
same camera that's being used
it's flicker when he's taking a photo
with his family Disneyland right so they
were actually using that API they
couldn't tell me if they'd caught
anybody but just giving them free access
and I'm hoping that maybe they got one
or two guys with it I'd be great I also
went to a thorn as a hackathon with
Facebook Facebook and thorne and one of
the challenges with this is that
sometimes the police will come they'll
see a phone or they'll have an image
that may have been sent to a kid on
social media but they don't have time to
do a forensic image of that device it
can take months or even longer than that
what this allows them to do is actually
be on the device right immediately they
can actually upload an image to this
tool Xiao and it'll tell them if there's
any GPS coordinates serial numbers
anything it's identifiable in that in
that image and they can do it from a
mobile phone and they can do it from a
laptop as well so sort of a simple
solution but it's something that is
being used by law enforcement and that
was it man I was right on 45 minutes so
I have a little bit of time for
questions so or do you guys just want to
go drink beer right there do a
microphone sure I can you can scream and
I'll repeat it
so would would any one of you guys
experts think or investigate what's
going on now with Russians and would you
agree that at least professional space
sponsors hackers from foreign country
would not probably live ah obvious signs
that they are involved in it or is
anyone looking at this from the
professional side some are looking at TV
and stuff is like come on it's so
obvious are you guys involved in this
and do you have any insight on that yeah
I don't want your comment I don't get
involved in the nation-state stuff that
scares the crap out of me when I was
involved it just it simplify I don't
want to details but like really anyone
here can probably agree if I'm
professional hacker on that level I
would probably not leave my own
signature in that software itself right
that's kind of its own predictors
there's always no experts are standing
up and saying so right there's always
you know you're always looking for for
someone to make a mistake I've been
involved in other types of
investigations that are more like
intrusions and things like that and you
know you talk about attribution and
things like that it's a lot harder to
prove but you can start to look at some
of the larger campaigns incorporated
intelligence additional data sources you
can start to make assumptions right but
you're not going to be able to actually
prosecute them or get all the evidence
unless you get the other nation states
actually involved to actually help with
that investigation right so a business
they kind of they can only do so much
the FBI can only do so much if some of
these countries are not they're not
working with us they're not willing to
participate then you can only your
investigation is only going to go so far
unfortunately
right
yes so you mentioned with Twitter they
seem to scrub exif data that seems to
becoming RB becoming more popular with
stuff like imager comm does scrubbing
exif data on image house like that like
the ward some of your efforts yeah for
this but one thing I did learn and in
one investigation I won't say which
social media platform but that
information is still stored so you can
if you believe that there might be
evidence associated with an
investigation you can actually go to
some of these providers they either have
the original image uploaded somewhere or
they've actually extracted a lot of that
exif data i'm actually found that a lot
of the data that's in those that in the
images it does have marketing use you
know looking at GPS coordinates things
like that make model a camera so the
some of those organizations are
harvesting that information it's it's
available either in a database or they
have the original image so if you're in
the FBI or someone like that they have
access to that information still so if
you're involved in crimes you want to
make sure you scrub the image before you
upload it to a website they already know
this container this question here thanks
all that was an awesome presentation i'm
just there's a couple like buzzwords you
didn't talk about and I'm just kind of
curious like how these figure into your
work mainly like MAC addresses and like
IMEI numbers and phones and laptops and
stuff like how accessible are those to
forensic departments like do are they
just staying on the router and therefore
they're not going over the wires you
just can't really do anything with them
or like there's there ways to work with
those yeah we include those and we
include that in the software we get the
MAC address for systems because the IMEI
the IMSI all that information anything
that's available in the SIM card we're
able to pull yeah we have access to all
that data it's in the report
we've got another guy here I'm here oh
yeah
two mics guys really just a quick
question the problem would the exist
tool was that when you create
laughter oh not snapchat a screenshot
from the picture then you have no data
or metadata of that picture so is there
any idea do you have any idea how to
overcome that yeah yeah so the question
was regarding it is you can it's pretty
easy you can even easily scrub
information from images you can also you
know take a screenshot of the image
right so that was your question it
removes all the data well there's other
technologies that are available for that
if you look at Microsoft photo DNA
they're doing some really interesting
things particularly for identifying they
call innocent images so even if you take
a screenshot of it there's ways they can
actually look at the image itself and
there's some really interesting things
that hackathon I went to there was a
bunch of data scientists we had data
sciences from our team there and they
were showing all these really cool
things the guys that actually did this
stuff where they're actually looking at
when you go to a hotel take a photo of
the bedsheets and everything like that
and upload it and they're able to use
machine learning to identify you know
these images they can see like what you
know if it's a Holiday Inn in Texas or
something like that they could identify
some of that there's a lot of really
cool things in the images themselves but
that's for people that are like way
smarter than I am
you you just mentioned or alluded to
this in your previous response but I was
wondering what your experience was with
the various image recognition engines
you know there's so many more of them
making themselves available and they're
growing in performance and maturity and
affordability so have you started to
integrate those tools into the work that
you're doing or it's still early days
well I think a lot of really interesting
things on the machine learning side with
the images kind of we were talking about
- with like the photo DNA and things
like that and you know that kind of gets
you know beyond like what I what I I do
I deal with just like data I'm really
bad at math so I'm good investigations I
might leverage some of those tools to do
an investigation but yeah there's a lot
of really cool stuff that's happening
that's you know again it's kind of
beyond my skill set hi why is it that
you don't like being compared to a
real-life mr. robot yeah I'm not that
smart so that's the thing is like a lot
of this stuff I kind of stumbled into it
you know I didn't really create a lot of
these tools I sort of had theories and I
tie things together right there's got to
be a way to bring this data together and
you know I trained a defence of security
and things like that but yeah when
someone starts calling you mr. robot
you're like come on fuck off any more
questions so I'll be around so if you
want to talk to me some more more than
happy to answer more questions thanks a
lot appreciate it