[Music]
like garland Sherratt I'm with HootSuite
security architect but the views here
expressed are my own that's a little bit
loud for you guys everyone's good okay
alright so I want you to realize that
you've entered a bit of a different
world
I call it garland or the land of gar so
a lot of the speakers here are here
because they're experts I'm an expert
because sorry I'm here because I'm not
an expert I thought that identity
I still think identity authentication
very interesting subjects and I wanted
to learn more about them and I thought
this is a good opportunity for me to
have do you have that kind of force
learning and now I want to share that
with you guys so what I want to do is
essentially survey the whole space a lot
of it anyway of authentication a little
bit of identity and leave you with a
foundation a way of looking at the space
and understanding what's going on
especially with passwords but also with
authentication in general and I have to
say I'm pretty grateful to be able to
speak to here today so I normally cringe
when speakers do polls but in this case
it's appropriate I want to start you
thinking about some of the issues so
here number one how many of you think
that passwords are bad ends up please
okay
all right number two how many of you
would like to get rid of all passwords
okay a few less than I expected this is
good and how many of you think it's
possible to get rid of all passwords
hmm okay you guys are going to be a good
audience okay so I spent a lot of time
reading and reading and reading after
this presentation was accepted for four
b-sides and I knew I had a problem when
that document I collect with all my
thoughts came to about 36 pages so
that's 36 pages of a Word document
small print so you can imagine that kind
of condense this down into 45-minute
talk is a bit of a challenge I hope I'll
do it justice so the topic is the title
winning the world of passwords so what
does weaning mean
weaning is only for mammals it's
essentially the idea of taking an infant
of that mammal getting it on to adult
food getting it away from its mother's
milk and if you've spent any time on a
farm like I have you know that weaning
is quite a distressing process and it's
distressing for not only the service
provider but also the user so passwords
are going to be the same way it's going
to be distressful to get rid of them
it'll be disruptive but I'm going to
show you why there's hope so I'm going
to talk a little bit about all spaces to
try to try to cover enterprise business
to consumer and also the personal space
as well so passwords started a long time
ago probably the beginning of human
civilization certainly you know
organized civilization but in time
should in nit password started with time
sharing in the nineteen sixties the idea
being that a user you don't tend to get
yourself to the mainframe quite a
different situation as today now
passwords are a form of identification
and authentication it's always been a
game of cat and mouse there's the bad
guys fighting the good guys new ideas on
one side opposing ideas on the other
side
the whole subject of identity
authentication fascinating areas and I
become more and more interested as I've
gotten into them and I encourage you to
go do some research as well to start you
off with a very very simple view you can
look at identification as using a user
ID to assert an identity and then after
that you can look at authentication as
using a password or something to prove
that identity now that's a highly
simplified view but it's a good place to
start so there's a whole bunch of things
wrong with passwords let's let's start
one of the major ones is the passwords
push responsibility on to users that
they're simply not prepared to handle
and they they do not want that
responsibility so they find it really
hard to manage them you have to keep
those passwords secret you have to store
them for a long period of time and of
course users can't really create and
generate good quality passwords and they
can't create and generate and use and
store unique passwords across all sites
now it turns out the only way today to
manage the chaos of passwords I think
I've got about 300 I remember those the
only way to do is with the password
manager and of course when you start
looking at this you discover the first
thing is that the vast majority of
people don't use a password manager now
in this audience
my guess is going to be that half a you
do I don't know let's let's take a poll
how many of you use a password manager
it's more than half that's very very
nice I don't know how anyone would
survive without it but a lot of people
do now I'm going to start with some of
the problems with passwords so these
problems that I'm talking about on this
chart are in fact all solvable today
with password
managers if the majority of people use
password managers those problems would
either be gone away or they'd be
mitigated so weak passwords people
choose them so they can remember them at
Deloitte study 2013 found that six mill
million passwords and they found that
the 10,000 of those passwords that were
most used would access 98% of the
accounts so you rankle the passwords
that the one the 10,000 that occurred
the most did all the 2% of accounts it
could open them up pretty scary right
that's massive reuse so users are
routinely reusing passwords and
usernames of course because usernames
are often email addresses they store
them in text files they write them down
they email them to themselves they
shared with other people
users are subject to phishing social
engineering key loggers on their devices
now all of these password managers would
help with but the fact is people are not
using them they haven't sent something's
wrong but they're just not using them
there's a bit of a chicken and egg in
fact there's quite a bit of a chicken
and egg until users all have password
managers or the majority do service
providers cannot insist on long complex
passwords and until service providers
insist on long complex passwords most
users who are lazy quite frankly in
their computing are not going to go get
themselves a password manager so we're
stuck it's it's simply not going
anywhere now some other issues with
passwords a lot of service providers
don't manage passwords well thankfully
the things going away but someone and
still collect passwords over HTTP and
some of them still collect passwords for
third-party sites using by directly
collecting user IDs and passwords they
should be using OAuth a lot of them have
to learn now
at the in the enterprise space one of
the big thing is you're going to run
into is probably have run into is shared
accounts and the issues that causes
especially with off-boarding so a lot of
accounts have more than one person using
the credentials when the people leave
company should be changing those
credentials do they oftentimes not now
help desk help desks cost a lot of money
to run and a lot of those help desk
calls are actually for password changes
there is a study by mandiant labs just
this year average enterprise spends
$180,000 on password resets for every
thousand users $180,000 for every
thousand users and on average about
twenty to fifty percent of all the calls
to the help desk were to reset passwords
so with the problems wire password still
being used there's a lot of advantages
to them it worked for about 50 years and
for users they're pretty easy to
understand users have no challenge at
all you don't need any special hardware
you simply walk up to any thing in the
world today and you can log into your
account may not be safe to do that but
you can do it it's easy to change your
password to revoke the account if you
forget your email you simply request a
link through email you've got a new link
to log in and it's very easy on the
other side for the service providers to
implement every every language has
libraries you know to implement password
systems there's also economics I find in
any space not security I mean everywhere
it's really fun to look at the
incentives that are making things the
way they are now here you can see
essentially a tragedy of the Commons or
in economics that's called a negative
externality it turns out many types
of market failures a negative
externality is one of those types of
market failures if you're interested in
economics like I have encourage you to
go read all the flavors of market a
constraint of market failures quite
interesting so a negative externality is
when two parties are in a transaction
and some third party is being hit with
some negative benefits so they're not
involved in the transaction but they're
still still being impacted by it so in
in password security you find that low
value sites have no incentive at all to
improve the security of their
authentication systems so when there's
breaches say their password files are
stolen it's the high value sites that
are impacted because people reuse
passwords any and user IDs so the
high-value sites get hit by going to
drive-by shootings in a sense the low
value sites have no cost at all because
their stuffs not of high value and you
find that okay yeah let's that's enough
I'm doing pretty well I've got I've got
12 minutes down and 10 charts down so I
can I don't have to rush quite as much
as I thought I might need to so I'm
going to start with the issues what are
passwords so passwords are a shared
secret now shared secrets can be good
and bad in the case of passwords good
and bad where do you see passwords most
people think about passwords as the
logins for all their accounts of their
web accounts they think of those
passwords but there's other places too
where passwords occurs so equally
important and in fact you could argue
it's more important because it gets less
attention and I'll talk more about this
is account recovery so account recovery
uses a variety of mechanisms I'll talk a
lot more about this but passwords are
clearly one of those you would know
those passwords as
challenge/response or security answers
and questions or recovery one-time
passwords all those are essentially
passwords now there's also master
passwords people call the master
passwords for things like password
managers so it's kind of a meta password
it's not a password to a simple account
it's an account that gives you access to
passwords for a lot of accounts and of
course there's device password
there's your computer password your
phone password so passwords are one form
of authentication factor what are some
of the other forms so you all know MFA
and authentication know have an AR so
have can be hardware or software
you've got mobile devices smart cards
and they're on the software side you've
got seeds for your DOP totp devices
software and hardware in the old days
and certificates and then what you are
typically comes down to biometrics and
I'll talk a lot more about this as well
fascinating subject so everything you
can imagine about your body has already
been or will become a biometric and
people are now adding additional factors
like location and more to come the
biometrics are definitely all the rage
and I guess it probably started with
smartphones so I've got to come up with
a way to categorize biometrics it's my
own personal way of doing it I'm sure
there's many ways of breaking them down
but I've tried to think about the risks
the relative risks of the different
types of biometrics so I've broken it
down into two four different categories
so contact is where you actually have to
be at the person in order to measure the
thing to record it so fingerprint and
DNA are really good examples of those
things that could be done at a distance
kind of more interesting right selfie
photos selfie videos even your iris
scans could be done at a distance
visible pulse on your skin can be done
from video
very interesting stuff persistent things
so fingerprints and DNA hangs around
everywhere you go you leave your
fingerprints and your DNA and there's
more things to come kind of science
fiction a few years ago but people are
starting to do them invasive so invasive
meaning kind of affects your body so you
swallow something you implant something
or you can tattoo something and there's
more so one of the issues is biometrics
is that they are slowly in some
instances at least replacing passwords
touch ID on my phone a lot of the time
as I turn my phone on and use it it
doesn't ask for a password it asks me
for touch ID there's windows hello
realsense cameras so it raises a really
important question that I don't think
it's adequately dealt with and that
question is are biometrics more like
passwords or are they more like user IDs
so I want to ask you guys how many of
you think biometric various kinds more
like passwords how many you think more
like user IDs okay could you all come up
here and do the presentation okay all
right so I see I'm preaching to the
choir very nice so the issue to the
biometrics they're easy to steal and you
can use them without the owner of the
biometrics being aware of them that's um
that's a big deal so persistent and
remote type biometrics in my taxonomy
there those can all be done it can all
be stolen and used without your
knowledge and of course even with your
knowledge one of our government's
probably have your biometrics how
certain are you that though that data is
really safe with them biometrics can be
fooled so iris scanning can be fooled by
photographs if it's not well done
fingerprint verification with Plato and
there's stories about people when
they're drunk sleeping having their
fingers used on their phones
so that the point is that biometrics are
a lot more public than passwords you
don't go around telling people your
passwords at least most normal people
don't but biometrics you you spray them
around essentially so if you look at a
spectrum passwords on the one hand or
quite private user IDs very public
biometric somewhere in the middle and
very interesting hard to define space in
the middle most importantly I think is
that you can change your passwords you
can't change your biometrics if if your
service provider has a breach you lose
your password whatever you can just
change it if you lose your DNA if you
lose your iris scans if you lose your
fingerprints and I would argue they're
already gone then you can't change those
they're yours for life unless you
believe in too much science fiction so I
would say the conclusion is that
biometrics are a factor of
authentication but they cannot be relied
on entirely and cannot be fully trusted
either so I'm going to try an experiment
here I hope this works so there's this
really cool clip and let me let me just
do this a simple way I will extend you
see that
Oh sir duplicate okay so I want to set
the scene a mind share has just happened
or has it here we go
[Music]
i gathering that you probably didn't
hear a single word of that am i right
let's do this again alright so I have to
tell you what happened
so a mindshare did it happen or not
you've got to prove whether it's you or
not you biometrics don't work after a
mine chair because you've got somebody
else's body right or the body goes
someone else's mind big long password
master password okay that would have
worked better if you could have heard it
so an important consideration for
passwords for biometrics especially for
a few different types of authentication
is the local versus remote dichotomy so
the key point is what's appropriate for
local and what's appropriate for remote
authentication so locally if you're
talking to your computer your phone
what's appropriate and I would argue
that when it's a local authentication
it's okay to use what I would call
unstrung methods a password biometric
those are things that are very useful
for authenticating you either fully or
somewhat but they must not leave your
device you should not be sending
passwords across the network you should
not be sending biometrics across the
network if you have any interest in this
subject I'll point you to the global
identity foundation their principles of
identity in 3.0 principle number 8 talks
about biometrics fascinating stuff if
you get into identity you'll be spending
a long time reading it's really fun so
remote or cloud on the other hand I
would argue you need strong methods you
should be using methods based on
publicly public key crypto should not be
sending biometrics should not be sending
passwords across the network now how do
you mitigate passwords passwords have a
lot of faults and you can mitigate them
you can replace them so I'm going to
start with some of the simpler ways so
on devices there's biometrics that can
partially replace passwords so you know
that your phone sometimes a super
password most of the time asks you for
biometrics the biometrics are meaning
that you don't have to use your password
quite as often and it lets you lose
essentially a longer password if you
want to now two-factor authentication
passwords sorry with two-factor
authentication you can essentially
reduce the strength of the password I'm
sorry we took that authentication you
are able to have an additional factor
therefore you don't need a strong a
password now some of the ways of doing
this totp you can fish them real time
though as the previous speaker just
mentioned there's out-of-band aka
mobile push and there's five boat Fido
UTF Universal second factor which is
based on a hardware token and public key
crypto very nice stuff something coming
up is called by few different names so
I've chosen to call it adaptive
continuous authentication it started out
as risk-based authentication it's also
called behavioral and any combination of
the words I've just stated so the whole
idea of adaptive is that you're looking
at the risk of the action being done and
the risk of the act or of that action
and continuous means not only when you
log into your device your computer the
whole time you're using it you're
continuously being evaluated for risk
factors so essentially your device the
cloud potentially has sensors that are
that are being used to collect risk type
information and make decisions in real
time banks started out with risk based
authentication in this so there's a few
different flavors the bank one I
mentioned that's primarily cloud based
there's local base and then this
combination of local and cloud
and Google trust API is something
interested to look at it's a risk based
system so with passwords you can easily
hide them today using password managers
and using something called a few names
but secure web authentication a type of
password manager built into some SSO
systems secure
SSO secure web that education is not
sam'l I'll talk about that a bit later
so if you really want to stop sharing
passwords and sharing I mean between
sites so I mentioned before the the need
to authenticate or to gain access to
resources on a third-party site so oh
I'd lets you do that in the old days
your your site that wanted to post to
your Facebook page would collect your
user ID and password it's such a great
idea because then they've got it too and
they can misuse it they can lose it Oh
on fixes that and others really I would
say one of the marvels of the universe
and and if you ever have a chance of
using it you definitely should and
anybody who is still collecting
credentials should definitely move to
OAuth type systems now a complete
replacement some of you will definitely
recognize these how many of you have
ever played with client certificates
okay
so quite a typic time around a really
long time they have a long history their
form a public key crypto they're
essentially the reverse of a server
certificate so normally you care about
who the server is and you only want to
go to that server if through TLS if it's
if it's the right server client
certificates are the reverse the server
cares about who you are and the server
knows who you are and whether you should
have access there fantastic idea in my
opinion I've never actually played with
one my understanding is the issues with
server side with client certificates
essentially bad use
experiences for managing the certs so
certs they interact with browsers with
operating systems with multiple devices
and then around the issues these days
I've got four different devices I use
for various things I want everything to
work seamlessly amongst those devices
how do you do that with client
certificates now I got to thinking
everything with this for a little while
I've seen this a few other places a
couple other places on the web people
thinking the same ideas but it hasn't
been pursued what if everyone had a
password manager would my password
manager be able to manage my client
certificates and sync them between
devices store them securely as easily
for my client certificates as it does
for my passwords I think it might
however I wouldn't put money on this I
think TLS certificates have probably
passed their opportunity window so
replacing passwords will keep going I'm
going to talk about how authentication
can be put from passwords to other
things and in this case hardware things
so hardware tokens have be around for a
while in the form of smart cards totp
tokens those are those old secure ID
things I'm pretty sure every single one
of you if you're old enough at one point
was carrying one around I certainly did
and now more recently Fido UTF tokens so
UTF token is client-server and really
nicely secured there's also increasingly
smart devices doing this you no longer
need a piece of hardware your phones
your watches your tablets your your
nimmy bands the really important thing
is that you've now got something in your
pocket that used to be the special piece
of hardware and this opens up the door
for all sorts of new authentication
things now I want to talk a little bit
about trusted computing trusted
computing started out with things like
TPM chips
and it's moved on to mobile devices like
secure and clave on Apple and I forget
what it's called on Google the idea is
that there's this little hardened
processor in your computer your phone
which stores your keys and protects them
from the bad world and also protects
them from you so it's a kind of
intelligent thing has its own mind in a
sense storing your keys and enabling you
to do secure public private key type
protocols this is a really key
increasingly all high-value or you know
high-end devices have secure computing
and it really changes things so moving
on to replacing passwords with software
this is all quite interesting so in the
consumer space you might have heard of
Open ID Connect
it's gone to a few flavours started with
open ID then moved to open ID Connect
open ID Connect is a combination of open
ID and so on so the idea being that
you've got you know what maybe a social
logins of Google Google Facebook
Microsoft Yahoo all of these are pushing
this because they all want to be your
portal to the rest of the web so they're
doing you a favor in the sense you've
only got one set of credentials to lose
and to manage but they're also trying to
grab you into their ecosystem now in the
enterprise space sam'l is the big winner
so security assertion markup language
it's very much like Open ID Connect by
the enterprise space and enables you how
many of you use sam'l RSS oh I should
say in enterprise I would have expected
more okay so it's fantastic my company
has it amazing thing log in once and
your hundred services or more are all
off the same credentials now phyto UAF
universal dedication framework is
software as well it's in the same suite
of protocols as by those u2f and you can
look at a little bit like SSO in your
pocket your device lets you log into a
bun
services with kind of pre stored keys
and an issue though is how do you do
this between different devices so let's
dedicate a one phone does your tablet
work automatically account recovery I
looked at this before it's a pet peeve
of mine and it's something that is a
mess in my opinion and it gets not
nearly enough attention so today as
nearly as I can figure the best thing
you can do for account recovery is to
answer all those security questions with
completely fake answers and store those
completely fake answers that are long
and random by the way in some other
completely safe place how many people do
that not a hell of a lot so challenge
response essentially account recovery
mechanism is very hard to manage for
users and users are encouraged in fact
you know what's your favorite pet dumb
idea right so as a result service
providers are tending towards preferring
recovery using other mechanisms the
other mechanisms they tend towards are
email and SMS do you think email and SMS
are secure probably not so if you
compromise the email or SMS you've now
compromised many of the accounts that
rely on this mechanism this by the way
recently deprecated the use of SMS for
multi-factor authentication what are
some of the alternatives to this in the
enterprise it's probably not a big deal
because there's help desks and help desk
you know they have ways of
authenticating users in the consumer
space it's a bit more problematic to
come up with good solutions there are
some real-world identity verification
services but you've probably never run
into them so you can you can
authenticate with with a mail service so
the governments of Canada tend to use
that for some things works well take a
few days people don't like that in
Germany they have the post ident system
where you have to go to a post office
to to authenticate yourself and recently
Facebook has created Facebook delegated
account recovery so for github and more
things in the future likely I'll mention
that Fido doesn't cover account recovery
and I want to say that this whole area
needs a lot more attention that it's
getting because authentication you know
everyone looks at that they don't think
about recovery but recovery can take
over your account as easily as bad a
dedication or lost authentication so
it's pretty obvious passwords aren't
perfect why are they still hanging
around so a lot of lower risk lower
value sites have simply no incentive to
movement to move beyond them a more kind
of positive reason is that for
multi-factor authentication you need
multiple factors and and I'm going to
argue more and more as good so something
you know is pretty important you never
want to get rid of that something you
know as one of the factors in your
authentication so what happens if you
cannot use a trusted device for some
reason so you you've lost your phone you
have to log into a public terminal
heaven forbid if you use a friend's
phone friends computer or you live in
part of the world where you have to use
a public terminal maybe you don't have a
cell phone what do you do if you don't
have a trusted device then a device you
own that you're reasonably sure you know
what's happening to it and you can't
store secrets on the device for instance
so it's really important in that case
that will fall back into ekend ism of
passwords I do want to mention some
privacy concerns as well not of
passwords but of some of the
alternatives so with SSO all everything
is tied back to that identity provider
and that does create privacy concerns it
means that more tension as you paid to
this so you need to look at schemes
sometimes called variable authentic
identity so you create pseudonyms for
some types of services you can create
anonym x' public key crypto makes this
possible it makes possible all sorts of
really cool stuff and identity now where
are you still going to need passwords
indicated you can't get rid of them you
don't want to get rid of them where do
you still need them so device passwords
as a fallback to the biometric and
underlying the biometric your device
password is really the thing encrypting
your phone it's the biometrics that are
kind of a key into that now master
passwords as well master passwords
password managers you have TP managers
if you like doing that kind of thing
like Aussie there's debate about that
but that's certainly a valid place for a
master password and of course rested so
you could you could argue that the
password getting you into SSO system is
kind of like a master password is it
matter password I talked about giving
you access to multiple passwords now you
used to you're essentially moving from a
world where you had n passwords like 300
in my case maybe a little bit more to a
few passwords and I want to call those
those end passwords what I call them
forgotten passwords essentially they're
forgettable they're forgotten they're
typically bad passwords with a few good
passwords I want to call those memorized
passwords so they're memorable you make
them memorable you remember them you pay
attention to them I think a really key
point about the first point I didn't
mention this but for device passwords
it's really important to recognize that
a lot of things in the world are
starting to push authentication or
delegated in this end to your device
they'll happily let you use the device
to authenticate the service or second
fact or whatever that means the security
of your device is pretty critical
those services in a sense are letting
your device choose for you you need to
pay attention to that device this is my
second last slide so I want to say
there's no silver bullet for for getting
rid of passwords but you can see that
the trends are all going the right
direction so two trends decreasing
number of passwords you're going from
one password per account to a couple of
master passwords that you guard with
your life well not literally
so Hardware tokens smart devices the UAF
of Phi oh not to be confused with you to
f SS o and o on are all things that are
going to decrease the number of
passwords in your lives and on the other
side there's a whole bunch of things
that are causing you to need to use
passwords less often so password
managers are clearly one of those
because they hide that complexity from
you see OTP will push the you to F of
phyto biometrics definitely and I'll say
a bit more on my ultimate slide and
continuous adaptive authentication as
that grows over time we're still very
early that grows over time
that'll have a big impact on decreasing
number of passwords and asking your
password only when it's really important
for something something critical so some
final thoughts for you don't over rely
on biometrics don't trick don't treat
biometrics as as an absolute truth they
are very far from that and don't misuse
them don't send them across the network
don't store them into database somewhere
bad ideas they're very much ok on your
device on your computer stored locally
and something you control but don't send
them across the network account recovery
definitely pay more attention to this
it's really important that
all aspects of authentication of a
service the rebalance not only the login
portion but also the recovery at the
backend now for businesses I want to
encourage you to not allow users to use
dumb passwords now what's a dumb
password it's certainly one of the top
thousand most use passwords and I'd
argue even the most 10,000 10,000 most
use passwords with bad choices as well
it's great if you can block users from
choosing those passwords and also block
them from choosing otherwise we'd
passwords like too short for instance
for the industry as a whole I talked
about incentives before I would love to
come up with a way to create incentives
for the use of password managers
I'm not saying pasture managers are a
solution to everything but today given
the technology today deployed given the
critical mass and the weight of all the
websites that use password managers desk
you can do today to manage the
complexity for users how do you get to a
point where users want to use a password
manager if you can figure that one out
you should go buy stock in the password
managers and go work for them I haven't
figured it out I - of any thoughts in
the coffee break I would love to hear
them and then the other side of this
essentially how do you create
disincentives for dumb passwords for
companies allowing people to use dumb
passwords how would you encourage all
sides to disallow dumb passwords weak
passwords and even more importantly how
would you ever create a way of
preventing reuse of passwords
if you could create a system that would
prevent reuse of passwords you'd be
solving a lot of problems now I created
one of these myself it so happens if you
go look for my blog you'll find it it's
a little bit controversial but it's
definitely a way of doing it
now on the government side governments
have a mixed record of doing things they
do good they do bad a lot of people in
security automatically dislike
government intervention and redaction
but I want to argue there are some
places like the tragedy of the comments
those market failures where government's
can't have a good role to play so I
would like to find I'd like to see
whether there's a role for governments
in in regulating some aspect of
authentication to help solve some of
these problems you can get a little bit
of a flavor of some of the kind of
thinking Bruce Meyers
recent vlog on thoughts about the need
for regulation in the IOT space I would
encourage you to go read that and if
you're not following should I or
definitely do so that's it that's it for
my presentation
I've left a fair bit of time for for
questions and let's don't forget to wait
for a microphone please I noticed that
some of the canadian banks for instance
force you to use a particular length
password and following a particular
format how on earth could this be
beneficial for the user so i length
I'll repeat that so he's saying more
cannot pass her cannot be longer than
six cannot be shorter than six that
that's pretty plain dumb no idea I never
heard of that one I can't even see
there's a lot of legacy things right so
oh can someone give them my key
this is really interesting so part of
the reason you do that is so that the
users don't reuse passwords if you have
a completely different password format
you prevent somebody from using their
Facebook password on the bank security
risks the bank face are not password
guessing because like you said we detect
any sort of multiple attempt so that's
not where the whole is effectively thank
you I'm glad we could get that answered
that's really interesting so that's
trying to work around the problem of as
mentioned before with the vast majority
of people out in the real world not in
this room don't use password managers
trying to work around that quite an
interesting solution
my company has a nerf cube with a
microphone in it and we toss it around
to speakers for questioners pretty
interesting yes please hi thanks for the
talk I'm just wondering if if we're
using password managers could we not
just give people the password instead of
saying make up your own password and
then it's gonna have your dog's name or
whatever just here's the password that
you should use and it's you know 32
characters long and very random that's a
fantastic question
so you recall I was talking about my
blood exercise what if everyone had a
password manager could you somehow start
using TLS client certs instead of
passwords it would open up all sorts of
new ways of looking at things and this
in fact is one of them rather than
hoping users who choose a long password
complex you'd give it to them and of
course you know it sounds nice right I'd
love it because I use a passive manager
religiously most users would would croak
on that would definitely find another
website to use they never go back so
it's it's part of the chicken leg that I
talked about again you until you have
the critical mass you can't do these
things and without with the critical
mass you can't get there it's a it's a
no-win situation requires a bit of
intelligent thinking any more questions
yes so I mean this is a literacy issue
as soon as the users can be educated to
the ramifications of using weak
passwords they will then be invested in
not doing so so being able to at least
have a parsley shoulder the burden of
responsibility is the key here and
because this plays such an impactful
role across so many different services
in our society then there are a number
of different bodies from organizational
to governmental that can actually help
to raise the level of literacy around
the need for robust passwords so why are
we kind of granted we're expecting the
users to be lazy or
unwilling etc but that is actually where
we can be most impactful instead of
trying to enforce some sort of mechanism
yes so did you guys hear that yeah okay
so I'm not very hopeful about the
ability to educate users too or give in
to them to start using password managers
and good password hygiene and good
device I Aegina and all those things I
honestly don't know how you would ever
do that
you could issue everybody at birth with
a little implanted you know implanted
token with their certificate but that
might have problems as well I can't
imagine how you'd ever educate users I'd
love to see that I've often thought I
talked about government action I've
often thought that government should be
doing more to educate people just like
you said but it's interesting I'm not
aware of any governments that have
really done that in any serious way and
I'm not holding my breath
any more questions
this is possibly kind of an edge case in
terms of past reviews but kind of
recently there's been reports of you
know crossing borders into the US where
some will ask you for your Facebook
password so what's the interplay there
is like oh I have a specific password
for Facebook versus let me login to last
test and get my Facebook password it's
like oh no give me that too so I can
look at all of your passwords and kind
of how do you can you think of that so
might be ways to mitigate those
circumstances that's a really
interesting one you know you guys
probably all know I mean I read every
single article article I can find about
border crossings and impacts and
troubles the the big think remembered a
border crossing is you have very few
rights at least in the short term so to
do that yes very interesting question if
you tell the guy I can't log into pacer
at Facebook I don't remember the
password Oh login your password manager
no problem however there is another way
luckily there are cookies left on your
mobile device hopefully so that you can
get into Facebook without having to be
authentic 8 so it's sure make sure
you're authenticated to Facebook before
you cross the border or and more
importantly make sure you don't get
called in to secondary screening that I
don't see any more questions
okay there is one so some of the
discussion makes me think of No Child
Left Behind because some people don't
really want to use Internet services I
mean I'm not snobby but you know when
internet banking came on I was right not
to but not everybody is like that so
you're talking about kind of getting a
critical mass and things like that for
better practitioners I think client-side
certificates been around for forever
um but I don't know it maybe it's just a
comment like good luck with that because
not everybody has planned to use the
services that they've been given or need
to use right
yeah so I do know one person in the
world who has no internet services it's
my mother I lied actually she has email
now because I set it up for but that's
it her iPad has no password she wouldn't
know how to log in a website or for life
depended on it but other people I'd say
on the whole people are slowly getting
into it I think it's really important to
not forget all the privacy issues as
technology goes forward the world goes
forward privacy tends to fall by the
wayside you want to find solutions that
enable privacy I mentioned before I
think I touched on it very briefly
couples with SSO for instance the
identity provider is always tying things
back to you I'm guessing that even in a
hundred years with technology that none
of us can fathom I'm guessing there's
going to be password still to access you
know certain types of dark web dish type
accounts that you want to have no
ability for anyone to tie to anything
I don't think passwords are going away I
think that they will always have some
kind of value both kind of on the
privacy enhancing side and on the side
of enhancing just the other factors I
think that maybe it's one work okay you
seem to be a big proponent of the
password managers and I you know I I'm
not against them I have lots of clients
who use them and they're definitely
better than nothing personally I'm a bit
of a dinosaur so the the whole threat of
it of having a single point of failure
has kept me away from them in my own use
because over the years I've developed
sort of a rolling password algorithm
that I found that works really well and
I'm happy with it and I just haven't
made the jump so the my question is you
know can you convince me and someone who
sort of knows what's going on
you know is a password manager better
than whatever system that I've got that
you know I can't teach all users to you
so you know for those people yeah
absolutely use the pasture manager but
you know my wife all the people are
close to me I've talked to no use decent
algorithms and how to you know keep them
non guessable even if somebody gets a
decent sample of them is that better or
should I still be looking more seriously
into a password manager so I want to be
clear pasture managers are not the
be-all end-all but I think today they're
the best we're going to do for the vast
majority of cases and users so so that's
being the case I I didn't touch on in my
presentation something that kind of
underlies my thinking and a lot of
subjects and it's the word resilience
and resilience means that no matter what
happens you can kind of come back from
it and in the case of case of passwords
password managers you want to keep in
mind resilience as well as privacy
obviously and security so password
managers you want to look for one that
zero knowledge and if you don't know is
ear o knowledge is pretty interesting
concept the idea is that everything is
encrypted at your end only time it ever
gets to the network is after it's been
encrypted and the keys for that
encryption don't get to the network
either so any good password manager
today the big ones they're all zero
knowledge very very important if anyone
even walks into their data centers takes
all the hard drives off and spends a lot
of time trying to decrypt them they're
not going to get anything and from
Brasilians point of view so that's
that's because to protection essentially
of your information the risks then are
not at the server side they're not the
servant side assuming is properly
implemented and a lot of those companies
do bug bounties and adopt the risks
right your device and in fact in
security the risks are usually at the
end device and from resilience point of
view putting stuff in the cloud
increases your resilience and that's
true with any service really there's
obviously issues to be addressed but the
cloud gives you resilience and my
passwords are synced between all my
devices one of my devices doesn't work I
go to the other one to help recover that
device
while I was preparing this presentation
my home computer crapped out totally
we're talking it wouldn't respond to
control-alt-delete what the hell so I
needed my recovery password for
BitLocker because what you know what
paranoid security guy wouldn't use
BitLocker how do they get that recovery
password pull up my phone it's it's
there through my password manager that
gives me resilience gives me the ability
to sufferin to come back from you know
issues with with computing environments
and I can also of course use it offline
as well if the cloud goes down my
devices keep working with my password
manager there's a question here yeah I
think one of the important things is
that you don't necessarily use the same
set of recovery mechanisms do you treat
all of your data in your passwords
differently so your bitcoins would be
recoverable in a different way than your
hugging at work or on a website certain
things might be stored in a password
manager other things you might store a
key that you can use to decrypt decrypt
the printed password that you keep
around and you keep the second half of
that at your mom's house yes DZ that
goes to resilience the more
knowledgeable you are about IT and
security in general I would argue the
more forms of backup you have of all
things not only your data but your
passwords your keys your tokens and
indeed you don't want to rely on any one
thing if you have multiple things ways
the back things up you're better off of
course
you now increase the probability of
losing it one of those things or using
them so infrequently you forget how they
work or they stopped working but it's
always a trade-off resilience is very
important that our I would argue you
should always consider that in anything
you do
including
occasion going once going twice sold
thank you very much it's really a
pleasure
[Applause]