so sittin come and surprise I'm novices
Oh hopefully never will be and so this
is a rather technical talk if you're
Sissel you're probably in over your head
okay good it's good if I haven't scared
anyone away yet um so what I'm going to
talk about today how to use electronic
equipment apparently so increasingly
compiler writers are taking advantage of
undefined behaviors in C and C++
programming languages to improve
optimizations I've been participating on
the C Standards Committee since about
2004 so I actually was involved in C the
development of C 11 from start to end
which has recently occurred to me that
now I'm sort of responsible in a way for
for C and and you know during that time
we like to think the language is getting
better but more secure but actually it's
becoming less secure because the still
the the biggest driver for the evolution
of C language is opportunity for greater
optimization and less well defined the
languages the more opportunity you have
to optimize it you know so I frequently
get into these discussions where we're
saying you know you know if six turns
out to be nine do you care how fast you
got that result and apparently they do
so so frequently these optimizations
tend to interfere with the ability of
developers or security analysts or
security tools to really analyze the
code and determine what it's doing right
and so what happens is there's code that
looks like it's there it looks like it's
doing something but it's actually being
removed from the compiler and then it
becomes very difficult for humans or
source Canales tool that's not
implementation specific to analyze the
behavior so this is leading
to increase faults and software and
those are leading to increased
vulnerabilities there we go set the
wrong direction so um so some years ago
i authored this vulnerability note with
a chad dougherty at cert this was april
2008 this was quite a while ago and this
was about GCC but maybe the last two
weeks
there was the exact same sort of
vulnerability was noted in the clang
compiler so i'm not sure if it took them
nine years to catch up with how bad GCC
is or they you know people just got
around to noticing but some of these
open source compilers are sort of the
wild west of compilers and I'll chat a
little bit more about why that's the
case um yep still going to run way so
undefined behaviors so I you know when I
joined the C Committee my goal was to
make more or C a more secure language
and then you know to change C to make it
more secure and of course what happened
was that C wound up changing me instead
and and really you know it's a very it's
a very bright group of people who are
involved in C Standards Committee and if
you give to give a very great group of
people the set of requirements that they
were given they produce a C language you
know if you give them a different set of
requirements they produce Java right but
but C is the language that you get given
given the goals they had and undefined
behaviors you know although this is sort
of misunderstood or they're not there by
accident they are intentionally put
there and you know the idea is that
there because they belong there but one
of the mistakes I think the committee
made was the this term undefined
behavior is actually too broad because
it encompasses really three completely
different kinds of things so the first
one is it gives the implementers license
not to catch certain kinds of errors
that are difficult to diagnose and it's
the one thing about the committee it's
weensy standards written by C developers
of C compiler vendors for C compiler
vendors and they don't like to be
particularly hard on each other
so kind of like oh hey Jeff it's too
rough you know don't worry about it go
home have dinner with your wife you know
no problem so so but this is also meant
because there are you know there cases
that our NP complete or np-hard that
just take too much processing to you
know be you know to always know that
you're going to diagnose a problem so
consequently these compilers not
required to diagnose these problems the
second ones to avoid defining obscure
corner cases okay so it turns out let's
say you have int min smallest signed
integer number most negative number and
you take the remainder after dividing by
minus one okay can't tell me what result
you get okay large negative number
divided by minus one what's the
remainder anybody you're thinking this
log you're thinking too hard ciara you
say zero
yeah you get zero okay you divide
something I minus one there's zero
things left over kind of the same thing
as dividing by one okay on an Intel
processor if you do that what you get is
a segmentation fault okay
and in in c99 that was what was called
implicit undefined behavior so it was
undefined behavior but they didn't tell
you about it and so for c11 you know I
submitted a proposal and we discussed it
in committing we want up modifying the
language to make an explicit undefined
behavior and the reason is the C
committee doesn't want to publish people
who write code for the Intel platform to
make them add an extra test to test for
this edge condition because that would
slow down their compilers and the result
of that is the burden of doing these
checks kind of gets deferred to the
programmer so that's the second reason
the third reason is to identify areas of
possible possible conforming language
extension so here for example when you
an F open on a file there's a few
different modes that you can specify and
if you specify anything else is
undefined behavior okay so if you put a
Y in as a mode you know do you think
it's going to crash
absolutely not right so the reason they
did that was you know the standard has
to run on a variety of platforms file
systems have a lot of inconsistencies
and different features that aren't
available in all platforms so that's a
mechanism to allow implementations to
extend the behavior of their
implementation to match the file system
so that's a third completely different
reason but they're all classifieds
undefined behavior and a compiler can
ignore undefined behavior completely
with unpredictable results typically the
Committee will say the compiler can go
out and play the game of life at that
point and that's allowed for by the
standard the second is behave in a
documented manner characters the
environments example when you say int
main remainder minus one on Intel
platform it characteristically false
that's the behavior of that platform
that's a loud behavior or it could
terminate translation or execution with
the diagnostic that's that's the most
you could hope for so the the basic
concept the basic design of an
optimizing compiler for C is largely the
same as for any other language basically
you try to replace computations with
more efficient methods that produce the
same result so so some so here's the you
know gross oversimplification I have
some optimizations limonade undefined
behaviors we'll call those the good
optimizations and then we have the ones
that introduce vulnerabilities and we
call those the bad optimizations oh by
the way I worked with this I used to
work with David keen who's the chair of
the C standards can be now that convener
of the international standards committee
and he he didn't like the fact that I
called this talk dangerous optimizations
he thought I should just called it
optimizations and that's a little window
into the mindset of people in the C
committee okay so so the C standard
specifies the results of the computation
as if on an abstract machine but doesn't
specify the methods that are used so in
the abstract machine the semantics have
to closely follow what this
specification says
but an actual implementation doesn't
have to you know reproduce all the same
steps if it can conduce that you know
for example values not need it or that
there's no side effects occurring that
would require you know that code to be
executed so basically the compilers
optimizers free to choose any method
that produces the correct result so so
this gives the compiler the leeway to
remove cause that's deemed unused or
unneeded when building a program and
this is typically referred to at the as
if rule because the program has to it
has to run as if it we're executing on
the abstract machine but it doesn't have
to follow all the exact methods and
occasionally you'll you'll see a little
bit of you know you'll see two places in
the standard you'll see a volatile with
volatile and with memset underbar s
where there's language in the standard
that says must operate you know
according to the rules of the abstract
machine so those are two places where
the standard says that you know you
can't use the as if rule doesn't apply
you have to implement the semantics
exactly so as volatile for example if
you say x equals x and x is volatile
qualified you need to read the variable
x and then you need to write the
variable x back out but if that was
involved to qualify that code would be
optimized out for sure
okay so compiler vendors use various
implementation strategies one strategies
hardware behavior where you basically
generate the assembly code and you let
the hardware do whatever the hardware
does and for many years that was kind of
how C worked so you know the people in
the room with the grey hair the white
hair the no hair
probably have been exposed to that type
of programming another model super debug
where you trap any undefined behavior
great for debugging very impractical for
deploying code because it has
significant slowdowns and third is total
license and total license you can treat
any possible undefined behaviors that
can't happen condition which allows you
to optimize out Optima
aggressively so just to start with a
simple one constant folding is the
process of simplifying constant
expressions at compile time
so cost expression x' can be simple
literal such as the integer two
variables are never modified or
variables that are explicitly marked as
constant so again to go back to my old
example if you get your Intel processor
out and you say it man
remainder -1 you print the results as 0
and that gives you a sort of a
misleading sense of warmth that your
your your implementation is going to
produce a 0 result but what's happening
in this case is that int main remainder
1 is a cost expression so it's actually
the compiler that we places that with a
0 so there's no runtime code being
generated so if you were to replace this
code oh I think I have so here's a
here's this code compiled on Microsoft
Visual Studio with optimization disabled
so you know these these optimizations
are so automatic that you cannot disable
them they just happen and you can see
that we're just pushing 0 onto the stack
and printing it out so there's no
division operation of being generated
here so if you actually want to see
what's happening you have to use sort of
non-deterministic values and then you
can see that we're going to generate an
idea of instruction which will now fault
when you provide it min and minus 1 is
the arguments so so a little lesson here
is that when you're writing these little
tests to test behavior
be very careful that the program is
doing something otherwise the compiler
is very very likely to optimize out your
little test and you're not going to be
testing what you think you were testing
um ok so this is the this is the kind of
the major voll that I'm going to chat
about this is the one that Chad and I
published back in 2008 but you know it's
I mean the thing is it's not really bold
this is how the compiler works that
still works this way today so when you
read the C standard there's a clause
that says when an expression that has
endured type is added to or subtracted
from point
the result has a type of the pointer
operand so that's basically just
defining pointer arithmetic and array
indexing notation is is sort of a
syntactic veneer for point arithmetic if
you index an array P at index n it's
just going to expand to 2p plus and
scaled for the size of the element type
and then be referenced so C goes further
to say
I got a laser pointy thing on here I can
remember here we are so what this
paragraph says is that you can form this
pointer dereference this value and you
can form every pointer up to here and
you can dereference this value and the c
standard requires that you can form this
pointer okay this is well-defined
behavior the C standard has to support
the formation this pointer but if you
dereference this value it's undefined
behavior and if you form this next
pointer it's also undefined behavior so
what the c standard allows is that you
can form the one to four pointer the too
far pointer and the reason for that was
in the early days of c programming
people wrote loops where they
incremented the pointer and then test it
to see if it was this one and then
stopped the loop and so the state of
standards committee decided to allow
that behavior and and so it's now
enshrined in the language okay so so a
typical thing a c programmer might do if
they've taken my you know secure coding
in c and c++ course is they might decide
you know we should be concerned about
buffer overflows because they've got
unintended consequences so to do that
you might have a say a pointer to the
beginning of array pointer to the end of
the rain you might have a size which you
would express as a size the argument not
an int and part of my secure coding
course I have one day committed to
talking about integers so if you you
ever have time for that
explain why it needs to be side t but
the easy thing is just to declare it
size D for now and so we'll do a test to
see if pointer plus Len is greater than
max that means we're trying to to
reference a location beyond the bounds
of the array and so we'll return an
error condition that case but no matter
what your implementation is what your
model is there's a bug in this code
which is for very large values of Len
point applause Len can wrap around which
would create undefined behavior and
under the hardware behavior model the
result would typically wrap around and
point to an address is actually lower in
memory than pointer okay so to fix the
bug an experienced programmer who sort
of internalize this hardware behavior
model of undefined behavior might add a
test where they test to see if pointer
plus Len is less the pointer to detect
the the wraparound behavior okay so the
reason I said experienced programmer
there and I'll give you a little more
insight into the C Standards Committee
okay say you're trying to get a feature
or something change in the C standard
the best way to do that is say you know
hey I work for Intel and we've just add
this vectorized instruction but there's
no way to to use it from C code can we
modify the C language so that
programmers can use our new vectorized
instruction and they'll say yes because
the C standard very you know they like
to support hardware you know that's the
purpose is to give you access to the
hardware okay the second thing you could
do is you can go and say you know we've
noticed that naive programmers
frequently make the following error
right and it turns out the C standard
can make does not give a shit about
naive programmers okay so that argument
doesn't fly at all you know we had an
hour discussion about some behavior
where no one in the committee knew the
answer we had to spend an hour kind of
going back and forth to we could sort
out how something worked and then a guy
from Cisco who doesn't have a compiler
he's got a bunch of developers said and
you expect developers know this and it
in unison entirely said yes absolutely
so if you come to them and you say you
know an experienced programmer such as
yourself might make this mistake you've
got a chance of them listen to you so
that's that's why it was couched in
those B terms so so a compiler that
follows a total license model like GCC
and now clang may optimize out the first
part of this check leaving the bounds to
feed it okay so the reason for this is
because if a pointer plus an unsigned
Len compares less than pointer then
undefined behavior has occurred okay so
the the exact undefined behavior that
has occurred is that you know if I take
a pointer to this array and I add a size
and now I'm checking to see if it
wrapped around without a doubt I just
try to form a pointer which was outside
the bounds of the array and by this
language and the standard that makes
that undefined behavior okay so this
this code invokes undefined behavior you
know so consequently the the compiler
can assume undefined behavior doesn't
occur and it can remove that code is
dead code okay
so that sounds bad but then you know
when you look at it he starts to see how
this comes about right so what's going
on here the optimization is called
algebraic simplification which you know
sounds like something we all did in
sixth grade algebra so the the
optimization says that optimization may
be may be perform for comparisons
between P and V 1 and P and V 2 where P
is the same pointer and V 1 and V 2 are
integer variables and so total license
model allows that to be reduced to
comparison between V 1 and V 2
however if v1 or v2 overflow when add it
to P the results of comparing those two
values directly is not the same as doing
the arithmetic and then doing the
comparison and so the one of the fun
things about digital arithmetic is that
because of possible overflows computer
arithmetic doesn't always obey
the algebraic identities of mathematics
so you know so it does there is Matt
there are mathematical models that
describe digital arithmetic but they're
not the ones you learned in sixth grade
okay so if you go back to our example
what you'll see is this expression
pointer plus a little lesson pointer is
the same we can add zero to the right
hand expression without changing that
and now basically we have a comparison
of P plus v1 compared to P plus v2 this
can be simplified to a comparison
between v1 and v2 and lend cannot be
less than zero because Len is unsigned
so consequently this code doesn't do
anything and the compiler removes it
okay and are consequently our you know
our balance check has been defeated okay
so once you're aware of this problem
it's actually quite simple to fix so so
if you know that pointer is less than or
equal to max which we do in this case
because pointer points beginning the Ray
max points at the end you can just
subtract a pointer from both sides and
compare to see if Len is greater than
maximize pointer so this wraparound
because max is greater than pointer and
consequently there is no undefined
behavior here and the compiler is
required to evaluate this expression at
runtime to generate the code and
evaluate the expression so so this code
will always succeed and it's a very easy
fix to make but you know developers are
know is aware of this and in fact this
particular defect occurred in some in
the plan nine code written at Bell Labs
so you know when I say experienced
programmers make this mistake you know
those guys are pretty pretty experienced
okay so thanks to the magic of Google
and the internet you can google the
history of this on like the GCC devilís
and you'll see that a lot of people said
a lot of bad things to me without try to
or this problem on the GCT devilís so
you know one thing that developers came
back with was they said well hey if you
have something like this this actually
works your advantage because it'll
simplify this to comparison between N
and 100 and that eliminates a possible
wraparound in both those expressions so
this this would the obstetrician here
would eliminate undefined behaviors that
makes it a good optimization in this
case is probably not a big deal unless
one expression wraps but not the other
so but you know you don't you don't want
to ship this code and the reason you
don't want to ship this code is because
optimizations are optional right they're
not required you don't want to depend on
an optimization to make your code
correct and so as a developer what you'd
want to do is perform this
simplification yourself and and ship
this code so and not rely on the
compiler to make your code correct now
the other thing I'll say is you know a
lot of developers would spot this code
but frequently the problem is that this
sort of thing is hidden in macros so
it's not apparent when you look at the
source code it's not it's not apparent
this is happening until you see the
macro expansion no questions so far I
scared a couple people away they're like
wait a second I'm a CISO and this guy is
speaking some odd language I don't
understand okay so the behavior points
are overflow change as of the following
versions of the compiler I believe we're
now on GCC seven one so this has
happened a while ago but one of the
things you'll see here is that this
changed in a maintenance release okay
and and when you look at when you look
at portability behaviors undefined
making implementation defined
unspecified behavior and undefined
behaviors are all portability issues but
undefined behavior is the most severe
right because there is no specification
of that behavior and so the compiler can
do whatever it wants right and
and and you know I say a lot of things
that sound like compiler writers evil
but they're they're you know they're
trying to do the best they can for your
codebase right so so usually what
they're doing is when they see undefined
behavior they take a guess as to what
maybe you were after right and but if
they guess wrong if their guest doesn't
meet your expectations then you're going
to have a defect and the other thing
that happens is undefined behaviors is
that you know compiler writers look at
these as opportunities for optimizations
and so when they you know when they're
done writing optimizations they'll
release it is part of a maintenance
release and if your code had undefined
behaviors it may have worked previously
and now it might might fail because the
compiler now deals with that undefined
behavior differently so this particular
optimizations perform by default and Oh
to nabob include optimizing for space
not performed Oh 100 0 it can be enabled
with a strict overflow option or
disabled 402 and above with the no
strict overflow option the only way you
could okay so here's how this
optimization came about there's a guy
named Ian Lance Taylor and he's at
Google and he implemented this
optimization okay and of all the people
on the GCC dev list you know he was the
only one who didn't you know scream with
me he was the only one who had like a
rational conversation with me and and
basically okay here's Google's kind of
deal right they have a few applications
they run a lot okay so they have these
farms and computers and they looked at
you know they looked at this
optimization then they discovered but we
could get a half percent improvement
that would allow us to get rid and we
know our code doesn't have this error
right and they'll give us a half percent
improvement we could get rid of this
number of machines and save four hundred
thousand dollars a year right so it
looks really good to them to do this
optimization so they do it and then
everyone else gets this and your
codebase maybe does have this problem
right so so we had discussion with Ian
and base
they they kept this optimization end
right but what we agreed was that they
they set a flag - sorry - to notify you
that the optimization was being
performed so what you can do now is you
can set strict overflow equals n where n
is greater than or equal to 3 and now
the compiler will warn when this
optimization is taking place now the
problem is this is not included in wall
okay and probably the only way you would
find out about this is if you came to my
talk and if you came to my talk you
probably know not to have this undefined
behavior so so today this is still you
know a pretty significant problem okay
so there's a bunch of GCC options F
strict overflow allows the compiler to
assume strict signed overflow behavior
signed arithmetic overflow undefined
behavior so the compiler will assume
that it doesn't happen and that permits
aggressive optimization so for example
if you write I plus penny greater than I
the compiler would just assume that's
always true for any sign value I and of
course that's only true if that that
expression doesn't wrap around so when
this option is in effect any attempt to
determine okay so this is kind of a key
to this you know so most the worst code
is code that's written for security
either by developers or by security
folks okay and part of the reason is
it's it's very easy to invoke undefined
behavior when you're testing for
undefined behavior right so you kind of
say hey does this undefined behavior
exist and the compiler says oh he's just
invoke undefined behavior and they take
your tests away so your test disappears
so when you're writing tests for
undefined behavior for security
vulnerabilities you have to be very
careful not to invoke undefined behavior
so FV instructs GCC to
assume that signed arithmetic overflow
of addition subtraction multiplication
will wrap around so it's similar to no
strict overflow and it will disable
optimizations assume integer overflow
behaviors undefined so this is the
option that was enabled for the Java
front-end as required by the Java
language specification so Java language
Java language only has signed integers
and the sign integers have well-defined
wraparound behavior in C you have
unsigned integers which have
well-defined wraparound behavior and you
have sign into you have signed integers
which have undefined behavior on
overflow and of course now she doesn't
have a Java front-end anymore it just
got removed as of 71
okay so strict over 4 equals n this of
course only applies when strict overflow
is active right so in other words this
flag to diagnose this problem this
optimization is only going to be
triggered when you're performing the
optimization so if you so you have to
make sure that you're optimizing your
code in order to detect these
optimization errors so there's three
warning levels so an optimization which
assumes find overflow doesn't occur SATA
yeah this is always kind of the promisee
right so one of the premises of the C
languages trust the programmer right and
and a good example that is say you take
an INT and you assign it to a short
write the compiler will look at that and
think huh that looks pretty dodgy right
I mean clearly you can't store all the
values that we represent as an int in a
short but we're going to trust the
programmer and we're going to trust that
the programmer knows that the range of
values being stored in this integer can
be represented as a short we're going to
go ahead and make that conversion and
the same thing is true with these this
code right these expressions don't
necessarily overflow it depends
on the the values that they take so at a
setting of one it will warn about cases
that are both questionable and easy to
avoid such as X plus 1 greater than X
with strict overflow the compiler will
simplify this to 1 and this is the the
only level you that's enabled by wall
higher levels aren't and have to be
explicitly requested so strict air flow
equals to will tell you about other
cases where comparisons simplify to a
constant so for example if you take the
absolute value of a signed integer value
it will be turning negative values for
you know the most negative so if you say
absolute value of int men the answers
int men you get the same negative value
back and that's because on a to stop the
the negation of in men so level 3 is the
also one of other cases we're comparing
as simple comparison simplified for
example X plus 1 greater than Y being
simplified to X greater than 0 and this
is the lowest warning level which will
warn on the specific optimization I was
describing earlier that eliminates the
bounds check strict overflow because 4
will also warn on other simplifications
like this arithmetic simplification
which I would think in almost all cases
you would want to have this and then 5
you know will warn about cases where the
compiler reduces the magnitude so so
we've some of the work I've done in the
C Standards Committee we we introduced a
C analyze ability annex into the C 11
standard it's a normative but optional
annex so not everyone has to implement
it I know for certain the Oracle you
know the old Sun C compiler guys they're
implementing those annex so what we did
was we defined we added a couple
definitions so we defined out about
store and we found defined
undefined behavior as undefined behavior
that doesn't perform an out of bounds
store and then we define the term
critical undefined behavior was which is
basically the old-style critical and
defined behavior so there are by the way
200 explicit undefined behaviors in the
C language and all 200 of them used to
be critical and defined behaviors so the
requirement is that basically besides a
short list of critical undefined
behaviors all undefined behaviors have
to be bounded undefined behaviors if
your compiler implements an Excel and so
now instead they're being 200 undefined
behaviors you have to worry about
writing out of bounds you're limited to
nine and the nine are are this
particular list the sorts of things that
usually result in that okay so to kind
of wrap this up and I the wrap-up here
sometimes my recommendation surprises
people at the end of this which is okay
ignore undefined behaviors that's not a
surprise you know having undefined
behavior in your code doesn't mean your
code is wrong but it means that you know
the compiler can change and in a future
version of your code might be wrong and
so it's best not to depend on undefined
behaviors I would recommend trying to
find and eliminate dead code instead of
letting the compiler do it so if you can
use a strict overflow flag to indicate
it's rewriting the code because there's
undefined behavior like that example of
you know n plus 100 compared to you know
n plus 3 or whatever you know do they do
the simplification yourself so you're
not relying on the compiler to do the
optimization so so we've seen that some
optimizations can eliminate undefined
behaviors while others will introduce
vulnerabilities so a lot of you know
security people who don't quite know
what they're talking about will you know
well first you know most a lot of people
will ignore this completely right
know anything about this but then you
learn a little bit about it and then you
think we should have enforced wraparound
behavior and frankly that's not the
recommendation I would give and the
reason is because you're turning off all
the optimizations and many of those
optimizations are fixing your code and
some of those optimizations are breaking
your code but generally speaking if you
just turn them off your code is going to
get worse in terms of quality and
security and it's going to get slower at
the same time so my recommendation is go
ahead and build optimized code but turn
on the warning flag to find out where
the compiler is doing these
optimizations for you and take a look
and if it's optimizing on the assumption
that's different than your assumption
your assumptions wrong if you need to
revise your code and finally you know
tell your vendor to implement an excel
and use it because it's cool and finally
the C standard is a contract between
compiler writers and programmers but
really only compiler writers show up for
these and me and the guy from Cisco and
so we've had votes that have been 32 to
where Cisco you know Cisco and me vote
the same way and everyone else is
against us and and sometimes that reason
is because well that's hard to do you
know so they don't want to do it so the
contracts continually being amended and
you know less more security cautious
group sort of get involved the tendency
is to is to eliminate guarantees from
the standard it's kind of like you know
getting divorce from your spouse and
telling your spells to you know just
handle the divorce and you'll be happy
whatever the outcome is you know that's
not going to work out good for you my
friend okay so I'm done take some
questions
yes sir yeah
um yeah I teach it conferences I did a
three-day course here on secure coding
in Java but we also come on site and
deliver on site and the on-site
deliveries are generally more popular
just because it's easier to fly me
somewhere that needs to fly 30 people to
a conference but yeah let me know and we
can come come to your site and deliver
that for you sir how the compilers tend
to be so other compilers I haven't
looked at all of them
you know I now know that clang behaves
similarly you know Visual Studio for
however much people hate Microsoft I
mean they're they're a little bit more
reasonable because they they're
controlled by one vendor they don't have
this wild-west where everyone's looking
out for their own interests sort of
thing so yeah so it's kind of you have
to look you know I mean I'll tell you
I'll tell you some other like random
frightening things but you know when you
get a C compiler it it will happen
there'll be an implementation a set of
flags where it conforms to the standard
it might not be the default set of flags
so you know the out-of-the-box compiler
you use might be non conforming to the C
standard you know so some of those
compilers do really wacky things
the IBM compiler actually treats
unsigned integers is unwrap arounds
undefined behavior which is a violation
of the standard so by default it behaves
in a non-conforming mode but they
basically you know these compilers grow
up with their users and their code bases
and they're sort of designed to work
with the code that's you know uses these
compilers to for compilation under the
questions sir this is a problem
generally for static analysis tools
because a lot of static analysis tools
work for multiple different platforms
right so they can sell it more widely
and
so it's kind of very difficult for them
to know what the specific optimizations
are that different compilers are
performing so this class of problems
frequently not diagnosed and that was
actually my first slide that these
optimizations really make it hard for
human analysts static analysis or you
know anything else to detect and
certainly you know the thing that
irritates me the most about all of this
is you know when the compiler vendor
says hey this is undefined
I can optimize here they know it's
undefined they could generate a warning
at that point but usually they don't so
you have to kind of bug them to like
this GCC case to go back and add the
warning so anyone's even being notified
that the undefined behaviors there I
mean they know it's there and they're
not frequently not diagnosing it sorry
oh yeah so you should look at your
warnings I mean so I I've had a lot of
customers who are going to go buy
fortify or Coverity of some expensive
analysis tool but they aren't you know
they don't have their warning level set
and aren't paying attention to the
warnings I have done a study while I was
at CMU and and really the compilers are
more effective at diagnosing these type
of problems than the analysis tools so
before you go you know I think you know
you should use static analysis tools but
before you buy them you know set your
warning level to the highest level and
address those warnings and you know
address them smartly because they're a
lot of people go in and say well if I
click cast all over the place it will
shut the warnings up ok now your codes
worse than it was before because you
have all the same problems but now
you're not getting Diagnostics anymore
okay any other questions that's fun come
on done No yeah yep
um you know it's so it's a little bit of
give and take you know I mean so there
are places where guarantees are weakened
I'll give you a quick example when you
read on initialize memory now this
committees introduce a concept of wobbly
values right so that means that every
time you read a uninitialized value you
can get a different value so you could
have an express you can say if X do this
and then and it will do it and then down
below you can say if not X do this and
it would do that too because if it's
uninitialized it can now vary every time
you read it so so that's an area where
the language is becoming less defined
but you know we've added an excact
interfaces those are nice secure
functions
you know we've added memset underbar s
which can't be optimized out so it lets
you say clear passwords from memory
before you pass that memory to free
normally if you just say mem set and
then free that memphis' always optimize
out because it's a dead code store and
developers don't realize that whenever
you see memset followed by free it's
basically a vulnerability because
they're trying to clear it out but it's
not going to happen so yeah it's back
and forth but you know basically you
need to just you know you just need to
know how the language works and
programmed correctly well yeah I mean
there's this no there's no substitute
for knowledge okay anyone else I'm
having fun so yes sir
oh well I think what I was trying to say
with those slides is is that you if you
want to test for the existence of these
optimizations you need to do two things
one is you need to have the strict
overflow flag set and you also need to
have the optimizations being performed
so you have to set strict overflow on or
set knops a high optimization level so
it's going to optimize the code in order
to get the Diagnostics so we just set
strict overflow and hit optimization 0
you owe the order doesn't matter but you
need to specify both if it's not
optimizing it won't diagnose the
optimizations ok any of the questions
you are recording all this right that's
good
I'm out now I'm running back in my head
it's like who died and sold Google
mm-hmm any other questions
ok thanks for that info Cisco track I
think for the weekend
Thanks thank you very much
[Applause]