welcome everybody it's quite uh quite
late already
so that's focus on continuous catch and
security assessment of inspect so first
questions first like who knows what in
Figgis we need to improve that so we
you've been talking a lot about the ICD
pipelines and we have really been
focusing on on anything regarding like
code to a bill so now like this is not
all right so we deployed into an
infrastructure so deploy it into
something that actually runs our
application so how are we actually sure
that everything that runs in our
infrastructure is configured according
to our plan so that's what we are
talking about today so think about
inspect focusing more on infrastructure
when you deploy your application instead
of like being as part of like code
checking tool so I'm in the industry for
about like 8 to 10 years I started at
Deutsche Telekom NS AP and we really
started with OpenStack automating
OpenStack do it all and then automated
me but if you're like working for big
tacko you have big regulations as well
so you have like those paper documents
hundreds of pages how you have to harden
your server which is neat but it's not
really cool if you're starting a cloud
environment with you want to scale quick
and so that's not that's not working out
so we figured there's a there's a gap
and we started a company called volcano
stack which is really was focusing on
how can I oughta mate compliance
requirements which is essentially
allowed inspect and our our company
you've got acquired by chef and I'm
heading the complete environment
engineering of that whole kit now so
when we talk about when you talk about
security we also need to talk about
compliance and we need to be remembered
like why is that even important and
we've seen a couple of things happening
in the past
or big companies have not behaved in a
good way as we consider it give me so
this is still happening so there are
like security risks all over but then we
see like there's a loophole like the
exploration this is scandal and there's
regulation so we can all complain about
regulations but essentially they're or
are intended to improve the greater good
still like mostly it's a lot of paper
documents and it's really hard to apply
those regulations in your environment so
people are normally and not really
complaining about the regulation but how
difficult it is to apply those
regulations so let's see how can we can
make this better but just to give you an
overview there are a lot so there are a
lot of regulations and if you're like in
multinational company it's very likely
that you have to cover multiple at the
same point in time even if they have an
overlap so when we talk about compliance
to we need to understand that compliance
and security are not necessarily the
same thing so they're like compliance
essentially is the wording up ok this is
the expected state so this is something
that I define that should be that should
be right but saying my user account name
is all lowercase is also a compliance
rule but it's not necessarily a security
rule but if compliance is done right it
deftly like it should improve like this
security as well
so we quickly go over it you know it
like there are like the the basic
vulnerabilities are well known and so we
see two aspects here as law which is
essentially like security Mis
configuration and also like components
of known vulnerabilities and this
applies for operating systems as law
this applies for basic applications like
Tomcat web server operating systems so
it's really well known so it's not that
we don't understand that problem but
it's really difficult so like would you
agree
and like let's take a look at the
documents so there are like secure to
your hardening guides available for
decades really
so that is try to understand I how long
does it take you to verify those
documents on your server so are you
compliant of course first good that's
good so what we like as a coder right we
know like we know this we want out of
made you want to right-click we want to
run it in our CI CD pipeline and this is
really what we figured like there sir
the descriptions that we how every part
of the pipeline they all work together
but they talk different languages
difficult on top of that we we have like
in the past we had a nappy deployed on
one server great but now we have more
servers so like many old testing is
really difficult it's scales even
further so now we have more servers
great so now we need to check all those
and like we figured already like DevOps
is deployed like improving the speed
like our path we deploy then we have
cloud is growing and we have IOT which
like the number of devices is now
growing as well so that's that's a
challenge and to apply those rules
across over really difficult so we I
will talk now about the solution so we
talked about the problem we've seen in
and we talked about how can we solve
that and I used the term compliance
driven infrastructure because I want to
get those requirements really as early
as possible on the pipeline as we've
talked like today already security as
early as possible in the pipeline so in
this specific example I will give you
two open source projects in specs and
the Deaf side project that helps you to
run those guidelines quickly on your
server so what is inspect so inspect is
really really a tool that
your infrastructure testing compliance
and security requirement into code and
we have a look and now how this works we
take a really simple example in this
case it's just hey let's verify that
you're using ssh version 2 sound easy
right
so this is how you do it normally you're
writing come on rerun grep looks great
so that's really cool if you're like a
developer you understand regular
expression it's working out well with my
best trip but how do you share that in
your organization so we came up with a
language that allows you to say hey I
test the requirement so that our final
state so in this case I am saying
there's a HD config protocol should be
set compared to two so it's now
different I don't use any regular
expressions anymore so I just define it
and on top of that I can define need a
data to that as well so I have an impact
critical T title description you have
additional options to add tags reference
so we are like working both like major
like US government agencies and they use
it because they have so many different
like cross references and you want to
attach that to the code as well so so
we've talked a little bit so the cool
thing is about this task you can run it
locally and you can run it remotely you
can run it against their like SSH in RM
and the docker container and we
completely have a look at how that burns
so we have here we just started afresh
darker container run T - alright so
containers absolutely trust me that this
is a new container so and I say I have a
quick test in here trials
what's a look so that is just test out
sorry good thank you
so yeah so let's tell ya here's the
fresh pepper container so here I have a
simple test that is just saying hey is
this package install and I say inspect
xx foil package and now I target the
docker container so it's connecting
remotely
I have not installed anything into that
container so that's completely remodeled
so I can do that locally and remotely so
that that's great so I can now test my
infrastructure so this is not like only
focusing on a single operating system we
cover like all major operating systems I
just figured like a bun - we of course
support a bun - 1604 we also support
Windows 2016 and Windows Nana so that's
all included so it should be you should
be able to cover your operating system
you have a lot of out-of-the-box
resources to cover like basic
configuration ranging from for operating
system tasks like users packages groups
databases so that gives you really like
easy start to verify what what is there
since it's all available as a separate
thing like you're not depending on a
DevOps tool but you can easily combine
it the chef puppet ansible docker but
even if you have a manually deployed
server and we have a couple of companies
using it for AIX infrastructure for
example banks in specific so they use
they have a lot of those servers running
and they can now use this tool to
remotely verify their servers and they
are normally really in a restricted
environment so that's a pretty mean so
now we've seen those requirements before
and now we need to translate those to
inspect and this is giving you an idea
like here we see a requirement from from
the text translated to code so we can
now attach the title description and all
this
we attach to the code which makes it
really easy to also visualize it later
on
so now as Hume you have a test like
hundreds of tests CSS benchmark who
knows he has benchmarks great
so those benchmarks who is agreeing with
all rules of the CIS benchmarks okay
so we've seen a lot of companies
disagreeing with that so the challenge
with that is that you have to manage
that right so if you if CS coming up
with a new baseline like now you need to
take up your gyro or you take your
markdown file if you've managed to
overlay and very disagree and update it
to the latest version so what we do
instead and inspect we provide the
capability to say I inherit the profile
so in this case I can take the CSS level
1 profile for example I can inherit it
and I can say I disagree with a couple
of rules and this is a this is fine so I
can just agree inside the organization
and make it part of the code as well so
that means like you're you're only
managing the overlay when anything
changes in the app stream profile you
provoke and is taking that into
consideration as well and then not only
you have multiple environments where you
also say you want to differ and that
that you can put this in multiple stages
so we see you see a baseline in a second
so that you can talk about it as well
and we talk about now content right so I
gave you an idea of how that tool works
so we do quick overview and we now talk
about the condom because like what the
tool value if there is no content that
you can just use so we talked about the
deficit project and it comes with a
couple of baselines like for Linux for
Windows and also the caching baseline
for Linux and windows so that is pretty
neat and we can just use them
so we've just started the docker
container you've seen it and we have
here the project and we have
make that soup for the baseline have
been oh yeah thank you
this is computer so here like this desk
tech project it's a github comm / def
sack and before example look for a Linux
base line here we have so it's a simple
simple ruling a number of controls are
included in here so we can look those up
again no time to explain this in detail
that so but what we can do now is we
just like copy over like this line I can
say okay in spec instead of this simple
like simple rule if all I'm just running
the whole base line again that docker
container so downloading does this base
line and running it again from what
container so now it's running you will
see in a second like something boom
so now we have a response so in this
case like kernel parameters are like
this is darker but so this can be easily
applied to any other environment as well
so the same thing works for for Windows
as well and so I just I think I show you
quickly the patch space line so we have
a patch base line as well all it Linux
hatch waste line we downloaded from
github and we run it again that
container so it's a freshly started to
go into container
it's may be cached a couple of days ago
let's see if our like packages are
up-to-date so now there so we see you
have a couple of packages not up-to-date
so it's just like you can run it open
source and you see immediately that they
are in your container or even if it's
like not a container could be VN you see
the result so now as part of an
organization
you really want to manage that across
like multiple things so in this case for
example you want to have a company
profile so that's now even a bigger
scope right so company profile so that
means like as a company you normally
have multiple operating systems you have
maybe Windows and Linux you want to tie
those together and you want to
distribute just one profile to be run
everywhere so we've seen now like Linux
baseline is the amount of tasks imposed
in the baseline the same for Windows and
we can now define a media profile that
is aggregating mobile profiles so the
advantage here is that within spec you
can define those and you can make simple
baselines for specific components so we
can use SSH command you can say yet my
application as a component so you make
individual component the baseline for
individual components so that makes it
really manageable and you can focus a
baseline on one specific component and
you can manage those in github but like
now you get like multiple like baselines
and it's still like difficult to share
those around and that's why we came out
of the meetup profile and this is how it
works so you can say in your media
profile I include control and I can also
like this is how you manage you overlays
to like I can tip control I can change
controls and this is really powerful
because it allows you to manage
everything and I have an example
available so this is the I call of the
acne profile so that a profile is
essentially for acne Inc and you see I
just pull in a couple of like profile
I'd say I depend on the patch profile
and the base Linux profile windows and
this is all for example so that that
makes it easy to use the
everywhere so now let's have a look how
we include that for example hardening I
just say hey I was just want to include
like every rule from that baseline of
course we can disagree same applies for
patching so now let's run this baseline
on the same docker container so as
you've seen you have Windows and then of
things mix and obviously we want to
minimize false positives so like hey
when I run Windows stuff on Linux is
that run all right so let's see so I I'm
here so we have the docker container
here so I catch that locally so it's a
little bit bigger okay now we run the
aggregation on that docker container so
that means like Windows pets profile
then it's patch profile Windows
hardening Linux hardening so they all
run now against the same container
that's difficult on that yeah so it's
not optimal to read but I like what you
see here like multiple profiles have
been executed so the so this is the
patching you've seen it and here's the
windows patch baseline for example and
you see that all those tasks have been
skinned so in inspect allows you to
define an only if condition for example
that says only run those controls like
if you're on Windows and for those bass
lines they are implicitly there because
like the linux bass line is saying in
the media data i'm only supporting linux
so then inspect knows hey if you run
this again windows i don't need to
execute that because like it's not
intended to one of those so so that
means like you can you really get a
better overview across your
infrastructure by saying hey this does
not apply to you and why is that
important
the same can be applied to an
application so let's assume you do this
for apache and you're you assume you
don't
have a pesci installed on your machine
but then accidentally like a for a quick
fix you meet an Apache to be installed
and that ministry doors locking in and
pulling Apache to be like solve the
business need and then now you need to
implement Apache hardening as well so
then if you do that like you run the
next skin immediately it will figure out
the Apaches install and then boom like
you have all the tests running without
like additional like managing so to sum
this up we have like this allows you to
receive compliance not as a blocker
anymore and as late-game
in your CIC pipeline we've automated it
so the whole baseline that we have are
now part of a code so they are managing
get like the same as you do with
everything else and then you can deploy
this everywhere every developer can just
download a spec run those baselines and
see the result so that's a lot better
and we're having the additional
descriptions attached to really can see
what's going on with you can attach
references like web links and this makes
it really easy to work with that so
instead of like hurting it like it's the
latest stage in your infrastructure
we've seen companies using those
baseline to verify existing manually
deployed servers and then they figure
out oh we are not complying with our
rules and then they start building
automation so luckily the dev site
project is shipping hardening cookbooks
for chef puppet modules and also ansible
modules for those baseline so it's
really easy to get started so you start
normally locally you test it in your
environment you put this in your CI CDI
by pipeline remediate you verify again
and you can now make it a continuous
cycle so that's why I call it continuous
compliance so just to sum up what we've
seen we have seen inspect as a tool to
test and manage complex testing and
compliance rules we have seen content
the desig hardening
how you can use it and those combined
really enable you to day to just get
started run it on your server and see
what's going on further resources are
available let's inspect I oh very can
downloaded I have stickers with me so in
case you need one
we have also like the desk tech project
providing you with all the baselines and
that should that should get you started
please join inspect help to cover more
also join the Deaf side project
contribute there so it's all open source
so we are all together on this to
improve the security of our
infrastructure thank you very much and I
think we have a couple of minutes for
questions yeah so you mean like when
you're lengthen a test fails
where's fits to so there are a couple of
possibilities so for example you can put
this into into Jenkins
mr. Jenkins plug-in that like an output
J unit on command line but we have also
like chef as the company's providing
commercial tooling around that so like
there's a tooling available where you
can show like every fail control you can
manage it that is doing all the
integration inside any commercial tool
okay yeah
that is a very good question
so they are not defined so right now
this is implemented in the Linux patched
base line and we implemented the pet we
implemented it for various Linux systems
like Ubuntu Red Hat right now so this is
using the information that the operating
system has available so for goodness
it's using Windows Update Services and
for for lat
Sandra's its RPM essentially you can
also like we haven't done this right now
here open-source but you can also ask
the mirror to say so we do this a couple
of other companies who maintain this
because you're not a company that that's
maintaining it so they are like they are
doing this so reading the packages off
the API get the response and return this
planet the result so it really depends
on how you want to implement it the
version is really asking the operating
system but if you're using in all error
for example like you still have troubles
of that approach so you like the
ultimate goal and this is where we want
to want to get there that you have the
local state and also like like an
upstream perspective on that yeah very
good question any other question yeah so
we like it you can go into technical
details so we have multiple like we have
an abstraction built into a inspects so
that means like we essentially from
Inspira perspective you only know two
things we can transfer a file so the
loader file will run a command so that
the only like that the interface and
then we have multiple back-end
information back implementations how we
call it so one back end is the SSH one
others local and others is
docker for example so there can like
this extensible we could potentially add
more we could increment telnet if you
want to let be down lon
so so that's the abstraction and then we
have written all the logic in to inspect
resource this how we call it and this is
an inspector be a gulet resources and in
this case for example let's take the
package resource oh yeah so so here this
is in spec lip resources and let's take
a look into the package resource so here
you see like we have multiple package
mentors implemented and based on the
let's let's take the def package manager
and here we call out to two dpkg get the
response parse the result and make it
available and adjacent mic form it so
that it can deal with this and I can
give you a quick example
so in spec has also a cool shell two
clave of that so here we have all
resources for example gives you all
everything and we can say doctor give me
our containers and trees pool so I can
say doctor where give me all containers
for image is equal to 1/2 so ok and
trees so ok now we want to make sure
that we have only the running ones so
here is really like this is the this is
really also covering internally if you
have really a parse the data we have it
available we can't the query engine
essentially so which allows you to write
really complicated compliance pools of
that and that may be
we run CS baseline on it we run PCI
baselines on it so that might be
covering a lot and we work with mitre
that has like they challenged us a lot
of those those tests so this is really
like give there's a really good engine
underneath and it's really easy to
extend as well so we don't expect
everybody to like contribute the stuff
to our open source project but instead
our like we call it inspect profile you
can have custom resources included there
as well for example if you have a
homegrown application you want to write
tests for that you can do that with an
inspector file in this case take a look
on the on the inspect bio page
documentation here and yeah talk about
the profile and this is giving you a
good overview about like how this works
and how you can extend this and so yeah
I cannot cover this here but just give
you a good in anything else okay yeah
PCI is a very difficult one for sure and
like you cannot cover all controls for
sure so right now in spec is not
optimized to the manual occurring like
the manual questions so it's really
focusing on anything that it can
automate so there you can cover like
rules for like system hardening for TLS
version 1.2 migration for example so for
example this is maybe interesting
there's an SSL base line available so in
case you need to implement the TLS
version 1.2 migration for PCI a take
this profile or you can run it against
the server and should give you a good
hint of like what's if you have migrated
all your ciphers already yeah um so
so inspect by itself is just a
command-line tool so you can do whatever
you like in this case let's say instead
I just execute executed pro farm simple
profile x6 profile and I can say former
Jason for example I didn't take you and
then you get adjacent output of that
result so that makes it really easy to
embed it everywhere so we use as chef be
used inspect as the core engine for chef
compliance and chef automate if they
like this is really we used the same
technique so there's nothing else that
we add on top so you can use that as
well you can just type use the Jason
type it somewhere like if you want to I
know a couple of companies Piper to
supply for example so yeah it's right
you can transform the JSON output as you
like okay make sure you pick up some
stickers with me so I don't want to
bring them home thank you very much
[Applause]