thank you all right so my name is Franz
Rosen I work as a security adviser at
6'5 everything is like 69 and squeezed
but it will work anyway
and I work as a security visor to
testify and we do automation for
monitoring where websites basically so
we're looking for vulnerabilities all
over the place and I also do a lot of
bug bounties so I am I spend a lot of
time with hacker one in bad crowd and
cynic and I also do a bunch of research
there so I try to find one abilities on
these companies and then implement them
into our products and also try to like
move further all the time so I'm trying
to share everything I'm doing just to
keep me up to speed also so it's a
challenge for me and by exposing
everything I do which is cool so I do a
lot of blogging as our lab slog I will
mention some of the blog posts and but
you should take a look at it's quite fun
and I also love this image and because I
was up in northern Sweden and it was
like 35 - Celsius and I took it damage
and I was like I had fun I used it as a
profile pic and I met some people
outside of Sweden and they're like yeah
yeah you're dressed as ania of course
but it's really so they started from my
my like as the Swedish mania so I I like
that try I'll gonna stick to it so I'm
going to talk about DNS hijacking and
I'm going to talk about the background
of this because we've been doing
research since October 2014 regarding
this and a lot of stuff has happened so
I will go through exactly what happens
in Stan and where we asked right now I
also talked about some tools and
techniques people are using today and
I'm going to tell you why those tools
doesn't really cover everything and also
what to do with those tools to actually
make it work better also and mutations
of this specific thing and which means
that we started with one point of the
whole core concept but then I'm going to
talk about how that mutated in two
totally different areas
and that still has a lot of potential
into doing research and also some formal
mitigations that you can do and about
like how to monitor for this so
subdomain takeover October 2014
basically the concept was like this
let's take a ruler uka was vulnerable
then still vulnerable today the basic
concept is us a company is starting a
campaign for example and you want to
host that campaign on a subdomain and
also Haruka is nice like you you can
easily just run a run a dyno on on
Heroku and you run your campaign
everything works really well you point
your subdomain to that Oracle instance
everything is awesome everything works
great but to route could cost money if
you want to like get the best out of
Heroku so when the campaign is over you
shut down their recurrences but the nest
records are free doesn't cost anything
to have DNS records so they shut down
the website nobody cares about campaign
dot site up from pointing to a root
group which basically means that anybody
can go in and say oh this domain is not
used at the ruku I will register myself
on a repo and say this domain is mine
and I will host whatever you want on it
that's the core concept and when we
posted this three years ago there were
17 providers the biggest 17 providers
that we found back in those days that
was vulnerable to this and we showed a
bunch of examples of what you can find
out how you can fingerprint those
services on subdomains so you know that
okay I can probably most likely take
over these domains so this is just for
example this github Oroku s3 and desc
and when we did this there was also
another guy called Stephano that posted
a blog the 12th the 12th of October
about actually taking over subdomains of
a Facebook acquired like acquired a
company and he spoke a little bit about
like guru kudos doesn't do any
validation so you were able to do this
nine days later when we saw that we
posted all our research and the research
was like this is all over the place like
this is happening all over and when we
started
talking with these companies the
services not the actual vulnerable
clients but when we started talking with
the with the services and like you can
do this like why are not validating that
me as arbitrary person just comes in and
say that this is my domain and they're
like yeah yeah we know we where we know
it's like but but they don't use it like
they don't use us anymore right
so they're really not our customers and
that was like one argument another
argument is like yeah we know it's the
security issue but if you read our
documentation everything says like
clearly that you should not do this you
should remove your DNS records when this
happens however when we started talking
with the customers of these services
they threw money at us they were like
holy shit why did we not know about this
so all these companies just like poured
money just because they were like we
have no idea we were like vulnerable by
just forgetting about these DNS records
and we saw a bunch of reports as soon as
we published this we saw a bunch of
reports that actually abuse this in a
chain of vulnerabilities one example is
a guy called Ernest Windham and what he
did was actually found he found a
subdomain take over on ubiquity which is
like this Wi-Fi hardware company and
they had their internal SSO allowing any
subdomain of of their their site to
actually get the tokens using SSO and
which asically may made it possible for
him to take over the the login for the
administrators of this domain also we've
also seen a bunch of reports after this
so people are just like hammering out
companies finding all these issues which
is hilarious and the problem with it is
though that the first report I published
back in the days on s3 on Twitter has
been copied all the time so in that
coffee it actually says we have written
an advisory over at the tech to fight so
people is like like ho hey friends this
dude says is working for detective is
that really true because people are just
copying the exact same text that I did
back in the days which is quite fine
we've also seen instances just like
sneaking up on different places so
you know about certificate transparency
right so as soon as you're issuing a
certificate and somebody is using it in
a browser or if you're using SSL
provided actually connected to
certificate transparency I think most of
them are and those certificates needs to
be communicated so you're able to
actually search for what certificates
that has been published and if you look
at uber dot-com today you will see that
one friend of mine called zoom on Greece
s key has has actually one issued as a
cell certificate on one of the domains
and this is also like an artifact of
basically being able to either control
the email or control the website another
thing was a guy called Jonathan Claudius
at the Mozilla he went out in February
this year actually and talked about
subdomain takeover and said like this is
probably the new form of exercise like
we're not seeing this go away anytime
soon and that's also a verification that
this is actually a problem that people
starting to realize is actually a
problem hopefully we'll see the service
providers actually doing something about
it we've not seen it yet I know also
some things happened in in even domains
that wasn't really explainable and one
example was a blog post we did and last
year actually and the case was basically
that a trailing trailing doctor means
basically a domain with a trailing dot
if you visited that one a bunch of
services said yeah but we don't have
anything on this trailing doctor main we
have something on the regular domain but
not if you're at this trailing dot and
trailing doses like in the specification
of how DNS actually works so the problem
is isn't actually in the implementation
of how that trailing dot actually works
but as the cloud provider is doing it
wrong and in this case it was AWS that
basically if you add the trailing dots
it said nothing is here and the problem
with AWS and CloudFront in general is
that a bunch of big companies are using
those and also CloudFront enables you to
upload your own certificates and there
is one sort of certificate that is like
really bad to make sure like to let
anybody else have and that's a Evy SSL
and EVS SLE
basically like the biggest sort of
verification you can do on life if this
domain actually owned by a company and
because that verification actually
exists a bunch of browsers are just like
yeah we're not even going to show the
domain we're going to show the company
owning the domain so by using this
trailing dot we were able to actually
host stuff on part of i/o which is a
paypal domain and and route it to our
own site so this is actually it just
says PayPal calm but it's actually so it
shows you example calm and the cool
thing was the addition to this was that
if you're emailing someone with yahoo
email and you end the sentence with yeah
you should go to paypal calm and end
that sentence with the dot the links to
that paypal would be with the dot and
since this was CloudFront CloudFront has
something called logging and they also
have something called cookie logging and
these in combination made us when we
started doing research with this
we went back a couple of days later and
had like cookies for people signing in
on the document which was really bad so
AWS actually went back in like okay
we're going to fix this because the fun
thing is that SSL is not really like SOP
the same origin policy SSL is like oh
you have a training dot we don't care
it's the same thing but the cloud
providers did not care about that
there's probably a bunch of other cloud
providers still vulnerable to exactly
this so when we logged about it we also
went out and said like cloud front as
well as three are vulnerable to to this
specific thing another thing we saw
during this time was that Trump got hat
Trump attacked earlier this year and a
guy posted them like hacked by Promaster
nothing is impossible peace from Iraq on
Dhananjay Toronto and when we saw this
we started like doing some small
research and I had another friend I was
like taking a look at it and we're like
this is probably a subdomain takeover
and because he was using a third party
that was actually vulnerable to it and a
couple of days later we see a tweet from
Brian Krebs that says he got in touch
with the Iraqi hacker and he referenced
the blog post that I did in 2014 which
was like yes that's the
them that's that's how it actually went
down so tools there's a bunch of tools
that has popped up there was one tool
that actually existed long before and we
did this called sub root sub root is
basically a Python script that tries to
brute force using a bunch of resolvers
trying to brute force a bunch of
subdomains nobody's actually developing
sub root like long any longer so it's
actually stopped developing it's really
fast and really good still however a
friend of mine called Ahmed actually
adapted that project so he moves it over
to something called sub Lister and sub
Lister is basically trying to both doing
brute force but also trying to use a
bunch of external services that like
certificate transparency passive total
Google and net craft and try to collect
all the sub domains to do stuff with
them a bunch of other projects has
popped up there's a C implementation a
for a high performance dns resolver
which is basically called mass DNS and
what it does is like superfast trying to
resolve all all the things you actually
have so if you give it a bunch of
domains disable to actually resolve them
really fast and give you back the result
and to get this really good list there's
also a project from a friend of mine
called chubs he actually did a pretty
like permutation script so basically you
give it a bunch of subdomains and you
give it a bunch of like staging live
production demo whatever about a word
list and they will combine that so it
will make like wwa Jing or staging or
staging W or staging - w w and troy like
creates all these mutation lists and
combine this with mass DNS you have a
really powerful tool to actually get all
these domains there's also a project
from another guy called Answer Man and
on Sherman actually build a TKO subs
it's called it's basically looking for
subdomain takeovers but instead of just
finding them it actually takes the main
over automatically which is kind of a
douchebag move like that's that's not
really how you want to do it sometimes
if you're doing this continually on a
company you can see that they're
vulnerable in a couple of hours
like they're moving at the Maine or
something and if you're having this
running all the time you'll just claim
it in the middle of them trying to do
stop so that's that's pretty messed up
but there's a competition in this trying
to find all this dimension and trying to
prove that they're vulnerable so this is
like one adaptation of trying to be the
fastest to actually show that they're
being vulnerable now what are they
actually looking for like there's one
concept of actually looking at how they
actually resolve and looking for
patterns into their records so in this
example you would look for for pointing
two buckets at s3 or github or looking
at a roo craft but that's really not the
way to do it because you need to resolve
them and you and you need to also see if
they're not resolving and you need to
use those in combination to actually
make sure what happens so one of these
things that happens is and one of the
things that the tools are missing out on
our dead DNS records so what is that
then it's DNS records it's basically
something that really doesn't look like
it's there if you like making a host
request to it it will say like NX domain
this doesn't really exist and this
doesn't really exist but if you look at
admin dr. Elcom that will also say like
this doesn't exist but if you start
digging deeper you will see that admin
dr. Essam actually points to
product-related local so that actually
has a record so the difference between
we cannot resolve and it actually has
the DNS records are totally different
and none of these tools are actually
checking for if the actual record exists
or not and X domain is like whatever it
doesn't exist and that's a really bad
thing because there's examples of here's
the game that Western Union com a couple
of years ago I found this and it was
pointing to the Western Union gang comm
and that one was up progressed and the
cool thing with this vulnerability is
that you could actually look at the
expire date of the domain and see that
this was actually nine years old nobody
has seen this in nine years and nobody
actually touched it so that's also one
indication this these guys have a public
bug bounty so that was an indication
that all the tools out there are
actually missing out a bunch of issues
a guy called a Matthew Bryant or also
known as mandatory
mandatory programmer and mandatory I
don't know
mandatory a bunch of stuff prefix
mandatory he actually posted last year
and really interesting attack method and
what he was looking at was not looking
at us domains that doesn't exist but
domains where the name server says don't
ask me I don't know or it says no I'm
refusing to answer your DNS requests
those called surveil and refused those
are the DNS errors that he was actually
doing a research wrong and he noticed
that a bunch of cloud services having
DNS services was actually allowing
anybody to actually take these domains
he was focusing on apex domains meaning
blah blah blah com so he took that accom
list from from Verisign and loop them
through and looked after all with all of
the ones giving refused to the name
service they had and then he checked
those name services or name servers and
see what type of service that they were
using and he noticed that a bunch of
them had AWS route 53 which was one of
the services that doesn't really care
who's owning the zone five and when I
read this I was like okay this does not
sound good because there's something
called subdomain delegation which means
that a subdomain of your ethics can
contain a different name server so you
can delegate the subdomain to a
different name server and when I talked
with him like you know that there's
subdomain delegation and he's like yeah
I haven't looked in it is this probably
people vulnerable to it and when we did
that we're like holy fucking christ like
this is actually a big big problem like
a bunch of people using route 53 for
example every time they launched a new
app they actually creates a sone file
for that subdomain only the records of
that specific app so they don't have a
huge amount of things in their regular
song file
they have like children's song files all
over the place and that meant that a
subdomain that had a name server that
says no we're refusing to answer your
DNS call because we have a different
name server than the parent and the
ethics and you could basically go in and
just take that one and the status codes
for this was basically like
and the no error is the regular one like
that results everything is okay then NX
domain is like we don't exist this
doesn't exist and that one could still
have a DNS record that's one of the
points I was showing with Western Union
and then you need to actually ask the
name server more and what Brian showed
was like the refused is we don't know
like we don't like this domain this was
something that wrote 53 digital ocean
and the cloudiness was actually like
doing with this domains and also the
surveil that one is not even responding
that means that the name server
connected could also be a domain that
has expired for example that happens a
lot or typos um and the tools find the
no error that's the focus everything is
focused on the no web and also other
three is basically just ignored if you
look at these codes for for sub routes
for example it basically has like okay
no error do you're saying look if it's a
cname or a if it's an X domain just
whatever and if it's something else just
whatever don't do anything and and the
subdomain delegation that he that we
actually tried when we saw what what
Matthew had done was basically an
example of lab dot example.com was
giving me a surveil and when looking at
the name servers of that subdomain you
can see that this is a subdomain
delegation basically so example of comm
points to for a specific AWS DNS records
for route 53 but the subdomain has its
own for and looking at these four you
could actually collect these four save
them it connects the AWS a command line
interface and say I want the zone I want
a new zone for labs example comm and
when you do that you get your four own
name servers but if you combine that and
start like looking for similar matches
as soon as you get a match and these
ones are connected you can actually just
take the domain because if one of the
name servers actually responds that one
will be the the prioritized one and what
happened also you can get some really
funky stuff going on with Rob 53 so if
you get one of them the other three will
upgrade to its edge in is likely to its
and like siblings which is interesting
so you can basically eliminate the error
and just take over the subdomain
completely so basically then you host
this on file of labs dot example oakum
and another thing and like just to
summarize nobody is like what looking
for this so please start doing it and
another example of another thing that
Matthew talked about two years ago was
was orphaned ec2 wipies and the ec2 IPS
is basically when you launch an easy-to
you have the ability to connect an IP to
it you can reserve an IP which basically
means that if you restart the easy two
you will keep the same IP but if you
don't reserve an IP it will just take a
new one and if you're pointing your dns
records to the oldest ec2 IP and
somebody just reboot sites basically
just a reboot you will get the new IP
and that that IP just released into the
void and someone else can take it
so trying to like automate this like how
do you find orphaned I piece I tend to
like look at the title of like I find
all the subdomains and I look at the
titles trying to strip out the ones not
connected to the company and I did it on
one side and one just popped up and I
was like this is weird this is the site
building Cubs interfaces for doing
furnitures or doing like houses and when
I go to their dev site comm there's a
web shop this Web shop looks really
really funky right this is actually a
web shop for cannabis and this is a
start-up in San Francisco and they
suddenly have a subdomain with a web
shop selling weed and you should take a
look at this site it's just freaking
awesome I've never seen a site like this
it's so weird but basically I told them
like hey hey guys so you have a web shop
you don't know that that you have a web
shop and this Web shop actually sells
weed it sells weed to like the
California people but it still sells
weed and this doesn't look promising to
your investors like that's you should
and what happened like five minutes
later they like here here's 300 bucks
Thanks and they're like a couple of
hours later realized what happened and
they're like okay here's $250 dollars
more like oh this is so embarrassing
like that was the worst thing that could
happen in terms of this orphan like
these so the flow is basically the flow
that needs to be modified in these
applications is basically routing
routing all the things you use mass DNS
sub route whatever collecting oh errors
in the no errors are the ones that
actually doing doing something giving
something back and look for patterns in
those those collect the surveilling
refuse and if you get those try to trace
the name servers and collect the name
service that actually gives this refused
because you can find a lot of like fun
examples of this is basically AWS route
53 gives you four name servers
some people are typing them manually and
one of them are not really a proper
domain so basically you have one of them
actually giving you errors and that's
the fun thing you can actually find name
servers of valid domains three of them
are totally fine one of them is not and
what happens is that AWS route 53 is
doing like a round-robin for the DNS so
you can get like a 25% hit due to one of
the name service being expired and you
take that one and then you can play
around with it which is quite fun also
because you never even see it because if
one fails it will just take another one
so you can have a failed name server in
your DNS zone for how long there is
until someone takes it and you start
getting 25% loss and somebody else gets
that hit also NX domains you need to
like collect if it's a cname you should
actually take a look further but because
the fee name is basically a shortcut it
says like use everything I have from
this domain instead and and then you
need to like move forward and you need
to like almost like recursive look for
patterns in those things and you can
find stuff like a subdomain gives an X
domain pointing to a cname and that
cname and has a like a vulnerable name
server and and you can like do fun fun
stuff with that also doing result
check the no error for patterns looking
for these vulnerability
shake the ns4 pattern same thing with
the survey and the MX domain you need to
traverse up to a 8x and also check if
the apex is vulnerable because if that
one is vulnerable you might have found
the domain that doesn't really exist at
all and you can register it and also
like try to improve this collect all the
sub domain names that you have the
suffixes sort them by popularity and
like I tend to sort www because you know
that one exists and you sort them below
the ones having the popularity like
above two and then you know that as soon
as you get the W you probably like to
like look for the most common ones at
least and then analyze unknowns looking
for the titles of all sites filter out
the common titles like if the title is
the same as the domain and also generate
screenshots of the chunk of data that
you have so you can actually see if
there's some patterns and do this every
day all the time and push your
notification changes so one thing I do
is basically I got this in January on
the morning I was leaving my daughter
for for daycare and I saw my email like
Oh BRR bounces dr. Burdick home is
pointing to s3 that's super weird and I
looked at looked at it and yeah it was
vulnerable so I took the domain I went
to history and like this is my domain I
took it over but then I started looking
at the DNS records and I was like okay
so this points to support post mail comm
which is like a server provider for
treated like tracking bounces and that
one was pointing to a like a static IP
but it turns out that that static IP was
released and sparked post mail stuff
like they stopped using that domain and
that one was taking over by s3 so s3
just because they'd like need their own
IPS and just take them when they're
orphans and this hosts them suddenly
uber was gone and I can just place my
site like my website on there and like
trigger XSS and stuff and uber was like
okay the best kind of bug phases which
is just delete everything because we
don't use this anymore and they were
like here's thousand bucks so and
there's a bunch of guys doing this
there's a like a competition and I
really want to like challenge these guys
and get other people to do this because
we're like five people that actually are
doing this systematically these three
are my biggest competition its Mattias
Paulson honest winnin and Luke young
which is like three guys that are doing
exactly what I'm doing and they realize
the same
as I've done so this is really my
competition however I actually grabbed
the shorts on my bug bounty rewards from
back in 2014 and looking at the trend on
takeovers this is just takeovers and you
can see that it doesn't really matter
having that competition because there's
so many doing it wrong you can basically
see do you see anything okay so there's
that you see the dots that's the trend
so the trend goes up to there the last
month so shit is happening right now
everybody's volun to this nobody is
doing anything particular to actually
solve this we try to automate it for
testify and our customers but it's still
like so much fun for it and here's a guy
with a horse I hope I'm going to manage
this but but so another mutation of this
problem is called email snooping and
epilation
a group of white hats actually went out
a couple of months ago it's like October
last year and they said that they were
able to actually read a reverse emails
and they also thanked us for for
bringing this to light because that was
one of the reason they were actually
looking for stuff and what they actually
found was that there's basically three
email services that people use if you're
not using one of the three you're using
one of these three basically you don't
know it
that's the read that's the difference so
those two in being vulnerable is Megan
and SendGrid
and AWS SES is not really vulnerable to
this specific specific thing but what
this nipple lesion guys actually saw was
that they didn't use any verification at
all and you can just go in if somebody
pointed something to main gun and was
using that and they also exposed an MX
record and that meant that they could
actually receive emails to that host but
if you only use them for sending out
emails you still had to have an MX
record from them which basically meant
that if and they also have this thing
where they're like really good at
sending emails but they also want to
receive emails and make it easy for you
to receive them and have web hooks when
you get an email and stuff so that
service had no verification and they saw
that they can just go in say that this
domain is mine and get all the emails
for that for that
specifically and when I saw this I was
like okay so this is super interesting
and yeah MX records is inbound mail only
doesn't really apply through outgoing
and and when I saw this I was like this
is not fixed at all and I took a look at
it and I saw this service is called
inbound mail and also being able to add
new domains to make an account and when
I tested it said the domain is already
taken and the other one said no no you
need to validate the domain and when I
looked at the request the request was to
API version 3 claimed Wayne guess what I
did
version 2 not patched could just claim
the domain again and I was like okay so
this is bad the other one and they
actually fix that of course they were
like ok now we're going to fix all our
API versions and the other one was was
like ok so the domain is now taken
nobody else can use it
but if you want tracking please add a
cname to email dot your site comm and
point it to us please do that because if
you point it to us we can actually track
emails using a subdomain of your own and
looks really fun and awesome
the problem is with cname cname inherits
everything cname inherits MX records so
pointing a subdomain to an MX record
means that you get them or to another
domain means that you're getting the MX
records on that cname and combine that
with the whitelisted aliases basically
meaning there's a bunch of aliases five
of them being in the specification of
how SSL verification works so if you own
one of these aliases on an email you're
able to actually issue a certificate by
an OK way of doing it they allow that to
be done so combining this with this one
having a cname inheriting a MX from
mailgun you can just add the example of
comments that the emails of the example
are come to subdomain and suddenly you
have the postmaster and you can get the
postmaster emails and you can issue with
certificates on that and when we saw
this and we started talking with people
we're like ok if we understand
everything this is this is bad
another guy it was like yeah when I
at the blog post about this I was like
you're gonna this guy's going to come to
us and do something and I also went
through the net Elysion team in like
yeah but you forgot about this stuff and
they're like ah I wish I found it and
yeah and basically and some final notes
about this is basically there's a guy
called MP from from Belgium he actually
did a really fun thing earlier this year
and he was able to actually found a
tweet by Donald Trump and that reference
website that expired so what he did was
actually find this expired domain and
put a YouTube video on there that was
just a parody of how Trump like dances
in Russia and loves Russia and so that's
not really still there and showing that
trumpet-like
has been there in Russia also also a
really fun thing was that when in it was
two years ago something and will.i.am
the the like R&B artist actually went
out and like someone hacked my Twitter
account and somebody posted like hash
dot I dot M because he knows he owns
idols m and going into that website
you're like okay this is actually an s3
bucket and somebody can just take it and
it was like this for so long they they
have like wild card dot I dot M and you
can place whatever you want on that on
that domain and it has been like that
for so many years but suddenly something
happens and he just moved it to cloud
from being vulnerable in the exact same
way so now you can you can claim
whatever you want for for idols am sorry
will.i.am but he knows about it but he
he doesn't care so it's like a Sheree
version of a website hosting and so
basically no your nor DNS zone files and
everything you need to make sure that
everything is connected to everything
and you need to monitor this automation
is the only way to actually solve this
problem you can get some of the services
actually starting doing domain
validation some of them will never do
that for sure and will.i.am loves this
thing with subdomain takeovers thank you
very much
all right cool yeah sure anybody have
any questions here's one yes so that's
what Google is doing Google has probably
the best they're probably the only one
patching this today and what they're
doing is that they have one place of
verifying your domain which is Google
Webmaster so you validate their domain
and then they connect everything to that
but it turns out that they've been
vulnerable two times the last year
one being the Google DNS Google DNS they
didn't really care about the domains you
were adding and that was what was
Matthew Bryan showed and I also
contacted them about subdomain
delegation because they did they did
properly with the ethics but the
subdomain did they did not so yes that
could be that could be a solution to it
they ever are well aware about this and
they're trying to like figure something
out they haven't really doing it and
they probably need something that on one
level verify every domain that you ever
owned on your account by bike seat like
some form of txt records or something so
yes but there's still one service out of
like now it's probably like 60 or 60 of
them being vulnerable and and they knew
what about this since 2014 and they're
like yeah we're aware it's not that
common but it is it is actually cool
someone else yeah so yeah shop says open
source both Alpina's and he has another
thing called acid note which is
basically Matias also they have an open
source project which is basically you
can connect your widgets one of them
widgets being like collect all the
subdomains and asset node can regularly
run tests on all these domains and yeah
you're probably know yeah
anything else you can come talk to me
later no problem
I have stickers also Cheers thank you
[Laughter]