so welcome to this to this talk so it's
a it's actually we've we've created this
talk and the slide deck for the first
time so it's a hassleberry dis we try to
tune down the number of slides that
we'll have about seventy seven of them
so make sure to cover those so it is
about embedding gdpr
into the S DLC so it's a little bit too
early for an acronym drinking game
virtual so we'll try to keep acronyms as
low as possible but it's really a story
about two worlds and and two sides of
the story that we see coming together
more and more and actually also the
reason why we've been doing this talk is
we actually work together today in
companies called thorium week we work
indulgent and TV joint is last year
because of this increasing number of
questions around privacy and GDP are
projects and what we see also a lot of
our customers is that actually it's not
one question it's not only about GDP our
and also the kind of projects that I am
doing so just just to make sure that we
added pictures to make sure that you
understand the time Sebastian and he is
here but what we see is that with
software security projects we see
questions around GDP are having GDP our
related projects we also see this is not
something that stands on its own
so that's that's really the reason that
we wanted to like research more like how
does this fit together how can we like
include this kind of compliance
regulation which is like quite a high
level and then based on on this
regulation fit together it's something
that's more like very practical that we
try to embed in the software development
lifecycle so that's that's the
background around this see go all right
so what are we going to talk to about
today I first will give you a very brief
introduction into the GDP are because
some of you or maybe most of you might
not know what to dull about afterwards
said I will introduce you a bit into the
SDLC into the
and framework and then we will bring it
all together and we have created a
mapping of sand and gdpr and this
mapping will show you how you can become
gt-r compliance by introducing an S DLC
and using them as a framework within
your organization and finally we will
present some conclusions and next steps
to improve the framework over the years
and make it something that all of you
can can use within your organization so
GDP our system for general data
protection regulation it's a new privacy
legislation within Europe the world
right the word regulation is important
because it's not like a directive in
which all nations can change the law
within their own country it means that
the law is directly applicable in the
entire European Union the law will also
remain applicable within United Kingdom
even though brexit will happen the law
will become applicable 25th of May 2018
which means we still have like one year
in order to become compliant it might
seem like a lot of time but for most
organizations it will become nearly
impossible to become fully compliant by
the time so it's really the time is now
to start acting what are the goals of
the GDP are the first goal is to unify
privacy legislation within the entire
European Union and the second goal is to
improve the rights of you to of the
protection of personal data and right to
the data subjects he all privacy
legislation dates from 1995 which is
more than 20 years old and as we all
know 20 years ago there didn't exist
big data social media the internet was
still new so in the last 10 in the last
20 years more data personal data of all
of us than ever before was collected and
processed so this new law tries to give
control back to the data subjects to us
all what is personal data we often see
that most people has a too narrow
definition of personal data
most people think personal data is my
name my address and some other data
which is very very easy to think of but
all data which is ident which is related
to an ident
fight or identifiable person is
considered personal data which means
that a lot of IP data is also considered
as personal data and must be processed
as defined by the law means that cookies
mailboxes histories surf history certain
card numbers IP addresses that are all
considered personal data and must be
processed and protected well if there's
one thing you should know about the gdpr
because it's a very long and difficult
legislation it's this slide the gdpr has
seven principles which just which should
be followed in order to process personal
data legally if you do not abide with
one of these seven principles you're
processing personal data on a legal
matter and you should stop the
processing I'm not going to go too deep
in these principles because I could talk
one hour about these principles on this
slide alone but you should know that
some of these principles are managed by
legal departments such as the
justification and transparency principle
but that other principles are directly
related to application development and
to security for instance the
proportionality principle states that
you can only use the personal data that
you need in relation to your finality in
relation to your goal that means for
instance if you design a new application
that you must make sure that you don't
use data fields within your applications
that aren't necessary it also means that
you should define retention periods and
it uses design automated tools in order
to make sure that personal data is
deleted when the retention period is is
past confidentiality it means that data
and applications which are built needs
to be secured at adequate security
controls should be in place and
accountability it means that you as a
controller or a processor as an
organization that processes personal
data must be able to prove by using
audit trail by using artifacts
deliverables
that you have taken all the other
principles in design so if there is a
law if there is a complaint so
you should be able to prove that you did
what what was necessary
these are three articles that go deeper
into confidentiality so these are three
articles that build further upon the
principle of confidentiality there are a
lot of details within the articles but
in every article there's one principle
that comes back it says that you need to
be able to identify security risks so in
your software development process you
need to start with identifying security
risk and then build security controls in
order to provide adequate technical and
organizational measures in order to
manage those risks depending on your
risk appetite of your organization all
right so which brings us indeed to the
to the software development lifecycle
and so I'm very lucky or very lucky we
have guys like you around to go over all
this legislation and to have us like
understand specifically what is what is
necessary but before we add these like
extra activities we also have to
understand what the security valid life
cycle is so again here I could also like
explain for one hour what the software
development lifecycle is or ask you the
software development lifecycle is but
what it boils down to is you have your
stages in software development like
designing building testing and operating
code and and then most of the time these
are like Sprint's iterations of and of
developers creating creating software
and functionality now the whole idea of
a well-functioning secure development
lifecycle is that you embed security
activities like application security
activities in those development
activities which means is we have to add
threat molding we have to add coding
guidelines source code reviews security
testing as part of the processes and the
status of producing software and
security testing is something that you
do at the end so security pen testing is
not the only thing you should be doing
should really go like introducing
software security activities as early as
possible in the different iterations
what's important there is that the the
people are involved
get some training some awareness and the
the way we introduce this is we use like
a secure development lifecycle framework
maybe you know you know of Microsoft SEL
what we use in our practice is o of Sam
so Sam is a software assurance maturity
model which actually are one of the co
project leaders own so it's not
coincidence that we're using this one is
actually one of the older and more
certainly a very mature project in the
sense that is being used a lot by
organizations to introduce software
security activities in development or on
cycles now this is built around 12
security practices which we have here at
the bottom covering governance governing
building software governing verification
activities in this Q development
lifecycle and also covering operations
aspects in them in the secure develop
lifecycle so what we've done is we've
looked at this and we've really liked
and that's where we work together like
how can we now like merge these two
things together and what we have the GDP
are and what's important there it has to
be right risk risk based you have to do
these activities based on risk for your
data subjects based on risk that your
software is being exposed to so and that
and that's interesting because if you
look in more detail in some you will see
that some some activities are also risk
based specifically if you if you go into
detail and go and look at some there's
like under each of these twelve security
practices there's different levels of
maturity with different level of red
liquid different security activities you
can't do everything for all software so
what you do is you pick the specific
activities that are important for a
software based on the risk or the risk
level of your applications and that
matches very well the GDP art is called
that's also risk based so and that's why
we did this this activity we're
receiving maybe you can explain what you
did
we looked at the sin domains and we were
looking what GDP our articles can we
match with a different domain we've
created here a high level overview but
we've also created a detailed overview
for every maturity level of SEM we've
matched what GDP our article relates to
this we will also make this detailed
overview available to you all it will be
posted on the OS chapter overview web
site and now we will go into the details
and let you see in more detail what can
you do in order to become GTR compliance
by using Sam and by using the SDLC first
we will talk about SM it's about
strategy metrics not sudden masochism
within this presentation to be clear I'm
sorry strategy metrics it means that you
need to create a risk management system
within your organization first of all on
enterprise level secondly on application
level on enterprise level it means that
you should include
gdpr and privacy and information
security aspects in your overall risk
profile of your organization and that
you should also create a GDP our
implementation roadmap based upon these
risks if you have high risks related to
certain privacy domains we should create
policy and control measures to control
those risks depending on your
organization and the types of data
processing that your organization does
secondly on an application level you
need to create a personal data inventory
the law states that you need to create
an overview of all your processing
records this is a grant overview of all
applications or business processes in
which you states which types of personal
data are used within which process in
which application and based upon this
overview you can define which
applications are critical and as a
higher risk for the organization with
which in relation to the GDP are based
upon these risks you can then do
additional assessments such as data
protection impact assessments in order
to further define the risk for an
application and to mitigate those
personal
risks policy in compliance I think it is
a pretty straightforward domain in its
step that the gtp are as a whole is an
external compliant driver which should
be taking into account when you design
when you create new applications and
also for your organization as a whole
and that you should create the necessary
policies and processors in order to make
sure that these principles from the gtp
are are taken into account when you
build new applications for instance the
GDP are sets that you need to take
certain amuse a ssin into account it's a
system of how you make personal data
less identifiable so you can create a
policy or an instruction Notah in order
to make sure that your developers follow
the basic principles of your of the GTR
within their operations it's about
creating accountability to the different
roles defining different roles within
your organization and making sure that
people follow these rules the Data
Protection Officer is also a very
important person that should be
appointed within your organization and
this person has the final accountability
within the organization in relation to
privacy and this person is also
responsible for monitoring the GTR
compliance within the organization so
this person has the rights to go to your
operations simply to go to your
development teams and ask do you follow
these privacy policies it is also better
not to create privacy policies to try to
embed the privacy policies between
operational policies of the teams
because otherwise you get two or three
sets of policies that might conflict
with each other so it's best to
collaborate with all the different teams
in order to create one set of overview
policies education and guidance the gdpr
has a lot of new requirements and most
people don't really know the GDP are
maybe do a little tests who of you are
application developers right if you know
what the GDP are requires from you
some people know here but in most cases
then all hands go down so it's also the
desk of the data protection officer to
raise this awareness within the
organization and the data protection
officer should therefore create an
education matrix based upon the roles
within the organization to make sure
that all roles within the organization
know what they need to do in relation to
privacy and in relation to their roles
so for instance developers they should
know everything about confidentiality
and security which is required by the
GTR but they should also know about the
data subject rights for instance how can
i implement data portability within a
new application yeah so so what you see
so what you see is that 3/4 for each of
the security practices we have some
activities on your left and we have the
gdpr activities or deliverables that
identifies being applicable in an
application lifecycle or a development
lifecycle on the right so that we can
match and try to like have as much
overlap and as much integration as
possible now what what Siebel just has
covered is the three security practices
there are more like on the governance
part of a development lifecycle where
obviously there's a rather good fit with
the gdpr when it comes down to the
creation the building of software it's
much more challenging now one of the
first steps in a new development
lifecycle is doing a what is called
threat assessment or technical risk
analysis now this is this is crucial in
itself as a very important activity to
drive other security activities in the
rest of the development lifecycle and it
it looks and it combines very well with
a like privacy risk analysis so
typically in the beginning of a software
development lifecycle you're going to
look at what are my technical risks and
combine to that you're also going to do
okay what are my privacy potential
privacy problems there and that we do
with the data privacy impact assessments
now typically you don't do that
completely you do that it likes
kind of threshold question there and
then if certain thresholds are our path
to do that in more detail and you would
go for a full data privacy impact
assessment so that's something that
integrates quite well and we do more and
more so one of the aspects and you see
that also there are different activities
in threat assessment all of the ones is
also like making sure that you evaluate
risk from third-party components confirm
components that are being used or
supplied by your suppliers or that are
being used by your processes or people
that actually like run software
functionality for you so there that
matches also with like the due diligence
and the check stand that you have to do
all the processors that process data for
you so that that's an important match
there as well so cheap is going to
explain a little bit more what is data
privacy impact assessment is as you see
with most customers they really have a
hard time defining what the data
protection impacts isn't it's already
cheating or what it needs to be the law
decides it is methodology for
identifying and mitigating compliance
and conformities and personal data risks
so it means that a personal data impact
assessment has always two different
types of assessments that you do it's
based on the law and based on a personal
data security in order to conduct a good
data protection impact assessment you
really need greetings
first of all you need to describe the
processing that you want to do and the
application that you will build so you
will describe the processing its
purposes the interests of your
organization and the list of third
parties or also other internal parties
that you will share your data with so
you today as you bring the data flows
within within you metadata flows
secondly you need to identify the risks
the proportion lot it starts you to
proportionality assessment which means
that you should identify which data you
use and try to define do I really need
all this data or can I build the same
application with with less data in order
to still be able to reach my goals
you should assess the data subjects
right can they be rectified again the
data
forgotten all these things should be
taken into account and we should be
taking into your backlog you should
identify the information security risks
and if they are too high you should take
measures in order to mitigate them and
the final step is to describe the
mitigation and then to define your
residual risk and if the residual risk
is low then you can go ads and build the
application if the residual risk remains
high that you need to contact the
privacy Commission or your national data
protection Authority in order to ask
them if it's still okay or that you
should take additional risk or if the
project needs to be killed in some cases
all right thank you so so this is a very
important step which will drive the next
one and this is an important security
practice in some and for any likely
development is is requirements obviously
you need to have like create and
functionality now security garments are
more like the non-functional wear in
general there are a like a whole static
security requirement you'd want to
integrate here and where we would
piggyback on those based on also like
the traveling activity and the likely
impact assessment that we've done to add
a couple of extra security requirement
that are related to compliance
specifically these like obtain versus
opt out these like content regulation
like how far do you want to go it's not
only primary use but also secondary use
you need to capture that and those you
can actually add a security requirement
to your to your project now in general
and what what's important here is also
to understand how your developers really
like use these and and integrate these
in their activities so one of the ways
that we see that works well is to create
like what we call like GDP our epic
overall like what's the story what's not
necessary for this application but also
like little stories what to be what it
has to be created or made or assured in
the software itself these are what we
call them call the GDP our stories and
that those are the kind of requirements
that developments get or developers get
and we as that do their product by
it's what like Shannon explained earlier
on in the keynote it's like you have to
like wrap this in a way that developers
can understand that and use this within
their within their development
activities so that's that's a very
important activity now there's different
levels you see it's like and summons
based on levels like having like higher
and higher maturity levels specifically
there is their requirements and we're
not going to cover every year code is
like security requirement here that
would bring us to far but this is really
the place where you can add the least
privilege requirements where you can add
like retention requirements that you
can't add like is it necessary yes or no
to encrypt or pseudonym eyes or
anonymize certain pieces of data so
that's an old based on modeling activity
that we've done before an important one
is and that something to realize is that
rarely do we see software being created
like one monolithic piece it's really
like pieces of software and services
working together also having software
suppliers or like serve providing
services so having a data processing
agreement in place with your suppliers
an important aspect of that as well and
maps really well on something you need
to have as part of your GDP are
activities something to be checked here
as well which is important the gdpr is
also when you like use these services
and like store data or around is to have
like these basic checks to make sure
that this kind of data is not
transferred out of Europe because they
need like extra security guarantees
around that so these map very well on
specifically security requirements and
different levels of security practice in
there in some development so one last
creation of construction security
practice is security architecture where
I'll leave it for you to go over all the
security activities that are part of a
typical security architecture practice
what maps here really well from the GDP
are is the privacy by design principles
in general as an architect as a software
architect you want to have like security
patterns
security design principles integrated in
reference architectures and reusable
components in your software and this
privacy by design if you integrate that
in these specific secure security
principles that that combination is
again can become very strong
so here again there is definitely things
that you can map and we can integrate so
those are the the construction
activities where in the next I would
take group of security practices in some
it's more focused on like making sure
that what we should test that we are
saying that we're going to do we did
actually like deliver that so an
important part is there is design review
is like checking indeed this is software
architecture just as design covers our
security requirement in the first place
so this is also a natural placeholder to
make those checks versus the privacy
requirements the second one is besides
the design is having a look at the code
itself so an important security practice
called implementation review which
actually doing source code review or
static analysis as part of our security
activity is making sure that the code
actually doesn't have any secure coding
bugs in them now it becomes a little bit
harder because it is a coding books like
something related to own like a gdpr
is a coding book related to not having
like proper content so this is hard so
this is one of the activities that Maps
relatively bad on gdpr
but it it does help to have some like
basic checks in place and overall being
combined with GDP are also means your
software has to be secure so the things
that you're doing in terms of like
software and testing and static analysis
is good in overall in showing that
you're taking appropriate technical
measures
so in essence itself it proves or it
shows compliance which is which is also
true for the next security practice
which is more focused on dynamic
security testing where we have code
analysis we also have like
Namek testing of your software in a QA
or a testing environment or even in
production what's important here is that
you don't only go for testing the like
is there input validation can I do
sequel injection here also it's
important that you take that first list
of security requirement including those
privacy requirements and also do like
basic checking if indeed these were
implemented incorrectly or not now
there's a couple of tools that also help
you checking if certain parts of the
privacy is implemented correctly in an
integral publications there's a tool
like gostrey which helps you like to
check what kind of cookies is an
application using and what to reach what
the reason behind behind those cookies
so those are our basic text which you
can easily integrate in a security
testing plan there's other tools like
IAB one turist
which does some automatic scanning all
of that obligation to treat to check for
certain privacy related aspect so having
a look at those tools have a look at how
you could integrate running those tools
as part of your security desk scanning
can help you there as well
so here you see that for the testing
part there's there's a couple of places
where you can add or stop in these gdpr
activities the gdpr also is a lot
stricter and when it comes to data
breaches as for now there is no
obligation whatsoever to a point to
report the data breach at whoever the
gdpr commits that every organization who
has a personal data breach should notify
the national data protection authority
of this data breach this should be done
by the data protection officer so this
means that you should have within your
organization an incident management
process that involves the data
protection officer that the data
protection officer is notified within
your organization of the data breach it
also means that if you have to notify
the data protection authority of data
breaches that you should be able to
identify data breach of yourself as an
organization
so you can do that by with a manual
process a whistle-blower process in
which employees can say hey I think you
have a data breach please look at it but
it's even better to implement the
necessary tools such as seam tools while
web application firewalls in order to
identify data breaches whenever they
they apply next slide okay
environment hardening also important
that you have a batch system in place
that for every new update the risk to an
application that you make sure that the
necessary controls are again exercise in
order to make sure that the update
doesn't bring new security risks to your
application or to your system it's also
important that when you have more and
more than one configuration possibility
within your application that you make
sure that after every update the most
privacy friendly setting is applied
that's called privacy by default that
the most privacy friendly setting by
default is the one that's all an example
of an organization that doesn't comply
with this principle is Microsoft some
people who will use Microsoft m.d put in
the settings of Microsoft 10 is a
checkbox which is automatically on which
state that Microsoft has access to all
your data including to personal data on
Microsoft Office 365 you can put it out
but by definition it's all yeah it's
also important to have systems trigger
privacy or security related related
incidents by creating a locks and it can
be done by theme or web application
firewalls as said before finally
operational enablement it means that you
should have audit trail that you should
document everything you do in order to
make sure that your organization is with
your that your applications are secure
and that you take the necessary steps
when an incident occurs so you should
documents breach indicators to ensure a
timely follow-up the most data
protection authorities also provides
templates in order to follow up of
incidents that should be used so check
the website of
local data protection authority in order
to implement these documents within your
data bridge process and include gdb our
consideration to all your operational
security guides it whatever your
document related to your new application
that you're building make sure that you
implement gdpr within it that you have a
gdp are filled in by which you can prove
that you've taken gdpr into account
during the entire process alright so
that was in really like very fast though
the 12 security practices of some and
where we saw like overlap or parts we
could integrate GDP our deliverables or
activities now we don't do this like for
the fun of it and what what we see is
that others a lot of projects that we
actively really are are like already
doing this so there's there's one
customer obviously I become state which
one it is we have an NDA VT guys but
there are they are very open about this
and they also will allow us to share the
outcome of the project here so and this
this customer really not only wants to
have like some assessment they
specifically also asked like that is all
good and fine but I also want to have
like an assessment in terms of GDP our
compliance and in this case also PCI
compliance because they're not only like
working on privacy relations and
sensitive information they also like
handled credit card information so
that's an excellent an excellent use
case where we do like sort of kind like
some assessment as part of how you would
apply and introduce the secure
development lifecycle framework and an
organization in first place but by
integrating both like checks but how are
you doing software security and also how
are you do you take into account like
GDP our activities and what do you do in
terms of like PCI related activities it
becomes really like a combined approach
instead of like separate activities
which is definitely what we see already
worthwhile because you only have to go
to these development teams once with all
the questions at the same time otherwise
they have to look this like go through
these three times the differ
people so that works very well so we
have agreement of this particular
customer that once we've done this
because thrille and within ongoing works
or not really well on what we're doing
here is it once we have a questionnaire
we can share that also with the
community so we will definitely after
after the project share that
questionnaire within some projects
together also with the current mappings
or that ongoing work there but quite
interesting now what we what we really
like advocate here and what and what we
see that is adding the value really in
in terms of the skill development
lifecycle by adding also the GDP our
activities as part of a security
activity it reinforces that and it
integrates really all really well on the
development lifecycle so you have the
development lifecycle we already like to
try to integrate security activities and
by integrating the compliancy activities
it all starts to work together and
what's important here and and that's
also what throughout what's most
important in terms of the Software
Assurance maturity model is you need to
relate and understand how your
developers produce and deploy software
so where the GDP are and also some of
these skill develop lifecycle activities
are more like based on gauge and like
before you put software in an accepted
environment you have to do a code review
before you do like like a release in
production you have to do like a pen
test that doesn't work anymore
now iteration is look like software
releases are going that fast that you
like need to automate and introduce some
security activities as part of the
development lifecycle and likewise also
need to introduce gdpr compliance
requirements so but for instance like we
we told by adding GDP our epics and
stories to a product backlog we make
sure that indeed developers get start
with with the right sort of requirements
and connectivity's
so what are the main advantages of what
we've learned today first of all we
should all remember that GDP R and s DLC
reinforce each other you can create a
good security development lifecycle
process by implementing GDP R and s dlc
make sure that personal data is
adequately protected and by thereby make
sure that your GDP are compliant so you
should really try to leverage both
systems in order to make sure that your
data is well protected if you're a web
application security specialist try to
befriend the DPO try to create processes
that are GTR compliant and try to use
the GPO as a friend in order to create
more budget in order to create more
visibility in order to create more
support for security projects within
your organization it's win-win the
deathblow wins because he can make sure
that the organization is compliant you
as a security specialist to win because
more security is implemented within the
organization so try to make use of this
of this moment in time when all
organizations are TTP are focused GDP
are aware and try to come to your
compliance yeah I think it's it's indeed
we get right and obviously you get a lot
of questions around this it it's an
excellent moment right now to use or
abuse this live GDP our pressure to
indeed support or create this business
case for an overall skilled around the
lifecycle so don't like focus too much
on the GDP our site have like something
that works brought and you can like plug
in the compliancy triggers and then next
time there is another compliance key
requirement comes along you can also
start adding those in the in these
activities
something we've which which we've
covered a couple of times but by
providing the security velopment
lifecycle deliverables you actually
start showing compliance towards whoever
is going to ask for it so if in the case
you have an incident and a local DPA is
going to like do it all it or do a
preventive audit you can already
demonstrate that you're actually doing
this by showing the NOC deliverables
I like indeed like his
that already is but extending the
community of a secure development
lifecycle like a security guys and
development teams that try to work
together by adding also like people from
the legal departments and from from dpo
and creating like this shared community
that's that's definitely something that
will be a keys to success here now in
terms of next steps so we've we've done
this mapping before 1cg quite some value
in this and and and are really
implementing this in a lot of but in a
couple of projects with our customers
what we're also going do is share this
with the bit community so there's a some
project where we going to donate not
only declined high level mappings with
also the detailed mappings and
afterwards questionnaire now in one
month maybe you're not aware of it but
if we're going to organise an OS summit
so it's not like a regular conference
it's like really a summit to work on a
lot of deliverables and there's
definitely a couple of some related
working sessions there so we'll improve
those and have some feedback from other
project members as well so an in general
like a collection and set we really also
like to get feedback what do you think
of this would you use it in your own
organization if you use this and you see
there's things that can be improved
please share that back with the
community as well so that we can share
this amongst each other all right
which brings us to the questions any
questions remarks yeah there's there's a
mic here in the front or if you can
share the mic there so that afterward
for the recording hello there so I'm
Simon from vertical structure haded and
we're very much really interesting to
look and I have a question about you
know mentioned briefly earlier on data
shouldn't be transferred out of Europe
and do you have any thoughts about how
this will apply after the UK leaves the
EU and what what we will do I don't need
too much
vacation for a Great Britain because
Great Britain stated it will also
implement the gt-r even when you leave
the European Union so I think for a
personal data and privately it will be a
great rating it's still part of the
European Union
even after practice all right all
questions as we become nervous now we're
now having legislation start to direct
all I can take as well no definitely not
I will repeat the legislation drives a
lot of our activities in general so I do
say we should probably be very glad we
have legislation to like have some kind
of agreement between us and society and
and in general security is it's a little
bit sad to say if there is no like
little pressure things will not improve
so we should really use this as an
opportunity and instead of like fighting
it taking it as an opportunity to indeed
make make software safer sooner yes all
right
and you mentioned that you wanted to
integrate the GPR to a backlog by
putting African stories you actually
also monitor that to use to date for the
stories as you just put to say 2018 may
looks and that's later yeah it's a
that's a good question it's a it's not
by adding it that it will actually be
implemented so it's it's also making
sure that there's awareness of the
people are involved that that these
stories are picked for some sprints
before next next May in 2018 so indeed
it it's it's by adding the stories you
make it like understandable for
development but you also have to
understand that you have to make sure
that by by talking to the stakeholders
like marketing the
apartment like business who really
drives the implementation of the
features that also need to include these
this kind of like GDP are related
stories yes thanks for the talk to Anna
green from National Grid the GDP our
rules that may seem to be rules that
apply to systems in production now there
is an activity that goes before that
which is for example debt migration
system migrations and so on so forth
word different set of activities are
taking place so what's your view on data
breaches during a development phase the
gdpr applies to all personal data it
doesn't matter if a personal data is in
a development phase or if it's in
production GDP are also requires you to
protect your test environments GDP are
even advises if it's possible to use
sudonym eyes or anonymized data in test
environments whenever possible so a data
breach within the test environment is as
bad as the data breach within the
production environment alright so if you
have any other questions please please
come and join us directly afterwards if
they don't operate wrong don't hesitate
to contact us I've no other email
address if your questions about some if
you have questions about the privacy or
security related activities motive and
my email address are available and I do
answer through emails it just can take
some time all right
okay enjoy the conference