cause misconfigurations good afternoon
and welcome to exploiting cause
misconfigurations
for bitcoins and bounties have you ever
looks at a Bitcoin exchange and wondered
how hard it would be to hack perhaps you
heard about the recent theft of 60
million dollars worth of bitcoins from
BitFenix and thought I wonder if I could
have done that maybe you even took a
look at a Bitcoin exchange and you saw a
tangled mess of web sockets sub resource
integrity content security policy web
application firewalls cross-origin
resource sharing and thought that looks
like quite a lot of work to hack in this
session I'll share with you how causes
simplicity is its weakness how that
weakness
leads to some really interesting
problems and how to exploit those
problems to steal bitcoins around seven
years ago I just got into security and I
just read about these really cool things
called buffer overflows so on this
particular evening I was trying to
exploit a buffer overflow in an FTP
service by typing really long URLs in
Firefox and Firefox crashed so I thought
great I found a buffer overflow in
Firefox and I went on the slackers IRC
channel to ask what shall I do with this
for a moment code execution
vulnerability that I'm just about to
have in Firefox and they told me about
this website and I can't tell you the
real name but I'm going to call it we
buy own day and the way the side works
is anyone can sign up to it and submit
the details of a critical vulnerability
in a widely used piece of software like
Firefox and their team of internal
experts will evaluate this vulnerability
and if they like it they'll make an
offer to buy the intellectual property
from you and if you accept the offer
then they get it if you reject the offer
or they don't make any offer then they
will act as though they never seen that
vulnerability so it's a system built on
trust you have to trust that the company
will do what they say but it was quite a
widely respected company so it seemed
like it works and I try to build an
exploit
this stuff overflow turned out it wasn't
it was a denial of service but anyway I
submitted it anyway why not and while
submitting it I noticed that this
website didn't have any cross-site
request forgery tokens anywhere and I
thought okay that's a bit weird looks
like I can't really make a page which
will change someone's email address and
hijack their account and get me access
to all their zero dates that's kind of
cool and then I thought what should I do
with this vulnerability I know what to
do I'll sell it to these guys so an hey
there
I found this vulnerability it's not in a
widely used piece of software but it
isn't your website and it can be used to
hijack people's account would you prefer
to buy this vulnerability from me or
would you rather act like you never knew
it even existed and somewhat predictably
they ended up buying it from me and at
the time I was pretty happy with that
outcome in effect that was the first bug
bounty that I ever got but in retrospect
I have to wonder how a security company
that's staffed by an internal team of
security experts where all the users are
also security experts that's full of
easily sold intellectual property can
have a trivial cross-site request
forgery vulnerability that's really easy
to find and exploit I think the only
answer is the back in 2009 awareness of
cross my request for you was just really
poor the vulnerabilities were there they
were easy to find but nobody was looking
for them and what I'm going to show you
today is that thats where causes at the
moment first I'll talk very briefly
about the fundamentals of cause from a
hackers point of view and I'll focus on
various limitations that are in the
cause design and implementation and the
workarounds that real websites end up
doing to handle these limitations and
then I'll look at what goes wrong with
these workarounds and how we can use it
to steal bitcoins and hack various other
sites and then I'll look at some more
esoteric issues and ways to exploit
causes that are a bit less obvious
and then I'll talk about various
mitigations that browser vendors
specification authors and developers can
take and take five minutes of questions
so who's here who here is already
familiar with the basics of how courts
works okay cool most of you that's good
if you're not this one sliders who
you're going to get so please pay
attention cause is about what a website
can make your web browser do I say the
Eurozone Gmail and you want to let users
embed their Dropbox files you can easily
make the users web browsers send a
request to Dropbox and Dropbox will send
the response but the web browser won't
let Gmail read the response from Dropbox
thanks to the same origin policy which
is like what underpins most web security
but say that Dropbox
actually trusts Gmail and thinks they
have a reasonably secure setup I want to
let Gmail embed their users files
that's where cross-origin resource
sharing comes in they can specify this
HTTP header which says they trust Gmail
and the web browser will compare the
origin its own mail or Google comm with
the one specified in this header and if
they match then it gives access to that
content now by itself that header only
gives access to users public files on
Dropbox if job box wanted to let Gmail
embed users private files those has to
add this additional header which is
called allow credentials and set it to
true that means that the web browser
will send the user the users cookies
when it fetches this file and so private
files can be accessed too so that's the
core concept of course as all a hacker
really needs to know about the basics of
how it works and from that it doesn't
sound like there's very much potential
for things to go wrong and as long as
Dropbox doesn't like tri-polar header or
Gmail doesn't get hacked then it's not
too bad but what if Dropbox decides the
Yahoo Mail also has a highly secure
operation and they want to trust your
email - you might think from reading the
specification
that job box could specify a list of
origins which they trust but in practice
that doesn't work you can only ever
specify one origin so what do you do if
you want to trust most college uns well
hold that thought
also what if you want to trust all
subdomains of your site you might know
that cause supports wildcards but
unfortunately the only wildcard it
supports is a star on its own you can
say you trust all lava jhin's you can
say you trust one specific halogen but
your car say I trust all my subdomains
or something like that which seems to be
quite a common use case in real sites
also there's a special exception with
the way that the wild-card has treated
which is if you use the wild-card in
conjunction with the allow credentials
header web browsers will ignore that
allow credential setup this kind of
makes sense because if you browse the
web you'll find random sites like
developers mozilla.org that inexplicably
say they want to trust all their private
data with every web site on the internet
but so in fact so this looks really
scary but in fact it's not actually
about that so what do you do if you want
to trust multiple origins or all of your
subdomains you've only got one choice
which is to dynamically inspect their
incoming origin header from the browser
and decide if you trust it and if you do
trust it reflect it back to the user and
making that flash is the only way I can
do justice to how bad it is it's bad
because it's much more likely to be
vulnerable you've gone from a static
hard-coded value to something that's
dynamically generated based on user
input but it's even worse than that
because it's also somewhat I can tell
much less likely to be discovered during
a pen test because if you don't send any
course headers when you're browsing when
you're doing a security audit you won't
see any cause headers coming back from
the site if it's doing dynamic
generation so you'll never realize the
site even uses quartz
and I think as a result of that you've
got a whole bunch of sites where this
security critical functionality based on
pars and user-supplied yoloz hasn't even
gone through a security audit so when I
say people's awareness of cause is
really poor in this year everyone's
heard of cause but I think a huge number
of people haven't realized how
widespread dynamic generation is because
if you don't look for it you just won't
find it so I'm going to look at what
goes wrong with a bunch of sites that I
found in the world all of these sites
have bug bounty programs so you can be
reasonably sure that these have already
been fairly heavily tested by other
people before me also when I did this
research I was extremely lazy I used
like a four line curved script and I
didn't bother registering or logging in
to any of these sites so all the
vulnerabilities I'm going to talk about
in this section they're real
vulnerabilities and they're low-hanging
fruit they're easy to find
okay first off there's simplest thing
that can go wrong when you dynamically
generate the allow origin header is that
you just reflect whatever origin header
you get given which is surprisingly
common for such a crazy behavior I very
quickly found a Bitcoin exchange which I
sadly can't name that had this behavior
so if we look at the top request this
says hi I'm skeleton scribe dotnet can I
access this users private key there five
at a pikey that is and this exchange
says yes skeleton described on there you
sound trustworthy have this users pro
private API key and that means with a
tiny bit of trivial JavaScript I can
grab anyone's private API key and once
I've got the safety Ikey I've got quite
a few options the first thing to do
would probably be to disable
notifications on the user's account as
Bitcoin exchanges have a history of
being hacked horribly modern ones are
very keen to show how seriously they
take security now one of the ways they
do that is by generating email
notifications for practically every
action
if you sign in you get a notification if
you change any settings you get a
notification and if you make any trades
or whatever you get a notification but
that's cool because the API key can be
used to silently turn off all
notifications after that well I probably
enable two-factor authentication on
their account tie to my phone which just
means they can't log in and sets me up
nicely for the next stage which is just
the transfer their bitcoins to an
address of my choice or to use their
account to play straight because this is
because this is a Bitcoin exchange if I
were to compromise a decent number of
accounts with this I could potentially
pump up the value of an altcoin and that
I bought in on previously and thus
indirectly generate myself money without
leaving a massive audit trail although
because this is a Bitcoin leaving a
massive audit trail isn't too much of a
problem when I reported this
vulnerability it was patched in under 20
minutes alive which is the fastest that
I've ever seen a vulnerability patched
they were also kind enough to tell me
that the root cause of this
vulnerability was the vulnerable third
party package that just added these
headers by default so from what I
understand this exchange never actually
intended to use Commons in the first
place it just kind of popped up there
and remove the less security great other
times people try to validate the header
the origin header but something goes
wrong here this is a different exchange
post I cut mine for other reasons and
they're validating that the origin
starts with BTC net I think they think
that the origin header might contain a
full URL specifying a part and suchlike
and that's why they're doing this but of
course that means they trust BTC evil
dotnet which is not great when I found
this I thought cool I'll just find out
how I still bitcoins from this site and
then that will go into my talk willingly
but due to the design of that API I ran
into some difficulties with that
and I couldn't actually prove that it
was a serious security issue in the time
I took so I thought I'll just come back
to this later and have another go and
when I came back in a couple of weeks I
found that that the site had just shut
down completely the company like ceased
operations and if you wanted your
bitcoins but you had to phone them up so
that's why I'm twisted concepts this one
I'm not going to speculate as that why
that would have happened just something
to watch out for when you're dealing
with Bitcoin exchanges I guess something
else that some sites do is they validate
the end of the origin and they forget to
put a dot start so here I think they're
trying to trust all their subdomains
this is the mate oh this is the real
site I have a bug bounty program and
they trust not as a mate Oh calm great
work probably the most noteworthy thing
here is the number of security headers
they've got they've got content security
policy strict Transport Security content
type options XSS protection and yet with
two extra headers they remove all their
security the other notable thing about
this for mobility is that it's possibly
the least impressive bug bound kicks
difference that I've ever had I reported
this issue to them and didn't get any
reply and I reminded them a few times
and I still didn't get any reply and I
thought okay whatever I don't really
care I'll just full disclose it in
ninety days and after ninety days I went
to full disclose it and I found that
they fixed so they didn't reply to me
they didn't acknowledge it or give me
any credit or anything then one hacker
won but they did fix it I'm not sure why
they would do that I think maybe they
thought this was quite an embarrassing
issue perhaps but well it's public now
anyway okay both of those all three of
those issues are quite obvious provided
you're looking for cause issues now I'm
going to look at some more subtle
perhaps more technically interesting
ways to screw up cause on your site if
you were paying attention earlier you
would have noticed that
specification has a reference to the
null origin which raises the question
what is the neurology and I decided to
spoof the no origin to a bunch of sites
to see if anybody trusted it and I found
that Google Google's PDF viewer which
converts a PDF and HTML trusts to no
origin with credentials so that's cool
and even better there's a Bitcoin wallet
that trusts in origin excellent you can
find loads more sites that have
explicitly whitelisted the null origin
using rapid sevens sonar HTTP which is a
great resource or using showed out so
that just leaves the question well how
do I get the now origin who has it
accepted wisdom on Stack Overflow and
the like seems to be the local file this
file was on your local filesystem use
the null origin and I think that might
be why it ends up being white listed but
there's this great little html5 feature
which is the sandbox attribute for
iframes the purpose of this is to
prevent the contents of an iframe from
doing anything bad by isolating it in a
separate origin and you can probably
guess what origin it puts the contents
in it's the null origin yeah so that
means any website can get hold of the
null origin and thanks to that I could
still use as Google at the count details
like their user ID they their email
address nothing super sensitive but some
stuff you probably don't want every
website uses in knowing and I could also
download encrypted backups of other
people's Bitcoin wallets and you might
think it's encrypted what can I do but
luckily for me it's encrypted with the
password that the user chose on the
website which didn't even have a
password strength meter at the time and
here I was able to launch an offline
brute-force attack against it so that
was potentially quite serious so in
conclusion what have we learned about
the null origin well it's actually the
wild card in disguise if some
they trust star you can tell what they
could try to say if they say they trust
no it's not immediately obvious that
they're giving access to every site out
there but actually it's worse than the
wild-card it's more dangerous because
the exception with regard to credentials
and the wild-card doesn't apply to the
null origin so if you say you trust the
null origin with credentials you are
genuinely sacrificing the same-origin
policy entirely on your site there's one
other thing about the now origin I think
the work the choice of the term null was
not ideal because some what I can tell
some frameworks let they let you
configure which origins you want your
application to trust and if you don't
bother to configure the value of this
variable then the programming language
decides to output it is null so you're
trying to say I don't trust any sites
and the end result is that you trust
every site on the Internet
perhaps it should be renamed okay let's
look at a different slightly subtle
issue which I'm going to live demo on
Google Finance right so here on Google
Finance we can see some share
information related to my to my account
and if I was a hypothetically rich
person the share information might be
really quite valuable so let's see if
the site is using course
I just realize that not display screen
this would take a second
right so we were just on Google Finance
with some share info and I've just sent
in a request and got it in verb so I'm
going to see if these guys support cause
I'm just going to delete this token here
because I can't guess the value of that
but it doesn't actually make any
difference right so first off if you
look at the head as you're getting back
there were no calls head is there so a
tested that wasn't acutely aware of
dynamic cause generation might not
realize the slightest supports caused at
all but we're going to try an origin we
think they're likely to trust like
google.com like google.com probably
trust Google calm and if we send that
then sure enough we've got them trusting
Google calm with credentials fair enough
no security risk alert and we can try
the obvious at attacks of seeing if
they're using starts with or ends with
but as you can see we don't get the
origin headers back they're just not
working also if you try the null origin
then it causes an internal server error
but there's no actual vulnerability that
has just kind of funny but interestingly
they are trusting all their subdomains
so I can put anything google.com and
that by itself isn't too bad but they
also don't validate the protocol so here
HTTP Google com is saying they trust
HTTP evil or Google com
let's see if we can do anything
interesting with that
okay so say that you're in a say that
I'm accessing Google Finance I've got
some sensitive share info on there and
you're in a position to view and tamper
with my network traffic maybe I'm using
insecure Wi-Fi in a coffee shop maybe
you've done BGP hijacking on my
company's office that's kind of
fashionable at the moment or maybe
you're just at NSA sitting on every
networks
sampling with everything anyway if I
access Google Finance directly that's
protected with HTTPS it's pretty
difficult for you to modify view or
tamper with that content but as soon as
I load any site over HTTP you can
intercept that request and spoof
whatever response you like so here I try
and load cnn.com and you can redirect me
to evil google calm and the grouser will
silently follow that redirects and load
up HTTP evil or Google com
and once again it's an unencrypted
connection you can catch that request
and spoof the response and now you're
going to send some malicious JavaScript
that's going to use courts it's going to
use cause to send a request to Google
Finance and the browser will put on this
origin header saying this request to
Google Finance is coming from evil
Google com
but as we've seen Google just that so
they go great that's a trust where the
origin and past my sensitive financial
information back to your malicious
JavaScript which you can then log or
send off to wherever you want so
although Google Finance is using HTTPS
they've kind of undone their use of
HTTPS through their use of course ie
when I found this issue
I thought about reporting it to Google
and I wasn't sure if it was serious
enough for them to care so I sent them
an email and didn't get a reply and so I
was like fine I'll just live them on it
because I don't think this is a serious
issue really requires a
man-in-the-middle and a few weeks after
my presentation I got a direct message
on Twitter and I said hey there you know
that vulnerability in Google Finance you
demoed yeah I submitted it to Google and
they paid me a thousand
hopefully I'm not 100% your the truth of
this I haven't fully verified it yet but
my presentations might be more valuable
than you think okay you might now be
thinking great I know how to safely
trust all of my subdomains
I've just got a whitelist the protocol
and these ends with the dot but please
don't do that
for start obviously if any of your
subdomains have cross-site scripting
you've just removed your security and
some even quite well secured
applications like bugzilla have
intentional cross-site scripting
vulnerabilities on subdomains it's a
feature it doesn't compromise the
stability of Bugzilla due to the way
it's implemented but it will compromise
your site if you trust all your
subdomains also if you've got hanging
sea names and the like someone might sub
hijack a subdomain third parties all
that stuff even if all your
infrastructure is completely secure and
there's no one XSS vulnerability in it
or any of the third parties or using
anywhere your customers your clients
infrastructure can lead to excess
vulnerabilities in subdomains some
unscrupulous ISPs they detect a failed
DNS lookup and they inject a page a fake
search page basically full of adverts to
get some ad revenue and these pages have
a history of occasionally being
vulnerable to cross-site scripting so
someone could inject something that does
not resolve dot your site calm the ISP
injects a page full of ads and it's
vulnerable to JavaScript injection and
you've just lost your security in fact
recently someone found that McAfee web
gateway which is something designed to
make your enterprise users more secure
or something had a very similar behavior
so only a few months ago if you were
using McAfee Web Gateway this was
introducing a cross-site scripting
vulnerability into the page it showed
for every domain name they didn't result
this is quite a good example of how
adding security mechanisms can introduce
vulnerabilities if you
lay along complexity and additional
layers you'll get interactions between
layers which remove your security okay
so far I've focused on exploiting sites
that have said that allow credentials
flag to trick that's because most of the
time if this flag is set to false or not
specified which just means it defaults
to false you can't do very much because
you might as well send a request
directly rather than using your victim
to send it but sometimes there's
something about the users environment
which we can exploit the very well-known
case of this which for the sake of
completeness I absolutely can't skip is
that even if you don't allow credentials
if you allow access from arbitrary
origins using cause you're losing a lot
of ie IP based security that your site
might have for example the the IDE
IntelliJ which was for Java but that
which was for Java development binds a
server to localhost so you can't access
as an attacker you can't hit the server
directly because it's bound to your
victims localhost but someone found that
thanks to their course configuration
they could ask this server they could
make you ask the server for your private
SSH keys which it would hand over to an
RBC site so that was kind of bad and in
fact using a couple of additional issues
they got a remote code execution and
they ultimately got a $50,000 bounty for
this which is not bad so I highly
recommend reading the blog post I
submitted something to those guys
recently but sadly didn't get $50,000
bounty so if your site uses IP based
access controls IP whiteness or binding
to an inaccessible network interface
you've got to be really careful with
your use of course now for some more
exciting stuff if you read the core
specification you'll find a section
titled implementation considerations and
that's a code word for hackers please
pay attention to this section it says if
you dynamic
generate the allow origin header make
sure you specify very origin if you
don't then something may go wrong and
you might think okay specifying a static
header what could possible who could
fail to do that
that sounds really easy and I guess it
is pretty easy probably the first people
to fail to do this will the w3c speaking
to this brilliant quote I must say it
doesn't make me very confident that soon
more sites will be supporting cause it's
not even the w3c manages to configure
its server like well said could have
said it better myself so what happens if
you don't specify this header well most
of the time I think things will just not
work but sometimes it's more interesting
if you've done a lot of web app pen
testing you probably from time to time
encountered an unexploited or cross-site
scripting vulnerability that looks
vaguely like this so here the problem is
that the users input that's being
reflected is coming in the X user HTTP
header and there's no way to make
someone's browser send that header
across the main normally now thanks to
the course head it though we can see in
the response we can send this header
cross-domain with some JavaScript now by
itself that doesn't actually make this
issue exploitable because we're sending
this request with JavaScript the
response is just landing in a JavaScript
variable so our injected HTML isn't
being rendered it's just being stored in
a variable but if they haven't specified
very origin then this response may be
cached and may be served up on
subsequent requests to this page so just
by appending a tiny bit more code we can
say send this payload with course and
then we can redirect the user to exactly
the same euro and the browser will
probably go oh I've already cached this
response and then show the user the page
with the injected JavaScript so
cross-site scripting someone and because
this is exploiting the browser cache a
client-side cache it's actually quite
reliable it works most of the time
if the stars are aligned you might be
able to get away with server-side cash
poison it's quite common for sites that
will say the origin header to reflect it
regardless of whether it's actually a
valid origin or not and Internet
Explorer the guards the regards a
carriage return i /r as being a valid
terminator for HTTP header so when it
looks at the response to that to that
request it sees an additional content
type header which changes the char set
to UTS seven which is great for
triggering cross-site scripting
vulnerabilities and once again by itself
this isn't much good because there's no
way I can make your version of Internet
Explorer so in such a dodgy origin
header but what I can do is use book and
manually send our origin head in myself
and in hope it gets cached on the server
site and served up to other users and if
the very origin header isn't set by the
server that's not implausible so that's
cool in theory you can have any kind of
vulnerability in the processing of the
origin header like someone could be
using in a sequel statement but this is
a vulnerability with it that I've
actually seen quite a few times so what
have we learnt firstly most importantly
if you're a pen tester make sure you
look for dynamic generation of course
headers whenever you test a site you've
got to specify an origin header that you
think they're likely to trust to try and
coax them into revealing this
functionality and then if you do find it
I just audit if it has any of the
vulnerabilities that I've mentioned the
verb suite scanner will of course do
this for you automatically as I'll
fairly recently but it won't build an
exploit for you and that's probably
where the most fun is to be had as far
as the specification goes well I think
the wild card exception with credentials
has been a good thing for security
because we've seen it saved sites like
developers Mozilla dorg but I think it
should be applies to the null origin too
because that's just as dangerous or it's
more dangerous at the moment I actually
suggested this to the WCC earlier this
week and someone from Dropbox replied
and said actually Dropbox relies on
having credentialed access to the null
origin so that might be problematic I
just need to persuade them to implement
it in a different way and we might be
able to push that forward also I think
the specification should allow for
partial wildcards to let people with a
static value trust all their subdomains
and reduce the number of sites forced to
do dynamic generation as far as browsers
go I definitely think they should allow
multiple origins to be specified in a
static way in this header because once
again that reduces the number of sites
forced to do dynamic generation which is
risky coding and it's often implemented
in weird places like like in Apache
configs and stuff rather than an actual
code where it's likely to get a proper
review also browsers could take the
opportunity to block a reverse mixed
content basically that issue that I
showed you on Google Finance browsers
already blocked HTTPS sites trying to
load scripts over HTTP but they're very
happily as we saw let HTTP site glance
full access to http origin so why not
just brought that - if you're a
developer well is possible don't do
dynamic generation of course headers
that's the safest approach but if you
have to validate with caution make sure
it gets a security audit and don't
forget to verify the protocol and always
specify very origin and never trust null
that goes for you to Dropbox okay you
can grab the slides or that and there's
a write up of like the core technical
content of this online and the three key
things to remember are that cause
msconfig relations are often critical
sometimes subtle and absolutely out
there if you look for them I'm going to
take five minutes of questions now and
if you have any more after that after
that you can come and speak to
down the back and also if you've got any
questions about the CERN interesting
interplays between vendors and the
latest I watch the top 10 and number 7
I'd be very happy to talk about that as
well yeah don't forget to follow me on
Twitter
thank you for listening so it the what
Oh
does the flag allow credentials does it
work only with cookies I think it allows
basic or those you got to but it won't
allow you know like your random X header
that you've got some JavaScript sticking
on because you the that's not like a
browser handled I could enjoy okay
thanks any other questions at all okay
cool thank you