I gave for inter destiny I don't
everyone I'm Kazuki to go thank you for
coming into my station today my station
is today how to read better security
through mini hardening project when I
was in Japan I was organiser of
hardening project mini Halloween
projects so today I want to talk about
that
my name is Kazuki I was organized of
mini hardening in the path that's why
I'm standing here when I was in Japan I
also belong to last Japan marketing with
G I will talk about data moving me to
Java history I was working for Nikkei
which is a famous economic newspaper
company in Japan that company's owner
all Financial Times you know that and
after that I moved to elaborate Japan
and then as a cloud Support Engineer
cloud Support Engineer is a customer
support by phone and chat or email but a
very technical position then customer is
asking about the program I will help
them as far as we can even if it's not
issue address and last August I moved to
Dublin to bear the Japanese team a
Tavares customer support Japanese team
has two sites in Seattle and in Tokyo
and so doubling insult site and you can
see my name if you like Japanese
questions you can see that you know I
think you know a place but today you
address has over 80 services I know or
mustard and in the past we have watched
marketing with sea which is frontier
group
for letting people and all security
about 10 people are working here are
there that's see I'm not security at
this part so I'm counterfeit engineer
but I strongly estate seal securities
experts
so I belong to that team the main
purpose is marketing or what so having a
booth at a big companies then we gave up
papers to explain the last lots of
people sell like that oh I've never had
blast or like that oh I had my first
name but realized so it's helpful so
that's our motivation once to Japan have
local chapter at low Q to Cannes I send
a customer these are large areas and
city in Japan and sometimes mini
hardening project which is which I
organized is cooperated with them and
exhibited our competition okay this is
today's agenda I will talk about
hardening project first it's an
introduction then let's talk about
original and very heartening project in
second topic as our topic I will explain
the detail of my our competition I will
talk about motivation and past
competition and then showing technical
elements and forth since the title of
this session is how to read so I will
also talk about creating team if we want
to do a similar event I think you might
find it helpful
and finally fix topic 8 conclusion
here it's not the first topic is about
housing project nowadays is a variety of
risk you know for example
DTOs by Amelia Voght net is very no
issue today that kind of water nets are
possible to generate a huge traffic and
brew never devices are not easy to fix
that and another girl's breed was well
known issue address only one only one by
P bug but it was a large issue also we
cannot ignore our kind of services I
show them in the world
there are so many open bolt but you know
today's you can see a lot of competition
Rex appear capture-the-flag becoming
very common second in Japan is a Vegas
city resident a bit of course you know
this phone is one of the biggest
conference and other can be sensitive
lengths and see this time is showing
lots of competitions these competitions
are focusing on very technical it sings
very nice really nice and this cone is
including social hug event but however
please thinking about business in
security area sorry is coming from sales
of course I know many many security guys
thinking about your day our own business
I know that here I want to say there are
no events or competitions with
considering realloc situation at father
I know yet here we have hardening
project
hardening project is not only security
competition but also focusing on
business let me talk about word trust we
are basically focusing on three kind of
elements to understand hardening project
I think a variation rules are good steps
to know first I was first one is report
every team have to send a report
regarding the investigation till end of
the competition I don't know in the
other situation it's very important to
report and share the situation second
one itself if you have ecommerce site is
directly applied to sales amount
you cannot stop important ecommerce site
so you have to protect your business as
well the last lines security
investigation our name is starting by
cutting so security investigation is
important of course in hardening project
each team take over proneural
environment basically there are
ecommerce site because it's easy to a
major SLA instead other content such as
customer support for and VPN endpoint
and monitoring system their own and
window we must try and at work you have
to avoid the scoping sa Rae is important
things to school and housing project is
trying to simulate their business so
each team have to treat customer and
just take holders as well like boss
all of you is reckless real guys are
dendi and green guides are professional
t like me 10 days in the next slide
having environment including ecommerce
site and you can see by our database at
where you can see that it depends on
story and in light up a site there is a
professional team the team is trying to
inspect servers and then stopping
important demo
recruiting servers and disappearing
contents so Saturday eating some
important things are bad crap log dive
deep and one time and place it right on
the side yet flora of Game Master this
guy this flora is simulating customer
such as buying web buying something and
a growing website also clora
this one and evaluating SLA over each
website which means for example even if
ecommerce site is still alive you can
see see that and possible to buy
something but if customer support form
is done then some customer might be
supine
while we are in business there are lots
of stakeholders here in our mini
hardening project each team has to be
aware of them probably
your boss is ordering something you are
in competition at a slightly more email
next let me talk about original and mini
hardening project the original one is
called hardening project it's a simple
project name and our is called mini
since it's smaller than original
original housing project that is since
it is security competition but focused
on business we also need a kind of
business skills such as writing the
email or reporting listen to the high
level team were sending email for all
customers in database when data breaches
happen that's all the expected behavior
but it's not it's not easy to do that
then the program is original line so big
event and mini is smaller than original
so it's possible to frequently our mini
hardening project studied since 2012
2014 here let me show you define lots of
different theories but mostly depending
on scale our competition is smaller than
reasonable k-member is ha and
competition time is less than half three
hours but our me is not difficult I
think notes are only two to three
security issues are 10 to 20
here you can fix them easy such as find
update WordPress update and fix lightly
Devils by such kind of activity then
your enemy's time you only have three a
lot it's very short and in original
hardening project there are 64 50 to 60
issues that's too much
I think Israeli attack guards can
inspect her about as well also attack
coming but our designs we have only only
have three to four persons but our
original hardware project has over 10
persons only attack turns and another
difference is creating see unscientific
is exponential of I mean housing project
these pictures during competition when
you attend to hardening project possible
to experience a security issues I think
that is a precious opportunity also it
is suitable for training to know a weak
point a meaning is only run the event
mostly using common and security a very
common and simple security issues we are
thinking about some attendees might be
nervous and you know I'm very say
Japanese is mostly shy I think so
requirement is not seen I can go event
without friends in past we have end
conditions during almost three years we
do not create environment each time we
are using same environment in shutdown
three four five times we had around 100
attendees in series on competitions
and after that we decided to recreate
new environment but then I already
decided to move the W at sorry 2016 so
today other guys are having
responsibility for that they already had
three events on 68 attendees invited
with spray engineering environment
this is timeline basically we have
computational at subject start at 10:30
then some team is studying ice break
cause mostly person does not know each
other which means fascinating
competition itself is starting at 12 and
enzyme is 15 this is again only one day
event so we have to decide ranking on 15
to 16 I'll talk about excitement later
but this one hour is quite busy after
the cognition and ending session we
start drinking this is also good
opportunity for night 20 the next is
technical element in construction and
security issues and also scoring first
of all we are using a debrief we
recreated environment by using V PC and
ec2 and we of course sent request of
simulated event for degrees it's
approved based on policy of address it
is basically allowed except specific
very cheap instance okay you can see Bob
your infrastructure I left I screen guys
are you know professor dream on room
guys attendees on left side here is the
resources for professional team and
light side is resources for attendees
and then go be there and other ways it's
completely closed environment on the
using by PC to implement all stuff
princey next right green guys there is a
manager interface which is a controlled
by professional T general to see and
eNOS registered in a scaredy DNS so if
it's too long but also Tivat eNOS and
many services tend to miss a very tiny
services is here if we can recreate that
and other services because it's a closed
environment and after that also
attendees hug or or so that resulted
it's an we think about SAS digital
services are sorry software the puppies
not far bird but
it's authorities and here is a you can
see that firewall where we keep straight
and wintering system and Ginny's chest
and at today's and web servers as well
each attendees has clients here general
range of brands and Tom have an Italian
axe first first-time attendees are
connected to each client then it is
possible to access the resources okay
and good moment yeah and you can see
three servers and one is resources here
it's a fake ad resourcing which means
experience and dummy ecommerce site or
fishing services if client is sitting
attendees might be access to free up
resources and attackers has only saw set
over here is crystal and Mario host and
she has a lot of clients
cause some attendees are usually
investigation by IP address rules based
on based on IP addresses IP table so it
is a point over here and if a specific
address is broked and then another
instance used at first you can see only
one column here
attack Laura so Laura is evaluating a
surname Unser's among like an simulating
customer behavior so here it's an
overview and moving the vulnerabilities
you know common security issues are
using old versions bash pods open SSL
plot to these old versions are having
critical issues so I think you cannot
forget major issues such as heart rate
or stroke also well-known issues are
very simple they are responsible for
history working especially the first
configuration is another issue so for
example the photo per pod is causing
issues when load increased typically we
have to configure Mark's client then at
last as I issue is SSL certificate is by
expiring then we should updated expired
certificate at work okay pleasing
nothing if competition is started and
you found issues like an weak passwords
or Valjean okay change password and
update old versions ok uses done after
spending here our professional team will
provide short movie it's a few Japanese
but I translated sovereign Caesar
attention Allah next AHA cozy poday go
yonder Norelco Dionisio salaita K Bonet
Kiba dachi no Kudo she reminds us a tale
or a style Co comedy no Katya cheers I
can talk on Okinawa nakka nakka doc will
spare you today
but ASIMO Natasha she don't mainly I
keep that stone as you know me don't
stay to knock you out of the way so low
and I cannot forego their rock allow yo
Josh Danzig are you Mahalakshmi Romita
team III notice villa de leyva kanashimi
Totino quagga Kyoukai sir yo can you
il-10 tequila or economical committed
suicide are you gonna came through you
know not sure diameter we also have ng
online statistic relation horses sounds
general Starr trusting these effects of
harder than before
if critical issues in environment are
not resolved you can see sub very
building stopping important demons and
content disappearing triturated or
encrypted and also flow HTTP dolly dos
attacks effective just SLA here
necessary investigations
backup content stop is Damon
finding malicious file process change we
cluster on when competition is over we
have to create squad as I mentioned
before we are not only taking server but
also reading report carefully we are
focusing on business again reports are
important things
even if issue is only reported we will
count as a report school fixing security
issues are counting school but it's not
high school
so reporting and fixing if she had a
slight pause condition it could be
highest and to evaluate we made a shell
script because we only have an hour
after the competition ended so
automatically judging expected fix on
each servers
after that Ranieri we are seeing
irregular or find pride in each
environment manually ok here swings
causes of me having projects so start
from website here is a vulnerabilities
right and then expected initiation here
between answers and here's a checkpoint
how to check by professional team and we
also have to be based score and last
card line is team squad constructed by
six to eight weeks to school and
reporting school fix school fix to
squirrels taking real environment by
script automatically and it means seeing
hips are not if not fixed putting zero
and suggest the post deputies score
professional team read report carefree
and if issue is reported putting here
pay school I think you can guess three
theory Japanese but you can just for
example shows a graph wrote
FTP users or grab I hear sorry
grab a toast a server or silicon on top
- here like this it's been very basic
things okay last section on this topic
provides very simple are submitting
customer showing survive living or not
verified content with the latest or not
legacy and poor check it is not digital
to injury but flora is quite important
for showing SLA on real-time metrics and
simulating custom behavior first topic
is creating own event in our case to
manage the address this infrastructure
Japanese one foreign security
organization sponsored artificially it
cost around $100 each competition of
course team members or volunteer so I
have to ask them to provide private time
for this project this case is not easy
to meet in person
of course professionals are very busy
and another problem is that a person is
in Okinawa which is a island in Japan
and 1500 kilometers away Tokyo from
Tokyo is amazing Mironov III is far from
here under maybe 1500 kilometres away so
we are discussing in online by using
slug file-sharing by Google Doc and
their video meetings by Google hangout
even though we hardening projectors I
said it's a smaller than or is not one
but we need a lot of effort before
competition organizers are tasks such as
team building and implement reliability
and making sure script and attacking
with your attendees in completion day
it's sitting time but for white hackers
after that we have to evaluate besides
ranking and like feedback for everything
but it was not all we had for common
words when we start the inhuman powers
not strong but easy to talk to each
other today the team has at least seven
members except me I'm remotely helping
them a bit so desperately the road to
organizer and other grants across Turkey
and chlorogene as we're talking about by
flight benefit widen it a first thing
this networking opportunity I can
connect with other specialists and I've
had my growth
this is not section conquer ISM if you
are interested in a kind of a double
event personally I think you can use bwa
it is a broken web application project
to start from small things it's not so
it's now inactive but you can imagine
what kind of vulnerability is impossible
to break and how to fix that you can try
them another two is you know what stood
up it is a wonderful tool for evaluating
automatically after complications we can
bring together in is a pair it is a
Japanese cone public drinking space we
are really enjoying talk reaches across
that seam and professional team this is
a nice opportunity for networking and
this is a site it's my pleasure if my
presentation is interesting for you and
it contact me for you how interested in
project I can introduce me housing
project and explain about the original
hardening project as well so welcome to
contact me by Facebook Twitter Linkedin
so in my post are almost Stephanie's but
I can try from for you to in English
subtle thank you very much
[Laughter]