hi so I'm Harlan Bravo from check marks
and I'm very happy to be here talking
about DevOps and not actually just
talking about others but rather talking
as part of the whole separate track of
death circle which is a huge progress
and since I have been doing the DevOps
talk for about four years I think that
was the first time and when I had a
stock in almost no fork I think in US
and what was it back then it was DevOps
is here and there is them there are
companies like Netflix and Linkedin who
are doing this cool thing and deploying
two times a day and that's called devil
and we all under them but probably no
one actually do that except them since
then four years passed by and things
changed things change
also from technology perspective and
things change for process perspective so
much more companies much more projects
are doing DevOps now but the thing is
that the definition of DevOps is
actually quite wide so we have this
whole huge tract here a lot of people
all talking about DevOps and it's a very
different definition for each and every
one of what we mean for devil so I
wanted to map that and I also wanted to
map in my presentation what DevOps what
processes what are the building blocks
of DevOps and how security and security
checks might fit in into each and every
one of them
so talking and is a general approach
DevOps is about processes connections
between development test and delivery
processes and automation automation and
tools and that's probably the key here
the automation of those processes so if
we take a look into the building blocks
we have and let's go backwards let's do
some reverse engineering I have been
thinking the whole
'we going backwards and you will see
that the down the presentation
production production is not an actual
parts of death but rather a finish line
so we are going there we are striving
together but the process itself is
getting there so the steps we are
interested in are C ICD and development
those are the building blocks where the
processes actually happens over
production and there might be several
security checks that might be is it we
can apply on each and every step well in
production we have some security checks
that we can put there like laugh and
Russ and there are four CI MCD a
solutions like is dust even penetration
testing will all discuss in which cases
it might fit and in which not and SAS it
also can be a solution for certain steps
so the question is what actually in each
and every building block is about
development is pretty simple one we have
the flow of checking out the code the
developer sit around in their desk jobs
and they check out the code the do the
development is around IDs or without IDs
depends on language they use them
compile and commit it back and it's a
significant part of the process that
where it begins and some security checks
can be applied here again dependent on
the whole process so let's not dive into
it now but rather further and down the
presentation when we see the whole
process composed next step is blocks of
CI and C D so in that an area of a lot
of confusion what's the I stands for
what CD stands for and if you ask people
a lot of people which will say different
things sometimes they confuse CI with CD
and MCD there is also a separate
confusion about it so CI is basically
only the build process is taking the
code checks in and committed are
committed by the developer adding it to
the mainline and making sure it doesn't
break the mainline it doesn't break the
code so basically it's about two using
the right tool and there are great tools
for that today building a pretty simple
process will make that for you and it's
also a great place to imply some
security checks next step is a bit
trickier what C D stands for it's also
continuous something but what D stands
for and that's an important part here
because in general the process is about
taking the code taking the change from
developers up to the user and taking to
the user might mean a lot of different
things it might be a SAS application
which is installing cloud it might be an
on-premise application installed and
delivered for each and every of your
customers and it's a very different
process of deployment so that CD but
there is a huge difference between
continuous delivery and continuous
deployment and in a lot of cases we say
CD when we meet one of them without
making clear water correctly and when
continuous delivery a both of them go
from committing the code running the
unit test building the a package and
running the acceptance test which might
mean a lot to Matic testing a huge suite
of photo mode automatic test but then
the difference is about how we switch to
production for continuous delivery we do
it manually and for continuous
deployment is done automatically and
that's a difference
and that's the difference mites also
huge difference for security because
basically when it's automatic you don't
have a chance to stop it it runs and
either you inherit in the process some
Checkers and sell the process up on
those checkers rather on many off stage
you have a point to make the decision
okay you can see okay we have certain
results of this test we have certain
results of security tests and we might
decide either to go or to stop it to
make the show stop a very important
decision the security policy should
define what are the showstoppers what
would you stop the product the delivery
for and doesn't matter the derivatives
automatic or the deliveries manual but
you should ask yourself these questions
first and only after that you should
think how you will implement this
decision so we have heard a lot of talks
today and some of them are say are we're
asking how many of you are in the
waterfall and how many of you are in
continuous deployment and some guys were
telling us about the great process they
have over continued separation but the
truth is that most projects are
somewhere in the middle and it's not
even organization wise it rises
specifically ProjectWise because there
are a lot of organizations where you can
find all of them some legacy projects
are still releasing each eighteen months
and some newer projects are deploying
few times a day and for those projects
you shall find a different
implementation of security policy and
that's a very important decision because
otherwise it will probably I don't want
to say it will not work but they will
reject it you will be fighting and there
is a way to find a way there is a way to
find how the security my feet each and
every
stage where the project is each and
every flow the project is implementing
the important key sandals here is the
first right the project is on the DevOps
scale the further left the security
should start and why is that
let's take a deeper look into how the
process goes if the log into CI CD again
we have drops to the deployment what the
deployment process is less important for
in our case it's the look into this flow
in this flow we have the CI and the CD
component and it does really matter here
where the CCD is continuous delivery or
continuous deployment so what happens
here we have the checkout and the
compilation and the unit testing that
continuous integration continuous
integration is the first step where you
can start implementing the security
policy then we switch to the CD part in
the CD part there is the price and
package creation the deployment and the
environment that of environment that you
might choose to deploy as an end-to-end
test so again going backwards we can
take a look and into the answer incest
and so and test differ for those who go
for continuous deployment versus
continuous delivery for example if you
are not practicing continuous deployment
you can really afford during the
penetration testing penetration testing
is depends on the deployment environment
it's used to put their several
environments not just staging and
testing environment but just deploy a
separate I know few of our customers who
work this way if for example you plan
your releasing an on-prem application
which is released each two months it's
free month you can really afford putting
aside separately
system and man penetration testing on
each version it's really possible and
you will still doing the CD it will not
stop the city it will run the size of it
the same goes for dust and I are
destined ayahs are both a bit time
consuming a product but again then they
can run if they are not stopping the
process and here at the end of the
process it's really the final frontier
before is or taking the decision to go
to production or going back into the
development process so if the
development process is not stopping in
the production is not stopping they can
keep running
aside of affair of the whole circle and
here again we are coming back to the
question what would you stop the process
over if the penetration testing finds
what type of finding would make you say
it's a showstopper we are not proceeding
further or if the dust finds or is it is
find and here is another very important
question how do you trust how do you
trust all penetration testers usually
it's a pretty trusted source but the
tools we all know the tools are might be
different there might be more testable
and then what might be less stressful
and that stability and the trust is very
important for the decision making and
for choosing the place in the process
where you choose to integrate the tool
another important aspect of of the
decision-making is the dependency check
and that's something that you can also
do in step in several stages of your
process you can do the dependency check
when you create the document and it
might be an important choice to do it
there because actually docker brings a
makes a difference here versus the
packages we used to do two years ago
because usually you don't even if you
did the dependency check in previous
step
it is a dependency checks of the
libraries that you are using in your
code but into the docker you're all for
packaging and things like oils or web
servers which were not checked as part
of the development process so this is a
point where you should take the decision
and you might want to do the checkers
both here and in previous stages and
here we also have the continuous
integration part where we can do also a
lot of checks the continuous integration
part is very important actually because
it happens usually much much often than
the continuous deployment if well for
those who are doing the continuous
deployment it's actually the same thing
but for those who don't and that let it
means the majority of the project it
actually happens much often usually the
continuous integration is few times a
day and the continuous and the CD
process might be a once a day a nightly
build it might be also once a week for
certain project it depends a lot if the
project is legacy with you and that's
actually also very important input into
your decision legacy project brings in a
lot of old code all code that nobody
actually knows what he'll happening
there as millions in a lot of cases
millions of lines of code with a lot of
security vulnerabilities that have been
there for years already and that's an
important and here it brings us to an
important decision how we treat the sect
and do we want to fix everything we find
or we want to do some segregation and
hold the cells or will do is I would
like to map this into some sort of
policy mapping and policy implementation
meting into the process
so gone further and from the CI decision
the CI decision is mainly do you break
the build over security and I have been
in a lot of conferences when the key
word would be break to build over
security go ahead guys break build over
security it's a great goal to go for but
the actual thing the devops people will
probably hate you know I don't know if
you personally they will probably hate
all over the world because the thing
they hate the most is when the build is
broken but the thing is that built
broken build could be justified and
that's the key here
can you bring in the tools that broke
built over very justified result if
results are not justified they will
eventually push you off they will
eventually block the option of breaking
the build because I don't want to go
around and fix something which is
actually false
so the CI is something that all the
system is dependent on CI basically
delays all the process significantly
much more than C then C D de because
that when in my in our own company we
have in the group I work with we have 40
developers when the build breaks or
faulted 40 developers are unemployed
they're sitting and waiting till the
Builder sticks so if you have in a big
organization 36 365 developers and each
developer bridge breaks the builds one
to the zero once a year each day the
bridge the build is broken and they're
not actually proceeding as the process
is stopped so breaking the build is a
very very significant decision and
security professionals should bring
the requirement to bring to break a bill
only when they are really really
trusting the tools the over which
results they want to break the build it
should be it shall be very very
qualified result so what are the
problems of security tools security
checkers is security checks with the
process the speed it takes time to run
it takes time for the security analysis
tools to run and the stability the
stability is basically the quality the
stools bring and it's some combination
sort of combination of time it takes and
the quality ring so if the test security
test runs for seven hours 14 hours and
afterwards brings you 300 results out of
which two hundreds are false positives
you can't really break the build over it
and you actually have a general problem
dealing with it it's a general approach
so here comes the thing of the policy
definition the policy shall fit the
process for the process will not dictate
the policy after all you're the security
professionals and you shall require what
the security stage should be but thing
is that getting to the security stage is
them the process
you shall not start from that point but
you rather shall get there gradually
like one of the possible approaches
would be dividing the session it works
for a Legacy Project dividing two
backlog and new findings if you have 1
million line of code or 3 million line
of code and you scan
and with sass though for example and you
probably that size of the project will
bring you hundreds of findings so the
project has been has been developed
already for ten years five years and
most of developers that started
developing it over the left nobody knows
what's going on there and how to fix it
today on the other hand they keep
developing it so the new findings are
much easier to be sick so if you would
be realistic do this division let the
past be treated separately and let the
future and today be treated in a
separate way so you can implement the
policy you can drop the belt over new
findings while the old findings the
findings of the legacy code you can put
in a backlog as required and the
security team requires some sorts of
burn down for this backlog over the
versions and as a process as the project
goes further that will actually make
much more sense than failing the bill
overall results bill because it still
they clean all hundreds of results it
will take probably years or if it works
very fast month another approach might
be evolving policy start small and add
more and more checks as you go so start
from the most important checkers and
then expand it again even for that
approach you can take both the policy
the division to backlog and the new ones
and the for the most important versions
less important another option is
segregation of the policy over the
molarity type or age so you might want
to be aware of everything that happens
but you would require at the show
stopper only certain things like it
might be a very high severity
vulnerabilities or it might be an age
and it's also very valid approach which
says and based on some standards some
standards require that sort of appliance
when you have a vulnerability in your
code for more than 30 60 or 90 days it
gets a higher priority so if it's only
for 30 days
guys you have sometimes still to fix it
but if we have 60 I will fail the build
and that's something that you can get
out of tools tools allow this option and
this information with regards to the
findings another important aspect to be
taken care of is open source open source
and it's relatively open source security
is surprisingly well relatively new in
part of the whole process and it's very
it's actually surprising because open
source has been here for years more like
I don't know 20 years now more but the
security of open source it still is not
a part of the policy for a lot of
organizations like like okay we have
starts we started thinking about it
because the legal department asked that
but the liability open source brings is
totally comparable to the
vulnerabilities you have in your
internal code it should be mined is the
same way even maybe more seriously
because the vulnerability you have in
your code you're aware of or maybe
someone who is going after you aware of
the vulnerability of the open source are
out public everyone knows about them and
if someone wants to use it they can use
them first and only after that it tries
to discover the vulnerabilities you have
on your code
so we have the code produced in-house
and we have the open-source and the
question is where exactly would be the
best stage of the process to do to
implement security and I will be
probably saying something very known
here but the earlier you fix the issue
the cheaper and easier it would be so
let's go and take a look into the
development process so in the CI process
you have your option now let's see what
actually happens if you shift it all to
the developers place
let's not implement it in the CI but
let's require the developer not to
commit to master branch if there are
security vulnerabilities that is
something that will actually eliminate
the requirement to fail the build to do
the whole headache for the whole company
and for the whole project but it will
shift the headache to be personal
developer a problem so at the beginning
when we do the design it's a known thing
other people talked about it today
designing for security is important it's
not part of of my of my presentation
here but the thing is that this last
part is something that can be done for
developer at the development stage and
also this information is pretty now you
probably have seen it before you can use
it with your management it's very a
management usually love this slide
because there are numbers here and you
actually can show them and see it's
cheaper there let's do it cheaper so the
slide is used for years already and it's
still true
you can't really measure the exact
number but in general its right so
taking a look into the development in
the development process we have the
check out and we
have the ID part as a compilation and
testing so here we can actually do a lot
to prevent the security problem from the
start when the developer is writing the
code there are integrated our tools were
here which are integrating with the IDE
and and allowing to do the security scan
from the ID also the open source
analysis shall be tested at this stage
because in most cases the ones the
chooses to use certain library or not to
use it
first of all is a developer library open
source libraries are not going through
certain committee well there are
companies working this way but there few
of them in most chair in most cases the
variable goes to github walks whatever
component actually does what he needs
download it and put it into the form
file he's working with so already at
this stage the open source analysis
might be performed and that is actually
especially for open source it's a very
important decision because if open
source has vulnerabilities and you are
not a contributor for it for this open
source you will not start fixing it what
you will do in this what you should do
you should change the library and in
easier case it might be look for a newer
version and the newer version already
have it solved but in some cases there
is no newer version so you should change
the library entirely and that's a big
decision and as early this decision is
made early the decision is made the less
painful it would be to do the change so
this part is actually the leftist
frontier and the further the most left
frontier for security check and the less
expensive and the less painful for the
product so taking it back to the whole
picture and so we have the CD
the CI and the development and you can
choose to implement security wherever it
works for the project and for some
project you will require you it might be
enough just to do the checks at the end
of the whole process even if they do see
ICD but they release once a half one
half a year they do it in circle but
they have enough time to do penetration
testing and you don't have the tools and
you don't have the time and the project
is legacy so it's a huge headache now to
start scanning it with the source code
analysis to do only the checks at the
end and that would be good enough on the
other hand if you have continuous
deployment you can't really afford it
or if you don't have continuous
deployment that you have a very high
page deployment which is also something
that requires you to shift left to take
the checker editor check and do it
earlier to do it as part of CI to do it
as automatic parts of the CD but even
then the decision of how to work with it
should be made according to the project
what is the size of a project how old it
is and how responsive the developers are
there is something that I didn't mention
with because it's really nothing you
hire you will eventually have to work
with the developers developers will have
to fix the findings so there is a need
to engage the developers but the thing
is that engagements developers it
besides the stuff that my the other
lecturer said today and yesterday it's
basically the same key it should be a
quality result result which actually is
not false positive and it should be fast
because if the project security delights
them or a security brings not very
qualified findings they will lose their
trust and if you do bring a serious
results that will eventually do that and
will embrace it into the project into
the process so
the main takeout that I would say for
for me would be security policy that
fits the flow a shift left is important
as the further right you are in DevOps
and the open source Security shall not
be neglected because it's a very
significant part the same way as your
own internal internally produced code in
that would be my part and if you have
some questions I think we have got more
time some questions over there so you
mentioned that it is always better to
fix in the early stage using development
interface but what if there is 10,000
issues and how do you need to prioritize
it maybe developers are working it's not
feasible to fix all those issues as
rightly and they will start to hate
because you know it's finding all these
things and they they don't have enough
time to fix it so how to address this
problem yes I have mentioned it earlier
basically if you have 10,000 findings
the best way would be to divide it to
say okay we have we're starting our
program now let's do the 10,000 findings
aside and make a plan of eliminating it
first the highest than lower and let's
street only the new findings that's the
one that is that are created on the code
produced right now that would be the way
that will buy your developers because it
will be close to the time to produce the
code they will understand where where it
comes from and they will not have to dig
deep into why a millions of lines of
code produced years before them that
will make the whole process easier it
will
not probably which the security would
strive for eliminating all at one but it
will make it happen it will make it a
seed to go further
that's something reachable like a
low-hanging fruit thank you very much
good thank you
[Applause]
[Music]