again much and welcome Belfast it's a
beautiful city I don't come from here I
come from London as you can tell from
the atom as as introduction went I am
NOT a little bit flawed but I work for
the same company she does and I used to
be my background as I used to be the CTO
at places like Bank of America BT and
UBS and that included a lot of security
operations and various other things
so the talk of today is to kind of give
you some insightful background and
experience on the developments around
things like what we're now calling dev
setups so it's a combination of death
ops and security and particular it's
about how to maintain or develop job
security in an act rapidly changing
world I will try to run through these
life pretty quickly I have a very short
number of slides if I get to the end and
we have time for questions I'll take
them here if not I'll take them outside
so the question that we're posing today
is essentially how to maintain or create
job security in an emerging world in a
developing world and the two key
developments that I want to raise or
highlight here is that security had
always been a back of this function
traditionally has always been thought
about as in some cases and afterthought
but there's a number of previous
presenters already talked about you know
developers are taking over the world
applications are taking over the world
and consequently applications and in
future is happening now but more so in
future machines in the form of Internet
of Things you know more advanced
computers possibly even FII and machine
learning and so on these are going to
become consistent components in a
security context and you can't talk to a
machine generally speaking with a human
being you can go and have a conversation
on the machine you can ask if nice
things but generally don't get very far
with it whereas a human you can you can
use biometrics and various other things
to control and manage behaviors and you
can get coral of insightful stuff about
that but nevertheless
companies especially some of the
businesses I've worked with in the past
are always looking to deliver and create
more better automation better faster
things better faster ways of doing
things and that necessitates if you're
going to do it correctly putting
security in line in all of that so
security is no longer an external thing
it's no longer a parallel thing that you
do on the side it's no longer
you do at the end is something you do
throughout the process especially if
you're going to do DevOps correctly so
in that context how do you maintain
security have you maintained your
security how do you make sure that as a
security specialist and as somebody that
pervades or creates or develop security
technologies you remain relevant in that
rapidly changing world and it is a
changing world because of things like
media because of raising awareness in
newspapers and so on now more people
know about security also there are more
security incidents occurring whether
people like to admit that or not
consequently these two things add up to
a point where you know you can walk down
the street today most people understand
some degree of security of in terms of
relative terms if you go to corporations
especially the big guys especially the
regulated industry that financial
services health care and so on
regulators expect the executives and
those businesses to know about security
not necessarily become security experts
but have security at part part of their
core responsibilities and this means
that you're seeing a rise in the number
of real CISOs that exist in
organizations being elevated into board
level possibly beyond roles and so on so
they're no longer back-office functions
no longer backroom or functions of song
so this creates essentially a divergence
of demand that has to be addressed the
first one you see on the left-hand side
is how do you continue to deliver value
the the synopsis of the talk that
Elizabeth wrote was purely around
focusing how do you change the context
of a security conversation from one of
pure protection and pure you know pure
stoppage or whatever you want to call it
through to one where it's a function of
business development and business
enablement it security now needs to be
an enabling function you cannot stand
there in a boardroom and say you can't
do this anymore because because because
because business people want to do
business and you can't stop that
otherwise your business goes out of
business so the first one is delivering
value and you've got to be able to
deliver value in a way that makes sure
that you are doing something that is in
line with what the business wants to do
and appropriate
what the business wants to do I remember
conversations would see so as some of
which I've ended up having to fire in
the end because it's scented their
entire role in life was to stop the
business doing business but you cannot
take an online business offline that's
getting done the second one is build
trust security is a complicated topic it
is a specialist topic if you apply
yourselves to it and you become a
specialist in that world you'll be
treated as guru specialist people
learning people etcetera in these
organizations you will be held somewhat
higher than than traditional IT guys in
most respects because you are operating
a name really murky weird world right
the point without is you've got to get
out from that world and you're going to
start having conversations in business
language with business people you've got
to start having that building building
that trust with people and that means
that you've got to understand business
language it is no longer sufficient to
say that I have a security problem and I
think we need to do this that and the
other in technical terms because the
business people just don't care their
job is to make money now as far as
they're concerned any type of
conversation along those kind of lines
is going to result with you effectively
getting being fired or move sideways so
that results in a situation where as a
security specialist you need to do two
things right and there's a Jew a Latino
people are very very good security
stretchers are generally very good and
I've had the privilege of hiring all the
smartest people on a planet to do this
they're greater security side but
they're not so good at the enablement
side how do you play security in a
context with a language with a set of
conditions with a set of expectations
that actually enables business how do
you make sure that people are doing
things securely nobody in their right
mind today would develop an insecure
system now that's a statement I make but
I would also state at the same time that
very deep you understand what that means
lots of people say they build secure
systems but generally they've done they
think about security second secondarily
in favour of things like UX and various
other things so you're going to be able
to secure a business and you're going to
be able to enable business at the same
time and in the world of dev said cops
that becomes very very critical because
forget about security for a second if
you talk about DevOps DevOps is all
about
Automation is all about taking cost and
overheads out of an organization
it's about speeding up the delivery
timeframe from an application concept
all the way to advocated globally and
that's without throwing in methods like
scrum and other things input which add
additional levels complexity so your
change cycle now becomes much quicker
when I started my career twenty odd five
years ago the change cycle typical
project was somewhere between three and
six months chain cycles in my last role
was up to two weeks or less sometimes
days we were continuously developing so
you've got to be able to put security in
that context you can't say to a person
oh you have a problem but it's going to
take me two weeks to figure out all the
problems that's a bad conversation have
because you're taking money away from
the business money away from the
business means business as well which
means as an employee of the business
you've just effectively shot yourself in
the foot there's a new term that I want
to introduce today most people
understand ROI in terms of return on
investment but there's a new term that
most people at least in the executive
businesses especially where businesses
are in large-scale or have some kind of
stakeholder situation like shareholders
and so on or they're in regulated
businesses it's essentially the risk of
loss and in simple terms what risk of
loss means is it's okay to define what
the risks are but you've also got to
understand exactly what the potential
losses are as a result of the execution
of that risk and you've got to present
it in business terms you cannot simply
say that I have a risk and then the
business going to have to figure out
what that risk represents in business
terms you've got to present it in simple
terms to them otherwise you've just lost
their they are out there focus on their
attention and what you've done isn't a
lien ated them the point is if you want
to be a valued function in the in the
development of their box and delivery of
rapid application security and so on
you've got to get those two blends links
correctly because if you don't one one
over balance the other and commercial
guarantee you commercial decisions will
always overtake
security conditions generally speaking
the other thing to think about are
things like you know essentially the
the way you present the context of a
security issue the way you present
security tools and investments etcetera
has to be done in the in the development
of the whole DevOps cycle you can't just
say I want to insert a security
condition here here and here
in the context of a develop lifecycle
because those kind of things don't make
sense unless you figure out what goes
before or goes after those situations
you also have to do it in such a way
that developers as a previous
presentation was talking about
developers get the ability to use
security functionality as a developer
asking a developer to think about
security stuff is not going to work
generally speaking but if you make the
security function part of the
development toolsets part of the the a
dlc context in terms of the
infrastructure that they use the
platforms that use and so on then
they're going to get those functionality
those elements by default and if you do
that they won't get in your way you
won't get in their way and there'll be
no argument so everything will go fine
the last one sorry is another thing that
we'll go through the language I talked
about several times before security you
know we have to admit that security
world has a defined language and I force
myself to learn that over time because
I've had to hire these you know these
type of people and work with these other
people so in my previous role at BT we
were lucky enough to acquire the counter
vein business which was the Bruce
Schneier organization and I spent almost
three years learning sitting beside
Bruce Schneier and kind of getting
brainwashed
trying to learn the language get myself
immersive and I went on a knee was tough
I was a pure IT guy he was a pure
security guy and trying to meet the
minds was a very hard thing to do but in
the end we did it and you know the key
thing that I would say there in terms of
learning is both terminology and
language are as importantly to each
other but they have contextual relevance
you cannot go into a boardroom and start
selling technical terms around because
the board people will not understand you
business people and on circuits
generally speaking developers will not
understand you because it's not their
role in life but you've got to present
those kind of things with an idea of
what the risks will be what a value of
doing these kind of pieces of work will
be what the value of delivering these
security functionalities will be again
if you make it transparent and you make
it part of the automation process in
DevOps then there should be no issue but
language is very very important not
getting the language correct or not
thinking about language when presenting
security functionality or developing
security processes is something that
will get people into trouble this is
something that is interesting chart and
we in preparation for this presentation
we we went to Google and where we you
know we did a search on Devex devstack
ops as a term and that's what came up so
it's only what you'll see you know from
2012 2012 to 2014 roughly there were you
know quite a number of inquiries but not
huge in terms of the total circle on
yems there was a spike in 2013 and what
we can found what we found without was
that was related to a number of fairly
well publicized wheat pieces of security
and then from 2014 onwards what you'll
see is a massive increase up until
current day whereas the 100% represents
is essentially does the the maximum
research return that you can find in
Google so basically you people go in and
search and they'll find at least one
article in reference of Google which has
been actually specifically determined to
be relevant to that context that's how
Google measures these kind of things I
don't think of it as a hundred searches
per se it's hundreds and relevance in
terms of a searcher term so what you're
now finding is you put them SEC opts
into Google at least you will find very
very good materials on what this means
despite the fact that active is
relatively new term and DevOps dev sir
coughs really as simple as their votes
plus security right whether you've got
one returned the other doesn't matter
but it also means two other things
it's the maturity of the the
stakeholders right they are still
maturing and not mature yet you've got
to take them through that journey you've
got to explain it to them and then the
third the other thing that's interesting
is that there's still a lot of confusion
out there lots and lots of people talk
about dev site cops but actually don't
away means they don't really understand
the context they don't really understand
the implications of what the combination
of those two things
means again I was involved in a project
that six months ago where this fairly
large software startup was going through
the process of developing their MVP
application and their idea of the exact
second officer was DevOps plus security
at the end so they hadn't even done
security through the agile process
displaying what I was saying so what
does that mean it means this basically
it means that you go understand the
things that you know as a specialist as
a key person in an organization that
knows security and so on as a security
technologist or as a security consultant
whatever you also going to understand
the things that you can get hold of you
may not know everything you may not have
access to everything but there will be
other times when you can have to get
access to information get access tools a
lot of tool vendors here today that will
give you capabilities that give you more
more extensive abilities to multiply
some of the capability of delivering and
then the last one is identify the things
that you need they may not be available
today there may be technologies that you
would want to put inside the DevOps
process that doesn't exist today but
there's a there's a simplistic guarantee
that at some point in the future
somebody will develop this or maybe to
you right you can see an opportunity in
a marketplace go out and develop it
there will be a market for this kind of
stuff you know you can know you can look
at any number you like you look at any
projection that you like there will be a
market for this because software is
going to take over the world
hardware is dying out generally speaking
and people writing software etc I mean
you know there are guys in Azerbaijan
who have you know cheap computers a
sense of writing really cool code it's
going to happen so the last thing there
are three things are just as a statement
I will make knowing everything trying to
know everything trying to get your
business to know everything trying to
get your customers to know everything
trying to get your specialists to know
everything is not going to happen it is
impossible you just don't have the
people the manpower the willingness
accept that there are always these kind
of counter
acting forces going on you've got to
understand and determine exactly what is
relevant to you as an organization as an
individual as a role you know you can
look at this career perspective as well
as especially in security what do you
want to know what are you offering to
the people who you're working with to
the partners that you work with us on
and then the last one is the most
important one is you've got to know what
matters to an organization at every
given point in time and that will change
guaranteed that will change again in my
last roll at UBS you know the number of
conversations where I was dragged in
front of a regulator or the executive
board to explain security issues you've
got to understand what is important to
your constituents a core stakeholders at
any point in time and in devops world
that is critical because in the devops
world all all of those opportunities are
about optimization it's about automation
is about integration is about getting
rid of waste and driving efficiency if
you're not in the conversations as a
security person you're going to get
bypassed because there will be people
who will come to your organization or
there will be tool providers out there
that can say well you know neither
security specialist because I can put an
MI tool in the middle of a DevOps system
and it will do all of that right or I
can put application testing tools of the
case in point bunkbed of mine people
number of people who come to me and say
application testing tools you don't need
application testers anymore because it's
all automated you could put this tool in
paisa license fees and everything will
be all right the ability to eliminate
the human from the process hasn't
arrived yet right if you're especially a
security guy and you want to get into
this base this is the time to do it
because you will be in demand if you get
the context correct there are two roles
that have occurred inside or three roles
if you include data to big roles that
occurred in the enterprise world that
are now demanding more money than any
other role in any other previous point
in history one is risk it's achieved
risk officers are now paid more
generally speaking the moment anyone
else Parata
in an enterprise of any size ii wonder
security chief security office and so on
you only have to look at the 5100 or any
other metrics you want to choose the
number of people who have been elevated
as ceasers from somebody in operations
somebody in back-office to board level
exact or sub level exact but has the
power to make those kind of decisions
that change has occurred massively in
the last fourteen fifteen month or so
and the last one I just mentioned there
was data there has been a continual role
for a chief data officer for a long time
but you're only just beginning to see
chief data officer emerge as a full
executive function in those in
organizations thank you
I actually I think I've got five minutes
how much time do I have any questions
from anybody no questions the first time
River like that actually answer a
question for you while we're using
little time put up your hands if people
believe that there are more security
incidents than ever before okay
put up your hands if you feel that more
security incidents are reported than
ever before okay it's interesting the
truth is you're both right you know I've
had the privilege of paying for sort of
quite expensively a lot of extensive
research on this point there's a lot of
confusion for security out there
unfortunately and when you're talking
about invert the combination of DevOps
and security it becomes a fundamental
problem for a lot of enterprises that
deal with a lot of companies to deal
with and also presents an opportunity if
you're in the provider space or in the
software space or the services space to
address those most people I talked to
who are either in the security space or
buyers of security products and services
recognized that they need to prepare
more of their allocated budget for
security than ever before again give you
example at UBS my annual security budget
was close to about 20
the scent of my operating budget and my
operating budget was more than 5 billion
cool right thank you
[Applause]