hey everyone my name is Greg Anderson
today I'm going to be talking about
vulnerability management and how to do
less of it because I really don't like
vulnerability management
so yeah I'm Greg Anderson I'm from
Austin Texas I am a senior security
engineer at Pearson where my role is
focused on security automation I am also
the last security engineer at Pearson
I'm very lost hold out Pearson is a
company that operates in every country
of the world but - and we have 40,000
employees so keeping our application
security pipelines running is is really
tough and it would absolutely be
impossible without defect dojo I also am
a former San Antonio chapter leader so
if there are any lost chapter leaders
here I know and I feel your pain and a
bunch of other boring stuff that no one
cares about so I'm really not a big fan
of new tools to me new tools are kind of
like ads that you see on like news
articles there's tons of them 90% of the
time they aren't well documented or they
over promise or they simply don't work
and so my hope is that by the end of
this you will think that defect dojo is
this different and easy to use and
helpful for you
but to explain why I created this when I
started my career at security
vulnerability management for me was
greatest - dotto does anyone still using
greatest hands any brave souls Excel aw
come on
being modest but yes the vulnerability
management for me was greatest - dotto
at the time I was working at Rackspace
and I felt that myself in the team spent
60% of our time doing reports and trying
to count metrics rather than doing what
we were hired to do which was try to
break into products and so we tried a
variety of commercial tools to try and
get more in phishing get more efficiency
out of the team but honestly we hated
them all every single one only seemed to
make things worse that's not going to
work the other thing that I should note
at the time is that I was fresh at a
school from the University of Texas
which according to most ranking
institutions in the US and the the top
10 for computer science so I had a huge
ego in an opinion about everything and
so I was in a meeting with my leadership
team one day complaining about our
tooling as a lot of the recent college
grads do and I opened my big stupid
mouth and I said I think I could make
something better if you gave me the
chance and so probably because they were
tired of hearing me complain and putting
up with me they actually gave me the
opportunity so I was given two weeks to
make a prototype and so if you're
familiar with software development I
hope you'll agree that two weeks is not
a lot of time to create an entire new
product but what came out of those two
weeks they they really liked and so I
was given an additional two weeks and
another developer named Charles Neil who
is a great friend of mine and defect
dodrio would not be where to say
and so after a month of total
development time we took defect dojo
into production we migrated all the data
from the tools that we were using in to
defect dojo and it was an absolute
nightmare
we had vulnerabilities that were being
double counted on some days and not
being counted on others and that was
because we had a local time in Django
within our databases in UTC and that
took us months to figure out but what
came out of it was something that I
couldn't do my job today
now without and is a pillar of making
security engineering work with a ratio
of 1 to 40,000 and so what defect dojo
is is it's a security tool created by
security professionals for security
professionals with the idea being to
remove as much as possible or automate
the things we don't like to do such as
reporting metrics and baseline scanning
and the other thing that came out of
this is we had these principles that we
wanted to make sure we tried to follow
as defective Otto aged so as of now it's
been an OS project for maybe a year and
a half but it existed for about the
total of four years give or take and so
that the number one principle has always
been to allow engineers to focus on what
they're best at and what they're paid
for which is breaking into product we
also wanted it to be extremely
well-documented and so for the majority
of our new features we have always made
the new pour requests include the
documentation now we're not perfect at
that as I found out in my project review
two days ago because one of the things I
wrote was actually missing documentation
so that's that but you know decent hit
rate that the whole point being that
there are a lot of great security tools
out there that P
we'll have a very difficult time using
because they're they're not well
documented or the barrier to get them
working is so high that it makes it not
worth using the tool being able to
launch easily so dojo is written with
Python Django and if you're familiar
with Python and Django you can use the
traditional means to setup and install
it however but that's not really
practical for everyone especially in the
security industry so we created a
standalone install script which I'll
show later it's one line and we support
OSX any Linux system that's apt based
any system that's young based so as far
as Linux systems go the only ones that
are really left out or BSD systems
besides OSX there is also docker compose
and we have a one-click launch to docker
cloud which Aaron Weaver created
I don't know if he's here he might
already taken off but if you're here
hearing thanks because I really didn't
want to do that we also wanted to make
it easy to change there's a number of
security tools that I was really
impressed with but I had no idea how to
contribute to and I didn't have the time
to figure it out
so most features in dojo or if you
wanted to create a new feature can be
done by modifying three files so the
first is models which is how we actually
get data into the database and then use
for manipulating data and finally
templates which is what is rendered to
the end-user that's actually using the
application and so all this talking what
does it actually do so well the first
feature that I think is useful for us is
templating so imagine that you're a
security engineer and you're conducting
a vulnerability assessment and you find
cross-site scripting for x and you're
getting very tired of writing how to fix
cross-site scripting four times rather
than rewriting the same thing over and
over
you can save something as you write it
to be a template and then simply reuse
it report generation so depending on how
you interact with development teams some
security teams are still in the
traditional mantra of I create a really
pretty report and then I throw it over
the fence which you can absolutely do
but the flip side of that is we also
have to your integration so if your
developers are more comfortable with you
pushing directly to their issue
management that's also an option there
is a ton of metrics in defect dojo just
about every metric Under the Sun because
every leadership team that I ever worked
for always wanted different metrics and
so we just kept building and building
and building these metrics so everything
from life through time what is the most
valuable product what is the most
vulnerable endpoint that's likely to get
breached
what type of vulnerabilities are we
seeing the most all that is built-in and
readily available and also easy to
manipulate if there's something more
specific or less specific that you're
looking for the big one is centered
around scanners though so the ability to
combine the results for multiple
scanners to one report or we also
recently added deduplication so imagine
that you run three scans on an
application and you feel kind of mad
about two of the scanners you don't
really trust the results and everyone
knows that once you start throwing
closed positives over the wall it's it's
hard to earn that trust back so one
thing that deduplication does is we look
at the results from multiple dynamic
scanners and we use that to essentially
establish a confidence interval and then
so we only report on things that all
three of them fine or you can also just
remove duplicates so that way you're not
having to make sure that you can go
ahead and remove the overlap essentially
self-service tools so the idea be
mean to remove the the mundane from the
security engineers and give developers a
baseline to work with again so you don't
have to bother with the point click work
so to say and then finally plugins
something that a lot of organizations
that I've talked to are excited about is
that because defect dojo is written in
Django any plug-in that works with
Django will work with defect dojo the
most popular is LDAP integration so
without writing any code whatsoever if
you edit your settings file you now can
use LDAP instead of the user database no
one's asleep yet that's always exciting
but one thing I did forget to mention is
if you do make it to the end
I do have stickers so that motivates you
it always does I don't know why but easy
to please I guess I don't know but yes
so so this is the the dashboard that a
manager or an engineer would would first
see when they log in this is not the
end-all be-all Metrix page this is
simply to give folks a view of what
their week is looking like what they
have going on and what they've done so -
I know I'm feeling a lot of information
at you and to kind of explain the model
and workflow I wanted to just give like
a real simple example so I think
everyone is pretty familiar with
Google's product so that's why I'm going
to use Google so imagine if you will
that we're all security engineers at
Google and we are passed with testing
Google Docs so at the highest level
dojo has a model which is called the
product type which is used to refer to
an organization or product line for
Google Docs the organization or product
line would be Google suite
and then product types have products
which is just an application or a
product so again Google Docs products
have engagements and the idea of an
engagement is to record what you are
working on or what the goal of an
assessment is so maybe you're conducting
a PCI audit and you're you're using
nessus because they have a
pre-configured scan option to do that
which is test engagement that the test
and then tests of findings which is what
you actually found the vulnerability
details etc and then findings have
endpoints which is where the
vulnerability is located and so just
real quickly these are the current
scanners that you can upload results
from this is missing the OAuth
dependency checker which we added I
think in the last month and a half okay
so if you go back through the slides
later I have these these gifts of the
features actually playing but I realized
that that's not really a great
representation of what's going on and
how to work with it so instead I'm going
to try to break the cardinal rule of
presentations and do about 15 minutes of
live demo so we'll see how it goes but
as I get into the demo guys if you have
questions feel free to interject it's
great time to ask questions if for some
reason I don't see you because the
lights are kind of bright and so it's
kind of hard for me to see you all just
like throw something I don't do whatever
oh the other thing I should note about
this demo is I've essentially taking two
liberties of Lenny blows oh there we go
I've taken two liberties because I was
concerned about the internet connection
so what I've done is I've already cloned
the repository goes where it wouldn't be
able to download it here and I also
pulled down the necessary resources to
do the the report generation but so if
you were a security engineer and you
wanted to set this up you would you know
just visit our github repository you do
a git clone and then you would end up
here so the setup script that I was
talking about it's just set up - you run
it wants to know my password can you
guys see that okay well is that legible
awesome so hopefully I remember the
passwords and we pick a database name
it's semi robust well I shouldn't say
really robust but if you enter something
that already exists oh this way don't do
demos live don't worry you got this
oh man that's so scary it's like I
cannot get stuck this early I would
never live that down I know Matt would
be messaging me for years after that and
it did mortalized to in-video right so
so what it's doing now is it's just
applying all the updates it's pulling
later date latest database schema
updating the database applying the
initial data sets up the initial super
user I'm going to be lazy and just use
rude very secure oh yeah
okay good so we've made it this far so
defect odo net is now officially
installed and ready to run so all you
have to do to kick off the test server
is type in Python manage py run server
login with the admin account we created
oh man it's going so well no errors yet
because we do continuous integration and
all that I'll get to all our functional
tests etc right now we only have about
60% code coverage so I'm always worried
that I'm gonna fire this up I'm gonna
hit an error but anyways yeah so here we
are first thing you can do is just
create a product give it a description
you can also tag it if you want to
filter on tags later so maybe you want
to fill in technology information like
you're using MySQL and nginx give it a
product type now we have a product and
then so again we go to engagements to
actually start filling in vulnerability
information actually I'm sorry can can
you see that again my um I'd like to go
to electronic music festival so my
hearings kind of shot oh there's mic on
ah but that's up to you so you you could
do it in multiple ways you could create
two separate products or you could also
specify different endpoints so it's up
to you you could just create a separate
engagement you could create two products
that's it's semi flexible and that's
them
so we pick our start and end dates which
is when we hope to start testing and
hope to finish and then click done oh
now we click
and so finally right the exciting part
I'm actually going to put things up
there so I have to sample scan files
when it's Apple in is burp and so all
you do is click import scan hopefully
intuitive I'm going to set everything to
come in as active and verified that
that's up to you it's an option to
essentially say do I trust this tool or
do I want to vet the findings after I
import them so we'll start with Berkeley
and so now all the findings are in
defect dojo will show up in all our
metrics will show up against the product
etc but just to give you an example of
how the reporting works I want to also
import another tool so we go back up to
the engagement and again we import
another scan result
just go ahead and tag it this one off
so now we've also imported scan results
from Zack I'm going to go up to the
product level there is kind of a quick
view tricks right here so almost
everything is controlled on the right
hand side of the screen so these are all
the dropdowns essentially to control the
individual components and then
occasionally there will be additional
buttons but almost everything's on the
right and so these are the very brief
product summary metrics you know what
was found how long does it have been
open what tools found it etc so in case
you wanted to do a bake off against two
tools let's say you were setting two to
two similar tools from a vendor and you
want to know which one finds more or
which one has I guess you can do you
probably could do false positive
comparison but it's not quite as
intuitive the other metrics let's say
we'll go back up here to the control
drop-down and we will hopefully generate
a report
I'm going to do PDF and I'm going to let
this run for a minute because the the
zaps can is a semi large but so while
that's running there's things like
product type metrics which we don't have
great big graphs we just uploaded things
right now but you could break out you
know the individual bug count by
severity what type of vulnerabilities
are present and then the other thing
I'll just cover really quick is the the
thing that I use really frequently is
endpoint comparison so this shows us
from the scans where the most
vulnerabilities are for a given endpoint
and then I think I might need to update
those yep so if you flag a product type
is critical it will also show health
dashboards so you know just depending on
what granularity of detail you want it's
there the the higher-ups tend to just
want to know you know what's the health
of the product what's the most
vulnerable etc while engineers and
managers might want to know more about
the the types of findings and why
they're being introduced
hopefully our report is done by now
there's also a advanced report builder
so if you need to put in custom
informations executive summaries there
is drag and drops for cover pages tables
of contents etc now it's still running
does anyone have any questions while
this runs go forward
yes so we have both a generic importer
and also just a plain CSV importer so if
it's easier for you to convert to CSV or
the generic importer which is outlined
in the documentation that's definitely
an option
it's very easy to add additional
scanners if you have just a you know the
output result whatever it is XML or even
proprietary as long as it's easy to
parse and all of our scan files that do
the parsing or are just one file maybe a
hundred and twenty lines so it should be
very very short if you need to adapter
add an additional scanner or if you're
willing to send a sample scan to the
development team we'll eventually get to
it right now we're very swamped to be
honest with you yes great question um so
right now I believe it is just JIRA
unless someone has done additional work
has anyone integrated with gear before
had to do like so so gear is really bad
about certain metric side to do life
through time in JIRA ones and make a
custom thing yeah so it's pretty awful
here was a nightmare but it's the most
popular bug tracking system and software
development and so our JIRA integration
is really robust and I'll get into that
very shortly
is it hard to add additional one I would
say it's semi-difficult all you would
have to do was copy what we've done for
here you know replace your API calls
with the JIRA ones etc and it should
work but I would say that's an
intermediate level task
I saw another question right yes yes so
there is a model from now I guess
there's not a model person again I would
say semi tightly so we do have to have a
specific parser per scanner but I
tests are a generic type that holds all
scans if that make sense oh yes it's
finished I'll get you in just one second
okay so here is the report when it's
done I'm also running on like a one gig
machine so it's a little slower than
normal but I used to write all my
reports in docx and so the problem with
that is you have some engineers that
write things one way and some that like
different spacing and so it looks
inconsistent so my hope is that with the
defect dojo report you'll be able to
give more consistent reports to either
your clients or the dev teams and you
can also replace anything in here that
you don't like so for instance instead
of the defect og logo you could put your
company logo but yeah so it just has all
the findings by default it categorizes
it by severity descriptions mitigations
just your standard vulnerability report
but you don't have to write it and so if
you're conducting a manual assessment
typically you would use defect dojo as a
companion tool to to test with okay yes
sorry
great question that was something we ran
into a lot with retesting so what you
can do is if we go to the engagement so
let's say you were you were redoing this
AppScan essentially and rather than
storing it twice you just want a dip so
if things aren't there anymore you just
want them to close automatically was our
philosophy and so well we'll drill down
one more into the Zapp's can you go to
re-upload scan and you refill this out
and it'll automatically do that for you
so yeah I'll stop clicking through I'm
sure you guys get it any other questions
before I get to my lap yes
oh I see yeah so basically the ability
to scan multiple products at once from
one scan no not currently it's it's
something that is under active
development right now because we
realized that is a limitation that would
make certain people's lives much easier
so to do it right now you would have to
probably filter the eyepiece first and
then do separate scans to upload them
correctly to the products but it is
coming yes ah yeah so these are all
great questions because these are a lot
of the things we're actively working on
so at Pearson right now we are working
on API integration for checkmarks and
white hat so we want to get to what we
call scanner integration 2.0 which is we
realized right now this is not optimal
to have to upload files especially if
your team has limited resources it would
be much more optimal to instead hand
defect Ojo credentials for your API or
API keys and then have it completely
manage the scanners for you set up
schedules etc so we are we are actively
working on that we just added a
credential manager to make that easier
and so the next step will be to do that
API integration I will say though the
one thing that tends to break in defect
or the most is when scanners change
their output which seems to happen
fairly frequently I think that is our
biggest pain point right now in terms of
issues that occasionally spring back up
yes yes give it
yes so how the reports are actually
built as we use wk HTML to PDF or to
asciidoctor of the wh k WK HTML
extensions so as far as customizations
go the the best use case would be to not
not use the simple reports but instead
look back really quick but instead use
the report builder but the report
builder right now would be the limit on
customization and so everything from
cover pages to custom text you can also
attach images to finding so if you want
like a POC image in a report you can
also do that as well yeah awesome guys I
will get through my last slides and I
will I'm not answering your questions so
he's my friend I'm not just being me um
yeah so just where we are now again as a
project one thing we've really tried to
do is make defect dojo on par with
commercial tools in terms of testing
because we know it's very important to
have a seamless experience and that's
one of the things that open-source gets
knocked on frequently is if you're
relying on an open source tool and it
breaks that's a terrible experience so
to try and combat that we do have Travis
CI that runs against every single code
change that happens but again right now
we're only at about 60% code coverage
give or take we have the majority of
functionality covered but again if you
know QA folks that would be interested
we'd love additional help to build that
out further and then the tier
integration which is probably my
favorite thing we've done in the last
three months it is a completely
bi-directional link which was a
nightmare to implement so what this
allows is if someone comments in JIRA
they will also show up in defect dojo if
you comment on an issue that is in JIRA
that is originated from defect dojo that
comment will also be pushed to JIRA if
you close it in defect dojo it will be
closed into your if they close it in
Xero it will be closed in defect dojo
you can also even change the product in
JIRA so if someone reassigns a JIRA
issue that you created in dojo to
another project it will still maintain
that link which was something we
realized was an edge case we actually
had to rewrite the entire thing we
realized it so that was not fun but
works most of the time I think yea the
one-click installations already talked
about and covered that oh yeah in the
feature so we did finish the credential
manager that's in there now so the idea
being rather than having to go back and
forth with a developer to establish all
the necessary resources to start a test
we now have a credential manager that
you can tie to a product for different
environments you can set credentials
with dev staging production some more
thing I wanted to mention the password
manager oh well I'm sure it'll come to
me as soon as I wrap up yes so we want
to make it even easier we think we've
done a good job on getting an initial
setup out but I still think that there's
work to do to make it the most
compatible with AI I want to give an
easy production run button essentially
so right now right we set up without SSL
etc we want to offer a pre hardened
image rather than you having to go and
do all the configuration but we
desperately need help desperately
desperately right now we have 14
contributors give or take nine or so
have contributed over a thousand lines
of code but the project has really
ballooned in the last seven months give
or take and so we have had a hard time
keeping up with all the things we want
to go out and achieve because there's so
many different directions that people
want to take it and so trying it out we
already saw that through the demo how
these are just the resources so if you
need to go back through the pros
datian where it is on github the docks
and we also have a demo site or it's
really a skeleton demo so it's not quite
everything will work in it because of
resource constraint but if you just want
to see it again and go play with it we
have a Python anywhere site and yeah
that's all I got guys thank you so much
for your time and sitting and listening
to me blab I know it was a lot of
information I have defecto just stickers
if you would like them thank you and
I'll take any other questions that
anyone had except from that now I'm just
go ahead Matt yes ah yes so I believe so
I believe we expanded the API three
weeks ago to include scan files if not
one of the core contributors is working
on it I want to say yes but don't want
to be wrong yeah oh there you go
thanks Aaron if you're here but yeah so
the second question uh defect dojo is
relatively performant so one
organization that I helped set it up for
I know was pushing entries on the order
of half a million on a for CPU server
what 12 gigs are am and it it survived I
mean there was a couple of things that
were a little slow we do preload the
metrics so basically it's cached every
five minutes to try and make it more
efficient so you're not waiting to lunge
on all the data for your entire company
but I think it's it's very performant
compared to the other options right now
yes good
I so great question
so the API Doc's are actually in defect
dojo itself which I just realized is we
should probably copy that over thank you
for bringing that to my attention
um but yeah so as far as what you can do
with the API it's all here we are using
tasty pie and swagger to generate this
so if you're curious well you could do
it engagements relative to the API all
that information is here and you can try
it out to actually give that you just
need to grab your API key and you can
test to make sure that you've things
that you're actually making a call
correctly if you're having issues Pro it
might take a little bit time I don't use
the API that much to be honest with you
which I should anyone else awesome okay
thank you so much again guys I really
appreciate it I hope it was enjoyable I
hope it was helpful and thank you again