how did everybody alright alright we've
got two minutes sorry do it alright well
having two minutes well we'll split the
difference will do 26 cuz we got we had
50 slides a lot of demos alright and
there's a greater than usual chance that
everyone in the audience is not
necessarily a native English speaker and
I have a tendency to speak far too fast
anyway so we'll do a bus alright
actually I think I will we'll get
started
howdy everybody alright today I'm going
to talk about application attack surface
and some things that we've been doing to
use calculating attack surface and more
specifically watching attack surface
change over time that helps us integrate
application security testing into CI CD
pipelines so I'll provide a little bit
of background I'll talk about the
importance of attack surface talk about
how attack surface is relevant to the
things that organizations are trying to
do with DevOps and then talk about this
hybrid analysis mapping technology that
we have developed and some of the
history behind that we've got some extra
slides in the deck that show you how to
install I have links to different things
and show you how to do insults what will
probably scoot over a lot of the
installed discussion stuff just because
it's we are short on time and that those
are mainly in there for folks want to
replicate what I'm doing and then we'll
talk through a number of use cases that
we have developed that we use or they
were using this technology in these
techniques for my background is I'm a
software developer by background
original a lot originally a lot of early
server-side Java in the mid to late 90s
early 2000s that it's an early not
network but really what I've done for
the last you know 10 or 15 years of my
career is worked with organizations on
how the software that they're developing
impact the security of their
organizations and so my background is as
a
for developer that has come into the
world of security and as distinct from
other folks who may or may be identity
application security space coming from a
network penetration testing background
so I'm a developers focused on security
and that shapes the way that I approach
some of these issues and I help run the
o op San Antonio chapter with a couple
of other folks is everybody here
familiar with OSF yes that's good
we'll be doing some examples with OAuth
zap fantastic tool and it's great to you
know it is great with this API and with
its flexibility it's a really valuable
tool to integrate into different DevOps
apps app security testing activities
again I've got some example code bases
we've got links to downloads so and so
forth so if you want to all these slides
are online so you'll be able to if you
want to play around with this stuff you
can do all that too through out of those
links so let's look at a tax surface and
what do we mean by a tax service when I
talk about an applications attack
surface what I'm really saying is this
is this is the set or the list of all
the different ways that an attacker can
reach out and touch your piece of
software such as they can influence its
behavior because that's going to be the
set of things that they can try to
manipulate in order to gain some sort of
advantage when you think of a web
application really what we're talking
about from a web application is anything
in the HTTP request so the URL the
parameters the web method your headers
cookies and things of that nature
you'll from up in theory your web
application also has a tax surface and
then it may be pulling environment
variables in from the servers that it's
on but if you if that's where you're
being attacked from you don't really
have an application security concern you
need an incident response center to help
you write so when we think of an
application attack surface from a web
app standpoint we're looking at all of
the ways in the HTTP request that the
attacker can influence the behavior of
the application if you extend that
concept of attack surface to look at
mobile applications Internet of Things
applications these get more complicated
because on a mobile device you've got
you know
mobile device pulling in yo fees for the
network it may be it's receiving input
from the user you're talking to web
services things of that nature same
thing with Internet of Things and so
today we're going to be focused on
attack surface as it relates to web
applications but I do think that
extending that or you'll continue to
have questions about attack surface
across additional types of applications
is really though and what we're going to
look at using attack surface to do is to
help us target in this case dynamic
testing so we're going to look at how
can we use the concept of attack surface
to target automated dynamic application
security testing and how can we also use
the concept of attack surface to
understand or to target what we're doing
in the manual assessment or manual
penetration testing so what does attack
service have to do with DevOps
if you want your talk to be accepted
OAuth these days I think it has to have
DevOps in the title jim Monaco's make in
front of me had a previous presentation
that that may or may not be true but
what we've been able to do is to use the
concept of attack surface to help us get
really focused in what we're doing when
we're doing some app security testing in
a DevOps pipeline and so let's look at
what we want from security in a DevOps
pipeline again the you know at the
Netflix do an amazing things with
security and DevOps and there's links
here to a blog post as well as a video
from RSA this year but when when we look
at testing application security testing
as part of a devops pipeline we look at
that in three phases the first of the
testing phase we're going to do some
sort of testing activities to determine
you know what can I learn about the
security state of this software you know
for this given build that we've got
right now and one of the things that we
found is a lot of application security
testing tools and techniques don't lend
themselves well to being put out of the
box into a CI CD pipeline because they
run too long you know when the
organizations that we work with
anecdotally what we've seen is you know
security typically gets a budget for a
given run of the pipeline of about 8 to
12 minutes that's kind of what we've
seen as a bounds if security is going to
weigh in on the decision about whether
or not to break the build they get about
8 to 12 minutes to do that and so
you can't feel free to given build you
can say cool let's kick off like a three
hour or four to five can or a four hour
apps can crawl the application right
you're not as security you're not going
to be allowed to introduce those
synchronously into a pipeline you know
certainly there is value in doing those
testing activities but those have to be
handed in handle it in a vicar's manner
you're not going to be able to wait to
give a thumbs-up or a thumbs-down in a
build based on those long-running
testing activities and so when you think
of kicking off testing FF security
testing as part of the part of the
pipeline some of those tests against you
you may be able to wait for if you get
them within that window other tests you
may start those tests but you're going
to have to handle the results of that
testing out of and later on after you've
done the testing at least a testing your
it will wait for then you get to make a
decision so should this bill be approved
or not you know similar to if the unit
tests run and they fail we say this
build is not acceptable if the
functional test run but they fail in
this build is not acceptable from a
security standpoint how do you make a
determination if the build is reassemble
and in a perfect world security would be
able to weigh in and say we're never
going to allow critical or high
vulnerabilities in a pipeline build if
we find any critical or high
vulnerability x' we're going to find
we're going us we're going to fail this
build who would who would like to be
able to do that great good things
they're going to get to do that in their
organization a test area because the
challenge is for most application they
have legacy code that's in there right
there's probably findings that already
exist and hopefully there's a meter or a
remediation plan in place when you're
probably not going to get to break the
bill for three months waiting for all
the cross-site scripting vulnerabilities
to get sort of that pride you don't have
that kind of political power in the
organization for most of the folks that
we work with so another way to look at
this is to say potentially let's say our
policy is you can't introduce new
critical or high vulnerabilities right
that's politically much more tenable
because while we agree like hey we don't
like these vulnerabilities they're in
here but at least we've got a plan to
fix them go get fix down the road but
everybody should be able to agree that
we shouldn't be introducing new critical
on - our abilities right and so that's
one of the things that we
found is that security poles need to be
flexible in a lot of cases and to
understand this is what I'm going to be
able to get from a security standpoint
and these are the things that are simply
not reasonable for me to for me to be
able to expect you know finally we need
to take what we found and we need to
report those out to the developers and
again the best practice here is use the
tools that the developers are already
using standard you'll put it in put it
in JIRA so they're being tracked as buzz
it need to be fixed also we'll look at
things like chat ops how do we notify
how do we notify developers hey this
last check-in that you pushed in that
has changed the security state of the
application you have new findings that
are in there you've introduced new
attack surface that you need to be
concerned about but again the important
thing here is you need to be putting
these results into the tools that the
development teams are already using so
talk through a lot of this you know many
security tools are run too long to be
included in the pipeline build so full
staff staff security testing also
includes manual testing or comprehensive
security testing is going to include
manual testing and that's going to be
way too slow to include in most pipeline
builds but by looking at a TAC surface
it has it changes over time that can
help us focus certain testing activities
so if we have a very limited time to
test we probably want to test the parts
of the application that are the most
likely to have newly introduced
vulnerabilities right and that's going
to be new parts of the attack surface or
parts of the attack surface where the
application behavior has changed and so
by understanding how attack surface
changes over time that lets us focus
testing activities and we can also use
it to help us trigger testing activities
to say you know since the last time we
did manual testing this is how the
applications attack service has changed
with the limited amount of time that I
have to do manual testing the
application let me focus in on that you
know in furthermore I want to redo a
manual test either on some sort of time
and based basis or looking at the
evolution of the application say well
hey you know every time we've added 10
or more URLs of the application I want
to have a pen test
come in and look at this stuff right or
every time the attack services grown or
changed by five or ten percent so we
built in conjunction with are funded by
the US Department of Homeland Security a
technology we call hybrid analysis
mapping and the original goal of this
hybrid analysis mapping technology was
to correlate the results of static
testing with dynamic testing so to take
SAS results from
Verico to check marks a fortifying to
correlate that with dynamic results from
as a bourbon Afghan a web inspector and
this was developed with the with the
Department of Homeland Security is a
Small Business Innovation research
program and what we found as we develop
this research is that we were able to do
the thing we really set out to do which
was good but we also found other uses
for the technology and that's really
what I'm going to focus on today we'll
skip over this just for time but again
it's a really interesting use of this uh
you know the DHS S&T CSD SBIR program
the government loves acronyms now in one
important point to make is we don't as
soon as this talk is endorsed by DHS
this is me talking about the stuff that
we've done not them specifically
improving our content so that's
traditionally important point to make
but our original goal again was to
correlate between static and dynamic
testing work and after we made that work
we found out that we could make other
stuff with that technology as well so
they're ready here familiar with dynamic
application security testing right so
you're going to typically spider the
application to find the attack service
or start on the home page and you're
going to act like Google you're going to
spider find all the pages of the URLs
the forms that we pass is usually with
some login authentication and session
management stuff in there so that you
can you crawl and see the application
beyond the login page and then we're
going to do some targeted fuzzing we're
going to send in sequel control
characters if we see a JDBC error
message come back we say oh that looks
like there's a sequel injection
vulnerability here and a finding for
these in these cases looks like the CW
is a vulnerability type we use the mitre
common weakness enumeration the relative
URL like we're in the application
what page in the application are we on
and the entry point which for certain
vulnerability is like a reflected
cross-site scripting or a single
injection are going to have a parameter
or cookie or something into where the
payload was passed in so we want to
correlate those with static application
security testing so that's where we're
going to use source code or a binary
we're going to do some analysis build a
model of this application we're going to
do data flow control slow semantic
analysis again this is just kind of a
text flirting sequel injection where we
get tainted data in it paints a couple
strings along the way and then gets
passed to a sensitive function and
really what we're what we were trying to
do was to find the relationship between
the behavior of an application and the
source code responsible for that
behavior so for each what we essentially
do is we need to first standardize
vulnerability types again we use mitre
for that but we wanted to map when I
make a request to a particular URL what
code in this application is going to run
to embodies behavior that URL and when I
pass in a parameter to the application
where in the source codes of that
parameter usage show up so from this
basically what we do is we look at the
application source code detect the
language and framework and build an
attack surface model of the application
so we determine what are all of the URLs
is that the application will respond to
and where is the source code that's
responsible to serve each of those
requests and we figure out what are all
the parameters you can pass into the
application and where in the source code
is that entry point into the source
reflected and from that then we can
fairly easily coordinate static and
dynamic results so if I have a reflect
dynamic result saying reflected
cross-site scripting for login done JSP
for the username parameter I can go
query my endpoint database and this is
Alyssa's Java spring application
you know comment whatever about whatever
a login control or not Java 962 is the
source code responsible for that then we
look through our static findings we find
out hey there's a reflect across site
scripting and the source function for
that is at log and control of that Java
line 62 right so that's how we're able
to correlate between the stat
artifacts in the source code and the
dynamic behavior the running application
and so I was working with one of our
engineers to explain how this work we
work so it's very impressive yeah but
what else can we do with this and so
what we found is like with that data
structure we can do some interesting
things if you have a dynamic result but
you haven't done full static analysis
but if you have a dynamic result with a
for vulnerability you can query this and
find out like well where in the source
code should I start looking for how are
we going to fix this vulnerability right
that's not as good as most of the static
analysis vendors have like to plug in
then you can go through the full data
flow and control flow that's better but
if you haven't done that analysis by
having the data structure available you
can take a dynamic resultant map into an
entry point the source code as well see
we can also do some interesting stuff
where we can proceed dynamic scanners
and so if we've got this application
attack service remember we're looking at
the application source code and figuring
out from that again where the behavior
comes from each part of the attack
service if you look at the dynamic
testing the first step there is the
spider the application or to try and
guess discover the application attack
service but if we can proceed that
scanner we can hopefully avoid false
negatives right so we can proceed the
scanner to say you know here are all the
URLs that you might you want to test and
here all the parameters you can pass in
right and so this helps you deal deal
with like multi-step pages that you
might not be able to crawl through and
unused parameters I've worked on a
ColdFusion application wants to review
passing a parameter named Indy to any
page in the application whatever value
that was let's say it would be pass the
notice of parameters IVA the value of a
thousand it would delete order number
1000 yeah why nobody knows it yeah so
fine calculating this attack sir because
you can know about that beforehand so
we've taken this technology and embedded
it in a number of different things so
we've got a command-line client you can
use points of the source code to dump it
out that's handy from a standpoint of it
lets you do a visual
check to see how thing is this
application what are the parameters and
you can look in to see if you find any
parameters that have scary weird names
like debug all right and what it also
does is it will go in and show you four
four frameworks that use auto binding
like a spring and Ruby on Rails
it'll parse the model files and show you
situations where hey I can actually auto
bind like six levels down in the in this
parameter and that's probably not the
configuration that you want we also have
plugins for OS app and for burp that
lets you proceed that let you proceed
scans so if we go and look at the budget
store here we go and say I want to
import and points from source it's where
my source code is this can proceed this
scan and what we see is that you are
going to see things since we did did
that unauthenticated we're going to find
things like this admin that JSP page
that you wouldn't find in an
unauthenticated crawl because you're
going to see things like these debug
parameters that you would also never see
in the HTML or JavaScript the
application is rendered alright so we're
going to find more images we find parts
of the application that were that we're
not there before
so let's now think about looking at this
over time so if I let's look at the end
the attack surface at a stationary point
in time but what if we say let's look
between to get commits so we can see how
the applications changed and so for
example here
what this lets us do is it lets us look
between two different git commits and so
we see between these git commits we
added the attack surface of these four
URLs we didn't delete any attack surface
and we've got some percentage
calculations there - and so we can start
to see hey if the last time I did a
manual test was here and now I'm here
this tells you you may want to focus
your efforts on it these particular URLs
because they are the ones where it's
most likely that we're going to find
some sort of new bad behavior we can
also by looking at the files that were
that were affected by these by the get
commits in between these two points and
times by looking at all the files that
has changed and correlating those to the
files associated with the tak surface we
can also calculate URLs where the
behavior of those URLs may have changed
like this isn't perfect because we're
we're not actually doing a full analysis
through the ast and a full data flow or
control flow but what we're doing is
saying these files have changed and
these files are associated with attack
surface so here we can see we've got the
added attack surface we've got the
deleted attack surface but we also by
looking at the files impacted by the
commit see the attack surfaces behavior
might have changed based on the changes
that were made and so that again gives
us additional information about how this
applications behavior may have changed
over time and so I can use that to focus
our testing activities so
so now and this is that is now so what
we can do is we can watch a git
repository and you know we can watch a
git repository and watch for changes and
typically this would be something you do
with your CI CD server like your Jenkins
or your bamboo in this case we're going
to do it just by a polling because it's
easier to setup but if we go in here and
if we create some new attack surface and
search now if we push this out we see is
over here then the pick this up is going
to detect this new attack surface and
then it's going to do a very targeted
scan only of the new attack surface that
has been added to the application so
we're doing a dynamic test with that not
crawling the entire application and
fuzzing all of the pages but instead
we're doing scanning very specifically
of only the pages that were added
between those two commits and so you
know using that technique we can get
much more focused in the way that we're
doing our zap testing and we can use
that then to post out to the is that we
can post out to things like you know
HipChat or slats let's let folks know
hey for this commitment just went in I
did tests of the pages that are new and
the pages that have changed and we've
detected this new XYZ vulnerability in
there the goal here being you know and
again this is not a replacement for a
full application security program or you
doing static testing dynam
testing of the entire application but
the goal here is by limiting the test
time or the length of the test run we
can get this very focused on on only
testing the new stuff with the hope
being that we can identify
vulnerabilities much earlier in the
process and let the developers know
about them in the tool that they're
already using so that you don't have to
go through this giant cycle where you
find something reported it works its way
back to the system and says the
developer can see Oh for this thing I
just checked in there's two reflect
across site scripting vulnerabilities I
need to go yeah I need to go in to fix
those right now on in the code while on
these student so again I've got at least
two a github repository one thing I'll
warn you this is from an actual call we
had to the customer where the customer
action said you know so Dan
so this functionality is available in
that crappy kind of code that you write
yes yes it is because that's the way
that we needed all things is I Python
things together and then dump it on our
engineering team and they make actual
working good code out of it so this
stuff right now is still in the
not-quite pythonic stage you know but
again this or all these artifacts are
out there and github if you want to take
a look and replicate some of this stuff
and we've got some basic libraries in
there that will do the attack surface
disk that will you know and that has
some get utility functions that you can
use to again kind of wire this and stuff
together so that you can see these
examples so any questions I think I have
two minutes any questions yes yeah so
the question is how to identify the
attack service how do we identify so
when you point the the engine at some
source code it detects the language in
the framework and so it will say this is
a java application using spring or this
is a asp.net application and c-sharp of
web forms or Ruby on Rails application
and so we're limited right now in the
set of languages frameworks that we
support but is it text that language and
framework and then goes through this
code and identifies like for spring for
example it's going to go and it's going
to identify all of the controller
classes that have that annotation it's
going to parse out where what URLs is
attached to it parses the model so that
it can make those trees your courses the
auto-binding configuration and so then
it could say like hey I feel because I
feel because we understand how spring
translates URLs we can do the same thing
with like struts or your web forms and
things of that nature so that lets us go
in and calculate that attack surface
that then gets it set down a lot of the
other stuff yes so the question is does
the work with Web Services the REST API
it does I know for spring and I'm pretty
sure for Ruby on Rails and so yes like
so you know I know I said we work more
with the spring stuff but yes it
identifies those annotations indicating
that those are web service methods and
exposes those and so like a really handy
thing you can do with this if you're
doing mobile application pen testing
with a like spring rest based back-end
is you can use this to enumerate all
that attack surface and you don't have
to go through the full process of like
taking a mobile app you know chaining it
through zapper burp and then like
watching all the traffic so you know
here all the endpoint that we need to
talk to you
[Applause]