hi everyone I'm Conda Jenga and I'm from
Canada of the Xin hearing thanks for
having me
so today I'm going to talk about pushing
less that's how to do it and then how to
do it like a lot so I was this is a talk
that I created because I wish this New
Year through someone told me all of this
so I'm going to reveal all my secrets
basically that I've learned over the
past year just doing a whole lot of apps
a curse against people to 3 years so
there's really nice tooth marks to see
my slide for me basically and tell you
so when is pushing that so the earlier
you are in their top are called would
like cycle more left you are right so we
want to bring this over here and
specifically for specifically for what I
want to do I want to be a bit too perky
earlier and I want to go to the
development part right so this whole
talk is going to be that that security
should be in every single day but
specifically I want to talk about this
okay so you probably didn't in the news
500 times like this trip got at that
department got access building got
hacked a lot of times with problem it's
poorly built popper right like people
are we using the credentials everywhere
people have no ink revaluation regard
for it's a validation their each their
office badly executed or they just have
any so the next couple slides I'm going
to do is I'm gonna actually the current
state affairs is to bring us all up to a
state level because this talk is for
basically anyone difference in nineteen
not already an aspect expert so I want
all of us building language and
understand with everyone's doing the
chocolate aspect with all the different
pieces interval a B so some of these
sides will be review for you like a
shirt for your eyes it don't worry to
get really good at very fast and we have
to be permitted up okay so her state I
feel that we are looking we're all
looking the same way we're all looking
at the perimeter we're all looking at
the boundary around our department were
all looking at
and that's extremely important but I
feel that not all we can do I feel like
a lot of security don't have any like my
I've seen they have very little
application or software knowledge and
we're they have none if none like I have
explained to a previous security to you
that you can as film objection because
there's no database on the application
and a drop wait boards like is that how
much they do some of them goes on top or
some dudes but some don't want all of
them to software or have some loser no
software um so this is my cute
definition of an application security is
it's the art of making tougher secure a
lot of people grew in my imagination
what a lot of people think it is it's
like the security team states that
something as David likes is that for
developers to do for them and a software
developer are unaware that its research
facility approaches student so I feel
this is an issue so another thing that I
see a penetration testing okay so a lot
of places they don't suffer they just
giant water all or they do a bunch a
little water call good call agile or
they just like release things randomly
and Karl agile or some people actually
really need to agile or just check out
and basically a lot of what I see is my
design for if they hire debris has a
variance which I would call or she right
it's added risk first security
experience or your app great job raising
baby hamper there's no time left to give
the report in like two days before you
go to cross and then there's like all
the stuff of it now which is not what
this very previously they are defined it
gold mine in your app right and then and
then the developers have to stay up all
night or terrible and they click what
are you critical things that don't
tested enough and they show anyway and
they promise you the fix risk naturally
okay so this is not ideal a lot of
places exits they don't do anything they
don't even run a little scanner
don't do anything and they just release
it to the public facing Internet their
old back out of there and I hope this
works out
this is not good okay so this 500 treaty
conference eyes will be heard of CIA hif
confidentiality integrity availability
I'm going to go very briefly because
it's probably one or two people that are
like but that's not me about security
this is my security father suffers
elvers this is why bury your office so I
wish you emails this is why we don't
make more use because we want to make
sure that your app with the help your
app it all helps takes up the
confidential milites your set we want to
make sure the integrity is correct I
don't want to look like you guys EG know
how and I want to make sure it's
available so if you need to check your
information is actually available
I go to slide up because I to software
developers 17 years and still whenever
that's a long time to not know there's
most important thing that we want from
you right so this is the current state
of a person like you see like everyone
not sure your information a stylist I
see security and developers not fully
chooses how do you high fiving maybe not
honey I feel high patents should have
okay so this is where they should learn
to switch left and I have a client for
us which is completely off so I'm not in
your building a house and you like
string the realtor and your own sense
that's been doing and we've got those
everything go offense and then like a
week before send you a oh honey I wish
we put that second mattress because I
know they're G bathrooms would have been
a good idea and you think our bathroom
is in it it'd be terrible it's gonna
crash you economy and make a purchase
late for sure it's going to be like it's
an date you're going to have to excuse
your walking closet or into the bathroom
you have like pipes over top
we carry it in the software and
sustaining seriousness but we fixing
earlier ie fishing that it is cheaper
after another the developers will like
better
you're not making family at night really
state that they were ready which is we
got my information late wagon in the
attribution earlier so let's see how we
can do this okay actually before I so
decide so I really like Drew side
preparing application security produce
just so cool too right so let's start
with the main course so this is all
stuff that I feel you need to be able to
proudly say I have an application
security for my work you don't have to
do all these things for every single
athlete huh if you don't advocate this
elite high rent or get or whatever that
you don't do any DC right you you need
to learn I'm so the main first you
should be able to do longer dosage scan
or other than the assessment well they
say well there's only this is grave and
just run a little easier the scanner is
going to miss the this way there is a
doing things you should be able to do
set modeling which I'll go into more
detail later this spring sir intention
so you're going to break through app how
would you do it then obviously
transfixes um
secure code review or static code
analysis which are not to thing but this
time is they're kind of similarly it
will use which will go into more and
penetration testing if you have mission
critical application assistance that is
permissions or commentators you need to
protect your so if you can't do they say
you need to work on the main works you
haven't been fed you don't know these
things so up next is gravy you know what
that's it this is my interpreter just
attend this is our national dish needs a
purpose
and it is to listener so okay breathe so
I really like common then like gravy I
agree um so this is upset I feel that
you have a really nice application is
there also a website you actually had
money injure of an application carry
teammate more than just one person is
not me imagine you have multiple people
and you want and your lots of developers
we want to do a really good job so you
would okay so the first thing I would do
is educating so what if we took to the
my face
what if like a corset and passing and
that money I could never pay at my
current legislation send all the
developers what if I certainly do
workshop about all the things that I
know we both kind of my literally
sentence I was doing and how not to do
those things great like what if I did
like talks and lunch and learns and
lessons and we're in it and like I
winters know percent and helps them with
what they need right like 30
relationships what if I created secure
coding guidelines in conjunction with
developers not the fictitious and one
but like and I figured you Java what
framework to you what's the best way to
do these things what if we made or
records for all the soldiers to look at
oh I'm going to do that how should I do
it let me tell you explain what we want
from them you could develop a caracal
library which where you color secure
code samples in so those Wyatt or
reasonably is great some extend tested
we will teacher why ever would just read
equals easy I'm also don't put stuff in
the cool library those Commission's well
that's route ago you don't do it another
thing is a responsible or coordinated
disclosure programs or even just like
just soda link on your website this is a
GTA security swaps which was right here
just have an email address is answer the
email address
it can't go to nowhere so someone's
using your applications early let's say
you're a government
carriages either I go I switch this
number at the top and then I got old
records that don't you want me to report
up to you instead of read it because
actually not happy where they email to
contact that you no one answers so
they're like I know what I'll do I'll
tweet it that's epic sound asleep tell
me tell me first
right so different option tell me okay
so you don't always have to have to sir
what would you do it so this is the
extra special set when you need a very
high level of security shirt races let's
say or like at a canada existed coz in
other countries groups or like let's say
and your military developer that you
create and certainly carry but you want
or text that right or let's say your
Cola and we go delicious beverage and
you don't want to get your rescue rate
you want to protect it as well so it
really proves a very high level of
assurance
so that would be both safety programs so
what what fancy program is you can do it
as works like buy her some light on
proud or hacker once where they have all
the security researchers working for
them you give them a fake version of
your application to test and they just
feel free and then they act with like a
packet of new business and then they
enter a search and you pay a fee if they
find something is good no one else is
having a money day thank you for telling
me and selling it on the darknet
I appreciate that if you already are
doing all the other stuff this is a
going to pay for your buck to get those
really is Jersey if you're really big
feet like a can of your chocolate I who
are using your our juicer is amazing and
are like my counselors they companies
you can run their boatload of a
concurrent and you are totally awesome
job this did your small or you don't
have a big a plenty hot earnest is a
possibility another thing you could do
is read team exercise so who is
if you're a defender your booty write
software your dependents you were you
doing most security job fair decision
but if your attackers your bestie so I
also that I just find opportunities I
say both side so resin exercises is
written higher or if you're lucky of
your own teeth and they actually attack
you you panic able to attack you usually
your production systems usually you
don't tell them what could have like
there's some rules of engagement but you
don't know what this planning is I'm
like a cat's hat for it's like I get
these things is happy to deal with a red
team exercises like I hope you see it
coming right and it's after three days
they haven't got anywhere like your meat
if after three minutes they're like well
I have all your passwords and minimal
your boxes you're in trouble
the reason why they want you are reading
exercise and so you can know what the
old threats are so it can you do like
blah blah you're like I think this might
happen this would happen to seems like a
terrible commute Ernest I've seen
previous examples to this but when you
do regem exercise you don't deal with
your actions preser you reveal what the
nurses it's better
nice mounting paper exercise so the
southwest it's in the desert column as I
think is delicious
but if you don't have to wait we have
amazing security level of the shirts to
do it you can do this at any level and
this is capture the flag contest
I'm sorry chapter leaders or oh I'll
follow up and every year I was a really
small CTF we have other CGS to do City
that shirt from Coca Cola's and
basically a whole bunch of people get
together in ruse and they bring their
laptop and you put up a vulnerable
system and people have if they saw
security problems all surfaces and
pictures and everything is using good
and then as you get usual things you get
sleigh and you change the site to the
price another absolute happiness I would
you want to do this at work well it will
take the development actually like the
security pieces is like Crabtree
raining how writers don't just run the
stretch that you wait you're good to
other sets you can't just get one single
time really need exercise all of your
race right
another good thing is it you get it over
in charity which is what I want so badly
great and the last thing is it's really
great for recruiting because if you have
a developer and they won you should
probably get this job lychees it's may
have gotten after this okay oh wait a
minute
okay so there's another side here I read
in my eyes like five three times I look
features do like literally tens and so
it's doing that okay so now that I feel
do like a lot of ideas as wouldn't a
stations to recruit me I bet in your
head all you're like oh my gosh this
smells fantastic
how can I be part of it thanks graph
okay so a thing if you doing a good
tester go so this is not just a popular
developers forever went disappearing
rates of your project manager you could
give your developers time to test if you
are writing with a person manager you
Kasai them a tool to help them ago you
could through these are three recipes
you just you could pay for training
courses like there's lots of different
things you could do to enable the subdue
coach in the developers being at afraid
of the very end right so most people if
you're doing web apps use web proxy and
if so imagine here's you should rather
it's just like this between you and
there's my editor and everything goes
through it and it watches you as you're
using your app it listens to you a
bigger than what's going on and you can
do is if you can do at this top it
change to work it and you can see how
your website to do way right so you can
find all sorts of things there's free
vulnerabilities very gratefully ones
that there's very quality you come users
to your fire but I feel like that's a
year who did you have no applications
you're happening it's like you're the
ones that set a very good angry about
trained easily required okay so another
thing okay fashion when you touch your
coat if you're using a vulnerability
scanner
it's a hacker tool great thank you
I just wondering about that okay so what
we're really doing is our hacker tools
so I have this applied in because I
don't want any of you into trouble so
don't get you know your own license
server suite and then be like I'm going
to do here to end up on that and then
I'm going to hit active stance attack
that's illegal you always want to have
position to tech school was the actual
authority I like you as permission you
don't know you need like whoever the
application owner is that yours is
network if you're outside you need a
contract you want to do rating you don't
want them to say it over beers which
I'll that be cool set and accessible at
Cana you can cover your derrière and
make sure that you're covered and other
things are though the school wellness
plan ever so it's a lot of passions with
tested your codes I hope about there
anyway um so what we're building
standards like if you use an automated
tool when you test your code they will
connect resources like crazy so don't
point it at your little tiny step server
at 9:00 a.m. on Monday and I go get a
copy because everyone on your she's
disease do you need to make sure you
share the resources you need to be sure
HMS of your data these night watching it
backups of your data the ocean at prod
that is these are the neck tivity like
you might want to take a bit of time to
learn great it and make sure to tell
your box we're going on give this tree
to your head your back heads up when
you're able to scan and so there you
tweeted that you're doing it locally so
you can stand will be on your own
machine if you have that power but often
you're going to be standing on to your
dead servers tell people you might
trigger off your future crunch in Texas
dispersant that you're not for life at
all
security is today and the non severe
thing so I help you but what's going on
especially the first time just get the
picture
but this is something that if you're
tough our developer is sort of work on
Monday and you talk to about the minute
work your manager you could tack your
please like but any are we interested in
doing that because those other hashes
are what they do like their creative
through building codes like they're
usually very proud and they want to
build the best software they can like a
soap opera tours and you can lose that
okay threat modeling this is where the
strategies and the developer get
together kind of hang out and talk about
app and I think if you were going to
attack your app how would you do it if
you were to break in it they're like oh
you don't you do this this happens I did
not know that
thank you no test for that later
developers have a different way of
looking at things tricky and you watch
it over there feature so if your manager
set up is pretty much like it doesn't
need to be hours an hour you don't need
like I've seen some of the talks for in
terms of threat modeling and there's
like five books and there's like this
huge content and maybe one day to get to
that that stage if that's where you need
to be to show you that level of
assurance if you're staring at the
beginning and you want to start wishing
that you just want to have a meeting
talking asking them those are after
didn't work so that you have no idea I'm
reviewing oh so I'm not in love with
reviewing code I find it really hard but
it's important for quality but also you
can find all sorts of things wrong with
it search for your trap model go look
for any security activities happening so
it o in Christian happi here who have
your money looks agriculture and make
sure it's okay like I would like to talk
more about this but I'm running out of
time for like static code analysis and
it's like an automated version of that
and come talk to me after this why it's
better I did all that time so thank you
it's the one I want to get across you
could write better
so learn miss Cruz give your developers
time given char the week to learn those
it I'm trained yourself there's so many
precursor there's so many like very
cheap courses because there is fun
really quickly there's lots of resources
on Lynch so it's really like if you want
to know each entity collage um you think
I'm the security expert on your team so
everyone comes to you okay so another
thing I want to talk to you though is oh
uh which is your new best friend forever
this you are in a no op event right now
we have chapters all around the world we
have one of mine in my city we have
three events we usually save you pizza
we really want to teach a course read
anything about applications tree that
you want to note we have like if I go
back inside like that we have so many
tools it free software we have free
cheese on everything that goat or wicked
check it all off not work I know it
sounds like an advertisement but it
returns in your screen you could you
later a lot you can become separate
yourself from your peers right like you
go to a walk meetings you're going to
meet all the right people because of any
kind of questions you want and also you
know the user is amazing it's a reason I
would be nowhere there's a lot in my
career really like there's nothing
better than my holds reviews and IG is
happen to meet Susan well so thank you
so much for having me um is any chance
does anyone have it it or this does okay
I'm seeing the after I love talking