yes hello and welcome everyone to talk
about content security policy in this
presentation we'll be talking about what
happened in the world of CSP in the last
12 months we will show you how we rolled
out CSP large-scale at Google to over a
hundred products and we'll also show you
some new keywords that finally made CSP
violation reports in my opinion useful
for the first time in history of CSP and
finally last but not least we will talk
about recent bypasses how we address
them and but also like limitations and
what you have to be careful when using
CSP as a defense in-depth mechanism so
my name is Lucas this is Micaela we both
work for Google in Zurich
we've looked in a focus area that kind
of investigates promising education
technologies like CSP and new platform
features for example like sapore teens
and fifties we try to address cross-site
scripting which is unfortunate still a
big issue at Google it's getting better
but yeah yeah before I ask before I
start with the recap may I ask you guys
like who has worked with CSP before the
content security policy who has seen an
awesome a lot of folks that's really
cool for those of you who haven't have a
couple of interest slides like two or
three just to get your boot strapped in
a moment so yeah so brief recap so one
year ago we presented also in Rome at
OPSEC at this time we did a lot of
research on violence based content
security policies and how CSP is used in
general for mitigation on in into that
basically so we did a large-scale study
and we kind of found out that most of
the policies are widely spaced and most
policies are extremely by possible by
you know automatically generate of all
arm bypasses so a little bit
disappointing because if UCSB offers
like very nice properties right but it
seems to be the case that life is speech
did not really work out in practice so
we thought that maybe a North Face CSP
would be a nice option here instead of
itis pasty speech because it has like a
couple of advantages over viability
space CSP but there's some hurdles and
to really make adoption of non-space you
see kind of possible in practice we
worked on strict dynamic it was like a
new keyboard that kind of transitivity
propagates trust to newly created
scripts which I'll show you in a second
and yeah so this is the research paper
be presented at CCS if you want to know
more about that your Institute e of
white lists we won't go into detail on
that today but yeah very nice summary of
that
so a quick bootstrap how does an
on-stage CSP work in practice the idea
is basically that you have a content
security policy like the one on the top
here and basically the browser will only
execute JavaScript tags on the page if
the script tag has a nonce attribute and
the nonce altitude value is the same as
the value in the nonce attribute or of
the CSP header in the response from the
server so it's all client-side these are
important that this non-spell you has to
be random for for every response and
deep behind that is if there's a
cross-site scripting vector and an
attacker can inject HTML for example
then he should not be able to know the
nonce random nonce because it's like
different for every response that's the
idea behind it in addition to that
non-space CSP has some very nice other
properties that are especially
interesting for deployment which are you
don't have to come up with a host or
path whitelist in the first place
which is tremendously time-consuming
very error-prone often leads to
breakages and as you saw by our research
also is often by possible because of you
know she simply like endpoints or
libraries like angular ingredients which
usually write lists in your application
yes so this is how it works basically if
you take like money example.com and it
has like this content security policy in
the response header scripts with nonstop
to field whether that matches the value
of the nonce here will be allowed to
execute by the browser because all
browser side right and it doesn't matter
if it's like inline script or source
script right on the other hand classical
reflected cross-site scripting like the
one we see here like if an attacker just
injects the script tag he does not know
the nonce value right so she cannot set
the proper nouns attribute and the
browser will reject these kind of
scripts so that's the basic idea behind
the unknown spaced CSP so what's up to
stick dynamic right strict dynamic is
basically an extension which came in CSP
free and it is meant to help non-space
that also has a CSP to basically each
deployment because in theory you have to
propagate a nonce to every script and
every subscript that gets generated
which can be very hard especially if you
use a library that for example do like
dynamically loading or for modules and
stuff like that also if they are
constants right so it's hard for
developers to patch libraries of others
right
so what stricter Namek does it basically
propagates trust from a non stripped to
a dynamic dynamically created script for
example if it is created through
document element document grade element
script ID with this you can for example
monster I don't know the widget you're
using and all subsequent scripts that
the widget is creating are automatically
blessed right
so you have to trust the widget in the
first place you usually do if you load
it on your page right and yes so in
practice this is very important and
basically allowed us to do like
large-scale deployment of nantes TSP it
is also stepping stone somehow right
because you can slowly reach start with
accent libraries to propagate the
nuances themselves but this is a yeah
quite handy for deployment quick
overview for example stuff like also
inserted scripts like document right is
not less specific dynamic what is left
is like scripts that are created through
like the Dom API like for example create
element script and then
document.body.appendchild script so at
the time between it is this pattern we
we were saying that like you know parcel
inserted scripts are very likely to
contain user input and are like really
kind of dangerous and also it's like a
bad pattern anyway so this was
disallowed and great element script
penned child script is much more
controlled right because it's a code and
at this time it seems like this is like
very rare it was a very interesting talk
just before this one in the other track
by the Bastion that he's and Kota and
they kind of showed that these patterns
are actually not so rare but we'll talk
about this in at the end of the
presentation so SSS like we'll also talk
a bit how we kind of mask deployed CSP
at Google we kind of switched hat from
like breaking everything to try to make
it work and make something else more
secure turns out this is actually not
easy so basically I don't know if you
have ever tried to deploy a likely space
to speed to a big product right it is
very hard and it usually like for
products like Gmail it can take multiple
people multiple years to come up with a
virus based policy and it will cause
breakage is it's like very hard right
with the non spaced CSPs and
Slick's dynamic we were able to kind of
deploy a handful of people were able to
deploy strict CSP to over hundred
products in I don't know six or nine
months which is a big difference to the
how useful CSP was previously right so
nowadays like about the building users
get served a strict CSP it's like I said
like over 150 services that have to six
ESP header and in addition to that we
get like over 50 million CSP reports
yeah that's a lot and no we didn't break
everything it's just a lot of noise and
I will also talk about how we deal with
this noise and how we kind of try to
make sense out of these millions of CSP
reports right so there's a couple of
examples a bigger product like you know
Google photos has a 60 SP nowadays
Google+ passwords at google.com like
sensitive domains right the one of the
you know for us very important things is
that we actually built in the 60s P
support into core frameworks and the
idea is that it is on by default for all
the new services right so developer
actually has don't have to have to know
anything about CSP or whatever right
it's just enabled for a new service out
of the box and ideally it would not
interfere with the developer at all it
would just be supported by the framework
and silently broke this is very nice
because if this model works what it
means that basically rolling out to six
CSP is zero effort once you have
impacted into the framework right and
this is actually the case now and it's
really nice because there's a lot of
benefits as a dependent that mechanism
if you have a strict policy right and
deploying it is very cheap nowadays
right so like that's a very good
trade-off for mitigation I think so
Google+ is a prime example here so we
added the support of the framework and
Google+ is a big application right and
usually it takes a long time to make it
just be compatible but in this case
since it was built on a core framework
have to talk about black and it had 60s
be enabled and so probably no nothing
broke but I don't know yeah so there's a
couple of requirements here for this
model to work right and that might also
be a bit google specific what we still
thought it'll work share how we did it
and maybe it is useful for other people
as well right first thing that is very
important to have is a kind of service
independent CSP configuration like
previously the whitelist you have to
come up with the CSP that is tailored to
your application may be tailored to
every page right
very hard to maintain it doesn't scale
really right next slide I will show you
what the uses a CSP but that's basically
the nice property of nonce based
policies they all the same regardless of
your service right so you don't have to
maintain the policy itself on regular
basis usually so another thing that
really helped us a lot
our conformance tests this is a some
just a name for tests we call internally
that make sure that developers don't
submit bad patterns in the code and what
these tests are actually they are
already for a longer time like even
before CSP and stuff like that but they
were really really really helpful for us
because one of these tests kind of
disallows inline event handlers in HTML
code and so the code did not have these
patterns in the first place
so it makes it much easier to actually
roll out to CSP right because doesn't
repel within an event handles
another very important and crucial thing
is that the template you're using to
render HTML support auto 19 I will show
you in a second what that means and yeah
last but not least you also need
sophisticated monitoring tools because
if you get like 50 million CSP reports
you kind of have to deal with that and
make sense out of them right yeah so as
I mentioned just basically one policy
you can technically use for almost all
applications right
at Google we mostly use this one you
might be concerned about the answers in
line and HTTP and this policy this is
only for backward compatibility reasons
so a new browser like Chrome or Firefox
that supports ESP free will be able to
pass the strict dynamic and one side
effects of strict and enmities is that
makes the policy more narrow by dropping
all the whitelist entries and unsafe in
line so new browser just ignores these
directives because of the economic an
older browser who does not understand
sir dynamic just falls back to the
unsafe behavior but that is okay because
you don't want to break the side right
so the policy is effective for new
process that support these platform
features all browsers just use to fall
back so you don't have to do user agent
sniffing or so like that right and of
course there's like also other pieces
that make the policy more robust like
you have to restrict object rows and
base your other vices like also the
bypasses you can do yes so the other
thing that is very important for kind of
easy large-scale deployment of a
non-space CSP is a templating systems
that support or announcing there's a
couple we patched our things too if we
internally but one example that is also
available to the is also open sources
like closure templates and it's really
cool because you basically have on the
server side one place there you generate
the nonce
you set the response header and you also
provide this random nonce value to the
templating system so this is done in the
core framework in exactly one place
right and then the templating system
takes care of everything else in this
case you have like a closure template
that just like creates a script tag and
set some parameters right and the output
rendered output looks like that the
framework automatically adds a nonce
attribute for you with the value that
was set on the back end and the nice
thing is all your HTML templates
magically happen on set and you don't
have to refactor every single HTML page
propagate the nonce value through all
these channels to the single pages set
to manual delight and maybe forget some
and whatnot right so it's really a much
easier this way basically and this is
what
scales right so this is also where you
can just talk about Black Flag on G+ and
it has a strict dynamic PSD enabled so
yeah keep it yeah there's a problem
there's how do you find out if something
is broken right what you really don't
want is you don't want to roll out this
ESP that breaks Gmail because you see is
people be rolled back so fast that you
probably yeah you probably won't have a
chance to roll it out again right so you
really have to be careful that you don't
break existing functionality with the
content security policy originally CSP
violation reports were fought to help
with that right because then you have a
violation on the browser and reporting
is enabled the browser sends back a
violation report and this violation
report then is meant for the developer
to you know make some sense and tell him
what went wrong if he you know forgot to
nonce script or if you forgot an inline
event handler or basically if something
is broken right so the problem here is
that most of these violation reports are
not actionable I'll show in a second why
it is basically not possible to
distinguish between noise from browser
extensions and real violations and if
you get like 50 million reports per day
and most of it is noise it's really
problematic to find out what is actually
you know if something is broken at all
it's just all fine is just know it's
right so there's a really new there's a
really cool new keyword which is called
repot sample and it is basically similar
to what firefox already does it
basically sends the first 40 bytes of
the script that was blocked from
executing and it's already shipped in
from 59 which is in beta now and in
addition to the fire front functionality
it also does that for inland event
handlers which is really necessary
because otherwise you run into the same
problem again and you don't know if like
a violation caused by an event and
levels by an extension or your code
right so quick example to illustrate
that let's assume you have like an
inline script and you forgot the nonce
you will get a report like that our same
with an event handler you forgot to
remove the reflexology
handler CSP blocks it's right so you get
a report like that which looks exactly
like the first one and then the
problematic case is a browser extension
Chrome or Firefox extension injects the
script into your page inline or an
inline event handler and what will
happen is you will get exactly the same
CSP report so this is very problematic
right because just like three different
causes and they all can write the same
report and if like Chrome extensions or
Firefox extensions they're very popular
right so you get like a ton of Violation
report right and you have no idea from
there looking at the report if this is
like a breakage from your site or if
it's just noise the report sample
keyword is tremendously helpful here
because it tends to first 40 bytes of
the script that was blocked in this case
hello
in this case loaded and in this case
like some I know browser extension
injected script and with that you can
basically start building signatures for
popular browser extensions and you can
take the sample and search in your
codebase to find out if this is actually
in your code right and if yes you
probably have a breakage no violation
and you have to fix it right yes and
with that I will hand over to Mickey who
will talk about the tools we developed
at Google to make this task of the
points used easier thanks Lucas so what
we did to briefly recap is we took 50
has it was a little more than one year
ago we found out there was a problem
with what is the origin whitelist model
and so we added SiC dynamic and with
this modification we were able to to
deploy it at scale at Google this
created the need for some serious
tooling to prototype policies to monitor
violations and to actually assess the
quality of the policy itself so here I
present three tools two of which are
open source one is importantly history
internal but we have some plans to
eventually open source it in the future
so the first one is a browser extension
a Chrome extension which we call cs50
mitigator
which is very useful as CFG deployment
analysis tool and it basically
identifies
of a page that are not compatible with
CSP even graphically as you see it also
helps the developer make necessary
changes before deployment to make the
the web application CSP compliant and I
have a very quick demo here let's take
for example Google Finance which is not
yet CSP already and it's right like
screen resolution so we start the
extension and then we reload and we
immediately see that some here are some
borders
so basically green border means there is
an inline event handler the red border
means that there is a dryer scriptures
are not announced and so we can for
example I can go around a little bit the
stock stuff greener and so on yes I was
hoping to trigger I was hoping to
trigger one that had an inline event
handler so that you see border but I'm
not that lucky anyway at the end when
you know okay there are lots of things
that are not compatible to you you see
you can see here the little counter
going up and up okay so when when you're
ready to stop and a report is generated
and here you have everything that is not
compatible with a lot divided by
categories so for example you have
unknown script you have inline event
handlers and you can click on more and
you have the full code and then there
are some actionable information such as
you should do this you should with
factor markups we should avoid
JavaScript your eyes and so on this
second tool is a 50 evaluator which is
open source that you can go 250 -
evaluator dot with Google comm or use
the QR code and it is basically a tool
for evaluating how good a policy is
which is a very very hard task
a few tools online but it is very very
hard to score a policy because TSP is
evolving and look at it represented yes
so it's a very repetitive task well just
like a lot of things you have to take
care when you evaluate a CSP and this is
just a collection of all the checks you
pasted in a policy and will tell you
everything that is basically are in the
policy that allows like a crude bypass
you can also source script from some
other sites right and we'll just try to
fetch it doesn't always work but when it
works it's it's convenient right or
safer one is a bark stud go to org and
you see like if everything is green is
usually a good sign because parts of
chromodoris has project zero and release
bugs yeah makes sense to have a policy
there right so play around with it and
yeah feedback is always welcome okay and
then internally we have another tool
which will CSP fronting which is for
visualizing the sheer amount of CSP
violation reports that we get as Lucas
explained earlier on so we had to come
up with some interesting design choices
for example for deduplication so we have
a lot of duplicates reported are not
exactly the same but they are exactly
the same in meaning so we found out that
leveraging script sample is very useful
and actually sometimes it was the only
piece of signal the only signal that
actually made a difference so we have an
interface with real-time filtering you
see at the top which is performed
client-side of for example document your
I and so on I think due to resolution
issue is not very readable and sorry
about that
I saw online so yeah and then there is a
high level view and there is a detailed
violation view and you can drill down by
clicking on the orange orange bill icon
to see similar report across for example
browser versions browser and so on
finally we have some tools to measure
coverage for HTML responses at Google
scale so for example we can find out
regressions we can found out when
appropriately that was previously
sending a good CSP policies now is
sending a bad CSP policy or none at all
so this is done by integrating the CC
evaluator logic in such automated checks
which is which we found to be very
useful so I am going quickly to go
through some recent bypass and what can
go wrong what are the imitation of the
straight dynamic approach because it's
very important to to be clear about that
so strict dynamic is not a silver a
silver bullet and 50 internal is not a
silver bullet you can't just add CSP to
a side to make it invulnerable to XSS
and in fact while it provides a pretty
good degree of security in its list as a
defense in that mechanism for most
properties there are some somehow
complex and bypasses so for example in
this case you just the policy is just an
on space policy with script SRC but an
important attacker could do is inject a
base tag and to evil comm and if you
have an on script that has a relative
SRC well that SRC gets rebase to evil
comm and the solution here is just to
restrict base your eye to none or self
as you see fit and another another
bypass is by using a combination of SVG
and dangling markup which is a not
particularly new technique but it can be
a pretty powerful so in this case the
attacker add injects an SVG tag and then
uses set to animate attributes of the
SVG this makes us originally originally
present script tag in the page part of
the SVG which is governed by actually
another parser and another doctype and
basically this means that it is possible
to change attributes of the script tag
from SVG this has been fixed in chrome
58 there are also some techniques to
steal noses
so the hard part is actually to reuse
them because when you reuse we want to
reuse a script unknown well in theory
you have to trigger a browser reload and
this means that the nulls have changed
in the meantime so you don't get
scripted script execution from that but
there are some some some ways but let's
talk about stealing nonces first so in
this case we do it we accomplish that by
using CSS selectors so css3 is very
powerful and you can say something like
that match all the script tags that have
a nonce attribute that starts with a and
then replace the content with record a
so this allows expectation of the nonce
character by selector another semuc
technique is trying to force a C data
like mode in the past by using for
example dangling markup so usually it's
a form with an input and a text area
inside text area makes basically eats up
all the mark-up that follows and mix it
submittal to an attacker in this case
evil.com
slash form well CSP allows to restrict
form action but this is not really the
point there could be something much more
sensitive data after like credit cards
number or excessive tokens and so on in
P I is how do we use nonces that's very
hard and most of the times you actually
can't reuse analysis so usually the way
to it is possible to reuse notices in
the page only if there is some kind of a
symmetric set of JavaScript code and
execution on the same page and you can't
inject that logic it has to be already
present another another way is by
exploiting the multiple caches that are
in the browser's so HTTP cache is
usually not a big problem but for
example back forward cache which is a
dumb cache the same cache that when you
for example still in a form and you do
you hit the back button in the browser
and you see that the form is still still
that's the back forward cache in some
cases it might allow to actually use an
old known and so we can think of a few
scenarios here for example an XSS due to
data received a symmetrically the a post
message or a persistent Dom XSS where
the
dispatch via xhr right so this would
this will be scenarios and stealing and
reusing nonces would be possible so to
recap the injection of base has been
fixed by it can be fixed by a certain
behavior I the SVG bug has been fixed
and the exfiltration of nodes in general
we dealt with it by just hiding the nose
to the dome so basically during the
building parsing the browser's replace
the nose attribute with a dummy value
and this is in chrome 59 and this means
that CSS selectors and any other
technique that tries to get the the nose
would not work dangling multiple stacks
are a little bit more complex and there
is a proposal to forbid completely for
beta parser inserted things which are
disallowed by strict dynamic in the
first place so this would work out of
the box for economic compatible
properties also it would enforce best
coding practices I'm going a little bit
fast here because we have just a few
minutes left so there are some
JavaScript framework on libraries that
are very powerful and somehow introduced
bypasses for strict dynamic this is
because they have a needle-like
functionality using usually no script
Dom element as a source it can be a div
tag it can be a maker tag so basically
they have query selectors on let's say
inert tags and somehow they put it to
evil or evil like functionalities like
the pattern that is allowed by strict
dynamic which is create element script
and ecstasy or text so this is usually a
problem with unsafe evil or strict
dynamic so the solution in general is to
make the framework library CSP aware so
in a way these frameworks have are so
powerful that often have a full-featured
JavaScript parser in certain inside them
so they are kind of a virtual machine in
a way so they basically take away power
from the browser and they are the
browser can no longer enforce the
restrictions and so it makes sense to
have some kind of cSPD of the yes at
least a stripped down version of CSP
since with great power comes great
responsibility
so two primitives would be
adding could whitelist for evil or evil
things that are similar let's say to CFD
hashes this is completely different to
origin whitelist that you should really
forget and or non checking so for
example what happened in jQuery is that
dot HTML dot append replaced with and so
on when they you pass a script
JavaScript code the what they do is they
can't provide it to inner HTML because
the script does not get evaluated when a
path path to inner HTML what we do is
they take the JavaScript code and they
do create element script and they put it
there or they call evil this is the code
so you can see if there is you strict
well you'd get aligned script code
appendchild remove child which is
exactly what strict dynamic allows or
they just called evil code
well for example Dropbox fix the each
dish by just patching required to check
gnosis they just have a Windows est
script nonce and basically the check
again against it we have a more generic
solution that is using the appendix of
this this presentation which I invite
you to look up so to wrap up you should
not use watches based a CSP because this
is always by passable
not only is good enough unless you run
frameworks with symbolic JavaScript
execution capabilities in that case you
should take responsibility for that and
ask them simple nonce plastic dynamic
economic slightly relaxes don't exercise
protection but it is significantly
easier to deploy in fact we believe that
most of the times nonce only
is impossible to to deploy a large scale
for complex application also hash only
in a specific dynamic are very
interesting combination so for example
hash specific dynamic is it's this idea
of having a bootstrapping script just as
one script at inline script that has
unknown hash and dynamically loads the
scripts so this is very interesting
because for example you can not even
have a web server or any a kind of
think content and still benefit from
strict dynamic so in conclusion fifty
Weiss's are broken
nonspecific dynamic greatly simplify CSP
rollout ESP is not a silver bullet and
this is very important and I will always
press this
there are bypasses this is a mitigations
is a defense-in-depth mechanism and the
bypasses are becoming actually more and
more difficult and complex technically
which is good means we're doing a good
job and 50 is still very powerful
defense in that mechanism to mitigate
XSS also I'd like to say if a company CP
does not come for free even if strict
dynamic is easier to deploy you should
still put some effort for example in
having in non sinn script tags so for
example having sweet contextual out
escaping some plating system which is
actually very rare in the industry still
and so it is natural that you would need
to also take care of the bypasses of the
one or two JavaScript or framework that
might be problematic in our experience
patching for example jQuery it is not so
hard to patch them usually there there
are very few things per library and we
are we fixed for example internally
Google closure bypasses and we hope to
be able to upstream some of the other
fixes to jQuery and other commonly used
libraries and with that I questions are
very welcome thanks a lot