hello everyone yeah my presentation is
going to be super breed files just
present to you the booklet that we did
we actually started this project over a
year ago with some research to find out
what does already exist in the field of
yeah who does what kind of work in order
to teach children how they can protect
their privacy so we had a bit of look
around checked out with other
organizations or veggie dish and then
try to fill again so we found out that
most of the organizations mostly yeah
target speed parents either parents so
they tried to tell them how to control
their their children's communications
better or they try to tell kids yeah
don't talk to any strangers on the
internet right so we wanted to do
something different and this is why we
have yeah we've done together with many
of our member organizations this short
comic comic book list so our main
motivation was really to empower kids to
give them some tools in order to
understand how their data is collected
online and also some really hands-on
guidance on for example installing the
signal private messenger so to give them
really alternatives to the big data
collection apps that are out there so
the booklet was published in October
2016 and it was immediately super
popular within only six week it was
downloaded over our 20 yeah 20 second
average time and then
had the total download of 25 k now so
this is really good and that's for the
English version only every members
involved in writing this thing we had
five of our organizations participating
and writing the different chapters we
already have in the works translations
into 15 languages some are finalized
some are still ongoing and need to be
put in layout and fun stuff like that
and yeah and we have also agreed group
members and observers working on the
translations I think well more than a
sauna right now so our mission is really
to help kit make safer and more informed
choices about what they share and how
they share their information online and
we have we do that through a couple of
chapters like what the internet actually
is what privacy is and as I said some
really hands-on advice on how to improve
the security of smartphones stuff like
that so yeah so the booklet is called
digital defenders because of good guys
this is for defenders are fighting
against bad guys the data intruders and
this whole booklet takes place in in
some sort of parallel universe yeah so
the coming we were joined by a comic
book itís can I was that luck he did
some awesome work there and yeah the
every members involved in actually
writing and producing the content where
bits of freedom open rights group the
chaos computer club with Kozma Schuler
project a shaft FD Romania media mock
raphy and many more so as I said we
already have a couple of translations
ready as it's out in
Serbian already is it has been
translated and also printed in German
it's published in Greek Italian and
Turkish I think they also printed it in
Turkey and distributed it so that's
great and very soon we are going to
publish the spanish and french version
but as I said many many more languages
are underway so there's still a lot of
work to do and we were able to
distribute it in the Member States
thanks to many volunteers who helped us
but we can always use more of course so
if your language is not there yet and
you can come to us and ya help us with
the translations you can also donate
donate to every members in the Member
States so that they can then print the
booklets and distribute it to the school
so yeah that's really it so I have for a
couple of them like this is the german
one this is the english one the english
one has a very nice closer also to take
out and put up in your apartment so yeah
[Applause]