everybody um so I think we were
preparing for our talk today we thought
maybe it was more like just talking
about something interesting and maybe
get a discussion going so this was great
to hear all these great talks about
various projects people are doing the
Senate for democracy and technology is
doing a number of great projects but I
don't have any beautiful handouts or
graphic novels about them so instead I
thought one thing that's been really
interesting for us and our presence in
Europe right now is the GPRS concepts
around explain ability for those of you
who are in the first session this
morning on big data about the question
and answer session led to a lot of
really interesting ideas and
conversation so I thought I would share
a couple of thoughts from my perspective
as someone from the United States and
then maybe hopefully we could talk as a
group if people are interested and if
not we can go early and have more coffee
whatever people prefer I just saw a
really interesting quote from a
professor named Barry O'Sullivan the
computer science department at the
University College in Cork who said that
he says for me the true hallmark of
intelligence is the ability to explain
there are a lot of tasks that can be
automated by a technology that can do
the job very well but it doesn't really
understand what it's doing or doesn't
understand why it did something in a
particular setting this is really
interesting to me I saw that we just
automated poker poker can now be played
by artificial intelligence including
bluffing which is really fascinating um
it's interesting because I'm not
entirely certain that people understand
why they did what they did in a
particular setting and if you asked for
an explanation from someone if I say why
did you take a picture of this why did
you write that down and all this other
thing you'll have an answer you'll be
able to explain the decision but I'm not
confident that that explanation existed
before I asked you right it's sort of
something that you came up with and once
you were asked to come up with it and
that kind of rationalizing behavior I'm
curious if what we're doing is is
forcing it onto
technology and trying to build the same
accountability we expect from each other
from its artificial system rather than
sort of thinking broadly about what
accountability might work best for this
new technology that operates a bit
differently than a person so far the
word sort of making it more like a
person so in the u.s. there's explained
ability is a really popular theme for
any kind of best practices documents or
any sort of kind of arguments around how
we should manage algorithmic fairness so
the US Association of Computing
Machinery just released an ethics
statement and principle seven principles
one of them is explained ability which
about which they say systems and
institutions that use algorithmic
decision-making are encouraged to
provide explanations regarding both the
procedures followed by the algorithm and
the specific decisions that are made
this is particularly important in a
public policy context so that's one kind
of perspective and then a woman named
Cathy O'Neil who I'm sure many of you
are familiar with who recently published
weapons of mass destruction has an
argument around sort of transparency
that relates to explain ability which is
that you should feel comfortable telling
people your criteria for a decision
your logic for a decision if those
criteria are robust her argument was
made in the context of teacher
evaluations when they were saying we
can't tell the teachers what the
evaluation is based on or they will game
the system Kathy's argument which makes
a lot of sense is that if your system
can be gamed it's not a very good system
reason that we can tell people generally
what constitutes the factors that make
up your credit score for example is
because those factors are incredibly
robust predictors for your
creditworthiness so if you carry a low
debt if you pay your payments on time
and if you have had a long history of
credit you are in fact a better credit
risk so in that context to game the
system means to be a better credit risk
which is the outcome they're trying to
get out anyway so it makes perfect sense
to share them if you apply the same
logic to policing what should be true is
that the criteria used to predict who's
going to commit a crime should be things
that make
you disinclined to commit a crime so
telling people what these things are if
they game the system should mean there's
less crime everybody wins
but obviously this concept of gaming and
proprietary information is is a barrier
to that so one last point of view and
sort of explain ability from from from
my perspective is you know at CDT when
we were thinking about this we we agreed
with the sentiment of the computing
machinery concept but we felt that it
could be used a bit more abstractly
which is to say if you if you as a
company or you as an institution who is
using a predictive anything predictive
analytics or automated decision-making
have to answer to yourself how how much
you can explain about what you've done
it gives you the opportunity to
understand the weaknesses of your own
system and if you have to make that
public then it gives other people the
opportunity to evaluate how they want to
use your technology so it could be a
system where you say listen we used we
use pred pol it turns out pred pol is
like 95% garbage five percent useful
then if you know that about it you don't
have to stop using it necessarily or
demand an explanation but it will
definitely lower your credibility to try
and use it to make a high-quality
decision as opposed to if you could say
the data that goes into here is really
robust we've checked it against these
standards and therefore we know that
it's it's pretty explainable the results
and now you can use it for more things
so we thought of explain ability more as
a criteria rather than a barrier I don't
think I'm explaining that quite right in
any case this morning's conversation
seemed to center around whether or not X
explained ability and explanation was a
sufficient transparency measure and it
seems like folks has sort of differing
views on that I don't remember where it
left off but if anybody is interested in
talking about explain ability at all
good or we could be done because I think
I'm last yeah so
eight points of view GDP are
okay no problem no conversation thanks
[Applause]