- [Adam] And for our next speaker,
we're gonna have Anthony
Randazzo from Expel.
Thank you.
I'm really excited to be here.
Thank you, ATT&CK team for
giving me the opportunity
to know present cloud things.
Cloud is sort of this
new frontier in security
that we're starting to discover,
so I'm happy to be here.
All right, so again, my
name is Anthony Randazzo.
I lead the global response
team here at Expel.
What is Expel?
Expel's a technology company
that's built this SAS
application, the SAS platform,
to enable our 24/7 managed
detection and response service.
We integrate directly with the APIs
and more than 45 different
security vendors.
Prior to Expel, I managed a
Fortune 25 healthcare detection
and response team.
Before that, I dabbled
in threat intelligence.
I was a crime analyst at iSIGHT Partners,
which was subsequently
acquired by FireEye.
Just a quick disclaimer, I'm
by no means a cloud expert,
but I do frequently
contribute our cloud detection
and response findings to our
blog, which you can see here.
Feel free to hit that URL
up for some cool to that.
All right.
So what to expect from this presentation.
We're all insecurity and we all know
that security is sort of this afterthought
in our corporate technology environments.
It shouldn't be a surprise to anybody
that cloud sort of
followed that similar path.
To be honest, we're actually observing
that much of cloud security
is actually falling
on people outside of
traditional security teams
like devops or cloud architecture.
But it's not all doom and gloom.
So this presentation's less
about how we can use ATT&CK
and its current form today,
but how we can evolve and mature it.
So today, we're gonna
cover ATT&CK for cloud
as we see it here,
defending the control plane,
a real world incident
and some other incidents
and how we've applied
ATT&CK for cloud there
and then some takeaways.
Just a quick note again,
on this presentation,
it assumes that you have a
limited knowledge of cloud.
So apologies if there's
anything that's elementary
to the cloud experts out there,
or if I've overlooked a
foundational information
for less experienced
cloud security people.
So ATT&CK for clouds just over a year old.
The community has been iterating
as the world learns more
about attackers in the cloud.
Jen and the ATT&CK team
released some really, really
great changes last month,
plus all the new sub techniques for cloud.
So what exactly is ATT&CK for cloud.
Simply put it's a way
to communicate how attackers misuse
and abuse cloud services.
So we see this as two big buckets today.
We have infrastructure as a service
and we have software as a service.
So infrastructure as a service
are those large cloud providers
like AWS, Azure, Google.
The ATT&CK surface for these
infrastructures as a service
are similar because they're providing
almost the same services as each other,
they just use different names.
When we talk about software as a service,
these are cloud services
that you don't have to
manage any infrastructure
or a platform.
The big ones, we all know,
Salesforce, ServiceNow,
Zoom, Workday, GitHub, et cetera.
The ATT&CK services with these,
there's a little bit more variance,
but are likely gonna be concerned
with the identity and access
management that software
and the service APIs for them.
So how is cloud different
from the rest of the enterprise ATT&CK?
So there there's clearly
enough differences
in the ATT&CK surfaces of
each of the operating systems.
So Linux, Windows, Mac, that
they weren't their own matrix.
But what makes the cloud matrices
or the cloud providers different?
It's not really that much.
So identity and access management
is the primary differentiator
in each of these cloud platforms.
They all provide the same services.
It's how you access those
services at their core.
So each platform has a different identity
and access management.
And we'd argue that much
of the learning curve
actually lies with the IAM,
the identity and access management
for security practitioners.
So what makes the cloud matrices similar,
and this is the big thing here,
each of them have what we call a control
or a management plane.
And this is a similar attack surface
across each of those providers.
So the infrastructure as a service users,
we use this control plane
to manage the various
cloud resources via APIs.
And this is where we're
actually seeing attackers abuse
and misuse cloud services.
And it'll be one of the main
focuses of this presentation.
So considering the differences
and similarities today,
is this enough for each
of these cloud providers
to warrant their own matrix.
Today we have an AWS
matrix, and Azure matrix,
and GCP matrix.
And the answer is actually no.
So last month, Jen on the ATT&CK team
announced their consolidation
from one matrix down
or from the three matrices
down to one matrix
based on what we know
about attackers today.
So let's zoom in on the
the cloud attack surfaces.
There's lots of new
technology in the cloud
that didn't even exist 10 years ago.
And there's quite attack
surfaces at the same time.
So we already mentioned the control plane,
the management plane,
it's a way to abstract administration away
from all of these various
services using one thing.
We have Kubernetes and it's
control plane for management.
Kubernetes being a way
to manage or containerize the environment.
I'm not an expert by
any means of Kubernetes,
so I will stop there.
Storage services like
S3 or Azure Blob Service
or Google cloud service,
this is your hard drives in the cloud.
The compute resources,
so all of the VMs that run in the cloud.
So Amazon EC2, Azure VM,
this is where all of our
applications are running
that are not in containerized
or even in containerized environments.
Cloud databases and AWS,
RDS, Redshift, et cetera.
So why did we choose to
focus on this control plane
given we know about all of
these different attack surfaces?
A few reasons.
Our theory was that it
would likely be easier
to spot attacker fingerprints.
And I'll get more on this soon
with regards to like the data that we use
to spot those fingerprints.
But it's also a super
high risk for businesses,
a business, any businesses.
If you lose the access
keys to your control plane,
it could potentially be
like having domain admin
for a Windows environment.
Another reason, there's
not a ton of traction
with EDR in the cloud.
There's very few vendors
that are actually spending
a ton of effort here
and there's even less
customers deploying it
that could be possibly due to
the reason I mentioned before
of cloud security falling
on other teams like devops.
And lastly, the migration
to containerized and
serverless cloud compute.
So it's important to know
what we're responsible for
versus what our cloud
providers are responsible for
regarding security.
So this is the shared responsibility model
for cloud security.
Each provider has one and
they're all relatively the same.
This is AWS's, which much of
the rest of this presentation
will be the focus of.
But what what we found out
through the shared responsibility model
is that the cloud provider
is actually responsible
for very little security.
And I think this is kinda a
misconception that people have
when migrating to the cloud
that there's inherently more security.
It's definitely true in some instances,
but generally speaking, it's not.
So on this diagram,
the blue mostly represents all
the different cloud services.
that each provider offers,
that's EC2 and VPC,
S3 storage, IAM, RDS, all
these different acronyms
that are services and AWS.
All of these services are
managed by their control plane,
and the control plane is made
up of many different APIs
to access each service.
So there's three ways
that you can actually
access those services
through the control plane.
First, the web UI, that's
console.aws.amazon.com.
Next is the CLI, which is
the command line interface
through some shell.
This isn't commonly used.
And then we have programmatic access
through software development kits, SDKs.
And this is the most common
because most AWS resources
are managed programmatically
through infrastructures code
like Terraform or cloud formation.
But we do know that
the cloud control plane
is actually a shared responsibility.
AWS tries to make the
APIs inherently secure,
and you can make the debate
as to whether there's
vulnerabilities or their features,
but they're also providing
protection through paid services
like Amazon guard duty
So here is a brief story
of our threat detection journey in AWS.
We know we wanted to focus on
defending the control plane,
but where do we start?
So first we ask what native
detection capabilities
or services does AWS offer
for the control plane?
The answer is guard duty,
and there's about 50 or so use
cases or guard duty findings
for the control plane that
offers threat detection
in that service.
So there's definitely some
great detection in guard duty,
but some are less helpful just
like any security product.
We actually have a couple
of blogs highlighting
the value we see in guard duty.
So knowing that what are our gaps?
We have guard duty, what are the gaps
and how we defend this control plane.
There's almost 10,000 different APIs.
So there's probably quite a few.
Shout out to Scott at Summit Route
for providing the plethora
of AWS security resources
we used sort of drive this detection
and response strategy as well.
So what's next?
Now we need to find the data
that we have available to us
to develop that detection
strategy for the control plane.
And with that, we're sort
of off the CloudTrail now.
So CloudTrail is the native AWS logging
for our control plane.
So we've got all the CloudTrail data.
How do we start building
threat detections?
What are our use cases?
What are our threat models?
So we decided to look at
offensive security tools
that abused or misused
the control plane in AWS.
These are penetration testing frameworks.
PACU is or was
and probably still is the
most well-known today.
This was open source from the good folks
over at Rhino Security Labs.
After we did this,
we built experimental detections
on the CloudTrail data
to see if, one, attackers were
actually using these tools,
which some were,
or two, are the attackers
abusing or misusing the APIs
that were identified in
these OSTs in other ways.
So from there, we iterated.
We tuned, enriched,
contextualized these detections
as we learned more about real attackers.
And we caught a bunch of
penetration testers in red team
along the way.
So this is an actual attack
that Expel detected and responded to.
It's what I would call an
unconventional coin miner.
Because when we generally
see a coin miner,
it's a result of an RCE exploitation
on some web application.
In this instance, we have an attacker
that identified root AWS access keys
and a GitHub repo or wherever it was,
and then used those keys we saw
from an unusual IP from that environment.
So let's talk about root
access key risk a little bit.
The root access key
risk allows an attacker
to have complete control
of potentially production environment.
This is route access, unless
there are some controls
that you can implement to
reduce access to root keys,
but in most instances
it's complete control
of that AWS account.
So basically the domain
admin of the AWS account.
So what did the attacker
do with those keys?
He or she created
multiple, extra large EC2s
and associated SSH key pairs
for those EC2 instances,
those are VMs.
Then they modified the
VPC security groups,
the virtual firewalls to allow any access.
And this was all done via
an automated bot written
in one of the AWS SDKs or
software development kits.
At this instance, it was going,
so a whole bot that was written and go.
So those SSH keys were then passed off
to access the new EC2s that were spun up
to install the coin miners.
This is where we actually
saw guard duty coming.
Guard duty detections are
based on three data sets.
It's CloudTrail, which is
the control plane logs.
Your DNS and AWS and your VPC flow logs,
which is your NetFlow.
But keep in mind that
this guard duty alert
is actually EC2 finding and
is not for the control plane.
This finding is actually meant
to identify evil in your EC2
based on DNS or flow traffic.
But at the end of the day,
it was great correlation for our analysts.
So with this story painted
or this picture painted,
this leads into how we visualize
MITRE ATT&CK for cloud.
So let's get into that a bit.
So what we have here is a model
of everything that occurred
with the AWS root keys
before those SSH keys
were used to authenticate to EC2.
Think of it as two phases of the attack.
But this also highlights how
little we know about attacks
on the infrastructure of service
platforms, AWS, GCP, Azure,
There's lots of maturity and
the other enterprise matrices.
So to detect an attacker here,
we're relying on our security signal
from those control planes.
So for AWS, it's CloudTrail.
And GCP, it's the admin activity,
the system event and the
data access audit logs.
It's the activity logs and Azure.
All of these control plane logs
are not created equal, though.
You got to think that AWS has been around
for probably five more...
It's got five more years
of maturity than GCP.
So naturally, the AWS control plane logs
are significantly more mature
than GCP in our experience.
So here is what we call the
second phase of the ATT&CK.
Everything after those SSH
keys were passed to the bot
to install the coin miners.
And what you're seeing here is
the enterprise Linux matrix.
So the first thing we observe
is obviously a much more well understood
and mature attack surface
than an attack for cloud.
But interestingly, this is
almost the same attack mapping
as we sort of mentioned
earlier with RCE exploitation
of a web application to
install a coin miner.
So we actually have a few
more examples of attackers
hopping around between the cloud
and the enterprise
windows or Linux matrices.
So similar to the attack
we described earlier,
we have another instance of an attacker,
except this came from the AWS CLI.
So it was more hands on keyboard,
but it was multiple compromised keys
and the attacker imported
their own SSH keys
to access the EC2.
Next, we had Python SDK access,
AWS system security manager,
SSM is the SCCM of AWS.
And by default, this
provides pseudo Linux access.
While this wasn't a real attacker,
it was a pretty sophisticated red team.
Next we have server-side
request forgery exploitation,
so SSRF.
These are the ones that we see
or we used to see most
commonly in the news,
similar to many high profile
breaches like Capital One,
essentially the EC2 instance,
the VM has credential
access to the control plane
through the instance metadata service
that provides data, the EC2,
that it needs to do its thing.
But essentially, you can take
those EC2 instance credentials
that may be over permissioned
and can use those
to do malicious abuse,
misuse the control plane,
or even use them and escalate privileges.
And lastly, we saw an RDS database.
What this was, was actually a broad scan
against open PostgreSQL databases.
It wasn't quite that hop between matrices,
but what was interesting
was that we were able
to identify how the database was ransomed
through the CloudTrail control plane logs.
And to do this, actually CloudTrail logs,
we saw when the password was changed
and that RDS instance was clearly exposed
to the open internet.
So based on our detection
response experience
in AWS here at Expel,
we developed this really
cool mind map for ATT&CK
for the APIs that we observed
being abused or misused
over the last 18 plus months.
So keep in mind that
many of these have yet
to be modeled into ATT&CK for cloud,
but we're definitely working
with Jen and the miter folks
to get some of this stuff
documented and modeled in.
But if you would like a
copy, the link is there,
and we're happy to
share it with everybody.
So let's talk about some of the takeaways.
There's clearly lots of
ATT&CK surface in the cloud.
But there's also lots of opportunity
to better understand all
of the enterprise matrices
and improve cloud in particular.
We don't know what we don't know.
There's a lot of public
detections out there
against CloudTrail,
but many of these vast
majority of these are
for what we would call
a risky configuration.
So an S3 bucket exposed to the internet
or an RDS bucket exposed to the internet.
A risky configuration change
on your VPC security group.
And these aren't really
pushing the envelope,
it's just a lot of alerts that
don't tell us a whole lot.
What we need are more
threat-centric detections.
We need more experimentation.
Again, this is sort of that new frontier,
and we need to try a
bunch of different things
to sort of see what sticks.
And lastly, attack automation I think
is really here to stay.
Almost every example that I had discussed
was an automated attack
with the exception of the one attacker
that was using the CLI.
But this limits our ability
to respond rapidly attacks.
And it almost implies that
we have to sort of shift
to this automated response
framework in the cloud.
So that's all I had today.
I hope that this is very
insightful for everybody.
I know this is a lot of new material
and a lot of new concepts to people.
18 months ago, I had virtually
no experience in the cloud.
So let me be a lesson to anybody else
that it's easy to spin up
and learn these things.
But I'm happy to elaborate
on anything in Slack.
And thanks again for having me here today.
- Thanks for sharing.
That was fantastic.
And like you said, a lot of us
are kind of in the same boat
where we know of the risks here,
we know of the growing threat,
but just getting those
first steps into the cloud,
it's such a learning curve.
So we definitely appreciate
all your insight.
We had a lot of great
questions building up in Slack,
so definitely over there.
You had some really good ones.
I'm gonna to poke your mind a little bit.
So you shared before like
the shared responsibility,
I think that's not something
necessarily that's new,
like even in the traditional
enterprise environment,
there's some kind of spillage
between the users and the actual vendors.
But what are your thoughts
on how as a security practitioner,
and we use this same example from Alley,
the small SOC, how do I
work with the big vendors?
I'm thinking about things
like metadata services,
things that maybe are
outside of my control.
What are your suggestion
here for like as a security practitioner,
how can I augment those services
as well as work with the vendors
to actually increase the security
as we learn more about these threats.
- Yeah, it's tough as a
small shot, because I mean,
as we all know, we're
stretched pretty thin as it is
from the security perspective.
I think it's important
which the community is
doing a very good job at,
but when we identified these things
that are inherently problematic,
like particularly metadata service
I'll use that as an example.
So the instance metadata service
after their Capital One breach,
there was so much pressure on AWS
to make that thing more secure
because it was causing so many problems.
But actually they revealed
instant metadata service
version two, which eliminates
a lot of the risks there.
However, it does take an army
to migrate all your
applications and everything
over to the new instance,
metadata service.
So yeah, it's tricky,
it's tricky for sure.
- Makes all sense.
And one of the interesting
things that you mentioned was
was kind of the overlap between
matrices, like you said.
I think one of the examples you shared
was cloud was the beginning of the breach,
and it quickly jumped over to Linux.
But thinking about for those
that are kind of more focused
on the native cloud attacks,
I think some of the trends we've seen
is a lot of that has
been either ransomware
or just complete exfiltration,
just attacking data in some way,
either holding hostage or stealing it.
what are your trend
or what do you kinda see on the horizon
in terms of those cloud native attacks?
- Sure, there's a couple
ways I can answer this.
I can be an optimist or an alarmist.
We don't know what we
don't know in the cloud
with regards to how...
Because the threat detection
monitoring really isn't there.
I don't think there's
a ton of organizations
that are doing this.
But once we learn more about attackers
and once that stuff starts
being socialized a little bit,
I'm almost curious to see if
more attackers actually migrate
to attacking things
like the control plane.
What's interesting about
the coin miner attack
is that that attacker
could have monetized
those root access keys
significantly more than
installing a few coin miners.
They had control
of what could have been
a production environment.
But I think that attackers
have risk management as well.
So how much heat do they
wanna bring on themselves?
But again, most of this
stuff is automated.
So there's a preconceived notion
of what the attacker wants to achieve.
- And then a final
question I had for you is,
personally, I've worked
with the cloud team
at ATT&CK and Jen in kind of
helping mature that model,
so we definitely appreciate everything
you guys have contributed
and kind of a work with us
to help build that out.
But one of the things to keep mentioned
is that we're all in this together.
All of this is maturing at the same time.
The trade craft from
adversaries is growing,
as well as our ability to detect
these things, harden them,
and then, like you said, share information
about whatever say is actually doing.
What advice can you give
to the community listening
on how we can work together
to actually like reach that end state
of more secure cloud development
and more secure cloud deployment?
- Yeah, so I think it'll evolve over time.
I think the cloud is
still relatively immature,
especially from a security perspective.
I mentioned how a lot of
cloud security falls on teams
that are outside of traditional security.
So I think as that matures a little more,
we'll get a better grasp of things.
But with that being said,
the information sharing
is really important here.
I think that's how the
security community as a whole
has evolved everything.
Look how mature attack for Linux
and attack for Windows this goes.
Those are contributions from
a bunch of people trying
to work together for a collective goal.
So I think as long as
long as we're continuing
to help each other, we'll get there.
- Yup, we're all in this together,
it's all about the community.
So thanks again for your presentation.
Like you said, definitely hop
over and hop over to Slack,
there's some great
questions building up there.
Definitely wants more insights from you.
But with that, I'm gonna
turn it back over to Adam
to introduce our next speaker.
Thanks again, Anthony.
- Yeah, and thank you both of you again.