- So without further ado,
Brian Donahue from Red Canary.
- First off, like thank you Adam,
thank you to the ATT&CK team
for organizing this conference
and for allowing me to
come and speak at it.
Apologies in advance if my
talk gets interrupted by
any dogs barking or the pitter patter of
toddlers running flat
footed above my head,
but such as the reality of life in 2020.
So without wasting any more time,
my talk is starting over with
sub-techniques and it's about
the lessons that we learned at Red Canary.
When we remapped from like
the old precept techniques
version of Miter ATT&CK to the
new sub techniques version of
ATT&CK.
So, before I go any further,
a few things about myself,
I work at Red Canary.
I primarily either like support
publication of content or
work on it myself, importantly,
in the context of this talk,
I am one of the lead writers
of our threat detection report,
which is like an effort to
gather all of the threats
we detect that our customer's
environments and sort of rank
and stack the Mitre attack
techniques associated with them
for the purposes of sort of
like determining which ATT&CK
techniques are most prevalent
in like creating sort of a,
a ranking order to them.
Prior to joining Red Canary,
I've worked as a journalist
and as a CTI analyst,
about 10 years ago now I was interviewing
for a job
as a social media editor at Threatpost.
It would have been my first
job, It was my first job.
The editors there asked me
how I had any experience with
social media, I lied.
I told them I did.
When in fact I did not,
they either believed me or
didn't care, but they hired me.
And that's how my career started here.
So if you dislike me or my talk,
you can send your hate
mail to Paul Roberts and or
Dennis Fisher.
Now that I've got that out of the way.
So we've already gone through who I am.
I'm gonna give you guys
just an absolute bare minimum background
on what red Canary does,
so that you can sort of
understand the context
around our remapping effort.
Then we'll run through the
seven lessons we learned,
and then we'll close with a minute or two
question and answers.
So like one of the primary
things Red Canary does
is manage, detection and response.
So we gathered telemetry from
our customers and points.
We parsed that telemetry
against like some thousand of
detection analytics to
surface potential threats.
Then those potential threats
are reviewed by a human
on our detection engineering team,
that detection engineer can
either suppress or hide that event,
or they can confirm that it's a threat
in which case they ship what we call
a confirmed threat detection to a customer
for the purposes of this talk,
that's effectively a
customer notification.
It's more than that, but
like for our purposes
just to understand that it includes
among many other things.
The Mitre ATT&CK techniques that
that threat is corresponded with.
So given the way our system operates,
we have a few different
options for how we can handle
ATTA&CK mapping.
We can do it at the behavioral analytic
or the detector level.
The benefit of doing it at that level
is that it's highly scalable.
You get to make your mapping decisions
when you write your detection analytic.
So you make that decision once
and it's automated from there on out.
The problem with that is
that it's bad at nuance.
So you might have a theory
about what your detection
analytic is gonna catch.
And then in practice,
it might catch something
altogether different.
A second option would be to do
this at the detection level.
So if we go back that last slide,
the detection level would be
at this human analysis level.
The benefits of doing it
at the human analysis level
is that it is good at nuance, right.
You've got all of the context.
You need to make a determination
about what you are,
what Mitre ATT&CK technique
is associated with it.
However, it's difficult to scale
because it slows down
your detection pipeline
because you have to make a
decision and choose from 200,
cell mode techniques.
Every time you detect the threat,
the third potential option is
like the why not both option.
And I'm actually gonna get into that
later on in this presentation.
So we actually map at the analytic level.
So we make the determinations
about what our analytics,
what technique they should map
to like when we're developing them.
And the reason we do this is because
primarily Red Canary's
exists to detect threats.
So when we adopted Mitre
ATT&CK a few years ago,
we made the decision to
optimize for threat detection
and speed since like, you often
times we're detecting things
of high priority rather than like being
a 100% accurate in our
mapping all the time.
So what this looks like in practice,
the red text at the top here
is a detection analytic.
It basically is looking for
a process that is an ltest
And to that also includes a
command line with domain trusts.
They're all trust this maps
to domain trust discovery.
And it's basically a
technique that adversary used
to make determinations about domain trusts
within an environment.
This is irrelevant for
the purposes of this talk,
but historically this detector
has helped us catch a whole
lot of trick bot activity.
So, now that you understand sort of this
high level background,
the first lesson that I'd
like to impart on you is like,
if you're going to map things,
or if you're gonna transition
from old Mitre to sub techniques,
like the first thing
you need to figure out
is all of the things that you were mapping
to Mitre ATT&CK in the first place.
So for our purposes,
that would include behavioral
detection analytics,
which I already sort of explained.
It would also include
Atomic Red Team tests.
So Atomic Red Team is an open source
adversary simulation, platform that,
that we manage and maintain
in all of the tests in it
are designed to simulate ATT&CK techniques
and they're map to ATT&CK techniques
for the purposes of this talk.
You can kind of think of these two things,
the behavioral analytics
and the atomic tests
sort of interchangeably,
'cause like the atomic tests are
isolated scripts that map to
ATT&CK and simulated behaviors.
The analytics are
isolated bits of Ruby code
also mapped to attack,
designed to catch techniques.
We also map a lot of our
research and educational content
to Mitre ATT&CK,
but like a lot of it is
derivative of our detection
and we didn't go back and
retroactively map any of it.
So that didn't really
involve any upfront work,
for your purposes you might be mapping
threat intelligence
reporting to Mitre ATT&CK.
You might have like charts
and tables that you're using
to determine things
like detection coverage,
or like any variety of security
controls, alerts, IFCs,
and the like.
So.
Sorry.
Having some issues here.
So, once you,
figure out what you need
to map to ATT&CK, it's time
to do the actual mapping.
Sorry, I'm having a little
bit of trouble controlling
the screen right now.
Alright, there we go.
So first things first, well I
guess it's the second thing.
So let the code do the work for you, okay.
So, luckily a Miter ATT&CK
created a useful little JSON
crosswalk script and effectively
what that'll tell you is
like a tech, it'll tell you
what a technique remaps through.
So maybe a technique
becomes a para-technique
and it'll tell you the
sub-techniques under it.
Maybe a technique becomes a sub-technique
and it'll tell you the
para-technique above it
or possibly the technique
if it's like scripting
has just deprecated.
So we took,
that JSON crosswalk script,
we built a little power shell script
that sort of helped it work specifically
with our environment and
like for atomic Red Team,
we kind of naively thought that the code
would do all the work for us.
We were quickly disabused of that notion
for the behavioral analytics
as I'll get to in a minute,
we sort of knew that we
were gonna have to do
a good deal of manual review there.
So, once you get to the
point where you realized
that you're gonna to have to do
a human review at some level,
you have to make a choice of
whether or not you want to
divide and conquer or do it
as a small team or individual.
So the benefits of doing
it as a team obviously
are that it will get done faster,
although it might get done faster
at the cost of it being less consistent.
The benefit of assigning
it to an individual
or a very small team, is that
it might be more consistent.
And then the cost of that
might be that it takes longer.
So if you have a
reasonable number of things
you need to remap, then by all means,
keep it to a small team or an individual.
However, for our purposes,
we've got thousands of
active detection analytics.
We've got 500 plus from
atomic Red Team tests.
And like, I don't even know how many,
but there's some like
200 plus ATT&CK technique
and sub-technique combos.
So that was just too much
work for any individual to do.
So we assembled a team consisting
of our intelligence team,
our threat research team, our
detection, engineering team.
And most importantly, not me.
So all credit goes to those three teams.
I stood back and watched
and asked a lot of questions
and wrote a blog about it eventually.
So I stole this quote from
my colleague, Katie Nickles,
but ATT&CK mapping is an
art; It's not a science.
So particularly if
you're gonna have a team
that's doing this work,
you should create a style guide,
because people interpret
techniques in different ways
in a style guide.
Like the other thing to remember is that
we're kind of learning
this on the fly, right.
Like these, these sub-techniques are new.
So a style guide will help us
learn like how to map things.
It will keep some guardrails
on how we map and it will help
enforce consistency, equally important
is to assign a review team.
So we assigned a team of
senior detection, engineers,
and intelligence analysts to
review every single mapping
decision that was made by
the broader remapping team.
This also helped to enforce consistency
and it helped us catch
errors that we may have made
in the mapping process.
Lesson five, fix, find them,
fix your legacy mapping issues.
So I'm gonna tell a little story.
So when we were working on
the threat detection report,
like the first thing we do is
we pull the data and we see,
and we make a pivot table and we see like,
what are the top 10 Mitre ATT&CK
techniques from last year?
The initial data poll
revealed that masquerading
was the top technique.
So we then went and we made a sub list
of the detectors that
converted to a threat
that was mapped to
masquerading most often.
And these two detectors showed up.
The first one looks for
untrusted binary, spawning,
suspicious windows service hosts.
The second one identifies SPC host
executing with a
suspicious pair of process.
All told these two detectors on their own
or in conjunction with one another
triggered on more than
4,000 confirmed threats.
However, when my colleague and our
principal intelligence analyst,
Jeff Felling went and reviewed
all the individual detections
associated with those to
a behavioral analytics,
he made a startling discovery.
He discovered that those
two analytics actually
were representative of Process Injection
and not of masquerading.
So we manually remapped them,
we run in the numbers again.
We also manually remapped
a few other analytics,
but they weren't nearly
as dramatic as these ones,
and process injection felt to number one
and then masquerading became number six.
So this is a great lesson.
Like this is the perfect time to review
your behavioral analytics.
Also probably good to be reviewing
them on a continual basis
just to make sure that
nothing changes over time.
Lesson number six,
considering the alternatives.
So I promised you that there
was a third sort of why not
both option for where we
could do our attack mapping
and here's why I'm gonna talk about that.
So again, mapping at the detection level
is the most accurate,
mapping at the analytic
level is the fastest.
However, we're developing an idea called
conditional mapping.
We haven't really operationalized it yet,
but the idea is that we're
gonna try and identify
ambiguous analytics.
Maybe they're just broad.
Maybe there's some sort
of other problem going on,
but the idea is,
like you pick out the ones
that don't always alert
on the thing you hypothesized,
they would alert on,
and then you require a
human review of those.
So you're still able
to keep the main benefit of
mapping at the analytic level,
because most of the mapping
is gonna get done there.
So you still have the speed.
And then you just
identify that small subset
of problematic detectors and you require
a human review of them.
Now the seventh and final lesson is
just to have fun with it guys.
Just kidding, that's not
the seventh lesson at all.
The seventh lesson is actually a lag back.
To give back to the
Mitre ATT&CK community.
So the ATT&CK team is
constantly looking for feedback.
They probably get less
of it than they need.
Whoops,
so,
ways you can give back.
Obviously the most obvious way
to give back is probably to
contribute techniques
back to the Mitre ATT&CK.
But I think also like they
want feedback on what's working
and what's not working.
And by all means you
should reach out to them
and let them know, suggest improvements
and whatever else you can think of.
Finally, like if you learn something
while using a tech that might
be useful to the rest of us,
write a blog about it,
or give a talk about it.
And then while we're
on the topic of blogs,
I know that I only had 14
minutes here and I'm talking
incredibly fast, like a mad man.
So if you wanna take
more time with this talk,
we wrote a blog version, Matt
Graeber and Katie Nickels.
And I wrote a blog version of this talk
maybe a couple of weeks ago.
The link is right there.
I'll try to remember to
tweet it after this talk,
if any of you follow me on Twitter.
And I guess without further ado,
we can sort of jump into the Q and A.
- That was fantastic Brian, thank you.
That was, that was really great.
Like I said, i really appreciate
from coming from the ATT&CK side,
we did so much work to kind of produce
and publish these sub-techniques.
So we are really excited
to see like an organization
as large as Red Canary adopt it
and actually make it their own.
Like you said, I love the
quotes coming off that blog,
the art of this, as well
as all of the nuance.
So definitely I've seen a
lot of traction and kind of
activity going around about your talks.
So definitely stay queued
up for some questions.
One thing I just wanted to ask you was,
you kinda mentioned how
kind of artistic and free
kind of free spirited this mapping is.
And one of the things I was wondering is,
do you think that as advice
to other organizations,
this is an all or not
effort, or can you map, like,
can you map certain portions
to sub techniques and then
maybe stay behind and other areas,
you mentioned how like nuanced
Red Canary is with the,
you know, Atomic Red
team and the detections
as well as looking at the matrix itself.
Like, do you think there's
areas to carve that up,
or do you think it's the,
a binary yes or no kind of question.
- Yeah.
So I think that I'm
interested in talking to other
organizations about this.
'Cause I actually think
that like in a weird way,
Red Canary is like designed
to be mapped to Miter ATT&CK.
And I think that there's a lot
of people that would have a
lot of a harder time with that.
Like specifically if you're
doing like a lot of IOC
in signature based stuff,
I can see how it would be difficult to,
to map things through ATT&CK.
And also if like you're
dealing with a lot of alerts
that maybe are false positives,
that I could also understand
how that could be a problem,
but yeah,
for us like the Atomic Red team stuff
and the detection analytics
really, really teed us up
to have like a relatively easy
job of, of mapping to ATT&CK.
- Yep, tracking.
Thank you and thanks again.
Excellent talk, like I said,
I think the experienced wisdom
that you guys have got
kind of leading the way
and doing that mapping is
really greatly appreciated
and you know, big
benefits of the community.
So thank you.
But with that, I think we're right on time
to turn it over back to Adam for
our introduction of our next speaker.
- Great, thanks so much.
- Yeah, thank you.
Both Jamie and Brian.