[Music]
we have um
this panel is you know
quite special for me i'm privileged to
be here with you um i hope that we will
address regional and international
cooperation
we have distinguished panelists from
different perspectives uh
we will go through
you know a lot of interventions whether
from a perspective of regional
cooperation uh and bilateral cooperation
multilateral corporations we will try to
highlight uh during this panel the
importance of partnership uh the
different mechanisms that already exist
in africa
opportunities and definitely uh i think
we look forward to more participation
based on the outcome of not just of this
panel but the whole event and the
following events
let me start by introducing my dear
friend and colleague
mr adel suleiman from the african union
commission
we have been working together over the
past few years on the agenda for cyber
security in africa
in the framework of the african union
adel you have the floor
you are muted
please a mute yourself
sorry um
thank you very much dr sharif um i'm
really honored to be here with you guys
um uh as sheriff mentioned i think we've
been collaborating uh for the last few
years and i think this is a very good
opportunity
to
foster and strengthen this international
regional cooperation
in cyber space
so
[Music]
my name is adam salehman as mentioned by
dr sharif i am a senior policy officer
within the african indian commission
and the african union commission uh has
its um 2063 agenda and aspirations and
as well as also we are taking also note
of the un agenda
2030 and i think uh we uh concluded that
in order to
realize those uh
aspirations we need to leverage uh uh
digitalization
and i think for us digitalization is a
top priority
in fact
we
in 2020
we adopted a digital transformation
strategy for africa 2020 2030
and i think this is a multi-sectoral
strategy and in fact we are also now
developing sectoral strategy for
agriculture for education and for health
and commerce etc etc so and as well as
also uh if you uh maybe you are aware
that the african union also
is uh also adopting um the continental
free trade area
so i think the stakes are high for the
african union when it comes to digital
and and this is where cyber security
personal data protection becomes a
critical element in this equation
and the african union
because of that
we have cyber security as one of our
flagship project
for the commission
and i think um several actions were
taken by the african union commission to
make sure that
of course we have all this
initiative taken place on digital but we
need to make sure that um you know we
have a safe and trusted environment
and i think for that we are we are
trying our best to
to to make sure that
the trust is there within the community
the african community as well as
within uh in the region and also
globally
so
several initiatives that the african
union commission has taken i think
we
developed
the
cyber security uh convention at the
african union convention on cyber
security and personal data protection
and
it's not yet
entered into force
we have 10 countries who ratified the
convention we are still missing uh five
more countries and i think this is an
opportunity
for uh representatives from the african
countries to work with us in order to
make sure that the convention enter into
force because having a legal uh
framework i think this is one step to uh
for digital cooperation so that we speak
the same language uh uh on the continent
and um they uh also we have been
cooperating with also the uh
council of europe uh and and uh
every two years we organized the cyber
crime forum i think this one the last
one uh was done in june 2021 i think
some of you attended the forum uh and
thank you for all for your participation
and and
and input to the forum
we also working with gfc uh the gfc uh
global
forum for cyber expertise i think we're
working with them uh for some time
and in 2019 in fact we organized the
first african uh the first uh africa
located uh forum
and
i think we was it was a big event
because not only
it was a gfc uh annual meeting but also
there was um ungge representative the
ambassadors uh and also the open-ended
group they were there and there were
some consultations and i think it was
very fruitful discussion i think out of
this uh we were now we are in
implementing with gfc
uh capacity building initiative
for africa
and um also in tandem
just to make sure that
africa has the best advice
there because you know our team is is
not uh big in the african union
commission so what we did we established
the african indian cyber security expert
group
and i'm i'm happy to say that sharif is
one of our
leading
expert in the group
so i think the expert group has been of
great help and
we also when we talk about
digital cooperation
we also they are also active uh in the
un processes and i think this is it
gives us an advantage because sometimes
we're in the african union commission
there may be a conflict uh in terms of
scheduling so we have them attending
this uh and some of them were actually
members of the gde uh and and as well
they've been also constantly uh
attending the um
the uh open-ended uh and
working group and providing providing to
us some advice uh on cyber related
issues and i think we see that
as a very
important step that we have taken in
2019 and i think we've been working and
we continue working i think some of the
fruit of this
effort is that together with the
african union cyber security expert
group we were able to develop a
child online policy for africa it's a
draft but still i think we are going now
to the next phases of the draft we have
we will have some consultation with the
regional stakeholders that eventually
will go out to the member state and will
be adopted
by the
au
organs we also looked at the malibu
convention because we saw that countries
we don't have the enough ratification
so we thought maybe we have to take a
proactive measure to look at the level
of convention and see where it can be
improved uh
in the event that the model convention
is ratified is fully ratified then we
can introduce some of this amendment to
the convention so that it gives more
countries uh comfort to ratify the
convention um
also we are working now on the uh
continental side the security strategy
for africa i think this is a huge
undertaking but i think we are
we are also having task force uh
working group uh on that and we hope uh
by 2022 sometime in 2022 we will be able
to uh
to to have the draft uh uh
the uh strategy uh and and also going
through au process for adoption
um
i i don't want to take a lot of time but
also we have been cooperating with
some regional actors
uh where we uh for instance with the
european union commission
we have this initiative called freedom
policy and regulation initiative for
digital africa
where we are doing um several things
on digital to prepare
you know the groundwork for uh digital
africa and eventually
the uh single market for africa dividend
market for africa
and as i mentioned now cyber becomes
very critical because we are doing all
this initiative and
if we don't have trust within the
continent and we don't have confidence
then
then these initiatives are doomed to
fail so i think this is why cyber
security becomes a critical component i
will stop here and i'll be glad to take
questions thank you very much
thank you adel uh i really appreciate
you sharing with us quite a few points
we'll get back to discuss them
during the intervention after uh we have
we take the the i mean another two
interventions from distinguished
panelists so uh let me introduce my the
second panelist
uh mr serge zongo from the uh
international telecommunication union
the ito has done quite a bit when it
comes to information technology at the
international level of course we all
relate to the ws the world you know uh
high level distinguished event wsis that
actually it was in geneva and then in
tunisia as well um in
2003 2005 and from there on the itu was
the champion organization within the un
system when it comes to cyber security
uh serge it's a pleasure having you with
us uh uh the search is a program manager
at
the itu and and we look forward uh to
your uh comments and intervention and
also thoughts about international and
regional corporations
thank you dr sheriff
good afternoon to all good morning
from where you are connected
um as i said my name is serge valeri
and i'm a program of photographer at itu
and also
managing
all itu sub security activities in the
continent
and it's a very good place for us to uh
be part of this gathering that for us is
very important to um
um enhance the cooperation and also find
some synergies for all the stakeholders
of the ecosystem in the continent to
make sure that we are um
let's say acting on the
an efficient way
um
as you know the cyber security portfolio
program in itu is very broad
uh but today i will just um focus on
what we are doing really on the sub uh
on the search area
uh and uh
we we still
uh we're still updating our approach to
assist the countries
uh because i think that we can agree
that we are facing challenges in the
continent
uh we have lack of uh
local expertise
and relational structure in cyber
security
we have a lack of skills to respond and
manage
subsequent incidents
we are
challenging when we are challenged when
we need to
really
have deep and uh impactful development
even if we have some
funds available
and lastly we have lack of trust and
confidence in ic2 and ict adoptions
and to address these challenges uh we
are trying to um
keep
adjusting our search program
to really stock take the current
incident responsibilities in the
continent to establish
organizational structures
to improve its development in essence
response to continent
and
also
enhance the different submission and
also the stakeholders engagement
going through awareness creation and
promoting um really the cooperation
and to do so we we we our we we in
actually we developed kind of one called
active framework that's really based on
the services framework that first is
promoting and also
adjusting on the needs of our member
states
and this framework started by the third
assessment
where we're really
assessing the realness of in of the
country to establish national assert but
also more importantly preparing the
relevant
relevant stakeholders and needed
involvement for them to get a success of
self-implemented
and from from this assessment where
we're developing the
design
document agree design document and from
there we are going to establishment and
enhancement phase of the of the of the
cell
and really why we are
developing this framework is really to
explain
how what our approaches our approaches
prevent serves
um we started limiting search continents
i think
and uh we realized that we need really
to um
keep adjusting the approach to make more
sustainable research
and uh so this framework is really to um
fix this issue and also
um to present clearly the structure on
how the product is faced
and also to clarify the score and
responsibilities and efforts
to make sure that the software
implementing is uh able to
act as
a first and central pollution point in
the country of attenuation or
in the country national or regional
level
and to identify be able to identify and
different response
to and manage this project
so as i was saying
um we so far
did about 36 assessments of countries in
the country in the continent
and
we tabulated about 11 certs
and we
are
now financing
uh let's say we just analyzed gambia and
we are implementing burundi and malawi
and
we are assisting kenya constantly
enhanced the
buildings insert at communication
authority
um
the new approach that we have also in
research is really to talk to the
stakeholders in the continent that to
see where we can find some tillages and
put together the resources so we can
build some more
i say powerful impactful cert on the
continent on the countries and for
instance for burundi we have some
education for some
some countries
uh for instance uh chad
and uh
and now it's watini we have connection
with some other partners where we
discuss
we are um looking for the
the way to find some scenarios where we
can complete each other to make for more
impactful cells
i will
uh conclude by talking about disabled
drills that we are
running um since 2014
um we um
conducted more than 30 exercises and for
more than 100 countries
and in africa we have we
had disabilities in zambia rwanda
mauritius
tanzania kadiwa and uganda
and what we are really promoting during
these habitats is the collaboration
the um
partnership between the sun and the
country so they can create a kind of
channel of discussion and plenty sharing
to make sure that the soil that we are
in the continent are really talking to
each other are sharing expertise to be
more efficient when it comes to dealing
with separate incidents in the in the
continent
and we um this
because of the quebec we had um
this to last year global sovereignty
um but next year we're really looking
forward to have regional secretary for
africa we're still looking for the cross
country but it's something we plan uh
very soon
and for 2021 we
we had a regional ceremony for western
africa it was
and next week we having the national
service wheel for
and i think the second slice player is
the one who's invited the participant
and it's good that uh you also attend to
see what's happening on on this server
rates
so uh to conclude i will just call upon
um really more coordination and
synergies
for a better use of
available resources in the continent
because we have so much we need to just
need to make sure we are using them in a
better way our
on innovation ways of funding served for
better sustainability i think that uh we
got uh when we were doing the secretary
for it was a good example of togo i saw
that the qualification is there um i
think it will be sharing with us this
really
brilliant
and good initiative
um i also um call for more collaboration
and close sharing between search in
africa is something we need to improve
really to make sure that we have this
pronunciation platform like really
running smoothly
and lastly to create and improve
a strong cyber security
industry in the continent
this will conclude my remarks for this
moment thank you
um thank you very much serge for sharing
with us uh you know quite a broad
spectrum of activities within the itu uh
if you allow me also i'll get back to
some of the other activities in addition
of course to addressing your points
you highlighted the the i mean the
importance of networking cooperation how
the iq is taking a central role when it
comes to cyber drills
and
how to build you know this type of
continuous effort of sustaining certs
and and
leading the you know the models for cert
and the frameworks and at the same time
implementing it on the ground making
sure that they are built to be sustained
or and how to network you know partners
uh within africa and this is key to the
discussion that will come later on um
i'd like to pass the floor now to my
dear colleague and friend engineer
bedrock
he has been a really instrumental at all
levels at the i mean the
regional uh the arab regional uh uh
level uh he is leading in his home
country uh oman um oman has a very high
rank when it comes to cyber security
readiness in the global index um i mean
drafted and you know revisited every
couple of years by the itu uh he is also
leading in the gulf area uh between the
search and the gulf area in the arab
region oman is hosting the arab regional
uh cyber security center and they have a
distinguished you know
event and more recently uh he has also
assumed uh the chairmanship of the oic
the organization of islamic countries
cert
and and that's an organization that has
you know uh quite a few very active
players across a broad region
of islamic countries so i'd like to i
really look forward to uh engineering
uh you know uh sharing with us uh all at
all levels whether at the level of you
know the oic the arab region the gulf
area as well as in oman
the type of lessons and experiences that
they have came across uh especially when
it was it involves regional and
international partnerships and how it
impacts you know cyber security
readiness and incident response engineer
bad the floor is yours
thank you very much dr sharif i hope you
can hear me well
yes we can please go ahead excellent so
thank you very much again thank you to
first africa than to serve as a
representative a member of who i see
search for having me today with you uh
i'm gonna
actually address the regional and
international cyber security initiatives
as dr sharif
mentioned
probably we were fortunate to wear
multiple hats when it comes to cyber
security initiatives on a gcc level oic
third level as well as uh
through the itu arab regional cyber
security center that we host in oman and
we extend the services and the support
to the rest of itu member countries and
cyber security so in such a short time
that is allocated for this session just
address few high-level initiatives
outlining
what is happening in the region and this
is on the aspect of cyber security
strategies capacity building incident
and threat management as well as cyber
security innovation
as well as the role of women in cyber
security where we are also having a
number of initiatives supporting that
so on an ic level three important
initiatives that we have introduced as
dr sharif mentioned that oic is quite
actually a large organization it is
considered to be the second largest
organization after united nations with
57 member countries and we were glad to
have active members and board members
like egypt where dr sheriff come from so
one of those
global initiatives we introduced within
the yc cert is the global sea
certification program which is actually
a holistic framework of cyber security
professional certification that outlines
the overall approach independent
assessment impartially of examination
competences of trainers identification
and classification of cyber security
domains and the requirement of
professional memberships
the recent
global initiatives that we also
introduced was the global cyber security
award which is basically one of our icc
initiatives to encourage international
collaboration in the domain of cyber
security the award recognizes innovative
cyber security projects from around the
world
not been bounded by country or region
that contributes to uplifting
the cyber security globally the theme
for this year was cyber security
innovation towards society prosperity
and well-being
and we have announced actually the
winners of this award which is uh
it includes also a financial award to
incentivize
more members actually to contribute to
this program and the winners were
announced during the recent icy third
annual conference
the oic annual cyber drill is an
opportunity for not only the search
within the oic cert member countries but
also it's been extended to other
regional platforms uh that we
collaborate with including first
africa service the episode and others
basically to have teams participating
and this is
again in line with the cyber drills that
are actually developed and implemented
by itu for different regions
on the gcc third level which is the six
countries as you are aware
we have actually
established a cyber security strategy
with a detailed business plan that is
updated every two years but two main
projects and initiatives on the gcc
level one was the gcc malware
information sharing platform and the
threat intelligence sharing platform
that has been made available to all gcc
countries to actually share
information on related threats malware
incidents that they are experiencing
allowing other countries to be more
proactive towards addressing such
threats before they become a target of
it
on the regional level and through the
itu regional cyber security center
actually we annually conduct a regional
cyber security week that has multiple
events including uh
conference as well as a regional cyber
drill
but annually also we run a regional uh
capture the flag competition this has
not only been made available to national
search but also targeting youth in the
arab region where we believe
youth
actually
considers to be uh
the largest probably part of the
population in the arab region and we
have been witnessing a good number of
innovative projects coming from the
region as well as good talents when it
comes to
threats hunting and
identifying vulnerabilities within
running applications and systems and i
mentioned in my earlier introduction
that we do also support and in original
initiatives that it's called women in
cyber security middle east which
actually addresses
the needs
in this domain to bring more female
we have probably quite a lack in that in
the region and we thought of
having a dedicated initiatives to ensure
that capacity building are also built
within the female community and we were
fortunate actually to have a number of
cyber security leaders now in the
gcc level that are women
considering my deputy
also the regional center and this is we
appreciate the trust giving by itu roman
has been selected to host the first
itu regional cyber security center that
is extending its
support and services to the 193 member
countries of the itu
after it started only with the arab
region and we have been actually running
around
170 plus projects and initiatives within
the region that varies between
developing cyber security strategies
for cyber security but there are
dedicated cyber security strategies for
online for child online protection which
we did in bahrain we have participated
also with itu in a number of regional
cyber security development workshop for
the asia region for the arab region as
well as for east europe region
technical assessment has been provided
to a number of countries as well as
actually the incident management we have
recently concluded the
establishment of palestine cert where we
have actually supported the country of
palestine to establish their national
search and we are working with other
countries also in the region to ensure
that
national cert at least are established
when it comes to capacity building we
all believe that humans as well
as they are actually the weakest link
but there are also the one we count on
when it comes to cyber security so we
have actually run a good number of
cyber security trainings and workshops
around 86 plus
additionally we work certainly with the
regional and other international
organizations like ferris where we were
actually privileged to have an mou
signed with first a few years back and
based on that we had to run a joint
symposium and workshop we started in
egypt in 2016 thanks to dr sharifah at
that time he was leading the egypt sir
one of the successful event tweeted with
first followed by another symposium
in
darsalam as well as in tunisia and
basically today's also even
in cooperation with tunisia that is also
a member of the oic so we believe that
uh
having such regional initiatives will
maximize the value approach uh to the
cyber security community
and it is an opportunity to share
knowledge experiences and actually to
enable
more uh collaboration across countries
and overcome uh the reinvent the wheel
concept and i would support surgeons
concluding the remark that we do really
encourage more of this collaboration and
we look forward to such joint events
that will enable every participant to
understand what is going on in every
region and then we decide how we can
make the best out of it to benefit the
entire community to make the world a
safe cyberspace with that i would
conclude my remark thank you very much
for this opportunity
thank you uh engineer battery it has
been really a pleasure cooperating with
with you in different capacities but i'm
really
especially happy for you your presence
with us today i think you shared with us
quite a few modalities whether at the
level of the oic the organization of
islamic countries
and that's one dimension the other
dimension uh i mean sub-regional
activities like the ones that you shared
about the gulf cooperation
countries uh gcc assert and having you
know
some synergy when it comes to creating a
strategy and pushing the strategy
forward and finally with the the center
of excellence that you host in oman the
arab regional center of excellence of
the itu supported by the itu
and that you extended that and i'm
really impressed to see 170 plus
projects that's a lot of activities and
it really reflects back on you know uh
how the leadership or at all levels can
have a significant impact in the
developments um again it's it's one one
of the attributes that we're looking for
during our panel discussion today we'll
get back to you know some of the details
thanks for being with us um let us
move quickly to uh our you know uh
final you know
panelists uh uh within the first section
of this panel uh we decided to split the
panel first four speakers then we take
some questions from the floor uh and
then we move uh with the rest of the
panelists thank you all for being
patient with us and i think now i'd like
to introduce um
vish from the u.s state department um i
look forward to your talk uh
especially when the when it comes to the
u.s state department's involvement in
africa being a partner country um
throughout and also i would like to hear
from you on a different topic if you
have time uh to address the uh the
efforts that the us is leading with
other you know
countries across the globe within the un
uh system the un uh
open-ended working group and uh
i mean group of governmental experts and
this has been an effort ongoing for
several years we are fortunate to have a
few countries being members of the uh
ungge and being active on the uh your a
un open-ended working group from the
africa and the arab region uh so
the floor is yours
please go ahead
great thank you so much um it is a real
pleasure to be with you today um i think
following the excellent presentations
that have already happened i'm gonna be
brief and then as people have questions
i'm happy to address them um but i think
we've heard really great work that's
ongoing on the continent and in the
region um and
was wonderful to be i'm honored to be on
the panel
um yeah absolutely so i'll i'll just
start briefly by talking a little bit
about the us's commitment so first of
all the us is committed to strengthening
global cyber capacity build capacity to
protect and promote an open
interoperable and secure and reliable
internet open interoperable reliable and
secure those are the ways the words that
we use to describe the internet that
we're seeking
as vice president harris said in paris
in november the united states is
committed to working to advance security
in cyberspace to promote stability in
cyberspace and to ensure
ensure shared prosperity
so this includes our continued
partnerships with governments private
sector civil society and the technical
community around the world to advance
cyber security partners capacity on a
range of cyber issues
for more than a decade the department of
state has leveraged diplomatic
engagement and foreign assistance to
help our partner nations develop strong
cyber capacity
since 2012 actually we've been directly
involved um in capacity building in the
middle east and africa our very first
whole of government training for
partners was in accra ghana in
collaboration with ekowas and uh we
haven't stopped running since our
capacity building work covers five major
themes
first we assist governments to develop
and implement national cyber strategies
and effective whole of government
approaches to policies relating to cyber
space so national strategies second we
work to strengthen national incident
management capabilities and protect
critical infrastructure so that's
primarily been our work with c certs
that we've sponsored with sei
third we work to combat cyber crime
through the promoting the budapest
convention and providing practical legal
training and i'm not the one who usually
does that that's my colleagues who have
experience in law enforcement issues
fourth we work to promote
private public sector collaboration
including on things like cyber security
standards and finally we work to build a
culture of cyber security through
awareness and workforce development um
and in africa and the middle east we've
primarily worked on the first three of
those topics um we've worked with uh
sponsored a group called the mitre
corporation to help a few governments
and um
groups in regional organizations and
this is what um adil was talking about
um in 2018 for example we joined an
event that the african union convened
and we brought some experts to talk
about drafting national cyber strategies
um and then we've done a fair amount
with the software engineering institute
and the good news is that you're gonna
hear from justin directly i think later
on in the program about the work that
they're doing um
and uh you know we've been we've also
convened some regional training focused
on risk-based based approaches to cyber
security so think about your cyber
security not from a technical
perspective but from a
whole holistic perspective and you're
going to hear a little bit about those
approaches i think later on
um and we've also so in addition to our
capacity building we've engaged partners
in the middle east and africa on issues
of international security in cyberspace
including raising awareness of the
framework of responsible state behavior
in cyberspace and this is uh what dr
sharif was talking about
there have been a round of negotiations
at the united nations that he
participated in at one point um there
have been i think five or six group of
governmental experts uh where select
governments from across the world
self-nominated governments from across
the world sent an expert to negotiate at
the united nations about
work that we could do together to reduce
the risk of conflict in cyberspace
in addition to that um beginning in 2019
there uh was an
open-ended working group also convened
by the united nations also under the
work that they do focused on disarmament
and peace
and that open-ended working group was
open to all
and uh in this spring both uh the
current gge
and uh that open-ended working group is
open to all the open-ended working group
is open to all un member states so if
you if all governments that are members
of the un were invited and encouraged to
participate in those negotiations
whereas the gge is is select select
governments to nominate an expert and so
there are kind of complementary tracks
you might think um both of those had a
negotiation round that concluded in this
spring and they affirmed three things
as well as what i think of as an
underlying underlying support
the they affirmed a framework of
responsible state behavior in cyberspace
that includes an affirmation that
international law that exists already uh
things like the un charter apply to
the activities that governments do in
cyberspace
secondly they affirmed a list of norms
of responsible state behavior that good
governments operating in good faith
should do these things or should not do
these things in peace time these are
voluntary but they sort of outline um
the rules of the road uh the things that
are uh good behavior or are not good
behavior um and then the third piece of
the framework that has been offered
multiple times including this last
spring is uh the value of practical
confidence building measures so um
things as basic as exchanging points of
contact so that if there's an incident
of concern uh governments can reach out
to one another and know who to reach out
to um and i bring this up uh in part
because um in part because uh
there's a specific norm of responsible
state behavior in cyberspace that
relates to the work of c-certs and i'm
gonna read it it's in diplo speak so
then i'll kind of explain it a little
bit um but the the norm it was first
outlined in 2015 and it has subsequently
been reaffirmed both at the open-ended
working group so all u.n member states
and also at the most recent u.n group of
governmental experts and the norm says
states should not knowingly or could not
should not conduct or knowingly support
activities to harm the information
systems of the authorized emergency
response teams sometimes known as
computer emergency response teams or
cyber security incident response teams
of another state
a state should not use an authorized
emergency response team to engage in
malicious international activity
so this is what we call a normal
restraint uh
this is a norm where governments that
have signed up to it have said we're not
gonna use our certs to
do bad things to cause trouble to uh you
know conduct malicious activity we are
gonna
recognize
that
caesars have a special role to play um
this norm is a recognition that the
united states and the broader
international community have identified
the role of sea certs as essential and
deserving of protection in fact many
states categorize sea surge as part of
their critical infrastructure
and the norm recognizes the importance
of protecting sea certs when they are
providing incident response and network
defense services to the public
and and i'd also note that if sea certs
do engage in malicious international
activity they wouldn't be eligible for
protection under the norm right it's a
it's a norm of mutual commitment
um i realize i'm probably running out of
time so i uh will
you know i will just say that our
capacity building efforts
internationally and in the region um are
generally in line with supporting this
framework um they're always in line with
supporting this framework um and
sometimes they're directly about you
know engaging people's awareness of the
framework and um sometimes they're about
diving into specific pieces of the
framework um or just supporting
cybersecurity capacity in part so that
governments can commit to and and follow
the framework
um
[Music]
i want to be respectful of people's time
i'll just say that we do have some
capacity building programs for c cert
that we're sponsoring the software
engineering institute to do
in the region um particularly primarily
in africa
and i'm also going to put in the chat a
little bit a couple
places that i would encourage all
c-certs to
look to for information particularly the
u.s department of homeland security
offers uh
subscription feeds for threat
information and i would encourage folks
to sign up for that and um also we have
the homeowner's security information
network which is a nomination you must
apply to be part of but it can be a
great way for your team to get
information about threats that are
timely
and have them sort of automatically
deliver to you so with that i'll hand it
back to the chair and i look forward to
questions
thank you very much elizabeth you shared
with us
you know
a lot of activities across different
levels whether at the international
level
i'm really glad that you highlighted i
was counting on you to highlight you
know the links between the norms of
responsible state behavior and the
confidence building measures that are
developed have been developed over the
past uh you know over 10 12 years at the
un level they are adopted by the general
assembly of the united nations so that's
the broadest group of adult a group of
adoption really and it provides an
umbrella and reflecting back to uh our
colleagues working here and you know at
different serves instant handlers
there is a you know a special place for
you to make them happen uh talking about
norms it happens uh
and the confidence building measures it
happened at a high level where mostly i
mean they are led by diplomats uh you
know government officials international
lawyers uh experts you know uh
you know working with the un at all
levels however uh they have already
opened up you know with the open-ended
working group to organizations and first
where was invited to be part of the
organizations addressing the open-ended
working group and communicating with the
ungge group of governmental experts in
fact uh i i know that when i represented
you know egypt uh
the ungge in 2012 2013 i was the only
representative from uh africa and the
middle east and i lobbied to expand this
and thanks to the us and other partners
the uk
and most of the group you know endorsed
you know expanding that group and even
opening up uh you know the process to
include professional organizations like
first
and we were part of this and currently
we have a member of the organizing
committee who is a current um ge member
and we have been invited to the
open-ended working group as well so uh
it's it's really a pleasure to address
this because there is something at few
points actually that are quite relevant
not just one norm all the cdns about
about you know building confidence ahead
of time you know you don't build
confidence during a crisis time you
build confidence ahead of a crisis
hopefully no crisis is i mean
we don't face a major crisis that would
require you know international
interventions but you know day-to-day
challenges that we face
you mentioned in your talk uh you know a
little bit about you know the feeds that
are provided
uh you know to countries and feeds about
possible threats you know attack vectors
that are spreading
so quite a few points that we'll get
back to i'd like to open the floor for
to take some questions and i have some
questions of my own uh to address uh i
mean
to my colleagues
at different levels uh um maybe i i'll
start with general questions but let's
pose if and see if we have questions
from the floor first
unfortunately my french is non-existence
almost so please if you have questions
for for us i really appreciate if they
are in english
so with this said
let me start by
you know having
some few points maybe addressed we were
discussing now let's uh you know uh move
along the same lines of the
international collaboration uh with the
process of the ungge the open-ended
working group the african union also
has opened channels different you know
scenarios for uh you know uh discussing
norms uh confidence building measures uh
and also trying to have some synergy
between african countries when it comes
to adopting you know the the legal uh
framework the regulatory framework uh
can you highlight you know the
importance of you know this type of
synergy and coordination that happens
within the african union activities
so that i mean in africa we are aware of
what's happening elsewhere at the same
time we can reflect back on our
individual countries and regional
activities
uh thank you very much dr sheriff as you
mentioned there are so many things to go
on cyber
and i think
getting the priority right i think one
of these one of the challenges
um
so um
i think in just in general before i get
to these questions
so i think in general for the
african-american commission the
priorities are
to
help the countries i think we've been
doing some work with the u.s
strategies and i think we want to do
that also at the regional level and at
the continental level and also of course
we not we want to raise awareness
develop capacity and make sure that we
have a legal framework
um
i think
just i want to draw your attention that
i think we had
with the help of the u.s government we
had um a regional consultation in the
ecowas region recently
where
we tried to uh walk through the norms
and see
what is it that uh
african countries would
kind of
take like priorities uh when it comes to
the african norms so because i think
this this i think we have to be careful
here because
uh you know we don't want to dictate to
the countries what to do but i think we
leave it up to the countries to decide
what is what is it that
they think it would be
um an important element so so we are
doing this
[Music]
we had the gge and open-ended working
group and and
they spoke at links on about the norms
and
confidence building budget
i think we are trying to work with also
with the open-ended work group the gge
to have regional consultations
[Music]
consultation so that uh you know first
of all uh you know the policy makers are
kind of uh they are up to speed with all
these norms and why they're important
because i think we need to sell that i
think we don't have yet the political
will
uh across the board maybe it's here and
there but it's not across the board so
we need to make sure that we have this
awareness raising and consultations with
the african countries we are we
unfortunately we did one but uh we
didn't follow up with the uh
gge and open-ended working group uh and
we are looking forward i think we are
doing also some work with the gfc but
it's just a one-offs uh and we need to
make sure that we do
this thing consistently so that the
country understand this is the priority
this is something important uh because
you know trust and and and confidence in
ict is very paramount
for us to make sure that we
are implementing our
priority when it comes to the digital
space thank you
thank you adele for sharing
i think this is really quite useful for
all of us to to keep in mind it's quite
a challenging task and really having
partnership makes it uh quite a bit
easier uh i'd like to move to engineer
better and and really our experience in
in egypt and in the region african
region every arab region has been you
know the importance of building
partnership and trust uh starts at the
all levels you have you know annual
events you have cyber drills
cyber drills are very special to me um
in egypt we started off by uh you know
participating in the itu cyber drills
the
uh you know whether it's the arab region
of the african region we also
participated in the oic cyber drills and
asia pacific egypt is not asia pacific
but we got the partnership to work for
us
this helps the teams to work together to
gain trust at the operational level what
is your experience with
trying to build trust among you know
incident handlers
ahead of time ahead of the need of you
know
requiring coordination in time of a
crisis
yes uh dr sharif
i think being doing that for several
years now and as
you mentioned at different levels uh
within the oic the gcc the arab
countries as well as we do actually
national cyber drills also for the
government and the critical
infrastructure
we have actually realized that in
addition to building the competences
for teams to be much ready and prepared
to address cyber incident it has enabled
also the team to have
a one-to-one communication and a
one-to-many communication with the other
representative of national search in the
region that has enabled them to really
have that convenient to to pick up the
phone and talk to any colleague from a
member country either to seek a help or
support to address a specific incident
or to share an experience that they have
faced during an incidence that they have
addressed at their domestic level so i
have seen really quite significant
improvement in the readiness
of the countries in the region to
address cybersecurity threats and
challenges but it has also brought to
our
intention
that we should not only limit actually
such
value to be only to the national search
but we have also started engaging
specific critical national
infrastructure
sectors to the annual drills that we are
participating allowing them not only to
participate actually in the drills but
to share with us their experiences where
we have find they were quite good number
actually of talents and competences
within the critical national
infrastructure that they were
willing also to share their specific and
special type of incidents that probably
they have not been seen in other sectors
with the rest of the other countries
participating in the other regions so i
would say continuing with this will not
only enable us actually to be in a
better position to address cyber threats
but it enables us also to become
more proactive on uh
assuring the trust in sharing
information
it gives the convenience and the comfort
for
all countries in the region to believe
that information sharing is really
powerful
we have seen a quiet challenges
using actually the word of
confidentiality and sensitivity of
information not to be shared with the
other regions but through this drills i
think everybody has witnessed that
information sharing is actually helping
individual countries not only other
countries that they are sharing their
information with
so this is my
kind of
findings over uh the drills that we have
done and it also encourages us actually
to keep doing it in a way where it
becomes also more innovative and
predictive to address emerging threats
with the fourth industrial
revolution and the application
application associated with it i think
now we are going to address more
different challenges than we used to do
and we have also to consider that in our
future cyber trends thank you
thank you very much and i really uh
support your idea especially during the
covet time we have witnessed the global
you know
transformation rapid transformation if i
may say towards digital digitalization
whether it's in one sector or across
different sectors in africa especially
uh african countries relied on the ict
in ways that
were really uh only tapped upon no
before the the pandemic but now it's
everywhere in finance in education
culture exchange uh healthcare of course
uh industrial
i mean and work environment so there are
lots of applications now then many
sectors and i really appreciate also
sharing that you are now including the
sectoral uh certs and instant handlers
in such activities i'd like to move to a
question that we got uh to the itu about
the uh i mean again along the lines of
building capacity human capacity and you
know uh search address you addressed
before uh you know the the lack of uh
talents within africa and this is really
important for us to build and i think
many of the panelists also would share
the same idea would you like to add
something along these lines sir
thank you
to clarify beaten let's see
the number one let's look in the figures
we are about seven thousand certified
professional in africa
with a population of about 140 billion
does this mean that we really
need to um
let's say
improve and increase our position to be
able to uh
let's say
build this task force
to defend and to
manage essence uh in the continent
um united we we really um thinking that
uh
this
capacity building
development
policies or strategies should only be
embedded on the national specific
strategies and you will see that for
instance we just launched the
the second edition of the cyber security
studies guide
that we developed with many
stakeholders where we
we are trying to promote with using this
national
strategies
it
it it
really
plays or let's say the top priority of
the
of the area to be addressed the capacity
development in the countries where we
make sure that we can we can allocate no
not the
the
let's say the proper resources
are in the country or regional level to
make sure
that uh this
is something we can um
achieve
and also monitor to make sure that we
have we have built this capacity on the
needed area on the
region
so for us um
the campus development should not be
part of the these strategies we are
building our countries and make sure
that
we are monitoring them
accordingly and make sure that the
resources that we are putting in place
is really trying to build interested
money in the
efficient manner
so this is what i was going to uh give
us a
idea and i want to also um
come on what
uh
but i just said
uh if this is something really realizing
that the subway drills is also a way on
building this kind of um let's say
knowledge sharing and also
the capacity of the countries that only
that don't have really
some operational assert to be able to be
uh
easily going to other people
to look for expertise to deal with some
instant help in the countries and this
is something we really realize this is
something that's improving the continent
where we have one-to-one also let's say
more
group communication to be able to uh
address some incidents or challenges
that we have
thank you
thank you very much serge for sharing
with us and uh i i strongly agree with
you uh it's very critical i think all
this panels so far has uh have addressed
you know capacity building i'd like to
end with a quick question to a little
bit about you know you mentioned about
the us involvement in capacity building
in africa and across the globe actually
um how important you think this is going
to be on on your agenda when it comes to
you know uh you know coming from egypt i
always think about capacity building in
terms of a pyramid so you have you know
the broad uh base of the pyramid where
you have you know broad knowledge of
cyber security across different you know
professionals but when it approached to
decision makers uh at the top of the
pyramid the the you know the high level
uh training of cyber i mean cyber
security professionals incident handlers
um what type of engagement do you
anticipate especially when it comes to
operational uh you know incident
handling
this is you know not something that you
get from attending a class or a session
but it has to to do with you know uh
engagement with uh teams providing the
services
thanks uh yeah that's a that's a
definitely a challenge i would say that
our i kind of think of this in in two in
two levels we are we are doing a range
of capacity building that i think
hopefully addresses everything from uh
you know technical training to new c
search staff which we are funding the
software engineering institute to do all
the way up to um we have had a range of
conversations that are focused on
national cyber security strategies and
those um those are those are those are
top level conversations right in an
ideal scenario a national cyber security
strategy is drafted at the mid to senior
level and then you know approved by
cabinet um
i i would also say that i think a couple
of people have raised a question of
political will um and political will is
something that we
we struggle with in the united states um
we struggle with it uh at
the political level our senior political
leaders we also struggle um with uh the
private sector having the awareness of
the need to make cyber security a
priority and um there's a you know the
discussion of is it a chief technical
officer or a chief technology officer
question or is it a
chief um
chief operational question or is it the
ceo right should it be the head of the
company paying attention to cyber
security and obviously i um i and others
at sizza um really think that it should
be a ceo question not just a technology
officer question um and so we're we're
doing a lot and this is this is more
domestically but my colleagues are doing
a lot to
raise the profile of cyber security and
i think frankly we've gotten a lot more
attention as we've had some very
prominent cyber security incidents that
have had
daily
effects on people's daily lives such as
the shutdown besides the ransomware
attack that led the private company
colonial pipeline to shut down their
pipeline transmitting uh petroleum fuel
uh to a good chunk of the east coast so
i'm sure if you may have been impacted
by that personally um
i live a little bit north so i didn't
have to put gasoline in in plastic bags
which no one should ever do but people
did it because they were worried about
getting access to gasoline um again
please don't ever put gasoline in in
plastic bags that's a very bad idea um
but uh it does it does illustrate how
you know the one way to get political
will is to have a really bad incident
and our our hope is that the technical
assistance we can provide can help raise
the awareness of cyber security so that
you can learn from our mistakes um and
and get that senior level political will
and get those private companies to
understand the need to to put this high
on the agenda um just in terms of what
our our work has done we've you know
we've done a range of things um i think
one thing that i would draw your
attention to is in 2019 before travel
stopped we convened a small group of um
some t-shirts on the continent along
with the african union commission
to talk about uh exchange between sea
certs on the continent an exchange of
information so that if a hack works in
one country
you know incident handlers in in that
country can share with their their
neighbors and and appropriate steps can
you know be taken so that uh
government networks can defend
themselves going back to the point about
confidence building measures i think
those kinds of things are opportunities
to build relationships that can then be
relevant um in in
when there is an incident but i would
also say that i think formal confidence
building measures at the regional level
or between individual governments or
within regional economic communities
can be a really beneficial way to
not simply rely on those individual
relationships built at conferences like
this one but also to
um help raise political will and raise
awareness of the need for this so you
know a formal confidence building
measure negotiated one gun one country
to the other can be an opportunity for
uh the c for a technical community or a
national ministry of communications for
example to get um buy-in from the
president or from the minister to
explain you know this is why we're
building this formal confidence building
measure and we think out of this we will
be able to address incidents as they
occur or if they were to occur so wrap
it all back up
thank you very much
for sharing i mean such really
very important comments also you shared
it in a quite a diplomatic way so we
really appreciate that with this i'd
like to thank uh all the panelists so
far that spoke and then we move to the
next uh you know part of our panel i'd
like to uh recognize that two of our
panelists they were basically uh engaged
in other activities and they they took
time to join us so if they want to leave
please feel free to do that
thank you very much for your
contribution and then we move to the
next
panelist
let me start with
nick small from cyber4dev
nick the floor is yours
great thank you and uh good day
everybody um let me start just uh by uh
thanking our hosts for this event which
i can see by the participant list is
very well attended which
is very encouraging and a quick shout
out to uh
the first team who have uh organized the
logistics of this so very well for us uh
um this is uh i i've i've been lucky
enough to be on a another first event
before and i i i really appreciate
uh the planning that goes into these
um i'd like to just spend a cup a few
minutes uh first of all introducing uh
cyber for cyber resilience for
development which is an eu project uh
for which i am a regional coordinator
focused on africa
um and speak a little bit about what we
do and then um i'd also like to come
back to a few of the comments um that
have been made by
some of the earlier panelists which i
thought were very uh insightful and very
relevant um i'm going to uh make take
that faithful step of trying to share my
screen
um and uh let me do that very quickly
um so just as introduction um cyber
resilience for development is an
eu-funded project
that has been in operation for several
years now
with the goal of engaging with
um organizations countries regional
entities
um around building cyber resilience and
building cyber resilience for
development
uh and i stress the word development and
i go back to elizabeth's comments um
just a little bit there earlier she used
the point of uh
shed prosperity the shed prosperity that
we can all gain uh from the benefits
that
cyberspace can provide us
and
our agenda and our our mission
is to
pres
promote the resilience that's needed
so that people um across the world can
benefit from um from what cyber uh has
to offer
and um you know we we feel it's very
important that we don't lose sight of
that in the sense that
i i think many of us spend our days
worrying and addressing and uh watching
threats and risks that are emerging but
we also have to recognize that uh
with um with the reach of cyberspace
today the benefits that it delivers are
not not a nice to have they are a
must-have
and they they really do act um to be
able to promote that development and
that shared perspective prosperity
across the globe
um
very quickly our project as i say eu
funded we have three primary
implementation partners
um which are the republic of estonia and
the information systems authority
um the british foreign commonwealth and
development office and the ministry of
foreign affairs from the netherlands and
together these influen implementation
partners
support our efforts but um we very much
rely upon
expertise from across europe to be able
to
deliver our various initiatives and
interventions
wherever we can find the right expertise
and the right capabilities
to support our efforts
i'm briefly looking at what is it we do
and
how do we seek to engage
um
we we work with partner countries really
in three primary areas
the first of which is the obvious um
one around incident response and um
cyber security and
response
capabilities uh building up those um
both for
um
environments where there may not be a
assert or a sea cert in place today but
also very much working with
those sea certs that are underway but
are um seeking to further mature their
capabilities uh further grow
both their capacity but also
their integration into the international
cyber security community
a secondary focus is lies in the one
that again elizabeth described above in
the sense of the national strategies
and um here
we we don't seek to
in any way you know dictate or advise
strongly what a national strategy
uh must contain but rather
um look more at the practical side of
implementing a strategy
um
we all know that um
it takes an awful lot of effort it takes
an awful lot of collaboration
and cooperation to see a strategy and
the national cyber security strategy
adopted and reached that important phase
of
cabinet approval
but often um
we we then worry about what next how do
we get this strategy implemented how do
we actually um
deliver on that strategy and reach the
goals that uh
that the strategy sets out so we seek to
uh engage with partners very much on the
practical aspects of implementing
strategies
i i i i'll step back slightly and say
well while not um uh you know by by not
necessarily
suggesting um
major content of the national strategies
one thing i think we do recommend is to
try and try and keep it as
um uh as balanced and as manageable as
possible because um
uh often
you know in other fields we've seen
wonderful strategies develop
that
are very difficult to implement
because they are so far-reaching and so
broad so taking things in
in
logical and prioritized steps uh
sometimes is the most manageable way
to see these strategies progress
um a third area of focus is
uh one which
you know the these sessions um are very
much a part of and that is building up
the um
communication and cooperation of
cyber professionals uh from across the
continent and with that uh
getting
getting the lines of communication and
cooperation open across the globe
um
there was uh an interesting comment many
made just earlier by engineer badar from
from oman where he spoke about the
importance of one-on-one connections
um and this is something that we strive
to support which is building those
relationships between
those individuals and those
those
experts or technicians
that sit and have to deal with um
risks and threats on a daily basis
getting them connected with their
counterparts um in other nations or
within other certs within their country
to be able to build
those levels of trust where information
can be shared
um we we really do believe in that word
trust that uh um you know cooperation
comes from having trust across
sea certs and um
uh
cyber security incident response
teams as a whole
and um the only way to build trust is is
through building relationships
um the uh the pandemic in the past uh a
couple of years now we've faced has
really restricted our ability to uh
uh facilitate
face-to-face meeting but i think
we we feel strongly that
as we progress and hopefully find our
way uh back to
our new normal our new normal will also
include um us being able to have
just these types of events face to face
where individuals can
build relationships can meet people
and can
with that go back and be able to reach
out in the future knowing who it is and
and uh who it is they're engaging with
and have that level of trust um as they
move forward
um so i think i've i've already used up
all my time just uh
through an introduction
um but uh i think uh i have a few points
that i think we'll we'll we'll get to uh
when we get to questions so uh
sheriff i'll i'll hand it back to you
and then look forward to uh fielding
some questions thank you
thanks for sharing nick i really
appreciate all your points uh
building trust is key we'll get back to
that later i'd like to move to our next
panelist
mr jeremy uh kittengam i hope that i got
your name correctly you are
you know
you know very much welcome to join in
the discussions uh following up on what
already has been uh covered uh jeremy is
with the uk home office please uh jeremy
the floor is yours
okay uh thank you very much hopefully
everybody can hear me um thank you dr
sharif for that introduction and thank
you to
um afrika cert and first for invitation
to this event and and to all our
participants
so i'm going to also try to share my
screen um but i will keep it brief um in
the interests of time
so hopefully everybody can um see my
first slide there so just by way of an
introduction what i want to talk about
um today is
uh an initiative known as the african
commonwealth national cyber risk
assessment initiative
this is a program that is sponsored by
the uk's foreign commonwealth and
development office and it's delivered by
the home office
international cyber team
so the focus of this project is to
really help countries to gain an
understanding of cybersecurity risk at
the national level particularly to
critical national infrastructure and
essential digital services and
more importantly to be able to use that
information to help drive cyber security
capacity building and ultimately to help
to mitigate those national risks
so over the last
three years we've been working with the
african commonwealth countries
we've been working with countries on an
individual basis um to help run those
national cyber risk assessment projects
and gain that understanding and also
we've worked with the african
commonwealth as a community via our
um annual uh capacity building
conference where we bring together
representatives from uh the african
commonwealth and we focus on capacity
building under a number of headings um
you know clearly with our focus on
national risk assessment and cni uh we
focus on cni protection
but we also focus on strategy and policy
particularly looking at how assessments
like a national risk assessment but also
a maturity assessment like oxford
university's capacity maturity model
assessment how those insights can be
brought together to help shape strategy
and policy
as part of our work across the
commonwealth we've also
gathered a view of where capacity gaps
are most acute and some of the
requirements and that's led us to focus
in a number of areas one is about skills
and we've already heard about that so
you know raising the skill levels and
particularly looking at diversity and
inclusion as a key plank of you know
improving
the availability of skills within any
country
looking at cyber attack exercises which
i know have already come up so running
tabletop virtual cyber attack
simulations and how important they are
and how that's a capability that every
country can benefit from
and we've looked at countering
cybercrime because that emerges as a
major concern for every country and we
look at threat intelligence as a key
tool um to help us with that insight
so
because our focus is on national cyber
risk assessment i thought i'd just spend
a few minutes giving a bit of context to
what we mean when we talk about national
cyber risk assessment so we're really
talking about a strategic national level
assessment and it fitting in with an
overall top-down approach that might
start with a national view of overall
risk
then factor out the cyber element of
that risk and then continue in a
top-down approach that helps develop an
understanding of that cyber risk in the
context of national risk and then use
that to help feed the capacity building
actions that will follow on from that so
we promote a very top-down approach um
working from a national picture and a
national strategy policy on on down
in terms of why we've got this focus on
risk assessment it's because we believe
it's a critical part of the jigsaw
puzzle when it comes to understanding
how to improve cyber security and
focusing on cni and essential digital
services is a core part of
pretty much every country's national
cyber security strategy
so understanding risk in terms of impact
and likelihood understanding
dependencies
which is a theme i might come back to um
and looking at what constitutes the
likelihood of a cyber attack so looking
at threat vectors looking at
vulnerabilities
and then the whole point of the exercise
of conducting nsra is to combine all
those insights into a an
analysis and a report and
recommendations that can drive capacity
building so um i won't dwell on this one
we've already touched on colonial
pipeline cyber security attacks to the
critical national infrastructure are
escalating and becoming more and more of
a concern to all of us it wasn't always
the case but now it's very much an area
of of key concern for all of us um so
protecting our critical national
infrastructure is important
uh
pretty much every piece of modern
critical national infrastructure is
underpinned by an information system
hence cyber is important
sectors like communications and
utilities cut across every other sector
so dependencies are really important and
unless we understand what are the
systems that make up our cni then we'll
find it very hard to defend those
systems and add resilience to those
systems um so we recommend a cyclical
approach
measuring the risk picture um through a
survey
analyzing the risk picture
using that to prioritize where to focus
scarce investment effort and then the
the fourth and most important stage is
to feed that information into action
plans programs and projects and that's
basically the essence of our national
cyber risk assessment guidance
we look at threats and threats need to
be
tracked all the time there are trends
we're seeing a lot more supply chain
attacks so we need to constantly track
those attacks
understanding the capacity building
capabilities that are going to make most
difference is important so mapping that
risk picture onto where we can invest so
things like risk management within cni
organizations
training asset management incident
management these are all important
capacity building headings that you can
map the insights of a risk assessment
into
risk itself we use the standard model um
for risk and we gather information on
impacts at that lowest level we provide
tools and calculate the various aspects
of risk
this allows us to reduce the overall
risk by mitigating impacts and reducing
likelihood and taking actions at that
lowest level there
so just to give an idea of what does an
analysis look like this is your standard
impact and likelihood grid the numbers
in there are illustrative of the number
of systems across all sectors that we
find at that level of risk so this
allows the immediate sort of
categorization and the red highlighted
systems there you know it shows that in
this illustrative example there are four
systems at a likelihood of five and an
impact of five so these are critical
systems that really need urgent action
to address so that's typical of the
insights that come from a national cyber
risk assessment obviously you can drill
down by sector and and conduct various
and analytical views
um
just a few sort of highlighted best
practices
we've found that taking a very broad
view of impact is important so
considering things like national
reputation
we aggregate
components of systems up into coarse
grain systems that deliver essential
services that's how we break down
cni into a manageable set of systems
we believe it's really important to
understand national and international
dependencies because our supply chains
are so much more interconnected now and
becoming even more interconnected
and the final slide there is just a
summary of what we consider the best
practice very happy to
make these slides available
but in the interest of time i think i
will stop there
thank you very much dr sharif
thank you jeremy you really
shared with us a very lively
presentation i really appreciate this
you touched upon you know quite a few
important points
when it comes to critical national
infrastructure recognizing them
coordinating efforts the
interdependencies you touched upon
interdependencies this is really
critical
you know failure and one of the
infrastructure can result in just not
you know affecting a specific sector it
can have a ripple effect so that's a
very important aspect of looking at
things having assessment at different
levels is also important
you touched upon supply chain attacks
and advanced persistent threat without
even
using the you know the the apt acronym
but you know this is a pattern of cyber
attacks that we are seeing uh i mean
recently i've started seeing more of and
unfortunately we anticipate more of it
in the i mean the days to come thank you
very much again for sharing now we have
our final uh presenter for the uh for
this panel uh uh palitium uh asif
actually it's
you know
very important to have uh incident
responders from cesar to being with us
and i really appreciate you
sharing with us your experiences as it
applies to regional and international
cooperation thank you
hello dr sheriff can you hear me
uh i hope i got your name correctly i i
did my best yes you did you did you did
great
so you did great thank you very much
thank you
i know it's not the the easiest one yeah
so so thank you very much uh thank you
once again to the team to to africa to
tune certain to first you know inviting
us uh we're very very very proud of
being part of this
panel with these
such a great panelist and uh giving us
the ability the the the opportunity to
talk about uh
you know togori's initiative so uh thank
you very much
uh the slides are in french i'm sorry
about that but i'm going to speak
english and
and i'm happy to take any questions you
know in french or or in english about it
so so no issue so
the idea is to describe the the
international initiatives that we had to
take in place in with that we have to
take in togo to build effective you know
operational framework for for our cyber
security program you know how to build
uh effective uh cert and suck you know
uh you know how to to build effective
incident response capabilities and
protect uh efficiency efficiently you
know our critical infrastructure so uh
in togo we decided to do it via
ppp so public partner public private
part partnership and i'm happy that the
colleague elizabeth talked about you
know the importance of public private
initiatives so
i'm going to just describe here today
what we've done in togo so my name is
parakeet masi i'm the head of search tg
so the national search of togo and the
technical director of cyber defense
africa the
company created by tokules republic
sorry to
handle cyber security initiatives in
togo so
i'm going to describe quick quickly the
challenges of cyber security that we had
to face to explain why we had to put in
place a public private partnership and
the first results that we're having so
uh so far so quickly and i'm
uh
i'll try to get into the the time slot
that i have meaning the the uh seven to
ten minutes
that i have so sorry if i go quickly on
some slides but
no issues i'm i'll take the time to
respond to the questions
so um
the challenges of cyber security that we
had to face in togo you know the the
togolese republic has a
strong development plan based on the
digital as a matter of fact 70
of our uh five-year plan of development
70 of the projects are really rely on it
on a digital plat platform yeah so uh
fortunately for for us that gave us the
the
to discuss the importance that gave us
the chance to discuss the importance the
importance of cyber security into that
that that pro program so
uh
we had an urgent need to protect you
know our critical infrastructures uh our
public institutions and and uh and and
and the citizens right because all these
uh
public initiatives are impacting the
citizens directly right so we had the
urgency to uh protect them
we also had the financial
issue right cyber security is uh is is
is quite an expensive pro program so we
had to
find solutions to you know on how to
finance it and how to finance it
on a sustainable way
not only relying on on
public funds on our
public you know state fine financing so
we had to find a solution on how to
finance our cyber security program
uh a lot of the panelists that talked to
today obviously they talked about
building capacity you know in terms of
technologies human resources and so on
so uh in in in togo uh as many of the
african countries and and as many of the
countries in the world you know we are
limited in terms of resources right in
terms of human resources so that's one
of the challenges that we had to face as
well
and on the other hand you know the the
the attack surface is increasing right
and we uh dr sheriff just talked about
the apts right and
and the the threats the attacks that are
more and more sophisticated right so we
we
and when when when you compare this to
the uh urgency of protection you know
the the the actors the the threat actors
they don't wait for you to be ready
right they they they hack you right now
straight straight away so we had to do
well and we had to do quick and the last
point that i want to discuss is as
a challenge that we had to face was the
lack of trust you know in in our country
uh
the public institutions do not get the
trust from the private sector from the
citizens from the partners and so on
right so we had to build trust and so
that the the the national cert had the
trust of all these entities
and at the same time we wanted to be you
know not only build a cert but build one
of the best cert in the region you know
we we our
the vision of the government uh was to
not not only do it but do it well and do
it the best way as we could so we had
the political will we had the leadership
from the double
republic from the head of states to all
the ministers involved into that into
that project so digital economy security
defense and so on
they were all really really involved
into the project so we had the political
win uh
we created a national agency for cyber
security right it was important on our
ecosystem
but then we had that
decree
designating our operators of essential
services so the critical infrastructures
and they had the obligation to protect
themselves against cyber attacks right
so
when we seen this we decided to create a
company you know private company uh
that was part of the shares were held by
the state and this company we gave
this company the ability to operate the
national cert right so then this company
not only will operate the national sect
but we want this company to
behave as a private entity you know
because
in our ecosystem the private sector has
this uh capability to deliver better
services you know better quality of
services than the public sector so we
wanted really this company to have a
private mindset and not only be a public
institution so we decided to add to this
to the role of this company the ability
to operate the national suck and this
service would be provided to the
critical infrastructures
so now we ended up having a company that
will operate the cert the national cert
and the national stock and
this this
model gave us you know uh uh
synergies we created since synergies uh
in terms of resources in terms of
finance uh because actually we use the
same resources for the celt and the
national sock
where the goal is to pro
protect the critical infrastructures
now uh
for the financing issue
uh we decided that the
services so the security for the uh
for the
critical infrastructures would be uh
paid by by by actually the private
sector right this critical
infrastructure they would have to pay
for the services for uh
protection
and then we will use this money that
this company is is having to operate the
self you know so we found we we actually
found a way to finance our cyber
security uh by the private sector
and then we have uh
we
we decided to bring in a private uh
partner which is uh aseco data systems a
polish company to help us build this
company uh because then we would you
know use the track records we would use
their their their processes we will use
their quality of service to provide the
best in class quality of service to uh
the the private sector and this actually
helped us as well to
you know have a knowledge transfer and
transfer of technologies and all that
done in the best way post possible
because then our interests were aligned
right it's not only a provider
delivering services or trainings to
another another to its client but now we
created that company together so the
transfer of knowledge and the transfer
of technologies are done from partner to
partner you know
because we built this company together
so
let me present you the structure of the
project uh really quickly so you have uh
togolese republic and aseco
so togolese republic holds 68 of the
shares of that company and aseco has 32
percent of the shares it's really
important because this is how we control
our sovereignty 68
of the shares is what is required in
togo
to have the control of the company so we
can take any decision we want without
the private partner right so we just we
created cga together we have the
national agency of cyber security and
tabula's republic is issuing you know
laws and decrees and and and all you
know the
regulatory frame framework
the ansi is delegating some services you
know all the technical services to cyber
defense africa now all the technical and
operational activities are done by cyber
defense africa this company created by
both douglas republic and aseco data
systems a second data system
is helping cyber defense africa and
togolese republic actually to build you
know capacity
we actually had uh uh
you know support from from from a bank
and this was important because by doing
so we do not impact on the state finance
we do we we do not rely on the state you
know money to actually develop our cyber
security program so now we have a
sustainable model right and we are able
to deliver the self-services non-pro
profit obviously free for all the
citizens and everybody that needs to you
know uh
that need help to respond to its
incidents we are here to help and we
develop services for you know a circ
client as well and and then that's where
we get getting paid and that's where we
get the money to you know pay the the
bank so this is the model that we have
structured in togo to uh you know
develop our cyber security
program so
quickly i will not waste time on on this
slide i talked about it cyber defense
africa is a ppp between togo and aseco
data systems and i will go uh on my
final slide uh presenting the first
results right that we've uh experienced
so far so uh our journey of cyber
security started in december
where uh we released the law on cyber
security and fight against cyber cyber
crime so basically to 2018 and 2019
was the regulatory framework you know
all the laws all the decrees that were
necessary to put in place uh the cyber
structure in the in the country so end
of 2019 we created cyber defense africa
and the the the real you know the
technical story started really in 2020
when we when we recruited the whole team
the technical team of cga and we started
the journey you know that 2020 was also
a big event in the world named kovid19
um but this
did not you know
impacted us as uh as such because
2021 we were actually you know february
2021 we were actually able to launch
officially the cert tg so the national
assert of togolese republic
so
we designated the first operators of
essential services in togo in january
2021 and we started protecting them in
you know you know uh if efficiently
starting from march 2021. so the third
tg as of now uh they deliver a couple of
services you know uh you know uh
regular services that cert provide you
know uh handling of incidents respond to
incidents uh awareness campaigns uh
audits you know uh and so on and so on
and we also do you know the the the
forensics in partners with the law
enforcement here in togo uh that's you
know the on on the third side and on the
south side we provide a lot of services
you know paid services so in togo right
as of now we have a
company that belongs to the togolese
republic republic
capable of handling efficiently at least
we we working hard on it to
help the critical infrastructures to
protect themselves and the money we are
getting getting from this uh from these
services are actually invested in the in
the self and
and that's the model that we've put in
place in togo thank you very very much
sheriff and i hope that i did not uh uh
you know uh
exceeded the the time thank you very
much
thank you very much we really appreciate
you sharing with us quite a unique
experience the experience of the togo
national
third
in my view in my you know professional
view based on experience over 20 years
in cyber security is quite unique it has
elements of you know
public private partnership that is you
know worthy of recognition as well as
one thing that you didn't mention which
is your cert is 100
nationals uh so it's operated by uh
i mean only it's it's really nice to
build you know on uh you know unique
partnership with other you know
i mean outsiders foreign nationals at
the end of the day you build 100 percent
togolese i mean
national cert of serving both uh you
know private sector as well as the
general public and you've done this in a
challenging time of the pandemic so it's
worthy of recognition thank you very
much for sharing um i think we come at i
mean to the end of our panel i'd like to
thank all uh you know the panelists for
such you know
very distinguished and special
comprehensive presentations i hope that
this panel highlighted what we promised
to highlight in terms of you know the
importance of regional international
collaboration to face cyber security
challenges uh i we have had experiences
from different panelists from different
backgrounds i look forward to more
discussions throughout the day and the
coming couple of days the trainings and
i i think this is a very important step
forward for africa and the arab region
and with our partners from across the
globe thank you very very much and i
passed the floor to tracy to take us to
the break thank you very much