[Music]
okay so now we have i will have our last
panel it's about observed malicious
cyber criminality during covet in the
african and arab regions we have expert
experts from different regions that they
will share the experiences and discuss
at attack trend updates see certain
observations
new tendencies and malicious and cyber
criminality during collide
so i will start
with uh
mr abdul hakeem
he's here
i'm taking you are here so abdul hakim
i don't know if all the panelists are
with me
he's here okay great
so okay
so yes
hi
so i'm hakim hi how are you
hakeem has several leadership positions
and i will not list all of them i i will
just say that he is the chair of african
union cyber security expert group chair
of working group on cyber incident
management and critical information
protection and chair of nigerian
national cyber security policy and
strategy review
uh and finally
he is a nigerian computer society
national cyber security policy and
satisfied committee okay
so uh it's over to you abdul hakim you
will share with us your perspectives
about the observed malicious during
kovite
19.
uh thank you very much welfare uh first
of all let me fully and wholeheartedly
agree with
something chris just said
we are actually uh protecting our
communities not just simply protecting
uh computers
now um
early this year uh the kenyan uh c cert
coordination center
indicated that between july and
september 2020 it detected three point i
mean 35.2 million
uh cyber threat events
uh which was uh and that was just in the
quarter of uh july to september 2020
uh which was a
152.9 percent increase from the
previous uh quarter uh and and this was
accompanied by you know a commensurate
increase in malware and web application
attacks
they attributed this to the uptick of
e-commerce
and to the kovid pandemic
the attackers tended to
target
remote working systems and e-commerce
you know tools and sites
having said that clearly
other statistics have shown that south
africa kenya and nigeria tend to be have
been the most affected in terms of
quantum
uh across africa
indeed in nigeria the nigerian central
bank warned of a spike in phishing
attacks
uh malicious spam and ransomware uh you
know related attacks and these these
attacks tended to have
messages for example from health
organizations like the nigerian center
for disease control or even the world
health organization itself and so they
were using coronavirus as a bait to
impersonate brands
uh circulate unfortunately
disinformation uh thereby misleading
customers and employees
and so in some cases uh they were able
to spoof
the you know the registration process to
collect
government aid or even aid uh you know
from uh relief agencies uh packages from
relief agencies
and in other cases we've seen where
cyber criminals endeavor to collect
victims information
uh things like account details and the
like under the guise of a likely
transfer of
relief funds
on the 2nd of september 2020 the
nigerian economic and financial crimes
commission operatives arrested at least
13 suspects believed to be members of an
organized
criminal
syndicate who
specialized in defrauding victims you
know of a lot of money millions of naira
and though the workings of these groups
as networks or connected individuals are
not very clear
because it's still being proved by this
security operatives
that said
we've seen instances where criminals
impersonate bank staff and advise
victims to download mobile apps
ostensibly to ease their banking needs
including loans during this
trying uh period related to kobe
and the truth of the matter is i think
end users really need to be careful
check their emails even their phone
calls if they're claiming to be from
some of these
health organizations or government
agencies especially if the caller asks
for bank information or you know click
on any link or website
um you know also we know these basic
cyber hygiene rules of avoid clicking
attachments and emails you know that
especially if they they claim to have
some kind of kovit 19 pandemic
connotation
uh so we've seen
uh you know people downloading mobile
apps from sources they're not sure about
and those apps have tended in some
instances to contain
a ransomware
we also have another nigerian cybercrime
group called silvateria
that has specifically targeted
organizations and workers this time not
just
the organization but the workers
responding to kobet 19.
and i think one of the challenges
that i personally have observed and
maybe this is something other countries
can improve upon is that sometimes even
the names of these apps especially by
government organizations are not really
intuitive
for example the app relating to the
national identity management commission
which basically deals with you know the
national identity
is called mws i mean
what does f you know m as in martha w as
in water s
as in streets i mean what does that have
to do
with identity management
and so for example the railway
corporation in nigeria their app is
called secure fare but you see you
actually need
within the names of the apps preferably
at the beginning
something that directly relates that app
to
you know the end user organization or
agency
but
the cbn also says it's continuing to
monitor these criminal activities
and again
i think it's very important that
government agencies and private
corporate establishments
also monitor
however
while they are sending
awareness and advocacy messages by phone
and email to customers calling for
caution in all online transactions and
dealings
i think many of us especially in in in
public bureaucracy
don't appreciate that many of the
legitimate
recipients are functionally illiterate
and thus you know such messaging media
really needs to be uh fully considered
or in this case recon reconsidered
because there's no need sending a slew
of advocacy or positive messages
advising
people who inherently
it's not that they can't read at all but
they can't read very well especially
the lingua franca english
so
having said that we do need to
engender partnerships between government
and the private sector to address some
of these problems uh because one of the
challenges we have is that if response
mechanisms are
dominated by security agencies then of
course there are concerns that will be
raised about issues relating to
abuse accountability uh access to
information as well as
the obligations of even the commercial
sector players to report attacks if they
feel government is everything then they
may feel there's nothing that they need
to do and thereby quote unquote saves
you know their money
and so sometimes this may cause a
reluctance to report offenses
and the continuation of the perpetuation
of behavior that increases all of our
vulnerability
to cyber crime one of the ways forward i
think is also to
invest in joint
task forces to build confidence between
public and private sector and and i
think this is a a very uh
preferable option we should look at
because effective collaboration between
for example financial institution uh
corporates in nigeria we have the cyber
crime advisory council would be a
practical step because it builds the
multi-stakeholder
um ecosystem that you know i've heard
discussed by some of the previous
speakers in in other sessions the issue
though is that we do need to achieve a
positive balance between protection of
privacy
and then the need
enforcement
bottom line or rather really in
addressing the challenges
of
remote workforces during pandemic
anticipated the pandemic in the first
place no did any of us really uh uh
anticipate that we would live and
continue to live with the situation for
so long
um so
a hybrid approach i think would be very
useful to all of us
um we have the challenge of
managing
on-premise systems remotely
we do need to ensure that mobile device
management has
two-factor authentication you know to
access
as a default
we have to um you know deal with
distributed uh denial of services so
those solutions must be in place
uh we need to be able to leverage
managed service providers to increase
resource capabilities and incidence
response because again our communities
our uh our organizations do have
uh uh insufficiency or lack of uh you
know the right kind of resources uh we
also need to look at adapting or the
adoption of cloud-based options
requiring wholesale change uh such as uh
extended detection and response uh
because it becomes important that
becomes important as updates are pushed
in from the cloud
i've i've
learned from some of our uh african csos
is that um
for human error and foolishness
uh we must build capabilities with this
mindset whether the threat stems from
intentional accidental or part of a
larger conspiracy
cyber incident management demands
continuous improvements
based on monitoring the important what
we would call our crown jewels or the
important data
so we have to prioritize our data
remote worker systems are important and
does play a crucial role however
only it is only one component of a much
wider uh you know cyber security
uh ecosystem we must bear in mind that
cyber criminals look
and weigh the effort versus the game and
will always invariably take the cheaper
way to uh you know to carry out and
exploit
uh threat intelligence and collaboration
as many of uh the previous speakers have
said is key
we must continue to share
uh and increase the visibility of
develop and develop capabilities um our
remote worker environment will vary in
different locations
but we must understand that the remote
worker environment is a tug of war which
requires options to mitigate threats
without hampering underlying
productivity and in closing i would want
to say that institutions should continue
to raise awareness among their customers
on information security outside the
office space
they need to build institutional
capacity to deal with cyber crime and
keep abreast
with the innovations uh and the
technology in general
we must enhance existing
people
initiatives and last but not least we
must
always seek ways to protect the
endpoints which are our customers
regardless of their status or their
level of enlightenment or education
thank you very much
thank you
for sharing this information from
nigeria and about the cyber security of
observed cyber security events
and thank you also for the
recommendations that you have given in
the second part of your speech
to face these challenges
now let's go to tunisia
the head of a watch alert and warning
division and she said he has been
working at thinset since 2010 and he is
passionate about open source tools
so
muhamdali it's over to you
okay thank you
so uh good evening ladies and gentlemen
uh first of all let me thank you all for
participating to this uh session today
so let me introduce myself i am bernard
head of the watch alert and on the
division of things
subject of my presentation is about
observed malicious activity observed by
the insect during the covered 19
pandemic
so my talk is relevant to those
of us who are cyber security expert
computer emergency response team and
decision makers
so uh the content of mathematician i
will start in the introduction by
explaining the reasons of hacking then i
will talk about talk of several
malicious activities and i will finish
with
conclusion
so
we know all that the main goal of
hackers is to have an easy and fast way
to get money using their skills in
betraying information systems
so to reach this main goal they wait
passionately for the right opportunities
so uh the corona pandemic represented a
good opportunity for them and this
explaining the rise of malaysian cyber
activities in our currencies in the
world especially during the quarantine
period
they are similar in terms of types and
methods but the difference is only in
the number of occurrence from one
country
to another
so uh because of that government in most
countries in the world have resorted to
quarantined quarantine to limit the
spread of corona this quarantine imposed
on institution to adopt
remote work using vpn connection and
organize remote meetings
with the video conferencing solution so
working remotely using vpn imposed on
internet server providers an extra
effort
to provide secure
services and ensure its continuity for
customers
we also
find a phishing operation for some
employees who work in financial and
sensitive institution
in anticipating or visiting some safety
measures when working remotely or not
being well prepared to use vpn
connection or using a video conference
solution which has
which has zero day vulnerability or
weakness like the example of zom in
april 2020
so
in tunisia we found some malicious
activity related to this and some
markers it says activity
only an effect as
some hackers threatened the isp with
ddos attack
and demand the demanded ransom in
exchange for stopping this attack so
speak about ransom models as you can see
in this slide
so uh
as for the provision of earth and
financial aid which was carried out by
most of the government in the world
especially indonesia it was an important
uh driver of the
of the record by provoking the group
affected by corona and trying to steal
the reduction and personal data by
social engineering
fishing smashing attack fake news
fake facebook world fake website in
order to sit on them and to publish
their data
if they did not pay the required ransom
as soon as possible
so uh the tunisian government depended
on la
company with the financial operation of
those affected
by the corona virus it was constantly
targeted with its customer by hackers to
steal their credential so let's now look
at the next slide we'll show you what
has what has been passed
and sorted by date from slides 6 to 13
so as you can see this universe 9
prime 2020
another one
11 prime 2020
next one
7 may 2020
so i you can see on the slide that is
the
log file that contains the
victim identify
[Music]
nine november 2020
so already our investigation began that
uh
master cena not bad in the
involved in these attacks
another 1 30 in november 2020
the same method and thinking fishing is
missing
fake webpage fake
facebook message
okay
last one
so
we have 120 victim in less than
uh
24 hours
so uh also customer of measure telecom
operator indonesia have been targeted by
fake news
and vision attacks via facebook pages
controlled by hackers to entice them to
participate in falsified competition to
win a limited connection
this is an example
so
in addition we do not forget
vulnerabilities exploitation in the
information system of some sensitive
institution
and the installation of some malware
like ransomware web shell botnets and
advances persist persistent threats in
their private network
especially the expectation of the
vulnerability
of
microsoft
exchange
so uh to introduce the number of
affected microsoft ourselves uh service
uh transferred follow the process to
assist all the affected establishment so
banks government
presidency of the public private
companies hotels so um
multiple servers has been compromised
with the
worksheet
so
there is some malware installed after
the exploitation of
the vulnerability of microsoft exchange
i mean x
[Music]
fdh
so this is an sp webshell
okay
here are some marvel involved during the
investigation
so
there is a workshell detected by the
semantic and powder protection
in
victim
institution
so
as just to summarize the main point of
my talk the number of incidents handed
by twisted in
was increased three times more than the
previous one due to malicious activities
during the covet 19 quarantine so all
groups like cyber security experts legal
experts government and social workers
must
work together in order to find the
appropriate solution to avoid or to
reduce hacking attempts during disaster
or during severe time
so uh
thank you for your attention
that's all madam
to you thank you muhammad ali for your
information very informative and
detailed uh presentation
now let's go to code evoir with vladimir
amman vladimir is the head of
codifier he has nearly 10 years of
professional experience in the field of
cyber security in cote d'ivoire in
addition to the technical background
acquired during the year spanned a cyber
security analyst at
the at second development
and the platform for combating cyber
crime so vladimir it's all with you
hi
vlad unfortunately has not made it yet
ah okay
so at least you introduced him
then let's go to ahmed
with dr
uh
ahmed with dr hyde from hajjali
uh uh dr haytham is an executive cyber
security specialist chatham and nassim
dr haytham he
holds a phd in cyber security management
and the master degree in digital
forensics
over to you dr haifam
hello good afternoon
thank you for inviting us thank you for
the kind introduction
and um actually been listening to you uh
most of the time and um
we are kind of in the same bin uh we've
been experiencing uh the same things um
technically with africa and with europe
and with americans as well uh the
pandemic actually did
uh
was an eye opener as well for most of us
and uh it's clearly have shown us a
message as well
um i wanna talk from perspective of
certs and what have certs uh felt during
the pandemic and what kind of detection
that we have seen from the malicious
activity uh whether it's around the
globe or here within the sultanate
cyberspace
um actually uh as dr hakeem
just mentioned earlier that as a society
um mostly has got affected by different
kind of categories so i'll talk about
generally what happened with the society
and then we'll go into
government or uh companies and
organization the society during the
pandemic was hit with very crafted uh
kind of social engineering identity
theft
a lot of the usual that has been
mentioned earlier
with emphasis on ransomware and
intelligence gathering so we have
noticed that a lot of impersonation uh
identity theft of uh world organization
health center or the cdc here in the
sultanate as well uh with different uh
versions of
an infectious map that has been uh
trying to uh be spreading around the
application especially mobile phones
where it tells you download this
infection map that will show you who's
getting infected around you and give you
alerts and also will give you indication
how many uh people are infected with the
corvette 19
during the pandemic from 2020 until
today
there are a couple of those applications
which are a malicious application that
again a root access to your device and
then they aim into financial
uh kind of credentials in the mobile
itself or in the uh systems uh general
uh the importance i want to emphasize
that
the specially corrupted malware and
malicious activity that has been
targeting the society as us members of
the society as well who works in
different kind of categories whether
it's in law enforcement or critical
infrastructure national infrastructure
or government agencies they can also get
hit either with that malicious
application or a family member who can
get uh who got that infectious
application for example a ransomware and
then spreads through the network now
unfortunately during the pandemic um
small to uh medium kind of
entrepreneurship programs or let's say
companies
have uh mostly suffered why because of
their weak infrastructure they were not
able or they were not ready for a sudden
transformation whether they are aiming
to provide their services online through
the
sales within the e-commerce system uh
let's say
transforming the business module or
actually accommodating a large number of
staff and employees working remotely now
the factor that assert we have noticed
that once we deployed a lot of remote
working remotely from home
they all start to get targeted in a
different way
perhaps when the infrastructure team or
let's say the support team within the
organization can better
save the employees from different kind
of attack because of the infrastructure
how it's set up the antivirus and so on
but once the employee has taken for
example his machine his laptop or his
desktop or anything working from home
then he's subject to a different kind of
atmosphere or infrastructure whether
he's using a free wi-fi maybe somebody
else is joining that wi-fi uh some
people are
family members who get their phones or
devices infected in the same network so
the network of the organization has been
compromised uh at home
and that's a different level so as a
search we start observing all kind of
malicious activity that are happening
either way home or or actually targeting
people at work at the infrastructure so
we are started initiating
kind of a guideline if you are working
at home you need to have a separate kind
of network if you are working at home
you need to ensure that you are
activating antivirus you are upgrading
yourself using a proxy uh you're making
sure that you are in a network alone uh
send a guideline how to operate during
the pandemic or working remotely
now
uh what kind of top malicious activities
that we have seen is social engineering
and also ransomware ransomware was
really huge
impact on a lot of organization
a lot of data has been lost
but again
we learning fast in a curve as well the
thing is that i want to mention uh as a
society as well that we're trying to
protect ourselves inside the society as
mentioned today earlier uh once we are
trying to achieve that level of security
or that level of awareness where people
are not supposed to click and malicious
link or they must identify that sharing
over sharing of information through
social media and getting the information
from the right places whether we can see
that a lot of
heat maps or infection maps that have
been spreading around they are
pretending to be an official one from
the world health organization or from
the cdc uh they start rolling out
vaccines and then again the shift
paradigm has shifted now they are
focusing on people saying hey get
registered in the vaccine or financial
aid during the pandemic a lot of people
have lost their work uh less of their
job so there was a different kind of
scheme that happened where people say
well the government is allocating this
much funds uh if you are interested or
you are affected please fill in this
information unfortunately people are
over sharing their information they
share their sensitive information some
people went to the extent that they are
sharing uh banking or financial
information along with otp for some
reason they believe that the otp will be
a type of verification where they can
verify they are receiving the money but
unfortunately they were scamming them in
there so essert or the national cert at
that level we have uh started giving a
lot of awareness uh we started spreading
the news we saw hitting in different
multiple uh attitudes we are being
active in social media we are being
active in the radio uh we are being
active even in tv uh directing people
that you should get the resources from
the right places you should get the
numbers and you should not over share
your information and especially sharing
the links from unknown sources claiming
to be a fund area or
trying or claiming to be an official
site that they are trying to get
financial aid and so on
so at that perspective and i know it's
been a long day and uh i just trying to
avoid a lot of the talks that has been
already been shared and overshared here
in the platform uh so yeah from that
perspective i would like to end my
short and brief
status on the infectious heart happening
during the covet 19 pandemic and the
malicious activity that happened
targeting society at first and then
targeting the critical infrastructure or
the dominant infrastructure at all back
at you alpha thank you hi dr thank you
very much yes you said an interesting
thing uh many many cyber security events
were because we had to switch online uh
on non-planned with an unplanned and
programmed processes so we had to face
many challenges thank you thank you
thanks again now i will go to
hear some features from a global global
organization from icon
with carlos alvarez carlos
leads icons and icons engagement with
the with the trust and public safety
communities i can in the internet
corporation for assigned names and
numbers and he will speak about dns trc
ticr project
dnst icr stands for domain name
security threat information collection
and reporting so it's over to you carlos
thank you alpha thank you so much and
thank you everyone for being here and
for staying with us even though we're
running a little late yes
um
so yeah like walter said i lead eiken's
engagement with them
in general law enforcement be criminal
or civil
as well as with all the different
flavors within the cyber security
industry that includes incident response
threat intelligence
operational security etc
the the topic that i want to speak with
all of you for a few minutes is
the project that we started at the
beginning of the pandemic
that we called dns sticker
that stands as welcome set
for domain name security threat
identification collection and reporting
in march of last year um
like many others we realized that we had
to do something
to
look into what the bad guys were
doing with
or in the domain name space
we were seeing
left and right all sorts of reports
some
claiming that um
that the world was falling apart because
the
malicious actors everywhere were
registering thousands and thousands of
domains
to conduct all sorts of different
malicious activity um
so we started our project
what it does
is that it pulls all the zone files for
all the generic top-level domains
that means all the
um the tlds that are not country codes
so remember that there are generic
top-level domains and there are country
code top level domains
the country codes have only two
characters at the right of the last dot
some examples are dot d e dot c dot r u
dot a t
anything that has three or more
characters is a generic top-level domain
so we
download um and analyze all those
corresponding to
tlbs with three or more characters
and we analyze them we look into all the
zone files
um
trying to find hits from a dictionary of
forts
that are related to the pandemic
that dictionary forms includes
tens
of words in different scripts not only
in latin script
[Music]
and we of course recently updated it to
include omnicron related omicron
not only but omicron
related um
terms
um
since the beginning and even though we
started in march
we did the analysis going back
to january of 2020.
um
just to see if anything had had happened
as the world was realizing that
that something was coming in january of
2020.
we identify the domains that have
anything to do with terms related to the
pandemic
and we verify them against
some mental sources that we think
are
probably the best for this purpose that
we could find virus total fish tank
alien vault otx and google safe browsing
the domains may or may not get hits
meaning
a domain that we see
as having any relation to a pandemic
term
may come back
with a report maybe
total says something about that domain
or maybe
google save browse and says something
about that domain
we then have a human
um
check the actual report that we get back
that
analyst
not only looks at that report but
carries on several other manual steps
and only if he has
certainty that the domain is not only
malicious but within icann scope
then that domain gets reported with
evidence to the registrar
with which the domain was created
for us as coordinators of the
technical functioning of the dns
we have the must that we have to avoid
false positives we can't allow ourselves
to report as malicious domains that are
not
and we have the obligation to increase
trust among registrars and registries
the registry is being the operators of
the top level domains and the registrars
in our world in the gtld space the
registrar's paying the companies that
sell the domains
to the public
after all this time
we have some numbers here and it's
interesting to see
remembering that i can't
remit is
is narrow
um
the project
was scoped specifically to address
phishing and malware domains
nothing else
we can't
look or act on domains used for fraud or
scams um
it's very specific because our scope
coming from our bylaws are to help
coordinate the technical functioning of
the domain name system globally
and we have to help ensure that it stays
secure and
resilient so this excludes content
um
and that leaves out many of the things
that that many others may have been
investigating
since january of 2020 to this month we
have identified
almost 360 000 pandemic related domains
that includes both legitimate and
malicious domains that's the total
universe of pandemic related domains
that according to our dictionary have
been created within
the entire detail the universe
now from may of 2020 to august of
this year
the number that we detected
was 200 almost 247 000 of
pandemic-related domains of which only
6.1 domains
came back with
a report from varus total or google safe
browse
or otx
so we have basically fifteen thousand
of the two hundred forty seven 000
pandemic related domains that we
identified as having at least one report
and not only that that had one report
but also that had name servers and were
resolving to an ap entrance meaning they
were operational
of this
our analyst
considered that
only 4400
had received high confidence reports the
other
10 000 and something
um
[Music]
the reports received for those 10 000
plus
other domains were not of enough
confidence for him to continue
looking into
remember that for example virus total is
a collection of engines
and some of the engines used in various
total are
worthy of
but let's say
in a very informal way are worthy of a
whole lot of trust
while some of those
engines other
among those engines
you may not be able to trust their
results as much
i'm not gonna name names
um that's not the purpose
um
[Music]
and of those four thousand four hundred
because of our scope
um we could only flag as malicious and
within our scope
370 domains
which is far different from what
was reported or what has been reported
in the median
frequently that there were thousands and
thousands and thousands of domains
remember that caveat
that we don't look at front we don't
look at scams
that's where the bulk of the domains
related to the pandemic were being
created
and that that
to me that that's what explains the
difference in the numbers that were
important
um if you look at the reports that
interpol has put out
for
palo alto
now you will see that they have very
specific information with tens of
thousands of domains yeah
they can include and they do include and
they should include because it's within
their scope
domains that have been used to sell
counterfeit masks
to sell um
miracle cures
we can't look at that that's content
that's outside our scope we would
violate we would be in breach of our
by-laws if we looked into that
so staying within malware and fishing
in the universe of pandemic related
domains
seventy months domains
and we reported them to the registrars
and they were acted on
um
unfortunately the project um
is not focused on any particular region
we don't look at this
on a per region basis we we could we
have not done it but we could probably
um look for example at
where the aess are located if if we see
a malicious domain
we could try to group them
on a
periodical basis
and try to see what's there uh
territorial connection where the as for
each domain is located and then try to
come up with
match over time
um we could also see where the registers
are located
um
just to try to enrich the public
reporting on the project but we are not
doing so at the moment
um for now the
the priority for us is expanding the
scope of the project um
but this is a process everything within
icann has to follow a process we are
following that process
um
and um
we are seeking input and we are in
discussions with for example the
governmental advisory committee
um so that they can
share with iken
how the scope of this project should be
expanded what other
types of malicious activity or what what
other kinds of events could be
analyzed through this project through
this tool the dns sticker
we'll see where it goes
but the tool is there it works it's
effective
and it's accurate
so
that's what i have for now
thank you so much for your attention and
waffle back to you thank you
thank you carlos thank you for
interesting presentation and the
information that you have shared with us
personally i know that within icann
during
this pandemic
a lot and a lot of work has been done to
protect the consumers from the malicious
domain names
so it was our last presentation in the
panel
is there any question from the
attendance
tent
i can't see any question
so everything was clear
so i think i have to close this panel so
i would like to thank you again uh thank
all our nice language panel panelists
for
what you have shared and presented it
was really very interesting
and um