good morning everybody welcome to the
Tuesday morning in that Auggie and it is
Ted
for that so as you may have noticed I
have Betty Burke up here with me we
asked her to give an encore presentation
and after yesterday Ryan said a lot of
nice things about Betty that I can't
possibly math so instead of a tell a
little story about the beatings of new
Nog anybody here remember new nod it was
like eight years ago so I was reading
through some old emails yesterday trying
to remember what happened and when in
early 2010
we made the decision that was time to
become a separate Sentinel organization
shortly after that we realized that we
were just a bunch of volunteers who had
no idea how to run a conference and
thankfully Betty agreed to step in and
offer advice to us informally while we
were trying to figure things out but we
realized that we had to actually hire
somebody to do the work for us so I
think it was around the summer where we
put out a solicitation for an executive
director an interim executive director
actually becomes important in a moment
and to help us decide through the
formation in early years of new Nog
first thought of course was well what's
just hired Betty but we took a step back
and realized that we had to do this
right we only got one shot we need to
make sure we were making the right
decision so we ended up in getting 12
resumes I think it was in the
interviewing six different candidates
and after all that and by this time it's
November we went through all the
candidates found our top two one of whom
was Betty of course and realized what we
knew all along pretty much but I had to
validate that she was the right person
for the job not only does she have the
experience the knowledge of the
community but we knew that she could
take us forward into new Nog thankfully
also around then we got a bridge loan
from Erin to pay salary for executive
director for the first year or so so
Betty could actually get real money from
us and I'll just be a volunteer
Betty signed her contract in early
January of 2011 and as an interim
executive director somewhere along the
way the interim title went away
she became a full-time employee and here
it is seven or so years later and
anyways thank you very much Betty for
all you've done for us and now I'd like
to hear and see what you'd like to tell
us so a bit about my thank you thank you
everyone for the wonderful watch that I
received yesterday picture of it I
couldn't talk yesterday that me to get
through today I promise
thank you very much I appreciate
everything so a bit about me for those
of you who know me today you don't know
how I got here and I didn't want to give
you just the technical pieces of our
history new nog or of the Internet in
particular but myself and how I related
I don't know if you find it relevant or
not it's not a traditional Nana talk but
it's about me so I started at the
University of michigan-flint the
University of Michigan is a wonderful
was a wonderful home to me is a
wonderful place today there are three
campuses and I was lucky enough to work
for many years on the Flint campus and
that's really where I began my
collaboration work I feel that my
strongest strength and nanog and in the
community is my ability to bring people
together and I learned that at u of
m-flint
because it was a regional campus and it
needed to collaborate with the main
campus and the other regional campus in
Dearborn and everything I learnt in
those early years was about building
partnerships from within the campus
structure itself to working with the
other universities in our local area
from building you know buildings if you
will to academic programs on to building
fiber projects within regions
of the area I was asked to come to
Merrick Network where I was part of the
University of Michigan and that was also
about collaboration
Erika pearly found out that I was
interested he was the CEO the president
of merit excuse me at the time and found
out I was thinking of leaving my role as
a technical person at U of M and he said
well come to work at Merritt Network I
have this thing called the National
Science Foundation projects and maybe
Michigan regional network called mish
net I don't know you'll be happy we'll
find something for you to do and he
trusted and believed in me and I
believed in him that I would find a
wonderful place to call home for a
number of years at Merritt and I think
that although there are a lot of people
who hear about Merritt and the regional
network it really is important to Nanog
in lots of ways both good and bad but
for me it was wonderful mostly I was
also asked while I was there to join the
Michigan Information Technology Center
which was the final stages if you will
to the building infrastructure for B as
part of MIT C I had the good fortune of
building fiber into an advanced tier
three data center and building a Comfort
Center and managing the conference
center which helped me understand what
it took to not only provide for but be a
customer of hotels and conference center
of business and something I was a
consumer but not a provider for so it
was an interesting period of time and it
was also important in our history
because it was the corporate
headquarters for merit network and
Internet - so I had an opportunity to
work with folks in internet2 which is an
outgrowth of many of the projects in the
early days of our network as Steve said
I was a contractor too
nyan are for a number of years Nana when
we started as new nog we didn't have any
money but thanks to our colleagues at
Aran
they give us some money to hire me and
then over time it looked like it was
really good to make it so I turned from
a contractor to an employee in about
so me and I now has some employees for
the first time here the early days of
networking to me involved a number of
lease line surface over an exit 25
network with primary and secondary
communication processes so if you really
want to know about the history of all of
that technology if you visit Merritt
that network or merit dot or merit net
number of DNS will take you to
description of these early projects in
the network and Nana even Nanog died org
has some of this history my technical
even I was asked yesterday sort of so
are you just a business manager or do
you have some technical understanding of
this technology and I indicated that I
feel I have enough technical background
to be dangerous sort of like you can be
ask me a little bit but not completely
the early days of my career I was a
traditional manager but I was a 1970s
graduate from high school and I didn't
see myself as being someone involved in
Internet technology until about 70 77273
reg in the 70s and I started my CS
program computer science was a program
of engineering science which is very
typical back when there there were real
strong programs for networks at that
networkers at that time in many college
campus environments so I was in physics
when I helped build a computer science
program in my early days of programming
were basic anybody remember basic q
basic I was real good and COBOL and
Fortran and I really thought I was
moving up the scale when I learned
Pascal in assembly language my early
computers were burrows and Amdahl a
prime computer and moving on to IBM
mainframes much of that work was serial
and done over key punches instead of PCs
and then PC single drives with our dual
drives without hard drives and in many
ways that was my version of the network
we didn't know what it was going to be
what it is today as I became a manager
of that technology I learned enough to
be a manager on the campus environment
we developed a corpus Network we decided
that connecting to the in Arbor campus
for certain applications and business
development was hard on a single device
so we developed servers and single
networks and token ring became a part of
our industry and we eventually moved on
to Novell not worse anybody who
remembered Novell it was big I thought I
was really something when I went to Ann
Arbor I was lucky enough to follow Elise
gerich and Bill Norton I shared that
this was though when I came to Ann Arbor
and I came to Ann Arbor to work on
Triple A authentication accounting an
authoress authorization software and
that was developed if you know
Marit and one of the things they hired
me to do when I came to America was work
on implementing the dialing network for
customers in Michigan so I used this
proprietary software that they built to
make that possible and eventually worked
in collaboration to spend that software
off it became something that merit
realized there was
Minoo it reached end-of-life within
Michigan and our network and had value
to the rest of the internet community
and it was one of those projects that
became as part of my work a spin-off
became its own company I also had the
good fortune of beginning to work on
merits internal systems part of which we
use today is some of the work that I got
to do in the early day is called mailman
NOLA Services in building Oracle which
was our first registration database I
also had the good fortune of following
Bill if you will and realizing at the
end of its life was the route servers so
how did we turn down the service that we
had built over time meant merit because
it was no longer as useful so I was
involved with a number of colleagues and
turning down that service at the same
time I had the good fortune of being
asked to move the routing asset database
used today to a commercial for free
service so again collaboration and some
of the background that I brought with me
from working in a non-profit environment
helped to put the early fee structure in
place for re DB when I went to Internet
to as I indicated I was able to use my
building construction background from
building buildings on a regional campus
from trailers to buildings to actually
building a very large 35 billion
construction of the new building within
advanced data center and that was really
what I feel is a great accomplishment
for my days in Ann Arbor as I indicated
I got to manage conference center which
I think really helps here at Nanog in
terms of my interface and understanding
of what it also means for people to
service us the there's so many I wrote a
list actually in timeline of the people
that have made a difference in my career
and Tanana and it's just it's too long
huh forget someone it's easier for me to
say thank you to all of you you you know
who you are and you know that you made a
difference to me so I won't I'll try now
I think my biggest thank you at u of
m-flint
is my business and accounting folks
because that's where I started in my
nonprofit experience which is important
to us
didn't happen accidentally I had a lot
of experience given to me by being in
the accounting and Finance area at a
non-profit University called G of them
it's great the presidents of merit over
time there were three that I work for
most importantly Eric awkwardly in its
Board of Merit and actually the second
Mike Nick Pearson was there at a really
important time for merit and Nanog I had
the good fortune of being asked by Eric
to get involved in this project called
the MSF net and
nanog when it began in 1994 which Elise
told me it was our first and I'm meeting
and somebody at me and I found out that
I was in charge
ultimately of the work that Susan our
and some others were doing and at an
enema meaning they came to find me
and the Nanak said the Nano community
said we know you were in charge and we
want more information we want more
control and Mike McPherson and the board
at Merritt were able to believe in me
and believe in all of you that you knew
you wanted to give some first
transparency so it was the first changes
that we made to the charter of nanog
trying to meet the needs of what Nanak
was but listening to the community that
they wanted some more involvement in the
process and through that process of
revolution evolution I like to call it
we developed a steering committee and I
went around Steve was first one I said
Steve Feldman some other folks like
Marty Hanigan and Rodney Jaffe if you're
gonna speak up you need to help you need
to volunteer to be on the steering
committee need to volunteer to chair the
program committee we're no longer going
to have merit appointments or America
only appointees to this to these roles
but we're actually going to ask you to
do some work so thanks to many of them
for the early work in volunteering on
the steering committee and helping me
help nanog and lots of things happened
during that period of time and again you
can go to the website
don't push me in all the dates although
I happen and in 2010 it was time for me
to you lead the University of Michigan I
had many jobs many opportunities there
but it was time to leave and at the same
time Nanna felt that it was time to
using Patrick's words grow up and move
away from home and it sort of it was
very meaningful it was a good home
Merritt was a great home to man table
for a long time it just needed to grow
and make that final step and see if it
was ready to go out on its own
and I was asked to come back to oversee
the development evolution of a while
stabilized this new thing called new not
that we like today love today called
neon and thank you to the DNR board of
directors who believed in me in all of
the early members who believed in me to
go from being in a lone situation to
having almost 5 million dollars in the
bank I couldn't do that by myself the
board can do that and all of you need a
thing you might take away and through
that process
although the board of directors is
important to the process of nanna the
program committee by far has been more
my passion is making sure that the PC is
enabled to have the autonomous ability
to put together a program that is a
program of peers it's not something I
decided although I have to say I feel
like I influence them or influenced the
PC a lot during those days because I
knew why you had to be on your own for
that very reason but the program
committee was really putting together a
peer review panel and they're really the
backbone of nanog so what do I see today
well someone asked me what is the
internet what's gonna be I don't know
you know for me
46 some years later what I thought was
the network is something beyond my
belief and so in another 30 years
I hope it's the same beyond my belief of
what it can be because I think it's
limitless thanks to all the engineers
the systems developers social media
development cloud who didn't own back
when I started if that we would have a
cloud who would know what we're gonna
have in 20 years but it is
the thoughtfulness and the carefulness
of all of you that make it so that our
grandchildren mine especially that I
care about have really something that's
really an integral part of their life I
think in that development you have to
maintain a sense of social
responsibility my hope is that the
government stays the government and we
try really hard as operators not to
bring the politics into our life that we
don't have someone telling us how we
have to build the next generation of the
Internet and that we take care of some
of those issues that we all know about
existing today but we take our own
personal part and being responsible
that's the role I see of Nana is to make
sure that is a collective we all are in
this thing together that it's not one
part of the industry called peering or
equipment vendors or ISPs or software
developers but we're all of those that's
the fabric of the Internet and we all
have a part I think my last parting
comment is that I hope all of you become
engaged it's not necessarily that you
become a member but you're engaged what
happened back in the 70s 80s 90s let's
not repeat let's not think that someone
else is going to solve our problem we
have to all be engaged as members as
participants as speakers engagement is
the name of the game let the Board of
Directors know how you feel let the
program committee be the peers to decide
if your presentation is great one of the
things I left the newcomers with
yesterday was how do you go from being
an engaged newcomer to someone who's
comfortable enough
to stand in front of the Nanak community
and talk in the Nano community when I
started was limited to 100 it was easy
to look out across this audience and
speak to a hundred people now you're
looking at a thousand twelve hundred how
do you how do you feel comfortable
enough to do that when do you know
you've arrived and again one of the
things that the program committee is
helping to do is help you find your
voice so as a newcomer find your voice
as someone who's been here for a while
use your voice this is the place Nano is
unique as far as I'm aware that's one of
the only places that truly is different
there's lots of conferences out there
and all sorts of our industries from a
security conference to appearing
conference to a local long but really if
something not owned by the policy
registry making registry but in
partnership with Nanog is the place
where operators are small large
companies alike can be equal partners
with the board and I hope you continue
to find your voice and be engaged and
that's so if you have questions I'll be
happy with my trusty sheet of paper and
give you the time but again I think that
my issue is that we're not done there's
a lot to be built a lot to talk about
and we do it together and the board is
just that someone who organizes a lot of
conversation because you elect the board
and you elect the the voice so be
engaged and the program is only as
strong as all of you are willing to
submit a presentation to the program
committee otherwise you have just
she's fresh impression of what's
important thank you
Thank You Betty
[Applause]
all right
Thanks any questions anyone want to know
anything you have a question for me or
are we done what's up all right
all right thank you again and I look
forward to coming to Vancouver as an
attendee everybody say thank you to
better you tonight at the beer here