hi good morning everybody our first talk
this morning
is choose your own networking adventure
or choose your own adventure networking
networking professionals roads to
success its moderated by Kayla Clifford
I put this together but I was basically
going off of an idea or a talk that I
saw two years ago it inspired me to get
this panel together professionals to
discuss their career paths the talk that
I saw was by Dani Rossman and this is
basically an extension of that I really
feel like this is important to not just
the younger generation but people who
are stuck in their careers who aren't
sure where they want to go so I have my
panelists here to explain their paths
and how they got to where they are and
also to have a focus on advice for the
future generation and also talk about
some of the failures that they've gone
through that have got them where they
are today and that stand out to them so
my panelists here in no particular order
Chris Jezebel Matt Sylvie Marty and
Danielle and they're all gonna be going
over there their career timelines for
you so thank you Chris
take it away hi I'm Chris Wood field
it's kind of its kind of intimidating to
think about the fact that I've actually
been in this business for 20 years now
21 years ago I never would have imagined
this would be my life's work but but
here we are and very happy and I feel
very fulfilled and how things have gone
for me so early days I had always had a
fascination with this type of technology
especially you know going back to even
the 80s dial-up BBS's but for a long
time I always assumed that this was just
things that other smart people did you
know I could never be smart enough to do
that
so I'll just be a happy consumer and
enjoy hanging out on IRC channels and
and check out Usenet groups and things
long as ledger lines yes remember using
it so I went to college got a
communications degree with designs of
being a graphic designer
did that for a couple years and that's
an around that's around the time I first
encountered the Netscape Browser
actually no is the mosaic browser then
Netscape and saw how you know Scott saw
books on how to design web pages how to
get on the internet and you know me
working on the Internet is kind of like
an alcoholic working behind a bar it was
I was just so fascinated by it I wanted
to be a part of this as much as I
possibly could but I had no idea how how
do I get there again this is something
that you know my mentality was though
this is something that other smart
people build I can never imagine having
the skill levels needed to to work on
this but this was the same time that
Linux became a thing so at some point I
decided okay I'll start messing around I
got a secondhand PC from a friend
installed one of the first Linux distros
back in the days when they were sent
around on floppy disks I did not have a
cd-rom drive taught myself a few things
enough to be dangerous again
nothing and nothing that made me think I
could actually make this useful until I
found some friends who were pretty much
like minded and did actually have jobs
working at ISPs and I said oh maybe I
should talk to them and figure out how
to get my foot in the door a while later
I got my first job in the business
working night shifts in a knock at a
company called des Jack's that was that
was fascinating but at the same time
night shifts are not something I wanted
to be doing long-term so if you can do
it great it did not work for me so I
started looking at other opportunities
taking what I learned and going from
there eventually I wound up at a company
called Internet and I stayed there for
ten years moving my way up from doing
customer installs to to eventually
winding up in the architecture group a
number of my colleagues from that time
are actually here in this room and and
in the meantime I relocated moved to
Atlanta that that job kind of went it's
you know ran its course
and then I wound up the happy
coincidences of working on a working on
an open source project that someone I
had actually gone to college with was
one of the many maintainer zuv happened
to work at Yahoo and that led to a job
there which took me to the Bay Area from
there I moved on to Twitter stayed there
for about five and a half years built
that network up from something that was
really only sending text to the the the
all streaming all photo install self
eing of monstrosity it is today most
recently I took a step back from
operational roles and moved to
Salesforce about a year and a half ago
and now I'm actually focusing on
software which is something I had no
idea I would ever have the aptitude for
looking back at my time twenty years ago
when I was first trying to figure out
how the internet worked and I think it's
a great journey some of the things that
I think I was able to do that made me
successful always be curious and always
always look for a thing
technology's on your own time don't just
concentrate on the technologies and
tools that you're being you're you're
actively working on set up set yourself
up a home lab this was this was not an
easy thing to do 20 years ago nowadays
virtually anybody can download router
images there's open source routing
software take advantage of an ecosystem
because the you know the the ability to
learn networking is you know the
technology is available that allow
people who were learn networking are far
far beyond what they were back in you
know back in the old days if I could do
things differently I would say I
probably would have there are definitely
times in my career where I where I
failed to do that and became complacent
and became very heads down and just not
a serve enough on these are the
technologies I want to work on these are
the things I want to learn how do i
integrate this into what I'm doing I
think have I done a little bit more of
that it might be a little bit more more
successful I'm not that I don't think
I'm not but there's things to keep in
mind and I think it's my time thank you
so I'm probably the most least seasoned
professional up here and I made my
courage or directory' into this area
kind of randomly ice-sub life we take a
step back and we go to college right my
parents had always I could really
instilled in me become an engineer you
need to become an engineer so I you know
I went into college thinking I was gonna
become a software engineer that's just
kind of work I was going to do and then
it quickly became apparent that I'm not
really gonna enjoy that so I moved into
doing finance and that's kind of how I
started this whole kind of trajectory of
my career I
I started working on the family business
doing the you know kind of the books the
accounting whatever then I realized that
corporate finances poking out what I
want to do either so you know it's all
learning experiences right I mean that's
the biggest thing for me so you know
once I ended college and I started
networking with people in my senior
seminar class I got in touch with
someone a recruiter from Google who was
looking for someone that had
construction background with like a
passion for technology and it was a
random merge of things that I had that
kind of led me into getting into Google
at some point you know that job didn't
work out but I ended up doing a network
the supply chain position at Google and
I did that for a couple of years and
then you know again through networking
and just meaning people I ended up at
Facebook back in 2009 and for you know
doing at that time I was doing data
center asset management so a little bit
of network in the sense that I was kind
of focused on the hardware but and
absolutely not nothing to do with the
network itself so I did that for three
years and then I went to another company
and you know I think the lesson learned
there for me you know there's a bad
decision on my part in retrospect go
ahead you know they think the thing I
learned by leaving and going to another
company is that culture is dramatically
important for me for me to be happy at a
company so you know always do research
on where you're going you know different
cultures drive with different people and
it really depends on kind of where
you've land with them so you know I
didn't say but that long at that company
and then I came back to Facebook at that
point we were now growing our the edge
Network and they you know we just needed
more people so you know I reached out to
a manager of the team and I said hey
like I'm interested in coming back and
he's like look you have a lot of the
skills that we want but you obviously
don't have any experience in network
whatsoever but yeah like let's let's try
it out so I've been back now for four
years
I am now managing the edge network
delivery team which is kind of a hybrid
of i hearing coordinator i basically is
just extending our network deeper and
deeper into ISPs and yeah I mean that's
that's kind of the quick and dirty on
I'm kind of my my career trajectory
lessons learn you know throughout my
very short stint is one you know do jobs
that you may not may or may not think I
might like ideal for you just based on
learning opportunities you know if I
hadn't done the finance stuff I want
probably would have never gotten into
Google and I would have never been here
it just kind of all they all built on
each other the other thing is you know
obviously research and culture is super
important it might not be to you but
flick for me that was a big thing and
then the last thing is just networking
right I mean you never know who you're
gonna meet obviously we all know that we
that's what we do at these conferences
but you know making sure that you you
know your net we actually were talking
about it when we got up here like your
name just precedes you right people know
of you without ever having met you so
you know it's really important I think
for you to just make sure that whatever
you do you just kind of think think of
that and and just constantly network
with people you never know what kind of
jobs are out there that you might be
interested in later thank you
next we'll have Marty to talk about his
career path alright so those of you who
those of you who know me know it's easy
for me to get up in the stage and talk
about technical things and finance
things but to talk about myself I don't
like to do that but here I am and bear
with me I tried to put together a
chronology that wasn't too detailed I've
done a lot of things over my career I've
been involved in the internet for a
really long time
it started in 1985 when my mother
brought home UNIX computer she was
working at AT&T Bell Labs I think it was
called the Nash 3 and she brought home
65 five and a quarter inch floppies with
it and somehow he figured out to get a
log how to get a login prompt but was
never able to
he's logged in I had no concept of
default logins and passwords from there
I tied up my houses phone line for a
long time but BBS's and over downloads
and just learned everything I could
about serial communications and modems
and things kind of fast forward I took
some notes here I'm just kind of keep it
moving
so that actually had helped me to meet a
guy named Michael Barrow Michael and I
Michael founded the MIT Internet special
interest group and I helped him out I
was the meeting coordinator and I
brought in people to kind of talk to
audiences about the Internet and we also
taught people how to use telnet and FTP
and you know fun protocols like that
that I'm sure you're all very well aware
of these days that parlayed itself into
a job running the NSFNET node at Bo's
calm which was really my my first kind
of foray into the Internet I was the
firewall administrator and I ran a socks
proxy and all the things that went along
with it
fast forward 1995 my first foray into
social media
I had solid solid UNIX skills learned
from my previous experience and some
networking skills from bos and I built
upon that platform here at Firefly you
all use the technology that Firefly
developed every time you see a stupid
banner ad for something that you you
thought about it was because Firefly
invented this kind of agents protocol
these little quotes are little anecdotes
that I thought might personalize this a
little bit this one says Joe you sure
you guys can handle 10 megabits that's
Joe Provo he he's his boss told me 10
megabit ATM to the internet from
Cambridge Mass which at the time I was
really excited about but in retrospect
not a good fit but also that kind of
underscores relationships and some of
the relationships that I've had with
people in the businesses started all the
way back then and and Joe's one of those
people went on to be the chief engineer
at Teac which was basically the
University for BBN you usually took a
job at Teac you spent one or two months
working in the NOC for me and then you
immediately quit and got a job BBN went
on from there to a few other interesting
things I I for 8 into
services a little bit did some security
then I went on to work on ss7
technologies again I think the point
that I'm trying to make with my career
progression is that the internet
underpins many things but it was really
about a little bit of a DD and the
applications and their applications of
what utilizes the underlying
infrastructure and I've been able to
kind of maintain a little bit of pinball
with the applications and and how they
work and how they affect society and the
internet but it was always underpinned
by the Internet I worked at a company
called des XCOM which was acquired by
level three and if you go to the newly
minted CenturyLink sign in Westminster
and walk into the lobby you can see the
patent level 3 acquired that company I
ended up there this anecdote is Brian
teared off and we were using ascend gr
Epps's high-capacity Ethernet switches
and they didn't really work and they
ascended been acquired by cascade and
their stuff was so broken that I think
it was at 11 or 12 o'clock at night
Brian and I drove over to the Cascade
labs in Westborough Massachusetts put a
Cisco 7500 in our trash bag brought it
back to our datacenter in Cambridge
where all the kind of technology was
happening and swapped them out and then
hid the GRS so no one would know that we
ever used it it's very fun and the GRF
had a couple of acronyms one was goes
really fast and the other was gets
really and you can figure it out from
there okay so did some other interesting
stuff again more underpinning to the
network and the applications landed at
bar a sign through an acquisition this
one was really interesting I had through
my UNIX and networking skills learned
about the communications rule our
enforcement Assistance Act and got a
little bit of expertise in that
basically
third-party lawful surveillance I worked
at Barisan and I did some the merger and
acquisition work for the company that
they acquired that I was at and helped
them build their Kelly a Service Bureau
which was really really fascinating and
I learned a lot and I learned a new
respect for alarm for spent
professionals and the work that they do
political political arguments aside it's
a it's a very interesting thing and they
do they do a lot of great work and the
anecdote here is I was on a call testing
with the FBI and I
they they answered the phone and they
said hello and I said his YT home wasn't
funny
[Laughter]
then from there I kind of did a few
other things I ended up I work on the
Bahamas for a couple years my friend
Kristen later did some work with me
there I ended up building a data center
in Iceland for Vernon global and I
landed at Akamai this anecdote you all
may know well warning mr Gilmore Patrick
Gilmore I worked for him for maybe five
or six years and then took over the
group and I think the rest is kind of
history there I learned pretty much
everything I know about interconnection
at Akamai and under Patrick and with
Kristian Kaufman and Noam Friedman and
it was a really great experience went to
Microsoft did a little time they're
really great shop I love the people from
there I landed at which which is where
I'm at today another application that is
underpinned by the infrastructure and
really fascinating new problems I work
with some of the best engineers in the
business the network the software
engineers the video guys really
fantastic and I think it's really gonna
drive the edge and I'm really looking
forward to learning and contributing and
helping to solve some problems so to get
to the questions and get over with this
so what would I do differently and
failures and things like that I'm not
going there don't ever look back it
doesn't matter you learn from your
mistakes and you move on and then what
but what advice can I give all of you
admire people I have a short list here
and nobody should turn red when I
mention your name but Barry and Mary
shine they we owe them a little debt
they're part of the reason we're all
here but I don't think many people are
very familiar with them software tool
and I'd the world first is be on the
planet small debt john curran learned a
lot from him Silby we've worked together
on some fascinating stuff that I have a
great respect for her she's really smart
and I love working with her my friend
Gabe Cole mike barrow chris Malita
patrick of course I miss Randy I wish he
would come back and and stop going to
the ivy TF this is better Randy R as
Turk Bergen not Senna but I love Richie
centre as well but Richard Turk Bergen
is a really great guy - no need
and then obviously Nanog and all you
guys it's without the relationships and
nanog and the education then and the and
the and the mentoring that some of you
folks have given to me I wouldn't be up
on the stage today and I really
appreciate it thank you
Thank You Marie and next we have met all
right so where do I start
so my title the senior technical network
planner which I realize probably doesn't
tell you much I currently work at Akamai
Technologies
so let's festro through a little bit of
this stuff to begin with a lot of this
is about the things that I learned and
the things I learned about myself along
the way so it starts in New York City I
went to college in New York City the job
boards in the computer science
department said hey we have a paid
internship for J random Wall Street
company come down here make an egregious
amount of money for a starving college
student and do sysadmin so I'm like sure
that sounds like a great idea and so I
did that and so what followed next was
four years of me holding down a
part-time job while carrying a full
engineering load because the work was
just that interesting and so there are a
couple of different companies that I'm
not gonna list all of them but just
doing standard or shoot you an existed
man old school you know where every
machine had a name and you knew each one
of them by name not true anymore but
that's where we were after after college
first I started at a mind Fox which was
the New York City hacker ISP and I kept
the machines from being too owned on a
regular basis and and that was just a
lot of fun you know it was very much a
start-up atmosphere and I got to start
learning the what do I want in a
professional environment what do I want
you know how what what is relaxed what
is too relaxed and just learning more
about what I enjoy in terms of work
environment after that went to psi net
pipeline New York and did a lot of work
there also sysadmin but it's beginning
to edge into the network side of things
that's where the slow transition
happened after I left psi net I was in
the situation where you know they they
eliminated their Manhattan office most
of my friends had moved up to Boston at
that point I was looking around and
someone said hey you know I'm leaving
BBN
do you want my job and so I said sure
there's a lot about saying yes to
there's a continuous thing and started
in their system operation center
basically doing systems support for
their newfangled web hosting thingy that
they did for a while but also then over
time getting more into the network side
and analyzing the network side and more
and going tier 2 support for network
analysis and on top of that finding that
I really had a love for statistics you
know taking a look at every piece of
Time series data you have represents a
signal and signals can be processed and
teaching people showing people how to
visualize information and showing people
the narrative that is behind data so
that you can actually make decisions and
tell a story and figure out what you're
gonna do next and that is a thread that
goes throughout whatever comes next so
after being at BBN for a while and then
doing tools for a while at BBN as well
where I found out that while I am pretty
good at coding I am not actually a
software engineer I went to a startup
which we're not going to talk about much
besides the fact that this is where I
learned that there are certain there are
certain work environments that are so
bad for you that it's not worth the
money in general they're there they're
there are situations like did you hold
on for the IPO yes I hold on for the IPO
and then got out as quickly as possible
because it was just when you dread
coming to work every day only so much
money will compensate for that so after
I left there this fellow the name of avi
Friedman's whom sure a few of you know
said hey there's this company called
Akamai and we need networking people you
interested I said yes sure why not and
so that starts that was 2000 and 2002
and being at Akamai was a fascinating
thing and wonderful network architecture
and you know when the Juniper m20 is
getting rolled in on the cargo pallet
right next to your cube you take the cap
off you plug in the serial cable you can
figure it put the cap back on roll it
the door repeat a lot and just getting
things going and moving fast was kind of
amazing
then the dot-com bust happened Akamai
lost 2/3 of a peep for 2/3 of its people
including me and I went to Tufts
University for a while and he didn't
that inch there and got to basically
rebuild the network from a leer 2
corridor layer 3 core and that was where
I really got deep hardcore into network
engineering where it was effectively my
network and it affected thousands of
students across eastern Massachusetts
and really having the responsibility if
things went wrong and working with an
amazing team and so it was it was a
really really great experience all
around and somewhere in there I got I
got to do a master's degree because it
turns out that universities will pay you
on product this is also so one thing
that's on here is hi my name is Matt
Ringel and I'm a recovering wedding
photographer one of the things that I
did during that time was I did wedding
photography I do a lot of photography in
general this seemed like a reasonable
way to do to to monetize the toys and
the big thing I learned there is
contracts every customer I gave every
color I had I gave a contract to and
understanding what a contract actually
meant and understanding what those
negotiations actually meant was gigantic
understanding how to fill out a customer
what's going on after all that came back
to Akamai first on the revenue side
professional services built a web
performance consulting group offering
contracts again learning sales learning
how to sell ideas to people after a
whole bunch of time doing that which was
amazing went back to engineering first
network architecture with this fellow by
the name of Martin Hannigan is my boss
and then after doing that for a couple
years going to network planning and now
I'm position all of my positions have
been influenced with that authority you
know where nobody reports to me but a
lot of people listen to me and so this
is more about understanding how to get
ideas into people's heads and making
them understand what's going on and then
being able to do the research necessary
combined
of statistics and data and selling ideas
to actually get to a coherent strategy
that everybody buys into for how we're
going to deploy in let's say the
Americas and that's kind of weird
there's no way to study for deployment
strategy for the Americas for the
largest CD in the world it's a
culmination of all these things that
come together in in finality I think the
the advice that I would give I'm
actually going to read this one out
because I wrote it out be a student of
your profession that sounds a lot like
what Chris said never never forget what
it means to sit down and study
consciously spend time learning more
finding out more about the corners of
your field that aren't necessarily in
front of you at your job
one of the biggest mistakes you can make
is falling into the groove of thinking
that the things you do for your job is
the extent of what you need to know
there's a big difference between ten
years of experience and two years of
experience repeated five times thank you
thank you next we have Sylvie all right
so it just made me realize that my
tenure in this industry is now twenty
five year this year yeah so I started
during I came I came to the industry via
the business side when I was in high
school I came across this program that
was called Junior Achievement where you
start your own company for six months
and at the end you need to fold it and
and close it and it was an all-girl
company and we did what we did boxer
shorts for men and we we won kinda
you're interesting and we won company of
the year for Canada and there was a
really cool experience and it showed me
the the power of working together
towards a common goal and it also Swift
admire my study path into more the
business side so I went to the business
school by didn't I didn't want to let go
of the technical side so I did IT
so information systems and by
specializing in market research and
quantitative analysis and I think that
was a that was a good mix for me and
then I had landed my first job actually
thanks to Junior Achievement I landed my
first job at the Laurentian group which
was a Financial Group and they they
basically hired I didn't know this but
they hired grabs from Junior Achievement
and he kind of gave you an internship
for the summer time so I learned a ton
there I was rotating two or three weeks
through different departments so I it
was a really good experience to get
acquainted to all corners of the
business of financial services and and
then I had paid for my studies and I was
antsy to travel and I didn't know where
I wanted to go so I really picked the
other end of the world as my destination
and I went to Australia and meanwhile I
retained my job at the Laurentian group
my boss was super great and he said look
this is an opportunity of a lifetime
take some time off we'll wait for you
take three months six months eight
months whatever you want we'll wait for
you so it was really great that I could
do that travel and come back to
something because I'm a little insecure
financially so so that was a good a good
trip so we went backpacking and
throughout the backpacking then I
started realizing that we were quite far
away and that communications were really
really hard to come by I couldn't I have
three children now and they're young
adults and I could not fathom being one
connection away from them over there in
1993 when I was backpacking I called my
parents maybe once every ten days when
we got a phone booth that's all we could
get so it just shows you how far we've
come in in 92 in since 93 to now like
we're just one whatsapp away so and then
I
had a great opportunity my mentor at the
Laurentian group became the CEO of
Telugu and Telugu abused to be the crown
Corporation for overseas
telecommunications and he said were no
longer a crown corporation we need new
people we need new ways of thinking why
don't you come over for an interview and
I got a job there and I started I was
the only one that had the IT background
so I started on the digital
communication side because that's
something that I understood it was zeros
and ones it was like oh I get that
that's fine and this is where I finally
met basically submarine cables
satellites and the Internet and I became
at it from being the first product
manager created the backbone 6 4 5 3
which if you know me you say you know
that I call this my firstborn and it
truly is my firstborn and it's been a
really really amazing trip so just
creating this backbone and growing it
then I went to mobile communications
because I thought I needed to learn
something else and mobile was booming I
don't know if you remember we had these
really big phones like like this and it
was the GSM starts I was part of that it
was also a great learning experience and
then I came back to tell a globe which
was acquired by VSNL telecommunications
and what happened there was a bit
magical because I came to my first night
Auggie in 2003 and I met all of you guys
I have to say that you were really
really scary at first like extreme I was
extremely intimidated and I thought wow
like these people come to the mics like
this is 2003 we've changed a lot and
people were shouting at each other and
they were basically I think discussing
violently
friend points of view and I thought oh
well that's not the carrier world like
we're very much gentlemanly and more
mild manners they will will disagree but
we're not gonna flinging salts so so
that I it was a little hard for me and
at the time there was only 7% women and
I remember sue Harris saying that she
was giving the stats from the conference
and she was so happy that there was 7
percent women I'm like wow okay where am
I
what's going on but I stuck around I saw
it as a challenge I said this the world
is not seven percent women we need more
this internet I believe in it and I
started getting really involved with
Nanak so I started with the program
committee and then the steering
committee and then what became new nog
so I was on the board of the first new
nog and it's been tremendous and I did
this because I truly believe that I
could have an impact and I could I had a
voice I have something to say and it was
an interesting crowd to do this from the
internet what fascinates still what
fascinates me still today is that we're
all competing but we're all
collaborating and it wouldn't work any
other way and I think that if we put a
good effort in collaborating we can
self-regulate and we can make really
truly grand things and we're due to a
really large extent we're doing that
really well so that's great
and also being then being part of it
like you being part of the the crowd
here I got a call from Google to say
would you like to come and join our
infrastructure group and at first I
thought huh content company I don't know
I don't know that I want to do that
and then I went for the interview and
then I thought you know what I will say
yes because I know nothing about content
distribution and I know the backbone so
yes this is my next thing the lesson
learned for me is that whenever you get
a little comfortable a little to this I
know I know this I know the four corners
of my garden but probably it's time to
move on it's time to learn something new
and that's been a recurring theme and I
didn't quite understand what I was going
through but now with perspective I can
tell you that if I feel too comfortable
it's time to move on I need to learn
something new so that's something that I
would really wish someone told me
earlier because I would have taken
bigger risks and that's the other thing
I'd like to tell you is take risks risks
are fun
the risks are help are there to help you
grow and if you skin your knees it's
quite okay you can stand up again and
pick it up but like you said Marty you
don't learn from your success you do
learn from your mistakes
so it's really important to to learn
from your mistakes an important thing
for me that I do want to talk about is
coming to Nanog and and getting involved
with nanog I did suffer from a condition
that I had no idea what it was called
until I realized it was called the
impostor syndrome I really felt I did
not belong here
that everyone around me was much smarter
than me they could all they could all do
this town better than me and it was
really really uncomfortable but I only
learned that it was called impostor
syndrome maybe five years ago so if
you're feeling that everyone around you
is more smart and can do this a ton
better look that up you might have that
condition too
but you know what you can cure it you
can you can gain in confidence and you
can definitely do great things the only
barrier to your success often times is
you so that's I will leave you on that
Thank You silly for the sake of time
where we were gonna have questions for
the audience but we're gonna go ahead
and let Jezebel speak
Jezebel actually stepped in we had
another panelist who was sick and wasn't
able to make it so she stepped in at the
last minute to take over for her and we
really appreciate that so Jezebel take
it away so sorry I don't have a slide I
just stepped in yesterday but I promise
to put one in and so you can go through
my career path in this industry as well
unlike everybody else I actually studied
art in university and I had a different
vision I saw things differently than
what I thought to most people saw so I
expressed myself in painting and
sculptors had nothing today was
infrastructure or technology but it
turns out they're actually quite closely
related when I got out of college I
realized I have to make a living he
can't support herself even you are not
willing to sell art which I was not
willing to part from my art so I went to
work for a law firm the law firm
specialized in contract law intellectual
property and immigration in the Silicon
Valley and we worked a lot with startup
companies and I felt that fascinating
that there were so many opportunities
and so let me back up for a quick second
I was born and raised in China so all
the opportunities here just seemed
incredible to me you can do anything you
want if you invest yourself to it so one
of the
people at the firm as the clients of the
firm was above net communications and
when I was getting ready as Sylvie said
if you get too comfortable in your
environment it's time to leave I
realized I was getting too comfortable
in the law firm and I didn't want to
become a lawyer I realized that early on
that's just not the kind of person that
I am but as the office manager for the
law firm I had to deal with telecom for
the whole office such as SIP trunking
for all of the phone lines and Internet
connectivity for the office I was
working surreal on the phone with call
support was to get those things turned
up the CEO of the buff net was coming
into the office and he was sitting in
the lobby waiting and he hurt me on the
phone with the technician on the other
end of the call saying you handled that
quite well what are you going to be
doing what are you doing I hear you're
looking to leave the firm what are you
going to be doing I said I don't know
but this is not for me I want to do
something new and I want to try
something named he said well I started
this new company called above net and do
you want to come and give it a try I was
like what do you guys still he said oh
we're a colocation and network company I
had no idea what colocation meant so I
was like he said it's a carrier hotel
and I said is that like a hotel he said
no no it's for machines you know
information exchange the internet my I
thought what could be the harm now you
know this is let me give it a try
so I went and what I loved about art is
that it's ever evolving so at above net
I wanted to learn about everything that
there is to know and you can bet that
everyone in the company all of the
engineers welcomed me with open arms
they they said you want to learn this
sure let me set up a couple of pieces of
equipment
get you a login so you can play around
you have any questions ask us anytime
you're interested in learning this is
how we learned this is how we can help
you learn so I build a lot of friends
and I see you guys in the audience and I
I know that I can't be here without you
guys and so if you are starting your
career in this industry rely on your
friends and this community because this
is one of the most supportive
communities there is so just like Matt
avi was my VP of engineering at above
net and he asked me hey I'm going to
this new company called Akamai
Technologies and they're doing some
incredible innovative technology do you
want to come and work for us here in
Cambridge Massachusetts I was like I
hate snow no not really I don't know I
don't want to move he said how about if
you fly out and meet some of the people
and see where a CDN I was like what's a
CDN and that was in 2000 so I I want to
interview and I met some of the smartest
people in my life
and before I left I said you know what
where do I sign up
I don't care what he pay me what I'll be
doing I want to work with these smart
people I'm curious in learning all the
things that you are doing and how you're
going to be changing the world so I will
say at Akamai for a few years just like
Matt the dot bomb happened we went
through some really tough times and in
the second to the last round of layoffs
I left
Akamai well I have all this knowledge in
infrastructure and II technology telecom
and I where am I going to go well State
Street one of the biggest banks was
hiring
I said oh I can work in a procurement
team I they said what we need someone to
lead a procurement team that's what the
innovative methodology of thinking so I
I said well I can do that and I even
know contracts so I want to work for
them
I learned a lot from that and I will
come back to that on the lesson I
learned from my career I let them I was
one of the youngest VPS that they've
ever had I led a pretty big team and
everyone on my team was older than me I
worked till 11:45 on New Year's Eve so
we can close a mainframe contract with
IBM and I would just say that I will
never go back to work for a bank from
there I went to a few other startups I
realized that my passion and my drive is
truly with trying to change the world
and doing something new and different so
I want to a startup that made
interactive LED panels I helped a friend
to start a company called iyx reach a
left limit rework with another friend at
a layer and then went to Seoul to GTT
and three years ago we started a new
company called packet fabric and so this
is just quickly going through what I've
done in the industry and I know that
there's another session coming up and so
I'm going to just be brief the lesson
that I've learned from all of these
experiences is truly leave your vision
be curious because technology is an
ever-evolving thing and don't ever think
that you've learned everything there is
to know about something because there's
always something new and someone knows
something better than you but just
because of that doesn't mean that you
should
leave your abilities because as
individuals we can all change the world
and lastly trust in your herd so I think
on my way here I said I'm paying homage
to my nerd herd and leave in your tribe
in your village this is my village this
is this is the reason why that I can be
successful and we all can be successful
that's why I stepped in to help out
because this is your support group if
you need to learn something know
something have questions and you want to
start a new company ask your community
and they're there to help you and they
are willing to give you the most honest
and Rudo feedback sometimes you don't
want to hear about but the best friends
give you the toughed toughest advice and
give you the truth so thank you so much
Isabel alright that's the end of our
presentation well if you wanted to ask
any questions to any of these people
they're always available walking around
the hallways just feel free to come up
you know ask them for advice thank you
everyone so much
you