thanks Michael so Nana would like to
once again thanks Jennifer networks for
sponsoring hackathon 73 the event took
place this past Saturday and it was an
all-day event all in we had 39 attendees
there was a sampling of network
engineers system admins and recent grads
across various vendors providers in
hyperscale companies there was not only
a sense of learning something new new
technology but also benefited from
meeting and working with new people I'd
like to talk a little about the actual
event and then bring up the top two
teams the hackathon was focused on
security and automation something we all
need to think about these were the five
takeaways understanding that automation
plays a critical crucial part in
security the importance of
interoperability and integration scope
of automation for security and that
security will require multiple parts of
your organization to work together and
then finally understanding dev SEC ops
sowhat's dev SEC Ops I'll leave you with
this quote in other words when you hear
DevOps today you should probably be
thinking dev ops QA test info SEC
the participants were broken out into
nine teams part of the morning was spent
laying the groundwork as well as talking
about the importance of a system with
the message bus and feedback loop
mechanism each team had servers front
ended by a V SRX firewall that they were
required to secure while allowing only
good traffic in team started out with
tools like security onion and Cabana but
could use whatever other tools they felt
necessary phase one had one or two
attacks that could be manually blocked
then we amped it up with phase two
juniper amplified the attacks such that
the only way to effectively keep
services available was to automate the
blocking of bad actors and finally in
Phase three along with me automated
attacks we had engineers hacking all the
teams and now I'd like to bring up team
problem gopher
forward use the mic Thanks
thanks Vincent so we're team problem
gopher Brandon I'm Jason game
Oxshott and Mike I think here Eddie had
to head back to the day Wow bet he was
right it's Kanak word up here in front
of a lot of people so forward there we
go okay so our talk will be just quick
overview recap of the topology what we
saw did encountered as a problem what we
do differently in the future so the
topology was pretty straightforward they
gave us V SRX routers Vincent said we
had a DMZ and a trust zone we had to
keep some services up and running on
those devices and they ramped up
everything they give us a pretty good
topology but one of the first things
that they started off with was they gave
us saltstack framework because anyone
used salt salt stack yeah that was our
reaction to so we looked around the
table and said hey who's do salt before
add like what is this ginger templating
thing do then we started figuring out
that we had a lot of traffic coming in
from the knids on the message bus so we
were able to start parsing that out get
some of those going so the vinson
already had this slide up earlier but
the workflow was basically the message
comes in off the message bus the reactor
sees it and if it matches a certain
pattern it sends it on to react and then
we wanted to extract the IPS and then
push information from the IPS
off to the firewall to block the traffic
so here's like a sample message bus will
act charge is gonna go into detail here
in a second but the orange highlighting
there is what we needed a key off on and
then you'll see the blue is the ASCII
arrows and the yellow is the malicious I
peed tuple that we needed to separate
some stuff out of but I'll turn over to
a cat to talk about
right so this is actually part of the
code that we were using to try and
detect the type of attack that's coming
in so there are different keys that
actually get taken care of in multiple
files as part of the reactor interface
for salt and this particular ginger
template actually gets invoked as part
of the passing exercise now the the
traffic flow that we actually showed you
earlier showcases some of the fields
that we want to look at particularly the
IP address of the or the source IP
address of the attacker and once we were
able to actually pass that we can use
that to create a V SRX policy over the
salt interface that we have and this
passing interface is fairly simple it's
really just trying to detect if you can
see a couple of IP addresses there we're
white listing those IP addresses so that
we don't actually block the source NAT
interface itself and also some of the
internal subnets that potentially would
just be trustful devices and much of the
other stuff is trying to just get the
sort of the syslog messages in a way as
part of the salt reactor interface and
use that to split on the source IP and
try and determine if we have a unique
way of identifying the attack in this
case the source IP and the port number
and once you've done that we sort of
push it into as you can see on the
right-hand side and the push policy said
which is the separate push policy that
gets invoked as soon as we leave
identify the particular flow so the RT
IDP as the the key value in which we're
trying to match uses that to then use
the Junos install config assault module
to go ahead and push the required policy
inwards I think one of the good things
about the entire exercise was that even
though it was using the Junos device we
were able to hide it behind the salt
interface so people have didn't really
have to learn the the syntax of like the
the window interface itself but could
really just work with the salt workflow
and with that in much of the
the overall workflow this is what we try
to modify and work further in with some
of the manual configurations later on to
try and permit certain required flows as
part of the exercise yeah and this is
part of the yeah meal encoding that we
had to avoid some of the rendering
problems
incidentally assaults sort of extends
the plugins for ginger to allow you to
do an encoding without having to work
with quotes and skipping different
characters yeah and running do you want
to talk about maybe the policy that
you're playing nope
okay so I'll continue and the idea was
that there are two different portions of
the network that we had to deal with
there was a trust part and there was the
DMZ the DMZ was the portion where some
of the pods were located the web servers
that we had to protect against the
attacks and make sure that those
services stay up and the trust network
is the area that we have our tool server
running where our scripts would be
running and passing the attacks and then
enforcing the policies on the vs rx so
the policy propagation was fairly simple
but it does all combined together into
the salt stack interface and I think
overall for all of us it was more of the
the set of learnings as part of the
exercise learning how to deal with salts
tagged to to work with things like
squirt you know Cabana for actually
looking at the logs from the attacks
coming in and then combining the manual
sort of entries that we use to basically
define the permissible flows on the V
SRX and then have the salt stack do
everything dynamically when the tacks
start coming in in full force so once it
really stepped up the attacks in like
the phase 2 phase 3 etcetera we didn't
really have to touch our V SRX at all
the salt stack was continuously
responding to each and every attack
that's identified at every point in time
and all the subsequent attacks can
automatically blocked because the V SRX
has the policies after that so I think
that probably bolsters the initial
intent of the exercise which is to
showcase how you can automate using
something like sole stack or frankly any
the management tool and use that to push
policies dynamically as you detect
attacks right so automation is sort of a
key part of the security exercise yeah
so absolutely we would hack again and if
anything most of us have been
participating in all the hackathons
consistently I would also recommend that
even if there are folks who have been
coded earlier please do come come back
there are hackathons happening in every
nanog now so I would recommend joining
up in the team that you're comfortable
with and just proceeding with the attack
with the exercise so yeah you get to
learn a lot and you get to code so I
think that's pretty awesome but thanks
to my noggin remember for setting up the
entire exercise thank you thanks team
problem golfer and now I'd like to bring
up team ocean six to have them talk
about their experience at the hackathon
hi it's not six it's just four but we
were six at the hackathon so we had a
few casualties yesterday yes asacs some
folks from Oracle cloud infrastructures
Flavio from PayPal and myself from leak
X we're kind of an ad-hoc group that got
put together and that's not a bad thing
to say because we won second place and
so I think you just have to be open and
find yourself together and a team and
start working on the topic so in
contrast to the other group which gave
you a lot of technical details right at
first we would like to play them and
explain to you more about what we had to
do as a as a task or what what happened
actually because this was a Red Team
Blue Team game and our task as a
participant group was to defend our
production network with all the tools
that we have in the beginning we noticed
that the attacker was doing some very
simple sin flooding and pin flooding
probably with a tooth to light legs like
HP and we detected those from just from
looking at the syslog and the suspects
were collected in a Cabana instance and
for the ping floods we were detecting it
we are the security onion tool in the in
the squirt overview web interface and we
also noticed some service
vulnerabilities that were also present
in the log because what is it
essentially doing it's taking a full
traffic capture on the inbound and then
running it through an IDs row in this
instance and then generating events from
it so if you have a new name is FTP and
abled and such stuff that pops up in the
logs so the very first thing that we did
we knew that we had to ensure that
certain services were available and we
were white listing though
in a global policy that prevented us
from doing fat fingers and by accident
blocking something or in the event our
automation happened to do something
which was not intended that the services
were kept available oh yeah we had two
web service to secure and obviously we
secured the FTP and we also patched the
service in and one of the other way okay
now I will hand over to say yet who will
explain to you how we can configure the
virtual SRX router so to print our
services either we had to go on the
server in Paget and Benedict will talk
more about it in later slides I was
working on the SRX site of it so what we
did we actually quickly saw some of the
syn floods that we are able to configure
manually to block it on our policies and
then make sure that that's gone and you
are looking into the ping floods but
more on that later we also noticed that
if you want to automate it we probably
want us to resupply at the policy so
that we have a you know workflow that we
can quickly update using salt mechanism
and just don't have to rejigger a lot of
policies with the salt updates so we
moved our global policies or our that
policies or even later on we figure out
we have to put the nat in because we've
gone through an app ID as well as a part
of attack so we created a Google policy
make sure that we have address books at
there that we can add bad IPS to and
then towards our zone and also towards
our TMZ's so initially it was pretty
easy to man we block it and as attack
ramped up we may begin to realize that
we have to get our salt stack up and
running and make sure it works so these
are the masses like probably you already
saw that in the last presentation too so
some of the key fields we parsed on was
RT IDP so these are the syslog messages
we were getting from SRX to one of our
salt master so the
he feels we were passing on was our tid
P so that means it's attack then
sourcing dust and then the severity of
the event there are a couple of fields
in yellow that we probably wanted to
pass on as a future enhancement but
these were the key fields we actually
parsed on so this was that spread our
parser so extract IP was one of the
script that actually went through the
log and parsed through it
lovely you want to add to how we did the
parsing yeah so so basically so one
thing that that was kind of a challenge
was that the data the type of the data
was it would change a lot because we're
being attacked and then the syslog
messages would would change a lot so
basically every time we would get some
different type of event sometimes it
would break the the parsing so we would
have to change that on the go and we
have multiple basically iterations
trying to get that data from the logs
right and at some point and like we
mentioned and that's the reason we
changed the policy we even blocked our
own access to the to the system using
the automated the automation so that was
part of it yeah so you want to talk more
about this part yeah so this is showing
the web interface of this quert tool and
now that we had all the automation up
and running we could fight the attacks
coming in from different IP addresses
but we also noticed when carefully
looking at the events that there were
some attacks that had only very few
packets they have a very low footprint
but they managed to get remote code
execution on one of our servers and we
followed the trace that we found there
and basically it's a but it was a
vulnerability in a tomcat java
application server
that allowed remote code execution on
the machine so we check the server and
we saw that there were some showcase
applications running that were supposed
to have this vulnerability
so the solution basically was to keep
the service available but to shut down
those particular vulnerable applications
and besides all the automation that you
might have in place to fight volumetric
attacks you need to be careful because
there's depending on the software that
you're running many many vulnerabilities
how an attacker can sneak into your
network through the services that you I
are offering and if they are insecure
take over the network so that was our
solution to this thing we'd like to
share some experience with you that we
had while learning sauce tech so
saltstack
we're kind of all programmers and
software guys but a small stack was the
new of us and it's we found it to be a
quite steep learning curve at the
beginning if you start from very scratch
but it's also a very powerful tool we
found it hard to diagnose because mainly
we were just not using it in a very
sophisticated manner we were kind of
naive just doing things and then we
waited a father for the next attack to
come in we could have been more clever
and so we could have prepared some tests
actually with fake or dummy data in
order to test the stuff that we were
automating yeah
as we said we had some errors with the
passing and this broke our automated
policy push but we were able to fix it
later
however pushing the policy to the actual
device was pretty easy
we didn't happen to know any juniper
commands at all we could have done the
same with Cisco or other vendors and
sorts tech price provides a very good
level of abstraction from the actual
hardware being used yeah so what you
also might want to think you need when
you when you're doing something like
this you need to get a complete picture
of what is going on so we noticed that
we did receive logs from the SRX but no
messages from our intrusion detection
and prevention system in in our message
bus so if we could have also received
those messages we may have been fighting
those small volumes targeted attacks on
an automated way so lessons learned
basically if you have data sources make
them all available in one big system so
that you can attach to the data sources
and act accordingly yeah
about the salsa event lock structure
yeah so when you have Rosses log
messages they're kind of unstructured
and they're getting converted in a salt
stack structure and you have to yeah
just to be careful what data you you're
using and if you're doing it correctly
okay I think yeah that's the last slide
is basically what we may want to do
better in the future you can we would
would like to switch over to test-driven
development we would also like to which
we did basically everything that we are
seeing in the logs as very important and
we need to act upon it but the IDS and
also the other systems they had a level
of threat attached to the log messages
so we could have been filtering on those
and only acting upon the high threat
level messages and for example the
medium and low threat message
we could have just forwarded them to an
engineer for manual review if they needs
to be some action taken also not only
wants to say something so let me just
emphasize the in terms of developing the
code because the the software is Evan
even driven right so we whenever we get
an even then we we parse it and take an
action in it that is lowdown development
significantly for us because we would
wait on the D attacks so that's that's
one thing that the the test-driven
development would have made it much
better you know if we written the the
test before and prepare some inputs and
so we could test it more fastly so
that's definitely one of the for me the
biggest lesson you know that's all I
wanted to emphasize anybody want to
mention anything else last few things
like for most of us in this team was it
was our first hackathon so I strongly
recommend or and encourage other people
who haven't done I acted on - I attended
most of us didn't had any background of
doing any other I had a card on so it's
not really you know just go through the
experience and I appreciate jennifer and
nan nan up for arranging it there will
be next one in Vancouver so strongly
encourage everyone to attend one they'll
definitely a bunch of learning for all
for all the skill levels so thank you
thank you Berg thanks dog
and that was and that's the hackathon
recap again thanks to nanog and juniper
networks and let's give them one last
round of applause to all of our
participants as well as our winners
[Applause]