I wanted to thank you all for coming
this is the Nanak 73 hackathon I think
we've been doing these for about two
years now and leaves you know it's now a
regular part of the meeting we tried
different different themes different
approaches each time this is a this is a
new way of doing this over hope we're
hoping everybody has learns a lot and
has a good time my name is Chris I'm
with the program committee thank our
sponsors juniper who are going to be
running the content and the program
itself so thank you very much
everybody from juniper who stepped in to
help us out a few general items if you
haven't gotten them on the Wi-Fi yet
there are two base stations Nanog and
Nanog legacy the difference is one is
secured the other is not the username
and password is simply Nanog nanog if
you have any problems we can try to help
you out get on if you haven't trouble
getting on meals and breaks are going to
be served right outside and you know
feel free to to eat drink in here the
bathrooms are down the hallway near the
elevators starting at 4 p.m. we will
start the Nanna registration that will
be held out in the foyer starting at 4
that goes from 4 p.m. to 6 p.m. so step
out and get your badge if for your
regular nan-oh's registration this is
not your Nana registration this is only
for the hackathon and that is important
because the sunday social event which is
later this evening requires your nanog
badge for entry so if you want to go to
the social make sure you're able to pick
up your badge at some point what during
the the window that the registration
desk is open the general agenda for the
day we're gonna talk we're going to do
the intro and tutorial until about 10:30
we have a we have assigned teams for
this event we want to
you know this is something of a
challenge competition theme so we want
to try to keep the teams balanced if you
don't have a team talk to is Michael
here I don't see Mike okay talk to
Michael he's standing by the door he's
been handling team assignments if you if
there's people you want to work with
come talk to us we can probably manage a
little bit horse-trading
but we do want to try to keep the teams
balanced both in size and skill sets so
keep that in mind
lunch will be 12:30 to 1:30 again served
outside feel free to eat your table we
will have a 3 p.m. break and then we'll
go to 6 p.m. now at 6 p.m. we're going
to hat ask each team to to briefly
present on their on their experience and
and their what they came up with and how
they were able to manage the challenges
just a few minutes per team we've got I
think eight teams or 19 so we'll need to
keep each one short immediately after
the team presentations there will be a
voting link set out and we'll ask you
all to vote for which team you thought
had the best presentation I would like
to ask you not to vote for your own team
otherwise the voting would get pretty
simple and then we'll close we'll have
raffles to give away after this we'll
have a reception here if you your so
you're welcome to stay around for that
or you can head off to the Nanog social
and with that I want to have them hand
the mic to Oliver Sherman from juniper
who's going to be presenting the hack in
itself
good morning guys and we'll keep this
short and hopefully somewhat
entertaining kind of walk through kind
of the premise what we're up to
Dwan will kind of walk through the
actually what we're gonna do today and
kind of give you some intro into the
tools but first and foremost my name is
oliver sherman
I run a specialist team of engineers for
north and south america for juniper what
that means in english is we have a lot
of bright folks they can create things
like hackathons automation optical
expertise etc we'll kind of walk through
the premise of what today is we'll walk
through some things of what it is what
it's not I'll talk about some of the
giveaways and how that's gonna work you
may notice and and some of the slides
you may notice the hashtag JKD sitting
up front that's two numbers automation
mascot if you're interested in one I
have two here we'll see how we give
those away as the day progresses so
here's your first eye test but basically
what this says is this workshop is not
designed to be a Juniper commercial this
is not designed to teach you how to use
any one particular set of tools one of
the things about automation and security
it is now something that has to work
together and it should be an open
ecosystem of tools from a prises
perspective the way you'll be judged
today on teams is first of all forensics
what did you see what what is the red
team trying to do to your to your
systems you need to keep your business
systems up so be able to present on that
did you stop it and if you stopped it
how and we'll talk about a little bit
about the tools that are available to
you today and then if you didn't how
would you stop it and then of course the
best presentation right so if you need
to be able to explain the concept that
you've learned today
so what you should get out of this is
you know an understanding that
automation is a critical part of what we
have to do today we've all heard of
DevOps and DEF set cops and all the
different things that are out there as
well as that you know it's no longer a
it's no longer a separate thing very
much like about 15 years ago
for the most part infrastructure and
security came together this is where all
courts the organization have to come
together and really take a look at this
and make sure
work together who's heard the term dev
SEC ops DevOps net ops okay good because
there's all these new I consider the
marketing terms right Bizet
the years but there's a gentleman Jean
cam you know he said he you know you
really should be if you hear DevOps you
should really be thinking DevOps QA test
InfoSec and early because and that
outlines that everything should kind of
work together and flow together if you
think DevOps you really don't think of
network right you think of software
development you think of QA testing
making sure your codes secure agile all
those you know fun terms but really if
you think about how the network first of
all has been the bottleneck
traditionally in setting up things VMs
have been around for a long time we can
spin up a service like that right and
now you have containers even faster but
the network traditionally hasn't
followed but now the network's starting
to follow however a lot of this stuff is
done out of scripting and scripting is
not going to save the world they're all
a bunch of unique snowflakes that
replace what humans do in a keyboard
today so it's really you know more of a
dis replacing the process as you do it's
not a system so as things move around we
don't necessarily follow or we we have
human errors the other part is is that
from a security standpoint we protect
end-users really well but we also tend
to protect our data centers in the same
way and now we have different clouds
right we don't necessarily want to use
those same methodologies so how do we
change that so you know I I'm a big
believer of 67% of statistics are made
up on the fly but this says 90% of
issues in the network or security flaws
are caused by human error or behavior
that's interesting because it's not only
a fad figured an SNMP password I left
something blank but it's also maybe I'm
trying to do something malicious perhaps
of social engineering but how do I know
that to the nth degree and how can I
control that through heuristics and
different
now especially that all workflows start
to move around you know there is no
cloud somebody else's computer other
things we have to pay attention to but
those workflows end in different places
we have to keep up users expect
everything to always be on so blocking
things as you'll see today might not be
a good thing but you still have to
protect your network so how do you solve
that and of course the sales pitch
everybody's getting calls now that we
have you know the new buzzwords in the
market and the conversation is always
this rip out everything you have buy
from me and will solve all your problems
there's a couple problems with that
first of all for those of us that have
been doing this for a little while
that's never worked the other piece is
is that depending on your market meaning
if you're in education if you're and you
know in different energies and different
technologies or different verticals and
in a market your security stance is
unique to you your targets are unique to
you if you're an oil and gas obviously
there's there's targets there whether
you're education there's targets there
so things may be unique to you secondly
it's really tough to walk up to you know
your financial department say I've got
to spend all this money again to replace
all the stuff I just bought five years
ago it should all work together and
that's where we that's what we're show
today my favorite marketing term sdn but
the concept is good right having a
centralized controller that is able to
move things around and understand the
state of your network and that's kind of
a walk off today who's heard of the
message bus pub pub sub-models okay so
this is the concepts we'll start working
on today - where instead of creating
little unique scripts that solve a
problem looking at it from a message bus
perspective and how this functions and I
kind of put this more into security
context but it can be really be anything
it's when something happens anywhere in
the computer
architecture or actually started this
started in the 50s in cars but you
normalize data coming in you normalize
data coming out so in the in the sense
of provisioning of the device you turn
something on it comes on a network and
then you do something or in this case if
you get a log off of a server or off of
a network device or off of a sim that
says this has happened but then you
create a reaction to that what would
that reaction be so then I'll you start
to automate those types of
functionalities and what this concept
turns into is that whether it's endpoint
security whether it's whatever your
firewall product happens to be whatever
your sandbox technologies has to be
whatever you know your your sim has to
be it'll all work together and you can
take an entire network and turn that
into a firewall now my favorite question
around this is that isn't this nack
well no sort of but now this is tying
everything together to where I'm using
the intelligent to semi network not just
endpoint not just permitting people on
what's change so I can quickly react and
we'll do this in an open source of
course there's lots of different ways we
can we can solve this problem as well
and this started off actually several
years ago for us where we started
working with an event bus architecture
through some interim projects we work a
lot with new college grads and and
interns and this kind of shows the
system where you have network management
you have all your different technologies
working together and either a I'm
subscribing to an event or B I'm
publishing the event and we'll try to
talk about what that means today from an
attack perspective you have
reconnaissance you have infiltration
then you expand and pivot and then you
exploit you'll see different sides of
that today as we kind of turn up the
intensity on what we do and this will be
kind of phase it's going to get more
difficult as a day progresses
so we'll run for about seven hours the
objective will be to keep your business
services running and in this case what
business services will be is this basic
web services HTTP will have a dashboard
to show you know things working things
are not working there will be some
blockers in place because we know in
these environments and it's very simple
just to block this whole range of IPs
where all the attacks are coming from or
everything's whatever we know that's not
real world and Dwan will explain that in
a little more detail as far as oh the
components that are there also we're
here to help so we've worked out the red
team side of it obviously we're the the
red team actually there's two
individuals in the back to be running
all the red team stuff the ones
trustable and so it's Lakshmi but the
general over here was a laptop I don't
know about him so but some of it so they
will change as the day progresses a lot
of the beginning tools were automated so
that just automated scripts running
things against and then eventually we'll
we'll make that more difficult here's
the tools you have to choose from
they'll be a W a firewall layer 3 layer
4 which is a June 4 virtual SRX it's not
to teach you how to use that particular
tool it's just because we have those
handy but we as security onion will use
salt stack so open source tools you can
easily download if you feel like
installing something else feel free to
do that as well and then all the
environments from a scripting
perspective will have Python available
with that I'll give you mr. Dewan hall
there we go I'll prove that the
microphone smarter than I am
hey guys once I just want to cover some
of the rules and tools available and to
you in the hackathon the first one on
each of your tables there's a sheet of
paper that has the lab topology with
actually your exact IP addresses for the
lab I'll call out that we don't want you
to change the root password for the SRX
and that's because the salt minyan has
that configured so if you if you change
the root password you may break the
Avenger of an infrastructure that we're
trying to get you to do the SRX itself
is not under attack your security onion
is not under attack and your remote
access tool wakka moly is not under
attack the servers that are in scope of
the attack are your DMZ web 1 & 2 and
then your trust and tool servers inside
of your environment those are the ones
that are actually in scope for being
under attack
for remote access we're using guacamole
as an Apache service as a client list
remote management
so I'll just escape from the deck for
just a second and show you the guacamole
on the back of your paper on back of
your paper there is a pod number with
and there's a port so here I'm gonna log
in as pod to user 1 all the passwords
are route 1 2 3 we strongly encourage
you to go ahead and change the password
and I'll show you how to do that in just
a second so here I can go to settings
and I can change my password from root 1
2 3 to my own individual password you're
free to change that again strongly
encouraged to do so each user you guys
have to figure out whose user 1 you
through user 6 at inside of your pod
each user will have to RDP sessions one
to your web server two
and wonder your tool server as well as
three SSH sessions that are accessible
from there I'm going to go ahead and
pull up the SRX some of you may or may
not be familiar with you know so I just
want to give you just a quick show on
how you get into did you know show you
the existing configuration hopefully you
can see the percent sign at the bottom
actually you know I cannot I can put it
more in focus but I can't really make it
bigger so every extend it when you get
the percents on you need to type in CLI
to get to the actual CLI and then from
there you want to go to configure here
I'm just gonna do show security policies
you can you can show it to me better the
first place
No
it's okay folks we're professionals okay
that's kind of hard to see so there is a
policy here this policy is really just
to keep alive for your salt minion to
the SRX it says literally in the
description says do not delete so please
don't delete that policy and then we
just have a simple untrust to know this
actually is one I created but a simple
global policy does permit any and it has
IDP turned on so there are some false
positives when you get into security
onion in my colleague
Niraj is going to show you the security
onion tools through Cabana and as well
as the salt stack but there may be some
false positives through ITP so just
because you see an IDP alert doesn't
mean you can block so what I have
configured it on the SRX is a generic
IDP policy with no blocking so no no
inline blocking from IDP perspective is
one of the rules of engagement and then
if you were to make a change you need to
do a commit to actually have the change
take effect inside of the SRX now the
first stage the first stage is to get
you familiar with the tools did you
familiar with the SRX get you familiar
with the security onion etc and then
we're going to ramp it up with have
higher volume the point being is that at
some point it becomes too tedious to
manually go in and configure the
firewall you need to configure that
event-driven infrastructure to react off
with specific logs and automatically
update the firewall that that's the gist
of where we're driving to in addition
we're gonna have a dashboard displaying
the services for each pod whether or not
you block a good IP or a bad IP if
there's an IP address that's behaving
malicious you can block it completely
but you cannot block the good IP
addresses and we'll be testing for both
okay we're gonna be providing a score
for that and then I'll let Nawroz come
and show the security onion but it's a
suite of tools is open freeware the main
one is going to be Cabana which is a GUI
interface for the underline
squeal database the squirrel database
has all the IDS alerts from snort etc
and let me go back to the deck from
current slide so that that should get
you into guacamole I talked about the
dashboard for the stats I talked about
this I'll skip tittle policies if you
want to do the display set this is
exactly what the policy looks like you
can see that it's its permit any a
global policy and it just has IDP on
there so we're we're flagging off ID
alerts but we're not blocking we're
sending those logs both to your salt
master the tool server and we're sending
it to the security onion so there's two
locations for you to be able to find the
logs coming from the SRX talk about the
topology actually the port you're going
to need are 84 43 and port 8080 FTP as
well as the SCP and that's actually
going to be described in the Nanog the
Nano powerpoint that's going to be on
the agenda so the tools provided again
security onion salt stack with
event-driven infrastructure my colleague
is going to come show you the security
onion the big thing is that you can
download your own tools so you have
outbound internet you can download
whatever tools you want to or to your
tool server you can install any tool you
want to but you cannot use IPS to block
in line as long as you're not using IPS
the block in line it's pretty much free
gain for you to download whatever tool
you want to and the user name is going
to be authorized user
aka a user with the password of root one
two three I think I'm gonna skip ahead
and the deck and and show you the rules
of engagement and then I'll have my
colleague Niraj come up and show you the
actual tools themselves
one second there we go we discussed it
but basically you cannot block
legitimate customer traffic
you must have ping available across the
entire infrastructure and then you need
to have HTTP 80 80 80 HTTP and FTP any
questions about the rules of engagement
or how to access your pod environment
okay with that I'll turn it over to
Niraj to give us a quick demo of Cabana
which again is a web interface to the
underlying elastics that search engine
so yeah so I hope you guys can see my
screen so this is the basic overview of
how your security and you look like so
it's actually a pretty detailed UI and
you can see all the logs over here and
on the left you can see that it's alert
or notice alert total number of logs you
can scroll down to the event over here
actually it's not coming up in the in
the projector but actually here you can
see is the number of logs you can click
on the logs particular event and it's
actually across the time line so for
time watch alert game or what happened
you can actually scroll down and dig
deeper into it by clicking onto it and
it will show you the same number of logs
there and if you want to the go back to
the actual number one so actually each
widget has it on script so you have to
click on that to go back from that
perspective it has some decent diagrams
as well to help you analyze better if
you want to filter out some logs you can
do it from here so all the log types
will be shown at the bottom so it's this
RT flow or OSS is a cron job bro HTTP
snort RT IDP whatever so for example if
you want to filter these out says select
this and you will just see it and all
the packets corresponding to that you
can see at the bottom of the tool so you
can if you want to dig deeper inside it
so you can go from here and see the
actual packets and the timestamp so this
is basically the front-end NDB it is
getting all the data from this quill and
squirt database that is running on your
security onion
oh yeah one more thing if you want to
remove the bill to just go to the top
and remove it and it will auto update so
from the right if you can see you can
move to square tool and it is actually
gathering all the data on the back end
so this is a different view here
actually if you want to filter and get
logs corresponding to an IP you can just
go to the filter into the IP there and
you will get the packet captures
corresponding to that and if for example
if I want to see the
you know a packet capture corresponding
to this so I'll just click on this go
there dig deeper click on this and then
here you'll get all sorts of data
related to that package so it basically
what you can see with the why show view
you can see with this UI over here so
yeah so that's pretty much about the
security onion I mean if you guys have
any questions and any trouble try to
accessing the UI we are just at the back
you can come up there and we will tell
you how to do that the second thing I
want to walk you through is the salt
stats ooh basically I've shown you guys
I think that yeah so this is what a
basic infrastructure is that of salt
that is set up already or each of your
ports so basically there is the salt
master that is running on the tool
server there is a salt minion that is
running on the treasurer and that is
connected to the Junos device that is
the V SRX and through the net con so
what happens is that the salt master is
receiving logs and it is subscribing to
message was from the security engine as
well as the B SRX so whenever any event
happens it will publish it to the salt
master bus and actually you can
configure a reactor over here and to
automatically push the policies on the
you knows device so I'll just to walk
you through this actually some of the
command lines so as you can
yeah so being small rises for dependency
so here I have opened all the three
things that you guys might be needing
yeah so this is the red your tools this
is your SRX and this is your truss ever
so these are corresponding shell so
basically if you want to check the
configuration on your device as well so
salt has already configured it you know
already publishing commands to the Junos
device so you can just enter those
commands on your tools and they'll
respond so in case if you want to check
the interfaces or anything other so you
can just enter it here and it will
respond with all the information from
the device so you don't actually have to
go onto the device if you just want to
you know gather some information about
it on the SRX we have already shown some
of the policies yeah so currently there
are three security policies that one is
for this is the old my testing port so
it is only showing the two of the
policies so what actually happens is
that right now your I will just move
again to the slide
so yes so this come on yeah so this is
basically how a salt reactor actually
works so uh so there are right now four
files that I've configured you can
create any number of salt state file
sources files are basically files that
correspond to a particular state of the
device in respect to the salt it's a
salt term I have given couple of links
at the back of the slide deck so if you
want to go through those links you can
understand better how salt works so what
it does it that whenever an event occurs
so it pushes it to the this particular
I've given the path of the file so this
is the reactor it basically uses the
regular expression only the first circle
that you see that reactor triggers the
corresponding file that is named at
react to attack it's available on your
files on your pods that extract some of
the IPS that you want to block or push
corresponding policies for that and that
and that will invokes a policy set file
so basically policy at file is a policy
file which has predefined Juno's
commands so you can modify that as well
as per you need and that pushes the
policy back onto the SRX
so this is the very basic architecture
how the salt reactor works I have given
some of the loopholes so that you guys
have some of the work to do you know
just not everything so in case because
when you want to react to an attack so
every attack has a different message log
so extracting that information or that
IP from the message log will be
different corresponding to each and
every event so for example if you want
to blow Rd you do
eutteum alert for all eutteum logs the
locks will be similar but the
corresponding UTM log you have to
configure this particular reactor at dot
so basically you need to modify to three
lines or write a script that's it yeah
so this is basically the first filed as
I talked about so right now as you can
see that there's a bottom line
University of blue one SR X dot star so
the word star means that whatever events
come from University log 201 SRX it will
invoke the corresponding file on the SRB
reactor reactor
this dress this basically in turn will
this is re-ignited SLS file this will
just take the some of the details from
the message dog that is received for
example the host IP demon or the message
and once it's get that get that it
matches up that which kind of alert is
it so here I have shown you T flow you
can give whatever you want and basically
this file you need to modify you
corresponding to a message logo you have
to accept the data so this is basically
some Python and ginger so very simple
stuff if you are familiar with Python
scripting so that you can do and this is
the last file where you are pushing a
policy on the SRX device so this you can
modify as per you need but it will push
a basic policy corresponding to those
IDs which you extract so you may or may
not want to exclude that yeah so just to
show you a little bit of the command
line I will just skip through this yeah
so as far as the command line goes so we
will show you how the salt message was
looks
so as you can see this is the running
message much the message was or the
message is that I'm really receiving on
my board so basically you can see right
now the RT flow things are coming so
I'll just stop it for a moment so this
thing actually this is the message this
message you will receive corresponding
to every event but the content of
message might differ so from here I'm
extracting actually some of the IPS and
corresponding to that my reactor is
reacting and putting some policies on
the onto the SRX so when you try to you
know create a script or something like
that so actually if you want to check
the logs whether the script ran
successfully or it doesn't so what you
need to do is you need to keep
monitoring or check I mean after some
time what is the state of your salt
master so right now it started and it's
fine but if your script is not right so
you might see the some error message
over here so if you want to debug that
you can take it from this particular
part and you can check whatever you are
getting and maybe modify some of the
syntax as I said in India scripts so
this thing you can do also on the truss
server you might need to you know check
the status of your proxies because salt
master I subscribe to the salt minion
and which is connected to the SRX as I
showed in the first diagram so if you do
this you you will see that there are
proxy ID for the V SRX that we are using
in our infrastructure so always make
sure that you don't do not kill any of
these processes because you might lose
the connectivity yeah one of the things
at this
Oh
and so it
yep so right now I have my reactor
turned off so what I will do is that
I'll just quickly turn it on and give
you a live example that how it's working
it's better yep
and this is basically my reactor file so
I'll just right now you can see that
this is not matching anything else I put
I've just put some random keywords
everywhere so yeah so this regular
expression is the drama start you know
matching to the events that I was
getting on the solver so whenever you
change any configuration just make sure
you restart the salt monster to pick
that confrontation up otherwise it won't
pick it up so I'll just do
and make sure you check its status
sometime its fails so we let that out I
think it's working fine yeah
so once the reactor starts you might
want to see because when reactor starts
you might or it assigned some of the
variables that I have shown you like
demon message and everything so you
might want to check that work what
values are getting assigned to those
variables so for doing that what you
need to do is you can check that in the
log file so you can just go to
and here you'll see all the sort of look
it has it has a lot of logs I mean from
the past as well but yeah you can list
everything yes yeah so here you can see
that these are the values that are
getting assigned to all the variables
that I shown in my second file so you
can modify and get what whatever
variables you want to get yeah so so as
you can see that as soon as I turned on
my reactor so it automatically started
getting some of the IPS and
corresponding to some flow log so it has
pushed the salt block policy on the
device it was not before so this is how
it's triggering going through the files
and pushing a policy back so this is
right now I am pushed it for RT flow
some basic source address these are just
want to be at interlocks but what you
have to do is to equal to or modify some
of the files and make your alerts you
see for which you want to block react to
it so later on if the similar alerts
come it will automatically extract the
IPS and block those particular on the
SRX and in case you have any troubles
accessing it or with any of the issues
I'm Trachta to that you can come to me
directly so just a recap I mean the
workflow is the first attack will be
slow a low-volume IP addresses could you
used to use the tools so what you're
looking for is what type of attack or
what should you be looking for in your
syslog that you want to programmatically
block later and then when we turn up the
volume you'll be able to modify the logs
as Niraj described so the SRX is
automatically updated as attacks come
through and you no longer have to
manually do anything I should call out
that there's there may be some
unnecessary services running on your
servers and or unnecessary permissions
you're free to check those and again how
you defeat these attacks is totally up
to you we've given you a framework if
you want to come up with your own
framework that's fine
the only again the only ask is you
cannot use IPS to block in line okay
then the game would be over in like 20
minutes right so these are kind of old
attacks but that's the the mindset for
you
come up with your own tools you have
unfiltered access to the to the Internet
but you there is access where you cannot
go from pod to pod okay any questions
before we get started yes sir so the
question was is there and waiting access
the environment outside of guacamole
unfortunately there's not it's actually
hosted by the Juniper cloud lab lab
folks and it's very restricted us who
can access those environments any other
questions about the topologies or how
you access before we get started yes
Chris has a question about just a follow
on on your answer you know the you can
download anything to the pods they have
unrestricted access so it's perfectly
okay to write code in your laptop push
up to a github repo and then grab it
down from there get should be running on
all the machines if not you can install
it yes okay I think we'll start the
first stage at the attack do that and
I'll check in in about an hour or so
just to see how you guys are making out
and pause to see what folks saw it in
tool hey guys it's beer-thirty so I'd
like to get politics paused eight and
nine I had the most success in
identifying and quickly blocking
addresses if you guys could start off
with the sharing share with us you know
what you discovered what your
experiences were so if we could get one
representative from each each of you to
come up and
goto of you that's fine you can bring
the whole crew up if you'd like you have
a hdmi let's see if we get the HDMI
you you don't want to put you know I
thought you wanted to present the
forensics
and then the voting is going to be in
the slack Channel so please remember to
vote
try not to vote for yourself yeah make
it a little more fair vote for another
team
Aion say is anyone coming up to do two
presentation or you guys don't want to
get to the beer
you go and you to Mike you can introduce
yourself and so we are the pod 9 group
ocean 6 it's three of us here on the
stage and yeah we'll guide you through
what we did in this hackathon so at the
beginning there was forensics like we
were cooked looking at a this great
system that collects all the locks from
the vs uruk's and from row and from many
many sources and we were overwhelmed by
the amount of data that we saw so we
tried to find the needle in the haystack
and what we immediately noticed were
that there were some syn floods going on
we looked in the Cabana and in the
syslog section and yeah that was quite
easy to mitigate because it was just
some piece SRX we actually had just to
deny the syn floods and as we went
through the process we what we did we
had a global policy configure on the SRX
we added a address box set in there and
so to the boat trust and entrez zone and
we actually kept adding IPS as we detect
those in the address book from using our
salt basically process yeah so we knew
what services we had to offer real
reliably from our DM set and we white
list them and in the beginning and then
we split up basically in two groups one
group focused on the reactor and to get
the automated mitigation running and
another group looked at the individual
hosts like what services were running
what type of OS was it patched and we
found some insecure FTPS that we
immediately secured we also found some
other services and well it's kind of a
treasure trove of full of exploitable
software so we basically shut down
everything that
didn't need we hope that the amount of
information in Cabana like went down but
it wasn't so we were overwhelmed by the
attacks so we had to get the automation
the automated event processing up and
running so yeah we attached to the to
the vo cervix lock messages and looked
for the RTI DP messages and then the
hard part comes the message it says so
nicely structured Jason but what the the
actual log entry is that's just
unstructured text and you have to
extract the IP and I will hand over to
say it again so we had quite a few goes
on you know how do parts of reg X is
initially we thought there's just one
sin that has a source and destination in
it but it had more than one in so we
have to figure out okay how which one is
the most interesting one to grab on and
then in that what's the structure look
like how we can parse the source we can
separate the destination so it has a
source slash port again then but - I
know - greater than sign and the
destination side of it so actually most
of work is done by Aaron and Andrew and
you just got frustrated you know doing
great X's that he walked out he needed
some we're looking at the Reg X's and
then the end of it but yeah so that was
the whole thing that we figure out okay
and then are we actually broke up salt
because we end up doing some rules based
on the destination IP you correctly
realized that roll it back make sure we
are made sure that we are actually
parsing on the source IP and then
restructured our basically set policies
based on that and in the set policies we
are basically again adding it to the
address book bad at IP address book that
we created so yeah so just coming a
little bit pretty much on the same thing
on the even processing and I'm sure
everybody experienced this as well it's
hard to test the code because the events
they come you know
you don't know when they come so
definitely it's a good learning to see
this and also as they've mentioned
before the data is an instructor so that
means the input sometimes we would have
an input that we were not expecting and
that would basically break some things
yeah from the perspective of a software
developer like do it test driven just
dump some logs somewhere that you can
test your stuff but yeah we were right
in the middle of doing things so we
didn't do it and had to ask for some
more attacks yeah this is how these
unstructured text thing is look like the
RTI DP type of messages and here we had
to scrape all the the IP part and then
there was some targeted attack attacks
going on and I first thought hey that
that must be shell-shocked remote code
execution and I looked and I found
nothing so it must be something else
luckily we when we then found this
special thing going on here a
vulnerability in a java struts web
application and I was kind of too fast
in the beginning so I should have locked
into the tomcat web application manager
I saw that there was Tomcat running
there was an old Tomcat five I would
have shut it down immediately but it we
were not allowed to and then there was a
Tomcat 8 on the other web server and I
saw Tomcat 8 that knew that must be
secure it was not it was it allowed
remote code execution and then yeah
basically what we did we there were some
these these faulty web applications that
had the exploitability we just stopped
them and the other web applications were
still available so port 8080 was still
reachable yeah maybe we need to patch
those application in the future and
that's it basically
yeah just also on the parsing side I
think we also parse that red X on what's
a threat level so we also look at what
spread level is medium or high we
definitely just blog down based on the
source IP that I think the future
enhancements we probably want to do was
also looking at that ports and then
doing filters based on the specific
ports but I think it was just way too
long exercise to do if we didn't get to
it there's also some ping floods going
on we decide the signature didn't go pay
enough attention to go through the whole
signature and yeah but probably that was
for the static rules I don't think we
were getting any RTI RTI DP messages for
that so it was just another static
signature that we could have looked at
and configured static filter based on
that thank you thank you party
yeah you must have leave that off now
great job
so just as my colleague just asked me to
a spa date did you got you guys were
picking it up through the automation
which is which were describing to the
parsing right so your your black eye
peas we're getting updated through the
parsing of the logs yeah thank you so
I'll hand over the mic for problem hello
we're team problem gopher
Jason Gabe Brandon look shut Mike I'm
gonna stand up here and move the slides
manually so about two minutes after the
briefing we all looked at each other and
said who knows salt eventually at one
point we were overachieving but we did
spend probably the first hour working
with salt and trying to figure out
exactly how we're supposed to read the
message bus from Salt and what we're
supposed to do with all that information
so we did get into the configuration
files and here's kind of where we ended
up we did start keying in on what was
the big one was the RT IDP and so that
started sending everything over to the
extract IP file once it was there then
it became a matter of troubleshooting
from it's not keying in on the correct
splits and so you had to decide which
way is it going it wasn't picking up who
wrote all this I think it was so so
there's hardly any code really but in
terms of what we had to match it was
pretty much unstructured Texas at the
others indicated the focus was to
effectively get all of the IPS that we
want to match except for a couple of
quite listed either subnets or a piece
so the source net for the 198 dot for
address and of course the one 108
subnet that we didn't want to put a rule
against in addition to that if we move
forward yeah so one of the major
problems that we had for the first one R
was the fact that we were constantly
getting errors in terms of either quotes
or Collins in the unstructured data and
that was a big problem for a long time
so instead of trying to figure out how
to put quotes in a particular format so
that it somehow gets structured
incidentally salt decided to extend the
the ginger plugins that are available
for you to actually deal with this so
the amylin code allowed us to handle
this without worrying about any of the
quotes so as soon as it did that we
start getting the structured well
unstructured data at least in the format
that we need it and after that we didn't
get the initial failures but if you move
forward yeah so the structure was we
already know about this we went through
the basic cycle of trying to figure out
which of the files we want to touch in
the end all we really touched was the
extract IP file the rest of the stuff
just flowed through but instead of
actually starting off with manually
configuring anything on the system as we
mentioned we started off asking whether
we knew slack salt and as we went
through with it as soon as we figure out
what to do with salt it just started
working right so we didn't really have
to put any manual entries
incidentally we goofed around a little
bit with the entries that were getting
created so the initial sort of hints
that were given in the existing code was
taking the entire block along with the
port as a hostname parameter for what we
needed to create in the rules the
problem with that is that you end up
creating multiple rules for the same IP
each time you have a port so in order to
prevent that from happening
initially we decided to put in just the
IP and remove the port so that only one
entry gets created each time the problem
with that was however that as we went
forward
trust in the DMZ or two separate
networks and we were trying to send one
block and basically even though we had
already taken care of one of the IPS on
the trust side each time the DMZ started
reacting later because we added the DMZ
block a little later and therefore when
the attacks started coming in again
incidentally because the IP already
existed on the trust as soon as we try
to send the block of config it would
fail out for the entire set and as a
result the IP wouldn't get updated on
the DMZ so later on when we did get
exploited even though we actually had a
dot 20 address on the trust it was
because the config was actually failing
since we weren't actually creating a
unique entry based on the port number so
we decided to fold back to creating a an
entry based on port numbers as you can
kind of see near the end of the sections
so in the middle we don't have port
numbers because we thought this is
probably the best way to do it we will
have fewer number of entries but in the
end once we added the port numbers at
least the system was kind of secured but
yeah it cost us a little bit of time and
trying to figure out what happened thing
you go forward that's it oh yeah so
that's pretty much it but in the end I
guess as soon as we figured out salt it
was pretty much it for us
we weren't really adding any other code
or trying to add things manually we did
add things manually later on to try and
preserve some of the the port's that we
wanted to preserve for the services as
well as the fact that before we added
the the whitelisted subnets and IPs they
had already been created by salt as
rules so we didn't actually want them as
rules there so we had to then create
permit entries for them above that so
that they would still go through so that
is more of a hack job at the end but it
worked out huh it's a hackathon so
yourself yes so that's pretty much it
thank you sir next pod apartment to come
up and volunteer
how about pod three you guys expressed a
lot of frustration throughout the
process let's hear your take
pod three you're the next contestant
come on down
I'll stand next to you for moral support
I don't have anything to say I'll just
say next
that's the dongle life going on up here
push that in sometimes it's a minor to
push him all the way
all right and that's our presentation
maybe the same thing
okay all right so I don't know that
we're gonna add much but where the rock
came out and reactors so I think we
discovered a lot of the same things that
other people did missing quotes I think
we got that first but maybe we didn't
this issue where it would basically
discover both of the things in the log
message that were split by an arrow
and it would take the second one instead
of the first one which and then we
wanted the first one get rid of the less
than sign this is what our push policy
ended up looking like simple and clean
we did an address book we found the FTP
stuff disabled that this reverse shall
actually I think could have been
interesting to see if we could have
hacked into the system on the other end
of the reverse shell so we thought that
it would be so the way that we had
things running at the end was every time
a packet would or every time an IDP
event would be detected it would try to
configure the SRX that seems like a nice
denial of service attack against
yourself so I thought it'd be good to
separate those to have a queue of IP
addresses and then it'd probably be good
to have a timeout after a certain amount
of time that an IP address is removed on
our to-do list is to learn saltstack and
then it seemed like a squirt had and
Kabana both had a lot of useful
information that would have been nice to
feed into the reactor that's it
[Applause]
all right this table I forgot your pod
number there are many HDMI anyone have a
mini HDMI dongle
there was a comment about the amount of
logs in the security onion and I was
actually on purpose to overload with the
logs you should notice that you actually
were getting IDs logged from both squeal
and the SRX the security onion had a
interface in the DMZ zone and it was
seeing every packet in the in the DMZ so
if you were sending a syslog from the
SRX for one IDP event you actually had
two IDP events and you're in your
security onion to go through all right
how about you just speak to your
experience if you don't you can't show
PowerPoint presentation to so we're we
have a great name we chose team pod 11
that's creative we all agreed upon that
my name is Paul Fischetti and this is
Josh and Tom and it would be great if we
had the PowerPoint presentation because
then you could see that so basically our
goal was to push security policies out
to the Box automate security to deny
access to the DMZ zone and our outcome
was to understand salt I think that's
just like the other table was talking
about was kind of assess what we know
about salt and wasn't much but you know
the learning curve of trying to find out
how to access it and get it to work was
valuable you know how to connect to it
and then you know find the file and
start editing that file and reading code
and I think one of the plans they had
was or we had as a team was you know to
try and start parsing out bad actors and
we had some partial success of going
into the actual juniper and knocking out
some of the IP addresses and then I'm
going to turn it over to somebody else
talk about what they did because these
guys did a lot of
so I kind of went down a different path
mostly at the beginning in connecting to
assaults message bus with Python instead
and just kind of spitting out everything
that we were getting there to give us a
better idea of maybe what we were
looking for once I get the parse down to
something useful since I don't know a
whole lot about salt the thing that came
to mind was using the PI easy library
instead to push the config over to the
SRX but we're at a point where these
guys were making some pretty good
progress within salt - and I didn't want
to tie up the configuration or anything
so I just kind of abandoned that I think
we ran into a lot of the same problems
that some of the other teams did with
our salt stack configuration like it's
extremely frustrating to debug salt
stack when it's like a ginger error
message hidden inside another error
message
but we eventually got it to the point
where it was pushing the IPS to the
routers address book and block lists we
didn't use the global list we were
pushing it separately to the DMZ and the
trust we didn't go with we were just
blocking the IPS not using the port
numbers we did notice there was an issue
where some of the commits we were trying
to do to see him to either be getting
greatly delayed or just outright failing
that's something we'd like to look into
more i we didn't determine what was
causing the issue we were seeing the RT
IDP messages on the bus and we were
seeing it start to attempt to commit but
then it would roll back at some point I
think I think wrap it all up I think
they spent a lot of time trying to you
know create their code and trying to
push the code and get it out and not
being successful we did see the Tomcat
error also first saw the issue with it
but it comes spent a lot of time on the
code so that's it thank you creative
team pod 11 that's right
all right next pod this table
so if their team pot 11 I guess routine
pot six is that fair okay so so like
everybody else here we had enormous
challenges with the salt and actually so
many challenges that we spent all seven
hours on salt we did see some of the
errors coming through using the the
various the tools security onion and but
we were able to really we were spending
a lot of time trying to understand what
salt was what it did and how how to take
the events and actually flush configs
and that was when I had gotten caught up
for all the time so I don't know if you
guys have anything else to add no mic
shy troubleshooting the salt and not
really are you able to identify the
attackers looking through the Cabana or
you just were so focused on the salt try
doing that but then because of the
syntactical errors we were facing in
salt even when we were trying to put
something in the code it took a lot of
time to reflect in the like the results
to see if it was working or not and yeah
we're getting stuck mainly because
you're not able to find if only we knew
about yeah in code
[Laughter]
[Applause]
all right my iptables pod the we have
HDMI if your HDMI or you have a USB see
or display ya know do you have a dongle
for I believe you guys were the only
ones who actually implement IP tables
did anyone else do IP tables on the
server's themselves you guys did one as
well yeah I thought it was pretty clever
it was partly due to an ignorance of
salt stack and other things but we we
divided our team up into two parts and
we had one group that was handling the
yeah the Juniper platform and saw stack
just because their familiarity and the
two of us and another gentleman we were
working on the server's themselves and
looking at patching and things of that
sort
well while the the tasks were being
divided we thought that maybe it was
mandatory to do it manually and then do
salt so what we did on the manual side
we just start looking at IP tables and
trying to protect the services in the
boxes based on just you know the OSI
model and so that's what we we approach
that way and then we once I what's it
squirt is that right yes squirt had a
lot of really cool information and we
were considering how do you maybe
automate your IP tables based on some of
that data how could you use the salt
stack to move the data back and forth
and in in that space but I don't know
anything so at the first beginning over
approach is to understanding the
topology of a whole network instead of
looking at those logs so just look as a
topology we found like which server
supposed to get traffic from which type
of IP range that's why we started as a
part of the team started with the IP
tables let me see
so the trust server and the tools they
are one subnet and another one is a webs
so we have two set of rules for the IP
tables on the truss server and tools we
accept Oh traffic from the local subnet
the trusty resume and also we accept
traffic from the ports used by salt so
that they can communicate between the
master and meanings and also we accept
traffic used by the normal application
like 21 22 23 88 88 so supposing and
also we accept traffic from guacamole
and reject all other traffic and when I
when we configure the trust server IP
tables we mistake the community IP with
another one so that caused all of us
kicked out from the tools and the
instructors have to have to help us to
reset the trust of the two servers and
on the web servers the requirement is
different so we all in configure to
block or other traffic besides those
server service ports we want to allow so
except for IP tables another thing we
did is under as RX so kudos to another
to team members they are gone
so they defined the allowed services and
defines the zone specific rows allowing
only certain services and they say the
order is important have to block but
actors first than a law permitted ports
and then drop all the traffic so we want
to allow the ACL to be done any
dynamically updated from the salt
reactors but because of the format of
the
input or output sing what you couldn't
do that one thing and another sauce is
on the server's you can set up the
threshold of the was that TCP sink or
act those those drops records and also
you can also define the timeout of when
you see a single Direction connection
the default one is like three minutes
actually you can cut it down so during
that DDoS attack maybe that's a way to
go
no we just suffered from what most
companies suffer from we divided up into
teams and most of our team members got
better jobs before we could complete
their their wives were calling and ready
to go so so we had to just regroup every
time a wife called we had to regroup so
and mine was calling but I was told to
stay so I couldn't leave yeah you guys
actually did you actually guys actually
secured a bunch of services that we're
not invulnerable just by doing the IP
tables
did anyone download a tool from off the
internet did anyone install a different
tool nope yeah so I'm not sure where
Oliver got to you want us do the raffle
or the you guys did you guys catch to
vote in slacks
really one thank you for your time and
your participation and there and I know
it's you but it's like when you guys
were troubleshooting the salt the entire
time I always equate troubleshooting to
like playing the slots you always feel
like one more pull or more command it's
going to solve the problem so real quick
while we're waiting on the raffle to
come up first of all I want to thank you
guys we'd spent a lot of time automating
and doing things from a Juniper
perspective and we've been trying to
figure that out but one of the things
that we still have and we floated it
around a little bit today kind of
randomly and kind of not randomly is one
of our J kitties that we've brought here
today does anybody want to adopt a J
kitty the stuffed animal got it okay
we've we've got two volunteers so we'll
take that and now for the Nanog must be
present to win mileage may vary
does anybody not yeah does anybody still
not have access to the slack channel do
we want to put it up on the screen real
quick find
yeah you still had both of yours just
stick that a text window blow it up and
we should be good to go I totally
forgotten about stickies you should be
able to yeah there you go
okay and everyone see that all right
okay so get your votes in and while
we're doing that we will okay what we
want to do first well let's try this one
we've got a set of Star Wars as
dispensers thank Jennifer for those all
right let's see here I can't see number
is 0 1 3 0 9 4 0 1 3 0 9 4 going up
going twice
got it great thank you there you go
thank you
regrets one more of those let's see 0 1
3 0 8 9 0 1 3 0 8 9 anybody
I saw you raise your hand for a second I
think it was just a stretch all right
we'll try one more 0 1 3 0 to 9 at you
awesome great
thank you all right next up a Yeti
cooler with our wonderful sponsors logo
on it 0 1 3 0 9 5 0 Jeff alright thank
you alright okay next up and the
buckyballs now legal to sell in the
United States again zero one three zero
three nine zero one three zero three
nine anybody going once going twice
let's try one more zero one three zero
eight zero that you great thank you
Thanks
okay we have a mini press Oh espresso
machine looks like the arrow presses
answer to espresso I love my era press
it's pretty awesome zero one three zero
three six that's you okay
we'll put you back in
do you not drink coffee okay 0 1 3 0 8 4
got it yeah do you drink coffee
ok great thank you alright
usually we don't do that but all right
on - I've got an echo dot here 0 1 3 0 8
1 okay all right there you go thank you
let's see one more one more echo dot
zero one three zero four zero alright
great thank you four more Bose Soundlink
it's a bluetooth speaker in a rubbery
blue shade 0 1 3 0 9 2 0 1 3 0 9 -
anybody by the way I'll just I'll just
everything 0 1 3 so I'll just read off
the last three shouldn't start should
you realize that a while back it has
been 0 3 2
[Applause]
great thank you all right thank you all
right now we've got the the echo Prime
as it were the big boy see zero three
zero anybody awesome all right thank you
okay two more this is a hand powered
battery powered cell phone charger radio
light any Preppers in the house iPod mp3
player probably Swiss Army knife in
there somewhere
let's see zero one three zero three
seven zero three seven anybody going
once going twice
zero eight three zero eight three
all right there you go thank you thank
you
last item a thinkgeek bag of holding
back a backpack it's got the it's got
the monkey on it so last item zero one
three zero four one anybody going once
going do you have it awesome
great thank you all right that's it for
the raffles what do we have for voting
yet okay okay you know I'll hand the mic
back while you guys finish up the voting
we just wanted to recap the red team
maybe lakhs from you Niraj if you guys
could come up and talk a little bit
about about the exploits in tax and then
we'll hand it over to our hacker here
Zak so our red team consisted of these
three all the traffic that was generated
in the pods came from Lakshmi Niraj and
Zak so so we had divided the attacks
into four stages basically so the first
one was we were trying to do the DDoS so
like the team pointed out we were having
a small attack that's like we were
flooding each ping sorry ping packets
and then we had a syn flood and then in
the next stage we were doing a
reconnaissance attack so we were using
an map as well as nikto to see bottle
ports are open and all the other
exploits and in the third stage we were
like downloading the malware onto the
FTP folder so what we did was we we had
an upload folder which was used by the
FTP and we gave it right permission and
everything so it was constantly
downloading into it so one easy way to
remove that would have been to remove
that entire folder figure out that such
a folder was existing and remove it so
yeah and the last stage was the targeted
targeted attacks at neeraj and Zac we're
doing so I'll hand it over to them
first off I'm sorry it was actually
really fun so I started off doing pretty
noisy attacks if you guys saw anything
to do with open vas in your logs they
were my probes and I was sort of
cheating because I already knew what the
boxes had on them I know the exploits on
the boxes and things like that but I got
to start from a little position of power
so it was actually interesting to see
some of you guys create like an IP
tables rule where you allow there's
certain ports that we had to keep up
right and the problem was that the
surfaces on those ports were still
vulnerable and then you had to use the
automation piece to get the IDP log to
be able to see that there was actually
an injection attack happening on a port
that had to be open right just like a
production application in an environment
and then some of you guys had fun
removing the Tomcat applications
themselves that was awesome that stopped
me from getting in that way but
unfortunately that box had very weak ssh
credentials so I was running brute-force
SSH attacks that were just slowly going
through all the passwords and usernames
and getting in that way the dot 50 box
was your other box that was a little bit
less secure let's just say because it
had hundreds and hundreds of
vulnerabilities on it that one also had
Tomcat vulnerabilities so I was sort of
just attacking all those things and
turning it more from these very noisy
attacks early on to very very targeted
and very quiet attacks and I came around
towards the end and tried to share one
of my attacking IDs some guys thought it
was funny by just blocking that IP two
but I was just switching IPS to other
boxes all the time when I thought I was
being blocked but it's cool to see how
you're reacting and it's also cool to
see that really the only way to stop me
is not to respond at the speed that a
human operator can respond with all
those logs but it has to be something
that's automated because I can slide
very quietly under the radar and
basically exploit a box on a
vulnerability in only you know a very
small amount of packets if you actually
looked at the TCP dumps but yet
thanks for coming playing competing
whatever it is
oh yeah I mean I was supposed to do
targeted attacks as well but most of the
time I spend troubleshooting salt so
what actually I gave you guys whatever
the configurations were on those files
so I tried to make it as simple as
possible and actually the working
configuration and the confusion that is
not working it only had difference of
three lines in the code if you go by
that but it was kind of hard to find out
which three lines and what you actually
want to change so yeah but actually the
first time I agree I learned salt and
created my first reactor so it took me
for us so whoever bought it working with
job well done and whoever understand it
it still pretty awesome I couldn't what
sorry there and just from a topology
perspective we actually only had two
Callie server so Callie is a server that
it downloads has a lot of tools like the
nikto and map etc the open vast you can
install on top of it and then we had a
Metasploit Metasploit and then we had a
Metasploit able server so your server
that was web one and all the vulnerable
VMs that's like a practice server people
who want to practice how to hack that
one was put in there mainly to have a
lot of vulnerabilities create a lot of
noise and then the the targeted attack
was really on that web server to where
we just had that struts vulnerability
that you saw being attacked but all that
traffic was generated really from the
one kali server using ansible locks me
develop some ansible scripts to
constantly change the IP call a new
attack and running all of that traffic
for all your different pods basically
from one server so that's that's the
topology that we had leveraging
automation in the attack as well yeah
but like one tricky could have done is
just put one person on defense and just
said hey all you're gonna do is sit on
this box and you're going to look at
inbound and outbound connections and
when you see like weird established
reverse shells on port four four four
just close that session and just keep
doing it every time it comes back
alright you could just have one person
just playing defense and then all your
other guys looking at Sault I'm looking
at V SRX and the logs so we didn't
really set ground rules like that but it
was a fun day thank you
we already crest we have the grand
finale the showcase showdown the votes
are in
alright votes are in and our top two
teams are problem gopher pot 8th and
ocean 6 pod 9 plus guys stand up alright
awesome
we'll be getting in touch are all are
all of you coming mate attendees for the
main conference as well are there
anybody aren't okay then we don't have
that we're not gonna have that problem
then but during our recap our recap I
believe is Wednesday morning we're going
to be be having the winning teams on
stage to talk a little bit so well get
in touch and work on getting some sides
and slide materials for you guys to
present on Wednesday that is it for the
hackathon thank you everybody thank you
is the the reception set up outside
right is there anything out there okay
okay everything's out there
you