good afternoon everyone thank you all
for
making Nana a beautiful event this is
one of the smoothest Natick events I've
ever seen so special kudos to to Betty
for making this all happen I was still
in kind of like in training mode so
following through watching her but this
is really her her baby
I'd like to before I kind of jump into
closing remarks talk about a program
they have going on of rebranding nanog
and one of the questions is kind of wide
we rebrand as an organization we're
about to invest a significant amount of
time and resources into modernizing our
website and new marketing initiatives so
the thought was to kind of evaluate the
brand and see if it was time for a bit
of a refresh and we were looking for a
modern brand that was simple memorable
timeless and versatile and appropriate
and to that end here's our new nanog
logo you'll be seeing it more and more
kind of things propagate the negative
space in the middle is an end if you
didn't kind of catch that right off the
bat and the lines around talk about
interconnectedness or networking here's
a horizontal format at that logo here we
have a scene against various types of
background one it would be color
grayscale black or white on black here's
an example of it as a business card here
it is we're gonna be branding our events
from here on out so this is what you'll
be seeing as our branding for upcoming
vancouver event t-shirts and which leads
me into talking about our upcoming
website redesign and development this is
just a loose mock-up it's gonna look a
rather different than this but just give
you something for a visual to see how
the brand will be incorporated into the
website so timeline on that currently
we're in the final stage of the
development specs we should have a
pending board approval which will start
developing in August a functional beta
should be available by
Nach 74 and hopefully the new site will
be up and running before the end of 2018
closing remarks so early surgery
comments some have said they liked
informal setting I'm not so scared
anymore which I thought was just a
marvelous comment I fell for the title
it clicked a clickbait title it was very
pleased by the content the survey
remains open until February 20th and
please give your surveys they're very
important to helping us develop the
programs you see here so they're
important for space considerations
depending on how large an event and
what's basically how we need to allocate
space important for content development
and also important for our meeting
format and again it remains open until
Friday July 20th and at the bottom you
see a URL there but I'm sure you all
know how to access that we'd like to
thank our host sponsor coresight and
also like think our connectivity premium
and infrastructure sponsors without your
help we can't make these meetings take
place so again thank you all for your
support yes
in addition in addition thanks to our
meeting sponsors again wonderful efforts
again helps us put on these programs and
as you see Na Nog is growing and again
thank you all so very much for that and
here's the other list
Nanuk statistics so we had over a
thousand attendees here 1071 to be exact
a third of those are members student
registration was about 12 we had 21
speakers from the college of Maine
immersion program we have 12 students
here
female attendance was 12% and we had
over 12 out there sorry 23 countries
represented here at this event our top
organizations were juniper Oracle
Charter NTT DoCoMo Kia Facebook Comcast
and Google organizational descriptions
as typical 40% were service providers
22% vendors and IX and network operators
comprise about 13% special thanks to our
attendees all of you appreciate your
presence and making this a successful
event thank you to our members thank you
to the board of directors and the
committee's and a very special thank you
to Betty Burke
[Applause]
her years of service of this
organization are greatly appreciated and
she will definitely be missed we would
like to thank our sponsors and our staff
both Valerie and day who put a lot of
work into making this a reality
moving forward Valerie and des will be
in kind of new roles they will be taking
over making these meetings happen and
take place and Valerie would be focused
on helping deliver the content that you
see at these meetings we'd like to give
a special thanks to Lisa Volpe for
making the social couple work out as
well excuse me I'm Miller public
relations clarity line speed Cascadian
cirrus the ladies @h sorry Harrison
group was trying to read out the
initials Michele Allison and Kelsey save
the dates October 1st through 3rd we'll
be in Vancouver
February 18th through the 20th and 2019
we'll be in San Francisco and in June
10th through 12th we will be in
Washington DC our host sponsors will be
in tech savy digital reality and edge
micro also Nanog on the road September
21st will be in Washington DC November
12th will be in Toronto Canada the
conference timeline for this important
dates to remember
registration and room block will begin
on Monday July 9th call for
presentations will be from starting on
Monday July 9th as well the meeting
agenda will be published on Monday
September 17th hotel room block closures
will take place on September 7th on site
registration will be Sunday September
30th and lightning talks admissions
abstracts will be on September 30th as
well I'll see you all in Vancouver just
some things to remember about Vancouver
the hackathon will take place on the
30th the conference is from the 1st of
the 3rd
the host pest sponsors tech-savvy the
venue is the Hyatt Regency in Vancouver
it will be followed by air in 42 and
registration will open again mid July
2018 so with that thank you and see you
all in Vancouver
[Applause]
you