so thanks for the introduction I'm Nika
and I'm going
can you please shut the clock another
the Tigers roaming hi I'm Anita and
today I'm going to present a walk on how
to protect NTP with Horus 70 P is a
network time protocol and would
synchronize time cross computer systems
over the Internet many application of
malaria such as Taylor certificates DNS
even in a sec HTTP Cowboys are many
financial applications so for example
when we access a a web site our browser
check that the server he communicated
with actually hosts this website so in
order to do so he looked at certificates
and this is their certificate of
information and they experience in a
date
so in our day our priority to check it
in age to know what the time is and
wrong time in our browser can lead us to
accept old and may be compromised
certificates so now that you know how
major this protocol is let's talk about
about the NTP architecture so in a
nutshell NTP is client-server
architecture consists of two main
processes for process and selection
process in the pub process the client
here the client sends an type your query
still three or more NTP servers and get
NTP responses in the selection process
the best time samples are selected and
the client update his clock accordingly
however an TPD current MTB is highly
vulnerable to time shifting in this
especially made by man-in-the-middle
attack here men in the middle is
an attacker who controls the section
between the client and at least one of
the NTP servers and contemporary with
the NTP responses and then make it
believe that his symbol is the best one
and we should use it in order to update
our client talk he can also try and try
to change our time by simply dropping or
delaying packets to or from the servers
that is why encryption and
authentication are not sufficient and
previously studied even consider
man-in-the-middle it's too strong for it
to be but why doesn't it be so
vulnerable to my name in runaway as we
said before MTP is consists of two
processes post process and selection
process in the pool process we rely only
a small number of NTP servers form a
certain pool and they are often DNS
cache which means that the attacker only
needs management capabilities with
respect of few NTP servers in order to
maintain his attack and the selection
process algorithms assume that in
currency are rare and that the NTP
responses are well distributed around
the UTC the correct time and therefore
powerful and sophisticated man in the
middle attack here can bypass this
algorithm and he's beyond the scope of
traditional treatments in order to face
this limitation and we suggest a
modified entry client called
Honus with the following characteristics
it has probable security we can bound
the probability of successful time shift
we can attack even facing many me in the
middle of attacker
it has backward capability since there
is no need to change anything in the
server in the NTP service I'll only
limited software needed in the client
side and it had only local cache and
communication overhead since eventually
we query only few NTP servers so in
order to prove how honest they help to
protect NTP we need to define our
treatment on so we assume that the
attacker have full control of a large
function of NTP servers
sake Warner and we assume that he is
capable
of both deciding the content of an tepee
and the time when it's going to arrive
today client and of course we assume
that his malicious and try to shift the
time clock as much as possible
so how course is built first of all we
rely on many NTP servers
we generate a large server pool hundreds
of several times in order to raise the
threshold needed by their attacker on
the other side requiring only a few
servers that are randomly chosen in
every update we are talking about tens
of them in order to avoid overloading
NTP servers and family we use small
filtering in order to remove outliers
and make it hard today when in the
middle to contaminate the chosen time
samples so informally what the kunais
client do in order to your abilities
clock is that out of hundreds of servers
tens are choosing in random we ordered
them from low to high corn into their
value and then we drop deep from each
side take a look in the remaining cells
so focusing on the remaining set we ask
ourself to question we have two
conditions the first one is rather than
remaining samples are close to each
other and the other one is rather than
their average is close today science
cook if these both conditions are
satisfied then where we use their
average as the new clients time
otherwise if you fail to try again and
again out of hundreds of servers tens
are chosen randomly and we ordered them
from low to high and drop deforms I take
a look at the remaining set and our two
conditions
if you fail we try again and again and
again I told you we felt came times and
then we move to the panic mode where we
sample all the server's dropped outliers
and take their average as the new
clients clock
so first let us and let me present our
security guarantees and then we will I
will present our security analysis so
essentially what we show in our paper is
that even under extreme scenario
shifting time at the corners client its
by at least 100 millisecond from the UTC
will take the attack here at least 22
years in expectation this is when we
consider server pool of 500 servers but
seventh of whom are fully controlled by
the attacker
we also assume that fifteen servers are
all right and that the good samples are
within 23 5 millisecond from the UTC and
these are parameters that we derived
from experience that we conducted on
Amazon servers over 100 of servers was
in Europe and in the US and here we see
that the benefit of using over there
acorn tend to be as a function of the
number of servers that there are updates
and the ratio the P the ratio of the
malicious server in the pool
notice that the y-axis is a log scale
which means that the improvement is
exponential so for example if we will
take the lesson area where we have
approved 500 servers and seven so for my
fully controlled by the purple line we
can see that even using 8 servers we can
improve the content EP by a factor of
100 and I want I want you to present the
security analysis so in order to do so
we have to consider all the scenarios
that can happen and see how furnace is
handling them so as you remember out of
hundreds of servers we randomly choose M
terms of them and then we job D from
each side so the tsunamis are going to
depend on the number of militia service
that work worried and so the first time
is when we have the good samples the
good samples are and we noted in yellow
and general and malicious servers or
samples and are denoted in is a red
demon so there personally is when we
have more than two examples and less
than a - the bed samples so we have two
options the first is when an only
malicious servers remain in our we
remain except after we deform each side
however since we have more than two
examples we have at least one good
example in each side of the remaining
set which means that they are bounded by
good samples and the great samples are
occurring to our assumption and
Amazon is only go away I'm again $0.25
mosa confirmed at you to say which means
that the remaining set is also and 25
more seconds from the UTC Omega way and
their average that we used in order to
update our clock is Omega way from D to
C so it's bonded the second option is
what we have at least one good sample in
our remaining set and according to our
first condition all the examples in the
remaini said should be close to each
other which means that we have at least
one good sample which is omega T UTC
there are the other one are close to it
and then their effort should be also
close to the UTC and this is why we say
that these attacks strategies are
ineffective
another attack strategy won't be at you
a time-shifter o'clock but you make us
do sampling again and again and again
and I will discuss it later the second
scenario is opposite one is when we have
when the number of and good sample is
equal or less than the and the number of
malicious samples is
more or less or equal to a minus D so in
the worst case we have only malicious
sample you know remaining set and that
they're not bounded by a good sample
however according to our second giving
condition and their average that we use
in order to update our clock should be
close to the current a client flow which
means that we basically bound the the
maximal she that Corner's loves whatever
the probability of this scenario that we
have more than or equal to Emily's the
malicious server is extremely low since
it require malicious server to be much
higher rate than the rate in the
population and of course probability of
repeated shift is negligible therefore a
significant time shift here is
practically infeasible the second
strategy that I mentioned before was not
try to shift the client time but try to
cause him sample again and again and
again and move to panic mode where we
will all the servers are queried and may
be causing a multiple panic mode for
multiples whole server server can make
denial of service attack over the NTP
servers so in this scenario the attacker
need this the malicious server and at
least one while she's serving in our
remaining sets in order to violence for
example the first condition the first
connection a was that all the samples in
our memory in our remaining set are
close to each other so you will just
pick a sample time sample that is far
away however we saw that even if we set
a low panic threshold say a caco3 which
means that we go to panic mode after
three terms the probability of success
here is negligible
Karen will take the name decades in
order to force us to to achieve this
panic mode in another case the especial
case that we and want to add before I go
it said where the pool of available
servers is small say three so then in
this case one will sample all the pool
each time and then we can achieve and
deterministic security guarantees this
is important mostly for PTP security so
to conclude an TP is very vulnerable to
time shifting context especially made by
man-in-the-middle attack here since it
wasn't designed to to protect against a
teaching men in the middle attack here
so in the current version of ntp
attacker who controls even few servers
can shift the clients time and my PT
digital shift for a long time and
therefore we present a modified ntp
course with support provable security
even facing thank you it has backward
probability since there is no need to
change anything in the server side on
the in client side and we are talking
about really small software changes and
we had only low computational in
communication overhead here since we
prairie only few servers and these are
topic for our further research and maybe
we can achieve terrible title borne
pounds and my what can we achieve if we
wait the server according to their
reputation and can we benefit something
from slight changes in the server side
also and of course we would like to
extend commerce to other in time
synchronization protocol such as PDP and
that's it this is a link to our full
paper and I can take question on
questions now thank you
okay okay thank you very much
[Applause]