all right okay my name is Alan Carr
Sharma from Comcast
I'm datacenter architect they are
responsible for design and strategy for
national regional and local data centers
I would also like to introduce Tony P
Tony are you around over there so Tony
contributed a lot to this and Tony is
also author and editor of the new data
center routing protocol routing in
factories rift dealing a lot with IETF
on the topic and thank you Tony for
taking time to come out here and know
he'll be happy to answer any of the
questions so that's its quick background
on like why why routing in fat raise
what are we trying to do why we are here
the motivation behind it and you know
why why is there a need for something
else so little background few years ago
some of the major companies and Comcast
as well
due to the complexity is the scalability
issues on a GPS Isis and OSPF
made a move to the BGP based data
centers we did it very well it was great
for the time we made Network much better
the stability in the network the
reliability we came pretty far with that
but over time as things evolved and I
know most of the network guys now you
know it in production environment keep
we keep building things on top of you
know what we have built this like
stacking building a tower putting
another box another one another one and
when you get to the top it's not if you
need to change the foundation it's not
easy to go back and retrofit I mean
these brownfield production environments
are
rigid and oftentimes things come in as
oh we just need this this is temporary
and we know how long those temporary
things stay in the network most likely
until the end of life or until it breaks
so we started building PDP we went you
know following the best practices but as
we move forward we realize well this is
protocol as the foundation built for
different purposes guess everyone knows
what bgp was built for but as engineers
we got creative and we were able to fit
it in data centers and it was good for
the time so we'll go through some
motivations how things evolved in that
work at Comcast and think talking with
others I hear the same stories so we'll
go through those challenges and what
rift offers us we'll go through that and
its new so we hear well why is there
need for new we can hack BGP we can do
this yes we can but it reminds the story
of one of my friend Dominick who had
with a rich guy but he has old car and
he sees a awesome new feature came out
like GPS came out said oh you know what
I can fit I can buy that off the shelf
and I can fit it in my - you know
dashboard or you know wherever the GPS
goes why do I need you know my cars as
good as new
so we'll go through those things as well
let's let's take a quick look so get
started in the slides this is from when
I started networking I wasn't there at
time off you know ARPANET DARPA net when
I started it was networking and over
time I realized we have you know ipv4
issues and people started using that and
we made it almost we made it networking
we went further further and yes we all
came to the point where we see wall is
too much not and
it doesn't work and came out to almost
where it's kind of not working and there
you go well we need to make a switch we
need to go to ipv6 now you need
something new so let's get into the BGP
stuff so I'll IFC 79 38 what about four
years ago BGP data centers major
companies built it so here's the typical
topology leave spine architecture we're
at the top of rack leaf device then some
aggregation layer super aggregation in a
bunch of different aggregation levels
and the typical design was ok from the
north we are sending default down and
from the south to north it's sending the
small specific routes at the end result
of that was if I log in to my leaf
device and if I do show IP route I see
only one route there's only one default
there's not the troubleshooting is much
easier there's not much state so that so
that was good in the design again the
leaf devices they are all running same
way as number there are different
choices or we chose to run same es
because we didn't want routing from one
leaf to reach to the other one those
routes because the BGP is same as no
prevention mechanism and so every layer
is running its own es and there is a
small comment on the left side where it
says policy ACL we'll get to that later
but just wanted to make comment so the
policies the access control was done on
the leaf devices so the this worked
great but something we realized if we
follow the typical class architecture
the top devices if they lose a
northbound can
Dimity which was the top in our topology
going to back born we we lose the
inventor each ability over the loopback
IP so for for certain people the mindset
was well this is not a problem because
it's not impacting your production
traffic this is all for management and
your your production is not impacted but
if you look from operations perspective
or for any other inbound telemetry or
any other polling or any other
management stuff the device is not
reachable so it's it's a problem for ops
now again you can fix it by breaking the
class design by creating east-west links
running ibgp and certain things so that
that's kind of a small problem but
something you know against the pattern
but that's ok that did bother much and
we keep moving now over time we needed
to build some centralized services some
service training kind of stuff in
decentralized zones quick example is
load balancer and we we took some
central position in the network topology
created those services and that is when
we started feeling ok but again think
things what these are all mostly source
90 devices so there tree routing it was
working fine but over another year now
we ran into other issues the policies on
those top-of-rack boxes they people had
different issues one example for what we
went through was those top-of-rack have
limited DCAM and the AC else just went
you know up to the ceiling we could not
have AC else in security requirements
while we need some stateful inspection
so we had to have something like this
which is kind of it's the same services
own but it
grew bigger with like some policy
devices in the middle in those central
zone and you see those a CL and the
policies are not their own leaf anymore
so the traffic is all passing through
those central policy enforcement points
now what that brought is not only the
traffic the routing has to all the
routes have to pass through that central
zone that means the routes coming from
north following bdp go down to that
central zone and come back up and then
go back to the leaf again so that's
where we ran into okay
you have route coming down from one
device in going back up just for
clarification we used VRS so the
internal and external side of that it's
coming in one BRF and going back in the
other one so now when the BGP route came
from s number XYZ and loop back or go
back to the same device XYZ it's not
accepted there so again all this stuff
in testings we found now we need to fix
that
so again engineers came up with okay how
about you know BGP gives us all the
knobs to tweak it to hack it and we went
okay let's do allow SN and no we can get
the same routes back in so we we tried
that in lab again if you do that you
break the loop prevention some basic BGP
stuff and by by doing that now you have
all the routes all over the place so we
said ok b DP also gives us the filtering
so we go create route maps do some
policies build route filtering there but
then at that point you need it on every
single device a I want to accept default
and I
want to accept those it's all static
configuration all over the place and yes
it can be automated but it's in my
opinion it's no different than just
having static routing
I mean you are programming every single
route what you want where by policies
and at the same time when I talk to
dominate he was like oh I see new cars
came out with Bluetooth systems so he
went outside he bought the Bluetooth and
he hooked it up in his car and he's like
oh now my car has blue to it we are
fixing things
so with allow SN and the policies again
it's not clean so what we came up is
okay the problem is the air spot the BGP
carries that path information which is
breaking you know these same routes
accepted in you know when it's going
back in the same layer so how about we
just remove the path information how
about we erase it so that kind of same
good because again there are so many
options here so we hacked into BGP and
we said ok we raise clear a s path so
there's no path history at certain
points and we start fresh from that
point all the way until it's needed to
the next level so and that's where
pretty much we are today is operating
fine it's working and when I talk to
Dominic back he says oh you know what
these cars have backup cameras and I'm
gonna buy that any fix backup Cambron so
his car is still great so going into so
here it kind of highlights the flow that
I just talked about for the how the
routing is working so if we look from
the top there's default down going
through air Slayer going to the services
zone and coming back in the VR f2s
because those are logical links back to
our service spine and going to top of
rack so here you could easily see the
yes path on the left side in those
numbers 6500 1 2 2 2 4 5 back to 2 & 3
so some repetitions and that's where we
had to do allow a sin and clearly as bad
then as we moved on further this these
are the problems where we are today my
software group they say oh I need I need
your whole link state I need to know
which links are up which are down so I
you got to send me links it I don't have
links state their i I mean how do I do
it then do I run another IDP now just
for the link state anyway so that's one
of the missing feature that I don't have
hack in BGP today so going through all
those things know one after other it's
like well we are working you know it's
kind of anti pattern for what we need in
data centers and the leaf spine class
architecture is so widely deployed it's
unique and it's deterministic why not
build something that really works for
that what fits for that architecture so
that's where the rift came up just to
summarize the points what we talked as
the problems the issues with loopback
reach ability the yes path we raise it
allow es in setting policies there's no
link state this configuration is all yes
you can automate but typically it's a
static conveying define neighbors define
all kind of statements and so in the end
what we are trying to do is we are
trying to take this ebgp or some
exterior protocol and behave it make it
behave like IDP and we say it works so
this is kind of how we make it work it's
it's so close to where we are at a point
well
[Music]
anyway just a description of config so
on my device that I have thousands of
lines of BGP config whether it's coming
through some automation or some human
doing it or copy/paste whatever but
there are thousands of lines of config
whereas if we do something new we have
option to build it ground up and what we
have in routing in factories it could be
as simple as one statement and it does
things for the for your topology so what
is rift
routing in factories I was asking my
vendors to hey can you do these things
in BGP can you make some extensions or
those modifications work for almost
three years and when we sat down
together like well so those changes are
too many and if you do all of that then
it's not behaving like BGP anyway with
making neighbors coming up like OSPF and
we kept going on and then I met Tony and
we shared pretty similar mindset yeah
you know what you know it's time to know
reboot it's time to have something
better so a quick introduction on that
rift is open standard draft in ITF
there's a formal working group working
on it it's big for sauce architecture
the the basic points are that leaf spine
is pretty deterministic architecture so
we can make certain assumptions certain
enhancements modifications to have a
protocol which is built or well-suited
just for that rather than having other
ones which are which are great they are
great for they work in all kind of
topologies regular ones - like internet
appositive so
let's go through some of the high-level
points and I was told to keep the
session pretty high-level because I mean
if you need more details the specs are
out there on ITF working group document
you can read that and any questions for
in-depth stuff we can we can take that
any later and Tony is here as well so
before we do something new it's like
what what's the difference why do I need
it so we'll pick some of these the
interesting ones I found but as a
summary it's we took ok BTB is great and
all the IDPs are great so why don't we
take the best of both worlds we took the
best from distance vector protocols and
best from the link-state and we made a
hybrid so the way it works is it talks
distance vector down and link state up
we talk best from both of those and at
the end result we have it minimizes the
routing State on any single guards the
pattern we saw that we wanted that we
made bgp to work was through some
policies we send default down and
specific north that routing in factory
does by default that's the natural
behavior it does what so instead of
tweaking something it's coming naturally
here the it has the concept of topology
awareness because the class architecture
of the leaf spine is it's deterministic
topology so based on like it's always
going to be in that kind of topology
certain assumptions could be made and
optimizations could be added so smart
disaggregation we will go through that
in slides unequal cost multipathing
will go through that
load balancing on some failure of
northbound nodes which are not directly
connected to you the route reflections
blood reduction autonomous will go
through those so we will save time here
and other common features which are not
in detail described here but they are
all out there and I made these slides a
couple of weeks ago so things are moving
fast there is new draft that came out on
June 21 certain other things added but
the common things that you would expect
are there and if there are some more
things anyone you know feel free to
contribute this open standard drop so ok
taking a quick look at the class the
topology so this is how it looks like
the bottom there those racks of servers
with top of rack switches on them so
every layer has some kind of level of
sign and this is just a number so for
this purpose I'm taking here as zero
next level spine or whatever you call it
level 1 next some aggregation layer
level 2
next level 3 so that level brings the
concept of topology awareness where I
said in my whole irrigation layers so we
will get to the levels again in towards
the autonomous routing concept but I I
took some of the simple and
distinguishing features here so one of
the things enhancement that was added is
smart disaggregation so if we look here
on the top diagram we are getting
default down from spine 1 & 2 2 switch 1
& 2 so if one switch 1
Network Ten dot X something has to send
to one line to something it's going to
send half half to both the spines so
that's that's this steady state if the
link is shown in the lower diagram if
that link goes down typically what we
have today we will still keep sending
because we are still receiving default
that's how we are operating with our BGP
today but with the rift it knows ok that
link went down it would do smart
disaggregation so switch one knows well
spine one knows spine - link went down
spine one will send more specific routes
one line - something to switch one so
now if switch one has something to send
out two one nine two it will never send
to spine two for everything else it were
to still keep the load sharing the route
reflection concept so the biggest thing
that I heard from most of the engineers
around well in some engineers who have
been out there for more than 20 25 years
hard to get like oh so what is I don't
have a stress link I don't have you know
cross links there
so typically like people when they were
making diagrams they always had
interconnection but in the class
architecture we don't have that and it's
not really required but then how do we
get the state across devices in the same
layer so we added a route reflection
mechanism real simple here so the layer
in the middle spines they send their
adjacency information to the leaf
devices and they reflect it back north
to one layer of
so because of that route reflection
mechanism now we have same link state
information on the same layer of devices
otherwise we would have to have
east-west links now this also helps with
the first problem that we brought up the
loopback reach ability issue again it's
a minor issue but if you lose the
northbound links the local by piece from
that device low back or anything else
could be reflected back from south and
you have that reach ability from the
south
flirting reduction is it's safe it's
kind of a hot topic and one of the major
challenges why people wanted to move
from OSPF or is is to be DP to have
because they are in large-scale networks
it's flooding everywhere and it's too
much it's too chatty so we this is
recent tradition from different vendors
and different people coming together
contributing and very elegant loop very
elegant third reduction mechanism so at
high level leave one at the bottom will
choose its starting leader in the upper
layer the way it chooses or is based on
the level of connectivity it knows about
the north box and running a hash through
it into and it figure and it says ok you
whichever box it could be in this
diagram it shows spine1 as the flooding
leader so spine1 will send those updates
to northbound
and there's also second one for
redundancy spine - is the backup setting
leader so you have two two updates going
for you know for each prefix now that
the elegant series is not always all the
nodes are not going to choose the same
flirting leader it's kind of distributed
some leaf - or some other device will
meet you someone else so it's just
distributed all over the fabric so
you're not running just one device as
your designated router and updates going
just through that running that link as
hard or even if it's large number of
updates it can impact your convergence
times as well the bandwidth balancing
again everyone wants to use links
efficiently and oh we use our length
ninety percent you utilize it's not one
is ten percent other one is eighty
percent so there's some inherent
bandwidth based balancing capabilities
again high-level quick example this is
this is a kind of real-life example here
from the top aggregation box it's
getting default from upstream and it's
it's a air so one advertising default
down so typically in steady-state you
will get 50 percent traffic on one fifty
percent on two but if we lose the link
as shown here from here so onto the
backbone typically you would still keep
getting 50 50 however you have reduced
capacity but here we can it adjusts the
cost the bandwidth or justice distance
saying okay I have half of the bandwidth
so that information passed down now
the spine layer as one two three four
they they will adjust how much traffic
they can send north they will send 2/3
to a s or two which has double D
bandwidth and 1/3 to air so one so
that's the wave weighted ICMP behavior
some balancing on the fabric now
autonomous routing just because okay and
I say I'm seeing the time limited so in
autonomous routing each node can figure
out what its role in the fabric is where
what level it is that it can self
discover that and start routing by
itself the only thing you need is a seed
device which can be at the top here and
based on that seed it tells the lower
level lower levels received multiple
advertisements of levels and say okay I
receive those many values so I must be
this and it automatically figures it out
it does not need any GTP or any kind of
controller to push the config and tell
so there's it's not automated it's just
self discovered so fine we have all that
so what now what do we do so we move
from this to that just a quick quick
summary here so again it's open standard
you know everyone is wherever interest
rate who is running leaf spine you know
bring your problems feel free to
contribute this encouraged
specs are completely open there's
working group working on it things are
going fast very well some new drafts are
showing up for yang and
other necessary stuff major vendors are
on board we have Cisco and juniper
working on it and there's also a binary
package available for download and the
next IETF also has hackathon organized
there so all right any questions