hi my name is Steve Ulrich I'm with
Juniper Networks get right into it the
intent behind this talk is to really
encourage us to start having practical
operations or into discussions around
segment routing I think we've all for
the last six years gone through a number
of the breathless marketing presentation
that extol the wonders and virtues of
segment routing how it's going to make
our lives easier how it's going to
dramatically reduce the costs and
improve the efficiencies of everything
this conversation is a little bit
different this is a talk about some of
the things that we don't talk about when
we talk about segment routing typically
the you know when we're waxing poetic
about what segments routing is going to
do for us I want to point out I'm not
going to be bashing segment routing I
think the segment route is an incredibly
important technology for us to move
things forward and some of the things
that we're talking about here that
nothing is intractable this is just a
lot of hard work and we're gonna have to
start talking about this we're still
working through a lot of the issues and
I'm just gonna surface some of the
issues in the discussion today not
posing you know solutions for any of
these necessarily you know point out
some of the relative trade-offs for the
technologies that are under active
development and some of the practical
deployment considerations that were
grappling with as we start foraging
forward with segment routing it's going
to take some time there's gonna be some
bruising there's probably gonna be some
scarring and for those of you who are
anxious to get to the peering buffer you
know break for beer if you're looking to
simply replace LVP you can probably skip
straight to the end the folks I spend
most of my time with are in curtain you
know interested in fleeing their packets
in a specific direction and doing
something fairly stringent with the
traffic and steering around the network
so if you're looking to replace LDP most
of this probably doesn't apply to you
you might still find it interesting so a
brief overview of what I'm gonna be
talking about here I'll do like a three
slide review of segment routing I'm
going to talk about kind of the obvious
things that
cause a knee-jerk reaction or gag reflex
when we talk about segment routing a
label management RSVP and SR coexistence
some of the less obvious things when
we're talking about segment routing the
care and feeding of the controllers the
ubiquitous controller that will solve a
lot of our problems and that we're going
to be increasingly dependent upon in an
SRT environment a little bit of
discussion around srte protocols there's
a number of them to choose from what are
their relative merits of those a little
bit of discussion around traffic
protection and the state of things there
and effectively a call to action for
your more discussion around what's going
on with segment routing from a practical
deployment perspective so segment
routing types and label spaces and I'll
use the term segment CID interchangeably
apologies in advance for that there's
effectively four kinds of segments or
SIDS that I'm going to talk about today
one is the adjacency Sid you know that's
the interface specific label what's what
we tell you know typically see in our
IEP today the next one is the prefix SID
you might hear me interchangeably refer
to that as a node SID that represents
the least cost path to a particular
prefix in the network node SIDS or
special kind of prefix said they're
commonly bound to a loopback interface
these have domain wide significance so
this is kind of a you can think of it as
a consistent pointer or you know a
consistent destination inside the
network that everybody has the ability
to forward traffic to at the data plane
to less commonly discussed but you know
important to Sid types here anycast SIDS
where it's in any caste announcement of
the same label for a prefix binding you
know this represents the IGP least cost
path to a non-unique announcements in
the network and a binding SID and I'm
kind of doing a binding said a little
bit of a disservice by saying it you
know represents a tunnel binding SID is
a very useful tool in segment routing
from a traffic engineering perspective
and that it allows us to define you know
maybe a number of SIDS us maybe a Sid
list it may be a number of Sid lists in
order to define a path that we're
to bind traffic to if you can think of
it as kind of search and replace in the
path for segment routed traffic a little
bit of a few comments about segment ID
space SIDS are not labels they
practically manifest themselves in the
network as labels but they're encoded or
carried in labels acid' especially in
the prefix a domain is effectively the
announcement of a base or an index a
base or an IG be a label range and an
index into that into that label range
domain wide SIDS are you know a flooded
into the IGP so everybody understands
what they are they're allocated very
much like they are like you'd allocate a
1918 address space today this
announcement of a block plus an index
the block itself is you'll hear it
referred to as the sRGB for the segment
routing global block the global label
that everybody is interested in the
network is effectively the sRGB base
value plus the index for that node I'll
do a quick run through two forwarding
scenarios across the bottom of going
from router for to router seven on the
right we have a label stack here on the
left four presentations router four on
each one of these segments we're going
to pop and forward so router four is
presented with label 445 it pops that
forwards label stack with 56 and 67 out
the interface associated with label 45
it gets to router five pops the label
forward 67 67 is associated with the
penultimate hop for router seven we pop
that we forward the raw IP frame out to
router seven in the top portion of this
topology will demonstrate a little bit
of the expansion of the sRGB and index
behavior the index is or the base is
indicated here in the square brackets if
you look at you know router one to
router seven the shortest cause path to
that is via router to the index four
router 7 is 7 but router want
I'm sorry router 2 expects to receive a
label within its particular base and is
receiving a label four five Oh
seven the process is repeated at at
router three penultimate hop hopping
takes place and we present a a raw IP
packet to router seven a little bit
about any caste SIDS and binding SIDS
the diagrams at the bottom are largely
you know for illustration purposes any
caste SIDS again have a domain wide
significance this is a set of nodes that
use a non uniquely announced prefix the
forwarding choices made via the IGP best
cost at least cost path to to that
destination ecmp may be used for
forwarding we commonly use any caste
SIDS to represent a geographically close
set of nodes you might think of it as
core routers for a particular metro this
also enables us to utilize load
balancing and it provides redundancy in
the network binding SIDS this search and
replace for stuff at the data plane
these have no local cific significance
they're bound to other sr paths this may
be multiple segment lists or said Sid
Sid lists from a data playing
perspective we pop that that label and
we we forward it by imposing the
forwarding stack for the path that we
wanted to define we may actually specify
multiple paths and do things like way to
dcmp across for traffic presenting with
that particular binding sid so I'll
segue to the obvious stuff the stuff
that you people pay attention to when
they start to think about segment
routing deployment from a global label
space perspective and this is our prefix
is our node SIDS or anycast SIDS you
know this is pretty well baked out major
routing implementations have
demonstrated pretty good
interoperability there's a little bit of
attention to the deployment of anycast
SIDS that you know you probably want to
be careful careful about it's strongly
recommended that the sRGB for nodes
which are announcing any cassadee's have
an identical srgb value or srgb range
the drafts are pretty clear about this
point the other thing that is
important for the controller and for
those who are deploying with anycast
SIDS is that labels which resolve
underneath that top any casted that
you're forwarding to must be resolvable
by downstream nodes so you kind of have
to pre-bake that label stack from a
controller perspective with an
understanding as to what the subsequent
forwarding operations and the
perspective of the network is for
subsequently forward traffic as we've
gone about you know kind of
demonstrating interoperability from an
any casted perspective the conflict
resolution behavior has been pretty well
teased out there's still some
opportunity for miss configuration and
black holing of traffic for example if I
have a node which is announcing the
anycast prefix but is not announcing a
corresponding anycast
cid you may see black holing for traffic
the behavior is very similar to what you
might see with LDPE
if you didn't turn MPLS and LDP on on a
particular interface it can be really
difficult to kind of troubleshoot that
one yet the at the root of it all SPF is
done commonly against what the IG you
know the I GPS address family is and the
associated CID resolution is you know
kind of a byproduct of that so a little
bit of care needs to be exercised in
terms of ensuring that you consistently
deploy anycast SIDS with this
consistency of binding and operation a
slight segue around local label space
different vendors have had different
implementation and deployment
considerations around how they manage
their label space behavior of the sRGB
is pretty well baked across
implementations and there's good reason
for that
you know devices which have a very small
label space or you know the hardware is
limited in terms of its label processing
capability might you might require
special attention in terms of you know
load I'm sorry in terms of label
allocation but some implementations use
labels locally on the device for other
things or there might be kind of
additional services that go along with
that so examples of this would be
service specific labels that are used
for things like egress peering
engineering
or you might be doing a you know an
interface lookup and forwarding
operation over a specific interface to
override the forwarding you know the
need of IP forwarding behavior or if
you're doing things like associating
labels with individual member links on a
link aggregation bundle and you want to
be able to verify the path for that if
you bake a label stack in order to
exercise all of those member links
you'll want to do that with an awareness
as to what the label allocation is for
those deployments this is the one that
seems to come up most commonly when
folks are talking about segment routing
label stack size I'm carrying a ton of
overhead in order to forward a TCP ACK
one of the seductive things about
segment routing is it provides for very
granular traffic engineering the
controller does the imposition of a
label stack you can mix and match labels
in the forwarding in the stack in order
to achieve certain objectives but you
can get you know you can define the
paths on a per link basis all the way
across the network just like you can
with with RSVP today and this sounds
great but it can you know it entails a
number of additional considerations the
first one that leaps to mind here is
Hardware encapsulation capabilities some
hardware candidly is just severely
constrained in terms of the numbers that
it can't a number of labels that it
compose impose on a single pass this
includes some pretty popular chipsets
some hardware is you know you know
definable on this with software upgrades
some it's just baked into the forwarding
pipeline now if you control one end of
the connection with a virtual host or a
V switch capability you can potentially
offload some of this end cap with your
host stack if you're a transit or a
network provider you'll want to pay
particular attention to the capabilities
that you have on network ingress if you
need to do fine-grained
traffic engineering so if you need to do
that per interface level of traffic
engineering pay careful attention to
what
the hardware is capable of doing the
plot thickens
eww want to make sure that you
understand what the hardware
capabilities are because it's not just
labeling position that you have to be
aware of you have to take into
consideration the fact that some
hardware might have on deterministic
behavior when it experiences very deep
label stacks and it doesn't see the
bottom of stack bit so will all of the
transit links in your network support
forwarding deep label stacks will all of
the line cards in a system do that will
the load balancing behavior be
consistent if you have say a new
generation of hardware which is capable
of forwarding on these deep label stacks
but it's load bounces across links which
don't necessarily share that same
capability for nodes that do support
forwarding on deep label stacks and this
isn't a concern do you have access to
enough entropy sources are you peeking
under the hood of that label stack in
order to assure that you get the load
balancing that you're after
on the on lag members and is are you
potentially obscuring critical entropy
sources for forwarding and ensuring that
you get load balancing now some of you
might be saying hey this is no big deal
I'm going to use anycast SIDS and prefix
id's I'll define my pass I just want to
fling traffic in that direction and I'm
gonna have this you know small thin
label stack and it's not going to be a
concern we're going to come back to that
because it actually becomes a bit of a
nuanced consideration when we start
talking about contributing sources of
flows and traffic in the network well
shift gears a little bit here a lot of
folks that we're talking to are you know
who want to do something with segment
routing from a traffic engineering
perspective already has RSVP deployed
and there's you know there's this
conversation that we persistently have
around RSVP and s our coexistence and at
the end of the day the tacit assumption
or a dominance assumption rather
that you want to move from RSVP to
segment routing that might be because
there's a range of kind of architectural
shifts that you're going to go down
maybe you're focused on horizontal
scalability you want to take advantage
of the fact that segment routing
provides for leveraging yd CMP inside
the network but if there's this
long-term need to run RSVP and s are in
the network at the same time it's
probably in your best interest to look
at in introducing a controller to manage
traffic across both the SR and the RSVP
domains as quickly as possible it's
particularly important for folks who are
you know managing durably managing
things like point-to-multipoint te and
their network for a long time and have a
point-to-multipoint considerations from
a service delivery perspective so the
place the the the the real gacho with SR
and RSVP coexistence is this problem of
dark bandwidth whenever we're just
injecting s our traffic into the same
domain as rsvp-te LSP is we run the
route you have the risk of robbing
capacity from the RSVP space this is a
generic problem associated with Darkman
with the management of dark bandwidth
pools there's a draft here which is
currently in a working group last call
which provides a really nice breakdown
and discussion of the migration
discussion considerations and I've
candidly ripped off some of the content
from that that draft you know to break
out some of this discussion so the draft
and the conversations we're having here
kind of break this out into a number of
different considerations we looked at a
few things here one is static bandwidth
partitioning on each link I'll just
assign so much bandwidth to each domain
and SR traffic is admitted into the
network in order to satisfy those
requirements
RSVP does its thing the problem here is
that we haven't really solved the
problem of dark bandwidth through
stranding capacity which might be you
know left behind by one protocol versus
another another mode of operation is to
just introduce centralized capacity
management to controller into the domain
to facilitate introduction and
management across both domains but the
the rub here is
that if your long term goal here is to
move to SR you're introducing a
controller for something that you're
effectively going to throw away with the
management of the RSP RSVP traffic
another approach that folks have
discussed is flooding the SR utilization
into the IGP and then what we could do
is we can modify the decision process on
rsvp-te headends you know change the the
see SPF algorithms to accommodate for
this this carries with it all the
Associated downside of reworking RSVP
and you're bumping is a bunch of stuff
that that works and you know there's not
a whole lot of gain to be had there
another mode of operation might be
running s are directly over RSVP so you
you effectively resolve SR destinations
over IGP shortcuts in the RSVP to te
domain but then you have this problem of
how do i back it out and you don't want
to have a circular dependency here what
we've more or less settled on and you're
starting to see some exploration of
deployment with is reflecting the SR
traffic utilization into the IG P's max
reservable bandwidth here at first blush
this looks like the option I outlined on
the first page on the previous slide but
in this case what we're doing is we're
measuring the overall SR traffic on the
TE interfaces and reducing the amount of
available bandwidth that's that's there
for RSVP we don't have to change
anything in terms of the existing
rsvp-te
machinery this does make some assumption
that the auto bandwidth machinery is in
operation in the network already and
this has the added perk of allowing you
to introduce an SR only controller into
the network the algorithm out here that
is is outlined on the right hand side we
retrieve the srf stats we calculate a
smooth average here we flood that into
the max reservable bandwidth that value
there's some discussion that could be
had around you know what priority do we
flood that into the network but the
punch line is the rsvp-te head end nodes
can then adjust their LSP accordingly
and try
effectively starts to move away from
where we're loading the links with SR
traffic and that we're pushing RSVP
incrementally to just the the RSVP only
enabled links and domains from here I'll
shift to some of the less obvious stuff
that becomes obvious that becomes
apparent when you start to dig into and
under the hood of actual SR deployment
I'll start with a little bit of a segue
here around controllers and they're
incredibly important but often under
represented a companion the collector at
a high level the controller slurps the
LSD B from the network it gets a picture
the topology you can do that any number
of ways a passive IGP peering
relationship with though with existing
network VG pls reflecting those
attributes out into the network or you
can get this out using streaming
telemetry the controller takes into
consideration in the network state the
utilization it gets that from the
collector it kind of lunges us all
together with an understanding of what
the traffic demands are and it
presumably understands what the hardware
capabilities are and what the projected
loads are going to be and then it pushes
down a segments list to the ingress to
put traffic onto the network and from
there we're going to kind of talk about
some of the options for pushing that
information into the headend and what
the relative merits of some of those
approaches are at a high level
centralized there's a lot to love about
centralized path computation it has the
best view of what the available
resources are in the network there's
really no other place in the network
where we have this kind of visibility
and now we can start to you know kind of
realize the you know the the the actual
potential of some of the
software-defined capabilities in the LAN
this does carry with it some attendant
considerations you have to buy a
collector or you have to develop your
collector or in controller this well you
have to do both this carries with it
you know staffing
you know some code dependencies in terms
of what the capabilities are from a
control playing perspective and from a
controller perspective and with the
introduction of a controller you have
new availability considerations and new
concerns around what is the policy
that's being pushed into the network so
the thing is with segment routing all of
the traffic engineering is controller
driven there are some new developments
that are taking place right now in order
to provide what is effectively you know
I call it RSVP without soft state where
we provide dynamic policies which take
into consideration things like link
affinity SR lg's but by and large folks
are looking at using controllers in
order to push down the policy and the
admission for SR traffic and one of the
hottest area of conversations when you
talk to either an RSVP developer or an
SR controller developer is label stack
compression and that holds true whether
you are talking about doing this on box
with these dynamic policies or whether
you're talking about doing this off box
at the controller which brings us to the
care and feeding of our controllers the
care and feeding of our controllers
requires a lot of telemetry information
the auto bandwidth and the machinery
that we had previously in the RSVP
domain has to move somewhere so a
controller needs to have visibility into
the traffic loads it's got to understand
what the situation is and be able to
proactively move traffic loads or deal
with failures in the network this
implies a lot more aggressive
instrumentation than we have
historically seen inside of you know
today's networks the previous discussion
around streaming telemetry is a critical
component in terms of actually enabling
us to do segment routing deployments
with visibility into what the actual
network utilization looks like so you
know probably the pre step for all of
this is to really look at reworking your
instrumentation to utilize streaming
telemetry and as much as I thought I'd
be
kidding about it the practical reality
is we are talking about actually getting
access to per label traffic statistics
the reason for that being that folks
want to have small label stacks and they
want to understand what actually is the
contributing flow for whatever traffic
is coming into the network element so we
need to talk about stats and given that
we need stats what does the hardware
actually enable us to do from a stats
perspective now if you had everything
you'd have access to per interface per
direction per label per class per
traffic class stats and then you'd want
all the same for whatever you're pushing
down in terms of policy into the device
unfortunately the reality is far uglier
outside of fib capacity and ACL you know
space counters are the most precious
resource on modern Asics and so you're
gonna get some subset of that list and
it's probably going to be a
disappointing a subset the other thing
is getting the stats off the device and
cycling through all of the per interface
per label stats that are on the device
is gonna require likely new collection
infrastructure so you want to revisit
the previous presentation and see about
looking at you know collector options
now if you do get some useful subset of
stats information what does a label
counter actually get you any caste
prefix ID's they're actually a great
place to hide traffic all sorts of
traffic that's destined for a particular
metro is actually hiding underneath that
you're actually going to have to look
and see what's under what's hiding
underneath that label if you're looking
at srte policy counters you're gonna
have to look at how many policies
actually collapse to a common anycast
prefix any caste or prefix SID
at various midpoints in the network and
you're probably only going to get this
in one direction this is going to
require a lot of planning and management
on
where you put your traffic sources and
sinks and at the end of the day I'd
really like to encourage you to look at
your IP fix and s flow collection
infrastructure and look at that to
provide the visibility underneath those
top label stats and divorce yourself
from classic forwarding prefix and you
know associated router metadata in order
to get at that information I'll quickly
segue to srte traffic protocol traffic
engineering protocols there's three that
I'm going to discuss here
BGP srte this is a very active draft
there's a lot of development taking
place in this in this space here this is
very useful in ecmp dense environments
it doesn't know it doesn't specify an
interface as no interface
you know tunnel te or in named LSP
instead you want to think of this as
policy and rules for steering this
allows you to specify a segment list or
list a range of segment lists which
would be weighted ecmp
forwarded from that device which brings
the question of new considerations
around data plane programming and
validation this is BGP I kind of have to
trust that you did what I sent you to
and what I told you to do do you know
that the node actually accepted the list
of segment lists you you sent it do you
know what got tangled up in policy logic
the answer is you don't you have to go
and interrogate the device in order to
do that you want to be able to do that
in a scalable manner so you'll want to
limit Ori for that did you get to
specify a protect or a bypass path no
and if you really need to specify a
bypass or a protect path with some
awareness as to what the capacity and
the utilization will be on that this
might not be the tool that you're
looking for
next is P SEP peace F has been extended
to provide for segment routing LSP
you know configuration it has a range of
delegation and management models that
are pre slick it does retain a bit of an
RSVP ish
view it's capable of signaling the paths
thus doing nifty things like flow
mapping and you know using for this for
something other than you know IGP
shortcuts is still a work in progress
actual definition of a protect path is
work that's underway there is a draft
that discusses protect path placement
it's you know do for a refresh now one
really interesting thing about doing it
this is that you actually get a fighting
chance at some sort of a contract with a
node instead of the trust but verify
mode of a BGP operation or
spray-and-pray
you can actually understand what the
node is capable of doing it based on the
actual capabilities that you negotiate
with the piece up with a PCE at that
ingress node a more recent development
that we've been talking to folks about
is actual our PC based path placement a
number of operators are looking to
leverage the the web api is that every
vendor has been popping up with lately
juniper has got PR PD Arista has yo sub
belief cisco has a service layer there's
something called g ribby or the google
rib interface from the open config folks
all of these provide a mechanism to
define label stacks and paths and they
provide mechanisms to associate rib
entries with these paths this enables
you to build an agent or to do something
novel in terms of actually you know
doing controller selection or actually
creating a bypass path that is under
your control the other thing that it
does is it freshens and modernizes the
toolkit for folks from a development
perspective so instead of using you know
arcane protocols in order to do this you
know you can start to take advantage of
the more modern toolkits and SDKs that
vendors are providing here the flip side
here is it does require internal
development expertise you are leveraging
a vendors specific interfaces
API is in order to get the job done here
and you know this carries with it all
the baggage associated with you know
testing and verifying those those api's
that you're getting from the vendors on
subsequent code releases and new
deployments and packaging considerations
finally I'll leave you with a bit of
discussion around srte traffic
protection you know the old ad was you
know it's 1:00 a.m. do you know where
your children are well it's 1:00 a.m. do
you know what your protect path is
chances are you probably didn't get to
specify it the knee-jerk reaction in the
SR space is to talk about TI LFA and
there's truth be told a lot to like
about TI LFA there's no midpoint state
the fact that it comes up with a trio
post convergence path that's optimal and
has no micro loops is huge but the
practical reality is it's pretty
computationally intensive particularly
if you have things like s or LG's it may
very well require label stack
compression to stay within whatever your
protection
and cap capabilities are and so all of
that conversation that we had previously
around instrumenting the traffic the
hardware capabilities from a transit
path or from a label ingress and in
position perspective holds true for what
is now traffic protection that is
largely outside of your control
so from a practical deployment
perspective protect path placement let's
just put it under an area the domain of
area of active development and if you're
looking to deploy and have a strong need
for you know for a specified protect
path placement or a need to garner that
in advance you'll want to start talking
with your vendors in the standards
bodies about what we need to be doing
here so in conclusion I'm out of time
here
te with SR it didn't really get easier
it just got different there's a lot of
work that remains to be done in terms of
operationalizing this you know the data
the data plane
simplification the elimination of soft
state this is hugely useful for us going
forward as we look to build networks
differently but we're going to have to
build the complementary toolkit and
infrastructure in order to account for
this and in many cases we're probably
going to have to roll our own solutions
so in the meantime you know there's
there's no silver bullets here you can
expect a you know an interesting
workplace as we work through the
implementation considerations here and I
in the future now nog I really hope to
you know listen to some presentations
from operators who are really digging
into the weeds on some of these problems
and putting forth the solutions or the
operational experiences that they've had
and with that are there any questions I
guess
it's not a question Steve but it's just
a comment so I'm Rob Sookie right
co-chair the spring working group in the
ATF this is some where we were we're
really trying to focus the working group
on so bringing the realities of the
things that we can't deploy and the
things they're difficult to deploy
please bring them to the working group
we're listening we'd love to work on
them this is a my ATF nano outreach
okay then thank you