thanks everybody okay everybody hear me
well it's great to be here in Denver
sunny day and we're gonna talk about
ipv6 here indoors so that feels great
some background on me
I'm gonna talk about how our path to
going I P v6 only at t-mobile and I was
born and raised in Sweden I moved to the
u.s. in 2007 in 2009 I remember
attending an Aeron conference in San
Antonio I lived in Dallas but it at that
time and and I met with Stan barber who
some of you guys might be familiar with
and we were talking about the deployment
of ipv4 versus ipv6 in the Europe and
versus US and can I came to the
conclusion that you know it's it's we're
a little behind here in the US and maybe
we should do something so we founded the
Texas ipv6 task force and back in 2009
we were inspired by the Rocky Mountain
task force here in Denver who by the way
they were sponsor and there's some
events going on tonight if anybody is up
for free beer anybody who's doing ipv6
and nevertheless I started work for a
company called secure 64 also based here
in Denver a DNS company and one day this
sales guy comes you know comes into my
office and says hey you got to talk to
this guy camera and at t-mobile he's
talking about dns64 not 64 ipv6 I have
no idea what he's talking about so I
know you're into ipv6 so why don't you
give him a call so I did and Cameron
who's still with t-mobile who Newsday
who is a good friend and somebody I
worked very closely with he convinced me
that you know dns64 nat64 was the right
path for a mobile service provider to
take to transition to ipv6 and we
actually secured 64 at that point became
partners of t-mobile and we had the
first commercial dns64 platform
anyway fast for a couple years I worked
for Microsoft doing dns for them for a
while and then about two years ago this
opportunity showed up to lead the
architectural group within t-mobile so I
jumped on that and you know end of 2016
when I started one of the first team
Cameron said was by the way we're
turning off ipv4 on our iPhones here
shortly so that might be something you
want to look into and dig into so it's
kind of cool to have that full circle
first working as a vendor and now
have have the first-hand view of what we
trying to accomplish and why we're
moving to ipv6 if you want to reach me
you know here's my t-mobile email
address and Twitter Linkedin and so
forth or feel free to find me in the
corridors here lately after after this
talk so I'm gonna talk about our journey
to become ipv4 independent I'm gonna
have a little bit of an talking about
retries returns and happy eyeballs and
how that is affecting our network I've
been doing a little bit of research
there lately and then give you guys a
background for those who who doesn't
know nat64 dns64 and some of the
technologies we are using like prefix
discovery and for 64 X lat
and then talk about application level
fallback to ipv4 and what that is and
then some best practices and some
learnings that I've had from removing
ipv4 from our network so our customer
base is pretty easy to deal with
compared to perhaps you know a wired
service provider where there's nest
thermostats and all kinds of stuff and
the bulk of our customer base is either
Android handsets or Apple devices and
Android from starting from 4.3 and
onwards have had support for ipv6 plus
four six 4x lat and that's when we
decided to turn on ipv6 on these Android
handsets and for Apple in 2015 at their
developer conference they announced that
starting June 1st 2016
any application within the application
store needs to be not only you know
working on a v6 like a dual stack
environment but actually must support
ipv6 only networking so it's been
tremendously helpful for us to to have
those two giants behind us also helping
us pushing the transition to ipv6 and
yes the quick survey how many of you
guys are t-mobile customers in here
raise a hand and how many of you guys
have a iPhone so I don't know if you
guys are aware but but you're actually
having a v6 only experienced today right
so we have about you know give or take
10 million iPhones in our network and
there's no ipv4 interface if you look at
the interface you turn off Wi-Fi and
look at your interfaces there is no ipv4
interface it's their only ipv6 so that's
a pretty cool accomplishment in my
opinion and I mean this is stuff that's
ready this is nothing we're gonna turn
on a year from now two years from now
this is now right now we've had it on
for a year and a half it works right and
we've really reached a utopia that I
think we all talked about we have been
able to move clients to a new IP
protocol without even them probably
knowing that they moved to an ipv6 only
experience and we turn off our pv4 on
them so it's been a long journey
starting with Android 4.3 somewhere
around 2013 we've had talks similar to
this talk several times and it's
starting in 20 beginning of 2014 apricot
37 where we could announce based on the
world
ipv6 launch that we had 16 percent of
our customer base were preferring ipv6
over ipv4 outbound from Ras and then
from from there we've we've had several
talks as you guys can see and we've made
steady progress it's tapering off a
little bit here
at the end as we're getting close to a
hundred percent obviously it's a little
harder and there's more corner cases
that we need to take into account but as
you can see it's a good steady progress
and today based on the world IPV world
ipv6 launched at org website today
some 94 percent of our traffic is or 94
percent of our handsets I should say or
you know they're preferring ipv6 over
ipv4 going out from our AAS so that's a
pretty remarkable accomplishment and can
you guys turn on the clock here so I
know how much time I have left that
would be great that's a pretty
remarkable complements at this point you
you might want to look into like what's
that remaining six percent you know what
kind of corner case is are we like how's
the bottom of the barrel looking here in
terms of getting to a hundred percent
and you know I think we're kind of the
first service provider really pushing
you know closer you know
90% here that you know we can we can
look at that and see what's going on if
you look at the world ipv6 launch
there's you know a big bunch of
companies in there they're doing a lot
of good stuff on ipv6 I think everybody
is transitioning one way or another I
think on the wireless side of things is
us Verizon Wireless is doing a great job
they have a good adoption rate as well
and then reliance in India who's a new
entrance to market and they could kind
of go directly into ipv6 so looking at
the remaining 6% and zooming in and I
think it's five categories that you know
is is mostly contributing to the
remaining six percent we do have our
enterprise clients we have not migrated
our enterprise clients to ipv6 or dual
stack yes yet the the guests are dual
stack so if you ever if this if you ever
going to visit a t-mobile campus and if
you connect to guests you actually using
nat64 and dns64 and those technologies
that we're using for our handsets and
you're using those for for your your
experience there but we do we do have
the guests are dual stacked so if
there's an ipv4 literal or something
like that coming up and you have that
emergency ipv4 connectivity as well and
more on that later on how DNS 64 and not
64 works there's also some really old
handsets so Android handsets for example
before 4.3 they are not capable they're
capable do a stack but they're not turn
on in our network so if you look at this
link from developer.android.com you can
see it's about the world wild wide
population of these types of handsets
and tablets are this old is about four
four percent so that's measured who is
actually going to the Apple App Store to
download any new applications so so
about 4% I think that since that's a
worldwide number I think the number in
our network might be a little lower
typically your primary device is your
phone and you might want to upgrade that
a little bit more often you might have
an older tablet or something in your
home that
might not be upgraded as often using a
little longer so I think in our network
it might be less than 4% and also if
you're a power user you probably
upgraded your phone at some point so
most of the connections we're seeing
outbound you know coming from power
users start using browsing the Internet
lot so they probably have a newer
handset so maybe a couple of percent or
something could still constitute you
know old phones that are not being
upgraded and this is hard for us to do
anything we just have to wait them out
and at some point they'll you know buy a
new phone and that old grandma she'll
pass away and you know at some point
we'll we'll get to - no old handsets but
but they're still you know I'm surprised
because we're talking about like Samsung
Galaxy S 2 and that's a good example of
a phone that's you know not supporting
Android 4.3 so it's pretty old stuff
another thing that couldn't contribute a
little bit to this is retries over ipv4
for one or another reason
so think about we have an LTE network
you're an uber driver or something
you're using Google Maps or some other
application you drive into a tunnel you
might get some connectivity issues as
you drive out of the tunnel happy
eyeballs kicks in and you get a v4
connectivity and then the question
becomes do you stay now in v4 do you
move back to ipv6 there could be a
little bit of this you know I'm you're
starting some research on this and I'll
cover that in the next slide but it's
not significant tethering is another
case so if you have a phone you turn it
on as a mobile hotspot and some of our
phones is gonna expose yes three four to
your laptop like an iPhone it will be v4
only experience whereas others like I
have an LG V 30 a fairly new phone and
that's actually dual stack so if I do
with teterin
with that I get a dual stack experience
so there's some corner cases there maybe
one to two percent I would estimate in
that category as well and then the last
one is roaming
so our APN roaming protocol is set to
ipv4 only and this is a global setting
that we set so that means that whenever
you're roaming to another network
you will be ipv4 back to us and then out
to the internet from there so since it's
a global setting we need to make sure
that all the service providers in the
world can handle these six before we
turn it on so it's a little unfortunate
that this is a global setting for us and
and this is not only for international
roaming you know Canada Mexico Europe
and so forth but we also have roaming
partners in areas where we don't have a
lot of connectivity so like if you drive
up north here a couple hours into
Wyoming you're probably going to find
some spots where we don't have coverage
but we're partnering with some local
provider and they have coverage and in
that case you'll also be tunnelled back
to us VIP v4 so this is probably a 1 to
2% as well and as we build out our
coverage and we become less dependent on
those national roaming partners this
will this will actually burn down this
category but the international roaming
at some point will have to make a
decision if we want to turn that on and
go v6 so so don't go to Mexico or Canada
or Europe for vacation this summer if
you can stay in the US where you have
t-mobile coverage or maybe Puerto Rico
is a good alternative for you then you
know that would be good because then we
keep these statistics hi Sweden is you
know unfortunately they'll be
international roaming so you're screwed
but you know you can watch the game on
Wednesday we play in Mexico 5 a.m. in
the morning or 6 a.m. I guess here
anyway back to ipv6 so there's happy
eyeballs has been out for a while the
whole idea is that if ipv6 connectivity
is bad for one another reason you should
move over to ipv4 so there's a great
site that you can check your happy
eyeballs the h es - ipv6 comm and it's
like a JavaScript that every 5 seconds
we reach Weis and you can you can see
whether your v4 v6 and I've been driving
around a lot seeing you know how can I
induced failures here so so so and see
can I do I stay on ipv4 on that case or
am I am I going to go back to ipv6 after
after a while it's been tricky to in in
real life really in
these types of failures I don't know how
common they are I need to look into this
a little bit further but I also set up a
test bed that I just had a kind of a
JavaScript just reloading an image every
five seconds and then with iptables he
shut down ipv6 and see how different
browsers reacted and Safari
as well as Google Chrome was doing a
good job you know quickly jump over to
IP before doing the happy eyeball thing
and then as I removed that failure and
remove that IP tables rule with ipv6
they quickly determined that v6 is good
enough again and they move back to ipv6
so that's what I call the returns that
probably not covered into great length
how you should react to I P v6 becoming
available again after your on v4 in the
in RFC s and a happy eyeball RFC's and
so forth but interesting that you know
some of the major browsers are doing a
good job there others though like if you
if you're working on an edge or an
internet explorer if you induce that
failure it's gonna fail over and do ipv4
but then even if ipv6 becomes available
again it's actually not gonna fall back
into ipv6 so that's an interesting
corner case that maybe there's some work
here to be done by the browser vendors
and but still a Firefox on my Android I
couldn't get to work even doing happy
eyeball and fall over so once it started
to reload this image it was over v6 I
shut it down and it never actually fall
back to ipv4 and I think that is is
because it's doing the happy eyeball in
the beginning for that URL or that
domain name and it's not doing happy
eyeballs again it's just assuming that
that's gonna be good for the entire
session right once I had an in similarly
if I induced a failure but I I started
the the browser on ipv4 and Firefox
never failed back to ipv6 even if ipv6
was available at a later stage so I
think there's some corner cases here it
needs to be looked into as we're trying
to trend down to a hundred percent and
there's some corner cases there in the
browsers that probably need some some
work to to make this work a little bit
better so a little bit of a background
on how dns64 nat64 works
so you have the handset and the handset
is a v6 only handset so it will send out
a quite a query because there's no v4
interface so there's no point in sending
out any a queries and that will reach
our dns64 box if there's a quad a record
available we'll send that back to the
client and the client will take the
black path out to the v6 internet so
that's the ideal way of going because
there's no middle machines here that
needs to do anything and it's very
convenient for us and the worst case
scenario there's no v6 but there is a v4
address and in that case we do a
synthetic we append the prefix the dns64
prefix is 64 FF 9 B in this case and we
convert this from hex - from dark tall
to hex and we send that back to a client
to trick him into that there is actually
an ipv6 address for this website that
you're trying to reach and that entire
prefix is routed to our nat64 gateways
so that packet will now end up in our
nat64 gateway we can strip off the the
prefix and we can send that out on there
on the v4 Internet so we have a ton of
these nat64 gateways in our network
obviously they rather expensive you want
to deploy them in pairs so there's a
failure so ideally you know if you guys
can move all your content to ipv6 then
we don't we can decon them eventually
right so so we're getting closer and
closer and you know we'll see we'll see
how this goes but please move over to
ipv6 and I got to say you know that the
top content providers like the Google
Facebook of the world they've been doing
a tremendous good job of enabling ipv6
so so it's some of the smaller CD ends
and and some other cloud providers that
we're seeing some traffic going into
being v4 only still so we're also using
4 6 4x lat and 4 sixes 4 X let's is
often RFC six eight seven seven Cameron
actually Cameron Byrne he's one of the
authors to that and what it is it's a
kind of a small little piece of code on
your Android handset that exists posting
in an ipv4 address to your Android
handset and worst-case
if you encounter like an ipv4 literal
like something embedded into a website
then if you only had v6 you couldn't you
you were you were dead in the water but
this gives you this opportunity to still
communicate over v4 by sending it there
the the clat daemon that's running on
your 464xlat device is now going to do
kind of like we're doing with the nat64
dns64 it knows that dns64 prefix it's
gonna append it it's gonna create an
ipv6 package so it can go ipv6 only over
our network to the nat64 gateway and
from there we strip that header and send
it out so that's how it works on Android
phones there's a similar RFC or a kind
of another RC that we're also using RFC
cenicero 5-0 discovery of ipv6 prefixes
and this is instead of hard-coding these
dns64 not 64 prefixes in our network
instead we send a query for ipv4 only at
ARPA a quad a query and from there we
can determine can strip off the last 64
bits and from there that has it can
determine what the prefix is and you
start using that so we don't have to
hard code and provision anything so this
is great and that's how it's working in
in Android and Apple device is actually
doing something similar when it comes to
what I call application level fallback
so if you go to this URL at the bottom
there to the developer manual for for
Apple they're actually not recommending
you if you create some application to
use the low-level sockets instead
they're recommending the stuff in the
middle that's kind of in blueish here so
they want you to use what they call
nsurl session which is a higher level
API and they will take care of all the
translation on your behalf and falling
back to ipv4 if possible so the blue
stuff here is actually using an RFC
Center zero-five-zero sending out these
ipv6 ipv4 only ARPA and queries to
figure out the prefix and if you
encounter an ipv4 literal you can
actually fall back to ipv4 so here you
have a v6 only device with a browser
that
understands that it's a v6 only device
and it has this backdoor kind of into v4
as needed so it's kind of cool you know
I talked about this example where you
induce a failure just by adding an IP IP
tables and it's pretty cool you sit
there with a v6 only Apple device and
then you induce a failure on v6 and then
you see all sudden v4 traffic coming in
from that v6 only device because it's
going via that net that's 64 device so
so pretty cool stuff that one thing I
want to mention here though is that you
know we're moving to ipv4 fallback
mechanism further up in the stack here I
said you know it's an industry it used
to be a decision that we made from a
network perspective do you want to dual
stack this server or client or do want
to keep in v4 when I do v6 only on him
and that's something that then kind of
moved it into the OS layer with the 464
X lat
and now the application is taking and
making that decision on our behalf like
when is the SLA on v6 not good enough
and when do I need to fall back into the
v4 so it's kind of a you know an
interesting but a little bit scary new
path that we're seeing here and where's
this going to end you know there's a lot
of discussion on dns over HTTP you know
who says that the applications the
browser can't just forward all the DNS
records up to their resolver and make
decisions up there and who says they
can't is forward everything up to some
central cloud and from there yes routed
out on the internet right so something
to kind of think about and keep track of
so some of the learnings that I feel we
we did well and and some things that I
want to share is that you know obviously
invest in ipv6 a little bit it's like
you're a 401k retirement plan right you
you need to kind of constantly invest
and and move you know we've done a big
investment which was a very successful
investment early on with with our
handsets and that panned out really well
for us we're in pretty good shape now
and you know but we still have ways to
go with our internal clients with data
centers we we have what we call an
Annette which is the network management
network
we're running out of RFC 1918 space so
we have still ways to go and but now we
can kind of we're working on the
traditional upgrade cycles when
something goes end-of-life we can work
into and enable ipv6 a test point
determine what sites and applications
are important you know we did a lot of
scanning in advance before we turn on it
turned off ipv4 on our Apple devices and
some sites are is broken right so so we
did a lot of outreach there was a card a
credit card issuer here in the US who
had a DNS problem with their domain and
we couldn't reach it that dns64 kind of
derailed and we couldn't reach that site
and we managed to reach out to them and
and they actually fixed it you know
before we launched so that was great and
same thing as a university I reached out
to that fix their sites and some others
some other sites as well and so you know
this has been live for a year and a half
now so if you're a you know wireless
service provider from us or elsewhere
you know if it works for us chances are
pretty well it's gonna work for you too
right so I don't think we have to be too
concerned about turning off ipv4 anymore
it works very good at least in a
wireless environment with Apple and
Android handsets and don't try to fix
things with local overrides you know one
thing that you know when we had that
card issue having problems I was
thinking maybe we pop something in our
own DNS to your circumvent this problem
from from happening I think in general
that's probably a bad idea because you
know especially when we talk about you
know credit cards and those kinds of
things what happens if they move and
somebody else takes their IP address and
you know you don't want to be the man in
the middle and be liable for that it's
better if the actually where the problem
is if they can fix the problem there and
it's you know if you have the RFC es you
know dns64 not 64 hour season you can
point to the exact you know your
violation of section 5.3 and it's RFC is
easy that's good ammunition for them to
you know to fix on their side and also
pointing to the Apple policy that all
the applications today needs to be
capable of an ipv6 only experience in
Apple stores so that's a requirement and
you know they obviously they didn't you
know some of the applications didn't
live up to that requirement so they have
to go fix it on their side-scan social
media you know some of these stuff when
you're a large company like a t-mobile
it might be hard to get through to the
people that actually you know are
working on this you know we're a small
team working deep into this with DNS and
so forth but social media is a great
tool to use see if people are having
problems you know let's try them on our
phones and see if we can reproduce it
and we found some issues that way that
we could fix and work together with
application and providers to fix and
then you know don't try to change the
world maybe keep things in perspective
there's a lot of broken stuff out there
already people are under attack and
there's stuff that doesn't work they're
not RFC compliant and you know don't let
like you know a few sites that doesn't
work hinder your you know deployment or
and getting off of ipv4 so kind of dive
into it would be my suggestion and you
know work it out and it's been useful
for us you know yes diving into this and
and and at the end of the day you know
everything worked out fine so that's my
last slide we have about four minutes
for questions here so you say anybody
wants to go ahead
one two three why don't we wait with you
we go ahead to the right first and we'll
come back to you
ipv4 ipv6 nothing's working right baby
five yes B cloud so that the traffic
volume ratio is actually is an
interesting question you know we have a
lot of the it's it's actually you know
more more I would say more than ninety
four percent of our traffic is v6 at
this point right because the most of the
main content if you think about you know
oath or you know Yahoo and Facebook and
Google and the big content provider
they're all already there and ninety-six
percent of our handsets are already
there so you get these kind of matrix
where the traffic is is is really really
large in terms of ipv6 most of your
cases
great talk
thank you question was there any kind of
gradual rollout of this change to ipv6
or was it a big switch yep and you are
just Edward from Spotify okay and you
know it's it's it started with Android
really right so 4.3 it was kind of slow
start there and and then Apple provided
support at the later stage so it was
kind of a a a big it was like a Flag Day
right we're turning this on and then any
anybody with Android 4.3 is gonna have
it right so so so he wasn't gradually
but then we've grown gradually because
people are changing handsets they're
getting new handsets and those kinds of
things so alrighty cool
any other questions if not I want to
thanks everybody for listening it's been
great and let me know if you have any
more questions I'm here throughout the
day and tomorrow so thank you very much
you