okay thank you everybody
goodness me how do you follow Betty
actually I do probably have no I no
recollection but the very first operator
community where I gave her a technical
presentation was Nanog and I prepared
some slides and unfortunately Betty had
a look at them the day before and help
me make them better so probably no no
memory of that at all but it's um I was
looking back and I hear in my archive
and see that yes it was the first person
first conference I ever spoke up so
thank you for your help helping me find
my voice those years ago then this is a
presentation that I put together because
um I've worked on a few automated
networks and there's a lot of content
out there and a lots of learning a lots
of understanding about how to run an
automated network from the point of view
of writing software script systems that
that go and change your network device
go and change
what's configured out there but one of
the things that I've learned that's
that's very important is you actually
need to be able to not just run an
automated network but run an automated
business and have your network
influenced by what the business
understands and I haven't found an
enormous amount of content out there
about having the the automated network
take inspiration and and instructions
from an automated business so because
I've worked on a couple of businesses
that have worked like this I thought I
put together some slides about the
things that I've learned and you can
grab me afterwards and tell me what I've
done wrong or not um but but let's um
let's have a look at what I think um for
network engineers which most people in
the room probably discovered when they
first started and being able to talk to
their equipment using scripts rather
than using CLI instructions and the a
great place to start with automation is
producing some scripts that give you
reports what's happening on my network
right now you get information out of the
network
that's actionable and useful the next
part of the journey is you can take that
learning when you write software that
gets reports out of your systems you
become more confident you get more
familiar with the tools the libraries
that you can use and you start to write
scripts that impact a change on the
network like it's something that will
automatically bring up paying sessions
for example in a consistent manner
eventually some of those systems start
to work together you end up with a more
complete suite of tools that go and set
stuff up and it feels a bit more like a
an application you're starting to manage
the network rather than manage a device
and you start to have there something
that actually helps you make decisions
about something that's a lot more than
just pure configuration eventually the
ultimate place to reach the thing that
the next step to take which is perhaps
the hardest is to reach a fully
automated an integrated business so a
technology business with a set of
processes that are actually enforced and
delivered by your automated software
he's stopped configuring the network but
start to configure the entire product
generally this is solved by businesses
with with pretty large scale challenges
such as large access providers hosting
companies but but now this is something
that a medium-size ISP an IXP for
example can implement so this
presentation is based on that this is
these are my technical perspectives and
thoughts on the architecture of a
greenfield deployment of an alternative
business we as a business an internet
exchange point as a service operator we
build AI X's so what motivated us to
build our network and our product in a
fully automated manner it's because we
had to replicate this our intention and
our businesses to build lots of these
that are all identical and you can't do
that without process and software and
actually by getting it right and having
such strict but efficient processes that
we're getting helps you deliver
efficiency and leanness in your business
right from the beginning and it helps
your customers because they get an
assured service they get a service that
works the same way however it's set up
when it's set up because it's being
delivered by the same tools same
applications it allows you to integrate
with party databases like the I accept
database if you're interested in
clearing up hearing d-beam actually some
of some of the the reason we do this is
because we were quite frustrated with
some of the the legacy models and that
had been used and therefore the chance
to align the business and the technical
process with an efficient software stack
was in our DNA from the beginning and
the way this presentation may be
different from other automation
presentations you've seen before
it mainly focuses on how and why you
should build a data model and we'll talk
about exactly what that is in a moment
and we also hopefully will have time for
you to talk a little bit about the way
that we architects use some of the
software and some of the thing to do
with software testing from a network
point of view - ok so what do I mean by
data model I've said it a few times now
what what do I really mean by that and a
data model is a structured description
of all the things that your business
needs to know in order to operate so it
needs to understand which people you are
interact with which organizations in
your supplier or customer base and which
products that you sell for example and
and and the technical elements here
describe configuration descriptions and
infrastructure elements where your
switches are where your routers are and
the thing to do when you start to build
your data model is start by mapping the
steady state of the business when
nothing is changing who are the people
the organizations or products that we
sell when nothing is changing what is it
that my business knows and once you've
modeled that wanna probably a very large
sheet of paper or a whiteboard you can
then model the interactions between
these things so for example a person who
works for an organization and requests a
product which is configured in a certain
way that can be described in a
there's a quotation for a product that's
prepared for a person at a customer for
example and and these interactions also
need to be modeled why would you care
about that from an engineering point of
view why am i standing in front of it an
engineering conference and saying you
need to model quotes in your
organization actually there's a benefit
to you as an engineer for doing that
because very quickly you realize that
for example when you're setting up
monitoring when you're monitoring
customer services if you understand if
you've modeled the quotations if you've
modeled the thing that somebody intends
to buy from your company you can monitor
the thing that somebody wants to buy not
necessarily the thing that got rolled
out so if you start to model and if you
start to model everything that to do
with an order you can actually take
advantage of that at later stages of the
engineering process once you've modeled
the information once you've modeled you
people processes products you start so
you have to understand where does data
where does this information live in your
organization and actually whether you're
an established organization or whether
you're working on a greenfield product a
Greenfield application you'll probably
find that data naturally lives within
different teams in your organization so
invoicing will likely live with finance
and information about prospective
customers or current customers might
live with sales technical information
will live in a supports function or an
engineering function so you've modeled
exactly what information you need the
new model where it is and it's actually
fine for data to live in different tools
and different data bases around your
organization it's much worse if the data
doesn't exist in a database but it does
if you exist in databases they're spread
out in your organization but what you
have to watch out for is where the same
information can live in different
databases within your organization but
be subtly different each time for
example you might find that information
about an organization live separately in
your finance system your sales team your
support teams where you're dealing it so
you're thinking about the same
organization each time but subtle
fences and in engineering maybe we don't
care about the organization because well
we just deal with Fred and and that's
not okay
it's it's not fine for data to be
authoritative in more than one place the
data needs to be authoritative in a
single place and other databases around
the organization simply need to link an
index to that authoritative record so
for example if the CRM is going to be
the database where information about
organizations live that's fine but the
other tools in the organization need to
look at that database in order to get
information about that particular type
of record so when you when you build
your data model you've worked out where
you live where the data lives it's
important to follow some rules of
engagement which is that you store any
item of information just once in the
organization there's a benefit from
doing that it means that if you store
the information once and that
information is wrong in the place that
you store it you only need to fix it in
one place and then it's correct across
your entire organization storing the
data once and linking to it for data
based nurses is to call third normal
form and if you want to read more about
good design of that that's something you
can look at when you and when you store
that record in a database it needs to
have a unique identifier which is
nothing to do with the data itself so
for example an a s number isn't a good
record identification number for an
organization or whatever because an
organization can have more than one I
guess or it might change the a s that it
uses or something else in a s is it's an
attribute it's not an ID number for the
record within your database and you need
to decide where it's authoritative and
because you're working across teams is
therefore important to have buy-in
across the organization when you're
planning this you have to do it as a as
a business when you're actually modeling
your data now looking at some of the in
network specific stuff when you're
modeling your data you need to be very
careful to make sure that infrastructure
centric and customer centric or service
centric data doesn't live within the
same database record
this makes your database much more
scalable and easier to maintain and from
a portability point of view a specific
example here might be to make sure that
information about network ports and
network services that live on that port
separate pieces of information this
means that you could stack multiple
services on ports further down the line
or it's much more portable you can move
services around to a different port
without losing the service history if
you separated the infrastructure element
from the service element enough for
example once you've modeled your data
you're going to realize that in
engineering you're going to be
responsible for a bunch of information
though and there are some interesting
data based fashions you might read about
when you're trying to select a database
to hold that information there are two
there are many but there are two common
types of database that you might
consider and the documents store or no
SQL type of database and the relational
database now I've actually worked on
automated networks that have had both
kinds of database for authoritative
engineering data and I found the
relational databases suit that better
for the needs of an engineering database
about services ports configurations this
kind of thing
we tried them a non relational database
for this on the document store at a
previous organization and the developers
really really liked using it because it
was very extensible you can you can
define you can just extend the document
when you want to think of storing new
types of data as your service evolves
but I actually personally find that
strictness is a benefit in terms of
building a database that describes
configurations products ports and you
get a benefit from from having a
strictly defined database for
engineering information at the common
source of a common database is that I
actually use in our current stack we use
we use MySQL and
four truths about users ports and
services and this and at service states
for example things that are inherently
relational in our in our stack of
information that we need to remember and
we use time series databases like in
flux DB to store time series data about
that so port utilization light levels
error counts and information that is
about a single element that changes over
time we use influx db2 so information
about that and we also use some
third-party databases that I recommend
you have a look at as well like the Euro
X and the peering DB database is really
really good for getting information
about what people are going to do with
their connections to your network for
example so now we've talked about the
model we've we've talked about the fact
that you've mapped everything that you
need to know you've mapped the
interactions between those things and
you've worked out where they're going to
live in your organization it's time to
break out a text editor and write some
software well what might the
architecture look like the architecture
that we've settled on is these very
similar is in fact the one on the screen
right now and and the the interest at
the the area where I lights are the the
area where I find most interesting is
that single API layer in the middle the
API in in this architecture acts as a
gateway for these many different kinds
of database so we we don't use sugar but
it's an example of a database with an
API that can store information about
organizations and people MySQL is where
we store information about network
elements in flux DB the time series
database and also the Gateway to the
actual infrastructure where our service
lives on switches and in servers they
can all be addressed through endpoints
on our single common API this makes it
really easy for us to develop and
monitor the platform and much easier to
make changes to back-end services by
just writing technology classes at the
back that sorts of different databases
in the backend through a single API
layer and it also makes it easier to
expose
and data to customers this is a really
really good thing we I we've learned
quite a lot about what's happening on
the network if I if I learned that I'm
incrementing in our account on a
particular port why not actually make
that information available to customers
by the API if they're going to build
tools against our system as well so that
they can see what we see
I'm only running services for their
benefit so why wouldn't I share what I
know about the services they're enjoying
from us and having a single API layer
that can address all of the information
that we know that's all as an
organization it makes it easy to expose
parts of that to our customer
oh also having a single common API layer
gives you a benefit that means you can
no matter what the back-end storage
format or the back-end messaging format
actually is whether it's an XML API to a
invoicing system whether it's a but are
you going to have SQL databases and the
time series database whatever however
the backend data is stored you could
address it in its native format it from
your API and expose it to your tools to
your portals to your customers in a
single format like Jason so you can you
might have to address things very very
XML for example but you don't have to
expose that hora to your customers you
can give them nice clean Jason
consistent data for every kind of
information record that you hold here's
an example in fact of what it looks like
we have a single API layer as I
mentioned and on the on the Jason
document on the left that is a
description of a service that's called a
cert if you you have a service with us
you can ask our endpoint you can
authenticate and then ask what do you
know about this this endpoint and I'm
collecting information via a
bgp collector running bird a bgp route
server running bird there are different
servers are internal SQL database on
exposing that in a single JSON format to
our customer despite the fact that none
of these backends actually natively talk
Jason on the right now this is
information about a port which is in use
by a customer and you can I'm here I'm
pulling information from the switch
pulling information from our internal
SQL database again pulling information
from our influx DB database again
exposing it all in a single format Jason
to our customers so our customer can ask
for information one endpoints about
their services and the back-end
information can live in many many places
but a single request to a single
endpoint gets that information for the
customer in a single format and that's
what that architecture allows you to do
so now we have now we've now we've got
our data model we've got an API we've
got in a way of addressing that model in
a consistent manner how do we actually
use that from the point of view of a
network engineer well once you have
confidence your data model once you once
you find that you're using this
information using your tools you're
looking at the information you change
any information and it's working you're
confident and you can start to harness
that power of network configuration via
templates when your data model extends
across the business you can do that with
much greater accuracy and devolve
control what do I mean by that there's
an example and we we don't actually have
anybody in the organization with a
provisioning brief in their job at
asteroid our salespeople all the
customer themselves can deliver exchange
ports directly from the quotation so a
customer can describe what they need a
quotation is produced if everyone's
happy you can actually deliver the the
the port from the quote when the quotes
accepted it gets rolled out and the
advantage of doing that is we can
deliver not just the exchange port and
the answer related services like routes
over sessions but we can also deliver
our monitoring so we can
what is sold not what gets rolled out if
you've ever had a situation where you're
monitoring the you you're monitoring
what got rolled out but the customer
actually intended to buy something
different if you use what the
information that's in the quote to roll
out the product and to set up your
monitoring then you're delivering what
was ordered and you're monitoring what
was ordered not something different so
that these things work together in a bit
of a fire triangle you've got structured
data your data model data that is
correct and completes
you've got templates that describe how
monitoring or network parts or server
configuration stands they should be
configured and you've got a way of
rolling that out the automation which
we'll look at in a moment and the
templating engine that we use is is one
called ginger and I think these slides
will be online afterward so if you want
to have a look in a little bit more
detail you can have a look or I can
share more examples with you afterwards
too the nice thing the thing I like
about ginger is that it's not actually
specific to a particular back-end
configuration it's just a way of
managerial and the flat files so if you
can generate some plain text as a piece
of config you can develop that quite
quickly you can express that quite
easily in a ginger template so it can
take variables from your JSON API so in
our case where if I I can I put the
ambitious err what does this do this is
a bird configuration snippet that sets
up a bgp session and there's a stuff
that stays the same each time the stuff
that gets wrapped around the session and
then there's information that's coming
out of our api you can see in the double
curly brackets like there though the
network's a s number and the IP
addresses all coming from our json api
and using the ginger templates it allows
you to use programmatic methods within
your templates so you can see the top
and the bottom line of this config
snippet is indicating the start the end
of a for loop so I loop over that as
many times as there's information coming
in the JSON and for rolling that out we
don't actually have scripts for rolling
out configuration I use some
ansible for changing server
configuration so this is an example of a
task that again sets out roles out that
config that's on the last slide actually
so this is the instead of having to
write scripts that do that which are
pretty similar each time we just have to
manage config files that describe the
end state of what it is that would like
to be configured so here's a yeah
there's a bit of config that goes and
gets the information from our API it
goes and generates the config and then
rolls out onto the server and restarts
the daemon you can do conduct
conditional logic nicely in the and
several templates as well so you know
you're not not limited where you can see
that line starting when indicates that
we should only build a root server
session if that is flagged in the Jason
as being true you know we would like a
root server session to be configured
what are the advantages of doing
configuration through something like
unstable rather than having a a piece of
software you have to write and maintain
yourself well you don't need to write
the maintainer Peter saw for yourself
it's already there it's already complete
and allows the API layer to stay pretty
lightweight all the API layer has to do
is retrieve an update database records
or retrieve an update information excuse
me from a back-end worker and that's
that's not difficult to write and you
can write it in a in any language that's
familiar to you there's lots of stuff in
there there's so much good back-end code
in Python that a lot of network
engineers become very very familiar with
Python very quickly and I I chose to use
Python for our API because you get very
familiar with it when you're working in
network automation and it also means the
automation layer is very very
lightweight it's just configuration
files the sort of things we've all been
using for a long long time and when you
when you're building a data model and
when you're building your API layer it's
important to make sure that the
decisions you make when you're building
your API and mapping your data allow you
to store a retrieval process and
business logic as well as purely
technical information so you remember to
model and build tools for everything not
just the things that touch your network
for example we have them we have a
system call the campaign's that allows
networks to suggest where they'd like us
to build an IX next or allows someone to
support an existing campaign we model
that in the database as well because it
means that when we convert from a
campaign to of running exchange there's
a bunch of information that's already in
there and already structured that we can
use in the initial configure as well so
there's a strong advantage to some
modeling and mapping everything that
your organization does not just the
stuff that touches your network no
although I said I will talk a lot more
about the data model and and the stuff
for the rest of the business no network
automation so it can be complete without
talking a little bit about what we what
we do to talk to the switches and and
the servers that run our service
altogether and when you're running and
when you're running an automated network
at some point you are going to need to
write some stuff that goes and rolls out
config and what do you need to consider
when you're considering the messaging or
the communications between your common
API layer and the backend you need to
consider inter process communication how
are you going to trigger that there's
something the API need a layer needs to
instruct the backend and you need to
consider how you can map a model state
the state of a network job how did that
roll out completely that it fail why did
it work successfully and state you
should consider stuff to be device
independent so that when your vendor
evolves to a new configuration dialect
or a new product line or you maybe want
to pick a new vendor in the future and
you can do so just by writing a new and
back-end worker rather than
all news load of stuff you need to
consider as well if you can in your
back-end systems cope with device swap
outs if there's a device's failure for
example there inter-process
communication there's a couple of ways
of considering it and these are the two
that I've I've looked at before with
actually both both work fine it could be
message to you based like a system like
RabbitMQ this is a system that allows
you to leave a message you know in in a
queue as it says that describes a
something that must be done never
something-something what puts a message
on the queue saying here's something I
would like to be done and another
process picks up the message from the
queue and says okay I'll go and do that
for you then and rabbitmq is a good one
because it's got very good support in in
major scripting languages it's pretty
fault tolerant you can also impose
strict order muttering guaranteed
delivering delivery high availability
and but we didn't use RabbitMQ for this
project we used we built a separate web
service layer so we have a central api
but when we talk to the back-end servers
and switches we go through another web
services API and it's because it allowed
us to use an exactly identical
technology stack to our central API when
we got familiar with with with the
technology we just had two platforms
that look very very similar it's very
very extensible and because if any if it
needs to support a feature that isn't in
a message queue it can do it we just
have to write the feature and it allows
this to be decentralized so that the as
long as the mothership is available if
there's a there can be many many sites
with many many exchanges in front of
them a worker processes that are
independent of each other so if we lose
power in one city or whatever it doesn't
affect any part of the provisioning or
our system in another city and we chose
and when it comes to actually rolling
out config onto the network devices
themselves I look to trying to do write
a generic worker
system and and separate worker system
per back-end and I in the end we chose
this time to write a different worker
per back-end now this means that there's
a bit of copy-paste overhead which
actually is definitely an anti-pattern
if you if you find yourself copying and
pasting code lots of times it normally
means you've done something wrong but in
this case I decided that it was actually
just a little bit of overhead that can
be explained because it means that if I
need to treat vendors different vendor
systems slightly differently and I don't
have to treat them generically if a
particular vendor has a particular quirk
I could address that in that back-end
worker system without having to have
that hack in all of our back-end worker
systems and I use the system called
napalm
because allowed us to come continue with
ansible when we're addressing network
stacks rather than addressing as well as
addressing servers it allowed us to
quite a lot of Technology consistency
and it means that we can do switch a
server drop switch outs really really
easily because we just run an 8-pound
command that says roll out the whole
config and and the and that's a that's
our device emergency strategy done it
comes for free with napalm yeah as I
said here there's no need for a specific
software feature just an operational
process saying this is how to do it is
that he's okay
now um something that I I don't come
from a developer background I come from
a network engineering background and one
of the things that's actually helped me
write code this so far being quite
reliable is as I learned how to do
automated software testing in at a
previous organization that did automated
networking it was completely new to me
at the time but I will probably credit
and also mated software testing is the
thing that took me from a mediocre
script cert as someone who's confident
enough to actually write more
complicated architectures the the
important software testing architecture
mantra to learn is red green refactor
read write the test first before you
write the code run the test the tests
will work
the co doesn't exist then write the code
run the test the test goes green because
the code exists and you wrote it
properly then refactor the code to make
it more efficient run the test has it
gone red has it gone green you start
with a working state you can make
improvements to your code for efficiency
for readability or to make it work
better as a library that you you just
call for example and because you've
started with a with with a simplest
format for that code and prove that the
test works you can then write more
complicated stuff and check that it
still works by running the same tests
red green refactor then I use because we
use Python I use PI tests as a as a
framework for testing our our back-end
there are lots of methodologies on
automated software testing and as I
mentioned because I'm not from a pure
software development background I found
the unit testing methodology way you
mock outcomes and you mock data and then
run tests against that mock data quite
difficult to understand and off and
didn't I found that pretty hard and but
I found that writing integration tests
that in my development environment went
and did the thing for real
and then indicated whether it works or
not to actually be quite easy and and it
has my back so if you like me you might
find the the methodology of integration
testing rather than unit testing is is
easier to adopt right lots of tests
write tests for everything write to us
for everything he writes and remember to
cover desired exceptions where something
is important here's an example on the on
the screen now writing a test to make
sure that a regular user through our API
can look at their own contact record and
then check that it can't see all the
records to check that the thing that you
want to work works but also check that
the thing that you want to catch the
exception that you want to catch and can
be can be triggered as well and you run
the run the test
run these tests from scratch every time
I write a block of code you know it's
really really lightweight every time I
write anything run the test write some
more run the test you can actually
develop framework so that you can run
the test and carry on writing whilst you
whilst you're writing the next bit of
code and have something like a growl
notification pop up and say hey you you
broken something go back it's it really
does catch stuff the longer I think
there's a there's an efficiency from
writing tests and that you get because
he spend a lot less time debugging even
though he's spending time writing the
test it's an investment this is what an
error looks like okay this this would
have been quite a good one because I'm
Pete well it looks like as I've made a
mistake that's broken generating quotes
which this is what I said well this is
what an error looks like it goes back it
tells you what you've done wrong the
great thing about this when you're
writing automated tests is when you're
writing it tells you what you or you've
done wrong and it's much easier to go
back and fix a bug when your own
computers telling you you've made a
mistake here in this library in this
module then it is trying to figure out
something because a week after you
rolled out a change
someone from accounts can no longer send
an invoice so a couple a couple of extra
thoughts and there are lots and lots of
ways of expressing information to
customers lots and lots and lots of them
and I really can't stress enough the
value of expressing information that you
know to customers in the JSON format
because so many third-party databases
like peering DBA are making their
available information available it with
Jason you'll find that lots of people in
the room that are writing their own
applications and scripts and reporting's
systems that are based on looking in
those databases if you as their vendor
can also Express data in the same format
all of your stuff can be plugged into
work that other people are already doing
that I can't stress enough the value of
if you have to pick a way of expressing
information to customers Jason's the way
of doing it
so what is the single source of truth
it's there is the data model and that
you make available by your series of
tools that that's under the control of
all departments not just the engineering
department but all departments can
control the information so that they all
have a vested information in keeping
accurate which is used to configure
services and the network elements that's
accessible to all departments and
accessible to customers as well so that
they can perform more self-service tasks
information in in in one place and one
tool has generated as so many
efficiencies that have a significant
benefit to our organization and not
least one such as for example our
account managers are able to do some of
our first line support for example using
the tools that we give them which helps
account managers do the thing that they
really want to do which is help their
customers we generated so many
efficiencies that I can't stress enough
how I'm happy with how we've got to
without with the automation work that
we're doing ok I don't know if there's
any time for any questions but if
anybody has any questions you can either
grab me in the hallway in the breaks or
a somewhat the microphones now if it's
time Steve is there time yep there is so
if anybody has any questions I'd be
really really happy to take some hi
John O'Brien University of Pennsylvania
could you speak briefly about the
technology alternatives that the
significant alternatives you've
considered and why you went with the
stack you described ok so there's a lot
of so the vendor specific controllers
but you can use that that allow you to
control network state control network
configuration rollout network changes
that give you a head start you you've
got to do a lot less writing software if
you're using your vendors like contrail
for juniper or or something like that
that that takes you further along in the
network Automation element but I wanted
to be really really vendor agnostic I
didn't want to actually be tied to any
particular part of the system and when
you write your own API layer and workers
stack yourself you have 100% control in
vendor selection in the future as long
as the vendor has a programmatic
interface an API anything that's not
telnet an a expects script anything
better than that
then you've got no you're not tied to
any particular vendor I happen to really
like a vendor but one day they might
upset me I hope they don't and if I do
I'm not tied to their provisioning
system so it can move in terms of things
like ODL and the software controller and
utilities for orchestration that offers
again I found it just as easy to use may
pom and it was less for me to learn I'd
already learned ansible which I needed
to use to control our servers anyway but
figuring out napalm was almost no extra
work so it was it was a sure to step up
that learning a different open-source
controller for example and also I I
didn't really find something out there
that allowed me to reverse back into the
business you know wanting to understand
and if I literally want to be able to
express a product and make a make that
roll out from our quoting system how
would I plug that into something which
is purely focused on network
configuration States or configuration
management for example I'm gonna have to
do a load of work anyway so I might as
well just do this because then I know
the data model is exactly as we need it
I don't know if that answers your
question or is it that's fine thank you
very much for a nice talk
thank you hi there hello Andrew Danforth
Linode I just wanted to talk about you
said you had a you wanted to do a single
source of truth across all departments
was that an effort on you
part two coordinate across departments
to get that going in other words how did
you get buy-in from multiple departments
to have a single source of truth so I I
don't make any I don't make any guesses
that it's easy and Olding all companies
but I was very very very lucky to be
able to do this on a completely
greenfield idea on this occasion and one
of the reasons that we wanted to start
this business and offer this product is
because we actually wanted to understand
the most efficient way of delivering I
access as a service possible and there's
no way of doing that without modeling
and making this repeatable replicatable
and modeling everything that we know
it's the only logical way of approaching
the product that we wanted to build so I
was very very very lucky that actually
at the time that we we decided to build
this business everybody wanted to
contribute on a lane efficient system
that works a little bit as the way I
described it they we had to evolve the
idea of a little bit because everybody
had good ideas but there was so much
buying based on the fact that we were
frustrated with the legacy model that
that everybody wanted to do this work
and I you it's so important to get
buy-in from a whole organization you
have no option but to do that and in a
larger organization with in trend
entrench processes and that that will be
more difficult but actually if you do
other processes and that you can model
in your in your data model that you
actually already part the way there if
you're a process driven organization in
sales and finance and stuff anyway
that's actually half of the work done
figuring out what it is that you need to
do so it might be possible hopefully
it's possible to get buy-in across
departments if you're already quite
processed arisen thank you thank you I
don't see any more questions so I think
that's a thank you so thank you so much
everybody