welcome everybody good morning while
show
shisha and talked about attacking
a be softer I will attack them from a
different perspective and I will talk
about the taking a be best practices are
the book represent your
as trying to work with the awesome
people at UC Irvine's the problem Tyler
Perry Larson Stephen Crane
Michael fronts and Richard Bartel from
Manion arm if you look at the picture on
this
on his first slide how similar our does
bucks the DC
Rd how many different
families back families DC actually
all those books are the same underlying
back
their chests small genetic variations
are in the codes in the DNA of the book
that lead sir
very different a very different look up
to use dis bucks
and that's exactly what what's happening
is melberg are few families out there
and attackers use manual diverse
application
to have a different forms of detection
and common solution
for Melbourne depictions still rely on
signatures in similarity metrics
and in this talk will see that those
metrics
ants practices are no longer effective
so
the Melbourne landscapers is changing
how many different now for families do
you guys know out there
5 10 how many of those are actually
active at a at a specific point in time
there only very few male her family's
active at anything a point in time and
it's like a big
monoculture out out there and um on the
other hand
there are sour since of variants that
hipster
arm the Melbourne feeds off anti-virus
companies everything always
so all a by companies are actually
overrun by lots and lots of samples
and attackers use different forms of
Packers to hide the actual code
and manually diverse if I to sample was
just a little bit so they can get
biter a anti-virus engine and on the
other hand
it's all about the money right attackers
generate new samples defenders classics
by those samples
and it's just an endless loop the keeps
going and going and usually
as the system is right now attackers are
already at actually can use
very low res a real amount of resources
to generate a lot of reported 80
companies and
I'll argue that is resources that the 80
companies spend
should better be spent for something
else so for example
research it would actually solve the
problem or better security practices
like you seen in the gonna talk before
so
the Melber
distribution is like an ongoing now
ongoing
arms race between attackers and
defenders and it always starts
whereas and you now for instance that is
generated by
by an attacker and it continues the
attacker will distribute and send it out
an attack a bunch of targets continue
move along
and just spread them out as fast as it
goes at one point in time in AB bender
book at the first sample using one of
those feats and distributed to all the
other AB vendors
it might take up to months or years
until they have time to actually
analyzed at sample
and they will do first some automatic
and then some manual analysis of the
tumbling classified at one point in time
then they will update their signatures
send it out
and as soon as the sample is detected by
a bunch of
are a bunch of EV engines detector both
read a verse if I and send out the new
sample
and the game continues its like endless
fun right so
unfortunately defenders are always
in her empty limit its first of all
newly diversified samples are just not
detected by the
I did techniques that are used in
current systems and every time an
attacker read oversee fis
it's basically an you attack and
you have to start the whole up have
touched
have to start the whole spiel again and
just redo it from scratch
also the attacker is has a specific at
you my lover spreads very very fast
updating signatures and distributing
might have worked in the early nineties
but nowadays many can infect
all the computers there on the internet
in the matter of
minutes or hours it just doesn't work
anymore
you need to find other ways to hear are
to protect
up and the defenders usually have to
fight the time lag
between the analysis and yup they did
signatures which
takes a huge amount of time in between
now to question s can we
automate this process AB and
AB vendors notice or have known this for
quite a while now
but you're still locked into these old
practices
just don't want to move along now the
question is from the attacker side
can meet give an additional ensure even
and a higher adds to the attacker
and yes we can so
the core idea is that
the compiler is at the core of and
efficient automation
and we can use a different compiler
techniques to
enable a faster and more sorrow
diversification of in vidor binaries and
then
attacked the system's you in foster
arm in this talk and introducing fully
automatic diversity from elber
and it's basically an additional attack
that sparse
are any similarity based matching and it
should drive the point home that
similarity-based matching is not the
solution it's time to move along
and gets get on better security
practices
arm I'm inherently lazy so I don't want
to
are don't want to run a lot of love code
and a lot of manual work to produce
my huge set of male refineries so I'll
just do some automation right and a
compiler is the perfect place for that
so if you have to source code of a
specific
application we can run it through the
compiler and it usually generates
one single instance of Melber and the
current practices that
attackers used ok the generate the
binary and then run Packers on top of it
to generate individual samples
these Packers are very limited because
it just worked under
on the actual machine coat and the
compiler or regular compiler
always produce the same binary but
you're adding a different achche
you're heading a randomization component
in the compiler and using some flexible
flexibility in the language to produce a
different that
of Melbourne every time you're under
compiler and I will go into more detail
later on in the talk but that's
basically the
overview of to keep that your use so its
compiler base diversification
burn lots of information is available
and you can run a lot of fun stuff on
top of it
so the outline of the talk is as
follows: first
people discuss the state of the art of
Melbourne detection what is actually out
there what is used by the current
machines
then we will introduce now the
diversification is the new threat
an indent quickly talk about some
possible mitigation strategies
or better security practices that could
work on top of that
so what is the state of the art
technology texan
how to be fined now there and how to be
fine teas
ardizzone both its so
we have to know that melberg detection
is inherently limited in three ways:
first the fall performance and AB engine
should not slow down your computer too
much
so it is only a very limited amount of
resources that you can spend
on detecting or 22 see if something is
actually my older or not
on an individual computer second
now for scanning as always limited you
to the precision it he can get
arm based on the similarity metric or
detective Nick picnics
you always run into false positives and
false negatives
false negatives and whole buncha errors
in
it's it's just a pain also
%uh latency as the about the cert
limitation
there's always a very long time lag as
we've seen in the inner circle before
between the initial spratt of another
sample
and the time that actual users machines
are protected from from that Alber
so you look into the three different
ways of
detection mechanisms first the ball
the all this detection mechanism is
signature-based
server using a simple signature to
compare it and if you're wondering by
the way that's
George W signature up there the second
one
is static analysis so you're running
some
analysis on top of the the binary but
you're not executing it
and the third one as some behavioral
based matching
are you running the the binary leader in
a in a sandbox are some other
analysis scheme in public for to extract
additional information out of it
and each of these approaches has its
pros and cons
and we'll look into more detail a little
bit of each have one
first the fall signature-based detection
which is the bread and butter technique
for AV
and it has a lot of advantages to be
honest um
its it is very fast and very
are very ball known in a lot and yet yes
that you compare
the binary against the database known
bad samples
so you have to match a pattern according
like there different kinds of similarity
metrics that they have different
substrings regular expressions or
anything else
but yet you're basically is that you
have a big database of known bad
examples
and your matching the current sample
that you're analyzing against a set of
known bad once
and atlantis's art at it's very very
fast
and it has a very low false positive
rate if you're a little bit clever about
how the encoder signatures
you will have a pretty good match
unfortunately
arm the position is limited to known bad
samples
and are it takes time to to update the
signatures and to spread it and
are there's there's the big latency most
the second analysis technique is static
a binary analysis are setting analysis
based detection
and you search for potentially bad
patterns and
it like API call system calls and it's
like a lot of her sticks that are run on
top of that
arm and you're trying to detect those
statistics on top of it
are defined as its low overhead you can
just run the binary analysis and expect
that
each I calls and then decide if it's
good or bad according to two specific or
not up
a specific score unfortunately you
introduce false positives
along with that technique and there
depending on the
on how precise her stickers it can
actually be quiets quite bad
and also it's based on Bell known her
istics if you're a Melbourne writer you
can try to end
you Bates those respects and and get
around it
and finally behavior-based detection
up which executes a file in some form
and later a virtual machine or or
something like that
arm and detects possible that
modifications on top of it
it's the most precise if
the are if the molar does not tried to
evade detection
ordered the activated emulation or
there some other kind of bug involved
but unfortunately it comes is very high
overhead and
usually you cannot spend that much of of
time on a user's machine to detect that
for every single sample
so to summarize now for protection a
summarize the current practices Miller
detection
there's a large attack surface it's very
hard
to tact and all there's basically an
arms race between manual labor
certification and the actual
AB engines and the signature-based
detection techniques are similar to beat
detection me
techniques already lose precision or
effectiveness against that the mental
diversification
also the defenders have to cope with
very limited amount of resources
for the fall on a target machine up
forty and all others in the lab and to
push out new signatures a small
and there's no perfect solution out
there you girl you'll have false
positives
and/or negatives or a huge performance
impact or all of them together
server already hosts but can meet do
actually worse than that and the look
into Melbourne diversification right now
so
let's move from Packers on the binary
level to the source code level into the
compiler
and will use come %uh automation to
generate millions of Melbourne in
now for binaries there are no longer
similar to each other in an instance
and just just pop them out as fast as
possible
arm and I'll use softer diversification
for dat
their techniques works as follows:
usually our compiler
translates from a high-level language a
low-level language and the compiler
translates between these two formats
arm the language specification defines
the amount of transformations that are
allowed
and many per or most programming
languages XD full art said
undefined behavior and two compilers use
that set
of undefined behavior to actually
optimized application
any good compiler makes a deterministic
best guess
according to what did you but both
roadies
our best practices out of are
removed as best practices and at
randomization in the compiler
and according to the ground in value a
value but just money fine
the compilation process and generate
different binary all the time
and if he for example look into C&C plus
plus
those languages of rest a lot of
liberties that allow changes to the
to the runtime layout and to data
compiled code
so for example we can change the data
layout that's out there
our data structure layout honest
accurate can reorder local variables
understand ac
are we can run simplest keeping dollars
this and reorder structures
across the whole program and so on and
there's there's a lot of stuff we can do
just for today to Leo itself also be can
change the layout for a heap uptick to
beacon
modify all that and it's it's pretty
fancy what we can actually do
and fur coat began even do more than
that
rights %uh for example we can play
around with the register allocator
so began just shuffle the kinda
registers that are used
we can arm starve to register allocator
to produce more spill code and all that
and began to all the fancy stuff so that
any produced code will not look similar
to the
to the are to any other sample
we can change instructions selections
orbiting
even work on a more higher level on the
on the basic block law-abiding
basic blocks leading basic block merging
and just shuffling does basic blocks
around so that we can
maximize the differences between the are
between the different planets
so if we take these concepts from softer
diversification
to Melbourne diversification we see that
are right now we can start off with any
softer diversifying compiler
and liked I just explained softer
diversification ride
their original goal of softer
diversification was to protect
running applications against are against
any exploits said it Jing nynex but you
only work on your local machine
but we can use it for for bad practices
a small
and look into diversify a in compilers
cute for a from elber
forget years degenerate unique binaries
and minimize
common substrings your code or data
across the whole binary said it is no
longer possible to use any kind of
similarity metric
to compare toasters binaries arm
performance over had of the binder did
runs on your machine
is usually not an issue for us if you
don't care if the
compiled my over has 20 percent over had
between different samples
also RB diversify both code and data
lower
layout and look from for maximizing are
differences between individual samples
also
look into static data small you don't
want your
the simple string command giving away
all your secret
our secrets values that use our secret
strings that use
implemented this on top
of lol BM arm
it's fully implemented small changes to
the
code generator code Lee outer
register allocator spectrum the outer
and so on
and also some they'd obfuscation passes
on top of it
arm inputs is actually Elodie embed code
so you're pretty general if it compiles
lol embed code
we can't just generate the a diversified
finally out of it
and spit out as many buyers as possible
arm
but as you know this is the research
product retook the research project
and the code is very messy so as an
academic
and fortunate Canada released the source
code
not just kidding I'm not like any other
academics and
are both just released the source code
on get up and you can just forget of
and try it out for yourself
so implemented all the basic our basic
diversification techniques run on top of
a softer diversifying compiler
and we have a stat a set of static
diversification techniques on top of it
this far
so you can just use it to diversify all
your static data
arm as I said well I have a couple of
help files to to get you started but
some up to
coats and edges are pretty rough and
bill add more diversification techniques
as we go along
and especially for are some kind of
graph-based matching
where you try to extract high-level draw
some pub of
the generate a code you could still use
some
similarity metrics that what's the what
sort that the current
diversification but working on does but
there's a first
first part of the code and you can get
access to it
so let's have a look at similarity
metrics
arm this is a simple graph
of a bunch of programs
used mostly to spec CQ applications
and generated a a bunch of different
are different binaries and compared
those two binary is
which is each other and look and what
kind of the the longest common
substrings
in bytes was between does those
different different binary its
and for most of the binaries we see that
like up did there's basically no
sup sequence that's longer than 20 or so
bytes
and just 20 bytes is usually just a
function prologue or function epilogue
like passing a couple of
are of argument
and those are usually not but signatures
for for your ATV engine
so it's already pretty effective issue
which is comparing the
the files are in a in a very simple way
I hope it in crash
its
poet did crash
all there you go
so the next light was a demo anyway
though just moved over
and see if we can start the are
just a demo in safe with the way we've
seen yesterday that there was usually
work pretty well
in during presentations right so let's
just try our best arm Here I am running
on a
Arbor is simple lower scale
on netbooks so the CPU is not to
not too good let's just look at the
the simple file that we look at arm
and it's a very simple see file are just
to show you the the power of the
statically the diversification of a
bunch of springs me to have a string
copy
and to print that's and we're good to go
right so
if you run it through GCC
we get the binary
and it prints the stuff and Rick good to
go
me look in to
Ste brings
and PCB have hello world through bar
arguments that %uh that this would give
it away
so let's just try
to divers who fired for now arm
run it through diversifying compiler and
you have produced
up nice little
little file and if you go down
we see that all the static data
has been are encrypt that using are
magic X or encryption right now
with some random values on the plus side
beaches we can just use any one time pat
and
been ever be start of the compiler
ads description code that just art the
crib to date on the fly
arm and generate the code automatically
and runs that code through the divers if
I compile a small
to change the code layout of that you
might now
wonder what to speed implication s
how fast is that stuff so let's just
run or generate 200 samples Ford is too
simple
simple program and you see it's
it goes up consider it random number
summer out there flying by
yeah it's 65 70 1890
and we've generated hundreds different
binaries
just for the simple 59 c:\program are
its various
fairly fast do you guys want to give me
to random values between one and a
hundred
first number 32
42 29
equal random values
42 and 44
and the Cedars
whole lot of different this between the
the two binary is and that's just for
dirt debris small
simple example even like a spectrum
invocation different thank frames
and use the same optimization settings
and all that
and receded there's just a huge
differences just for that
very very small three line program
that's out there
and if you move down to the
the code %uh to the actual data me see
that the date is very different to you
so you might wonder does it actually
work
let's shirts compile its
and its it's the same
hier so it actually runs now let me try
to recovered a presentation that diet
might as s office crest
trash all the time somebody should
should bust that software to you
no I don't want to recover
and
and that's the team affect right that
does it to you
and we're back
a maybe I should have plucked in these
random presenter that I found here under
on the speaker's desk so we've seen the
demo
it work fairly ball right ago play up
play around with that
its open-source bill at more stuff as we
as we go along
and this was basically the first
scenario that I just Joe
right so we do have a compiler out there
and beaches
use it to spit out as many different
different binary study half
and you've seen it it's pretty fast but
you can
let let it run for half an hour and you
will or you will have a couple of
million examples
the big advantages the beaches run
on the LO embed code therefore a beacon
it is a very quick way to produce
different
are different diversified samples
a second scenario that you look at is
up a self the Bersih fine Melber and
right now does is not fully implement at
but we've played around with it for a
bit
so usually you have your static Melber
binary you send out
to infect or two to run and other
machines
arm not just at an lol game optimization
core on top of it
that is added alongside with the malware
and along with that be at
the Melber up now for a bit code and DLO
DM but cut
so we can use in a milder itself
RB can call the alluvium optimizer that
just
diversifies the bit code and of the
Melbourne
and the lol EMCOR again and produces
new lead over 35 Miller as we go along
and spread from system to system
and basically every time you try the
Doosan
new random value and just goes along and
bull
have our self diversifying Melber that
has
even stronger guarantees than any packer
or stronger bigger change than any
packing gift
arm what kinda
mitigation practices are kind of
mitigation strategies can be follow
well we've seen that any signature-based
protection is basically basically host
to a win
with these 10 10 out of 10 I'm awesome
nice arm so
let's look at what we can do first of
all recede
are one option would be to recover some
high-level semantics from the code
extract some
some deeper behavior on top of it which
is which is very hot
for early heart and will result in yet
another arm race between
arm elber riders and to other defenders
we can do full behavioral analysis which
shoots
orville catch Mallard any point in time
but this is very compute incentive
are intended and you have to to think
about if you actually want to use all
these resources for that
or are prohibited in initial
intrusion and fix the the broken softer
educate user and just
educate them enough so that they don't
run any random suffered
its honor system arm
let's conclude this is an attack talk
after all by the mature to defeat the
solutions for it
um first of all
they were City debates Melber a
Melbourne detection and we have built
a fully automatic ever see fine compiler
that you can run on any mail ranch it's
been out as many samples as you want
are there's no need for Packers anymore
and you can get much higher a much
higher quality pictures using that
diversifying compiler
also we can adopt a new similarity
metrics
as we go along and removing up from an
arms race between
attackers and defenders to an arms race
between
defenders and compiler writers which
gives
attackers much more power because it
scales much better to
to just change the compiler once and
then open source IDE and other people
can use it on top of it
are lessons you can learn a top of that
don't rely on any simple static
similarity metrics
that can to speed are
mitigated with is very simple tactics
arm
move along and get better security
practices in shape
and is that a I would like to are to MI
talk
and ask for any questions that you guys
might have how many pizza
NTP do you think that that Davis
vacation and 2p do you have what you're
with your engine
would you estimate with the 32
reordering town
arm that's a good question I have no
idea
I would see a very huge amount like the
long the program is
like any any like just take a simple if
at any if you can you can swap the if
condition
for for your program or just look at
compiling
a when you compile a simple function are
you can't just change to their
register order it ed anything on
instruction or just
alright instrument and a new shuffling
part and if the
are if you don't get enough bit out of
that you can always at garbage
instructions right
so at the compiler level you can just
taken other application and beef that
our application in today
into the translator code because you
know which registers are currently taken
I too can you can just scale it up as
far as you want
at cast so when a
have a flight Australian did in 2010 VX
class
and in the in the hash other time which
was a fuzzy ash where
the was it was sort of it was resistant
who and certain types of this type up
for authentication metrics to measure
something against is more fuzzy yes
um been diff is actually pretty good at
detecting
our diversification right now arm on the
downside
runs for a couple of minutes for each
binary
so it's just more compute resources that
you spent
in addition to that oMG are looking into
ways how we can defeat that to buy
by changing that a control flow graph
and
are and other things so be running in a
compiler I began at more and more stuff
septet
last question at I saw Michael Francis
work in 2000 8
on does first fck she gets baffles me
just started a nice I got a lot of Dhaka
grants
and I thought this was be used in the
App Store with Apple took to create
unique binaries for every download is
this is a trial not in the App Store
but are I guess it was used in Mozilla
was it
that it was there with his initial use
case to produce a new binary for
everybody that downloaded
just just push the the compilation into
the clout
and then everybody to download the
binary its its own individual binary and
if you find and exploit on your local
version it will not run
on any diversified person somewhere else
on the edit
serbia at the the diversification on top
of it
and if change some some other stuff for
Firdous working
our not to questions the first one being
what is the advantage of this
infrastructure over
the zone BZ mister engine from 2002
which
just takes a binary in them lipset and
and start inserting it'll
and %uh the second question is there's a
tool
built by the University of Denmark that
in 2005 did although instruction
diversification and control-flow
flattening at the same time
hallways you to about it um let's answer
the first question
first arm you're always limited
if you lift from from binary on the are
for example the all that they did ever
suffocation is much much much harder
if you if you just let you can you can
do all the coat the reciprocation
or a lot of the coat diversification by
doing by Nicole that thing
but you will have a very hard time
changing the data structures
arm Ford the second question can you
say going so there's a tool book called
Yabloko Ubuntu researchers at the
University of Kent
and I think it's by now pretty old its
from 2005 06
as modification to gcc that those both
the modification of instruction stream
but also
fully implements control flow flattening
and two all these other things that
would screw any formal
for structural matching house YouTube it
all I'm not too familiar with the other
one so I'll have to look into that
arm II guess for to
today to the data they were suffocation
as well %uh
I'm not sure they do today to
diversification but I mean that's a
what 10 line change arm but you have to
run is keeping dollars is right and and
look for
if your data structures at one point in
time passed into
are into connally to structure into a
system call or anything like that
so it's more than 10 lines the yeah
a opec if the operation will be view
use this against the program like fire I
am at the end of the day
it as the same thing if I had a law
handle
so arm fire I
runs in a are runs your sample in a in a
virtual machine and tries to expect some
behavior arm
forward that kind of protection which is
wait the couple minutes or do random
leader
but really this detection you can at
that on top of it
in the compiler small if you want to or
or aren't as the
a long delay before you run your
malicious activity
IRA's mostly behavioral based detection
and I my question is a
the tourney is looking for behavioral me
not looking for
differences in the binary yep but it
runs with a lot higher
much higher overhead right to spending
more resources into
so eventually you're gonna one goal to
opium optimizer
which has also been diversified Ando
it have you look better with the size of
the binary will be
about time yeah it's the a bookmaker
bites
right new them did you did you have a
chance to
run your staff against the X clamps
okay what I have a try against any
customization engine
the they said would pick up in a
polymorphic malware its and and group
them to see dr.
you you know put up the tree pollen the
branch all beyond all
arm be tried expect such behavior by
doing some
are some
more im inform matching but it wasn't
very effective
okay iight cool occurs or few months ago
some French guys PD's on opens opposite
name
ol million which seemed to
have a lot open at with the opposite so
can you comment on whether
the copy 00 p.m.
what project all well-being know that
they were being a little sufficient
okay all LLVM is also puzzled
I mean do you know about and he really
good I few months ago he doesn't know
what is project cost
so i think thats all over that between
your position that was it
okay it seems to be a pretty hot topic
right um
the there are different diversifying
compilers there's the one
by Michael front stairs art there's one
from
bird you did bergson top of GCC and
are and all that but most diversifying
compare compilers focus on
arm on softer diversification so for
diversification for security purposes
and this kind of spins the you to work
some more attacked based
approach