thanks for coming up buddy hope it went
on MLK I am
I'm Nick Walker this mccauley going to
POSCO talk about Windows Phone 8 so
up what what is Windows Phone 8s
Microsoft's latest mobile offering I
with certain
significant changes since Windows Phone
7 I ask only third position in market
share with quite a small
share overall as far as percentages go I
am
with Android obviously covering most the
market I was being a
I am pop only more and more applications
are here in the market
as a lot tougher ongoing development
from big corporations try a hot stock to
the market
something to a the market shares going
to increase quite quickly over the
coming months and years
I am and on top it up a lot of
I am enterprises Akali tryna and roller
and users a copper platform but which
will also draw a picture
I am as far as developer documentation
security however there's not that much
I while Ms De Anza really great source
for
functional went development information
how to write
a functional application there's not a
law
as far as security documentation there's
a lot surfaced of like kind of
Ste general recommendations on what to
do buspar Senegalese the API's is really
nothing at all
I so this talk Cup
aims to address this problem from two
angles one things the developers to
watch out for when you develop into
Windows Phone application
and two hot form as a security assessor
a Windows Phone application assessment
so
are given to a rundown of what we're
gonna talk a lot and general so we'll
talk a lot about
about the background of Windows Phone 8
and how it differs from Windows Phone 7
up home assessment a box assessment
marketplace applications
was required in the assessment how to
address
witnesses been found in the platform
also discuss
public research originated from the
jailbreak seen
and their impact on applications carry a
Windows Phone
8 I am took a little bit about
local data protection application some
boxer local data storage
love about encryption also discuss
a both Ligia might be /c mechanisms
available to users
and how to use them securely and also
discuss some
public not so legit my PC methods have
been scuppered
I that kind of open open those one
applications to
a security issues and office a little
bit
no talk to be complete without a little
bit of Temple validation so all covered
up
so
a little bit more about when those funny
background its arm
originally but a Windows Phone 7 as was
based on
when those competition colonel when dust
bunnies no longer based on 10 see
I miss the most of attire for the dust
desktop wasn't the last one the NT
Kernel in comparison to
Windows Phone 7 much just remove the
restriction the only
OM's can run native goat and now a
third-party developers
have access to that apostle nice post
one among its code is in
donuts a law native code isn't C-plus
possum 10
when Artie is also possible to write
pasting of five applications but also
backed by the
Munish see shot layer ensemble so
due to the move to the NT Kernel they
the security model is based on
standard anti security primitives such
as tokens ACLs
on it some the somewhat similar to metro
to stock up
Applications Inc up containers I which
are
influenced by the I capabilities that
your application
requests in the application manifest so
when you develop in Windows Phone a
application
but this is kind of the a screen you'll
see
and Visual Studio eyes just I'm just put
this up to kind of show you
the structure a lot about structural
Windows Phone application song its
top right all the aspects of the
application the
once highlight is the up manifest which
defines
a various config options about your
application similar to the manifest to
get on Android
platform your request she capabilities
and and I alright BC mechanisms are
kinda defined in a
I am on top about you of
the da sample files which are basically
XML files and define the user interface
I am
is also aspects about the confined I'll
at the waist up the interface ties into
the sea chocolate underneath
and not see underneath that you going to
dot CS files in drives
that the actual see shaman is called the
drug application
so I am these are the core security
controls that you get access to
on I Windows Phone 8 will cover those in
more detail laying
standard some boxing coat sign in you
explain migrations
so some books in itself on the way that
the the actual security models
derived is I some options based on not
contain a model
which excuse ops in separately privilege
containers
which are provisioned runtime: based on
their positions at their request
so you got a trusted computing base the
TCB
I which is basically day execution
contact for all trust that coats ok I'll
coat
I and the lease perles chamber
underneath is where I am
all application that's cute lot new OS
components and drivers any
possibly less that don't need to be ron
is really hyper alleged
on the dentist early spring Liz chamber
to produced a talk service
base they all use a long list of runs in
the least privilege chamber where
possible
I reduce the attack serviceapril it's
cold I
needs as much as possible into these Lee
least privileged chambers
so these chambers have provisioned a a
wrong time to your application based on
the
a capabilities the application request
so it's a %um
request access to the SD card or
I am send and I'll go into some asses
those will be applied to the container
when the content start
and these capabilities are also called
down to the filesystem
and registry access is also a overstreet
is an
this technique so they still dollars
down through this I am
contain a model so there are a few
differences however one year consider in
how applications deployed so the
security restrictions apply to an
optician
depend on how the application actually
put on Sat device
so thus to age can do it you can install
on top of the market place
we can develop for unlock your phone on
site loaded up the patient
so applications aside loaded face
less restrictions when you're in some
box and not
site loaded up with haitians can modify
and other side the lead
loaded up addition some books directory
include in
their at the install location up
honorees so
a siloed application actually modify the
code of another sign a lot of attention
so you have to consider when you test
inside look it up it's not necessarily
representative
of an application deployed marketplace
state sauce
something's consider when you do an
application test
so as far as code signing those I am all
OS components assigned by Microsoft
which of the G standard
Tampa protection reduces your talk
surface for mahler
and restricted privilege escalation so
that you can be sure that when you
applications run in a container its the
environment same know inside code will
run
I am all marketplace applications must
be signed
in order to be installed I am on a non
develop from what device
a slight differences when you do talking
about develop from
device so
the actual sign in the marketplace
applications occurs not before goes up
to the up
up to the marketplace pot jury in the
marketplace and Justin process
I am up point all the
applications able to marketplace also
protected use an
play ready DRM I'll which is then
stripped
once installed onto about device
so the coat sign in seems to have a few
discrepancies not really go entirely to
the bottom of
I so native among his coat seem
different effected
post-installation up a with post
inflation Parchin
so tamper with money coat a seems to
work fine
you can a staunch got accessed I am so
far system
which also more about getting later you
can modify
the dotnet and applications run just
fine
any modifications native code cause a up
to crush
I so as a useful tool when you talking
about doing
functional testing for things I
certificate been in in
cut the more secure applications
but it's a new dawn echoed can patch it
on a problem carry on with the test and
if you're in a Mon its coat done if you
and sorry in native code and in a
struggle and it's gonna just crush on
so we're trying to get Obama currently
in its miss something with looking at
the moment
so obviously would have been mature
platform
you've got standards a explanation
protections are you expect to see on
all the other platforms like I S a law
a annex unstuck cookies
so as far as encryption goes a
does support full device encryption off
for some reason
s not available for personal use so if
so your personal
Windows Phone 8 device it does no UI
option not
way to access in the UI to enable full
device encryption
I and i can only be enabled when you and
rolled device into a corporate
environment
I am for personal users our there is
something called the Data Protection API
which is it can be used to encrypt
specific pieces a day a last last up to
the developer of those applications to
be used as a
San API available when on the developers
write the application itself
I the some issues with the PAPI the talk
about later
I you should be aware these
so p
in the contacts a normal market place
applications a
because %uh some box your cigar a no
access
to I application another stations de Oro
binaries
I marketplace downloads pipe and SSL
like Windows Phone 7 well on Windows
Phone 7 that
sniffs the connection between the
marketplace and the phone and pulled the
a sup the in application installation
file from the stream
with no DRM aunt extract on to black box
us the application that waste are
that's not there is on the Windows Phone
8 marketplace
manual download and install option which
lunch spot the
sup itself down what is up saw strength
from the marketplace
stepped onto the SD card phone and
install a device
baugh the is up itself obviously still a
player to dr. a monthly installed the
device
so you can just extra coat and take a
look I
you first install to the bus so does
this mean that you can't
black box assassin and a nap because not
just the coat
well fortunately some volumes of
slipped up Malout I am was to break the
some books
so on the a tu vez a on the XT forums
there's attack a wolf us
a got full false as much as the heir to
the synthesis
how it's done so there's a capability
called
I D cup interrupt services I am which
Acer so capable in your quest as an OEM
to provide slightly high level of access
so the device functionality
so things like change in the registry I
am
you can do with the capability I am
says functionally compromise the
security model
this problem so for more info about the
this capability itself not covered up im
much detail here
Kosovo recovered Alex already covered up
a previously
now look at the a research the word on
into Windows Phone 7
a t just google so that will find
so the up the sums on a2 thats
house a diagnostic application which
isn't directly accessible
I am it's a hidden up which is used for
I'm sure was used for debugging a
development I'm it contains up on I'm
big puncher functionally including a
registry at a his office he got the
captain Sourav services capability
so the Reg Treader is an accessible
through any in the face
at all there's no waited directly up to
Sir
I am bought through phone bill a little
discuss later
I am the at a can be called directly
on opened to make gradual changes
so these two registry keys all the
registry keys that say
which user and
a day a directory the anti-peace service
so that's false from so you
do the issue the exploit the
vulnerability to a little talk about it
in a bit and modify these registry case
to change the NTP service to run system
not such a mess that they had our itself
from the router
C Drive rather than just standard user
pictures and profile
pitches and videos doughtery restart the
phone
negotiable filesystem at to see its best
system
so 19 see everything on the phone I you
can go start taking a look up the that
sucks up as a
marketplace applications installed gonna
look in that
application install path which is
available on the
cedar programs and then a GUID the GUID
he's
on Nazi Krupp if you go to the
marketplace on
on on a web browser and search for the
application
the GUID for the opposite actually in
the URL
for the application seeking just extra
I'll get off to go
surgent fine I am
people of all your money is done they
have coats and install reverse unlike
any other blood loss assessment you
doing another
I am mobile device and fine is awesome
bonobos
so few little side notes I am
welcome from been removed or any for a
moment
con functionally from Anne the device
isn't much to look up
I am it's still possible to restore this
in the a .contacttable Oprah container
because the windows the win files the
windows update files
actually contain the book signed
versions of town Ackman prompt
and FTP you just let rip struck these
from the
I when file package in with your
application install these
ops I'm you can't really do much with
obviously because you unleash perles
chamber
paw is a stock future work
sauna talk about local de protection now
I am go over the dept action API
so was a dick de papi has been in
Windows
has been in Windows sewing since a when
those two thousand
s designed to be as simple as possible I
am
it's used in a bunch when those tools
shoe store you wifi passwords
Saudi he credits I am and its little is
too much that's
encrypt a 2.2 lol you'll protect which
takes a
plain text law on wall TV but cipher
text
on on protect obviously does a reverse
so that's that
that's what's the native methods are
protected lol
but that you can also act as a botnet
left to access those and I
system DAW crypto system that's carried
opera talk with the doc
attacked data class I am its
a yes 2226 encrypt it blobs quite
literally only deals with the
and corruption and decryption it does
not say deal with any storage o'clock
today subsidize I left up to the
developers to
stall that they are properly
so abs workout that stop on desktop it
works
differently to the phone so on a desktop
the keys are derived from the user
credential
is in PB KDF to a per-user keys
a derived installed and filesystem onto
the set
not in the updated directory which means
because you've got to use a key
you can access and all the users that
are not contact source: someone uses
I am application these is adept at right
dept action API's one user eight starts
a McRib today it does
even northern same filesystem able to
access the files they cannot see the
crib but there because the context
is different Adams a and Krypton
there's a a caveat to this and not this
alls
you can specify a flock when used the
name a player
a to encrypt the locals and prefer the
local system teamster the user
contacts key which means a as he is the
key then
any is on the local system can access it
it sounds
so on the phone slightly
different and whether keys are stored
stored on those dark tuzla
but the issue is the among we're not
sure whether it's because a run on the
same music
a user ID but different contexts or
book all applications seem to use the
same drive must the key on the bus
so what location isn't that protection
AP on Windows Phone 8
not saying should they be able to access
that data a
on the only way you can do that is with
the sums on the bus
using the and TP book I
they cannot see just the crypt opticians
daya so should the somewhat be broken in
the future the Data Protection API
tunnel
becomes more the day of the station and
API than anything at all
I'm so something to watch out for work
only because we were only able to test
this
a on the AM Best we don't really know
officer
device specific issue I'm pick up with
one the somewhat it broke on another
device we can confirm
find out
so I can you kinda demonstrate this
issue I'm
we use crypto notes that a mystery as a
really simple de papi up
Corp use the up cope went for to call
tech today up
I'm not safe a block got to blow up you
can rights
rights of a lot location: up I calls on
protect on a
on that block I don't see the copies of
out the somewhat
Prince a somewhat your application just
call the crypt about a plain text
plan and democrats are not supplication
so how do you mitigate against this
issue
well locally the de papi a allows
a second ha sprays to be passed as a
second Brahma
I S base be a developer supplied
extricating was basically does
I a second possibly encryption site uses
the
a much the key father
unser and then Rita read/write City
based on the password is passed and
and the call to protect or attack method
I am
yeah I'm a case against the issue above
sea doc .doc
secondary key is obsolete and securing
critical
and storage atop should probably not be
on the device and should be
store else well got from a web service
securely
K on the Passover to my colleague Thomas
a okay so I'm next talked about the Data
Protection Act II
I'm I'm gonna talk a transmission
security in their data
I'm when it's a transmitted across the
wire
the so I am on Windows Phone a
its parts tell us 1.0 by default
and wires like if you compare this to to
Iowa's I wes is on at a last one point
during the latest
as the case so Windows Phone is a little
bit behind them
like that and but there's no there's no
weak ciphers at all supported
on his life is abundant when your pets
are crap and Inc a strat
and the one big problem at the moment is
there's no way to
well on and ride and there's a way to
override certificate checking
and this is a common problem with I'm
dried-up occasions where
they day into they override the
validation function and then
using self-signed certificates than a
the applications per se it's an
acknowledged any upset if carriers
and but on Windows Phone there's no
actual way to do this
there's no APIs and in the language in
c-sharp are we not see to actually a
disables difficult validation so this is
that this is a good thing
but and also means that you can't do I
things like
client certificates clients to forget
Sasol
am and also for high security
applications as well
and the there's no API's doing pending
because you can't have access to the
certificate chain
than it's really difficult to actually
am
much implementing in Windows Phone 8
applications currently
and but same as well
like there's a lot about the cations at
the moment which
at elder spot which don't use SSL
applications which
you'd really expects the right to be
using SSL
so things like Instagram I'm that do
there
%uh session tokens oh if I i'm up a
cleartext
and and as I mentioned as well that ops
at if they it's a fail to backed then
there's no way to actually proceed after
an SSL Ariza cut
and so I use a car actually arthritis
and so in summary for transmission
security there's not
lot really can survive other than
there's a lot to have control at the
moment by developers
there's no way to specify ciphers
there's no a two-out
override the validation checks and
if you do want to implement pending and
it it's possible to use their commercial
library
and are you cured implemented using
win32 APIs
and the problem with using win32 is
it takes a large amount of fat
if at API calls to actually implement a
cell
and it's quite prone to making mistakes
with the app
with the win32 APIs I'm
so the next season depresses
communication so
inter-process communication on Android
has been a huge saucer
are have security vulnerabilities and
Android applications
at this being like for lotto finder
applications the attack surfaces
at significance and because the eyepiece
and plants which are actually exposed
on them when this finite there's
its HS similarities to write to Iowa's
where
you've only got the prop file a nap
protocol handlers
am to actually implement I P say
so for example like Twitter and like
you can implement at protocol handler
for Twitter at like like the RI bill up
so and so to actually implement these
are protocol handlers well
you what you do is you I define them
approach gone lower than the application
manifest
at W I'm not money fast to and you could
say a PDF application handles a PDF file
type
RM you could implement sayre a
protocol under like for example threats
are of ice but
and and then you you write that
and my PRI function within our
application which handles the
the input from the I am you can also but
these with an hour
within web pages and seek it if you but
the link within a web page it doesn't
actually
provide any props when it when your eyes
triggered
and so unless you've got your
applications which register for the same
yar I
then this automatically fire the
application and damn
pass their parameters passed me Ritu the
a
to the application but no user
interaction required
so this could be a saw Sarah's and
from looking at that top IT marketplace
applications it seems that's their
most developers are aware of this and
and this isn't really
at and with not find any vulnerabilities
in this area so far and
so that was the way of doing I am
I've doing the documented I P say
at a space by then amistad but
and this another undocumented way as
well and
which is I've find this time it's called
cross supplication navigation forgery
and and it's essentially faucet
navigation from
one application to another application
and
CPU guy discovered it an issue with
toasts and
were Bob to demonstrate how this can be
used by an attack and how it could be
used to exploit
at Windows Phone applications
so for those in not familiar with
terrorists on
that s that basically it there's a pop
up at the top of that
have the Windows Phone 8 application I'm
and then if the user clicks not post
then it forces a
navigation at to happen seeking
deep link with and application which is
actually triggered the toaster
and say you can link to use that potts
the application
I'm but there's a vulnerability in that
business and documented API method
called shall post message: test
and this essentially I am allows you to
specify the
and and at PRI which specifies which
application has Sam originated the toast
I and the path to the screen with an
application
so this means I'm it can be any samples
grain within the application
am which is allocated to so
it's especially like 100 activities and
borrowing this phone
using this method everything's exported
and there's no way to
lock it down currently and see can
trigger
any is almost green with the application
I'm pass whatever promises you want to
this
to this summer screen as well and so if
there's a problem with in the handling
of their
the have at the promises which best part
is that an attacker could use this to
exploit the application
I'm so I looked its at I start looking
applications to see if I could find any
which we've learned about this type of
attack
and and this is a large a large OEM find
out which
at which needs to remain nameless at the
moment but
and essentially what this does is that
it takes that promises from the RI
I'm dead triggers a just a formative the
fun
just wipes the fun and so this is a
yes it could be abused by an attacker
they also compare the phone into a
automatic on some old as well
so when a call comes through then the
phone automatically accept the call
and and and automatically i connect the
call
I'm so this is a as an issue to
demonstrate this
type talk but really an hour and
in a more realistic scenario would be an
authenticated session
and an in a fog round application and
then a background application cadet
triggered that the text to force their
fall grant application to navigate
at and an exploit the flaw grant
application to do
as a malicious I'm
so my thoughts were well surely surely
Microsoft's
marketplace validation will detect this
kind of thing as well
the serve like and documented APIs and
and and and dynamic at
caught like calling functions at runtime
and but now it seems like he can that
you can use that the object get proper
dress tonight to resolve the function
address
and I'm branch do their branch to that
and then this this doesn't get detected
by the marketplace currently
and saipan gonna application which was
using this cult pic tiles
and this is a this application doesn't
use any malicious way but it just shows
that the
the marketplace validation isn't it
as good as it could be and I am that
there's doubt
gaps where an attack could potentially
get code on the marketplace
and I say like the risk is quite limited
the attack and its power on the fine to
exploit this issue
and also needs to they lost it means to
be an app which is vulnerable to
to doing something to do something
stupid with the arguments as well
and so how do you protect against this
book basically a
I say this to methods to do this that
the fastest see you have
to require user interaction at the far
the following actions were cut at the
second is implementing something like
cross-site request forgery tokens where
and the another gated from method you
can
I'm generating star a token and then
I'm and navigate to you can get the
token am
data and validate the token data past
I'm finally s up despite failing to talk
about
input validation and so up and
application security talk it wouldn't
really be complete without talking about
sir
Press scripting so at
essentially if not an attacker can
inject their
JavaScript on Windows Phone 8 that in if
its running at if
in use a web at a WebView
then you can essentially I'm if an
attack a
injects an iframe that can i friend
content within the application some box
and and then use this with Accenture X
about HTTP POST request
I'm experts write the data outside in
the Sun box
and then transmit this back to to remote
server I'm another interesting but
ability I found as well while assessing
marketplace applications was that remote
zongol loading
at so samples used to lay out their
d'gary in the application
and define whether controls are actually
laid out on the screen
by fund an advertising up which that
essentially
taxes on all from from a web service up
a cleartext
and unloads the sample into the air into
the local application
sounds like okay well what can you do
with this am
so when does on when this presentation
framework you can embed them
see shop code with then within zongol
and to get code execution
and but on when this but I Microsoft the
respected this
and Xcode an event handlers
they've been removed therefrom from this
on wall
and but I find out you can't instantiate
a web browser control
then you could load remote JavaScript
and
and I never about web and a remote web
site which got JavaScript on and then
spiff the UI
and essentially capture credentials and
get code execution that way
I'm so in summary I
don't download interested concerns
locally
don't take remote concerns load and the
local contacts without performing
validation
and and I don't think I really need to
say this but remote
loadings on wall is a dangerous
functionality like it's not common but
could be in future and so in summary I
see why Windows Phone 8 is one of their
well as the strongest mobile platforms
out there the kind of attacks which
we've discovered through our research
and
a mainly though risk issues which an
attacker would need to change together
to actually I'm
perform exploitation and compromise the
fun
well compromise ups on the platform and
but
it shows that like novel novel attack
methods and I'm
at s can still be found ten I'm
and used by an attacker and finally at
the OEM's is still trouble
like an OEM can still compromise their
security of their
of the platform entirely and so your
choice and I am
actually dictates that the security of
Windows Phone 8
I'm phones an upset okay thank you
and so in summary as well I just like to
say thanks to %uh the previous research
which has been profound and
X day farms as well it well a lot of
this
up sex OPSEC research can be out
the phone without that without the tells
and there's also not
there's also white paper which mimic a
Grand Am
which has got a lot more information
about Windows Phone 8 ups
and how to securely writers applications
so there any questions
a have you found that when you install
the
birth certificate on the phone does that
reliably work
to just intercept evening with the up
not doing bringing because I've had
issues with that
not working so
your a funder sometimes it just
fails and Ty Lee and obviously because
call the load the
and Methods its it's a pain a.m.
up naw its really flaky and I'm not much
to get
working reliably I honestly couldn't
tell you what a detective work in
baugh in some connections that will work
some connections of lol I think it's
based around how to develop a cotton
make such a request
I think through assert often AP I'll
work on one-way
doesn't mics Obama yet well
on key talk about the capabilities and
is unwilling Android where it's
is said to be in its proper or iowa's
where like later on you get this sorted
that these shoes or I so
the capabilities you request them
a people in team on a fast obviously
same as what an Android
at the club the substantially more
granular then you'd find on
on like an Android on Isla system other
quite
there are lots in a.m. they're a lot
more of them basically
RT gets the higher privilege one's idea
oh and provide is kinda gives you a big
blanket
ability on 3dmark ingestion process
I it it seems to clear whatever
a capabilities request in the money
first
and then Justin process and then just
analyzed code reassigned what
capabilities you what your code actual
users
so Mark ingestion process kind of class
I love you ask for Sophie awesome more
than you need
it won't give you any or to MPP
thing for the from song back you also
write the filesystem
or only within your local some books yet
you direct point so was up with the FTP
on MTP
MPP and TP yet with MTP get full
fossett's knox's system
sorry I thought he was speaking about
using the FTP service from Windows
Update
yet use in anti be bucking a full
read/write access to the entire the
possum
can even but the permit be over
MPPs serbian well no because you
you've got coat sign in which such a run
code a system
I am so you've got over you've only got
all system access
for this NTP service can be locally I
so you know what to run coda systems
econ run
the house