sauce going to show you guys I'm several
security attacks some of which I talked
about it can sec West couple weeks ago
and because I have less time than I had
anticipated I'm only going to
I'm going to skip the can sequester tax
again secure boot and only talk about
some new attacks at
previously we have not discussed so if
you're interested in the other attacks
and I'm you haven't seen the cancer
quest presentation
I'll be happy to make myself available
after the presentation outside somewhere
and I can show you those attacks as well
I'm not sure if the I can set my sights
are available yet cell
I can show them to you outside so anyway
like I said we'll be talking about some
attacks against you if I secure be today
and I developed this work along with
some my
colleagues like Jon butterworth who is
here today as well some other people who
are are not
present today so to purposes so
conversation is why introduce the idea
of the
in our food chain where we have the now
where that's higher up
at his fundamentally more powerful than
ours that's lower down
so for instance your operating system
level rootkits are now wear whatever
are fundamentally less privileged there
and the code that is higher up in this
is because code it's higher up on this
particular diagram
executes earlier during your system be a
process
and code that executes earlier is just
fundamentally able to
I server code that executes later I T
Ken
patch the code is being later or
whatever so
it's always beneficial for code from our
to execute earlier during the BIA
process
in the BIOS is the first code to XQ when
it though
reset button so it's the most powerful
now are that we can have
in this particular diagram we're not
talking about the management engine and
things of that nature
so as I said it's always advantageous
for
on rootkits to try to claw their way up
this food chain and not too long ago it
was
perfectly permissible for
a compromise operating system to go all
the way up the food chain
to make rights to the SPI flash chip
containing the BIOS and saw a bias
rootkit
as well as replace the the master boot
record with the boot kit or something
like that
this is all Costa Rica do that they were
there is nothing stopping you from doing
this
and so within the past two years signed
by its requirement has come into vogue
and this will prevent even compromise
rings Eurocode from writing
directly to the flash chip that contains
the buyers so it shouldn't be
possible for a compromise kernel driver
to just
make arbitrary rights to the bias Cohen
and
signed by its requirement unfortunately
doesn't do anything to address the other
booted concern
and actually boo kits are more popular
these days because
with later versions of Windows it's a
case that you can just inject
arbitrate going to the kernel because at
the sign driver requirement
and so boot kits became a pretty popular
way to try to you
bypasses requirement you would replace
the bootloader this would allow you to
get code execution before into US
colonel was looted
and then you could just installed looks
and in the US analyze it was leading
before it ever had a chance to establish
the at the sign driver requirement so
you if I is now on most your new systems
and a new system that will go out and
buy today will probably have you if I as
opposed to conventional bias
it is part of the UEFI specification
they introduces secure
would feature which was just designed to
fill in that
bootloader gap so the way this works is
unlike the signed by us requirement a
a compromise offering system can replace
a bit later the master boot record
and the the right will stick but I am
during the cleanup process secure boot
here's going to discover that the at the
river
the replaced malicious bootloader is not
a Kb cryptographically verified
so it's just going to say you know no
good I'm not going to arm
actually excuse you so this is
essentially just
relegated to a denial of service attack
so the way old this works
is from UEFI
has these if I variables which are also
on the
SPI flash chip some of them are not
authenticated which means see an
the operating system can change is not
authenticated variables at will
they can contain things like the boot
order for the system in the language and
so forth and so on
but then you also have the is
authenticated variables which are
security critical
they contain things like the N the allow
list
applications to run during the process
is both
as well as the key is used to sign the
the allow the executors balls
and so on
so what's pretty interesting about this
setup is
on the same medium the SPI flash chip
that contains your BIOS your platform
firmware
you also had these on non-volatile
variable some of which are authenticated
some of which are not
authenticate it's a summer which should
be changed or other one should not be
arbitrarily modifiable
so we have to think about how can we
have some
hasn't typeof granular security policy
that makes it so that
the UEFI code is never right appalled by
the operating system because like I said
you should be able to arbitrarily modify
the platform firmware
but he is non-volatile variables can be
updated by the operating system
so to do this we really have to look at
the Intel
SPI flash protection mechanisms so on
your
Intel chipset will provide a number of
ways for the buyers and the operating
system to work together to
protect these differing regions at the
SPI flash chip
and yet it's really up to the audience
to use these things in
in an intelligent way which they often
don't
so chief among these protection
mechanisms as the bias control register
and if you look at it it's really quite
an interesting protection mechanism
usually
these the is bias registers are quite
simple
an by Scott Roeder Shirley an exception
now you can see that there's a bias
right enable
date which does pretty much like what it
sounds if it's all one you should be
able to write to you
really certain regions at the bias and
then down
there's aspires lock enabled it to the
way this normally look
works when you have a la king bed is
that I you know
the bias what set their bio psych enable
bit and that just means that you can
change the bias reid enable that anymore
that's not how this works on if you read
the text not sure if you can on
on this is just from the the Intel
chipset documentation
you can see that it's very complicated
it says that
if the bias lock enable bit is set if
the
I operating system earnings your code
attempts to
set the bias write enable bit then an
SMI will be generated so it's
permissible for rings Yoko to set the
bias running a little bit
but if it's locked you'll have this
weird ass am i going on
so it's whatever illustrate what's
actually happening here we have some
diagrams
just to make it more clear so this is
the way it's supposed to work
we had some malicious ring 0 kernel
driver trying to make malicious rights
to the biased
the flash chip it sets bias write enable
I and no tissue that bias lock enable is
also said
so because it said is Sooners the
operating system sets by Astrid annual
an SMI is generated
and this SMI is in theory supposed to
come in and set by Astrid enable
back t0 so what's pretty interesting
here is that
by a friend enable bit was set the one
so by Astrid enable did occur but then
instantaneously system management which
is of course this
super privileged x86 mode even more
privilege in the hypervisor came in and
said
no no no you can actually do that not
pass go do not collect $200 dollars
by Sharon able is zero
and yeah I the end result is that in the
context the threat that attitude is said
by Astrid enable
it it never it was actually able to
exceed any cycles with the ad
the bias unlocked or or write enable the
should say
so that was the first mechanism it's
obviously quite complicated that sort of
a really
roundabout crazy way to protect spy
flash
but there's other protection mechanisms
as well there these protected range
registers
and there much simpler they disallowed
to mascot certain regions are the spy
flash
as not readable or not writeable so the
bias during every startup will say
this portion of the by at the at the spy
flash which corresponds to
the UEFI coat or something else really
important like that is just
not writeable period bike no crazy
protection mechanism is just not
writeable period
and nothing can touch this
so those are the arm the main protection
mechanisms we have
on the iris and x86 architecture but
they
can basically both do the same thing you
can use either one to lock down the spy
flash
but arm there's sort have differing
levels of strength
and that's because with protected rain
treasures even system management node
can right to
regions are this buy flash protected by
these protective and ranchers
but system management node is
responsible for the security of bias
control so system management can
right to read is that the spy flash at
only associated with this bias control
protection
are protected with protected range
registers
so just to further illustrate this in
II actually I should say the a this
particular
despite less protection mechanisms that
Intel provides us
forced the UEFI architecture into the
following scenario
S&M has to be responsible for doing the
rights
at the EF I variables on
if this isn't the case dan it wouldn't
necessarily be the case it just rings
you're a good kid
right to the if I variables and that
would be a
an instant security vulnerability
because an operating system to change
security critical
if I variables do turn off secure a bit
or something like that
so at the nature of these chipset
protection mechanisms forces us into
this case were S&M is now the broker
that does the rights to the if I
variables on our behalf
and also decides whether or not to
change if I variable is legitimate or
not
so if we have windows 8 coming along and
saying all right I want to create a new
if I variable
and system management gonna say okay
I'll do this right on your behalf
because
my var is not on authenticated security
critical variable
so that's fine go ahead and create this
new variable
that doesn't do anything in this case
but lets a Windows 8 came along and uses
when is the API that they provide and
tried to deal
on what changes authenticated variable
to something system in its rebuttal
would go I don't think so buddy I am
you have to have knowledge for special
private key in order to do that and it
was just a block this whole operation
so like I said that the critical up the
cradle
critical observation really this whole
talk is that
these non-volatile variables which our
security critical
in a bid up the system are fundamentally
less secure
the other regions at the spy flash the
reason is
the UEFI code can be made not writeable
after the during the early stages the
beat the system
but variable region the flash has to
remain writeable
while the operating system is going
that's because that's the easy if I
variables have to be able to be updated
by
by someone so the UEFI Co is pretty
locked down I can use is protected range
registers which are pretty solid and
pretty simple security mechanism
but the ear five variables are forced to
rely on the bias control protection
what this essentially means is that the
attack surface
against secure boot is this is a
superset
at the attacks in system management
Miley any vulnerability that would allow
you to get in a system manager mode
with instantly allow you to bypass
secure boot because then you would have
context
inside the app broker agent responsible
for deciding if
if I variable updates are legitimate or
not so in the S&M attack its instantly a
secure the break
so the question really is is it actually
feasible to get a system and shimon
its super privilege might have execution
dates security critical in tolls aware
this
so it should not be easy for even a ring
0 attacker to get the system it is
rumored
and it's not easy but it certainly is
possible there have been some attacks by
outlook to flow
and I am a fall from invisible things
labs and so forth
and we have actually found someone who
believes as well that will be presenting
later on this year so the point is that
system manager mode
is supposed to be bulletproof it's not
reveal to get in but
there definitely are S&M on her
abilities
part of the reason why that is the case
is
because its security critical nature
system mention know it should be treated
as a trusted code base
it is a absolutely vital to the security
the platform
attacker present system initial node
cancer burgundy hypervisor
can even defeat txt late lunch stuff
because of the absence as a as men
transfer monitor
so very important on so what with
something as security critical system
manager mode
what we would want to see is the amount
of code in SMM going down
or at least flatlining and because less
code West burbs right
but I we actually see the opposite with
UEFI vendors are dumping just more and
more code in a system management node
all kinds have crazy proprietary stuff
is ending up in System Manager
good like an its you guys public and
read this texas is justified known out
but
you can see like Dell USB emulation S&M
okay SMM dispatch SMM thunk
digital thermal sensor SMM which is what
you'd expect two seasons as a man is
responsible for handling thermal events
but yet near the point is there's all
kinds have
really crazy code going into system
measurement right now and
in my particular case I had 495
individual if I modules on my spy flash
and 144 them contributed code SMM so
there's two ton of code going SMM and a
goner build the end any of them
would be an instant secure boot bypass
so I expect because at this trend of
market going into S&M you'll probably
see
even more vulnerabilities in SMM in the
near future even despite the fact that
you if I suppose to be quote unquote
more secure
today's result is actually
that and a lot of cases we don't even
need to get into System Manager Mode to
defeat secure boot
we can actually defeat secure boot by
temporarily suppressing the execution
system management
so SMM is a very privileged important
part of the CPU is responsible for
thermal events
how can we like at temporarily disable
S&M
wealthy look at the Intel chipset
documentation there's actually a lot of
things a jump out the the most obvious
is one that just says
SMI enable and and at does what you
think it would do
with when it set to 0 SM eyes will not
fire
period I this bit can be locked so that
it should not be updatable by the
operating system
but we did a survey of 8,000 systems and
we found that on forty percent at them
they weren't bothering to our to lock
this bad news we're pretty recent
at the reason systems and this numbers
actually artificially low it could be
made much higher by downgrading
the the BIOS a major problem in by a
security is
the rollback problem only M's are
generally unwilling to
prevents an operating system from
rolling back the BIOS version so let's
say you have
bias revision a3 is not vulnerable to
some
vulnerability but a2 is usually it's a
case that you can just downgrade the
BIOS from the operating system to a
three day to you
and then exploit the vulnerability I am
we've pointed this out an
oh %um is our has a tent to stop this
kind a roll-back
even do even with the security
implications involved because
customers would get mad that I despise
her vision broke something and I wanted
on a roll it back so that their son want
to do that
so this number could be made much higher
by rolling back to bias revision which
we did mother doing this quick survey
so what this means is that on the sporty
person in the system is weak a temporary
leaders
disable System Manager murdered by
setting this to this bid
p.m. you
yes my neighbor 20 and what happens and
is that
the SMI routine that's responsible for
setting bias write enable
back 20 simply won't run so a
compromised
Irene 0 driver or root in Lex it has
come along and say by Astrid enable
Eagles won
debate will stick and system management
analyst canton is sit there silently
because it has been disabled
and what this allows us to do is because
those non-volatile variable regions was
dependent on it as my routine
for security I'll a compromise opening
system a ring 0 Curtis
now written make direct SPI write cycles
to this variable region
in change all the authenticated
variables and as I previously stated
is authenticated variables are critical
to the security the system because they
have like the at the white list have
allowed
secure boot application so an attacker
condition this come in
an answer a new malicious bootloader
into the application whitelisting
then it will execute despite the
presence of a secure fit
so we have a little video this attack
actually it's going to be a little bit
hard for you guys in the back to read
the text I apologize for that
I'm sure I'll be making this video
public in the near future
so this tack attack were actually doing
from Lenox just to illustrate that and
this isn't a
a Len X I went to a specific problem
even though
secure boot is often associated Windows
8 it's actually part of the UEFI
specification
and exploitable from Linux or Windows
and in fact this particular
vulnerability is actually easier to
exploit from 1x because
and Len XE have I O privileges from the
root account
wears an recent words a Windows yet have
a kernel driver
to be able to meet manipulate these
chipset registers
so this is a at an Intel based
motherboard we have secured with enabled
and we've installed this some just fake
boot kit
onto the if I partition Shin x64 DFI
and this case it is print some sweet
ASCII art and then lets the original
annex
later
so in this case a cure but soon able we
haven't done any attacks so
attempting to run any non-authorized
if I execute Wilson just gonna fail puke
it would not work at this point
and I'm just going into the BIOS
configuration settings now I'm showing
you that
I the way it's all it's not biased so
yes secure because enabled
then the DB is actually what we're going
to attack here in a second
and this is just I'll a whitelist
the hashes it if I execute a course
where he find one of the is just
automatically allow it to run
I don't even bother with some signature
verification process
and so we're going to use this as my
special attack to insert
the boot kit into the the authenticated
TV variable
so we have to go back into our next
actually launched attack from the root
account so this run the
original 1x pullover be later
yes I the tax is pretty small I didn't
anticipate that
so the way this attack works is reusing
flash ROM to first
I read a dump the bias
and we created this little application
that the NDP that will take the BIOS
image that was just dumped with flash
ROM
and Danny locate where the DB
is stored in the buyer's stamp and then
insert the air
at arbitrary entry into the DB
that the white list i should say
this is just chaining changing the other
by Esteban yes we haven't
actually attempted to write back to this
by slashing at
so we just add manually patch did so
that the bias image the variable region
at the bias
contains data hacked and white list for
our boot kit
and now we're going to try to you right
back
and its may be a little hard to get
sorry but you can see the flash ROM is
actually failing
and in one of these lines you see on
setting
a XTC which the bias control register
from Alexei to let's be so this is
trying to say I'm trying to set the bias
write enable bit
but when I read it back it still it's
not set the values to Alexei said at
least significant bit is not sticking
and that's because currently that SMI
routine that responsible for protecting
at that particular regions the flash
misfiring and it's saying
no you can't write enable the bias on I
don't approve this
too bad
so what we'll do now is warden
temporarily suppressed
SMM using that the method I just talked
about and try again
we call it
char is art for some juvenile reasons
that are worth going into and so that's
why you're seeing their name
okay
so right now we've used the attack
to set SMI naval 20 said no esta memes
are firing
and we want to do this pretty quickly
because SMM is actually really important
as I said it responsible for thermal
events
see you definitely don't want to just
turn of S&M and then go to town some
really bad things might happen to your
system
but OK with temporarily disabled S&M
let's try to our right back to patch
Tobias image with flash ROM
and at this time you can see no errors
it's an its succeeded
as the right enables duck and everything
so we're able to attend
add at hacked entry into the white list
to secure boot
list and then I will this reboot the
system and
verify that the book it actually works
now
I in this demo were like mainly watching
the bucket by like going into
on DFI shell and typing anymore be later
obviously if you're really exploiting
the issue it like replace
original legitimate when exploiters all
that would happen seamlessly upon
rebooting the system
what is being proposed for clarity and
as for extra comps
verbosity we're going right now to the
BIOS settings and you can and sorta see
that with
modified some of these at DB entries
arbitrarily
which you should definitely not be able
to do since these are like I said
critical to the security at the break up
the system
okay so now let's go back into the if I
shelling tryer bleak it again
okay and then we get this we ask the
artist I'm any guesses about what that
is
there's
Anna probably take us longer to get the
ASCII art Benedetta
actual attack we had at our junior
guided ads might it is doing that
so you're SMI suppression
can be used to feed as secure began a
lot %uh systems arbitrarily modified is
important if I variables
I I was just one way to temporarily
suppressed
SMM this is very chipset depended
there's all
other ways definitely to temporarily
suppress as a man
so I encourage you to disco look at your
specific chipset documentation like Rep
around for as a member SMI
and I can pretty much guarantee or find
other ways to suppress SMM
there is a relatively new
spy flash protection mechanism that
should to say it that should defeat this
type assessment suppression attack
it's called the pious right protected
and this
effective leader says that only SMM
can write to this by flash so it's if
if this is set even if you can suppress
SMN you'll be able to write to the flash
chip because
only SMM can try to win this is set
lucky for us
we serve eighty thousand systems in only
six were actually sending this so this
is relatively new bit and no one is
using it for the most part
I am in general there's a pretty long
tail he's OEM's for how long it takes
and actually start using new Intel
chipset protection mechanisms and yet no
one's jumped on board the bias right
protected train yet
so the
the the main point here is that all
these
security protocol parts have your
system's beat-up exist on the same
medium the spy flash
the different right ability properties
that
the different regions needs necessitates
that the if I variables that control the
configuration at secure boot
are less protected I other reasons that
the spy flashlight where the you if I
could exist
so it's pretty weak and there's a a very
large attack surface
against at the code that protects these
Esme
easy if I variables in any wanna any
sort of water billing system manager
mode
I can instantly just turn into a secure
be by SL even the Securities
in my opinion a good security feature
and something that is definitely needed
to plug this but get all
I it is certainly not bulletproof and
there's a huge attack service air and I
think you'll be seeing a lot of them
other attacks against in and obviously
Williams could really do themselves a
favor by going in and actually using
these latest
a.m. chipset protection mechanisms like
SMM bias write protect
so just as some related work that's
worth pointing out
and the for secure been attacked that
I'm aware was an
a tailor one software by passive when is
it secure boot
this is done by the the Intel P sir team
an their point was that basically if
this by flashes completely unprotected
sufferings your cur can go on
arbitrarily modify any reason service by
slash which is actually true even on
some of the latest greatest systems
from certain vendors I then obviously
can defeat secure because you can just
overwrite the bias code in
you know make secure pretty crazy things
and like I said I recently gave a
presentation
at ACK & sec West about another security
tak and that was
essentially pointing out that a lot of
Koreans re:
implementing security critical if I
variables as not authenticated
so that ring 0 operates a stinker can
come in
and you change if I variables at will
without any sort of attack in a lot of
these are security critical that can now
effectively disable security
and also we've come up with some attacks
again sad
signed buyers enforcement and if you can
reflash the biasing
yes obviously you can defeat secure be
and other sort of funny thing worth
pointing out is that
in our survey we look at some other data
points so as I always
already previously said most people are
using AZT nem bias write protect
and we also found that many OEMs are
even bothering to set these protected
range registers
at the simple not do not write this
region to the spy flash
I am so on these 7300 systems
and you know fifty percent of those that
were vulnerable to SMI suppression
SMI suppression immediately turns into a
arbitrary flash the bios my systems
so on yeah Williams could be doing a lot
better with using these
security protection mechanism so in
compliance is definitely
a huge issue as I artie said a lot of
Williams out there like Jesus I believe
are not even walking down
their flashy but all you can dislike
totally destroyed by Iris from the
router like totally picked the system
and yeah just a couple people to help us
this research the Intel P sir team they
actually
sounds we found some the same wonderful
isn't secure boot that's why we work a
presenting a cancer quest
an for a fall from Bro me a min of red
ortega help that's perfect our paper
and Rick Martinez is our security
contacted at Dell
is like the chief bias engineer so if
you have any security problems he can go
to him
and then at the year 59 developers will
not refer to them are here but
we use their kinda like to upload party
am
UEFI BIOS so
how much time do have left and curious
I get a number on the back three minutes
30 minutes okay on the time basically
than
so um any questions I made missus but
I'm how did you perform
system survey okay so we have a an
and agent called copernicus that's
really available from the mitre website
and what it does is it goes in Reitz
some a bunch of years
spy flash protection mechanisms as well
as is your dump your BIOS
kiss your interest in the security of
your your bias and also if you just want
to read an image that the bias this runs
on Windows
reason we created this was their slash
unfurl an expert there was really no
no good and a lot for Windows it's too
simple Windows kernel driver that goes
in reeds obvious
chipset registers and also president
your bias and
that's freely available with you on just
google Pernik as
mitre to burn is like the dude an or go
to the website and you can I am
check it out