[Music]
good afternoon everybody
I let's see what we can take this how to
scale your auditing events so oftentimes
this is us and well everything is fine
right until not everything is fine
anymore kind of the worst case scenario
probably you might run into is if you
learn about the breach from the press or
from your users and they complain
mightily if you're a bit more lucky
maybe somebody's just asking for ransom
especially for your data stores this has
been more or less common that people
take your data ransom and maybe they
have a backup and you can buy that back
or maybe they have just lead you data
nobody knows sometimes you just see it
on your cloud providers bill when
somebody got your ex's credentials and
started mining some cryptocurrency and
well it's not very efficient but as long
as it's not your own bill you can just
do that sometimes you just learn about
the breach after the fact and well not
nice but still better than most of the
other cases or ideally you can prove
that there was no harm done like there
was a breach but nothing actually
happened that would be the ideal case
and we want to figure out how can we
prove what has happened to our system or
what hasn't happened to our system and
yeah basically what we want to avoid is
the bottom half here where everything is
on fire and you just scream what is my
problem that is the part we don't want
to get into so unfortunately there are
no silver bullets or luckily there are
no silver bullets otherwise we wouldn't
need to be here or we wouldn't have a
good or a well-paying job so no silver
bullets but that's not the end of the
world that's actually more or less a
feature so for the rest of the talk if
you have any questions just ask them
either online or at the end we'll
probably have enough time at the end for
questions if I run out of time or if
there are too many questions I will just
tweet out the answers as well so if you
had to slider you can just ask your
questions there
if you forget them or if you're too shy
to ask in person just post your
questions and we'll get to them at the
and by the way does anybody her has
anybody figured out why I'm using that
handle for Twitter and slider and
everything it has something to do you
have it on the first slide as well it
has something to do with my name any
guesses any guesses something with my
last name who is old enough to remember
anybody remembers rot13
where you rotate the letters by 13 and
so if you take my last name which in
German basically or in Austrian German
where I'm from basically means
horseradish but with one n then this is
what you get and the nice thing about
rot13 is if you encrypt something again
then you're back at the original because
well 26 letters in the alphabet 13 times
2 you get back to the original so that's
why I'm using that for any questions so
how can we actually figure out what is
happening in our system one very nice
way to do that is audit D and who is
actually using already actively and I
not sure I can see anybody okay I think
you can see a couple of hands but not
very many so oddity is the Linux
auditing daemon this is the description
from the main page generally you have a
user space component to the auditing
subsystem to actually report or show you
what has been happening and you can
check that out with either or report to
get a report or or search to see all the
raw logs or you can filter them down
what you can do is you can generally see
what files have been accessed what
network connections have been made have
to answer been any system calls which
commands were ran by which users or
which security events have been
triggered stuff like that can all be
collected by Oddity and the general idea
is you have you use a space program and
the user space program is running some
action like op
a file or running a program and then you
have the system called processes for
user task and exit and at any one of
these when you run them there can be an
exclude rule and once you pass through
that exclude rule then that action will
be collected by the audit daemon so
basically you have some rules and
whatever passes through those rules will
then be collected and you can later on
checkout these security events what this
actually looks like is let's assume
we're locked in here let's say know that
my session just died okay
let's start fresh
so let's say we want to run the the the
report here and for example here you can
see we have collected in some timeframe
here we have collected a bunch of things
on our system for example we had 76
logins into our system we have lots of
failed login attempts
we'll see what has been happening there
a bit later on you can see which or how
many users have been able to
authenticate how many uses we have in
our system so this is just the general
overview of all the security related
events that we have in our system where
are those coming from so as we already
mentioned our search and let's start
with rod these are just the raw events
um this will keep scrolling for a while
and you can see these are all the
relevant events that we have been
collecting over time and how they are
structured once we're done scrolling
through them because there's so many
after some time we'll be done you can
use all search of course to filter down
or search what you're seeing there
once you're done here you can for
example see here this would be one entry
and you always have a type the type is
basically telling you what kind of event
do you have it could be you change
directory or you open the file or you
run a process or here we are aborting a
daemon and then you have the message the
message consists of two parts here you
can see this is a UNIX timestamp and
this is a unique ID sometimes you have
unique timestamps or you have IDs and
timestamps and they are duplicated this
is then normally when you have one call
that is logging multiple actions for
example if you open a program and it
also takes some other actions or open
support you might have multiple actions
that you're logging and they have done
the same timestamp and then same ID and
then depending on whatever action you
have here you might have different
things that are being collected so for
example you see that here this thing
failed and you have a process city and a
user ID but not everything has a process
or user ID depends a bit on what call
you're running
you could for example also say we are
running an or search and we run this
against success No so only our search
six if you can type English correctly
then it will even show you what it's
doing so these are all the things that
failed in our audit D logs this is still
a lot of events and also oftentimes you
don't have just a single system that you
want to monitor and generally whatever
you have here it's kind of very hard to
read and figure out what is really going
on with my system so this is where the
scaling parts comes into play so oddity
is a great tool to collect a lot of low
level system events but what do you make
out of that mess of all the events that
you have collected here so let's see
what we have here so before we go any
further one thing in case you're kind of
confused what do I even have in all my
logs here for example the rented
documentation on those is pretty good if
you had over to the Red Hat Enterprise
documentation it will explain to you for
example it has full examples of these
are some example calls they have and
they were just describing what all the
different pieces and parts in there are
but we don't want to dive too much into
the low-level details let's just say
like it's collecting a lot of stuff but
it's kind of hard to read and it's a bit
complicated and it's very hard to parse
as well and often times you want to
centralize the information especially if
you have lots of systems you don't just
want to have that sitting around on one
disc you want to kind of centralize and
figure out what overall is going on in
my system and if you want to look at
more rules because you want to fine tune
your system a bit more in the github
repository of Oddity you have actually a
lot of rules that you can look at for
example here you have the base
configured by default normally is you
don't have any rules you set some
buffers and then you set some failure
modes to collect stuff
but you have lots of other rules here
for example to say like oh I want to see
what is happening on the network here in
case it is readable you can see this is
what the configuration would look like
to collect anything that is happening on
the network so always on exit run on a
64-bit architecture when you have accept
or connect one of these two actions and
lock that thing under a key that we call
external access and afterwards you could
search for everything under external
access because that has passed through
that rule there are lots of examples in
that repository where you can see
different things that you might want to
collect for example power abuse when
somebody abuses their sudo privileges
we'll get back to that example a little
later on if you have any container
actions like somebody starts a container
and lots of other things here are the
examples this is what you can try out
and run then okay so speaking of
namespaces by the way those are still a
bit work in progress this has been split
up into multiple subtasks figuring out
which user has been doing what in what
container is still a bit tricky but
oddities in the process of adding all
the enrichment and figuring out which
container or namespace has been doing
what but that's still a bit of a work in
progress okay so we want to collect all
the things basically and ideally we also
want to centralize them no how do we do
that yeah how do I collect that well we
could just take the files and collect
all the files and then try to parse the
files but that still sometimes painful
by the way why am I talking about that
so I work for elastic the company behind
the elastic search lock search Cubana
some of you might use us for various use
cases either logs or also security
related events and I generally just talk
about the stuff that we do in that area
so this is highly monitored like hello
world application of oddity that we want
to walk through to see how that is all
fitting together so
lots of you are probably familiar with
that one called elk or elastic stack
nowadays we try to call it the elastic
stack because well we have added a bit
more because we have elastic search to
store everything log stitch to get and
parse the data and enrich it by the way
any idea what enrichment could be like
for example you have an IP address and
you want to get a geolocation of an IP
address that could be enrichment that
normally we do that that ingestion time
when we store something so the queries
will be faster afterwards and then we
have for example Cabana to visualize
what is going on or what we have
collected here the only thing is log
stash is sometimes a bit heavy because
well it started off as Ruby and is now
JRuby and I know just to collect events
normally people don't like the JVM to
collect their events so we figured that
out and at some point we added another
components called
beads and well then we tried to come up
with this new acronym called ELQ B or
Belk which could have looked something
like this but we didn't really stick
with that because we're always about
scaling and this is not very scalable
because what happens if we add another
open-source component to it then we'll
get another letter and it will get very
hard to make up another animal whatever
the next letter will be it will be very
hard to figure out some other animal
even though the LP that the B with the
elk owns is kind of cute we got rid of
that and now we just call it elastic
stack because that's scalable whatever
you have just stick it in there whatever
new products we add and this is the
general architecture that you can use
there however we only need three
components for today we'll use the beats
which is like a lightweight H in the
shipper written in goes you use so you
have native binaries so you can forward
your data then we put it into elastic
search to centralize it and then we have
Kabbalah to do some visualizations on
top of that and all the stuff that I'm
showing you now is open source and
Apache 2 license so you can just take it
and do whatever you want with that so
the first thing that we tried and I
wouldn't say we failed but it has severe
limitations as you'll see the first
thing that we try this we try to build a
so-called file bit module and the file
bit module is basically taking whatever
all the
the the log file is creating so when you
look at the raw log file those are also
stored in the log and that's var log
audit or audit or the log if I remember
correctly so these are the raw events
like it's the same thing as if you were
doing all all search raw you have the
same thing in a log file and we try to
collect those and this is kind of kind
of working but parsing this file is a
pain in the ass because every line is
looking different like depending on
whatever type you have you need to make
sure like how many attributes are coming
afterwards and how to split those up you
can do that and we have done that so I
can quickly show you what this looks
like if you've never seen Cubana this is
Cubana I'll just stick to the pre-built
dashboards I'm lazy I didn't build those
myself you can be lazy too so what I'm
interested in is file bit is basically
file bit is the thing that tail is log
files and it just collects log files and
at some point we figured out maybe there
should be modules to collect common
things and we call those file bit
modules and basically those are for
nginx or Oddity or Apache or my sequel
and lots of other formats we basically
know no on this operating system which
I'm using Ubuntu the log file for Oddity
is in vogue order it oddity dot log and
then we know approximately what the
standard log format looks like if you
change that log format you will
obviously need to customize that but we
try to figure out what you have
basically you just say like I want the
audit the events and then the beat will
figure out okay this is where the file
is this is what the file should look
like I will try to take that parse it
and just store and centralize it well
the auditing events that we have parsed
look something like this so we didn't I
didn't collect any from the file
recently but for example if I head over
to the last 24 hours you can see these
were all the event types
you have seen some before for example
we're changing a directory or we're
running a system call or something is
happening on a path so we have the event
types we can see which users have been
doing something and you can for example
see okay this is how many events were
successful or unsuccessful over time and
you can also see where they have been
coming from so surprisingly a lot of
those are from China and it guesses what
those events are yeah doesn't read to
say so ssh authentication login attempts
which failed so for example here if i
look in that list of users i've never
heard of that user and i would really be
curious what somebody has been doing
here so if i filter down on that one you
can see okay it was just authentic ation
tries that somebody tried and there was
a pretty much spike here when somebody
tried to use that user and you can see
some from solvent somebody from china
tried to login with that user six times
in a specific timeframe and you can see
here where and when so this is all kind
of nice but it's also slightly limited
by the way some other stuff that the
file bit modules can collect for you is
when did somebody run a sudo command
that might also be interesting so in the
last 24 hours you can see on which files
did which user run sudo commands how
many times and you could for example see
over time which users we're running the
pseudo commands and for example when a
user ran something that was not in the
sudoers list and well they shouldn't
have been doing that and then you can
dive into what has been happening here
or you could for example take a look at
well what was in the system logs
obviously there is a lot of stuff
happening in the system logs but we have
collected those as well and you can also
see for example which users or groups
were added over time
so that could also be kind of handy that
somebody created a new user here that
might be kind of suspicious if you
didn't expect that and you can also see
like which users have a shell or which
have a no login set and you can just
start up it down into those details and
if somebody breaks into
system those are all valuable things to
figure out what has actually happened
over time like has a user actually been
able to create new users and how did
that spread out through your entire
system in my example here okay I
remember that I've been doing that okay
I created an NTP user and I created a
group developers so that was me nobody
else has been creating groups but you
never sure what happened on your system
you can also see for example the SSH
login attempts over the last 24 hours
filter down on those you can see most of
them actually failed and you can see
this was me when I was doing some stuff
today myself you can see which users
were most popular to try to log in and
when you zoom out you can see okay China
was definitely leading normally I either
see Russia or China first but today that
the Russians seem to be taking the day
off only China active I'm by the way
very disappointed that we don't have
more login to attempts from Finland this
is an online system you could just try
to do stuff by the way and we'll
hopefully figure out what is happening
but please don't run a denial of service
attack against it otherwise the demo
will kind of um be not so much fun
anymore but yeah let's see if later on
we will have more login attempts from
Finland okay so this is what we have
been extracting however it turned out
over time that this is kind of a pain to
parse like I said and we also have this
thing where we need to talk food or eat
our own dog food though most people
don't like that dog food thing we
normally prefer to say like drink your
own champagne because it sounds much
fancier we had that moment where we had
to drink our own champagne a bit because
we have a cloud service where we provide
our services as a service and they said
well we want to get all these security
vents and well we have the right stack
why are we not collecting that and that
basically led us to reconsider how are
we interacting with Oddity and what we
could do with Oddity and basically what
we did is we
another beat because beats are basically
a framework and it's called the audit
beat so what we're doing is we're
reusing what audit D is doing and we're
using the same syntax we are just
collecting that directly and we make it
easier to correlate events the resell
resolve the user IDs and the user names
we have a native integration into
elasticsearch so we don't write out that
weird file that is a pain in the ass to
parse back but we're sending stuff in a
structured format off the machine right
away we were considering e BPF for some
time the problem was we have a lot of
users and also internal use cases which
had all the kernels and e BPF didn't
give us all the stuff that we wanted on
those so all it D is kind of like a
stopgap and giving us a lot of the
features that audit is it the DB PF is
also providing it's just that oddity
works with all the kernels and well we
wanted to use those we think that only
configuration is a bit easier and well
you have go binaries so it makes your
life a bit easier for that as well so
and it also does full documented data
enrichment so basically whenever you run
a command it comes from a namespace we
will run look up against the talker
socket if you have access to the doctor
socket obviously if you have access to
the doctor socket we will then resolve
what a specific container was doing and
we can enrich that with docker like base
images labels anything that you have on
that ecosystem we can enrichen on that
as well so what is already doing let's
take a look here we take a look at the
configuration file maybe that's the
right point in time to do that so like
all our beats audit speed is well repeat
or repeated game L is where the
configuration file lives let's jump to
the beginning of the file basically what
we have here is we have an audit team
module we are setting pretty much the
same settings that we have in the
default settings or I've supplied the
same settings where you see I have a
backlog limit I have I didn't set the
rate limit but you could set the rate
limit if there are too many requests
coming in for example as well I'm
getting rid of the raw vents
it's just unnecessary storage and I want
to keep the lipid slimmer and then after
that pipe which is everybody loves him
oh that's the way to just pass in a
random message first to remind myself
how that all the decent works always
works I have a comment to say that first
either you watch a file with - W or you
may monitor a system call with - a and
then action and the filter and then we
basically dive into that so for example
here we're watching a file here we would
for example watch the et Cie passwd file
and we tag the entire thing with
identity and if I scroll further down
here for example I watch the read access
to et Cie passwd from a user in a
specific group we'll come back to this
rule in a few moments but this is just
what the general oddity configuration
syntax looks like and so if you have
oddity running you can just take the
same rules and stick them in to audit
beat and it's doing the exact same thing
so what you get from that what I have
extracted here is do you want to see the
raw events first of the dashboard first
where do we go dashboards okay let's see
we have an overview and here this looks
pretty familiar to what we have seen
before let's switch tech back to the
last 15 minutes or so so it's not too
much you can see like which actions have
been running here somebody executed
something somebody locked in you
basically see over time how many of
these events have been happening you can
see
yeah which event categories you have
been collecting here and you see the raw
events down here but this is just
combined - put view of the raw events
that you have so if I had over to
discover these are basically the raw
events that we have collected and for
example for audit beat here these are
all the things I'm collecting here with
audit beat I see that in the last 15
minutes so the last fifteen minutes this
is that one here I have collected
approximately eight hundred events on my
system
and if I unfold one of these you can see
okay somebody seems to have tried to
login with an invalid user from that IP
address and you can also see some other
nice information here for example it's
something that we automatically can
enrich is the host information so I'm
right now enriching every event that I'm
collecting with the operating system so
you can see here I'm running on the
latest LT s of Ubuntu you can see some
internal IP address the host ID so you
can back-trace that to the instance or
for example if you know that some
specific security issue is just
affecting one specific operating system
or one specific version of the operating
system you could just fill the down on
that here so for example if I would
click on that plus I would only filter
down to my open to 18:04 dot one
instances however since this is the only
operating system I'm running here in my
example we have all the events collected
here as well so we're not really
filtering down on much but if you have a
fleet of operating systems this would be
the easiest way to filter down what
operating systems do you even have
running and then I'm also enriching the
cloud meta data so you can see my stuff
is running here on AWS in EU West 1a so
you West should be Ireland in the one
availability zone you can see the
instance ID you can see this is running
one of the cheap t2 micro instances so
you can filter is down easily on the
region or the cloud provider or the
instance ID and you can just see where
stuff is happening in your system this
is just things that we haven't reached
and you can see is here some something
has been happening with SSH and somebody
an unknown user seems to have tried to
log into our system so these are the raw
events ok let's see what else we can do
here so these are my configuration rules
let's log in with another user let's
take the elastic user first
so the first thing is if you if you fail
to login like I'm doing right now we
should be able to very easily tracked it
down what did we find that information
again we had a dashboard with the ssh
user so let's first let's try to find
that user again so if i had over to ssh
I know which user I'm looking for so we
didn't have any successful login
attempts but I'm trying to log in
okay the usernames are getting a little
more colorful now but I'm interested in
my elastic user and well that has only
been happening from that IP address
let's quickly check with my VPN yeah
that that was me I failed to login
that's correct
and since I'm roaming through my phone
and have the VPN on it does looks like
it's coming from home and not Finland ok
so let's try it again
and this time I'm logging in with the
right password and now let's let's see
what my user could be doing so for
example let's say I have nginx running
and I want to restart nginx and well
since I don't have sudo privileges I
will need to pick a user and actually
run a stead user and I hope I remember
that correctly and we have just
restarted the user the nginx process so
let's see if we can actually trace that
in our processes so we have another
dashboard here with for audit audit if I
could type audit speed where we have
executions and in the executions I know
that the elastic user has been doing
something so I will filter down on that
user you can see overall these were all
the commands that that user has been
running in the last 15 minutes and if I
look here you can actually see ah this
is what the user has been doing there
have been some other things been run
under that user but this is the event
that I'm interested in so if you open
that one up you can see okay this was
the actual event and
you can see the elastic user started
this command and was running that then
you can see all the other information
about the operating system and what is
more relevant is okay this was the
elastic user who has been running that
and you can see the user groups and you
could even just find the raw events
around that for example if you would
have too many events here if you have
lots of things going on in your system
maybe just running on the user itself is
not enough but we could for example
filter that down just with the regular
full-text search and then you would have
a single event and then you can see okay
this is what my user has been up to and
this is the actual event or the stuff
that that user has been triggering here
and it was actually a successful event
so we have been able to restart nginx or
for example we could say my user is just
trying to poke around the system for
example we could say e to see passwd I
just want to take a look at which users
do I have in my system and for that for
example we have created a dedicated rule
that we have mentioned before so this is
the rule here so basically what I'm
saying is if somebody is reading the HC
passwd file and it is the user is from
the group with the ID e 1001 which that
specific user is from then we want to
lock that with the tag developers passwd
read and the thing and to find that
actual event what we need to do is well
we can head over to the raw event and
then we could for example say we have
the tags is and then we have exactly
that tag that we have just specified and
that way we could filter down down for
my mm something events we would seen
last 15 minutes these were the events
with that tag that have been caused and
if you scroll further down you can
actually see what has been happening so
you can see here pin cat has been called
on that file so the object primary
that's always kind of like the target on
which you run something you can see we
have opened a file and you can see we
user has been running that and you can
see all the attributes of that user and
you can see well it was the elastic user
and you can see that was the group ID
which we have been filtering on so that
has that is what that user has been up
to let's try something else let's say
this user is logging out and we have the
admin user now and we kind of have a
curious we have a curious admin user and
that admin user is just poking around
the system abusing their privileges so
for example we take a look at home and
then we see okay we have our own home
directory but we also have the elastic
user directory and we'll just start
looking around and then we see oh we
have a file called secret txt and
obviously we want to look at what that
secret txt is doing so let's have a look
will this work obviously no because we
miss the privileges so if you could type
and you can see the file contains my
secret now this is clearly an abuse of
the privileges of sudo like that user
shouldn't be poking into the private
directory of any user so how can we
collect that with audit d so let's look
luckily we have created a rule and this
is the rule we're interested in here
which we have called the power abuse so
if we have a user ID for a root user who
is looking into stuff from non-root
users so these are the regular users
like my elastic user which has the group
ID 1001 so this is clean in that rule
and basically we want to lock that when
you try to access a file on by user of
that 1000 plus group we want to lock
that under power abuse so if I log head
over to my raw events again
I want to edit this and this should be
called power abuse now and if you're
lucky it was the very latest event that
we have here and you can actually see
okay the elastic admin user has been
running cat on the home directory or the
specific secret txt file of that user
and then you could ask the user was it
really necessary or are you may be
abusing your sudo privileges and there
are some other things here not
everything is really a security security
thing or some active power abuse but of
some of them might make sense to look
more into them but I mean landscape sue
saying okay this is probably less
harmful but for example everything in
the home directory that is something
where you might want to take a better
look at so for example you could just
filter down on the home directory and
just find all the events where somebody
use their sudo privileges to look into
stuff into the home directory so that
would be possible as well um okay
one other thing that we have added to
that is not part of oddity but we have
added that to audit beat is we have
added a file integrity check while the
audit these stuff will only work on
Linux because well it depends on the
kernel features the file integrity works
on other operating systems as well
depending on what operating system
you're using we will use different
mechanisms to check that if a file has
changed so for example on Linux every
time a file changed we you can do that
with inotify on Mac OS it's FS events
and on Windows it's redirect URI changes
W and with those we basically can
monitor one directory to see that if
something has changed so for example
let's take a very simple example let's
say we have we have our website and this
is working fine and somebody might be
abusing your website and add a file HTML
index no not like this
that's much better so here we have a
very simple website and if I would see
my cursor let's say somebody is changing
your website and let's do something like
this which is maybe not what you want on
your actual website so if somebody comes
to your site they will now see if this
is happening on your company website
you're probably not too happy and maybe
you want to figure out like how did that
change happen to my site and that's what
the file integrity module or where that
comes into play so let's see what we
have configured in the file integrity
module so if I scroll further down a bit
here besides the ODT module we have this
file integrity module and I can
configure which files or paths
I want to monitor so VAR w w HTML is
what i want to scan you can define like
how much data you want to scan or what
is the maximum file size that is mainly
not to take up too many resources on
your system
and you can also say like which hashing
algorithm do you want to use to figure
out which files have changed sha-1 is
the default we have a couple of others
I'll have those in the next slide so you
can figure out what is happening there
and then we can actually head back to
the dashboards to see if we can find
what has been happening here so here we
are interested in audit feed and we are
interested in the file integrity and we
can see okay three files were created
updated and changed you can see when
that happened you can see which user was
responsible for that change and here you
can see which files were most edited or
changed and since I was using VI well we
have the swap file and that's why we
don't have just one file but we have
multiple files being edited but that's
just how VI is handling files but this
is basically tracking everything will
change that we do to that directory and
it's hashing the files and thanks to
that hash we can just figure out who has
been doing what to a file and then you
will probably see why suddenly your
website has hearty emojis on it rather
than the actual content that you want to
have or probably stuff that is worse
than hearty emojis and you can see okay
on which host how many change events
happened this will be useful if you have
more than one host and you can see which
files what or what happened to the files
like where they move deleted updated
like all the operations that we are
being run on your files you can get the
idea of that year okay yeah this we are
the hash types that I promised you so
sha-1 is the default which is we think a
decent trade-off between speed and like
a good hashing function to get the most
performant hashing function that we have
is the last one that's as XS aged 64
that is the most performant hashing
function that is part of the file
integrity check okay since we have some
time left let's let's try something else
as well let's let's talk that's a net
cat
anybody wants to send me a message or do
I have to talk to myself
let's see telnet and ideally here our
messages will appear so if anybody is
quick enough telnet or anything else
will work to send messages how can I
find that I've opened another port or
been running a program to figure out
that somebody has been opening something
and maybe they should have been doing
that or shouldn't have been doing that
any guesses where to start let's head
over to the raw events again get rid of
the the filter you can see we have 1600
events in the last 15 minutes let's say
you know that something happened on a
specific port and well we have no idea
of where to start so actually I will
just start with the full-text search and
if I just start with 1025 since we are
logging all the system calls every time
the program has been running we can
actually very easily see okay which user
has been running what program and and
what has been happening so you can see
this was the user that has been running
the process so the elastic admin has
been running that and this was the
actual command that we have been running
so netcat l thousand 25 so people can
actually chat with me and nobody wants
to talk to me which is very sad but this
is just how to get started on that okay
we have seen the file integrity by the
way if you have lots of events something
that might be very useful is that you
don't just have static filters but then
you have something that learns
automatically kind of what is happening
on your system which might look
something like this for example these
are let's assume the unique IP address
is connected to your system or the users
locked into your system or whatever you
have and you probably have some pattern
where you see five weekdays
and then you have the weekend where
there's less activity and you want to
find anomalies like when something
unexpected is happening like here which
is kind of hard to see but if you zoom
into that you can actually see here the
blue band this is kind of the expected
baseline and here's something unexpected
happened and this is from our own
website the unique users on our website
and that was one and a half years ago or
almost two years ago when Amazon s3 went
down but this is just how to figure out
when unexpected stuff happens on your
system and especially with oddity which
can be a bit noisy and creates a lot of
events creating rules manual is often
the pain in the ass and having some
machine learning to actually learn what
is happening on your system normally can
be very beneficial on that end okay so
to wrap up and have some time for
questions I always compare this entire
thing a bit to Lego you have all these
building blocks but you need to stick
them together so you need to start with
the oddity rules like which oddity rules
make sense if you need inspiration like
I've mentioned before here you have a
lot of rules that you might want to take
a look at and which can teach you what
is possible or what might make sense and
then you need to figure out how do I get
or centralize those events we tried to
provide a solution for that but you can
also try to manually collect it then use
or report for example to see what is
happening in your system yeah and we've
basically seen going from oddity to the
audit pit and then integrating that with
logs and other dashboards and just
seeing what is happening to that system
overall that's the general idea if you
want to try that out yourself you can go
to dashboard and used I think you should
be logged in automatically with
dashboard only user so you will not be
able to delete any data you will not be
able to create any new visualizations
but you get to the default dashboards
let me actually try that out if that
works as I'm expecting it to work
hopefully
so you should be locked in with a user
automatically that doesn't have too many
permissions if you load this is not a
demo effect come on
No
No okay I will check if I have
misconfigured my dashboard user know
it's working it's just slow and if you
log into that you will not be able to
create any new visualization so you can
see I have a lot of more buttons here
but you will be able to for example to
here see which executions have been
running or which SSH users have tried to
log in and I'm not giving you the root
user but if you want to play around with
it this is the password and the user for
the regular access so you can just log
in and try some random stuff and see if
you can find that in the in the events
and I will delete that instance tomorrow
morning so yeah there shouldn't be too
much harm you can do but please don't
abuse the instance too much and by the
way I wanted to check to do it do we
have more ssh logging attempts from
finland now let's see and let's see how
good our geoip lookup is today because
that's always the question seems to be
pretty decent here
okay more or less you generally get the
idea if I'm not mistaken I think we were
about here or so we're slightly off but
at least this looks generally correct
I'm curious that was the wrong button
that's not what I wanted them come to me
I was curious which that's let's say
this this is where we what we're
interested in let's filter down on that
area and then I can see which usernames
you try it okay
and rocky seems to be in the house as
well so these are the ones the 27
locking attempts that you have tried
from this area and whatever your IP
addresses are okay if you want to take a
look at the code I mean this entire set
up is automated there is the terraform
stuff and the ansible configuration and
then the configuration files the thing
that you're probably most interested in
is the audit beat configuration which I
have in there as well so this is all
part of the repository you can just head
to the repository and check it out if
you want to give it a spin and this
should be pretty easy to reproduce on
any other system that you have as well
so that's the URL for that so if you
take the code from there you should get
this up and running in pretty much no
time and with that we have like 11
minutes left
time for questions also I have a bunch
of stickers over there if you want to
grab stickers be quick there might not
be enough for everybody any questions in
the room
otherwise I will had to slide off and I
have a very hard time seeing if anybody
has questions I think we have a question
over there thank you and while you're
getting while you're getting the
microphone let me have two slide oh as
well so we are not overlooking anybody
it's great to see some more
versions of this sort of technology but
there's a lot of commercial software
doing the same sort of things about a
lot of people who work in security
operation centers will be familiar with
things like carbon black Trend Micro
have deep inspect that there's quite a
lot how do you feel that this currently
compares with what's on the market from
from those commercial vendors so we
generally let's see what I can say now
let's let's just say like security will
be a big topic for us and we see that as
an opportunity to dive into lots of
other things I know that we are being
used for seem like use cases already
we'll probably try to get a bit more
into that space but it's a very wide
ecosystem and obviously there are a lot
of other vendors and a lot of commercial
vendors which have quite a head start on
us so we'll have to do some catching up
to do
but we'll try to do our best and we're
also trying to integrate with some other
tools for example if you had over to the
very first start page here you can see
we we are trying to get more security
analytics and this very things that we
are advertising here is generally we can
get net flow data for your firm then
your networking devices we tie into oils
query dope probably we will have some
native stuff that is very similar to
always query in beats as well soon and
we're playing around with the story
catalogs as well and try to integrate
into those as well and generally I mean
this is always the nice position that
you can take in open source is that
whatever you want to build you can do it
yourself because you have all the code
and you can just integrate into that but
like I said with the Lego bricks it's
more like stuff that you need to put
together we're not like this solution
that you buy and that's kind of the
final thing and it just works out of the
box it's giving you a much wider range
and you can integrate it in various
directions but it's probably a bit more
plumbing necessary but I would assume
that you're the right audience for
plumbing it don't get me wrong it's
better than some of the commercial
solutions I've seen by a big stretch
thanks a lot
any other questions okay while you can
think about that let let me head over to
questions I have seen here
okay bottom one is very good thank you
so yeah we have we have a file beet
module for always curious so if you have
always query installed you can collect
that so let me just quickly show that
file bit module OS query basically when
you run OS query it can create the logs
and then we have the file beet module
which can automatically collect that log
file so depending on what you have
activated here it will look something
like that where you see okay these are
my operating systems these are the
kernel versions these are all that the
packages that we have but we will also
soon enough have something where this
will be built into the beets directly so
you don't need to run always clear
yourself but if you want to run always
query you can totally do that just
generate the right logs with always
query and we will happily collect those
and we have even the pre-built
dashboards for you so you can just keep
using that and get an overview of what
you have running on your entire fleet of
machines based on the oil's query data I
think that was it for the questioners
here any other questions in the room we
have still seven minutes left I have a
very hard time seeing unfortunately for
multi-threading applications what's your
ability to distinguish between
multi-threaded applications and monitor
those you mean to distinguish the threat
would be a threading injection attack
I'm honestly not sure how well we would
handle that at the moment we I've never
seen how we would handle that to be
honest I'm not sure
maybe a quick search will give you
something or nothing at all then we
would be curious how that actually works
but I I don't know from the top of my
head to be honest well if there are no
other questions if you have any other
questions um also if you have like
general questions about our stack I'm
here happy to help with anything
I just find me afterwards and thanks a
lot oh by the way before you run out I'm
not sure if that will work out I try to
take a picture with you normally so I
can prove to my colleagues that I've
been working because they normally don't
know where I am I'm not sure if you will
be visible
let's see smile or not smile you don't
see me anyway that's better thank you
thanks now I can prove to my colleagues
that I've been working thanks a lot
[Music]