you
and this second one was what an older
version of optimises are produced as a
result so you had a back where this
mathematical function in a very rare
corner case produced a wrong result and
I found quite a couple of these kind of
bugs with this strategy yeah this is the
patch where this was introduced it's an
assembly I have no idea what it does and
now another tool that is very good to
combine with fuzzing is address
sanitizer and this is really something I
am currently running around and trying
to tell free software developers that
they make use of this tool because it's
really really simple and it it can
assign sometimes quite easily find bugs
so address sanitizer is a feature in the
compiler it's available both in GCC and
si lang and it can be enabled with this
flag - eff sanitized address so if you
only want to take one thing away from
this talk if you write software and C
then use this flag to test your software
and here's a little code example so
we're allocating a buffer and then just
writing zeros into it and then we're
freeing the buffer and then we're trying
to read from the buffer so it's a use
after free back kind of standard use
after free back you're freeing a buffer
and then still trying to read from it
and this is I mean this is a very simple
example but this is usually the kind of
pack you have in applications like
browsers these days when you have
security issues now here I have this
code
and now if I compile it okay yeah yeah
so what happens if I run this is is
essentially unpredictable so in this
case I have a zero and this will also
usually happen because we're not doing
anything between the freeing and the
reading of it but we we cannot rely that
the compiler will do anything
predictable in this situation now if we
add address and it either to it and also
I add G which just gives us some
debugging information then and I have to
do this then okay
repeat then we get a very nice error
message with this heap use after free
tells us in which line in the code it
happened and it tells us okay this is in
some memory region that was freed in
this line and it was allocated in this
line so we get a lot of information that
will help us to analyze this bug and the
thing is with use after free most of the
time these bugs don't crash your
application also if you have out of
one's memory reads they also usually
just your application continues running
and something strange may have happened
and so it's hard to find these bugs
without such a tool so address sanitizer
is very helpful that it allows you to
find these kinds of bugs yeah this is
again the error message and it's maybe
maybe you know wor grind which does
similar things but well grind is quite
limited because it works on the already
compiled
beautiful and some classes of parks
cannot be found with that strategy so
it's a bit like address sanitizer is a
more advanced version of walk around and
it's also much faster because it
operates at compile time so yeah and
what you ideally want to do is you're
combining fuzzing with address sanitizer
because then you will just find more
bugs and find these subtle bugs that are
otherwise very hard to find you probably
all remember this one the hot lead back
which was essentially an out-of-bounds
read back you had some buffer and and
the length and if you gave server length
that was longer than this buffer it
would just read that and send it back to
the user and I did a little experiment
with that I created a small tool that
was doing a handshake with open SSL with
itself and then added the possibility
that you could just swap out one of the
TLS packages with something you gave it
on the command line and by that I was
able to fast the handshake of open SSL
and then using that with an older
version that was vulnerable to
heartbleed after a couple of hours it
we've discovered the heartbleed bug now
you can say okay it's it's easy to find
it back if you already know where it is
but I would argue that in this
experiment I didn't use any information
that was very specific to heartbleed it
was just a handshake it was just a
normal fasting how I would have done it
otherwise if yeah I took it six hours
and another tool called lip father which
I will also talk about later a bit more
the developer of lip father wrote me
then an email and said he has replicated
this experiment with lip father and it
only took it five minutes so yeah then
something else I tried was I asked okay
if you have address sanitizer and it
finds all these marks can you compile a
whole
system with address sanitizer in a bird
so usually you use it for testing for
one application but if you compile the
whole system okay that may may find some
more subtle bugs and I created a gentle
system where everything except some
co-op packages was compiled with address
sanitizer so for you have some problems
if you want to compile GFC with it
because what essentially it is doing is
it is intercepting the memory allocation
functions of tree Lipsy and if you use
it jealously with it then you will get
some weird dependency conflicts and GCC
also didn't work because it's compiling
these these base functions entities in
executables so I had to exclude those
and a few more core dependencies but the
rest of the system everything was
compiled with address sanitizer it is
slow and it takes a lot of memory but it
is possible to run yeah and what was to
be expected is that just by doing this I
found a lot of parks in a lot of
packages and I have a list here I I made
it a bit longer this morning this is
stuff I found recently so you see a lot
of stuff that like bash or Python syslog
and also things where you say ok maybe
this is security critical like the
picture in OTR plugin there was a use
after free just by using it so no
fuzzing involved right anything just
starting it and if you opened a certain
dialog it would crash with the use after
free bug was fixed in the last version
yeah so yeah I think this was quite
worth it it led to a lot of bug fixes
and yeah there were some challenges with
it so the one thing with address
sanitizer is you can you can use a an
executable with address sanitizer with a
normal library that's not using address
sanitizer but if you do it the other way
around
it does not work so if you have a
library like let's say you compile your
system OpenSSL with address sanitizer
then all the binaries that are not
compiled with address sanitizer will
stop working
so if you re compiling your system with
address sanitizer you have to check in
which order you do it that nothing that
breaks and you also cannot easily just
include exclude one package if you want
to exclude something you also have to
exclude all the dependencies then there
are some build system if you one was
with Lib tool that when Lib tool is
compiling a library and it filters out
all compiler flags that it doesn't know
about and it didn't know about address
analyzer so that broke it's now fixed in
the get code of Lib tool but they have
not made a new release yet and then and
if you have some custom memory
allocation in an application that
usually also doesn't work yeah then one
in past talks I had about this I said ok
maybe this is something you may want to
use if you want to have a very secure
system but this is probably not a good
idea we had address analyzer was
designed as a testing tool and not as a
production tool and this introduces some
problems and someone on the security
list showed a way where how you could
use address sanitizer to become route if
you have a Seward executable compiled
with address sanitizer so this
introduces security issues so at least
in the way it's currently working it is
not usable practically as a as a
production protection mechanism so it's
a good testing tool but it's not
something you want to run in the real
world yeah but yeah it works I had half
a server running with it for I can serve
a pages and yeah found a lot of parks
with it I still have a large number of
locked files of bugs from that that I
have not I have not reported yet I
haven't gone
yet I probably somehow I have to
crowdsource that because there's so many
of them yeah but if you are involved in
any free software project please please
just compile it with address sanitizer
once and run the test suite and see if
something turns out what's up with that
okay um some other tools that are worth
mentioning
I'm lip father I already mentioned
earlier is it works similar than
American fuzzy lot but it works on the
function level so it's not calling an
application it's calling a function so
you're writing a wrapper function that
takes a buffer and the length and then
you feed that into the whatever function
you want to test the advantage of that
is first of all it's it's targeting
different things like it's a function in
other software and it's it's much faster
than a FL because FL has to like fork a
new process for every tested input and
this just is running in one process so
it's much faster but it it's a bit
tricky to use because you have to be
very careful that you're not for example
that you're not leaking any memory
inside your test function because then
just the memory of the process will grow
till it's too much because it's
executing this function millions of
times and so it's not as straightforward
to use but it's also very useful tool
especially if you integrate that in the
development process of a software I
think then it's a very powerful tool and
it's part of LLVM so yeah and this case
on which is like address sanitizer in
the linux kernel and this is just an
option you can in make menu config and a
debugging you can just enable that and
yeah when I tried this the first time
then I immediately got some warnings
that my graphics driver was accessing
some invalid memory so yeah it's
probably not not used as often as it
should be
and death now after a tool called sis
Cola which is adapting a strategy
similar what Lib father and Ava are
using with this coverage based fuzzing
to the kernel with Cisco fuzzing and I'm
also read that there are people trying
to fast other kernel inputs with similar
strategies yeah so then there are other
sanitizer features in the compilers so
one is UV Sun which detects undefined
behavior so maybe you know that in C
there are some things like if you have a
signed integer overflow or if you have a
shift left by a negative value these
things the standard says that they are
undefined so you cannot rely that they
do anything predictable and UV son finds
these things a bit of a problem with
that is that there are so many of these
bugs and usually they don't do anything
bad because most of the time the
compiler will just do what you expect it
to do like an integer overflow just okay
if you have int max plus 1 it gives it
mean that usually happens but you cannot
rely on it so yeah and there's also a
thread sanitizer and memory sanitizer
but these are a bit more tricky to use
so the really nice thing with address
sanitizer is that it's just your enable
it and it usually just works so yeah and
there's some work done to to adapt FL to
networking because the the standard a FL
is trust testing file inputs so you have
executable and give it some file and
yeah there's a patch for it to true let
it fast TCP inputs and there's also
another attempt where you're using a
preload library that will take something
from standard in and feed it into a TCP
port but these things are quite brittle
and it's not as straightforward to use
so you have to play around with it a bit
and
there's certainly room for improvement
here so and there's a part of American
fuzzy look to Android I have not tested
this myself but yeah if you know about
Android security it's probably a good
thing it is needed they should fast test
their stuff and what's interesting is
like I mentioned earlier that some of
the stage fright bugs were found with a
FL and what happened there is that the
guy who found them ported stage fright
library to standard Linux so he could
facets so yeah yeah and as a at the end
I want to ask you like who is involved
in some kind of C development or C++
development his hands up that's yeah
maybe a third and are you already using
fuzzing or are you using address
sanitizer or and who is not using both
fuzzing and address sanitizer from the
future okay so now you know what you
have to do next it will improve yourself
to a quality definitely yeah thanks for
listening
yeah and I'm I think we have time for
questions
all right so my first question would be
like what what is your attitude to
static code analysis maybe model
checking static code analysis okay it's
actually I have not used it a whole lot
and my impression was that it will
usually not find the most interesting
bugs but I don't have a lot of
experience with it so maybe I am wrong
on that no more questions
how did you find the OTR know the the
pigeon OTR plugin titude do you really
click on the you are yes I just I had
the general system built with retro
sanitizer and then I started the pigeon
and started a chat session and so the
back happened when you try to
authenticate your the other contact and
another interesting thing about that one
is it was already reported six months
earlier in their Park tracker but it was
ignored so this house also shows up that
your fuzzing project or your initiative
many targets file input systems or the
the attack surfaces is file input but
there's a whole whole lot Geron from
user input or on embedded systems where
you can't do this file stuff thingy yeah
so I mean that the patron back was there
was no fuzzing involved it was just yeah
I mean I talked about these two tools
AFL and address sanitizer and this was
just address sanitizer so this is just
use this to compile your software and
test it with it but there was also but
the developers from repo office they did
something where they emulated the clicks
on their GUI by based on an input and
use that for fuzzing which is also quite
interesting approach yeah I think the
the file input should be extended to all
using yeah definitely I wasn't but they
recognized STEM fields and and fill them
and because almost no user interface
today uses only file input yeah I mean
it's a rant class is the easiest thing
yes yes it's the low-hanging fruit you
know start
what kind of information do you need to
provide to FL about the structure of
files that nothing you give it a an
example file and the rest it does by
itself okay okay if there are no more
questions then yeah thanks for listening
you