ah
um yeah I'm having this talk in English
I hope there is nobody who expected in
German yeah I want to talk a bit about
own cloud and the encryption module in
it but it's more like I want to talk
about crypto design in general and this
is just an example and what I'm looking
at here but it's the the message is much
more general it's not any this the back
i'm going to show you is not i think it
doesn't have a very high impact but it
tells you a lot about how to design a
cryptosystem a quick introduction about
me I'm Hannah Burke I work part time as
a freelance journalist you may
occasionally read my articles on ghulam
and I also do a fuzzing which I is
supported by the linux foundation's core
infrastructure initiative and yeah i had
to talk about that earlier today and and
occasionally but this is just like my
private interest i do things with crypto
and i hope you all have heard this in
one way or another that if you do crypto
what what you should never do is that
inventing your own crypto algorithms
like if you think you invented a
super-secure cipher that nobody can
break then it's probably not very secure
but I want to ask you a bit like how do
exactly do we interpret that rule
because I think there are some
subtleties that are not entirely clear
and I mean this is an obvious example
this came up on the IETF crypto working
group list where someone presented in
new cipher the crystalline cipher and
there are a number of things like a yeah
it's designed to be as secure as a
one-time pad that's your real are
already a sign that something might be
strange
yeah random source is based upon
radioactive decay okay maybe a bit
complicated in your smartphone hopes to
set a new standard in security and then
the key sizes 16 kilobyte keys and salt
that's I think 128 kilobytes and you
should get them from a truly random
sauce and you can if you don't know
where to get your randomness here's a
URL where you can download your
randomness is so this I mean this is
obvious yeah that's not a serious
project that it but you have these
people come up every now and then on
some crypto mailing list someone comes
with oh I have invented a new cipher and
then like people point out some obvious
flaws and then they don't understand it
and okay that's not how we do crypto but
that's another thing and it's like okay
we all know we should use standard
algorithms we should use algorithms that
a lot of people have looked at like for
example AES or RS a or sha-256 but the
problem is even if you use these secure
algorithms and put them together into
some kind of protocol that doesn't
automatically make a secure protocol
like we learned a lot in the past
decades about how to put together things
and get a bad protocol like ssl version
3 as is ever and three the building
blocks are mostly quite okay it uses RSA
you can use it with AES or triple des
that are all secure algorithms but the
whole protocol together there are many
subtleties like how do you do padding
what kind of modes are you using from
those ciphers so I would say we need to
interpret this rule in a way that you
should not build your own crypto
algorithms but you also should not build
your own crypto protocols at least not
if you don't know what you're doing
yeah and that brings me to own cloud now
this catch my interest this was a press
release they later removed it from the
web page but there was luckily avoiders
news message which reproduce this press
release where they say okay they have an
encryption module and this modular
approach you can swap out the existing
aes-256 encryption with the new RSA
algorithm um RSA is from the 1970s I
think an Aes is from 2001 so um also I
mean RSA and AES are very different
algorithms RSA is the public key
algorithm and a SSM symmetric algorithm
so this doesn't make a lot of sense to
swap them out so okay we know on cloud
has written a press release obviously by
someone who doesn't know a lot about
crypto um and that kind of got me
interested in looking at what this
encryption module actually does so to
understand here is what act what this
module does is maybe not one what one
would expect so the threat model is a
bit unusual the idea is you have own
cloud installed on one server and you
trust that server but you include some
storage space maybe from some cloud
provider or something that you embed and
and you don't trust that storage space
for example if you want to upload very
big files you don't have enough space on
your web server and then you have some
external web space that you don't trust
and so you use encryption and your keys
are on the server where your own cloud
itself runs but the files should be safe
on some some potentially untrusted a
storage space so I'd like today okay
they are probably not a lot of people
who need this scenario so I assume this
is probably not used by a whole lot of
people or so i think the
vulnerability i'm going to show you is
not that big of a deal but yeah as I
said I want that you learned something
about crypto so so the first thing I did
is just look how do these encrypted
files look like what's in them and they
start with this text which says
something H begins something about
encryption module and now we have a
problem with the screen resolution the
thing on the right is a ES and then 256
cfb okay so we know something about the
cipher they are using they're using AES
and they're using it in cfb mode so what
you have to learn a bit about modes so
AES is a block cipher that means you
have a block off which is for AES 128
bits and you only encrypt the block so
the algorithm itself you cannot say
please encrypt this text you can only
encrypt the block so if you want to use
AES in practice you need some kind of
mode to use this block cipher for longer
inputs and they're different kind of
modes ECB so ECB is where you just
encrypt one block by another and this is
not really an encryption note this is
totally insecure you should just never
use that it's more or less just an
example to explain block modes then
there are quite common modes are cbc and
CTR they are for example used in cbc is
still used quite a lot in TLS although
we probably shouldn't be used and CTR is
in more modern products these modes only
encrypt something but they don't
guarantee you that that any authenticity
that means if an attacker can manipulate
your cipher text he may be able to
change it in a
and change it in a specific way that
like flipping a bit things like that so
you flip a bit in the ciphertext and the
pit gets also flipped in the decrypted
text and then there are modes like GCM
or poorly 1305 or ocb these are
so-called authenticated encryption or
more detailed authenticated encryption
with additional data and these modes
also guarantee you that unless you have
the the secret key you cannot change the
content so if you change something then
the recipient of the message will notice
it the algorithm will just say okay here
happened an error this ciphertext is not
correct and then there are some special
modes for hard disk encryption which is
a bit messy but that's not the topic
today and as a rule of sample you can
say usually you want to use
authenticated encryption there's almost
never a good reason not to use
authenticated encryption so what's the
cfp mode so it's a bit more unusual it's
not a very common mode the feature of
cfb mode is that it's self correcting
that if you you can start the decryption
in the middle of a cipher text and then
the you get one bad block and the next
block is correct again so what this
enables is that you can do things like
seeking I only want to download the
middle of a file or address the second
half or things like that and it's not
authenticated you can flip a in
the ciphertext and what happens then is
that this bit will be flipped in the
decrypted text and it will change the
next block to something basically random
so so as an attacker okay we cannot
decrypt the ciphertext but we can change
the content and so okay what does what
does how does this matter now let's
assume someone has an uncloudy instance
and
they are uploading some piece of
software for their colleagues like an
installer or are just a small X file
then can we can we maybe back door that
exif I'll if we're in a checker that can
access this space now if we look at an
exit file you will see this this program
cannot be run in DOS mode so even on
modern systems every Windows executable
still has a dose program embedded that
usually just displaced this text and the
interesting thing is that this is always
the same at least if you're using a
standard Microsoft compiler so we have
something here even if we don't know
what this XO file does we have some some
bites here where we know what they are
doing or where we know what they are so
we can manipulate them baby in the way
we want and this is yeah i created a
proof of concept here so we can just um
yeah and another thing is like the in
the fourth line there's this 0 0 0 1 0
this is the offset of the windows
executable header and so what windows
does is it checks this offset if there's
a PE header which is like the modern X a
header and if it's not there then it
assumes it's a das program so okay what
we could do here is and what I did the
proof of concept is that if you're just
and yeah and also for the block length
the block length is exactly one line
here it's 128 bits which is 16 bytes
which is exactly one line here so if we
change anything in the third line then
this will scramble the fourth line
because we had cfb mode you change
something next block has random content
so if we change a single bit in the
third line
the P the offset of the windows PE
header will be destroyed and it will be
a dose program for windows and in the
fifth line this this step does program
is always the same so we can change that
at least we can change one block of it
now yeah that's what I did and created a
proof-of-concept code so you're just
flipping one bit in the third block then
your ex or in this dust-up code with the
code you want to inject and then your ex
or the ciphertext with it and then yeah
we have changed the executable to
execute some code that we want now I
have a demo for this here's an uncloudy
instance and we upload some and
driver and I had a pretty executable
prepared here we'll just download putty
then I'm just using putty because it's a
small executable and ya know we don't
want to start it yep ok and now now we
we look on this server storage space now
we have the directory for the user admin
and we have the XE here now the
first interesting thing is the file name
is is still the same so we're already
leaking some information to our attic ok
better yeah and if you look into it as
we so before this H begin and uncloudy
encryption module stuff and now we run
this exploit code on put exe ok so we
yeah and now we download it again yes a
file and no now this so the Pooh TX is
the one we had before and to put a 1
access the one we just downloaded and
with so if we start the original with
those box because it's now a dose
executable it will say ok this cannot be
run in DOS mode and if we start
manipulated one ok it prints spoon
so that's on the screen right yeah so
what we did was yeah we we had an
executable online and we could inject
some code under our control now this is
only 16 bytes of code that doesn't
really give us a whole lot but we will
find other places in the executable that
usually have zeros or have other stuff
that we can predict and then we can jump
around and back draw many parts of the
files so this is definitely possible to
create something exploitable here yeah
then I reported this to own cloud the
first fix they proposed was that there
were now using counter mode and they are
so they are always encrypting blocks of
8 kilobytes and then use an H mega
authentication this is better but it
still has a problem that you can still
operate the blocks inside a file because
every block is is encrypted in the same
way and still the problem that the fine
aims are leaked is still there then then
the second fix they deployed is that
they they embedded a number for the
block so now you can no longer swap that
blocks around the filename leak is still
there this is what they shipped in
version 9 which was recently released
and now you might ask is this secure and
I can just say I don't know it's secure
enough that I did not find anything
obvious in it anymore but I'm yeah I
know a bit about crypto but I'm not like
an expert to audit these kinds of things
so in my opinion this module either
should get a professional audit from
someone who knows this stuff and I mean
also there are other potential issues
like how do they generate their keys and
that's this orbit the key storage makes
sense either this needs a professional
audit or the module should be
moved that's what I said told the own
cloud developers obviously they decided
otherwise they ship this now maybe fixed
version i don't know if it's secure yeah
then you might wonder why don't they use
authenticated encryption that's also
what I asked like just use GCM I mean
GCM is it's not perfect but it's
definitely better than building your own
combination of various modes the problem
with that is that on cloud is written in
PHP and PHP doesn't support GCM mode so
you currently cannot use authenticated
encryption modes from PHP they plan to
change that in PHP 7.1 the problem with
that is then you can maybe use it in 15
years because people tend to use PHP
versions which are 10 years old I don't
know I think the most common PHP version
is the 5.3 which I mean 5.4 is already
out of security support yeah hmm yeah
maybe I mean a PHP 7.1 is not released
yet so I think it will be released in
summer then okay you might how would you
do better what would I propose and it's
a bit difficult because the for this
scenario i think there's no ready-made
protocol or construction that you can
easily use and i think this is a problem
there should be something like i want to
encrypt a file and store it somewhere
with a key that is a pretty standard
scenario but there's no no really good
solution for it and you solve some
problems if you just use authenticated
encryption but like then if you want to
start like I want to be able to download
a part of a file then you need to check
that and this tracking there's no
standard for it and write with
authenticated encryption also has like
some traps where you have to get things
right so I think this is really a lack
of
some kind of protocol or standard for
this use scenario I thought about one
possibility but I'm not sure if I would
recommend it it was but I will present
it anyway I thought okay we have we have
standard for message encryption like
four emails like PGP or CMS which is as
my technology we could say okay we use
that I mean this is with public key
cryptography but we could say okay let's
use a public key cryptography it's it's
lower than the symmetric key but maybe
that we don't care we just want
something secure and this is maybe well
audited but then I looked how would I do
cryptographic message syntax in PHP and
in the documentation this was the
example and it's using hace 2 with 40
bits yeah that's kind of a yeah expert
mode crypto history from the 90s so it's
also not straightforward to get this
secure so and I don't know if this is a
good idea for this scenario so but yeah
yeah so takeaways don't invent your own
crypto don't invent crypto algorithms
don't invent crypto protocols
authenticated encryption should be used
Yuri whenever possible and unless
there's a very good reason not to do
that's the way to do it and I think we
lack some proper standards for these
kind of use scenarios although it's I
think quite a common thing there's no
standard solution where you can say here
put in your key here put in your thing
to encrypt that's something that should
be there and isn't there and yeah you
probably should not trust the unplowed
encryption module yeah thanks
other questions I'm just asking about
about your opinion do you consider ank
FS or a crypt of s for this use case as
a better alternative um what was the
first one and it was it's just one
question do you can see ya yeah I didn't
understand the first one so it was just
this question yeah you will consider an
gfs or equipped if s as a good at I
don't kill the first one I I know
equipped FS but the problem is that
these disk encryption things they do a
lot of trade-offs between security and
practicality and it's not really nice
what they're using either as encryption
modes so it's probably not a good
alternative either okay and also I mean
this is probably not available in PHP to
may include in your web application and
yeah I mean you're laughing but I think
I mean PHP whether you not like it or
not it's a standard programming language
that's used for a lot of applications
and I think there should be encryption
technology that's just usable and works
okay um does not
I think the the scenario that when
you're looking at clouds having a disk
you don't trust is not that exotic so it
says something you would recommend
actually a few your friendted space
somewhere in the cloud until you don't
want I mean it depends what you want to
do if I know that they're like backup
solutions that encrypt like ethic and
stuff but that dependent that matches
your use case because the that's not a
web applications oh yeah but I don't
have a good recommendation okay yeah
thanks
you