operations and other just we're talking
about
cia fbi uh a lot of coordination he's
basically doing their job trying to do
their job to get the data for criminal
investigations
and um with that over to you
yeah so the first fun fact is
we're german and we do beer but
so don't expect it too much
yeah all right all right so
um the german constitutional court
actually put a lot of
um safeguards in place uh for limiting
law enforcement from
basically uh trying to do their job and
conduct government hacking
so in 2016 the government agencies
finally
were done with their first kind of own
hacking software that they could use
to get all the data of the criminals but
because of the restrictions of the
constitutional court they ended up with
a
government hacking software trojan
malware
that could only convert record skype
conversations
and only on windows platforms so as
millions of euros and dollars went into
a malware that could do one thing record
skype conversations that's all a lot
more
nothing more fun
fact number three is um the
self-programmed remote
forensic software built by the federal
office for
criminal investigation to infiltrate was
so bad
that the national cyber security agency
which is actually working to defend
against any such software
had to support write the code and secure
the software at the servers
the support was supposed to be kept
under the waiter
as the image could be damaged and
obviously what happened
everyone found out and now um there's
those trust
issues between companies and civil
society and the cyber security agency
which is supposed to
defend uh against everything so
not so helpful fun fact number four
in 2017 the german government actually
set up its own entire agency
which was dedicated only to buy and
research and
program tools for hacking and big data
analysis and stuff
and they are supposed to give those
tools to other law enforcement agencies
and
security agencies in germany um problem
is
they so far have not succeeded in
developing buying or doing anything
remotely useful as of terms for hacking
tools for
other police agencies and
which is why the security agencies are
not very happy with all the resources
that went into that agency since 2017
because it has delivered zilch nothing
nada but then again on the plus side
after two years so 2019 it was finally
operational
only took two years to make it
operational and uh by the way it has
like
only 100 stats it took them two years to
hire 100 120 staff
so another fun fact um in 2014
germany's federal office for criminal
investigation
hacked the secure telegram messengers
accounts of
eight persons the users of these
accounts were suspects
in ongoing criminal investigations
against extremist right-wing
groups um the hack allowed them
to access the entire history of the
non-encrypted chats including media
files connected to the accounts
as well as new messages in real time
the hack used a mixed mixture of
features and flaws in the messenger and
account design
and it was a whole lot of work to get
there involved also the
telecommunication provider
and then the data that was obtained in
the hack together with other pieces of
evidence
was then presented in the court that
eventually convicted the suspects
in spring 2017 but there was additional
human intelligence information from the
domestic intelligence services as well
as
compelling evidence obtained through
conventional wiretapping
so the latter actually led to the
evidence of
led to the evidence that was then the
basis for the indictment
so the whole thing was probably
redundant
in fact number six so we are now having
a couple of laws on the table in
in germany and if all those laws pass
through the parliament and autumn this
year which hopefully they don't
um they will enable security agencies to
mandate telecommunication providers and
service providers and over the top
services
such as whatsapp that's how they are
defined
to deliver malware directly
to the users so you're gonna get
poisoned what's up updates
specifically only created for you with a
nice backdoor
and even better because they can involve
the internet service providers and they
work together with our
beautiful finfisher company in munich
they can actually they can actually set
up proxies that automatically deliver
that malware whenever
the users go to a certain website and
conduct
a beautiful man in the middle my way
delivery
we are so excited about that
so fun fact number seven um it has never
really been evaluated
rather government hacking led to any
real successes
in lowering or preventing crimes
nevertheless
their state level legislations and
federal legislations
are still being proposed that eventually
all security agencies should just do it
fun fact number eight uh right the
current status quo is that every
government agency in germany can do with
vulnerabilities whatever they want they
don't have to give it to the cyber
security agency they don't
have to give it to the vendor they don't
have to give it to anyone they can do
whatever they want sometimes
they can just keep it in the basement or
in the safe locked up and not talk about
it for years um but the funny thing is
no one wants to change that
uh there's processes that we've been
talking about for three years right now
which we want to establish also based on
the american vulnerabilities equities
process
but uh neither most of the civil society
groups uh nor industry
nor government agencies actually wants
that and they don't want to change the
status quo even though the status quo is
basically horribly
horrible for everyone uh law enforcement
cyber security agencies uh civil society
but no one wants to change it
so fact number nine even though the
focus of those legislations that we've
been mentioning
are more focused on domestic and
national security
the cyber security policies and
strategies that are being communicated
are actually super defense oriented
aiming to achieve
it security and resilience for society
and businesses
in 2017 um the german government even
proposed in the agenda
uh to have the goal to become the crypto
country number one
in the world so the german government
doesn't seem to understand that
government hacking does not necessarily
increase ig security
or in general they should maybe learn
more about their cyber stuff and
differentiate a little bit more
so if you know things like we're really
disorganized and nothing is working in
germany and government hacking is kind
of a mess here
you're right but as we are very german
of course we have a great
structure and a perfect organization
when it comes to cyber security
so uh you and i spends the last hour to
draw your little picture
of how the german cyber security
architecture looks like and
that's how it looked like uh so on the
top in the blue you see the european
level institutions which are connected
to the gray level which are the federal
institutions
which are connected to the purple ones
which is the state level institutions
we haven't come down to the local level
yet because we were running out of time
but that's gonna be most probably next
so if ever you think
cyber security in germany is not working
yeah that might have
something to do with that
like that
can you guys hear the cyber cyber or not
christian could you hear the
last video
ah so maybe we just post the link into
the chat groups then
okay it's a video of
politicians saying cyber because they
all want a cyber
without really knowing
so does anyone have any questions for
julia and and sven
you'll have to unmute yourselves to add
so the two of you don't think that uh
the german government uh especially with
uh the lovely jubbly who does what and
whatever
have the capabilities currently like the
dutch government do for hacking
so for for i i i mean for law
enforcement uh
no most probably gonna end up buying
some stuff from finfish or celebrate or
nso maybe not who knows um
the military also not
uh we're yet unsure about the
capabilities of the
foreign intelligence service it's
something that we don't know a lot about
it but honestly from what i've heard
i don't think so
for those who don't know uh the dutch
government was the first government that
um put in writing that uh they had the
right to
hack into any device anywhere in the
world
as long as a dutch prosecutor signed off
on it
so it could be an i.t iot or ics system
and they do a lot of hacking into for
example
cctv systems to get
footage of criminals or nation-states
the absolute proof of them hacking into
various government systems
so i just want to give another minute
for
questions
is there anyone else who has any other
yeah i see the question in the chat
about maximator which is the uh
the company which was set up between i
think the u.s and german intelligence
agencies to develop a crypto tool which
was
a great crypto tool because it was uh
only secure
for certain people and for other
governments they sold an insecure
version
um and let the germans and the americans
have access to all the communications
running through it
and the great thing is we even sold it
to some of our allies
um yeah that was kind of uh that was
kind of story here
earlier this year um i don't i don't
think we can repeat that
and on the other question if we have
like um the u.s cyber command
we do have a unit that's also horizontal
so pulling everything everyone who works
on information security
across the military but their
responsibilities to defend their own
systems
yeah and then maybe spend correct me if
i'm wrong
but i think technically or theoretically
if parliament signs off if they are
going into um
[Music]
into war then with with any country
and if they're sent there then they
could use
offensive tools there as well but i
don't know of any competitive cases
[Music]
uh yeah so so you need a parliamentary
mandate
for military operations uh afghanistan
was one thing that's the only thing we
know
that in afghanistan the um german
military cyber operation unit took down
some cell phone provider
a telecommunication provider but that's
the only thing we know
any last questions
okay i'd like to everyone who has their
camera on or microphone unlocked give a
big
hand of applause to julian smith
[Applause]