as humans we exist in the world in three
places home work in a third place
community and in each community there is
a give and a take a problem that needs
to be fixed and people who want to help
yet despite the energy we spend to
affect change there's no place to
organize our most valuable resource
ourselves it's time for us to bring
together all the elements have changed
to one place it's time for us to unlock
our potential
on third place you can start a project
tell your story and enable your
community to make change to donate funds
to your project
or volunteer their time or Len materials
in the third place you can always share
the change you make with the
contributors and community you impact
third place