afternoon my name is Nate Davis I came
aboard to Aaron about two months ago and
their director of engineering and i'm
here today give the air and update
before i started though i wanted to pass
along a message from kim hubbard she's
sorry that she's not here and she wanted
to say hi to everybody and that she is
planning on mission to the next nanog
okay starting first with some of erin's
key projects ipv6 Aaron is essentially
ipv6 ready from a system standpoint as
well as a business process standpoint
our registration modification functions
and ipv6 who is already tested and close
to being put into production swip is
still under test and we expect that to
be completed here in the next next few
days y2k like everybody else air in
space of the y2k issue really our yqk
project is a really three components
first they've legacy remediation
underway and that legacy remediation
should be completed by the end of june
likewise we have some hardware upgrades
to make operating system upgrades to
make and that is to be expected to be
done by the end of june at the same time
we're migrating from ingress as far as
our database structure to oracle and all
of our production systems should be
completed and y2k compliant by the end
of june
redundant servers we're planning on
placing redundant servers at the right
and AP Nick we actually have on site
right now originally installed one of
Rights servers and we're going in to do
the same i right we'll do the first
first server 22 right probably sometime
this summer and then later in the year
actually stole another server I'll to
Alta ap Nick the routing registry I know
there's been a lot of questions here
last few days concerning the routing
registry as you know let's started on
februari 899 and we've had 42 total
objects to date about twenty to
twenty-four thousand hundred eighty-six
queries to the routing registry taking a
another look at the breakdown of those
queries when the registry was first
announced in February we had about 8,300
queries that peaked to about 15,000
hundred 100 and march and has now
trickled down to about 664 in April we
think those mason mainly due to the
release of it general interest and now
that's sort of a died off a little bit
realize that this is a little bit of a
busy chart but our what our few who is
stats we're running on average about the
almost 6 million queries total honor who
is server just a slight trend upward on
those for a month a month when looking
at 1999 compared to 98 we're seeing a
little bit faster increase in the number
of hosts about two and a half seconds
our to excuse me two and half queries
per second and ninety-three percent of
those valid valid beam actually
returning results
moving on to the registration services
group statistics and this is a very busy
slide so I've taken a couple of the key
components out of this and have have
some of this information on the
following charts first of all the number
of / pointing towards have been issued
looking at this chart the background is
a total number of / 24 middle ground are
those two isps and in the foreground the
yellow are those two end users what's
interesting to note here is that in
March and April we had a peak if you
will the number of / 24 is issued that's
really due to two reasons the policy
change they are innate with respect to
issuing lowering the middle minimal
allegation from a / 20 or from a 19 20 /
20 and also the we had a number of large
ISPs come back for additional space asn
is issued per month likewise have seen a
general trend upward on the number of a
SMS that are being issued each one of
this time last year we were running
about 76 essence issued a month we're
now running about 111 and last slide
that I have today is just the
distribution of the solder blocks issued
since the beginning of the year today
for this year aarons the allocated to
the 3376 20 / 20 force up into the end
of april
that's really all I have I did want to
mention that in summary we had a members
meeting in April and during that time
the members actually made some
recommendations during the next night on
meeting candles planning to let
everybody know what the results of those
recommendations for any questions
questions questions any questions okay
hold on