okay before I get started are there any
questions oh sure oh ok ok oh I wasn't
so about DNS security there are there is
a lot to say there has not been a lot
has really been done in a useful fashion
but sort of like ipv6 it's believed that
it's better to know what's coming if it
comes see here is my windows laptop so
the protocol itself was not designed to
be secure and sure as hell it's not it's
a trivial matter to either make a result
or believe that your response is the one
it was waiting for or to insert your
data into someone else's cash as a side
effect of them asking you some question
and there really is no validation model
in the underlying protocol and that
makes it kind of dangerous to believe
anything you hear from dns and like to
think that there are no more location
buzz but you know now that I'm first
find has always been perfect but however
there are other implementations as well
we're having a good time doing
interoperability testing at ICF meetings
the Microsoft to their credit has been
buying pizza for these because they
recognize that this is an
extraordinarily good form of testing for
them although it tends to look bad when
everybody else in the room can fix
whatever the bug was that was just found
right then and Rickon and run the test
over again where they have to submit a
bug
important come back three months later
for whatever reason a laptop is not
powerful enough to build their dns
products but anyway this is this is part
of the seamy underside of the internet
which is first light make such good
fodder perfect for this this conference
because that's what people in this room
do for a living but you just that
statement i made a moment ago is is
fundamental you cannot believe what dns
tells you and yet all of us do so take
for example a relationship between your
ssh client and some server somewhere
where you is there's nothing in your
known hosts file for the server you're
going to go to so when you ssh to that
post is going to say gee I just got a
key that I've never seen before are you
sure you want to add this to your known
hosts file do you really want to connect
to this guy all of us just pretty much
say yes and there's no guarantee that
the host you get that key from is the
one that you think it is pretty easy to
get the a record that your assets H
plant seeds to be something different
from what the rest of the internet would
say or what you think you're seeing so
in case you didn't think you had enough
things to worry about now the e-commerce
hold that corresponds to that one is
fairly pluggable in that when a browser
goes to some web server somewhere and
sees a key that it's never seen before
there's a certification authority that
went along with that key and that
certification authority tends to be
that's not always but it can be
hardwired into the browser itself so
that when you get a key your browser
knows whether its manufacturer things it
ought to be trusting that and
furthermore it comes up with a pop-up
that says okay I just saw new
Kate came from uunet communications or
whatever it came from some in some place
and this is the certification authority
that and my level of trust for them
about that name about the company name
isn't just a host name anymore and so we
can hope that verisign and the other
certification authorities are not going
to allow joe random cracker incorporated
to have a key that has some other
companies shame in it because there's
nothing like that for email nothing like
that presses h the rest of the stuff is
pretty much wide open and since there
are so many script kiddie who is out
there that have this functionality for
polluting other people's campus or
spooking their resolvers so that the
response stacy isn't the one that they
thought they were waiting for the one
you thought they were waiting for i I've
included some of them in the vines kit I
figure they're going to be out there we
ought to have them too but long ago
during the internet weren't difficult i
was in favor of releasing the source
code to mr. morris's tool so a lot of
people were against that lot of people
are against this i have been called a
lot of names as a result of putting
these kiddie toys in the kit i guess on
my skin is getting thicker anyway you
should download the kit and run the
these tools against your own servers
just so you'll see how easy they are
where do you want to go today
and of course the tools that I get are
the bottom of the food chain you know
the these are things that were left on
some compromised computer that didn't
automatically delete themselves at the
end of an attack I'm sure that there are
much better ones available that have not
filtered their way to need yet so that's
the problem statement what are we doing
about us well in the usual internet way
a lot of different people are doing
different things and then in the center
you have a bunch of people working on
standards that are extraordinarily
painful both to work on and wait for the
biggest effort that's been made by
organized religion in this area is the
public-private p system known as DNS SEC
and this is a pretty much a normal model
of the benefits from the DNS hierarchy
itself so that when you get a referral
telling you that a given branch of the
DNS tree should be reached through the
sand so server you also get the some
kind of a key that would help you verify
the peace that when you start talking to
that host you're really talking to the
person that that part of the tree was
delegated to and it starts usually from
dot expectation is that someday we'll
figure out who owns dot and that person
will sign it and that the public key
that corresponds to the the actual
signing fee will be put on a t-shirt and
that whenever you want to verify you can
just look down
but dot will then not only sign itself
but it will sign its top level domains
like calm and as you and net and so
forth and the owners of those domains
assuming they are different from the
owner of the domain which seems likely
will then assign the second level names
like 6.com or an odd duck
with teeth that will allow you and know
by knowing you trust you know you got it
from some place you trust like an ietf
t-shirt you typed it in or somebody sent
it to you as a secure attachment or you
got it from a secure web server whatever
it is you've got some trusted key that
is higher above or has transitive
signing transitive signatures between
the name you want or to the name you
want then you can figure out the name
that you're asking about really is
securely owned by this is going to get
old about the person who sent it to you
and that's a pretty good model it's just
a normal straightforward application of
public key technology to the pns it
turns out that DNS is not a minha bowl
to this so for example when you want to
express a signature you have to make a
funny thing that looks kind of like a
resource record but it isn't really well
some people say this some people say it
isn't it that kind of resource record
sorry microphone is not going well give
you an example the signature is not
unique normally if you know the name
class and type of a resource record and
you know the name of the resource record
set of which it is a part and for a
signature that's not true you have to
dip into the first short word of the our
data section to get the type covered
filled out as well so it's actually a
quadruple not it's not a tuple that that
identifies it and that really violates
the model in some interesting ways
that's taken not interesting subtle
takes years sometimes for the
implications of those
design decisions to make himself known
and we're learning about them every day
as we go to implement this stuff and of
course dynamic updates will someday be
covered by this technology as well at
the moment the protocol development has
been mostly in the area of prairies has
been some effort to extend this to
include dynamic updates but it is
significantly less further along so I
mentioned that there are a lot of
different people doing different things
and this is more or less what I did in
response to the slowness that I
perceived in the standards body that
generates the public private stuff and T
sig is all about sneakernet it proceeds
from the assumption that in a LAN or a
campus it's usually going to be possible
to distribute a key by wandering around
with a poppy or reading it to somebody
over the phone or something else that
absolutely will not scale to the size of
the internet but would work pretty well
inside my company and as such it has not
been a popular standard people at least
in the standards body there is a
preference for something that could run
everywhere and solve everybody's problem
this can run everywhere and solve that
person's problem which is subtle but
different sneakernet is fine it's
especially fine if you don't include
clients in it most of us have one or two
DHCP servers and one or two dns servers
and walking around to those four
machines to have to share some secret is
just fine and it's also just time to
have those things not have user accounts
on them
presumably if only such events can log
in then you can have relatively secure
key storage this key has to be held it
doesn't have to be but it tends to be
held in clear text on the disk drive of
the people who are using it that's going
to make it very difficult for result
calm if you wanted to use this require
ease on your land so that your clients
would all know how to go about trusting
the responses they got from the
recursive name servers I would pretty
much mean that resolved comp would have
to have the shared secret and that
because it would have to be a world
readable file on posts that have users
on it and that's not going to be popular
either so I have to admit that a
public/private key system makes more
sense and T sig was originally developed
for dynamic update and zone transfers
in microsoft windows 2000 they're going
to kind of abandoned wins in a way and
here's somebody clapping hey that was my
first reaction but what it turns out
that they're doing is to embrace and
extend TCH so one of the things winds
could do that the DNS could not do at
time that wins was developed was have a
server come up and announce to the
network I'm here these are the services
i provide somebody comes to you know
runs around and starts to 10 know who is
the exchange server who is the file
server tell them it's me and NS didn't
have any any functionality like that at
that time it does now but there isn't a
good security amount for it which is to
say that for Microsoft the average
campus is thousands of machines not
dozens or hundreds as in my personal
case so they did not believe in the
transaction signature distributed by
with shared secrets is distributed by
true other events and synchronized so
forth so they developed something called
gssb c which is kind of the public
private thing applied to transaction
signatures but it uses a proprietary
format that is based on their
proprietary format for their version of
Kerberos so there's a problem in people
who want to sell against Microsoft into
some of these these corporate plans
because they won't be able to come up
with a server that is based on open
source simply good because Microsoft
doesn't want that to be possible so
we're still fighting that out
there have been two sets of RFC's
describing pianist act which is the
first standard i described
public-private sort of hierarchy system
and the first one had a lot of problems
the second one has some problems and
it's natural for RFC is to go through
this kind of gradual improvement what's
a little bit not natural is a fair
number of the people who are now
implementing the standards didn't even
bother to comment on some of the earlier
RFC's either because they weren't in the
DNS industry yet or they were busy with
other stuff or some of the some of the
concept being argued were more important
to security people than they were
important to DNS people and so it's
created kind of a marginal situation
where you know we at the Internet
software consortium are getting around
implement in this stuff and discovering
that there are a lot of ways in which it
literally cannot work so there will be
at least one more RFC before we're done
as to whether that the other RFC is
going to be a complete replacement we're
just sort of another hat on or another
series of add-ons there have been some
add-ons I don't know but the point is
this is taking a long time we've been at
it for at least three or four years and
we're not post yet
t sig on the other hand has not been
published as an RFC it's it's been held
up by a lot of really perfectly valid
criticisms of the approach and of the
details it is on the other hand
implemented in bio data to both of these
things are implemented but I will
caution anyone to really plan on
experimenting with the DNS SEC part but
don't plan on going into production with
it in a worldwide passion I'm told by
inversion right but the t6 stuff is as
ready as it will ever be and we are
using it and it's got some rough edges
will be filing off in the next state to
cut but fundamentally you can secure
zone transfers and you can secure
dynamic updates using t cig and you can
within the limits of your ability to
exchange keys with other second and
further level domain holders you can use
this DNS SEC code as well so for example
we exchange secure dns information with
john gilmore site and periodically with
tis labs it's the other other person
working on this with us
export control was a huge difficult for
us the Clinton administration has not
been friendly to the idea that if the
rest of the world has code to do RSA and
American companies are merely being hurt
if they can't also export it was hoping
all sorts of code that you could import
but not export and there was a kind of
the land like landmark excuse me ruling
a few weeks ago pertaining to all of
this but I haven't really decided how I
feel about that yet because it's clearly
going to go through another couple of of
Appeals it's going to go to the Supreme
Court there's no way the government's
going to back down based on a circuit
court appeal ruling and so that after
that is it may we have proceeded
independently from all that it turns out
that the Bureau of export administration
dxa has this serpentine Byzantine set of
regulations about what you can cannot do
and what order you have to do things in
and so on so you can apply for an
exemption basically it's it's that's
where you admit that these are munitions
that they are dangerous but you can
marginalize them and say that they
aren't that dangerous and could you
please have permission to ship them even
though it's arguably illegal so you
start by putting both knees on the
ground and your hands together and
they're allowed to do a number of things
including say no but if they say no then
there's an appeals process and they
could eventually have to explain why
they had to say no they're also allows
not answer or these not answered for
some number of months it would be bad
for us because the is cease funding
model depends on getting this code out
so there is another approach which is
what we took which is where you do a
self-certification where you instead of
asking their permission you send them a
letter saying look I've got this code
looks like it fits some of your
guidelines we don't think it fits them
all we're just going to ship it if you
have a problem with that let us know now
the form of them letting you know is not
that they send the marshals after me and
handcuffed me and take me away it's that
they would send us a cease and desist
letter and say you're a bad dog and
we'll talk about this later but for now
we want you to both cut down and we have
received no such letter it's not an
indication that we won't but so far we
haven't and we're into our third major
tarball that has always code in it so at
the moment I'm starting to feel safe I
know at the end of my prepared slides
and get rid of the sunglasses here
because I can't see you hoping there
will be questions especially detailed
technical questions from this obviously
10 sensitive running things I don't need
a sound board Randy book fair enough Oh
in his second scuffle northern there was
supposed to be one I was not there but
Oliver was there and mark coasters was
there they had the latest snapshot from
us for that workshop and I don't have
been strangely quiet it says it's as
though they're sleeping off the effects
of their journey or something like that
but the I'm curious do you know who else
has implemented T sick that they could
have been testing again ok I don't know
more than you do wish I did the rumors
were not sure probably because they had
no pizza it has to be more than one
question or not