okay thank you very much I'm done no I
guess I have more to do okay so let's
get on with it I'm going to talk to you
about three different parts I'm going to
give you a little bit of a review and
fiber very quickly just to give you a
feeling for what the complexities are
down there talk a little bit about WDM
systems and then close with IP over wzm
both pointing out a couple of key issues
as well as showing you some real world
experience that we've had so the first
thing to say about fiber is I'm not got
my screen set up right there a tech
person I've got half a screen
go forth he'll take me longer and give
to give the time all the way down
yeah
San Francisco
many thanks
well although that was a digital problem
because the message to you when you
enter the fiber world in transmission is
that it's an analog problem it's always
been an analog problem it continues to
be an analogue problem and the major
consequence of it being an analogue
problem is that it's very difficult to
have mid-span need as we talked about
with sauna last time
today's setup is that every single WDM
system does it differently at the
physical layer down at the analog
problem and no - you can't plug vendor a
into vendor B and Isis personally feel
it'll be quite some time before you ever
have a chance to do that so let's talk a
little bit about what are the issues
that this analog level of the world well
it's attenuation dispersion
non-linearity and reflectance is
basically the issues so let me show you
what a few of those are if you look at a
piece of fiber of course it's this long
piece of glass but it doesn't transmit
at all windows equally so you you've
probably been exposed to this you know
1550 window in the 1310 window this is
the absorption curve for fiber and those
two windows come about for very physical
reasons that water molecules in glass
caused this big spike and there turns
out to be two good regions to work at
now for long distance where I'm going to
focus the preferred choice is always in
the 1550 window because it's about half
the attenuation that you get at 1310 and
also as you'll see at this window a
thing came along called the optical
amplifier that really changed the way we
put the networks together the other
important part to know about fiber is in
addition to the from mathematical point
of view the real part which is the
attenuation there's the imaginary part
or the dispersion these lines are the
velocity if you will of different
wavelengths of light and it is not the
same for all wavelengths and there's two
kinds of fibers this is the original
fiber that 80 or 90 percent of the world
full of called standard dispersion non
dispersion shifted fiber and then when
people started working in the 1550 range
they went to this kind of fiber which
was either dispersion shifted originally
but then they define they found that
when they turn WDM on in the 1550 range
that dispersion was a good thing so
instead of having non dispersion shifted
fiber they went to non zero dispersion
shifted fiber which gives you a small
amount of dispersion but not zero at
1550 so what does this all mean it's all
wonderful but what it means at the end
of the day is that there was a
phenomenon called dispersion that
happens in the analog transmission of
ones and zeros over fiber you put in
nice clean shapes and at the end of the
fiber you get muck out and it's
frequency dependent this problem goes up
like the square of the bit rate so for
slow speeds at least in backbone slow
speeds oc3 oc12 sand for the most part
OC 48 dispersion isn't a great issue but
at OC 192 where our backbones are going
now suddenly this dispersion problem
becomes quite important there is a
number of kinds of dispersion another
one is called modal dispersion instead
of having a slope for each frequency
travels differently in multimode fibers
there is many modes in the fibre and
they all travel at different speeds and
the reason you never see multimode fibre
used in long-haul networks is because
the multimode fiber dispersion problem
much more severe with long distance than
a single mode fiber so that's the last
thing I'm going to say about multimode
fiber there's all kinds of problems I'm
going to just show you a couple another
one that you may have seen come up when
people started talking about OC 192
systems was a problem called
polarization mode dispersion even in
single mode fiber there are two
polarizations vertical and horizontal if
you will and it turns out that there can
be an interaction due to a variety of
causes most likely imperfections fibers
not really round and if you go fast
enough to
far enough it looks like the vertical
say is traveling at a different speed
than the horizontal and you end up with
a mode that is being dispersed in other
words bits are blending together again
and unlike the previous problem of
dispersion that was hit rate dependent
this one is a material property and this
is the one that sometimes you hear
people talk about I'd like to use OC 192
but my fiber plant won't support it it's
the PMD problem that they're usually
referring to so it's yet another kind of
this nonlinear problem
this one depending up on the fiber plant
and if there's not enough problems just
to show you some more along comes WDM
which we're going to talk about in the
middle in a minute and the issue with
WDM was if there's no dispersion between
the wavelengths as in this case the four
primary wavelengths travel down the
fiber they tend to interact with each
other and they create all these
different beat signals think of it in
terms of radios it's the same thing it's
intermodulation distortion and beat
patterns appearing the problem here with
four wave mixing is that some of these
patterns some of these interference
happen to fall exactly on one of the
frequencies you're transmitting so it
becomes impossible now to either
electrically or optically filter the
inner filter this kind of crosstalk out
of the systems so this is the
give-and-take that the people that
design WDM systems have to go through
constantly if we increase the bitrate we
have more problems with chromatic
dispersion if we lower our dispersion on
the fiber to correct for that problem we
caused four wave mixing problems and
it's a careful balancing act going back
and forth between these three simple
nonlinearities and a whole host of
others are carefully balanced with the
analog transmission level to make it all
work so my bottom line message there on
a couple of slides about fiber is that
it's an analogue problem it's
fundamentally in a proprietary solution
to a complex set of different nonlinear
interactions and depending on which
vendors technology look at for their
optical amplifiers or
piece of their systems they will choose
a different solution so no to WDM
systems are alike in this way so now
let's look at just the basic building
blocks of what WDM is well to give it a
historical perspective we wouldn't be
talking about WDM if we hadn't come
along with an optical amplifier in the
earlier days around nineteen nine Midna
ninety to ninety five somewhere in there
been an who you asked optical amplifiers
became commercial and the king of the
optical amplifier is the erbium doped
fiber amplifier known as the EDFA before
the EDFA we had systems that were
connected this would be going back to
our SONET talk this would be a line set
and these would be sections between
pairs of regenerators and you want to
get across the country every 40 to 80
kilometers you better have a hole in the
ground into which you can put a
regenerator that does a full 3 re
amplify reshape and retime regeneration
of a single wavelength signal so then in
the early 90s some bright physicists
came up with the ability to make an
optical amplifier this amplifier was
only a 1-hour amplifier it did not do
the reshape and retime functions but it
did compensate for attenuation in the
fiber plant and these became very
popular mostly because it turned out you
could stay some every 120 kilometers so
you have a lot less equipment and the
equipment tended to be a little bit more
reliable than regenerate if this
functionality was lower so the ground
was set this happened in the mid 90s
early 90s the mid 90s and then it was a
fairly simple jump forward kind of
happened slowly people tried one or two
waves in the early 90s but you know one
way of thinking about this is this
picture is what Sienna for example
brought us at least the investment
community in the 90s mid in 96 when they
went public the idea was we've already
stripped out a lot of the regions and
we've put in optical amplifiers optical
amplifiers can amplify all sorts of
signals simultaneously let's just
multiplex at the optical level many
different terminals each on their own
way
linked into a pipe and send them down
the wire and the optical amplifier will
amplify all of them and we'll sort them
out at the far end so this this again
was say 90 this kind of picture was 92
93 94 this was 96 and thereafter and by
the way the state of the art I threw
three terminals here it's to think of it
in two ways the sonic folks tend to put
out new SONET levels every three to four
years four times faster than the
previous level in WDM it's not the
bitrate it's the channel count that
matters and from 1990 till now the
channel count is increased from two to
128 OC 192 s on a single fiber giving
you now over a tera bit of capacity on a
single mode fiber using these DWDM
architectures so I wanted to show you a
little bit about the EDFA since that's
really about in my mind the heart of the
technologies that brought WDM to us it's
a device that takes a coma wavelengths
in the optical space so this would be
nanometers of light and this would be
amplitude send it through the device and
it comes out bigger all these channels
these are all being both of them being
modulated OC 48 OC 192 the amplifier
does not care it amplifies all of them
concurrently and it does it completely
optically there's a special fiber the
erbium doped fiber hence the erbium
doped fiber amplifier that has a has a
erbium atom added to it and about
getting into the physics it's capable of
actually if you pump it with light that
the erbium atoms get excited and when
the signal goes through they amplify the
signal spontaneous they give the
amplification of the signal so we have a
very simple device now that is bitrate
independent and as long as your your
wavelengths are within the pass band of
the EDFA it's channel count independent
to a great extent too so we see now for
example new amplifiers being offered
that will support 160 wavelengths you
start off with 16 32 whatever you want
throw on your system you put the fiber
in you put the amplifiers in and you're
good to go until you hit one to two
terabytes of today and WDM will probably
I think in the next couple of years will
see ten terabit systems on a single mode
fiber so once of the WDM systems
actually look like well we talked about
the amplifiers the WDM systems are
really just optical modulators and a
combining system this is a very simple
picture this would be 15 15 15 51
nanometers wavelengths if I'd been a
little bit more careful the actual what
the ITU does is is they recommend 100
gigahertz spacing which is actually 1.6
nanometers so if I draw on this out
properly there is a set of channels that
the IC UT prescribes and every one is
standardized on these are then combined
sent through up to I think about 800
kilometres is the state of the art using
amplifiers approximately every 100
kilometers and at the far end you
separate it back out using a optical
filter that detects each wavelength and
steers each wavelength to the right
receiver so if we look then at what goes
on inside the transmitter and receivers
what we have here in this architecture
is we have a know de conversion going on
usually the signal that's sent to a WDM
system is a short reach 1310 SONET
signal today that signal is terminated
and electrically it's electrically
drives generally an external modulator
which means that there is a precise
wavelength laser say 1550 or 1550 one
that is being driven through the
modulator and the modulation is being
applied electrically to that new carrier
so that coming out here is exactly the
same electrical signal that went in over
here but it's conveying converted onto a
specific wavelength for multiplexing
into the long-haul Network if we come
over here then on this side we have a
receiver for the 1550 light we have a
three-hour refund
of ree-ree amplify reshape and retiming
3r regeneration and then a new
transmitter put it out on the short
reach length it's important then to
think again about one of the things that
sonnet was so good for was this 3r
function and this three order function
is being folded into the WDM systems so
now if we look at the state-of-the-art
WDM systems have been used at various
line rates the most people generally
think that using a wavelength below c48
is not cost-effective at least in the
long haul so the state of the art today
is either OC 48 two-and-a-half gig
signals or OC 192 10 gig signals and
this this has been filled at the 40
lambda system for OC 48 is a Cianna
system that's been out for a number of
years the 16 wave 192 system for example
is the Nortel system which has also been
out for a number of years there is an
effort to expand this the kind of state
of the art of what the people are
putting as what will be available
shortly is 160 lambdas at 10 gigs 1.6
terabits of capacity on a single mode
fiber the other thing that's been going
on I'm not going to talk a lot about is
I've shown you WDM is a point-to-point
system but there's certainly a lot of
extensions being proposed one that's
been around for a while is the idea that
on a long-distance link Y go from just
data be if I could drop some traffic C
and D and places in between a and B the
configurable add drop multiplexer allows
you to drop a wavelength to sip from
firehose if you will it allows you to
get a more complex topology over a
limited physical infrastructure and then
of course what we're watching to see
this year next year is the entrance of
the Metro products WDM was a tremendous
solution for fiber exhaust in the long
haul and the transmission folks are
to see if they can repeat that
performance in the metro area by
supplying very versatile transmission
systems that will allow you to provision
services and metro areas very quickly a
little different play than fiber exhaust
here is a question of quick provisioning
rather than adding capacity where fiber
was limited okay well let me move on to
the last piece of my talk then which is
just a little bit of experience that
we've had at Cisco on how these systems
run there's a first I'll show you a
couple of things there's two points that
generally come up when we talk about
running IP over WDM the first one is
synchronization and again if we think
back to the talk we just heard about how
synchronization is done in the SONET
Network it's very different in a SONET
Network because it was originally
designed to support voice traffic the
whole point was to be able to multiplex
many many small tributaries up into
large trunk lines and the easily T
multiplex them at the other end so we
saw a very tight timing synchronization
plan to do timeslot extraction through
the ADM well that's not the way IP over
DWDM tends to get implemented now when
IP / DWDM tends to be implemented - as a
point-to-point connection to build up
either a partial or a full mesh between
your router connects as such the
connections between the routers
generally operate with packet / sonic
technology which you also saw a minute
ago and their direct connections between
a backbone router and another backbone
router and there's no SONET multiplexing
going on here there's no need for a
primary rate source here up here in the
WDM side it's a point-to-point link
between store-and-forward
tight boxes and therefore there is no
timing relationship between the link on
this router and any other link in any
other part of this network so there is
no need in Adi in an IP / DWDM
architecture to have to use a SONET
stratum based clocking system
what we do in our products is we relax
the clock accuracy to 20 parts per
million which happens to be the very
edge of the sonnet spec so that we can
bring a low cost clocking solution that
still Sonic compliant works great over
WDM and if you're using the router to
connect your pause links into a SONET
Network all we do is we loop time off
the stratum clocks that are inside the
sonnet network to provide us with local
blocking so you have the in the router
you have the precision to connect
synchronously into a SONET Network but
you also have a simpler solution if you
want to go straight over WDM because
it's just point-to-point another place
where there's a lot of discussion going
on is the need for optical protection
again if you is it coming about because
SONET is being displaced and as sun it's
being displaced the wonderful 50
milliseconds that SONET and people are
saying where am I going to get that my
message to this audience is that optimal
protection is a nice thing it fixes the
cloud generally fast 50 milliseconds but
it is limited to what's in the cloud it
does not protect the electronics
generally in the WDM systems although
sometimes that's part of the cloud but
it certainly doesn't protect anything
out here and sometimes things happen out
here so my message is that layer 3
restoration is required whether or not
you use optical protection optical
protection is great inside the cloud but
it is not sufficient to give your
network and in protection so just a
couple of slides about the experience
we've seen with some of our customers
here's a situation a test we performed
about a year ago using the Siena 40 wave
system and the GS are twelve thousands
we went in on one wavelength down 500 km
kilometres of fire fiber out wrapped
around back in out back in
around and around and around 20,000
kilometers of transmission air free from
the first day we plugged the GSR into
the centuries without a single piece of
sonnet equipment being needed there's a
corollary to this one too which I don't
have a slide for but we've put a press
release out recently where a particular
customer had some submarine requirements
plug the GSR into their transponder
system ran 7,500 kilometers through a
hundred and 50 optical amplifiers no
SONET equipment worked fine first day
got the pain it's really pretty easy if
you have Sonic compliant interfaces
here's another system we worked with
it's the Nortel 16 wave OC 192 system in
this case the way in is a little
different the way in is is because it's
configured as the four fiber blsr ring
is through a box that's kind of a
combination of DWDM and an add drop
multiplexer rolled into one my message
here was that in this particular product
in the first go they plugged the GSR in
over at OC 48 link and therefore we are
multiplexed with three other OC 48 up to
192 and put out on the ring that worked
fine now you want to go to 10 gigs
because SONET cisco and others will have
OC 192 soon this year late and cheater
there's an issue because this particular
vendor doesn't supply a transponder at
10 gigs
you would think gee let's put the
colored laser on our box and we're done
think again of those earlier slides I
showed you of all the complexity it's
not that simple
I think Nortel is now put out a
transponder that allows you to plug in
but the lesson is that the passive
systems are difficult to plug into
because of the analog complexities of
WDM transmission finally what have we
got well I've argued a few times now the
transmissions an analog problem and its
proprietary by nature DWDM provides
tremendous capacity
and if you use transponders it really is
an open architecture that's very
flexible we have done a large number of
Y of large deployments around the world
at this point over most everybody's WDM
equipment and it generally works pretty
well so this is not a future IP over
DWDM is quite doable in a reality today
thank you
time for a question time time for C time
for a question or two questions you
talked about later speed protection how
long do you think it would take for
discovery and fail over time yeah sorry
you asked about protection right layer
three protection layer three protection
well it's you can't compare it to fit
what how should I answer this you're
going to see a talk from this gentleman
I think in a minute on DPT which is a
solution that provides 50 millisecond
protection for direct router the router
connections but it's kind of still
physical layer the the reality is that
the restoration at layer 3 is
fundamentally more complex than
protection at layer 1 and I think what
we're looking for is something that's
fast enough to support real time
services I guess it's a sub second but
it may not get all the way to 50
milliseconds we're certainly looking for
input on what the right choice should be
I have question I'm quite confused by
your your presentation and I'm actually
from the optical research have the
background well my question my
impressions you are actually you are
using SONET training and that you you
have your son at the gear field into
your router and
and Siena's annan job in your rudder and
but you can't call yourself sounded
compliant because you don't have the
clock position we what the question was
we have some sonnet but I we is it fair
to say it's Sonic compliant it is Sonic
compliant in the sense that it complies
with gr 253 and the ANSI specs and the
ITU specs it is not so does compliant
sonnet signal in all senses but what it
is is that the concatenated sonnet
stream we're systick 'le multiplex
packets there is no notion of virtual
tributaries or circuits inside that
sonnet frame that we saw we don't do
what an ADM does but we're just as
compliant at the signalling level as any
ATM that's why we plug into the WDM
system so easily
yeah thanks that that's my impression
you actually you're not using an analog
system you're you're using Sun and
framing and a lot of for the sonnet
things there and it's not that as
dramatic as you described it's analog
technology it's now I'm not quite sure
what your point is but it certainly has
analog technology and certainly is
proprietary but that you know solid
framing you have sound out there and
it's digital