all right thanks a lot I did have cynics
in my presentation I just found out that
by going second day towards the end my
jokes have been told my content has been
covered but bear with me some things
will repeat and some things will be new
for you and I've tried to take kind of
an interesting slice and hopefully
anticipating that we'd be having a lot
of overlap so that so that we wouldn't
so today I want to look at the same
problem but we want to look at public
institutions and addressing the problem
of misinformation with these
institutions okay this will also help
lead up to a breakout session that my
colleague Jesse McCarthy is going to
leave this afternoon when we get to that
so hopefully it helped us prepare for
those who participate with us there all
right let's start with some of the
basics let's frame and all get on the
same page so there is confusion around
online information we all agree on that
it does not discriminate by age and it
does not discriminate by country these
players have all contributed to the
problem we know what those problem are
the producers blurring the lines between
fact and opinion bias sometimes sloppy
reporting on the news aggregators unseen
algorithms out there a business model
that supports a sharing of emotional
information and the amplification
process in addition news consumers
they're lazy thick ball not lazy we have
bad habits we've created bad habits due
to trying to deal with this firehose
amount of information that comes at us
every day and I think we should be
allowed to sort information by
preferences as long as we know what
we're doing in that process because
there's no way we can keep up with
everything so these bad habits need to
be changed they need to be fixed agreed
so it's going to take all three of these
players to help solve the problem all
right so the problem with our news
producers and with our aggregators
helping are that people
don't necessarily trust top-down
solutions these stats prove that but
since stats can be changed and
manipulated we won't spend too much time
on those but we do know there is not a
lot of trust for Facebook and Google to
make right decisions for us yes and we
know there's a lot of trust lost for our
free press for our media and the job
that they're doing and I've even
multiple studies that prove that and
that show that but then there's also a
little bit distrust for our governments
government intervention as well and that
lasts that if you could have read it if
you were looking at this one app here
you probably read it it showed that most
people do not want the internet
regulated even though if most folks do
not want the internet regulated we are
starting to see government's trying to
respond and fix this issue of
disinformation we talked yesterday about
Germany and Germany finding social media
platforms I think it's important to
point out that the the fine is millions
of dollars and if it's not removed
within 24 hours that is most definitely
going to infringe on free speech on
wouldn't you err on the side of caution
if you were that one who was pulling it
off to save your company millions of
dollars in addition we have bills
proposed in France that would give
judges emerg a grant judges emergency
action to remove fake news to especially
the fam'ly Tory fake news around
sensitive election times what we didn't
discuss yesterday was in Malaysia that
they just passed this was April they
passed a law about publishing and
sharing fake news and that comes with a
hefty six year and hundred and twenty
eight thousand dollar potential fine
there for sharing fake information the
first person arrested charged with this
was someone who shared a YouTube video
claiming that it took police too long to
respond to a shooting police say it was
eight minutes versus fifty minutes so
there again a gray area
and finally the Kenyan president signed
a bill criminalizing 17 different types
of cyber crimes oh I did want to give
you an update on the Malaysia and I'll
go back to that in a second
criminalizing 17 types of cyber crimes
and fake news of people who knowingly
share fake news can be fined up to fifty
thousand dollars or jail for two years
the Committee to Protect Journalists
claimed that that would criminalize free
speech and right now the courts have
temporarily suspended these provisions
seemed to endanger free speech and the
case was set to be heard on July 18th
and we're just waiting for a ruling but
back to Malaysia on the update they're
the country's new communications and
multimedia minister said that the law
would be repealed all right want to make
one more example most of you are
probably familiar with this
India's 4G revolution has brought on
over 200 million users online and in
this popular platform started a message
sharing platform started spreading fake
news and resulted in mob killings the
Indian government called for the the
platform to fix this so the app now
labels messages as forward it forward
instead of composed by sender limits
forwarding the five recipients inside
India and 20 and the rest of the world
and only group admins can send messages
and content as marked can be marked as
suspicious
despite this the last mob killing was
just two weeks ago which brings me to my
point that we can't leave out consumer
education when trying to combat this
problem the two building blocks are
personal responsibility we talked about
that yesterday folks need to understand
their role and a healthy information
cycle and we need to support community
education so what about museums that's
what we're going to talk about today
there are 50,000 museums and 202
countries around the world and that's
according to the International Committee
of museums and there's no way to know
that number for
or for anyone who's questioning that but
that gives you a sense of an idea and
visitorship in museums are growing
people trust museums they are typically
seen as non-political and they're seen
as educational most people trust museums
more than they'd like for example
history museum trust
museum more than they trust their
teacher or they trust a textbook or they
trust a relative people and when it
comes to their mission people also
believe that museums should make
recommendations on actions based on
their topic all right so we need to go
grassroots there was approved there's
proof that this works and Uganda a study
of 10,000 students through 120 schools
half of those students the students that
were trained were twice as likely to be
able to identify bs claims on health
issues so we know it works and we know
some adults are showing that they would
like to receive some of this some of
this training themselves at the Newseum
we are working to help combat this
problem through infographics that and we
supply on our website on Newseum ed org
like the ones you see here these are
just a small sampling of the things we
offer so we are supporting teachers we
are offering public programs on the
issue we are going into libraries we are
doing programs with the State Department
we are doing discussions and lectures
and workshops all around the country on
this topic so we're having a big a big
impact I do want to point out though as
important it is I see that you see these
are checklists these are processes
teachers like those you have to do that
but along with the health the Newseum
teaches the why the importance behind it
the responsibility how our democracy
depends on informed effective consumers
so we get into those gray areas and then
we have people then the consumers and
the students and the adults were whoever
we're talking to they get behind on this
issue and then they all realize that
they do contribute to the in
environment so the question is investing
in in public serving institutions an
alternative to policy that is going to
be our session our breakout session this
afternoon and so we hope that you come
and join our session so we can look at
how maybe news producers educational
institutions and and tech and and others
can work together to help solve this
problem thank you very much
[Applause]