hi my name is Lea Shanley as Dwight
mentioned I'm the co-executive director
of the South big data innovation hub for
those of you who may not be familiar the
big data innovation hubs were funded by
the National Science Foundation in 2015
there are four such hubs around the
country so you all are probably near one
of the hubs we are based at universities
and our role is to catalyze and
strengthen partnerships that connect
academic researchers industry government
and NGOs to apply data science and
analytics to social and scientific
challenges so I came to the
misinformation space back in 2011 when I
ran a lab called the Commons lab at the
Woodrow Wilson Center here in DC and we
were working to connect digital
volunteer groups who were beginning to
use social media to respond to disasters
like the Haiti earthquake with academic
researchers and with government to begin
to develop sets of best practices and
standards and to build trust within the
federal government for using these
approaches now through the hub well I
should back up at that time we tried to
raise awareness with policy makers and
we briefed Robert Muller we book brief
then post 9/11 Commission but by and
large policy makers were kind of deaf to
these challenges now they're aware and I
think the challenge will be
communicating how the research can can
result in action and get the
policymakers to understand so today
through the hub I now work with the
research community that spans many
disciplines so like academics like to do
they have given it a name from social
cybersecurity to cognitive security and
I bet there several other terms that are
in use but social cybersecurity is an
emerging academic discipline that works
to assess understand predict and
mitigate attempts by actors such as
terrorist groups to use media platforms
to recruit members coordinate activities
and influence the cognitive biases of
large groups of individuals for social
political or economic consequences
things that you guys have all been
talking about what I'm finding
fascinating and I'm sorry if this font a
little small for you to read but social
cybersecurity is an inherently
multidisciplinary and multi
methodological computational social
science the blends computer science and
data science as phil has discussed with
political science sociology
communication science journalism
organization science marketing
linguistics anthropology forensics
decision science social psychology and I
hope I'm not leaving out any others so
we are a diverse community our
researchers in this area are applying a
variety of methods and in the data
science space that includes network
analysis and visualization language
technologies data mining statistics and
so forth colleagues of mine
Kathleen Carly at Carnegie Mellon
University and in Argo Wall and others
began to look at how this field is
emerging in the academic space and they
have demonstrated that we are seeing a
dramatic increase in peer-reviewed
articles book chapters of conference
proceedings in this space but was it
what was a surprise perhaps is when they
did a network analysis is that not all
these researchers are connected to each
other so that they found out of the
third thirteen hundred and fifty-six
researchers who were publishing in this
space as of I think early last year only
three hundred work really connected
collaborating with each other writing
papers with each other the other
thousand are working in onesies and
twosies
so as the South hub which our role is to
serve as connective tissue how can we
begin to connect people across these
disciplines to connect data science with
the social science so we set up a
working group which we mentioned there's
long title work for the working group
but that social cybersecurity finding is
more palatable with the policy community
we now have about 50 researchers in this
space we meet monthly or virtually to
share the research that we're doing to
exchange ideas begin to think about best
practices in March I find
a workshop to bring these folks together
at carnegie mellon and we began to scope
out what would a collaborative research
platform look like links to data links
to experts tools resources etc something
that would raise all boats in the
research space we also are beginning to
think about what the research agenda is
where the priority areas that could
inform NSF and other funding
institutions in this space and I would
ask to become up here so that I can
invite you all I heard so many fantastic
talks today organizations who are
already building communities perhaps we
can form a consortium or if you'd like
to join our group please give us a ring
thank you thank you
Thank You Mia okay we're gonna we're
running a little behind we're gonna go
streaming