Oh back there great thank you
please state your name and affiliation
hi I'm Sara Otte so from the Philip
Merrill College of journalism at the
University of Maryland and I want to
kind of throw a little grenade over the
parapet here I have a political
scientist so of course I'm going to
disagree with every other political
scientist in the room so what do you do
if and and if you've come up with these
these these wonderful interesting things
but but what do you do if 20% of your
audience of your particular media outlet
actually well 80% voted for Trump and
and I disagree that and I very much
agree with the speaker that said we
can't just say we're right we're right
you're wrong so where do we go forward
in truthiness if if 30% of the American
population has a different truth than
the other 70% because I don't think it's
just we can shine a light on the facts
and say look let us enlighten you
because they're not going to come to the
same conclusion so that that's my I know
it's an unanswerable question but I
would be interested in some attempts to
say how do we get beyond that I am i
working yes I am I said but I just have
one thought on that really which is in
the form of a question
because that's safe which is well what
voices would they listen to what what
does a resonant interesting story mean
to them that isn't just nonsense on
stilts so I was very struck for example
the way Michael Moore spoke during the
election cycle and afterwards because he
knew from the inside the Trump
demographic if there is such a thing who
were the people from these communities
who are worth listening to
who are the voices that people will hear
where is the common ground I don't think
it seems we very dangerous to have a
dichotomy of saying well over there
there belies I think it's
a great challenge too but surely surely
one we're up to journalistically to
Commission and report upon people who
have something to say that can be heard
by diverse audiences that isn't just
wish fulfillment and lies I was my mind
I was simply going to say if we start
with that we'll make no headway if we
start with you're wrong and I'm right so
it's that simple we like to use
historical examples and stay away from
contemporary ones then sometimes they're
they're less charged and then people can
have this moments of self realization
but I think that's going to be the the
real key to success I have a quick
comment it I don't think this really
addresses the this question but it is
something that it has occurred to me
recently which plays a role and one way
in which one important thing that
traditional media had sort of converged
on is the clear distinction between
between news and opinion between facts
and opinion and I think that that line
is very easily blurred with new media or
fragmentation of the new media landscape
the role of social media and so on and I
think that that so when we talk about
what's true and what's not true and
what's facts and what's not facts I
think that that line gets blurred so
it's okay for somebody else to have a
different opinion right so but sometimes
a person may feel like the other people
are saying no because your opinion is
different from mine then therefore it is
false an opinion cannot be false but the
facts can so trying to get at a clear
labeling or distinction between facts
and opinion
outside of mainstream media or to bring
that kind of distinction that we have
sort of learned in mainstream media to
new media could help take out some of
that I think of that challenge of of
who's you know your truth versus my
truth instead of having that
conversation we should have a dialogue
about your opinion versus my opinion and
they're both valid
whereas facts are some are true and some
are not
great next any any next question anyone
tweezer ed yep thank you Lisa repelled
in with the International Foundation for
electoral systems so over the past few
days across the panels in the workshops
we've heard a lot of the words solution
ISM was thrown out in one of our side
panels the idea of a buck shot of
solutions that were sort of looking for
what what can we do what what
interventions are possible and I wonder
what conversations are we having around
what's effective how are we measuring
efficacy how are we measuring impact
because while in the initial stages the
idea of a lot of different approaches
and solutions is attractive over time
starting to converge around what is
working and are any of these potential
interventions actually creating harm
where we think they should be helping
and I just wonder how robust is that
conversation and what are some of the
different approaches that are being
taken towards that thank you I'll just
say that we're very far from there it is
hard to assess effectiveness of
solutions and sometimes nearly
impossible because you cannot create two
different worlds platforms are doing
some of that in ways that we
unfortunately don't see and are not
published so that's not necessarily
helpful to the general research
community and but that I know that there
are a lot of efforts trying to move in
that direction so for example the social
science one Commission has been
discussed and through a partnership
between some funding agencies including
some of the same ones that are funding
this meeting and and Facebook at least
there is the beginning of a conversation
about what data platforms might provide
to begin to quantify reach and effects
of both phenomena that you know that we
consider negative and also of
countermeasures but it's a very very
very beginning of that discussion
and we're very far in my opinion yeah oh
good good with our product we have
evaluation baked in to everything we're
doing and we've just we're now working
with the Corporation for Public
Broadcasting on a large evaluation grant
to look at the efficacy and strategies
were mining student comments we're
unpacking all of that work and in some
attempt to try to figure out efficacy of
the product so it's there I think you
know Phil just said platforms have a
greater capability to looking at the
data around solution so I think that in
my experience with the other groups that
we're working with a similar work is
happening I think that there's the next
stage is figuring out how do we how do
we connect all of those solutions
together and and as it also said we're
far from that I just want to quickly add
I think Phil's it was a filler animation
of over time is that evaluation I know
talking to folks in the World Bank who
do international development work they
said well you can take an evaluator a
snapshot a short-term and you might
think oh the project's a success we fed
all these people we built roads we did
this and says well you look at the
community two or three years later and
find out that that actually was a very
disruptive process and changed the
dynamics and your graphs show that over
time things can change since it wasn't
mentioned I'll just add in the education
community not much is being done to
evaluate this because there's not much
policy or let's be honest the high
stakes test attached to these skills and
until there is there probably won't be
much measurement and I'm not advocating
for another high-stakes test before
anyone thinks that I think we a question
the back over there Rick Weiss I'm the
director of sideline which is a
philanthropically supported free service
for reporters that connects them to
scientists to help them get facts into
their stories and we focus a lot on
scientists this is to follow on the
question from the Philip Merrill school
because scientists have a long history
of being relatively trusted by the
population the relatively high Dean's
like 40%
over the last many years we says better
than journalists and members of Congress
but I'm wondering whether other
populations who are not in the core of
the Trump voter ship but who could gain
the trust of that voter ship really
ought to be getting more attention and
I'm thinking in particular of
celebrities and sports figures and I
haven't heard anything in the last
couple days about focusing on those
populations which I think have
tremendous influence and have and could
do a lot of good if they were targeted
and put to work for this purpose I
wonder if any of you have any experience
with that or thoughts about it
I think marketers have very good
experience with that I don't know that
that same idea has been exported to this
domain we we do seem to find that those
who are pushing this information seem to
think that targeting influential nodes
in the network is effective so I think
that's a very good question yeah we got
a question Oh back there
good hi my name is Shawna Gordon akin I
was struck by during multiple of your
talks the role of attention in people
having the ability to assess the quality
of information and I was wondering if
you have any thoughts about environments
whether online are off that strive to
give people the time or resources they
need to devote attention as opposed to
sort of like competitively fighting over
it or restricting attention I have a
couple of thoughts about that I think I
find it very interesting when I look at
the research into how people spend their
time whether it's pew and the US or
Ofcom with the Kaiser Family Foundation
and others who gather data on this that
there is almost a saturation point in
people's waking hours with media and
multitasking but that so called digital
natives appear to events quite a strong
desire for a more granular control over
this time than we saw five or ten years
ago by which I mean rather than wanting
to do everything all the time on one
great big platform people seek different
registers and this is connected to the
idea of what sometimes called the
migration of the social stack which
simply means that the whole stack of our
social activities ranging up from the
most intimate moments with our family to
our relationships with state and
employer
these are all being kind of digitally
mediated or if technology is implicated
in them
and I think there's a lot of very
exciting stuff around in the development
of services and modes of practice that
are congenial to people's needs people
don't want all their time to be the same
they don't want one size to fit all and
whether it's in formal practices where
people now putting away your phone is a
gesture of respect towards someone
rather than getting it out I still
remember loudly using a phone being a
status symbol whereas now being offline
and uncontacted but as the CEOs boast
and so I think there's an interesting as
it were kind of nexus of forces here in
Europe we have regulation in France and
elsewhere about employees not being
expected or to be contactable outside of
working hours debates around schools
again France and Germany varlet leading
the way here about about their being
kind of mobile and connectivity free
zones more awareness around health and
so on this is a kind of mosaic but I
think in in kind of within it there is
quite a strong kind of evidence and
evidence and habit needs-based movement
towards a more kind of granular and
respectful control over people's time
and attention and while I'm feeling
optimistic I like to imagine the next
generation of services in a sense
building in a respect for attention as a
fundamental aspect of UX you know I
don't I think we might be the
underpricing or mispricing of people's
attention might in retrospect look like
a folly or artifact over the last few
years rather than a permanent feature of
digital culture and of course the move
towards AI LED system smart systems
voice systems contextual worn systems
and so on and so on
is in many ways terrifying and
interesting but also geared towards
freeing up attention so that's a very
kind of nebulous answer but I think
there are a lot of interesting movements
to research and tap into and I'm quite
inspired by the opportunities that lie
in particular around parenting education
and employment because I think as they
did in the first Industrial Revolution
these
often help establish and enforce social
norms around a baseline expectation of
human thriving and human rights I think
we need one more question here in the
front
one more hi my name is Susan Bolton I
sent a question it seems like one of the
big barriers hearing this is that a lot
of this efficacy and data is getting
access to the data from the platforms
and listening to Facebook yesterday is
there any work potentially to take the
models fill that you're doing at Indiana
University and I know that sounds giving
that to Facebook so they can run they're
like helping the platforms run their own
analysis and then hopefully being
brought in like if they're afraid to let
the data go will they be able to bring
in some of the tools inside their own
platforms and at least they're starting
to understand I know they've got a lot
of smart people that work there too but
like yep they can at least begin to
understand the impact of what's
happening on their platforms better I I
think actually that has been the mode
for quite a long time their main way to
engaged Outsiders has to bring them in I
think that this has is problematic in
some sense in the first one is that it
all relies on networks of kunos whom I
have a good friend or my former students
are there so I have some access but
somebody else who might have a much
better idea than mine doesn't have
access that's one problem of bias and
other problem is that very often that we
the reason why they bring researchers in
is that then you sign a nondisclosure
agreement they give you a laptop you can
do everything you want and publisher the
conference perhaps but that data stays
in closed and they have to make sure
that okay so the new model with social
science one actually is an effort to
break that and to allow a broader
community of researchers to have access
to data we will see if it works or not I
have no idea but I mean at
so that's why I'm a little bit
pessimistic about what you suggest
because I think to some extent it it has
happened
they have no shortage of very very smart
people and researchers and also access
very easy access to the outside but
sometimes it's what they don't seek that
might be good and so so that's why you
know and and and people who don't have
those connections have a very hard time
to grab their attention so I think that
it is a good it is a step in the right
direction that Facebook is now
considering at least considering we'll
see how it well it works the idea of not
doing it by bringing people in by by by
allowing some data to some extent to be
shared more widely okay please join me
in thanking our tremendous speakers and