so my group focused on global
disinformation threats on two different
axes so the first axis that we had was
between ideological and non ideological
or financial threats the other axes
ranged from less powerful and less
congregated to more powerful and more
congregated threats so on in terms of
like more ideological and more
congregated threats we were looking at
state actors so state acting media this
would be things such as channel one
Sputnik PressTV GRU and VOA in terms of
like financial but still more powerful
threats we're looking at commercial
influence such as Big Tobacco Sinclair
and Breitbart in terms of less powerful
but more ideological we have the
grassroots troll movements so we're
looking at things like that
QA Nam the whatsapp mobbing in India
that sort of thing and in terms of
financial but less powerful movements
we're looking at affiliate marketers so
we're looking at there was a group of
Macedonian teenagers who spread
information to basically just four
clicks to get more money and scamming
people
federal fraud sort of things so the
techniques that they use to do these
things are things like from
state-sponsored media we're looking at
TV and radio stations more traditional
media that's the same thing for the
commercial side so that's more
traditional media along with funding
certain scientific studies the more
non-traditional types of techniques
comes from the less congregated areas so
that comes from the market affiliates
and the grassroot trolls so that's like
huge campaigns from the grassroots roles
who all attack a certain person such as
on Twitter it's also with the bots from
the grassroots rural area with the
affiliate marketers more telemarketing
that sort of thing
so interventions for these ways that
they're spreading misinformation when it
comes to affiliate marketers so that's
less congregated unless ideological
tactics we're looking at ad tech reform
in terms of the less congregated more
ideological tactics we're looking at
stronger age regulations because a lot
of like the fortune Area trolls aren't
targeting teenagers we're also looking
at higher enforcement of the standards
community standards in terms of
state-sponsored media that could be its
own session but a lot of that is just
involved in diplomacy diplomacy and in
terms of commercial influence there's
actually a lot that we can do there so a
lot of that is like political money
transparency and transparency with
things like trade and stuff there's one
overarching concept that we really
talked about though and that was media
literacy and there's a lot of different
ways we can spread that it was mentioned
earlier that we could do that through
education but we can also do that
through like public libraries that's
great
next presentation AV team if you will
how it's made fake news faker fact
figure facts please come up
I want to get a picture of that as we
had our workshop my teenage son made the
slides so so wish me luck much go Fifi
okay this is his his particular approach
to creating fake news among his friends
they download and this is Shamu the
whale with a chainsaw he's about to cut
to the side of the of the thing and go
into into the audience with it
NASA recommends the chainsaw this is
where we're getting into what we really
did so there are certain tactics that
people use to help things spread fake
news and real news and I am the demon in
the room because I'm a growth hacker and
that's what people hire me to do
that's what faker fact hired me to do so
you start with a group of people say
your friends or if you look at pizza
gate they went to planting seeds in a
chat room so a lot of the fig news
starts in chat rooms and you need a few
people to give it traction initially so
that it enough Phil talked about the
bots they'll get a bot - all right so
the bots will retweeted a whole bunch of
times until it gets picked up by the
mainstream media and then they'll do a
story on it so you can give it
legitimacy that way confirmation bias is
a big thing once you hit that group of
people that you know that want that
story they're going to be spread it
especially if it has sort of a gossipy
or a novel approach to it that they
think is interesting then they're going
to they're going to repost it we're back
to the bottom one the humor
or the novelty is probably going to get
some reposts um I also can't see that oh
and the visuals can give it legitimacy
so if it's got a good visual like the
ones we just saw there it's going to get
reposted more often and if the photo
seems real and not not fake another
thing was if almost everybody in the
room agreed that if there was an
authority who had been quoted in the
article it gives it more legitimacy and
they would feel more comfortable sharing
it and oh and then emotionally
triggering words was another thing that
several people have spoken about things
like shockingly or the trolls in
Macedonia that the young lady just just
referenced they would take a regular
news article and make some dramatic
headline to turn it into clickbait so
that was a big way that things got
shared and then we had a whole list of
ideas of how to slow down people from
sharing it
starting with targeting people who are
willing to listen because some people
are at a far end of one end of the
spectrum or the other and and no matter
what you say if faker fact our website
says it's not true they're just gonna
write that off well faker fact is crazy
that's not that's not it at all another
way we thought might help was that if
you have posted something and we
probably all done it posted something
that turned out later to be wrong that
you honestly go back and say hey
everybody I posted this and it turned
out not to be true so I fell for it you
know this is the whole thing with like
the elders getting scammed if there's
awareness of it it might slow people
down a little bit if we put dates on the
stories so that we would know well this
story was written you know seven years
ago so it's not really applicable
anymore that would be helpful also
tracing the sources back to the original
article or the original source the
primary source so that you can you can
find out you know what what was actually
said under what conditions instead of
taking it out of context
also if you wanted to to discuss it with
somebody you could post links about the
same article from a more reputable
source so that would would disrepute the
person who's you know supporting the
ridiculousness asking people regularly
what's your source and something that
maybe the platform's would be able to do
is a way to not boost things because
sometimes someone will put some in city
areas to give it traction just to get
people to argue with them and if there's
a way that Facebook and Twitter and
other people once they start arguing and
all of those people start into that
particular topic on that particular link
if there was a way that the the
platforms could not prioritize that it
would help because if they're just
trying to stir up trouble it's actually
a marketing tactic it doesn't
necessarily mean that you are are
fighting with a legitimate person it's
easily could be somebody who's you know
been planted their stories about how
fake news has damaged people everyone in
the room felt like it was the whatsapp
issue and with India had been really
effective in in making everyone more
aware of how damaging it can be to to
spread fake news so probably if the news
media could pick up more stories about
how damaging the damage that have been
done on a personal level to people
because of fake news that would be a way
to slow it down and there's these days
there's an an AI app but you could also
embed the metadata in a way so that if
you're looking at a picture of something
that's been misrepresented then the AI
app or the metadata could be putting
away so that you can see the text that's
associated with that like this is a
person at a celebration crossing the
street and that would offset the idea
that this is a guy with an Isis flag
after the World Cup that kind of thing
on a lower level to keep those emotional
from being such a trigger if we could
all give maybe some emotional management
classes to our kids and ourselves that
would slow things down as well
that is the end thank you Thank You
Rebecca
and faker fact that was really great
thank you let's see let's see who we
have next Craig go and they have slides
today amazing huh Samantha from Craig go
away yes I am uh I don't work for Craig
Co I was I was just an attendee for this
workshop but I feel like I learned a lot
and Craig Coe is really open to feedback
from people and interaction and
contribution so I'm gonna talk about a
couple of the things that our group
leaders sort of brought up we broke into
groups and had a lot of ideas
surrounding the central concept so I'm
not going to go into all of those
various ideas but one of the first
things that we talked about is something
Craig Coe is working on the idea of
basically coming up with a nutrition
label for a news article and attaching
that label to the article in this slide
you can see an example of a u.s.
nutrition label compared to one in the
UK I personally did not know that the UK
one is so much better it's I to me it's
way more understandable just as a quick
summary that red that red section has
sort of like a dangerous or an unhealthy
amount of sodium or whatever that is one
of the things we talked about was how to
make it legible so if you were going to
do this idea if you're going to make a
nutrition label for news how would you
implement it and what would you want it
to show so we talked about maybe a few
indicators of journalism like
transparency or sources or you know a
few of the other elements of journalism
that you might want to track but also
how would you make it readable to the
reader and how would you implement it so
one thing that I think on
or someone know Farida mentioned was
that you probably would want to
incorporate designers because for
instance this UK label problem guessing
had designers involved whereas the u.s.
one maybe not so much so they have a
website there on the slide if you are
interested in this idea of coming up
with nutrition labels or how those could
be implemented if you follow that link
it's just cred web org slash cc IV or
you could just go to cred web org they
have a list of a lot of the indicators
they're thinking about and they're
looking for more contribution and ideas
related to that one of the other things
we talked about was how to not just
verify an image but how to study it in
sort of a wider context so I come from a
journalism background and there's a lot
of emphasis on verification we're
missing a couple slides that's okay
there's a lot of emphasis on verifying
an image like making sure that it's
quote unquote
real and that it does show what it
pertains to show but it also might be
even more important to know the context
of the distribution of it so if it's a
real image of Syria for example who
shared that image so not just what
Twitter but like which groups on Twitter
and then ideally you would want to find
out why they shared it so the frita
presented this it actually should spa
road from art history apparently but
it's a way to analyze a photo or an
image and basically learn a lot from it
to give you a lot more context to work
with i'll pause to let Jenny take a
photo so we put focused a lot on context
as well as the source and then when you
get into things like memes where they
add text or they add maybe fake context
or other context to that basically how
do you deal with that and incorporate it
so these are also things that I think
are very open for discussion and they
would like to get feedback and
contribution on so if you have any
thoughts on that or if you'd like to get
I know you couldn't really read that
wheel if anyone wants a copy of that I
think come see eat cred code that's all
thanks guys
[Applause]
thank you
Thank You Samantha fun fact the
unofficial mascot of Krypto is the
credible Hulk i rolls and groans and
with that next slide please
hi in this guy media literacy programs I
don't know Media literacy let's check
this up my name is Jesse Haas McCarthy
I'm with Museum Edie and I had the
pleasure of leading this breakout
session and I won my group left before
we came up with a title but - we use
this term a lot and it was our
jumping-off point what are the ultimate
highest goals we want in the education
or creating things around media literacy
you know what is the ultimate dream what
is the highest we can reach for and our
brilliance was contributed by these
individuals or individuals from these
organizations here and we focus on the
question of how can we build support for
a media literacy push across society and
what combination of news organizations
tech companies and education groups can
be assembled to drive that work and we
did we jumped in with what would be our
ultimate dream looks and I know you
can't read them but we looked at things
like power having true spoken to it
everyone everywhere has to detect
propaganda and wants to and as we
synthesize all of our ultimate goals we
came out with these sort of three key
things that everyone everywhere
participates in productive conversations
based on respect for other's knowledge
and expertise an understanding of why
being informed matters and a desire to
be challenged and become more informed
and then we want to look at practical
things these players in this
conversation can do through some
approaches and we looked at both the
idea of local community-based
and technology-based things like social
media platforms if you want to see our
brainstorming someone was kind enough to
share it on Twitter and you can see it
on the Newseum at Twitter our
brainstorming posters but we sorta
started playing around with social media
platform is making an incentive or some
sort of badge or something to encourage
the idea of a truth identity so making
being a truth finder a part of who you
are and what you share on social media
and sort of meters of engagement ways to
fall and track that and then we looked
at sort of community based organizations
and how can we bring them into that
bigger push with this Universal
statement of shared values or creating a
some sort of umbrella organization or
group or a conference that these
organizations could come to and share
and local teams leading to all these
different local environments but some of
the challenges we saw in this is there's
this challenge between wanting a media
literate society as an empowerment of
democracy and trying to create these
ultimate programmatic goals or these
ultimate creations where one person
tells other people what to do to achieve
this and that's about as undemocratic as
it gets
and so one participant posited this idea
of we need to find a way to create one
see that everyone gets on to that blooms
a thousand flowers and these local
community organizations and with that in
mind we jumped into what can we agree on
in there became this idea of what
programs could be created that or
collaborative as opposed to competitive
across these different organizations and
what that would look like
give me let me get the notes up and this
is where we really went big so we went
bigger go home on this one so we saw a
federal education mandate so that it
became a national trend or or maybe you
stepped down from that and we set a cool
media literacy holiday that everyone
could jump on to and participate on or
create programming around there is a
suggestion of a new nonprofit social
media platform strictly for utilizing
teaching and transmitting media literacy
one that's not out to make profit whose
goal is to be media literate as you
share
the idea of a media literacy could
manifester that social media and
community organizations can sign on to
so sort of a unified goals that all of
these groups can go to then take media
literacy to where people are looking TV
series comic book HBO special movie
documentary go to where people are
looking already and make it something
they see media literacy Oscars an awards
show for media literate organizations
reward this make it something we're
striving for an honorable to have
received and then we sort of played
around the idea of a hashtag codebook
sort of like an ever changing codebook
of hashtags that move and rotate enough
so that media literacy organizations get
them first and can push those ideas
before they get co-opted by everyone
who's just jumping on to what is
trending and the goal and all of this
was to create tangible things and I
think my mojo disappeared thank you
thank you thank you thank you Jesse and
Barbara and the museum team for
pie-in-the-sky media literacy programs
changing people's behaviors to prevent
miss info sharing gleb with the pro
truth pledge hey everyone hey can you
hear me now
excellent good that was a great the
previous presentation was a great
preparation for this presentation
because talking about a badge is the
approach you've pledge is a perfect
badge of ways that you can actually mark
yourself as being truthful and committed
to truthfulness but I'll mention the
approach you've pledged throughout the
presentation but here the presentation
focuses on a broader concept the
approach of pledge is only one strategy
of getting both private citizens and
public figures to prevent the sharing of
misinformation by these folks so how do
we do it the first thing is to look at
why people share misinformation what
happens why do they share misinformation
well there are several reasons according
to the research in behavioral science
and that's my area of expertise there
are no penalties for doing it there are
no penalties for sharing this
information that's one major reason why
people share invested information they
can still proceed themselves as overall
honest when they share misinformation if
they can do that that contributes to
sharing this information if they see
others both their opponents and allies
are sharing this information that makes
them more likely to share misinformation
and finally if they see it as helping
their in-group their tribe that
contributes to sharing this information
there are also certain things that
discourage the sharing of misinformation
some of them the flip side of what we
talked about so for example if we make
standards about truthfulness clear if
it's not an under doubt what does it
mean to be true for what does it mean to
be honest that discourages the sharing
of information a pre commitment to
truthful behavior like honor codes of
various sorts have been shown to clearly
encourage truthfulness reminders various
sorts of reminders about what truthful
behavior means interestingly there was a
study that showed that the 10
commandments shown somebody the Ten
Commandments makes him or her more
likely to be truthful
even if that person is an atheist it's
just a priming of truthfulness reminds
them of what being truthful means
perceiving your in-group as discouraging
misinformation sharing that's another
factor that is crucial and finally
having a self perception a personal
identity as committed to truthfulness so
as some previous group discussed
something like a badge so for public
figures there is an additional dynamic
and this includes reputational rewards
for honesty and reputation on penalties
for the psalmist you so those two things
are additional things that we want
public figures and organizations those
are specifically relevant to them so
what did we come up with we came up with
first we talked about private citizens
and here's some things for private
citizens that are going to be relevant
we want to invest positive emotions into
being truthful and encourage you owner
ability around truthfulness so saying
people saying I don't know what I'm not
sure being able to admit that right now
as opposed to feeling defensive and
having to have all the answers we want
to be empathetic but it's still very
important to call out people who share
misinformation otherwise there's not
going to be any penalties for sharing
this information so empathetically
calling these people out we want to show
people how sharing misinformation harms
the ring' group that might involve
reframing who they perceive as their
in-group so for example if right now
people perceive sharing this information
as benefiting their political cause
their ideology if we can reframe the
ring group as being about the whole
country as being about democracy as
being about protecting the United States
of America or other countries and which
their context is that would be helpful
so that's another dynamic and finally we
want to prime people for cultural
reference of truthfulness so it's
something like the boy who cried wolf or
Pinocchio or something like that so
cultural reference that make them think
about truthfulness they're going to be
helpful and for public for public
figures went onto public figures now
broadly speaking this is applicable to
all public figures all organizations we
thought that social profiles can be read
based on their truthfulness the pages of
public figures you know whether people
on the left pick on the right center or
whatever can be rated based on how
truthful they are if there's a rating
system of some sorts and if the whole
page can be G emphasized by social media
platforms if it consistently shares
misinformation so having the whole page
not specific articles BD emphasized but
the whole page and finally we thought
about if there can be a reward system
for politicians right now we thought
about the environmental movement how it
was incredibly successful created
essentially out of nothing in the 1950s
and 1960s became an incredibly
successful movement that was really
powerful you know Rachel Carson's Silent
Spring was published 1962 in 1970
Richard Nixon created an Environmental
Protection Agency so really powerful and
if that Lobby woodrick would reward
politicians who are honest by money
volunteer time and votes so having
something like that so these are all the
strategies that we talked about now the
pro truth pledges hits a number of those
strategies but there are so many other
things that can be done in this fear to
change people's behavior change people's
incentives both private citizens and
public figures to help them avoid
sharing misinformation and I hope all of
you contribute some ideas and think
about how you can change the behavior of
people you know of public figures you
know to encourage them to avoid sharing
misinformation
thank you thank you Gleb with Pro truth
pledge thanks what we have our
penultimate our pen ultimate workshop
presentation coming up standard
certification Scott a little different
hi thank you very much I'm I'm combating
the jinx of Kiev because I I presented
it Kiev about Arkady Benko when he was
dead and then I left and he was alive
again
and setting journalism back 50 years and
so I said to the group I can't present
because of this jinx and they all said
whatever get up there and go do the
presentation so anyway thank you very
much we talked about standards to
certification the there were three of us
oh oh this is gonna be a totally
different presentation that was plenty
done because this is a this is a grab
for what I submitted it to you okay so
it's changed a little bit since that but
all right so it was organized by three
groups which the w3c cred web group
which you can find at cred web org
Sandro is here and be sure to talk to
him about the involvement of the w3c in
the standard setting process for the
idea of a more credible web reporters
without borders known by its French
initials RSF Olaf is here and you should
talk to him about their efforts and then
my organizations the certified content
coalition and you can find out more on
the website there we wanted to start out
we thought we'd be able to do a lot of
great work and and maybe get through a
series of questions and we realized we
could really only get through one
question how to build a hard to game
journalism standard and then we came up
with one standard and we thought we're
just going to do this one standard we're
just going to tackle this one and this
is the easiest one provide full
transparency and identity of revenue
that'll be a standard that we're all
going to be able to agree on quickly and
then we'll be able to move on to the
next standard and so we started talking
about that one standard and we realized
that it's not at all easy this was
incredibly difficult there's a bunch of
stuff that goes on and you can go to the
Twitter handle and you can go to
misanthrope kinda get the latest version
of this so you don't have to read this
but I can tell you coming up with
standards is incredibly hard but that
being said it's important to try it's
really hard to come up with these
standards but if we don't do it somebody
else will let's see what this side okay
so the new version of the slide is so
this is organ Putin and Elon Musk who
would all like to come up with their
standards for
journalism is and so if if the people
the smart people in this room decide not
to do it just because it's hard then
other people will fill in the vacuum and
that would be really terrible the new
version of the slide has a big arrow on
it and the arrow was pointing this way
and so it's the other people that will
try to regulate it are either that but
that building if you're looking at these
monitors or in the White House if you're
looking at those monitors and and we
don't want either of those to happen so
so that's it the other slide that we
have was thanks very much we had an
amazing amazing pure super super helpful
and we're very appreciative of having
the time to present here and let's hope
now the jinx is broken Thank You sky
thank you our last workshop IREX get up
here
solving the citizens side of the
equation shouldn't have sat in the back
it's a long wait to use this clicker
Greene ok so what we did was we let a
Design Thinking workshop with a few
groups that were interested in tackling
these three themes so helping citizens
separate fact from fiction helping us
measure the impact of our efforts and
helping citizens actively seek quality
information so each of the participants
got to choose whichever one of these
themes that they wanted to take part in
we had groups of two to three in each of
them these are the participants having
lots of fun with their sticky notes
there you go and then these were their
ideas that they came up with the purpose
of these of this actual workshop what's
not to come up with ideas that are gonna
change the world but to really
understand the process that you need to
go through in order to try and innovate
using design thinking techniques so the
first group came up with a user driven
browser fact-checker
the second group - which wanted to
measure the impact of our efforts to
find misinformation thought of an
incentivized marketplace for citizens to
report fake news and in the last group
wanted to increase journalism's
responsiveness to people's needs by
finding more time and space for them so
these are the main reflections that came
out of the workshop these reflections
were from the participants themselves I
can read them we must avoid the tendency
to view users as a monolithic unit and
what this means is we shouldn't just
think that all our solutions are going
to be adapt for everyone around the
world every solution is contextual and
we need to look at users in that same
way there is a percentage of people who
we believe will never change their point
of view
so this is more of a question that the
participants came up with do we want to
cater all of our ideas to those people
or do we want to cater it to the rest
who we think are could go either way
still it is important to consider the
incentives for individuals to take part
in any process relating to fighting
misinformation this one speaks for
itself and lastly we should look for
solutions that capitalize on platforms
whose users comprise the target audience
this basically means once you've figured
out who your users are just for you find
the platforms that they're using right
now so you can touch base with them and
tackle that group appropriately thank
you
[Applause]