hey everybody this is great I work KQED
which is public NPR affiliate and PBS
affiliate in San Francisco and I'm part
of our education department I'm here to
talk about mostly solution-based stuff
but I hopefully will have some time to
weigh in on some of these other issues
at the end which are foundational to the
work that we're doing so I'm here to
talk about a solution for a product that
we've developed called KQED learn which
is an online space for student inquiry
and collaboration connecting students
connecting secondary classrooms middle
and high school classrooms across the
country around issues and questions that
matter to them so KQED learn is a free
platform for hosting and supporting
student inquiry investigation and media
making classrooms as they engage and ask
questions as they conduct inquiry and
investigations as they make and share
findings and multimedia formats
fostering connections and collaborations
between individuals and community and
finding an audience for great student
work at KQED the foundation of our work
is about elevating youth voice from the
classroom to our national conversations
we believe that teenagers should be
heard and in order for teenagers to be
heard we need to develop the tools and
platforms for them to be heard on so
what we do is we're going to work on
providing them framework and resources
to refine their voice and engaged in
informed discussion conduct their own
inquiry and produce stories that matter
to them and their communities and to
share their work with peers and more
there's a word missing it's widely I do
promise that while these are easy to
read I have I did get the memo and I
have several slides that you will not be
able to read later on so you know at the
root of the problem that we see it is is
inquiry or rather the failure to
adequately promote inquiry has led to a
generation or maybe generations of
people waiting to
told what matters and why as Haroon from
BBG said yesterday and it was also kind
of brought up today in a different way
this information is ineffective against
a well-educated informed citizenry and
maybe we think that in nurturing
curiosity and an inquiry mindset is part
of that equation so the first part of
our learn experience is called go above
the noise this is a series that we
produce at KQED that seeks to spark
civic engagement and informed debate
about issues that are relevant to youth
in their community we have a young
journalist who hosts our show we are
hyped on the animation and what we do in
this series is we we really bring topics
that we think kids are going to be
interested in as well as we have to find
this balance of stuff that teachers are
also interested in engaging in
discussions with their students and
through the series we model inquiry by
asking critical questions and
investigating answers of producing and
looking at things from multiple
perspectives talking about why sources
are good sources why sources or not and
then through the end what miles does is
guides people miles as the host what
miles does is guides students through
the process so that as he's learning
he's modeling what kinds of questions
and activities they should ask and then
we invite kids into discussion so this
is a national conversation and here's a
my first slide that you won't be able to
read so this is a good one good place
for us to go on here so what I'm gonna
do is I'm gonna I'm gonna paraphrase
some of this so this is a discussion
around free speech on college campuses
its stemmed from an episode we did about
the issues that happened at UC Berkeley
with Milo don't know his last name and
some of the other guys that are part of
his troop so this is for responses from
three schools around the country
two of them are in the Bay Area one of
them is in
Los Angeles and the other one is a
student from Quantico here in Virginia
and the first kid starts with a
provocation he says the presence of hate
speech and the Constitution's inability
to stop it
throws the whole thing into question 231
years it's too old it's too white right
the second kid says get a grip you're
wrong there's no expiration date on the
Constitution third kid says well I agree
that the Constitution is important but
he might have a point we do need to
think about this hate speech thing and
then the fourth student who's a middle
schooler from Virginia says sorry but we
need to protect all speech even hate
hate speech is ridiculous she does note
but if we stop protecting it then all of
our rights become vulnerable so we have
this wrecked kind of rich conversation
happening with students in urban
environments students across the country
students across grade levels that we're
really kind of excited about so after we
after students engage in this kind of
discussion they start to find their
voice they start to learn how to cite
resources from the how to build that
kind of into their natural language as
they're writing about the things that
they're thinking we then open it up for
questions to students we start providing
learning resources at the point of need
so as along with asking questions the
point where students begin to ask
questions again another slide you can't
read and ironically I can't either
so but we start providing just the weird
you know bifocals don't work I don't
know who where if anyone wears them and
they work tell me about it because they
just don't so our thing is you know what
we we then provide solution or sources
with other KQED media professionals
answering questions like what kind of
questions are there and how do I ask a
good question so we have media
personalities talking about well in the
show that I do or as a reporter and we
model those kinds of things throughout
this process then we get into our
investigations process our inquiry
process which is focused on four main
steps questioning investigating making
and sharing and reflecting and
responding to others I've pulled out a
little piece here this is from an
investigation on nuclear power that
spawned four
there was a an icon on the earlier slide
about nuclear power and one of the
videos we did this investigation has
four different schools seventy five
different participants they're sharing
19 different internet resources and
they've produced 61 different pieces of
media as a result of their
investigations there's a few of the kids
at the top of the list three minutes
okay so you're we have oh I gotta push
this and this here's this so at the
first stage we ask kids what they
already know so right you know if you're
a teacher you know about like KWL charts
and all kinds of things and activating
prior learning so we say before they
start doing the investigation what do
you already know about nuclear power
sometimes they're wrong sometimes they
don't know anything sometimes they're
right but the point is they can start to
see that what other kids are thinking
before they begin the process once they
begin the process they move into an
investigation stage here again I've told
you I promise slides you couldn't read I
am delivering on that promise
the investigation stage students can
rate share rate and discuss resources
and see the ways that others are valuing
or not valuing those same resources so
in this case here's one of the resources
on the top and you have in this
particular case there are 18 different
comments on this resource the resources
received oh it's a good one it's
received a great rating so you can see
down here students are like what are
they why I think this is a good resource
other students can start to see what
other kids are thinking then we move
into making and sharing media content so
at this point we bring we wrap it all
together at the beginning their initial
thought lays in the top so they can see
it they're caught so it's there they're
learning becomes presented in context
they can see where I was where I am we
roll in the citations on the right of
the articles or the resources that they
have cited as part of their research and
then the students share this content
reflect on it and then invite other
students to respond to their work as
well
so I mentioned earlier that we are
involved in elevating youth voice and
all of this is our attempt to get
students making amazing media becoming
literate and making positive
contributions and becoming civically
engaged in the spring of this year we
sponsored we decided to test the
hypothesis of whether students could
actually make media that our producers
would put on the radio our producers
didn't think that we could but we tried
it we ended up working with ten students
in kind of a rapid-fire prototype
session to see ten teachers excuse me in
a prototype and over about eight weeks
we ended up with 35 after eight weeks we
ended up with 35 students on the air
producing stories live on KQED radio
reaching an audience of about 250,000
people a day and then 75 more stories
published on KQED org our website which
is also viewed millions of times a month
how much for 30 seconds Phil I'm just
kidding okay so I had a bunch of stuff
but I do want to do one more slide and
this is just this is the way we define
this conversation that's come up a few
different times today it's skepticism
versus cynicism and I think I haven't
heard the word cynic but I think that
that's what we're talking about is the
cynic just trusts everything and the
skeptic kind of thinks about the things
and and questions and learns the
question as part of the process and then
you know we do we have some other
justifications
I'll show you slides later if you want
Thanks
[Applause]