I
I arrived yesterday lunchtime and at
that time I still thought that I was
very smart and then I started to me with
and talked with some of you folk and I
was transported back 20 or so years to
my time at University you know I
recognize some of the t-shirts in some
of the the haircuts and some of the
really infused conversations technical
conversations with that were going on
you know even even the accents were
right i don't know if dave and rob are
here or aj with the british accents is
there anyone here from Great Britain ya
wanna thank you one or two so I felt
very much at home but what was different
between the real 20-odd years ago and
yesterday was that I am now the guy in
the class that can't quite keep up now
you might think that I wouldn't be so
enthused about being here because of
that but you know if anything I'm even
more excited because it shows to me it
reaffirms to me that this is exactly the
mix of audience that I should be talking
to now at exactly the right time in
exactly the right location now i'm going
to be talking about flattening the
network however my objective my
objective is to pique the interest of
some of you in coming and joining me and
some of my colleagues for a birds of a
feather session in denver in june so if
i if i was a real optimist i would hope
to make every single one of you agree
with my view of the world but in 20
minutes my objective is just to pique
your interest you don't have to agree
with me I just would like to ask you to
start thinking about what I'm going to
talk about and I hope come and join us
for a bit more of a technical chat in
June at upwards on favor say
no you see a very familiar graph too
many of you and I'd like to thank the
University of Minnesota for some of
these figures you probably know the
University of Minnesota Swanson Gilder
and of course cisco systems now if you
haven't seen this exact graph before and
this is a logarithmic one you'll have
seen something something like this this
is one from our colleague Luke coupons
from Jupiter and this one's a linear
skill when your skill but you know
whether you view the great increase in
bandwidth demand that we've been seeing
and continue to see as being logarithmic
or exponential or or some kind of
moore's law equation I think we can all
agree can we not that the rate the rate
of growth a bandwidth demand is growing
yeah the growth is growing the growth
rate therefore we're talking about
acceleration and which case we need a
great more bandwidth supply over our
networks so where's this demand coming
from would anyone like to show to one or
two answers we say that this great
demand coming from
well I'd adventure to say thank you I
venture to see that not only are the
early users of the internet now using
far far more bandwidth than before but
we're even seeing Uncle Bill and Aunty
and granny who would never have thought
of using these technologies in the past
now on facebook now in social networking
now watching videos on YouTube now
watching even up loads of videos of
their own grandchildren living perhaps
thousands of miles away and just as an
example I was on YouTube now owned by
Google I gathered as quite a few Google
people here today good and I watched
this entire episode on youtube full
screen four by three aspect ratio at 480
interlace in other words I watched it
over the web on youtube at the original
broadcast definition I mean it is just
fantastical so if all of the middle
class and upper class people and the
Americas if all the people who can
afford it decide to jump on the web at
the same time will you you're all know
better than me they might have bandwidth
at we're going to be being asked to
provide over just the next few years it
is going to be absolutely gigantic and
actually reminds me as well that I'm
just watching my own television series
of 24 people familiar with a show called
24 key for Sullivan please Jack Bauer
it's run for a fantastical eight seasons
I am invested advertising in competition
between the the satellite channels and
the cable channels eight seasons is just
incredible you know and I think I've got
our friends at Cisco to thank for that
because they were funding it and I've
got we request for those of you from
Cisco if you can pick up a little bit
more money I understand that the feature
film is held up by folks at the moment
because they can't afford to fund it but
the point I'm trying to make here is I
watched almost all of the season eight
of 24
on the Fox website in high definition so
I think I've leave at this point enough
we're talking about a fantastic amount
of bandwidth that's needed and then last
is somebody in the audience please tell
me if there is who's going to have a pet
of a router on a single shelf within the
next few years we're going to need to
find another way of getting more
bandwidth out of our networks
what I like to do is just take a moment
to look a slight of a summary of just my
view of the situation just know now we
have a situation where we get a very
high volumes or video and Internet
traffic that's negatively impacting our
profitability we've get growing measures
measures of core routers to handle this
ever-increasing traffic and most
importantly for what I'm talking about
just now we get separate IP and
transport domains with very very little
cross domain visibility and what I'm
suggesting to do is that we get to a
situation where we have a new
architecture that leverages all of the
technologies that we have to snow that
is integration of the optical domain
into the IP domain with some form of
cross layer visibility and automation
and what I'm saying is that we need to
get smart we need to look at the bigger
picture by me I mean the the vendors and
if we are going to be helped is people
like all of you upon whom I'm relying to
design our new networks I like to take a
quotation from last week's state of the
union address we need to out-innovate
out-educate and out-build the rest of
the world innovation doesn't just change
our lives it's how we make a living in
other words the president of the u.s. it
has an implied warning there if we don't
innovate our network designs someone
else will
so here's all of you up on the top floor
and third or fourth floor according to
this diagram here running networks
designing the network's designing IP
networks which are robust indeed I
believe that you have to build an IP
layer protection just in case something
goes wrong down the stairs in layer one
early or too is that is that correct
just to be safe why is it that you have
to do that well it's because we cannot
easily see or even control what's
happening downstairs and this is a good
cue for the entrance of OT n optical
transport networks and I know this was
introduced this morning by Greg our
Hawkins and Brent and Dawson when they
were talking giving their excellent
presentation about 100g many of you have
already heard about otn some of you mean
on here before what's important for me
to tell you today is the otn has come of
age we now have the introduction at the
end of last year of the standard for ODU
flex so now we have a technology which
is just begging to be utilized for IP
networks just very briefly for those who
have not heritable TN to great
advantages firstly it's sailfin kind
itself time and the second thing is that
it's got variable with pipes of your
like you can choose the bandwidth that
you need for each and every application
but that's not all we now have the
ability to take vlans or other IP
traffic and groom it at several levels
port level support lambda lambda level
and to encapsulate this traffic in pipes
that have bandwidth of our own choosing
by that I mean we can have transport
pipes that can be any size at all
between 1.25 gig
and a hundred gate or even 400 gig yeah
we can start it with only 1.25 gig and
we can increase in increments of 1.25
gigabits per second in increments that
you choose and that's massive I believe
in my opinion now I'm saying that you
can do it not there more or us is
because I am talking about changing the
network you changing that the network
from this and that is not correct from
this which where we have an independent
IP and optical domain to this a single
unified control plane for you our
network designers have control not only
over the routers and the switches but
over all of the assets in the network so
what I'm talking about is a network that
uses all of our technologies to optimize
the entire network rather than just
local areas bottlenecks local
requirements and my friends this is not
a zero-sum game where you have to choose
between one technology or another and
let me just exemplify I want to mention
my daughter because she's watching just
now two three nights ago my daughter
who's two years old and i were watching
bambi does anyone remember bambi yeah
good thank you I see some tears of
hearing in people's eyes at the
beginning of Bambi hi the camera appears
to move through the through the forest
before we've actually met the baby deer
and we see a lot of small animals and
there is a point where mama bird lands
in the nest and this three little baby
birds and she drops in a twig with five
berries on it and in immediately two of
the parts grab the ends of the twig yeah
and they pull back and forth between
each other which is of course a zero-sum
game one of them is going to win and the
other one's going to lose but while they
are busy struggling away
the third little baby bird comes up and
eats all five varies leaving the other
two looking rather stupid so one thing
is this is not a situation where you
have to choose between one kind of
network or another kind one kind of
protocol or another what I'm saying is
why not use them all and why not control
them all yourselves in one single
cross-domain control plane now I know
historically you've all relied upon the
OSI model per protocol stack since 1984
before I had a breakfast discussion with
several people this morning at the
newbies conference and we talked just
for a few minutes about how the protocol
stack is used these days and it's still
extremely relevant in their opinion in
that it gives a means that people from
different companies from different
expertise can continue to understand
what each other's talking about but the
also mentioned to me that some other
things are starting to slip in
expressions like layer 2.5 yeah or layer
0 yeah i mean what's all that what's all
that how there's no such thing in the 84
or even the 94 protocol stack but the
point they were trying to make a to me
is this that the world has changed a
little bit over the last quarter century
and it's not quite so easy to put things
into the perspective of the original
stack if you like so this is an opening
in their opinion you know to form
something round about where three layer
to layer 2.5 I don't care layer 2.1
where we can make what I'm showing on
the screens just now actually work
they'll have to say it's some going to
be rather difficult transition for
people back in the company where I work
I mean let's face it human beings are
usually happiest in an environment where
we understand everything that's
on however I believe that most of you
who wish to who gravitate towards this
solution will be the ones who design the
new protocols that will assure the jobs
of me you and many many people for a
quite a number of years going forward
because just to paraphrase the State of
the Union speech if we don't do it
somebody else will now here I just
picked out some of the actually let's
have a look at this firm on this is some
this is just an example of three nodes
and you see this is not a God box this
is three separate shelves if you like at
a particular node quite discreet and at
the top at the top we've got the very
very intelligent rotor right the router
with a big power of the big CPU that
does the real thinking beneath it we've
got something that's the bandwidth
manager that's what analysts call cross
connects these days so let's just call
it cross connect and beneath that yeah
we've got the not very bright at all
optical box or raw done or DWDM box and
if as in this example you know this
particular stream needs the processing
power by golly it goes through the very
intelligent very useful router in this
example here we go the same three nodes
with something which is already been
predetermined by this control layer not
to need that level of processing and if
we go to hear we may even find that
sometimes at some loads we don't even
need one of the boxes for example the
cross-connect is missing from node two
so I'm not talking about having modular
systems I'm not talking about a god box
i'm not talking about something that can
do everything i'm talking about just
smartly picking out only the
functionality that we need
each node in the various networks now as
I said a few moments ago some people
will be uncomfortable so I just thought
with your permission I'd like to take
just a few moments to talk about some of
the potential hartles to be overcome a
number of people may argue with me you
know network flattening should be done
at the DWDM layer not at the ODU layer
to reduce the complexity and the number
of optical cross connects well I would
argue that there are situations where IP
/ WDM makes sense especially when we're
talking about having oak floors there
are trade-offs and one of the trade-offs
is that the the provider would need to
whoever ran the net what we need to
integrate both the IP and optics
operations groups and at the moment most
providers who need a clear demarcation
between IP and optical domains prefer
black and white interfaces from the
router that is not colored a CW DMR WDM
IP / w DM is typically limited to metro
and regional networks since as you all
know router wavelengths which are put
into DWDM must conform usually to very
rigorous engineering rules belief number
two you don't need to protect both IP
and optical layers hmm yeah an emphasis
should be put on IP layer protection
well I kind of think probably that this
claim assumes that optical protection
would be slow since it's down at the
lambda layers well if this is so it's a
fallacy again because the fact is in my
opinion as you move down the protocol
stack things actually happen faster
however I would argue also that two
protections are better than one so
something I'm particularly hoping we can
discuss in June
now I have some more beliefs up here you
can see I'm thinking I'm thinking to
myself sooo joyner that I'll give you
all my requests to put up on the web
yeah 442 read along with my slide set
because I think this would be a good
time to come to my conclusion hmm my
main objective is to get some of you
interested not all of you but some of
you interested in flattening flattening
the network and I'm hoping that these
people who think mmm this is interesting
let's think about it for the next few
months will then sign up to come to our
birds of a feather session which will be
in june though i'm going to be around
for the next two days i'll be at the
beer in gear i'll be in the social
tonight i'll be around until the end of
the conference on wednesday so please
feel free grab me come and talk with me
if you like to grab me right after this
I will also give you my contact details
out of cell phone here with me call me
up I'll come and meet you anytime over
the next couple of days or indeed I'll
give you my email address and by all
means please please write to make it but
I do hope to see a great many of you
come to the bof session and aim for in
to go together we've got a few minutes
for any questions for me how for me know
any general questions please
okay quick quick show of hands who at
the moment is considering coming to the
good old argument with me in June in
Denver I see good thank you very much
and I very much look forward to seeing
you thanks for listening to hear