I
and then when you maybe shouldn't use it
and what else you should consider before
just going in
straight into it so basically passive
DWDM is DWDM is a dense wave division
multiplexing there's also a coarse wave
division multiplexing DWDM lives in the
1550 nanometer band and if you're going
to have a true passive system there
shouldn't be any active components in
order to make light get from one end to
the other so a couple reasons for using
DWDM in a passive state would be the
cost passivity liam is very cheap you
don't have to buy extensive shelf
systems with you know varying cards just
to get that light out into your dark
fiber there's little complexity at all
it's pretty much as plug-and-play you
take your fiber from your gear and you
hook that straight into your shelf and
then your line side fiber whether it be
dark fiber from a carrier or it be fiber
across your campus you just plug that
into the usual ed MUX from lux support
on the corresponding shelf no
provisioning support wise there's
nothing no additional support contracts
it's really you only have to plug it in
so if you do have any problems you're
going to pretty much just keep
troubleshooting the same gear that
you're used to troubleshooting and then
density wise the systems are very
modular so you can easily get from an 82
a 64 wave system and all it consists of
is you know just a 1u rackmount they can
usually hold 16 shells or 16 waves in a
shelf the only downside is if you your
gear doesn't support xfp optics and they
only support sfp+ right now there are no
widely available sfp+ DWDM optics so you
have to go the cwdm route
here's a actually picture here of how
you would configure this equipment wise
you can see the shelf on the left is the
line side fiber and then each one of the
individual fibers on the top is say
transmitted and the bottom is received
for the given wavelength if you buy a
higher end unit because it will be some
standard ones that don't give you
monitor force higher end units will
provide you with the monitor port
that'll give you additional capabilities
as far as by potentially using an EDF a
or the line side oir here's a quick
little sample topology I wanted to point
something out with this to you is that
since the shelves are pretty much unique
to one another if you have two pair of
fiber you could use the same color
optics in one chassis multiple times so
that you know that way it allows you to
have less sparing of optics because the
optics are a little pricey so this way
you would have you know two of one
wavelength to of another and that way
you don't have to waste money on you
know having four different colors and
four different spares a little bit of
information on the optics here just like
the tangoga lrx FPS they have pretty
much the same reach availability so you
know they say 10 kilometers but in
optimal conditions you can usually push
from 25 kilometers easily without any
kind of amplification you see the
wavelength is a higher wave of light
then just a standard lr optic uses the
same single mode fiber that you use you
probably already have in your fiber
plant so it's really easy to make the
transition and then you know the one way
to tell these out you can see in the
image here is the bottom optic is the x
SP optic and they usually have the
lever so one student shouldn't you use
passive DWDM while the first question is
do you have fibro that's readily
available you could push this light
across if not you may have to purchase
dark fiber between sites and that can be
a little expensive again you know you
have to kind of way it now if you do
need to buy the fiber is it worth buying
the shelf or shelfs that you need for
the capacity and then also the optics
you know depending on your vendor they
list at 10,000 but I mean realistically
you can get them from most vendors
between three and six so you know that's
another cost potentially and then in
other countries that like the European
Union that was talking with remco Metro
dark fiber is so cheap there that in
some instances it's not a worthwhile
venue to use this dark fiber and passive
DWDM plus your vendor may not have
optics that are supported only other
considerations if you need redundancy
this won't give it to you out of the box
so you have to duplicate your build out
there may be distance limitations where
you would be required to use EDF phase
if you were trying to go with a pure
passive system then it wouldn't
necessarily be truly passive port
available availability if you are going
to be you know creating a redundant
configuration you will meet you will
need double the ports on your gear and
that may not be available also you know
if your fiber gets cut you lose
everything whereas if you had an active
solution that may have a protected path
it would automatically switch over
another downside is you know the vendors
sometimes have a 12 plus week lead time
just to receive the optics so if it's a
rush thing and you need to get this up
you know you have to plan for it and
then without any kind of up active
equipment you won't get any oir from
this other than what the gear that
terminates the fiber on each end provide
you with
and just as far as the other reading go
razz had a good presentation back at
nana 48 just covering a lot of the
physical air stuff with the optics and
fiber so anyone have any questions okay
thank you
and while we're doing the transition
here i am asked to remind you all to
fill out the surveys so they serve a
survey that is your way of influencing
the program in the end the conference
next time calendar
yes
to use mine No
was gonna be here
sorry sue I can't find it yes
No
sorry sir
sorry about these guys
okay good afternoon my name's Linda
Dunbar here some presenting this joint
confirm button talk together with Sue
Harris down there so this is talking
about the network issues in the data
center on cloud data center and some
potentially has me this is actually
called this particular page the the
partition of the brick down the cost is
in the center we can see that in data
center today network itself is really
only fifteen percent of the total cost
majority of the cost I on servers power
consumption but network itself actually
create big barrier for the data centers
and guilty and flexibility as we heard
from the talk from before lunch we can
see that in order to enable host to be
moved anywhere in the data center and
they have to crack into servers changing
code so that enable the host like the
load balancer to across different part
of the data center so this is involve
the research paper they're saying that
Network email innovation is actually a
key to enable the data center
scalability and agility so network self
we don't have to make it so rigid to
confine the servers into certain
locations okay um why large layer 2 is
the problem and we see that in the talk
before that there to traditionally is
confined into a smaller domain and
because of the reading layer to the lots
of broadcast messages the broadcast
messages cause traffic penguin suit
realization and cause
the switches to handle the traffic so
well the biggest broadcast messages we
think they are chu is our messages so
the message itself basically servers and
hosts frequently sending all those are
requests in many servers and hosts the
behavior I'm very unpredictable so some
us anymore and some are sending less and
especially under some uncertain
environment like a software reboot or
virtual machine starting up sometimes
you want to start server virtual
machines depending on the application
from some of them sending a lot more
than others that's the primary reason
that we want to keep the layer 2 from
confined in this picture you can see
that traditionally in traditional they
are tuna a traditional data center
network that each layer 2 is confined
into a few switches for switch few
switch ports but for many of the energy
or resource aware algorithm they try to
minimize the number of servers being
used because the virtual machine
technology and server being virtualized
hosts can be created and deleted on
demand very easily and they can even be
moved from one location to another
location so by moving the host
consolidating them into confined
locations or any locations you can shut
down servers you can even shut down
switches so that can better utilize the
resource you have in data center so when
you want to move those Coast two
different aggregations with different
rags or different rows of them in the
data center the traditional way of
breaking a large network into smaller
subnets no longer work anymore because
the broadcast messages are sending
through the
the core part of network and switches
and links I exposed to broadcast
messages from different subnets so in
this case the OP messages will be
flowing into the corporate network okay
here is another issue of the are
problems in the network one virtual
machine moves my great some of the
migrations out of service migration so
during the transition there will be
other hosts sending the ARP requests and
without any response coming back and
then they were repeatedly sending those
requests causing more messages in the
network and one the vm moved to the new
location there will be grandchildren's
are being sending out so here just
talking about some possible ways to
refine the broadcast messages so that
broadcast message in traditional network
is confined to layer two are confined to
one subnet and he were talking about you
don't necessarily have to do that you
can combine two smaller location smaller
domain when the layer to spin across
multiple racks or multiple rows or you
can use director based approach which
can be centralized or distribute method
to do the art which is the like layer to
layer three can delude protocol okay
here just talking about why this is a
better but our main intent actually is
to create a new working group in IETF we
call arm d which is a address resolution
for massive number of hosts within the
data center so initially we try to
document the scalability of our and
indeed indeed for ipv6 with increasing
number of hosts in the data center
and and then if I limitation of those
protocols and provide design design
recommendation and how to minimize the
issue and secondly maybe phase two is
potentially develop some solutions to
better support data centers with large
number of hosts and with the desire of
letting host to be placed anywhere in
the network so that's and any questions
actually we are looking for feedbacks hi
hi i paid my er um have you considered I
mean I followed the army mailing list so
I got a pretty good idea of what's the
discussions about but if if you look in
the really large scaling scaling things
in really big data centers you can't
really broadcast anything so the reality
is you know anything that and this
includes things like dhcp so have you
considered have you considered the
possibility that art isn't the arp as we
know it today is not the answer to this
well we agreed that office now the only
problem when you allow hosts to be
placed anywhere in the network it's
definitely not the only problem but in
IETF every time they create a working
group they want a very small focused
working group that's why we drill down
to arp and ND is well the issue is not
that all the problem dhcp is another
issue too i would say that uh well the
art you know our scaling is one issue
via mobility is you know something
different so can be solved by arp in
some ways but agree um
okay so Dave you've suggested that that
two hairs they've you suggested that our
pen solve it in some ways and I think
what we're looking to see is what pieces
are can solve in the general situation
and in mobility it's clear that it can
solve some mobility problems it cannot
one of the first things we're doing is
looking at the actual statistics from
actual networks and we'd love to talk to
anyone as you just saw before lunch we
had Yahoo's facing the general problem
so I think our first thing is
information gathering that we can
publish and discuss we've had a lot of
private discussions but I think we're
trying to first hit public data that we
can debate and then go from there okay
just one point I want to emphasize is 44
problem in data center there are many
different approaches to solve it right
as we saw in the top by yahoo before
lunch their approaches to change DHCP
and change the server so allow them the
virtual IP to be on different location
that's the ultimate goal right allow
those holes to be anywhere in the
network and our approach it is slightly
starting from the network that they are
two layers three blue part and to make
them scale to allow that happen without
all those broadcast ages broadcast
messages floating in the links and
switches okay
thank you next we have
he doesn't
see more
can you make it big
oh yes hi i'm ken florence from netflix
and i'm going to talk to you about a
blog post we did we've gotten a bunch of
questions on it so i thought it might be
a good idea to stand up here and take
some more maybe so basically a couple of
days ago we posted on our tech blog some
information about what we see in terms
of netflix performance on various
networks and I'll what I'm going to do
is go through kind of how we do it why
we do it and and so a little more detail
on how it all works so what we do is all
of our streaming clients are either
written by us or based on an SDK that we
put out and in that SDK there's lots of
specifications about what we want to log
including a lot of performance
information and as we get those logs
back we capture the IP address from the
clients that were connected with and
assign an AS number to those IP
addresses and then using that we group
by Network and assign the performance
characteristics of the various networks
so basically the clients are talking to
a bunch of Netflix servers in the AWS
cloud those netflix servers then pass
along the logs to a Hadoop cluster that
doesn't map reduce on them that data
processed data is then piped back to our
data warehouse and our netflix data
centers and then we have some reporting
servers that can kind of slice and dice
it for us so why do we do this we're
kind of in this interesting position of
getting a tremendous amount of
long duration high-definition views so
really seeing what can be supported in
terms of sustained through put on these
various networks obviously we get a lot
of questions you know both anecdotally
and through many other means friends
about how performance works what does it
mean when they when their client clauses
etc we also get a lot of questions about
do we feel like any of the networks are
manipulating our traffic in any way and
so we felt like this would be a good way
to just kind of get some data out there
in public and you know we don't see any
evidence of that today and it also
obviously helps us understand how the
performance is changing over time and
and what we can expect as time goes on
so there's a lot of stuff we'd like to
do better here one way is to make a
slide with that many lines readable is a
little bit challenging so if anybody's
like particularly good Excel food that
they want to share on how to do that I'm
open for suggestion also we've gotten a
lot of comments about something that we
knew was going to be an issue when we
put out the chart I didn't have a good
answer which is AT&T and Verizon have
obviously a lot of dsl offerings most of
a lot of fiber offerings and since we're
doing this by a s number we don't have a
good way right now of splitting that out
so if anybody from either AT&T or
Verizon or anybody else has any good
ideas on how to help us do that you know
I guess we could figure out what IP
blocks are being used for what and try
and post process the data like to avoid
that if possible but anyway open for
input on that didn't get the message the
memo that embark and centurytel over
CenturyLink when it goes
so we've gotta fix that and and there's
lots of other interesting metrics we'd
like to look at every time we track
internally not only time-weighted bit
rate but read buffers how many buffers
per session our we get from clients
we're working on some possible composite
metrics but we've got a lot of
interesting data to carve through and
always looking at better ways to kind of
understand client performance and how we
can improve it only put four Canadian
ISPs on the original Canadian chart
because they were the four canadians
that fell in the list of top and a SS
that we're looking at we want to dig
deeper into that and then obviously
there's a lot more that we could do to
improve so here's the almost readable
chart any questions
when you send out an email that asks you
know how was your streaming experience
is that triggered by metrics you see or
is that prayer ly random it's it's
random it's basically we're just always
looking for people's input we found that
was a really good way to identify
streams that had encoding problems and
stuff like that so it's kind of a QA
think Russ anybody else ok we're done
thank you and next up is oh there's a
question 1 there's no mic at that end
anymore so I'm doing curly from google I
have a question about I know that a
number of VoIP sources have as well as
is p information they also break out
blocks by tier of service and have used
that if you have her happen what have
you experienced and you know we do yes I
think we do get that from our
geolocation I don't have that wired into
parse on yet but that's I haven't used
it so I couldn't speak to the
reliability of it what I recall is it's
at least the last time I looked at it
it's not that interesting it was kind of
like showed a couple of low tears and
then everything under to make over to
Meg's or something was high speed or
something I don't know enough to go back
and look at them okay thank you