I
as you want
where we talk about the business of
nanog as opposed to the technical
content the organizations that make
things happen and where we get a chance
to interact with the rest of the
community to figure out what we want to
be and where we should go from here
quick agenda I'll give a steering
committee report Dave Meyer will give a
program committee report somebody
hopefully will give a communications
committee report CQ marketing working
group Andy Rosen's leg will talk about
what's happening at merit and then we'll
get into the transition to new nog the
usual reminder this is a meeting for all
of us we want to dialogue rather than a
lecture please step up to the mics
you
first of all the steering committee are
the people with the blue badges who will
stand up if they're not already up here
and wave to everybody so you know who we
are we are the equivalent of a board of
directors and soon we will be a board of
directors so we conducted the business
aspects of of nanog Oh magic okay since
then at 50 we've been spending most of
our time working on the transition
planning to the new nod organization
taking over the merit I'm taking over
the net other activity from merit and of
course while do it now we've been
conducting the usual business of making
sure that we're ready for this meeting
and future meetings coming up after this
meeting we need to of course continue
planning for future meetings and we're
going to complete the transition of the
activity into new nog and we'll have
more details on that in the second batch
of slides later there's what's a mailing
lists that you can join if you feel like
it the top one of course is the main
list for network operations of
engineering it's part of the main reason
this group exists and then I features is
made a discussion about nano as an
entity that's where the dog just
discussions happen as well and there's a
whole bunch of other mailing lists and
if you're interested the pendulum next
up is Dave Meyer who will give us a
brief overview of what's been happening
with the program committee
and they will give his a talk from the
microphone if it turns out they're gone
okay I could do it from here because I'm
going to continue my tradition of not
having any slides to bore you with but
here's lists that program committee
members um you can find them by the
ribeye the yellow on their badge so
tracking these people down if you have
questions about how the program
committee operates I did want to say a
few things first off if you're a
newcomer make the newcomer breakfast
tomorrow morning that's always a good
time and secondly everybody remember
that nana gets about us and all of the
material we get we get from you guys so
start thinking about 52 now we need you
know it's it's a long time in a long
path usually to get the agenda but the
earlier would get the stuff the better
off we are so think about that okay
thanks Dave any questions for Dave if
I'm the perfect video for me on the
under steering committee for that matter
definitely track us down if you do have
questions yeah and while we're talking
don't be shy if you have something to
ask jump up a standard a microphone in a
skit next is a communications committee
report I was Mike Smith who is the chair
couldn't be here and I think he tried to
appoint a proxy to present for him but
if not I will read the email that he
sent since nobody's jumping up to the
phones here oh just a moment here
okay here is what Mike said about the
communications committee Communications
Committee is you don't already know is
responsible for the mailing lists and
other things also de minimis he says the
list continues on this usual
subscription levels remained essentially
unchanged it's around 10,000 people
three users had rebooked posting
privileges I guess since the last
meeting and one person was almost band
but the AUP process worked upcoming
changes beginning in March we will begin
the process of moving the website
admitting list over to nu nog we will do
everything we can to minimize downtime
and in fact if you are in charge of Gd
DNS details for your organization or
have access to those they do please
lower or please listen to the
announcements so what's in our records
so that when the transition happens
universes are live so quickly Middle
East structure will stay unchanged it
won't be necessary to reapply to their
nog list although there will be a
message sent before the transition
happens explaining that it's going to
happen so you have a chance to
unsubscribe a few for some reason the
feeling the need to then there will be
new list for new node members and if you
have any suggestions for changes or the
website talk to Mike or anyone on the
grease communications committee and they
will help you that paraphrased is what
he sent to his email and he also
apologizes for not being here and it
shows us that our weather is here is
much better than what he's having a sale
right now so any questions that I can't
answer because he's not here okay
here's the I should have put up I was
talking here's the list of people who
are in the communications committee I
want to personally thank them for doing
this it's pretty much a thankless job
acting as a mailing list police
essentially they only get noticed when
they have to sit on somebody for doing
the wrong thing yes all right CQ is the
chair of our marketing working group he
has a set of slides later in the new
knife section which cover both what's
been happening up through this meeting
what's going to be happening in the
future so it seemed easier to just to
combine the two so I will let him give
that part of it later but while we're
here this is the list of marketing
working group members again if you don't
know already the marketing working group
is responsible for seeking out sponsors
defining new sponsorship opportunities
beyond the classic fear in gear and some
of the tables that use the outside and
it's transitioning into what's going to
be called the development working group
in the you know you know Bergen ization
next step is Andy who will give us a
report on what's happening at merit at
the moment we want to start as always by
thanking the host of the meeting in this
case Terremark terremark now hosting
their fourth nanog meeting and always do
an excellent job and finding an
excellent venue and making us feel very
welcome here every man dog host has the
job of setting up network within the
location that they've selected providing
the electrical service that you see at
your tables in front of you providing
volunteers to help staff registration
and other duties the host often also
takes the opportunity to throw a party
for attendees and you will enjoy that
tomorrow evening following beer and here
so a big thank you to Josh snow horn and
his friends
many other contributors to this meeting
Aaron as always contributes funding to
help support the broadcast and archiving
of nanog meetings AT&T has provided the
network including the local loop and IP
service hurricane electric is providing
ipv6 service internet to has provided 10
wireless access point access points ji
net solutions has contributed three
juniper switches that will be survey
giveaways so each day of the meeting you
can complete a survey to let us know how
the meeting is going for you and if you
are selected you will eventually receive
in the mail a brand-new juniper switch
and tear mark in addition to hosting the
meeting has also sponsored the name tag
lanyards every nanog meeting also
benefits from the input of lots of
supportive sponsors he listed here are
the 10 sponsors of beer and gear
alcatel-lucent arbor networks caradin
Cisco fpl FiberNet Merritt are a TV
network hardware resale OSI hardware
PCCW global and subspace communications
the mirror gear sponsors also double as
the sponsors of morning breakfasts
thanks as well to the break sponsors
exceed ian networks loan app myriad
supply pacnet Prolexic technologies and
xk el thanks to all the sponsors of this
meeting while we're talking about nan
tout 51 i'll give some of the statistics
about who's with us at this meeting
these numbers are about three hours out
of date so they're a little bit
different now 503 total attendees is now
about 515 so that's very strong
attendance for februari me
of those 503 409 paid 94 wage for being
hosts or sponsors or speakers 153
newcomers pretty consistently we've been
giving about thirty percent first-time
attendees so if you see people who don't
quite know where they're going help them
out and welcome the newcomers seven
students are among us there are 26
countries represented which which
account for 92 attendees who are from
outside of the US and Canada as well as
33 US states plus District of Columbia I
want to acknowledge the merit network
team who look after all of the details
that go into putting a meeting like this
together with us here and then I'm 51
are Larry Blanc David Gilbertson sue
Joyner don khon Carol wadsworth and Mike
sawaki and joining us as well from
Davenport University in grand rapids
michigan it is Pete Huff's well as well
as fond Kalin from Western Michigan
University let's give them a hand
I can also do recap of nanog 50 which
was in October in Atlanta we had 470
total attendees 357 paid 113 waived 133
newcomers again about thirty percent 13
students 21 countries 32 US states so we
are indeed coming from all over a very
positive financial result from that
meeting revenue of 346 expenses of about
320 so a bottom line of about twenty six
thousand dollars that the result of
strong attendance strong sponsorship and
lower hosting costs than you might find
in some other cities so an excellent
result there that's the end of my
comments okay funny how we don't get up
and grill him when there's a surplus
only when there's a deficit okay now
we're going to move on to the new mug
transition portion of the meeting first
of all is anybody out there who has not
yet heard the word nu nog oh good okay
so we've been working on this now for
close to a year the transition is pretty
much in its last stages and will be
complete by the time we show up for now
on 52 in Denver will give a report of
what we've been up to we're going to do
next so since our last meeting we've
been pretty busy in October we started
our search for an executive director we
put out bids for venues for 90 x 54 and
55 which are the first two meetings in
2012 i believe we held elections during
which the concept of nu nog was ratified
and a set of bylaws was adopted and we
adopted a budget in november we did most
of the work in the executive director
selection process including starting
interviewing people and we worked on the
contract with
for handling all the logistics for the
next meeting in Denver which is good
news because it means that you'll show
up in Denver and things will look
substantially like they do here things
will actually work we expect them to so
thanks to merit and the people who on
the new exciting to help negotiate I'm
successful in degree meant to do that in
December we executed that contract we
signed a contract for now 54 which is
the meeting a year from now in San Diego
and we started putting out bids for a
venue for 56 we adopted the sponsorship
model which is we'll get into more
detail during CQ section so I don't need
to go into it and we adopted a
membership structure now you can join
new nog you can pay your hundred dollars
and be a member which gives you blooding
privileges and the ability to say I'm
part of this January a big significant
thing that happened in January we hired
an executive director Betty could you
stand up from who would please Betty
Burke is our executive director she's a
full voting member of the board as well
so we look forward to working with Betty
for the 18 months of her contract and
and and making sure that things actually
happened we now have six board members
who think about stuff and one person who
actually makes it I'll half of it it
really shouldn't work that way but you
never know Betty is full-time working
for us this is her job and we know that
with her will be very successful we met
with a merit silvie and i traveled to
ann arbor enjoyed some decent weather
for michigan and add a really successful
meeting we agreed that we're going to
take ownership of the two servers that
host the mailing list in net org we're
going to take ownership of the router
that all your traffic is going through
right now those have been used
exclusively for net on projects for
years so makes sense we worked on
planning transition steps how to move
the data how to get everything over
don't see it mentioned here skip ahead
one slide to make sure actually no a
large part of the meeting was talking
about an intellectual property agreement
to transfer the nanog trademark and all
the associated content that goes around
it we came to informal agreement on that
so that transfer will happen we expect
subject only to the lawyers reviewing it
at this point I think so keep your
fingers crossed that the lawyers don't
say anything we don't want we've
confirmed to diamond level sponsors this
is big it actually gives us a large
cushion of cash that we can use to pay
deposits on future hotel contracts
and otherwise operate the the
corporation of new nog which we need
will start getting revenues and we won
our first meeting soon but until then we
needed a reserve to work from and these
two sponsorships will give us the base
basis for that it's not to say that
we're not welcoming more sponsors but
the first two really is it is a big big
turning point for us um ok I'm going to
now let's Sylvie who's our Vice Chair
give the rest of the slides since she
wants to get up and talk to so as T said
our next steps which is a big milestone
but it's coming in the next few few
weeks is to sign the agreement with
merit with the assignment of new nano
materials and marks so which means that
the Nano name and the mark will now be
transferred over to nu nog all the Nano
Gorgon piscina org the web the website
content the underlying programming the
meeting archives will also be
transferred over so these are really big
steps and it takes a lot of coordination
so big task ahead of us all the mailing
lists and its contents will also be
transferred over we're also finalizing
our financial controls policy which will
be adopted probably early februari so in
terms of next activities the big task
ahead of us are we're putting out an RFP
for this association in the conference
management the RFP will be issued in the
week of februari seven so right after
this na nóg the proposals will be due
in three weeks then we'll have an
initial screening will have until march
seven to screen all the proposals will
have to do due diligence two weeks after
that make a recommendation of one or
more
ender's to the board of directors then
start the selection and a negotiation of
contract and then establish the
transition process for main night so as
you can tell we're trying to do all of
this before nana 52 happens and we'll
start the formal operation start date at
june thirtieth so after the close of
nanog 52 marketing and development
update kriska Sanofi's so will be
transitioning the marketing working
group into the development working group
and what the marketing working group did
ha was basically promote sponsorship
through each of the nanos in San
Francisco we promoted well actually from
Austin to San Francisco we promoted
attendance and in San Francisco we also
took a initial step of meeting with our
sponsors and having the meet with the
sponsor of the next nanog this actually
worked out very well for us and as you
can see it planted turned out to be very
very profitable for us as well in
Atlanta we pretty much took the same
steps to promote and move that forward
here into miami and miami we're not
going to stop there and we'll keep on
moving but we will change the name and
Google functions will change too so the
new nog development working group like I
said will continue we continue to
proactively seek sponsors but we're also
be developing new sponsorship programs
and promoting a vent awareness outside
of our normal attendees one of the
things that we will also be looking for
is opportunities to join the development
work
and you know here's your opportunity to
join one of our hard working groups
within nu nog for the benefit of nanog
our sponsorship levels was one of the
things that we added this is a
guaranteed sponsorship for the event
year meaning that we are basically
taking our sponsors and most of them
that come to all of our events in a year
and asking them to join one of our
programs to where they commit to all
three events of prime our sponsorship
levels go from bronze silver gold and up
to diamond the new sponsorship
opportunities and benefits that we've
added the nog lab basically allows us to
explore new sponsorship opportunities
and we definitely want you to go out
there and you can benefit to us by
promoting to your marketing departments
you know opportunities here at nano so
to talk about our two sponsors the
diamond sponsors that we got for the
2011-2012 calendar year Google and NTT
America most graciously joined our
diamond sponsor program
so you so you understand our levels of
sponsorship our diamond program starts
at 75 k so we were very happy to have
those two sponsors join with us and
finding it someday hello hello I'm a
Duane I'm the new nog treasurer so have
a few slides with some dollar signs and
numbers on them as of the end of 2010
our income was just under 13 thousand
dollars those were all donations most
mostly individual donations our expenses
were just under six thousand most of
that was a deposit on a hotel for nanog
52 and some fees for applying for the
nonprofit status there's a breakdown of
donations received to date or actually
as of a few days ago 11 corporate
donation in the amount of a thousand
dollars in the rest individual donations
as shown there it wasn't exactly nine
cents but it but it did end with nine
cents yes I'll be happy to talk to you
that talk to you about that privately I
guess III did not get to the bottom of
that and as of a couple weeks ago we
began accepting memberships and these
numbers represent our memberships as of
again but two or three days ago and
since then since then I'm happy to say
this is about doubled so we've had a
number of people sign up today and a
couple yesterday so we're on the order
of about fifteen sixteen members right
now
here are our account balances as of a
few days ago and the in the sort of the
main operating account a little over
seven thousand dollars and in our
account that has the loan from Erin you
see that over there 21,000 I believe
this is my last slide so thank you very
much so now to make sure that naina
continues some update on the next
conferences so Nanak 52 will be hosted
by alcatel-lucent in Denver we also have
none of 53 joint with Aaron hosted by
Comcast and held in Philadelphia we have
a hotel contracted for Nanak 5554 it's
only a year away in San Diego februari
52 d 8 and the host still to be
announced Nanak 55 is in progress and
nanog 56 and with Aaron is also in
progress so two years out are planned so
what can you do so you can become a
member of this new organization today go
pay your dues at noon org and that gives
you the privilege of voting in annual
elections this new system is more
inclusive and previously if you remember
to vote in our elections previously you
had to have attended one nano meeting
now you can be a member of the mailing
list and have the same voting privilege
you can you need to be a member to serve
on a committee and you also get a
discount on your conference registration
fee what else can you do you can prepare
talk for an upcoming nanog you can
motivate your organization to sponsor
Chris I'll play a great plan you can
talk to Chris and the
Marketing working group and look at all
the options that are available you can
also consider standing in the fall
elections look at your time commitment
there are many openings and any
volunteering idea that you might have
comment talk to that er a new executive
director thank you that's the end of our
prepared slides despite off well as once
again if there are any questions or
comments or anybody want to throw food
at us or anything what drinks young no
all right then this is a nice big
non-controversial meeting the kind that
I like thank you very much and enjoy the
rest of it on