I
alright good afternoon everyone and
welcome
sure if you stayed out real late last
night
we're getting started now with a nice
talk on the lac nog thank you I hope you
enjoyed lunch my name is Christian
flirty I work for the Internet Society
i'm here with a couple of colleagues one
from latnok a torah you probably met him
during one of the bach meetings and
eduardo from nick dr we are all involved
in what we call lagna which is bouton
meeting and mailing list it's like like
a community as an analyst but for South
America Central America and the
Caribbean so if you are interested in
any of these countries and the internet
businesses and operations there then
probably you will be interested in our
project which is lag nog we already had
a meeting last year it was announced by
the way on the previous nano meeting
which was in 15 annual meeting like my
stone for you and also for us which
there we announced our first lag
Nachtmusik meeting week we took place in
Brazil last year knocked over with it in
Sao Paulo actually it wasn't in the in
the city it was far away from the city
near the airport and we there
because it was free of charge and we
wanted people really committed and
interested in the in the event to make
the effort to go there so during the
week there were three main meetings that
during the whole week one was the lad no
rain it took two days there one was the
the lag Nick Public Policy Forum which
was the second in the year it's the
first time we had to public forums like
the Aaron but for our region so the
second one place during the lagna week
and also the PTT forum which is an
Brazilian meeting for
traffic is changed and basically a
owners of alias numbers there soberly
and what is going to tell you more about
up shortly we've got a very good
attendance at that time more than 300
people during the week actually there
were like five hundred persisted none of
them were there at the any one time
there were more than 200 participants
and on all meetings they were
representing 24 countries this is the
geographical distribution of the
participants we created a prom committee
with representatives from organisations
vendors and service providers in the
region we wanted them the more
represented we are still working that
the same group is going to be involved
in the future lugnut meeting here are
some pictures that we took during the
event and that small social the social
wasn't as nice as ours yesterday but it
was a good one we will try to make a big
effort for the next one and yes it's
going to try our best yeah we will try
we will try so what about the next one
we are working in two events for 2011
actually it's going to be a short one
we'll call it a session during the lagna
quick the lagoon unique week is going to
take place in May in Cancun Mexico so
during this week there's going to be a
lag noqday session we are not going to
make call for presentation for this
session is just going to be a panel and
there we will launch the cultural
presentation we launched a the group the
code prom committee for the next one the
big one which is going to be in October
the week before the nano meeting so for
all of you interested in in in the
region you can you'll probably have
direct flights flights from from
Santiago if we make it our own Osiris to
actually from there are no flights from
Buenos Aires to Philadelphia but it's
not going to be hard to attend both so
this is going to be an October the third
and we will be announcing the different
dates on the mailing list for the
cultural presentations and and the
agenda and when we open the
registrations so all of you are welcome
to to participate on the mailing list of
course to participate on on the meeting
and and if any of you would like to add
something the presentations they can be
if you want to present it normally we
speak there in Spanish or Portuguese but
the presentation can be in any of those
well it can be in any language in fact
so we have a translation services there
so you want to present you don't have to
present in Spanish of Port wheel you can
presenting English there were there were
many many presentations during the past
event in English and there are many
participants on the list that are using
English and all of us can easily
understand so you've feel free to to
participate in whatever language you
want like a tip mark I just want to say
I've given a couple presentations at lac
neck and for those who are would be
worried about the language barriers if
your Spanish is rusty or whatever of it
it's it's extremely friendly to non
native Spanish speakers so I wouldn't
consider that to be a barrier in any way
whatsoever thank you
hi my name is Eduardo from the night CDR
I'm directly involved in the internet
exchange point proven in Brazil called
BTT Metro the event that Christian told
is called ATT 40 in the form is an
annual event this year will take place
in the end of november Souter in
November and first December if anyone
has interested in genetics chain in in
Brazil Latin America please join the
purine tracking will probably do a brief
presentation about the project or even
come to me the rattle here thanks and we
are also having to we are also
organising a day for traffic exchange
discussions during the lag Nick meet
meeting in May so both appearing and
traffic exchange issues and in general
operational issues are going to be
covered in that meeting so you're all of
you are invited for to both meetings so
feel free to contact us if you need
additional details or information about
them so thank you very much any question
thank you
thanks a lot that sounds real
interesting if you're doing business in
the black Nick region Argentina Chile in
October she's over number two
just
hi I'm manish from the research group at
Merrit and what i want to talk about
today very briefly is some traffic
analysis we've done on recently
allocated well recently as of three
months ago allocated /e blocks in
particular here's the framework that we
use for a darknet collection and
analysis so what we do is we work with
the rirs go ahead and get their
permission to advertise and collect this
data and then at the tail end of it what
our purpose is to make this data
available to the research community but
for the rirs in particular what we want
to do is make recommendations on what
they can do to watch out for potential
hot spot activity that or areas of the
address space that that they should stay
away from are not allocate to customers
so roughly our goal is analyzed the data
determine how much and what kinds of
pollution there is and whether there's
hope for cleanup or simply to quarantine
those those blocks and not not hand them
out in this particular study and I'm
calling this part two because I've done
one of these earlier on a different set
of blocks we were looking at six / aids
and we collected several data sets the
data set that I'll be just describing
the analysis on today consists of one
set of 3 / aids which were announced
simultaneously and then the other three
were announced at different different
kind time frames there's another data
set that was collected 47 contiguous
days of all 6 /a announcements so if you
saw if you were watching the the
Internet routing cable you would have
been very very amused to see such large
announcements suddenly appear so here's
here's a comparison of the traffic
volumes that we're seeing in these /
aids the 37 the 45 and 100 on top were
the ones that were announced
simultaneously and what is really cool
about about the analysis of about this
data this time is that we're actually
able to see simultaneous activity in all
three blocks and those spikes that
you're seeing there were essentially we
analyzed them a little bit more dug in
and those were backscatter from what we
think is
denial-of-service attacks for the DNS
servers we're trying to confirm some of
this with the with the folks at verisign
the bottom three graphs are the ones
that were the disjoint announcements and
what you're seeing there across most of
them is that the traffic ones are fairly
consistent except for the 5 / 8 now the
5 / it was a surprise for us in this
whole study the 5 / 8 is almost or it's
it's much more polluted than than
anything else we've seen well as as long
as you don't include the one /a your
scene speaks up as much as 250 megabits
per second of traffic and most of it as
it turns out is headed towards you know
easily memorized about human human
understandable addresses like five dot
five dot 505 and large bursts of UDP
streams essentially targeted for those
addresses another surprise in this study
for us was the 45 / 8 now this one is
actually reclaim space and reallocated
we expected to see all sites all sorts
of stuff in there but we found exactly
the opposite it was one of the cleaner
blocks so this was a very surprising
thing because 45 / 8 has been the
interop address space and to see it
surprisingly clean was was very
interesting so let's dig in a little bit
more our purpose here once again was to
find hot spots and figure out what we
can do to contain the damage the hot
spot these graphs are the six graphs
comparing the CDF function of the
destination / 24 address space so if you
see a straight line what that means as
the address is uniformly distributed
across the entire space there are no hot
spots if you see a curve it means that
the there's very strong hot spot
activity that means a few of the / 24 s
are accounting for larger than their
fair share of traffic as you can see the
45 and the in the 105 right in the
middle are relatively flat the only
thing you see is the kink in the middle
and that kink me know what would the
cause for that is that's basically the
caused by the configure there's a bias
in the way configure worm targets or
scans for other potential targets so we
know that kink and if you though if you
take the factor out that kink the
traffic is relatively uniformly district
across those blocks the five slash it on
the other hand you see very strong curve
very strong hot spotting 23 / 8 the same
thing and 37 / 800 / e as well once
again in 100 / 8 it's human human
memorize herbal addresses we see a lot
of packets going to 100 100 100 100 but
let's do some interesting case studies
very quickly so in the 37 /a this was
very interesting now here you would
think it's not one of those easy ones
it's not one dot one dot one that one so
why would you see such strong hotspot of
activity so you're looking at two graphs
here one is a top 10 destinations / 16
destinations within the 37 / a and the
graph on the right is what / 24 s and
what you see not only is a single / 16
accounting for the bulk of the traffic
but it's a single / 24 within that 16
that's accounting for most of this
traffic so we dug in a little bit more
this is the distribution by port of how
much traffic we're saying destination
port port 80 was very prominent in this
traffic and what we found was when we
figured out so we when we analyze a
traffic by hand we found all of it was
going to a single IP address and that IP
address as it as it as we found out was
quoted in a blog entry as being one of
the the IP addresses are used for fake
responses for blocking our Facebook
that's the so a single IP address is
causing this enormous spike in traffic
for unused address space the 23 / 8 once
again we see very strong hot spot
activity if you look at this / 24
distribution a single / 24 is accounting
for most of the traffic and when we
slice it more once again it's a single
IP address that's accounting for most of
the traffic the UDP destination port for
that traffic is 3100 source port 21 09
it's a single UDP stream well what is it
as it turns out we took all that scream
out you know try to extract something
out of it and turned out to be a video
stream and we said okay well that's
interesting what was sending video 22
darknet
we decoded it and it turned out to be
1080p video hmm video going to the
darknet nope it's not porn unless you
really weird it was actually a you know
copyrighted video so i probably
shouldn't play too much of it
essentially movie streams from from
animal planet and we you know in this
case once again we know that somebody's
sending this traffic out there to
misconfigured and they don't know that
they're streaming HD quality video into
nowhere once again very good candidate
for cleanup we could probably track this
person down 100 on the other hand is an
odd case it's one of the ones that you
that makes you scratch your head because
it's got a little bit of everything the
there's very strong hot spotting
activity as you can see once again and
the distributions are fairly high and
they don't don't drop off as rapidly you
can see / 16 distribution on the left
and / 24 traffic volumes on the right
and once again 100 100 100 is the
biggest culprit by far but the others
are also not not not insignificant and
and you know the distribution by port
numbers is also not very clear we see
some port 445 activity which is
configure once again some activity on
1640 we don't really know what that is
UDP of course has source source
destination ports 10,000 161 we know
what that is that's SNMP misconfigured
somewhere 53 DNS backscatter so it's got
a little bit of everything going on yeah
so we're still you know we've only made
one pass of analysis through the data
all we know is 100 / 8 is definitely
interesting it's got all kinds of stuff
we don't know the details about them yet
5 / 8 turns out to be an interesting one
and we were a little surprised by this
but I think once again it's largely
because of the five numbers very easy
for humans to type and remember and the
kinds of traffic we're seeing in here
are once again huge spikes we don't know
what the source of those spikes are the
source IP is very the the
the rent the port numbers vary but
they're all 250 byte packets and they're
all zeros we don't know we're not sure
ICMP six traffic interestingly very very
large volumes of icmpv6 traffic so if
anybody wants to know where ipv6 is
going to catch on while probably dark
net and and some other interesting of
flash video clips which you have which
we haven't decoded yet so no more no
more video clips moving very quickly to
the other / aids 105 fairly flat very
uninteresting it's interesting to note
that the volumes that I've been using on
these graphs on the left right there's
this number right here is 14 gigabytes
for the other graphs this was of the
order of 200 300 500 so both 105 and the
45 are orders of magnitude more quiet
than the others very little of interest
in terms of analyzing them we see
consistent patterns for 445 for
configure for UDP port 53 4 dns
backscatter and you know same thing
across 45 so to conclude very quickly
once again we're finding that pollution
tends to be he tends to greatly skew
dark net traffic activity different
darknets can have different reasons for
being polluted but you're starting to
get a feel for what basic baseline dark
net traffic looks like you know it's
going to be about 15 to 30 megabits per
second of base traffic spiking
occasionally 270 megabits per second
maybe 200 megabits per second depending
on what's going on heavily dominated by
configure for for tcp and heavily
dominated by a DNS backscatter for UDP
traffic we're sharing our results with
the relevant IRR IRS so that they can
make appropriate decisions about what to
do regarding cleanup or quarantine and
in conclusion here's the list of
specific / 24 s that we think deserve
particular attention from this batch of
analysis once again the 45 on the 105
are relatively relatively good but the
others we've highlighted with what the
key 24s are
see questions
Jared
uh I've done some analysis of a few
different people who've been doing sip
scanning and going and actually try to
initially initiate fraudulent phone
calls and there's there's a couple of
instances where I've seen the RTP media
set to be essentially what's a dark or
dark net IP address either one dot one
dot one dot one or 12 23 24 and
obviously you're seeing people sending
RTP media there as well did you look for
any of these RTP streams that look like
g.711 you allow or or whatnot or did you
encounter that very often and no I think
those were not standing out as obviously
as they were in the 1 / 8 i'm sure if we
were to look a little bit finer you know
a little bit deeper we'd probably find
it there so yeah you can we can take
another pass of that okay yeah boy what
I found is these are people who are
calling some fraudulent number in order
to rack up you know the premium toll
charges or whatnot and then they just
send the RTP media to somebody to
basically be discarded it or what not to
sell something to look for thanks really
just a comment as opposed to a question
i'm brandon ross and i'll speak with my
interop net volunteer hat on the 45 / 8
net I was shocked and surprised you
found to be relatively clean because for
many many years we've went setting up
the show we would announce the 45 / 8
out of OCT one or something on that
order of size and crush it with all the
background crap going to it but we never
I never other people have I've never
actually did any real analysis of what
was there so I found the comparison of
the other slide shakes fact that it
being cleaned to be shocking well its
comparative right so when I say clean
we're still talking about 15 to 30
megabits per second so with a t1 and
that's and that is consistent with what
we would see it usually it seemed to
average out around 2025 big Muslims
great thanks
I don't know Winston sorry
just wanna get off the slide
next up Jim cali for Renesys talking
about the egyptian internet connections
right now there yo Jim Thanks how is
this again control l have this issue
alright thanks I've seen fuzzier even
the normal it's because I have not
gotten a lot of sleep last five days and
it's because of this so Egypt left the
internet let's start off I've asked a
couple of friends to donate some slides
here to help us tell this tale Craig was
good enough to give me the arbor Atlas
data that shows you what traffic
normally looks like this is really the
very first sign of something well this
is what traffic normally looks like you
get these nice spikes diurnal traffic
patterns you're doing 12 13 gigs a day
in your easily doing a gig or so out and
of course on Friday last everything goes
away drops down to ultimately tens of
Meg's not a lot of traffic left headed
for Egyptian prefixes so thanks to arbor
for that data what happened well you
know from reading the paper what
happened basically what we saw was
shortly after midnight Friday over the
space of about a bad 20 minutes each of
the major Egyptian providers pulled
their routes they went from
approximately 3500 routes many of which
were little D aggregates down to about
maybe 150 in the space of twenty minutes
now global bgb convergence as you know
takes about 30 seconds maybe at the
outside it takes 60 seconds I'll show
you that these came in waves and they
were longer than that apart so it's
tends to suggest that there isn't one
big kill switch its individual providers
in sequence leaving the net Miriam you
want to take a look so I'll just jump in
here to them show you what you've done
them at the ripe NCC the URL on top also
has some life updated I'm graphs so you
can follow you know what's going on at
the moment dear and these graphs look
very empty but this is a snapshot of
what happens during that dead time under
27th 28th of January on top and we look
at the prefixes that were allocated to
Egypt by a fennec and look
announcements and withdrawals and can
clearly see how hard stops there on top
and at the bottom graph you can see the
number of renounce prefixes and dropping
at the same time so I'm yeah that's
quite impressive image I think and yeah
go to the website and you can follow you
know how to continue can take over again
so it's important to get this data from
as many independent perspectives as
possible because you know any one of us
could have blown this analysis so what
happened I mean back to the Renesys data
take a look at the ipv4 space as its
laid out so we've made a big heat map
here using the Hilbert curve layout that
you've seen XKCD and elsewhere thanks to
the measurement factory for the software
so the grey blocks are routed the black
box blocks here unrounded space even
though the internet is now full and the
orange little dots you see towards the
middle there are Egypt and so if you
look before and after using the same map
you zoom in on the afro neck allocations
and you can see the orange blocks that
Egypt previously had just gone just
vanished so as I said before it doesn't
suggest a kill switch or I've heard
stories that all the infrastructure goes
through a single piece of hardware it
doesn't look the case to me if you look
through this and will show you an
animation at the end that that calls
this out even a little more clearly but
these people are leaving the internet a
couple minutes apart up to several
minutes apart and it doesn't look like
it looks like sort of human phone call
time skill it's interesting because if
you go back before hand you look for
signs of congestion these are traceroute
Layton sees for our monitoring from New
York into all Egyptian prefixes and you
see that basically Layton sees were
pretty stable up until the point where
we couldn't do anymore Trace routes to
most of the prefixes in Egypt so you
don't see signs that the Egyptian
government was doing what I Ron did for
example after their election which was
throttling and congesting on purpose
it's interesting as a side note to look
at the same view from the inside here's
our Cairo machine trace routing to
everything in Egypt and you know what it
still takes 180 milliseconds of the 50th
percentile mostly because the state of
peering there as elsewhere is pretty bad
and
traffic goes to London and comes back so
what was left after the event well there
were several sources available and we
have tried not to identify all of them
to graphically to the media we will show
you the one that everybody knows about
um traffic did continue to flow by so we
here at sort of minimal levels there are
still some routes left even though the
routing is up routing is necessary but
not sufficient for connectivity lots of
the trace routes that you'll do inbound
to the remaining surviving prefixes will
die on the sea bone at Palermo there's
lots and lots of sites in Egypt that are
reachable perhaps but they don't you
can't get there because they have dns
issues as an example you know you could
still get to the stock exchange until
before yesterday but the institution
that does their trade settlement was
down so at some point you know the
internet connected economy falls below
the critical threshold where you can
actually do business ironically some
ipv6 actually stayed up is where a lot
of these were internet to piers carrying
ipv6 routes so if you kind of multiply
internet two times ipv6 I think nobody
really noticed that they were still up
here's the one that was sort of became
well known after the NGP mon folks named
them in the initial post which was the
newer group nor a group of course didn't
go down until yesterday no group is
interesting when we think that the
reason they may have been left on line
is because they have a lot of great
customers including the people I talked
about before in the financial industry
also includes the commercial
international bank of egypt and the
egyptian credit bureau a few others so
status today about 75 prefix is still up
but they really don't trace I don't know
that there's a lot going on interesting
when you telecom Egypt actually has some
Jordanian customers is about eight
prefixes for Jordanian space and we
don't know if that's co-located in Egypt
or if its terrestrial but that stuff is
still online this was very much an
Egyptian event this doesn't look at all
like the
Gyptian cable cuts that we've studied
before as you've seen in previous years
when we've done our reports on cable
cuts you see lots of different countries
downstream people who are trying to get
by on seemingly three and foreign flag
and it's it's a broad spectrum event
this was obviously very specific event
only Egyptian prefixes down we are
monitoring everything that's going on to
see if anything else becomes unstable
and just before I came up CNN was
announcing that Hosny Mubarak will no
longer stand for re-election we'll do a
quick visualization here as promised
this is at something that guys back in
New Hampshire cooked up it's at 60 times
real-time speed playback so one second
per minute we're going to show you what
we call a piecewise Hilbert curve become
clear in a second depicting the actual
prefixes that Egypt had and then they
will flash white as they are withdrawn
and fade to black this is the still and
let's get out here this is why they say
don't do this in the main session
good
alright fingers crossed okay time is
scanning through at the bottom from left
to right riya telecom in blue etisalat
and green link egypt in red te and green
will do this again in a second internet
egypt in pink and everybody else is in
gray at the bottom and you see the
blocks now flashing as we roll past 20
to 30 UTC which is just past 12 midnight
30 cairo time and that's it that's it
everything is now left you see a little
dust at the bottom which is the newer
group and a couple of other small blocks
so the first this is again staggered
sequence so te is the incumbent they
lead right off and they go out raya goes
a full minute later link egypt four
minutes later right so this doesn't snow
like one piece of equipment or 11
instantaneous push button etisalat takes
themselves out two minutes later and you
can see that everybody still has a
little bit of space left it's a sort of
a gradual take down internet egypt goes
six minutes later and now we're really
getting down into the bottoming out part
of this curve it's almost like watching
soap bubbles pop as the morse as the
less specific skill a leading the more
specifics they're tiny they're gone and
that's the end of the story so that's it
thanks very much