I
so if most of you probably seen it by
now but if not there was a press release
that went out a couple weeks ago got
some exciting times coming for us in
June where some of the large players are
going to be publishing their quad-a
records for their main ww site for a day
to see kind of keep track and see what
is going to break and make sure that
we're all ready for when we actually are
forced to run all of our websites
dual-stack so with that he's going for
Phil ok let me introduce Phil from the
internet society thank you thanks
everybody for coming we're excited to
talk about
open here
you folks
there we go there we go okay
do you do you have different thanks
again we're happy to be here to talk
about the world ipv6 day that will
happen on jun 8 of this year john
burroughs oski was planning to be here
but he was caught between doing a dual
stack rollout and some bad weather and
since his regrets we have Leslie dangle
from the internet society who is going
to be talking about the event overall
Igor Jasinski from yahoo is going to be
talking about why this is important for
them and Patrick Gilmore who will be
talking about why ipv6 is important for
them and what their strategy is we want
to do this as sort of three mini
sessions we've got 45 minutes I think
each of the speakers is going to spend
about 10 minutes and if you have
questions for any one of the speakers if
you would hold them for the end of that
but do it not for the end of the session
just for the end of who's speaking so
I'll hand it over to Leslie now thanks
Phil um and as Phil said I'm going to
give a bit of an overview of the day and
and why we care about it and why we
think you should too so it really is
June ate all of it in universal time at
which point major content providers have
agreed to turn on ipv6 on their front
doors not just on their side doors as
often is the case today it has nothing
to do with turning off ipv4 it really is
about an opportunity to both motivate
organizations across the internet
internet service providers carriers
content providers etc and users to
prepare themselves and their services
for for ipv6 and enix to ensure a
successful transition to an ipv4 an ipv4
ipv6 world it's really an opportunity to
collaborate to test writing
and it's really about laying the
groundwork for what we hope will be
large-scale long-term deployment of ipv6
I will note this is not a first it's
certainly the biggest so far but other
other entities in other parts of the
world have organized similar events so
we have a little bit of an idea of what
we're getting into so why we care about
it so the Internet Society we believe
that a best internet is one with
continued global addressing I think
everybody in this room understands
pretty well but if you want to have
continued global addressing ipv4 is not
the way of the future so v6 is where we
want to get to the point of having the
day and the point of why we're
supporting it is to help accelerate ipv6
deployment we believe that 2011 is going
to be a pivotal year for ipv6 deployment
not the least of which is because as of
this week we're running out of ipv4
addresses for reals and we think that
the world ipv6 day is going to be an
important milestone in that as well ipv6
has to work if we're going to exit 2011
into a future globally connected
internet and not just a network and it
must work not just technically it has to
work for businesses has to be business
viable and has to have a lot more
visible traffic and usage ultimately so
far everybody's known this at an
academic level understood it
hypothetically but it's been a bit of a
moving target to really try to say okay
this is the deadline by which I need to
get myself prepared or it's just been a
bit of a moving target it's going to be
much easier to set up and test your own
config in the light of a specific date
and it will be a lot easier to measure
actual impact of v4 v6 coexistence with
an event like this from our perspective
so what we have seen already since the
press release a couple of weeks ago
there's been lots of interest from all
over which is certainly good news we've
had interest from content providers
isps websites about 125 people entities
overall we are we have websites listed
on the official webpage for the day
we're creating space for sites who are
running dual staff already that is who
wish to be recognized for their efforts
and recognizes places you can go visit
if you are testing out your ipv6 and we
will be creating space as well for the
25 or so networks and hosting companies
who offer commercial v6 and who are
interested in helping their customers
participate so clearly there's interest
for them to get more customers but
interest for us to help direct people to
get the resources that they need there
are a lot of people around the globe who
are organizing their local region we
already have links in Japan and Slovenia
organizing local resources and planning
for material and information available
for the day itself so it's essentially
so far we've already had interest from
all over the globe so it really will be
a world ipv6 day so this is what we hope
to see on june eighth nothing it should
work right alright well okay we'll be
doing some measurement well people will
be doing some measurement in the
meantime if you want to test your ipv6
readiness you can test it out at test
ipv6 calm and we will be updating the
page to point to various activities that
are going to be various groups that are
going to be measuring what happens on
jun 8 measuring connectivity from
different perspectives brokenness etc
and
I believe Igor is going to talk a little
bit more about what kinds of brokenness
we're talking about measuring so here's
the URL for the actual website for the
day it's got information for what you
need to know if you want to come play
website owners what we're looking for is
the URL the website that you intend to
make available contact info for a
network engineer because although we do
hope it all works we still need to be
able to work this out collaboratively
and we're looking for web page
describing why ipv6 is important for you
and your business plans this isn't
exactly free advertising for your
website we really do want collaboration
here so stand up and you know raise your
voice for why ipv6 is important for
network operators and hosting companies
we're looking to see if you've got a
commercial ipv6 service offering and
again a web page describing why duty six
is important for your business so on and
so forth and we'll link to that the
website our website does contain a
little bit more information about what
you need to think through before you
stand up and decide that you want to be
visibly part of this because of course
you want to make sure that your networks
continue to work through the day so
certainly contact us if you're
interested in participating there's
contact info on that website contact us
if you're planning to do some
measurements or testing on the day we'd
certainly like to know about that and
help coordinate that as well and
certainly the main players that we
announce to the at the beginning of this
month our global companies with global
contents that happen to be largely
situated in the US we are definitely
looking for large content providers in
other regions of the world really help
us make this a truly a global ipv6 day
thanks any questions
this
ok so I'm eager with Yahoo and I'm going
to talk about our moment in ipv6 day and
a general content provider perspective
of it so first of all why are we doing
it we're doing to promote the ipv6
adoption we're doing it to show that
it's possible it's doable it should be
done and we're also trying to break the
chicken and egg paradigm except you
can't hear me basically we had a lot of
people going hey we want to turn off v6
we have you know we need content we're
going to you know for us to spend all
the effort into enabling v6 we need
actual users so we now have a date that
is set for and we want to have users and
we're going to have content this is also
last-ditch effort to break the broken
users problem there's a URL that you
can't see that well but it's there in
the slides it's a Aaron with you get a
pity sex info that list a lot of causes
of those broken users most of it is
operating systems thinking that there is
v6 when these sex isn't working in the
end user the current breakage stats are
about point O to six percent 18 months
ago the point O seven eight percent so
it's a huge improvement better while
that number seems very low and perfectly
acceptable point 0 to six percent for a
global content provider lucky ah who
translates to roughly 150 six thousand
users we fully expect that the 156,000
users will not be able to get to us well
on world ipv6 day and we're also one of
the reasons we're doing this is this is
the last ditch effort to remove the need
for white listing as long as the
breakage stats are above 0 point 0 1
percent there's absolutely no way that
we could go dual staff in a full
production scenario hopefully six months
awareness you know more things getting
fixed the numbers will drop enough and
if not perhaps there's going to be
enough press generated by world ipv6 day
and by users breaking that there will
actually get fixed and the other reason
for all that baby sucks day from a
content provider perspective is it
removes the first implemented penalty if
Google are the only ones to enable ipv6
or dual stack and nobody else's then
those 156,000 users will go up dub dub
your website com hmm not working
competitor Oh competitors working all
right i'll just use the competitor this
way hopefully all of us are part of all
that pd six-day the user goes yahoo com
well that's not working google de must
be off of google com that's not working
hmm that's funny let me go to facebook
and you know tell all my friends about
it wait facebook's not working too i
wonder if it's me and that's kind of why
I saw Oh has organized this so enough of
us are getting into this we want the
user to be aware that he has a problem
what we want the user to go nothing
happen awesome
so how does this affect a lot of people
while content providers first of all
please join this effort the level of
work for you may be minimal maybe a lot
depending on your architecture what
Yahoo is doing is we will be serving
dual stack for ww calm and all the
internationals forth that we can
relatively easily do it there are some
internationals where we will not be able
to offer dual stack due to country level
issues we doing this strictly for HTML
so images and ads are still going to be
served over before but at the very least
the first entry point is going to be
dual step if your content provider don't
forget to consider 64 in torino users
not doing so may cause a lot of extra
penalty in terms of latency not saying
do something about them just consider
your effects are and consider how you
can mitigate it and you may choose to
mitigate it you may choose not to
mitigate you may choose to mitigate 64
but not torito that's really your choice
but just think about it for isps out
there obviously please deploy v6 you may
want to step up your helpdesk on that
one day to deal with the broken users
and I'm going to plug test ipv6 calm one
more time it was written by Jason fesler
who is what my co-workers and it is a
great tool for end-user troubleshooting
and also for isps please think through
the impact of 64 in Torito in your
networks I know of at least one network
who didn't at first and all of a sudden
found that their balcony lotta traffic
across country to a certain Midwestern
university because they were choosing
their 64 relay if you don't know how to
deal with this the very nice kind folks
at hurricane electric are you know
always where's Martin Martin right there
he is always happy to talk to you about
it tell you what dishes you may run into
or whatnot for end-users please upgrade
and patch your systems it's amazing how
many things are fixed in the very latest
and greatest releases so please do so
and obviously for OS and software and
equipment vendors we've reported a lot
of bugs to you guys it would be the more
of them you address before world ipv6
day and get out to user the less users
are going to be effective so please
please please fix the issues and a lot
of them are documented on the wiki page
that I've linked it before so questions
bit more um Gator cool nice nice
presentation I'm wondering uh have you
guys considered putting up like sort of
an FAQ somewhere like I was thinking you
know what is it tests ipv6 com you know
I mean a lot of people probably like to
know about that and not everybody
actually watches the I know this would
be shocking thank you but not everybody
watches the video archive of you know
the plenary session in that I and that
kind of information would probably very
useful and maybe lighten up the load on
help desks if if you could put it out
there somewhere well my pretty you know
put a URL on that I got order something
we send the Jason send an email to the
Nanak mailing list about it the URL is
linked off I socks folder kt6 day if
nana wants to look kill it sweet please
there isn't faq on the website for the
day so if you want to look at it and see
if there are things that you think would
be useful to add we're happy to take it
and there is an FAQ on test ipv6 calm as
well
Igor Jared how are you doing so I'm so
because I'm wondering if I pv6 day goes
well what's what's the barrier threshold
for you from extending it from ipv6 day
to ipv6 two days or are you just going
to pull the plug after a day no matter
what we're going to pull the plug after
a day no matter what because we can't
measure brokenness while we're running
dual stuff so what we're actually hoping
to gain out of this is that's the day
before then stats the day after and see
if there's been a delta in the broken
user problem if the brokenness has
dropped below a certain threshold that
we have decided then there's nothing
stopping us if the brokenness is still
this high we will have no choice but to
do whitelisting ok i hope you review
that choice thank you
Jason shall enter verizon business you
know I have two questions for you you
are the first one is you talked about
the broken host problem have you looked
at the test ipv6 com site and do you
believe if that gives you a green light
response that you will not be affected
by the broken whose problem you
described there is I have a look at it
like I said the adjacent fesslers one of
my co-workers and a lot of the test
cases are actual things that we similar
methodology to how a lot of people
measure of brokenness there's only one
scenario that we found so far that that
website doesn't catch and we're not
quite sure how to measure it and that's
if you've configured a socks proxy on
your browser and socks proxies before
only we just have we haven't found a
good way to capture the test case every
other if you're not using proxies
configured in your browser that website
should capture everything else great
thank you my second question was you
talked about recommending times P they
think about the impact of using 624
tirado but you haven't talked about any
of the other transition technologies
it's more of 64 and Torito are it's not
using its of what that their users are
using it it's not dice p so much and you
know if the users are using tunnels to a
chi then there's not much that i
speaking you about it look at all the
transition technology i think
ninety-nine percent of transition
traffic is 64 into rita if i'm wrong
please let me know but just try not to
back hole the user all the way across
the country or possibly to another
continent
because you didn't think about something
for five minutes thank you
cool
now Patrick
why are there two optimizer I one's a
PDF it's actually much harder to see the
screen that it is that screen believe it
or not and the mouse is really fast I
know this will come as a shock to all of
you but I'm a little sleepy and my voice
is a little bed I'm sure no one here can
figure out why that is so my name is
Patrick Gilmore I work for a company
called akamai technologies we are CDN we
have almost no content of our own we do
have www me com which by the way has a
v6 bug on it so if you all go there we
can collect info on the nanog network or
something like that but very very few
people visit that however we have a
little bit of content from other people
so the problem with that is that we have
no agenda well we have an agenda but we
have no agenda that we can push because
our customers pay us to do certain
things so they tell us you know do v6 or
don't do v6 then that's what we're going
to do and we don't really get a much of
a voice in the decision we can suggest
things but we are a service provider we
don't get to decide what to do with you
know our customers own content we do
understand v6 is critical to the
Internet's future I know that sounds
like marketing speak but I actually
wrote that line because I believe it I
think it is critical which is sad but
true so we're working to make this
transition as seamless as possible for
our customers the idea is that the
customer should be able to just go
please v6 of 5 my webpage and then they
don't have to do anything so we're doing
lots of stuff like allowing them to keep
it before origin host and then we'll go
back well get see the caches / v 4 and
then serve the end users / v6 for
instance and things like that to make it
as seamless as possible and we're hoping
that will help a little bit of the hump
to get to v6 if people can just sort of
switch it on without doing anything
themselves um plus to be perfectly
honest I want to make
any off of it so um we agree that v six
days is necessary we've been you know
we've been an integral part of it from
late stages but you know long before the
press release we obviously want to see
what actually happens empirical data is
much much better than a lot of guesswork
and a lot of people out there right now
are guessing hey Igor has some stats or
yeah who has some stats and some you
know google has some stats and a few
others do but a lot of people are just
saying well we think this will happen
and so we'd like to actually see what
happens so we're here to support anybody
who wants to do v6 on the Akamai network
obviously is going to help them find fix
find in fix broken end users and the
chicken and egg problem the last two are
the big thing everybody talks about
chicken and egg oh we don't have enough
content on be 60 no users will be able t
60 we don't have enough users on b6
they'll be no content on v6 the reality
is that there'd be plenty of content on
v6 if they weren't broken end users
that's the real chicken and egg it's not
that there isn't any content on v6 is
that nobody wants to put their content
on v6 because you know Yahoo Google
Akamai ourselves we don't want to lose
you know a million dollars a day or
whatever for those hundred thousand
users that someone we disappear and then
clog our helpdesk lines so we're hoping
this will get us to a point where we can
go ahead and get past that huh so the
way Akamai is trying to do this is we
are trying to map both Internet's people
think of optimized a caching company but
what we really do is figure out which
web server goes to which end user um
there's two internets everybody here is
probably aware that v6 and before don't
look like it turns out I'm a few nights
ago I said that v6 looks like the v6 net
looks like Swiss cheese only it's the
holes not the cheese and it's getting
better but it actually still looks like
that we have some test data Akamai has
served v6 traffic and we looked at it
and we took for instance a little under
10,000 name servers picked randomly in
the United States and decided when they
would ask for a hostname we would give
them a v6 a quad a instead of
a and see what would happen on our on
our test Network not on customer stuff
um the latency was nearly double I
actually had to bring up my iPad so I
could have the actual members latency
was forty eight milliseconds for v4 and
eighty seven milliseconds for v6 I don't
know how many of you actually used
Akamai but nobody pays Akamai just slow
stuff down that's just not what they're
trying to do on of the Akamai network
and it's not what we're trying to do
either but that's a huge huge slow down
and if you look at the tunnels it's even
worse and a lot of people go why are you
measuring tunnels well we like I said we
have a web bug on Akamai com which I
admit fully admit there's a little bit
of selection bias there but you know we
get some hits on it eighty nine point
four percent that's almost ninety
percent of all v6 users coming to the
Akamai website are through tunnels I
mean there's essentially no one whose
native I mean ten percent ten point six
percent is just not worth talking about
so until we get these problems solved
until we can you know either get tunnels
in every single poppin you know
everywhere or if we can get more native
v6 then there's going to be these
adoption hurdles people don't want their
website to slow down to dot v6 this is a
problem so what Akamai's planning to do
is we're going to go ahead and map both
internets we're going to see how fast
the v6 is how fast the v4 is and when
somebody comes to us first we you know
we're going to have technology to figure
out if they're v6 enabled if they're not
obviously they get a fee for a dress
that's easy if they are then we'll do a
measurement and we'll figure out okay
we'll v4b has revealed will be six be
faster so I'm having trouble talking
can't imagine why but we'll hand out the
one that's faster and will let customers
have a knob to figure that out Oh a v6
is within ten percent go ahead and hand
out v6 or something like that so we are
trying to do everything we can to push
this along and give the customers every
option they can but at the end of the
day is still customers website so we
have to do what they say and that's I
think our strategy hopefully in a very
condensed nutshell obviously you can't
take an entire corporate strategy that
took a year to do in same
five minutes but hopefully that gave you
some idea I was worried Duane was going
to ask a question he's always scary yes
sir far left my name is Chris wealthy
from switch we host an ack my cluster in
Switzerland and and my question is are
you going to turn on v6 also fool or
non-us deployments yes in fact most of
the internet exchanges that are
currently v6 pairing or not in the
United States um I should say by the way
I don't remember I said that's the
10,000 name servers are just under
10,000 name servers we picked were in
North America so those numbers were
North American but we are rolling it out
worldwide it's just we have 1700 pops in
72 countries it takes a little while to
ask every single one for a v6 address
and then go and reconfigure the servers
but hopefully cross your fingers every
single internet exchange should have v6
by the end of this quarter I I know I
said that for last quarter but this
quarter really should be done and we're
trying to get all the Akamai nodes
inside of networks and transit nodes v6
ified you know shortly thereafter yes
sir hi my name is Mossad am I you should
know America can you go back to us right
yes sir oh my god agnostic Nia will use
this to be on ipv6 day you around again
we do whatever our customers tell us to
do so we have some customers that told
us to just dual stack and we'll do that
and we have the capability to do that on
a per host name basis so customers who
tell us the dual stack and pay no
attention to the telemetry will do that
if they tell us to do this will do this
no worries can i'm going to us
not the same thing is Hawaii of cinemark
holiday mark I was already up here once
domestic um uh no caffeine all right
south south state apparently um can you
say anything more about how you're going
to rank on ipv4 and a versus a quad a
destination I mean I don't know if you I
mean is it just like RTT packet loss I
mean how are you going to do that and so
I'm or if you can't say that's cool too
it well the the way Akamai decides these
things is a complex algorithm which
really comes down to a score and we
literally just have a number and we pick
two you know this one or that one but
the number is a combination of latency
packet loss and throughput the standard
stuff if you have you know one
millisecond but you've only got 500
kilobits and obviously you don't want to
use that path if you have you know 40
milliseconds and 50 milliseconds in the
40 milliseconds says ten percent packet
loss will pick the fifty percent 50
milliseconds etcetera etcetera so the
scores is pretty anybody's really
interested in can come talk to me but
it's it's pretty well established and
we're going to use the exact same
algorithm for v6 that we're currently
and have been using for v4 for a decade
that was kind of the question on the
desk because what we've seen before is
you know sort of preferential ranking of
ipv6 for example when resolvers used to
choose ipv6 first because we're trying
to boot you know get people to use it
right yes but you're going to use the
same oh well that's what we're going to
suggest but again whatever our customers
tell us to do that's what we're going to
do and the end of day if a customer
forces us to do you know v6 only within
the limitations of the system itself
that's what we're going to do Patrick
cured launched from the American you
need to come closer do because you scare
me when you
I'll scare you later um so I wanted to
to see if you can talk about how many of
your how you've been promoting to your
customers and how many of your customers
are actually going to participate in
ipv6 day because I think that's one of
the key components here of that you know
if you're giving customers requesting
dual stack enabling or enabling just for
the day to get an idea of the sense of
that is going to help a lot of us
understand the the support queries we're
going to get because if it's you know
yahoo and google and a few other
providers you know that's going to be
pretty well defined but if everyone
starts having problems with like their
semantic updates you know i don't know
if you can share those customer names
but i would love for you to have the
ability to pass this up to i sock or
someone else we can get an idea of the
scope of the testing can you share
anything about that what percentage your
customers etc so first of all I really
like the idea of passing the customers
that are going to enable v6 on v6 day
two I saw and I will take that back
because honestly that never occurred to
me and I don't know if marketing is
doing that or not so thank you for that
truth of the matter is very few
customers have asked us before 2010 been
count on one hand the number of
customers who asked us for v6 and we
have 4,000 customers so we're talking
point 1 percent in 2010 that went up
slightly it was in the double digits
2011 a few more have asked us but
honestly one of the reasons that we
don't have a full-blown v6 strategy this
moment with v6 enabled everywhere and
we're just doing like what bugs and
stuff is because there's very few
customers they can go down to back to
like count on two hands the number of
customers that are really pushing for it
most of the ones that ask for it they're
kind of like we've heard about this v6
thing what is that and so we are doing
the opposite we've trained all of our
sales staff they're going out and
they're telling customers by the way
we're going to have v6 and we're you
know like I said we're we've already
served v6 content but it's all testing
from Akamai stuff we're going to have
about a dozen customers on what we call
a
tech preview which is kind of like an
early beta and they have to agree that
they're not going to get mad at us if it
slows things down and stuff like that
and that's going to be v6 only host
names but that's going to be very soon
next 30-45 days I think I'm not sure um
but as by the time of v6 day any
customer that wants it should be able to
get it I don't want to make promises at
a podium in front of 600 my closest
friends but theoretically any customer
that wants it and asks for it and should
be able to have it by v6 day thanks
Allah thing thank you are you planning
on keeping the TTL is longer than 24
hours on any of these DNS names the
standard Akamai hostname has a 20-second
TTL be perfect thank you well it seems
from affiliates um when you say that
things are coming in over tunnels just
about everyone is coming over tunnels do
you mean 2002 / 16 6 24 or do you have
additional secret info about who's
running six rd and you know you're odd
six and four tunnel and things like that
so it says be broken and only ten point
six percent of them had a native IP
address that that's what I know sorry I
did I didn't actually do this testing I
asked somebody for the information and
they gave me this information I would be
curious to know that a little finer
detail if you remind me afterwards
because for some reason my brain is not
working very well to this morning I will
be happy to look it up for you thanks
that was a really lot of questions i'm
feeling like i did not explain things as
well so if anybody wants to come and ask
me afterwards feel free and i guess
that's it because I don't see anybody if
Mike is Jared up there no he's not okay
thank you everyone
okay thank you if anybody had any other
follow-up questions I'll just go ahead
and get up to the microwave a few more
minutes actually at one question for
Igor if you don't mind this is a Donna
roizman from softlayer could you
describe in a little bit more detail
what it is you're doing to measure ipv6
brokenness for your end users and is
there any information that you have that
you or any techniques you can't you have
you can make available to other websites
they want to gauge how much broken is
their end user base might experience
sure so again i'm going to plug test
test ipv6 com the source code for that
is actually most of it is open sourced
it's not quite at a point where you can
download it and quickly integrate it but
if you have a decent level of si skills
you can download the source code and
integrate all the testing that it's
doing the Geo web site and then all you
do is process logs is that what Yahoo is
using to measure brokenness for their
visitors we're using that kind of a
technique we're not using that code
because it takes some time for company
the size of Yahoo to go through all the
legal channels to open source something
so once we figure out the methodology
Jason on his own time wrote the code
that test nine TV sitcoms using and a
somebody else wrote the code that Yahoo
is using for testing just because the
infrastructure that we have in place you
know is a little different a yahoo
the other questions going once okay
looks like we have a
JC chillin verizon business unit so in
the spirit of trying to get people to
adopt ipv6 sooner rather than later
which i think is the goal of world ipv6
day what do you tell n sites and transit
providers that have a strategy of
planning to support ipv6 when they need
to in other words when they believe
they're going to run out of before
addresses tell them that as of Thursday
I Anna will have 0 / aids that's a rumor
no but the point I'm trying to make is
there are many transit providers and
many of their customers that have a
mentality that they really don't need to
do ipv6 until they're forced to and
they're not really forced to until they
themselves run out of available via for
addresses so especially n sites that
have a population of users that is not
growing many of them say why do I need
to do v6 and why do I need to do it now
that's from so as Igor just whispered to
me that the problem is they don't and
there's no reason for them if you have
if you have X number of IP addresses in
your hosting provider and you're not
growing or if you're going slow enough
to let the equipment swap out keep the
same number of addresses and support it
unfortunately the answer is you don't
need to do v6 before is going to be
around for a very very very long time so
what we do what I do personally is I
beat the drum and everybody up here is
beating the drum we did this on our own
time and we're here you know talking to
600 of are not so closest friends trying
to get everybody to do v6 this is
despite the fact that you know I'm not
really pleased to be six but we all want
it to happen end of day they're going to
be pockets of v4 forever and ever and
all we can do is get get over the hump
if we can get enough v6 out there that
v4 is the minority then maybe they'll
change even if they don't have to and if
they don't then they'll just suffer the
performance and other consequences
I'd like to say a couple words on that
front as well what we've been saying to
companies in that position is largely
even if you don't have to change your
networks for your purposes because
you've got enough address space there
will be more v6 only in in the world so
there will be people trying to reach you
starting from a v6 only network because
there are growing networks elsewhere
that's not really compelling in the
immediate business cycle but it is at
least a pointer to the long term
reasoning here I don't think it does
anything for companies making a decision
about whether to try to come play in
world ipv6 day I do hope that some of
the stats that we collect then we'll
start to paint a more compelling picture
about the reality of v6 in the future
but none of it is a short term argument
I mean the reality is going to be the
ipv4 is going to be with us for at least
10 years and probably 20 plus so for the
next year if they don't have v6 in their
planning cycle and they're not growing
you know okay just please try not to
break people who are doing tunnels or
whatnot remember X dot 25 and PDP 11s
are still in production so second and
they don't support ipv6 hi again masato
yamanishi of japan tocome america I'm
afraid many thing will happen on ipv6
day actually so I'm trying to figure out
the impact of this day and in yahoo
presentation you said D'Alessio or
broken user is decreasing is the measure
on side door of the fu or measure on
wwe.com so the measurement is actually
there's two different measurements by
two different people that i'm quoting
i'm not saying yahoo numbers there
Lorenzo from google
has posted their numbers and also Tory
Anderson from Norway the two numbers are
so close that you choose up different
measurements that are measuring the
world that have basically the same stats
and it's between point 0 to 6 and point
0 to four percent it's fluctuating so I
look out here and you know I've been
coming to Nana four dozen years and
stuff and the number of Macintoshes has
grown and grown and grown and there's
still only twenty percent or less of the
market and they are something like
eighty percent of the brokenness ipv6 so
so get them to fix it so they fix quite
a bit thank you apple and select people
with an apple with the very latest 10 10
dot 6 update the very nasty bug of 64
and RFC 1918 addresses has been fixed
and that alone dropped the brokenness
from point 05 12 point over 26 just that
one fix alone but many many block on
user problem will happen from the
combination of isp used on it for user
equipment cpe like that so fixing each
device doesn't dissolve the problem i
think yes you need to fix like i said
you need to fix all the bugs and
something that we are very afraid of is
that those are the stats with users with
0 point two percent of the users who
have ipv6 like turned on so something
we've been thinking and you know I
didn't want to bury my hand in the sand
but the question is really if the
percentage of users for v6 enabled is is
the percentage of users or v6 enable
really point two to six percent and one
in 10 of the v6 aware users are actually
broken and if there's more ipv6 aware
users is one is there going to be more
broken users or if we can drop the
number of broken users while increasing
the number of working users so is also
um sorry Jer one just remember everybody
where we're not worried about people who
are so
broken that they can't get to be six but
we're worried about us somebody who
thinks they're going to be it on v6 and
then they timeout 60 90 120 seconds
later because as far as the user is
concerned 100 20-second timeout is down
so if you don't have v6 or if your v6 is
so broken that you can't even ask for a
quad a or something like that then
you're actually not a problem to us
right now we're worried about people who
ask for a quad I think they can get to a
quad I try to get to a quad a and then
wait around while the user gets pissed
off and spills coffee on their machine
so so so Igor this is Jared again so one
of the concerns that I have in setting
the threshold where it is that that
you're stating that it needs to be
pointed one percent of the user is being
broken I said at the very least we know
one is that the one is fat I I wish we
could get security patch levels at that
high of a level within organizations I'm
sorry Patrick who almost spilled coffee
across all the attendees but trying to
aim for such a low threshold of
brokenness I think is actually quite
possibly an unreasonable expectation and
outstanding idea will create a botnet
that infects all the users and fixes
their v6 if only we could create a
botnet to turn on automatic patching on
people's windows machines as well but
unfortunately there's various laws and
regulations preventing us from doing
that which might be effective the thing
that and I'll say this since we don't
actually have any be six or before
business the thing that it comes back to
is security of n hosts isn't actually
impacting the business isn't perceived
to be impacting the business of major
content providers whereas the business
decision makers are stopped by the
perception that they are going to be
breaking their service for a percentage
of their customers and unfortunately
we're not the room that gets to decide
what that percentage is so I mean I
certainly take your point I'm with you
but to my point in my slide if v6 isn't
perceived as working for the business
decision
makers it's not going to happen and I
certainly understand that that reality
and part of that is us taking the
lessons that we know here technical
information back in educating the people
in our organizations and saying look you
know some amount of brokenness
ultimately happens there's lots of
people who can't reach the internet
because they have some crappy home dsl
or cable router thing that's proxying
their DNS requests and eats them but
vile effects google and yahoo and and
that that affects everyone equally
exactly the this is the point of v6 day
is to affect everyone equally absolutely
by the way a body'd a body'd computer
can still download adwords so yeah i'm
going to answer the question a little
bit directly a little bit more directly
I myself believe that this or if you had
asked me six months ago what I've told
you this threshold isn't point 01 it's
point 0 0 1 remember these are users who
get to need perfectly fine over ipv4 and
now i'm going to i I'm going to do
something that stops them from getting
to me I think that is wrong and for a
certain percentage like one in one in a
hundred thousand okay you know I've
impacted fifteen thousand users globally
that's bad and no those guys will have
to find some workarounds but 156,000
users because I decided I decided that
we should be handing out qua days that's
a problem so the same argument could be
made though for bc p38 compliance by
turning on unicast RPF people break out
a variety of things i understand that
they're not directly equated to each
other but in setting where you're
actually placing that decimal point has
a significant impact obviously on the
end-user perception but in getting
people to fix things and do the right
things i think it's important that we
not go and say what we're going to let
people be so broken and yet still work
that it's it's going to go and impact
the rest of the industry and the
opportunity for people to go to Jason
and say no really we actually
you want I pv6 because these things are
retarding the adoption of ipv6 in a
number of markets so I'm not saying that
we will not do dual stack with the
current brokenness numbers I am saying
that there's no way in hell that we will
do it without a whitelist so I think an
important point of what you just said
jared was in comparison it to be cd38
the context there is this is not just
the question what is the public good but
also belief in the value of the outcome
of deploying bcp to adhering a bcp 38
and implicitly then what we're saying
here is there isn't the business
perceived value in deploying ipv6 yet
which comes back to Jason's questions so
another side goal of world ipv6 day and
everything that we're doing this year
with ipv6 is to try to demonstrate that
you know there is more momentum behind
ipv6 so that at some point the the
perceived value of supporting ipv6 will
indeed outweigh whatever particular
numbers because the way the way that
Igor phrased it was he can't turn it on
because he thinks it's right so we need
to get more business support for the
value of ipv6 know if you really want
this to happen quickly get Jason to
install or Jason or John or other people
to install to few siegeans so there's
congestion and packet loss and then
people will see the value put another
way to go back to leslie point a million
dollars a day is a lot of money even to
Google I'm gonna get an echo little bit
on Patrick's comment remember these are
stats as measured against current
working before if you break before or if
you make leave for work worse then the
v6 brokenness numbers will look better
thank you very much that is how we're
measuring so when v4 starts to work
worse then the brokenness number will
look
in relation to it and then we're going
to go oh there's very little penalty
compared to be 42 v6 and at some point
we're going to go hum maybe we need to
be doing white listening for before
because v6 works so much better thank
you thank you very much folks thank
everyone num on the high sock and Yahoo
and Akamai once again I encourage
everyone to go view the I sock site and
look at the ipv6 world link check out
the list of websites that are already
quad-a enabled check out the ones that
are participating and speak to your
co-workers and your employers and
management and your end users and
content testers and encourage them to
participate as well if they're so
inclined next up we have sham won't you
as our next speaker is coming to podium
it's one to let you know a couple things
for those of you that rolled in a little
bit a little bit late today little
suited a reminder to please fill out
your surveys before the break it's going
to be after this next speaker get those
surveys done this morning so later on
today we can go ahead and draw the name
for a brand new juniper ax series switch
what a great thing to have another thing
is just another friendly reminder to
please silence your cell phones while
you're in the meeting room out of
courtesy for the speakers as well the
other attendees and with that I'm going
to do some form mozilla corporation
who's going to speak to us about DNS SEC
you have you
yeah i'm just going to fit all
differently to change
right ah good morning everyone I'm Sean
and I'm not a morning person especially
after that awesome party last night back
home and Singapore I'm probably waking
or thinking about making up around
ten-thirty in the morning so I'm a
systems admin for Mozilla and we
implemented DNS SEC for Mozilla a dog
towards the end of 2010 and just thought
i'd share my experience with you guys uh
just a little intro to mozilla we make a
we help make firefox which is the second
most popular browser in the world we've
got about 400 million users today which
is coincidentally also the number of DNS
queries we handy in a day across the
public name servers all right ah show
fans for people who were at the party
last night ah come on that's it okay
show fans if you had fun at the party
last night right sure fans if you've
implemented the NSX nice show fans if
you were at the DNS SEC tutorial on
Sunday by mark alright the reason i ask
that is the first part of the talk is
going to cover some of the basics of DNS
SEC if you're at the tutorial you would
have already heard most of this then we
go on to some of the implementation
details and the mistakes you should not
be making when you're thinking about DNS
SEC all right so what exactly is DNS SEC
v NS security extensions a bunch of
changes to DNS that ensures that your
data that helps you ensure that your
data hasn't changed in transit that
helps you validate the source and does
something called authenticated denial of
existence which basically means that you
have a surefire way of saying or knowing
that a subdomain or domain are doesn't
exist the arishok is based on public key
cryptography RFC's 40 33 34 and 35 are
the core documents that actually
describe it along with a bunch of
supplementary RFC's if you're new to dns
the Wikipedia article is an excellent
place to start some of these concepts
can be a little complex but once he
wants to get your head around it it's
pretty simple to work through it why DNS
SEC because well DNS is an excellent
system scales very well but it wasn't
created for today's world so we've seen
issues with pns security attacks our
cache poisoning for example and
hopefully DNS SEC will help mitigate
some of these things so what exactly is
new in DNS SEC RFC 4034 explains these
new for new resource records that we
have I'll just run through them a dns
key is nothing but so since the NSA is
based on public key cryptography you've
got a private key that you stored away
safely and a public key that's disputed
and the dns key record basically holds
your public key that's it it's very
simple it holds your public key the S
record or a delegation signer record is
an interesting record because a d/s
record actually is nothing but a pointer
to a DNS key record it sits in a pet in
your parents on and contains something
called a key tag or a key ID that is
uniquely a link to your key and has a
hash of the key and sits in the parent
zone so basically a d/s record for
mozilla.org would be in dot org will
point to a specific key in mozilla.org
that and that's basically what he s
record is ah an N Secord is basically
called next secure this is what helps
with the authenticated denial of
existence say for example you do a
lookup for bargard mozilla.org and such
domain does not exist an encyclical will
reply with well the next secure record
is food or mozilla.org and so the
problem with insect was that you could
actually run queries and find out all
your existing domains which you cannot
do with DNS but you could do that would
be NSX and that is why they came up with
n sec 3 which is basically the same
thing but the
difference being the names are hashed so
you could still technically walk the
tree find out demands but you're going
to get hash names and so you can't
really make much sense of them it's a
lot indicates that that domain doesn't
exist and others say god I saw Secord
signature is what I'd like to consider
as the tube or this is what actually
holds the signatures that can be
verified not created diagrams but I
would sort of look at it like that dsdna
ski vs are what are the records that do
data integrity and origin authentication
encik does denial of sorry authenticated
denial of existence and RSA records
exist for all of these D SDNS key and
psych records all of them have
signatures so moving on keys of course
since it's based on public key
cryptography as I've said we've had we
have public and private keys you stored
away the private key safely you
distribute the public keys you've got
two types of keys key signing keys as
the name implies sign other keys and so
on signing keys signs owns the key
signing key also signs the zone signing
key now in theory we do not actually
need multiple keys you could do DNS SEC
with just one key but there are
operational reasons as to why you would
like different keys as I said all your
when I spoke about the D s and D s
record which points to DNS key DNS keys
assuming you have only one key the DS
record for this case it's in the parent
zone ok assuming this ski is compromised
you're going to have to contact your
parent and change that D s eckerd every
time and this this could possibly cause
a break in your chain of authentication
I'll show you the chain of
authentication or soonish but so that's
the reason why you want to split your
keys make sure you know and the other
reason is zone signing keys can be
changed at your whim and fancy if you
lose this on signing key it's easy you
can just change it your key signing key
will sign the zone signing key and you
know
you don't lose your chain of trust at
all there are a bunch of algorithms that
you can use to generate your keys but
without going into too much detail the
most commonly used ones are probably
algorithm number five are they say and
with the hash of sha-1 and there's seven
of it RSA sha-1 and sexy I guess uh what
is it all over roll over is a process of
changing your keys DNS SEC does not mean
you generate keys once and you keep
signing forever up that's kind of not
the idea so you have rollovers value
probably this is again this decided by
your own local policy it could be six
months for the KSK a a month for the
xeriscape it all depends on what you
decide and how you want to work it out
the operational practices RFC 4641 is an
excellent read if you plan to implement
the NSA it explains some of these
concepts in great detail it also gives
you a situation up explains a couple of
situations where if you've lost keys or
you know you've keys your keys have been
stolen what are the possibilities that
you should think about ah just going to
explain that a little better just give
me a second
okay is that readable few guys are not
really sure if I should increase the
font size so this is basically something
that will explain the relationships
between the whole BS DNS key thing let
me know if you can't read it i'm just
going to show you the short version
first so that's basically what it looks
like this is an excellent tool from the
design called dns debugger which
actually runs through the whole chain of
trust as you can see it goes from dot to
dot org to mozilla the dog verifies the
whole chain that this record is actually
valid if you expand it a little further
i'll skip right down to this part where
it says org refers to mozilla.org for
mozilla dog 1bs record fond and comes
down here says checking d s so this this
is basically a d/s record that sits in
the parent domain checks the d/s record
over here which basically says in d s
this is the key tag 518 you can see that
corresponding DNS key here 5 16 18 as
well and then it continues down it finds
that this D s verifies the DNS key finds
to our 66 to 879 is the zone signing key
comes further down this is one signing
key actually signs that are saying and
so it verifies that record
uh-huh so going back before you actually
do the NS sec it's good if you check
that your top-level domain is sign it's
not it's not a must-have it's a good to
have thing because this means that you
like you saw in the previous slide it's
you have a complete chain of trust if
you don't do that then you're something
called an island of trust which means
you're separate the root is separate
there's no real link there are other
ways to go about this is C has the lv
i'll let you guys look it up it's got
loca side validation they sort of take
the place of fluid you put them as stuff
and you can validate check with your
register about the nsx because as I
mentioned es records are a crucial part
of this whole process your register is
the only entity right now that can
update your das records so they have to
be DNS SEC compliant or be in a position
to actually update IDs records I say you
might have to poke a bit because
sometimes they say for example if you
look at GoDaddy they've got a web
interface you just put in your dias
records you're good some other registers
you're going to have to email your dias
records to them and make sure they
update it so if the process is still
sort of you know in flux it depends the
URL there actually gives a list of
registers that do dot org and it's
sorted by DNS SEC also make sure your
software works you have to do your
testing or whatever DNS servers you use
bind unbound both of them actually
support DNS SEC look at key signing
software like Open DNS SEC figure out if
that's going to be useful and do your
testing before you go ahead ah this is
what our setup looks like it's a pretty
simple setup you've got our DNS configs
go to source control get pulled on by
the name servers and being sad means
we're pretty lazy about stuff so you
don't change much you have saina machine
which actually holds your keys sysadmin
still commit the source control the sign
of machine does the signing which is
back into source control which then
filters down the name servers
a bunch of stuff I'm not going to go
into too much detail here so key gen is
basically what generates are the keys
for you I'd like to highlight the minus
f KS k that is what denotes set
something called an S et bit at a secure
entry point bit that is what denotes a
key signing key and says this is
different from other keys if you don't
add that the second line right there
that's basically a zone sign key set
time you can have multiple keys you can
decide when they go active and stuff
like that so that's what it's used for
signs on is what actually does your
signing the minus s there is important
because it's a cool feature it's called
smart signing it looks at your whole
list of keys it decides what keys
expired when what is active signs your
zones according to that and that's those
are the changes you make to bind that
car named at conf enable yes validation
es point to assign zone file you should
be good this at this point you are
serving sign zones if you want to be
evaluating resolver you'll have to add
either manage keys and point to the root
trust stuff or atrocities that should
work steps to do things that's what we'd
be upgraded bind across the board
rebuilt by 9.7 for rhel5 when we did
this six wasn't out yet it was still
beta but yeah kick off the signers DNS
servers pick up changes yay when I'm
gonna skip this for now I can if I think
we're a little short on time so i'll
come back to showing you some commands
while i take questions this is another
excellent tool from sandia national labs
this is basically again beautifully
shows the whole authentication chain as
you can see right from the root i'm not
sure if yeah you can still read that so
that's that's actually routes dns key
filters down to dot orgs dns key the BS
record for dog sits in route dns key and
that's RDS for mozilla.org in the dark
zone and that's our dns key that
5 and 6 18 filters down to ours one
signing key six to eight nine seven and
then finally signed stuff so this is
this is really useful for you to ensure
that your stuff is correctly set up and
working as you can see it shows you the
whole authentication chain delegation
status secure da da da da to organ or to
muscle analog so things that you have to
be careful about your keys and
everything protect them you don't want
to be losing your keys are getting into
all sorts of trouble make sure you have
a backup plan both at the deployment
stage and four scenarios later what
happens if someone breaks into a sign a
machine what happens if you actually
accidentally loose pop private keys
these are situations you have to plan
for because with DNS SEC you do run the
risk of your entire domain being
unreachable if there is a security if
you've been if you've enabled DNS SEC
and if there's a problem in the
validation chain right now today it's
not an issue but eventually in the
future at some point if the the chain is
broken then yours ones are completely
unreachable always sign zones publish
the ones and then push your dsl Eckard's
at least for the first time it's it's
pretty crucial note that your network
equipment my teen changes we had cases
where our cisco and sometimes i think
even juniper i'm not i'm not the network
guy but yeah we had issues where DNS SEC
increases the amount of data that it
sends out because of all the signatures
and all that so we had stopped that word
truncate responses so that little
snippet help us or that boo-boos
security lameness I did the reverse
about what happened was I sent out the
d/s record store register and said hey
we'd like this push thought I expected
it would take about 24 hours and my
downtime was in the latter half of 12 oz
to push out stuff up but it went live in
the first 12 was and well so we were in
sign for a bit so as soon as the d/s
goes out
validating resolvers look at the d/s and
say hey we expected the NS key for
Mozilla a dog but the Mozilla dog
nameservers do not have a dns key hence
up they're not secure and that's exactly
what happened log levels in other thing
the default log levels in buying for DNS
SEC are set to debug we filled up this
pretty fast in like less than a week so
you might want to watch out for that and
change it of course Twitter everyone
fails you Mozilla dog has a DNS SEC
problem mock them as insecure and was
louder dog and recibir should be sign
says dog but isn't not good but yeah we
got not too yeah I got it on fixing that
pretty soon moving forward I'm sure this
is sort of a chicken and egg thing just
like rtv6 it's just that we don't have
any value 8english always we don't have
enough clients that actually use them so
we looked at it from the perspective of
let's go ahead and implement this
because this is good and you guys should
think about it in that way as well
because well you know more security more
win for the users from a Firefox
perspective although this is not an
official position there's been
discussion within the IT team that we
should have a DNS eck validator inside
Firefox that for example checks are
update URLs make sure that you don't
depend on the OS the browser itself will
actually validate where it's connecting
to to get its updates there was someone
here who is speaking to me yesterday
today should I think they've actually
have a patch that they plan to submit to
Mozilla to actually have a DNS SEC
validation in the browser so that's
pretty awesome and finally you can have
graphs ah the first graph is actually
the number of queries we actually do
this is Hector in the last week so it's
sort of you know still in flux but
that's the number of queries we do a
minute the second graph next to that is
the first ones DNS the second one is bns
sec and as you can see the second one is
missing a que so it's it's basically
nothing third graph combines both DNS
SEC is just
line down there really really
insignificant at this point so ah thanks
i will be happy to take questions if you
have any feel free to email me as well
do I decide good for that bad I think no
I think you were that good that's
wonderful okay well thank you much thank
you guys listen okay great well thank
you once again so folks we are going to
go ahead and break for our morning
coffee and everyone needs it to unpick
in the head a little bit so we'll be
back here at eleven-thirty for the next
round of talks thank you very much
you