so we are here for the closing session
so let's do the fun with flex so it's
not captured the flag it's a fun with
flags okay so first things first I would
like to thank you all of my colleagues
at integrity for helping us in terms of
creating the challenges and testing them
so yeah much love for you guys and to
all of the participants of the CTF and
quote we hope that you guys had fun and
also we would like to thank our sponsors
without them it wouldn't be possible to
make these call friends and especially
these two for the CTF ok so one thing
that that was really awesome this year
is that if you guys don't know the pony
awards basically they awarded on black
hats to people that is incredible things
in during that year and basically we had
a Portuguese nominee which I hope is in
the room bit come on man this sucks
what the hell is the guy he's been
through in the house this is going
really well so should we move on and
then we can try and track him cowboy I
was trying to see him before and it's
really cool because he was nominated for
the pony and you know it was really cool
he was nominated for the pony the font
the font is really nice yeah yeah
there's a nomination there's a pony and
I don't know if you understand that he
was nominated for the pony
is he like a life and draw really cool
I'm where we prepare this no yeah so
basically this year was really
interesting in terms of information
security basically one thing that Herman
is going to show that but there's a lot
of interesting stuff that happened this
year but I don't want to spoil it right
now anything one of those it's not on
what he's about to talk but it's the
pony Awards again like the Oscars for
information security people that do
great stuff
so in fleek was nominated for the pony
award
I don't know anybody knew this before
and basically the the word was the pony
for epic achievement I think the
nomination was an epic achievement for
it by itself honestly and and it's I
think is something that really makes all
our community project that he was even
nominated much more the fact that he
actually wanted so and and the foot
another fun fact was actually when I saw
when he tweeted that he was nominated I
was interested to see whether who would
win and so on and I found out by
accident so while googling and stuff
seeing what happened at the ponies in
blackhat so on 11 August I actually saw
that he actually want it but the fun
part was I tweeted this to him and he
said holy I had no ideas
[Laughter]
and where that is my pony and we had a
lot of tweeting back and forth where the
hell is the pony they didn't well and I
think that a man shall not be separated
from his pony said once a wise man you
guys all know this really so and
basically and I asked him today or
yesterday if he already had the pony he
still doesn't have the pony this is an
exact an example really I don't know
so basically this was I think the if it
was there they would have delivered it
with this slide there so basically we
are going to give a pony to not the pony
but a much better pony like this is a
really badass pony
it looks like Morpheus shirts you see
the glasses okay it's not golden but
it's but it's like a great pleasure to
give this you have to say some words
okay it's on
yeah so this Pony is better better than
the original and because it's here yeah
because it was the besides organizer
that gave it to me so uh I don't know
thank you everyone and you you can also
win ponies if you guys want but you have
to polish more stuff exactly and I don't
know web stuff just does not win awards
so but if it did you guys would win
thank you so and you know that we had a
lot of unicorns around this area in the
last few days
I heard but then you can say well we
don't have a unicorn we have a pony it's
much better
moving on okay so moving on for the CTF
team so as last year it was surrounded
in terms of the story around mr. robot
if you guys don't know what it is go
check it out because it is awesome and
yeah this was like our mr. robot moment
yesterday during the CTF so we've had
ten ten teams and they were really
focused yeah it was his birthday so yeah
it was nice and now people was worth
having for having fun as we can see and
yeah so so it happened yesterday between
1432 1638 lasted for three hours we've
had ten teams and we've had ten kids get
we have emojis that don't work exactly
come on
the more disease failing me so we've had
trivia which everyone loves
I use the iPhone 17 you new ones right
yeah and we have forensics web crypto
physical and misc so we've had a total
of 15 challenges where 12 of them were
solved at least once and we also used a
dynamic scoring system so we had a value
set for the child each at the challenges
and as soon teams were solving it the
the points were going down so because
most of the time we set some value for
that challenge but it's it ends up being
too easy
so in this Cindy's in this case its
value is going to be adjusted to what it
is worth
yeah basically a lot of people solve it
it's less valuable
so it's try to to balance balance it
think of okay so these were the
challenges that were soft so we had a
whole and intro whole it's a trivia
challenge which all of the teams solved
so trivia is not that hard right
and yeah and we've had this others so we
are going to go through all of these
these these these twelve and see which
were this so illusions yeah if you still
awake at the end will give the prizes
yes because we have a lot of slides to
go on through before that better so
we've had like 1563 keys and only 52
were correct ones it doesn't work
no like three so yeah you know doing
slides doing slides in hand for two I
advise it's normal we have more we have
more so pay attention okay in terms of
the challenges there were twelve so
these were the challenges and the
categories so starting on the on the
most soft one Soho which is was a trivia
100 and as you guys can see at the end
it was only worth 50 points because all
of all of the teams saw solve sol solved
it and the question was people stopped
crying and the name is whole so i think
this is an easy one so base basically we
were asking for the URL of the sinkhole
for one cry so people stop crying the
next one which is called intro so mr.
robot received a CD in the mail from
cisco it says it's his new album let's
hear the intro and we had a file named
music so after that we could play the
file and we can start hearing this okay
so of course we would think about Morse
code right or not and by thinking about
that we could try and decode this this
madman message and we do have online
sites with the strands like that into
the flag and as you guys can see here
the flag says what is left baby don't
hurt me don't hurt me no more so moving
on to the next one which is called White
Rose it was one of our physical
challenges so we've had three and it
size this box belongs to the mystery man
which in this case is why is Wild Rose
and what does it have inside again watch
or dress if you guys see the show you
guys will know why and yeah so we've had
this box and people had to lock pick it
it was really easy because we wanted the
teams to made it to the next phase
because inside once lock picks they
would found this so this it is is a
shredded paper and after putting it
together and as you guys can see here
people were using duct tape and there's
one worn that people do yes and after
that they would come up with this and
then they would I then identify these
three parts and if you guys can see it
correctly this is the hacker manifesto
and as we can see we have four parts and
after putting it to gather and after
doing a rot13
in military we would reach the flag so
it has been encrypted and shredded they
set so it was a fun one and a lot of you
like the physic doing the physical
challenges because it's something we
cannot do online right so it's fun
having people around and it's really fun
really weird stuff so another one that I
have made which is called presidents so
it says White Rose is is monitoring his
favorite candidates for president
what can you fight in this Trump or
sorry in this dump
yeah so in the dump file that we gave
them they first it was a pcap file so
once opened we could see that it has a
lot of Wi-Fi frames I think that is real
SSID maybe otherwise I think that's why
just trying to configure yeah forget
yeah it's something ever mine so yeah as
we can see we have the network which is
called faff a and moving on what is go
session I don't know man no one knows so
and after that we would try to crack the
passwords because we do have here the
four handshakes and using a tool like
air crack and some deke show dictionary
we could just find the password which is
really strong it has 18 sharks the
nuclear code probably but it has only
four right so yeah and after that we
could decode the traffic decode not we
could D decrypt the the traffic and
after searching through all of a lot
HTTP traffic because I went to Fox News
and they don't they don't use HTTP and
then I start searching for stuff like
CNN is fake news and drown the swamp and
other stuff like that and actually
people were thinking that was the key
the flag so yeah it was it was it was a
fun so moving on we could see that we
did have an FTP connection from that a
trump and after that he was just getting
the flag txt and after searching for
this for this day data we could find the
flag which says wpa2 ccmp shouldn't be
the only encryption layer as as we have
seen with the crack attack okay so now
it's your-turn Akal so that's that's a
fun one
well so basically NaCl is sodium if you
guys don't know it and there's a leap
sodium which is a cryptographic library
that if you're developing you should use
and not to roll your own hence the name
so you should not roll your own crypto
and you'll make mistakes that lead to
the attack that discover the catch is
vulnerable to okay there's a lot of
other problems yeah I know but I had to
come up with some something so and I
didn't want to give you just the the
piece that had the answer so it's
basically these increased stuff to
create stuff and what I wanted people to
to get to was not padding
although there's some crappy padding
there but I tried to pretend that the
padding was okay but basically you have
the age mech function and if you look at
it it's not it's not an age mech at all
it's just a key and the payload and the
digest so that was the the main problem
and if you looked at up what happens if
you do it like this you are vulnerable
to a hash length extension attack and
that was the solution the rest was just
for you guys to get lost in in the color
it actually should work but please don't
use this in production I think this was
ripped off from Stack Overflow or
something so okay so next we had one
which is called I RC which was made by
Philippe so this this was fun doing it
because I didn't get til the earlier
date to be vulnerable yeah it was making
you vulnerable so this was a real RC
boat but that was made in Titan there
was a lot of comments so if you went to
the find exploits and you did tried
something Hewitt and sqy and as a string
concatenation you can buy a do a basic
Union select and get the flag I
it's the main point here that we discuss
it was doing something that it's pretty
common for people that at least usually
look into web applications and web ship
which is quite basic c.coli but put it
in a medium that people are not so
comfortable with because you'll have to
use an IRC client or or use some
libraries to actually be able to use
this you can just point seecombe up here
it won't work so that's the fun part
okay so moving on to the next one so
this one was fun too
it was the physical 100 and the text
size
what were the brightest hacks of off of
- of 2017 so and since this was a
physical one and people were asking so
do you do you guys have any stuff for us
to try and test and we have said no you
guys have all of its everything yeah to
try and solve this and most of the
people got this t-shirt and as you guys
can see prob probably and so you guys
can see here like different color in
terms of the text there if you guys can
see them but it wasn't supposed yeah the
idea was not to be noticeable unless in
the dark so if you take your t-shirts in
the Sun and they'll go to the dark it
will actually be bright it's luminescent
you guys can see here in this video so
if you guys go it's in a dark place and
your t TT t-shirt is going to light up
just going to play it once again we are
just giving like power to the Lumet lu
luminescent ink
okay so you guys didn't know this right
Easter eggs Easter Egg everywhere so
it's it's nice because when you got when
you got the t-shirts like last week and
we get pick up the t-shirts and look at
the yeah what's the files over do
it like in five six five seconds right
but yeah it worked out pretty ok
I know that we when we started handing
the t-shirts yesterday no one said
anything so yeah I know but even with
other guys in the company when you show
them most of them didn't notice anything
strange we knew it so it for us is like
a this is completely yeah yeah yeah
thank you and it has like a lot of
difference on like Road pawn shadow
brokers don't forget you the V oh yeah
it's all right yeah and that's why I put
a bit yeah okay and the next one which
is called HDD it was done by Fabio the
little demon and it says the dark army
stole Cisco's laptop from his apartment
after you know like the blood the blood
yeah Beth so why was he hiding Sam Sam
think and a file was given which was
called HDD so on this one you were given
a hard drive partition if you wanted it
and went to the Documents folder you'll
see these files the goal of this
challenge was to get the password for
the compressed at heart file and that
put that password was split in three
parts and didn't on these JPEGs although
the content that you saw before it was
not solve it you had to use tools like
autopsy to see deleted files there is a
dot dot dot jpg there and so if you
extracted it and and so it's active
you'll see the first part on the second
one you'll see this image which you
don't see anything special just some
cards but used if you use that Kearse
functionality it is available on most of
fetishes like Photoshop paint.net and
GIMP curves cars you know
if you find the password so let me just
you guys can see it's right there yeah
so here you are you have to pull the
line to the bottom white corners and the
second part will show up guys team Zev
solve this so it's it's do a bear game
over that third part you just have to
beat walk this file or you can just
start the whole folder or even used to
extract the files from the partition and
you'll get this zip file I just had to
start two files and cut this yeah so
after that you put all these parts
together and compress the word and get
the flag hidden in plain sight so easy
okay so pipes so the net which is the
physical 300 so yeah you can okay so in
this one where the following eluate is
inside that's the center there is no
interface you cannot plug in any no rope
devices it just sees a cable and you
only sees cables cables everywhere any
needs your help
so what can you do so the thing here is
if there is a cable you can tap it and
the objective was was that you need to
tap the cable but in a way that you
don't interact the communication so a
few teams they cut the cable yeah I have
to get I had to give some hints ok this
is the setup you can tap the cable with
me very careful not to cut
wires yeah just need to cut the outside
of Ethernet cable and then there's like
four wires you just need to ring and two
oranges and then after explaining a bit
just giving some mins
I also said to them okay you can search
online for Ethernet tap or Ethernet
passive tap and you're gonna have some
some hints there so after this they had
to capture and it was like a cron job
every one minute running a few scripts
and yeah transferring files so they had
to put all those pickups together and
then inside the pcaps they had some more
hints this is this is the hint where the
secret is this is an SMTP communication
there was a lot more communications like
ten telnet FTP so after this they are
the secret but they also need the file
where the flag is
and this is a file that is transferred
with FTP protocol again not encrypted
yeah
classify dot zip we can see there and
then they had everything didn't they
just need to unzip the file and this is
the secret message from whiterose that's
it cool again physically so yeah oh and
do five nine yeah so to solve
so again if you guys follow the show
they basically use the read somewhere to
encrypt some stuff so and one of the one
of the issues on the show there is a way
to undo five nine so they think it's
possible and they need forensics and
they recover some files and the idea is
to see if you can decrypt them so
basically you get a tgz file that has a
readme dot txt a readme adopt exe dot F
Society and a snip just a piece that was
recovered from the script that was used
to encrypt from the from the ransomware
because you know resumes use PHP what's
really important is it's this this is
basically the snippet I cut everything
that did
matter for the fact but basically it has
two functions then while it does its
opens yet there will be a file in this
case we'll be reading it up txt that F
society it will open it will read the it
will read read media well the cryptid is
will open and it's not exercise the
clear file is just Rhema doc txt it
reads the whole file up to 2048 bytes
and there's a small detail about this it
will destroy the original file so it
goes to destroy file basically generates
random string of characters up to the
length of the file it does an F right
over the file and it closes the file so
basically instead of deleting because
it's easily recoverable obviously the
idea is to just overwrite it with random
bytes after that it will generate an
unique key because remember the the
clear text is already in memory it will
generate random AES key which is up here
so it will just generate 16 random bytes
and will return the key so it will
encrypt the file and their relatives the
problem is basically how this is using
the mt r and PHP function which is
basically piece of crap so the
interesting thing is the the mt rent is
deterministic so if you know the seed
you know exactly what next byte will be
in if you know what the next byte will
be by the seed you also can brute force
with the bytes you know and go back to
the seed which is what you can use with
PHP and tear and from solar designer
yeah so basically the idea was as you
see the idea of destroying the file was
not that smart because it uses the
emptier and also so basically you have
everything you need to decrypt you just
go to the original file which is just
random bytes you get a few of the
initial bytes run the PHP emptier and
cracker and it will output what was the
seed at the initial point before those
bytes
now where most teams probably filed at
least in our tests happen a lot is that
okay
so I know the seed let's generate das
key won't work because I see it is for
the destruction of the files so you have
to go basically set the seed before
destroying the file they say the seed
was this one to create the original I
think 60 bikes I think it was the size
of the file referendum bytes and then
generate the correct or the the the AES
key and just decrypted fun fact this
there was a real ransomware that use
this technique yeah so I just tried not
fixed right yeah fixed some parts as
much as it can be fixed but this 2048
use it like everywhere so only the first
2048 bytes of the file were encrypted in
that case again if you look for empty
ran and ran somewhere on the good on
Google you'll go right to the blog post
it explains all of this yeah so don't
use empty rent or PMF was this one yeah
okay so moving on so he had the trivia
question which is called underrated was
so funny about one by one team we shown
let's see so this one is called their
definition and most of the players you
usually don't read the description so
they just see okay it's a three-way it's
200 a I'm going to start and doing stuff
but they don't read it so here we are
asking for the definition of the ioctl
he quest parameter used in that exploit
and the name is also a hint which is it
is called rate and the rated because
this this flaw was was set to be only
the denial of service exploit and after
that been to showed that it could be
used to get route yeah so so every
basically as far as you could see if not
all but most of the team's knew exactly
what was what were we talking about
yeah so everyone knew that it was his
exploit and so on so actually they they
were the ones that got it right but a
lot of the teams are just closed because
they didn't read what was written there
fun fact the definition yeah definition
and fun fact it wasn't they are first at
that attempt yeah where they did got it
right so they had to try multiple times
so here we have the ioctl para parameter
which is called heat quest in this in
this case we have the T ALCS di but we
were asking for the definition so if you
search like in wiki in wiki pedia you
would find it which it says terminal IO
control simulates at terminal input so
that was the answer that was the answer
so T IOC STI and we wanted its
definition and the last one which was a
trivia for hundreds made by most it's
old school because something old people
you guys are all people should know like
anyone yeah I'm over 25 anything but
basically it's something well it's old
school and it was fixed by curved arrows
so it's something old right everyone was
trying like a lot of exploits names and
stuff and basically you can solve it on
Wikipedia again it's it's it's a trivia
everything everything is on Wikipedia
even the flags so basically if you go
and read about curved arrows you get to
a point where it says the protocol is
based on the earlier Needham Schroeder's
imaginary protocol it's based on that
one yeah if you guys went there you'll
see something about Needham Schroeder's
that is fixing the attack the flow is
fixed in the Kerberos protocol so
basically it goes back to Guerreros
Needham Schroeder's it fixes so it's
Needham shriller and that was it so we
have we had a flaw in this protocol
which then came up to be care and care
too bad yeah that was the answers
Needham Schroeder's Needham Schroeder's
symmetric Patrick a lot okay so now
moving to the fun parts so the prizes so
let's start with the raffle one so
come on guys anyone wants to help no any
do you guys still yeah I'm sensing a
deja vu from last year like we were like
10 minutes still we need to give it a
good mix I think pass it on Thanks yeah
let's us someone we don't know from this
is as random as we can if we can do we
wanted to use empty ran but it's crap so
yeah so we're treating least like that
but but honestly this is really
important for us and basically it's just
made flute plays life miserable because
he was the guy that last year put each
one of these my hands into digital form
Google stuff so that you could do that
really so he was expecting no one's this
year yeah sorry man so you want to great
one just a random guy from the audience
what's your name sir depends
yeah yeah yeah sure yeah it's not about
a it so he actually the pretty good
suggestion so he only literally just
made one suggestion see your champ
available during the entire event we're
thinking about it okay we actually
discussed this I don't know what it says
about us are you okay basically what did
he win a book yeah mark my notion of it
zero day
have fun it's it's kind of weird because
well what's it sexually new so yeah
Microsoft there and second let's choose
another random random guy oh girl random
girl I don't know your name I didn't
either this is not from the staff right
Louis Catalina this is I think this is
the first time we do a raffle and
everyone is in the room and you don't
have to take like 504 so and actually
you guys don't only take a book you guys
are we there yet
it's rope code also bye bye Christine
yes and you guys also get a ticket for
next year so you can write your email
which is nice because you have people
crying for tickets like yesterday
morning you know it's we've been sold
out like four
[Laughter]
so you guys know the tickets are cheap
because it's just to manage so that
people don't get tickets and don't come
over by the way we have over 90% of
people coming so it's really awesome so
I guess it works anyway as some of you
at least know it gets hard to get the
tickets because they really sold out
quickly even by sponsors and so on okay
moving on to the next price so which is
the lightning talk she's not here but
yeah but so she she want dinner
but she didn't well yeah yes and so
yellow a lien Galileo yeah yeah except
she won the lightning talk yesterday and
and she get the ticket for next we won't
forget it's like on Twitter yeah I don't
know any mail flamer so people vote it
was a really cool talk actual yeah it
was nice so moving on to the next gift
so the one who qualified so it's a drone
seller visa is in the room wrong solovey
de sala visa from their random team okay
so he's not qualified anymore I guess so
right give it to the next guy a Brock
you see if I'm not wrong does anyone
have any idea we'll just you just say
it's you and you'll believe it
yeah if here's enough it was team two so
it's easy a Barack you see if I'm not
wrong yeah well well for the cause is
just like one person
yes so this is a raspy pie 0w so which
is really nice stealth think and you
will get a ticket also for next year
okay so yeah yeah you'll get politics
yes
so exactly so tickets okay nice thank
you so you'll get tickets oh okay no we
like to give the prizes so if not here
we don't give you the price yeah
you need to be okay so moving on to the
CTF sorry the fun with flights prizes so
we had in third place st t so you guys
is this the old one okay so the price is
going to be tickets for besides next
year so that's it and that's it yeah so
the no any new that tell probably
wouldn't be here that we spoke to them
earlier yeah so the second team which
which is s XS SDF so if you guys aren't
here just come down please
they are still there
closely and it was a really close call
between them and probably yes like 60
points or something
Jack you're gonna come over also to give
first yeah so yeah he printed the the
price so I think it's he printed the
price him and Anna so which is was you
this really really nice so actually she
made the one that has electronics and
shines and parlor come on man and
you guys also get tickets for next year
[Applause]
so and now for the less price for the
winning team which is prob'ly
will also win let me just show this
which was made by Anna and Thiago
Anna you have to do you have to which is
really good which is really a badass
like a round of applause alright
it's really badass really nice
come on it was a lots of flowers right
these are unique prices no one else has
[Laughter]
and you guys will also win tickets for
next year and then the less Brian and
like we remember that yeah before buying
I don't know it's an idea which is good
and the price like this this is
something that no one in the world has
yes not even us
not even us so there are only you can
show it why yeah yeah so and this is
like any Hecker needs a hoodie so yeah
this is a badass oudy with a low go and
see well since as you can imagine we had
no idea so we'd these multiple sizes
yeah you guys just work it out I don't
care okay show everyone how cool you
look in
okay so okay so basically this this was
it
we had should have a slide with sponsors
and so on yeah we didn't have yeah we do
have of course you do yeah so basically
hope everyone enjoyed it so these were
like 80 slides them today so yeah yeah
so well wrapping this up I hope you guys
all enjoyed it
we're really going to read all of this
at least flipple put them on Google or
something and see what we're going to do
next year obviously there will be a
besides for sure you're okay we're okay
that's Google just trying to update a
problem and you can't let the root key
all control although control over here
okay I hope everyone had fun at least I
think it was yeah I think you did a ping
or something can I just ask everyone
with the red shirt to come down here to
do the mark it's not like the first time
we did exactly Wow
come on everyone yes so basically
obviously yeah although through the
names of favorites so we have their
Paulo we have Thiago we have money we
have Cooper we have Philippe Philippe
again Herman Bruno Bruno Claudio George
David and Pedro and also when it was not
here yes thank you guys
and and and obviously thank you to all
of you that came here and it's still
here at this time obviously to all the
speakers who actually came just to give
the talk it's interesting fact that we
actually this year said that we would
support a partial at least at least
partial part of costs no speaker that
was here in these two days actually asks
for that support so I think it means a
lot for knowing that um which is
basically we get to do more things with
with it those values either this year or
next year and again thank you all of you
think all the speakers thank all the
sponsors and see you in next
[Applause]