thank you know so first of all thank you
for being here
no no already presented the name of our
talk it's going to be about mostly about
men in the browser attacks will will
demo our own Trojan and discuss the
damage that one can do with it then
we'll move on to defense scenarios and
we'll present a new approach to defend
against this type of threats so for the
ones that are not familiar with the men
in the browser attacks we chose to quote
the wasp definition but basically it all
starts when a user's device gets
infected usually through some sort of
email phishing campaign I told you not
to click that attached
excel file and and then the Trojan just
quietly sits for the user to access one
of the infected websites and when it
does it's able to freely modify the HTTP
requests and responses and they are able
to inject arbitrary code into the web
page and to exfiltrate sensitive
information so this all happens the
trojan accesses the network stream after
decryption but before the browser
renders the the web page so and ends the
name main in the browser so it's useful
for you to use SSL in your websites you
should totally do it
but it does nothing to prevent these
attacks from happening but many in the
browser is not new they have been around
for some time let's do a quick incursion
into time so the first many the browser
trojan was used in 2007 and this was ten
years ago
Wow ten years old soon enough it will
not require an ID to violate
it's source code was released in 2011
which actually opened the doors to many
other men in the browser trojans so
below you can see a picture that
illustrates what we call a web inject
you can see that it has a target URL
which in this case is intentionally
redacted and it has some sections to
specify the injection and where to
inject so in this case it's adding one
field to the form asking for the user's
ATM PIN and as you know it doesn't
matter how dumb these things are and all
there are always lots of people that
will fall for this the second one I
would like to highlight is
timba it was first seen in 2012 and it's
special because it was the very first
one to tamper with HTTP headers it
actually only removed one header a very
specific header the X frame options
which allows the attacker to load the
web site inside the iframe for instance
and and then they can pursue and do a
click tracking attack against the
website but we don't have time to go to
cover all the men in the browser Trojans
so this table summarizes or includes
some of the most well-known Trojans when
the browser Trojans and their
capabilities so from left to right you
can see that they are able to do forum
grabbing they can collect data in any
form and they can do web injects that I
already mentioned and these two are
almost mandatory for any man in the
browser Trojans so they probably include
these two for sure but there are other
capabilities like keylogging the ability
to do data harvesting and Exel tration
remote access or also known as rat
Trojans and they are some of them a few
are capable of spreading outs like worms
they also can use web fakes or copies of
websites that the users will will
actually navigate but they are accessing
a different web server and finally the
HTTP headers tampering that timber is
capable of so here you can see the most
prevalent trojans in the first quarter
of 2002 a study by IBM and it's
interesting because the top three is
Zeus which was the first if you remember
and is still in the first position and
the second and third never question go
see our actual variants of Zeus so in
many ways they haven't changed for quite
a while and they are still effective and
still in the world doing damage also
they keep changing their web injects and
so it's becomes hard to detect when they
are actually modifying the web page
because they change the the scripts they
change the message and they do it to to
spread out to to other regions other
countries and other verticals main the
browser Trojans they are responsible for
millions in losses they they spread out
through different industries and they
have infected literally millions of
different devices across the globe so
but the the thing is it's no one knows
the real size of this problem I mean we
don't know how many men in the browser
trojan attacks go and notice but to give
you a couple of examples in 2007 go Z
was able to compromise 160 devices from
NASA
I guess the attacker was anxious to know
if we really landed on on the moon or
not and in 2010 Citadel was able to
to capture half a billion dollars but
this this problem is really important
and I think that we all should pay more
attention to it if you think about it it
doesn't matter if we are able to fix all
the vulnerabilities in our web
applications because even if we could do
it it doesn't matter for a man in the
browser attack because they don't need
vulnerabilities in order to do web
injects they can freely modify the
application let's take a look now at
some of the standards that you can use
to defend web applications on the client
side
starting with CSP content security
policy so it's meant to prevent script
injections into pages so you can set a
bunch of policies to you say to specify
which scripts can be loaded and from
where and you can do that with with the
header a special header or with the meta
tags it has some limitations it requires
a lot of configuration and maintenance
and I'd like to emphasize one of the
limitations which is it does not apply
to browser extensions so this is major
actually the the authors of the standard
they simply think that this is out of
scope for CSP to protect against any
code injection from browser extensions
here you can see an example so basically
on the top in blue you can see a policy
which basically allows same-origin
scripts but also scripts loaded from
www.example.com
the the the ash in that rule if they
don't the scripts will be blocked and it
will be sent a notification to that
endpoint that is specified there's also
a version
we're blocking does not occur just the
reporting and you can see the basic
structure it's a different header next
HP key P so HP key P is intended to pin
a certificate to a certain web server
into the browser so this is meant to
reduce the possibility of many in the
middle attacks with in with forged
certificates it it's kind of not really
supported by many browsers for instance
ie edge and Safari so it has received a
lot of support in Chrome but chrome just
announced that they are moving away from
this standard because it really caused a
lot of problems with with websites being
locked out if their certificate for some
reason doesn't match the certificate in
the user's browser here you can see an
example and again I'd like to emphasize
one thing which is it has the capability
of reporting to an end point if the
certificate is not matched
lastly the a chest yes which is meant to
enforce the use of SSL in your website
it's it protects web sites against
protocol downgrades and cookie hijacking
and well there's nothing really
particular about a chest yes but it
doesn't do anything against many in the
browser attacks so do you see the trend
a lot of this browser security is being
done using headers but there's a huge
caveat if you remove the headers you
will completely bypass these defenses so
this is what has been developed in the
in the scope of the w3c and also if we
were able to somehow prevent those
either
from being stripped no standard no
current standards is able to prevent the
script injection as I said CSP doesn't
do anything to block any script
injection from browser extensions as a
side note it's interesting to see that
as some of these standards they have
reports back capabilities which is
interesting because security
professionals they want to know when
their policies are being offended right
so then then we thought man this is bad
and want to make it worse that's when we
decided to do our own Trojan and here is
where I passed the token to to Paulo
that will demo and talk about all Trojan
and and following by a demo ok so let me
first say that this is my first besides
is it on ok awesome
let me first maybe ask you how many of
you access your banking own banking
banking system using a browser ok cool
how many of you have a different browser
profile to access your key banking and
do serve Facebook or other you have two
three four five six okay cool
not bad as a security company and maybe
as most of you we want to break things
and our main goal was to break HTTP
either based security standards like CSP
of course we want to do this but also
pass unnoticed so behave like a real
Trojan and recently we did a big effort
reverse engineering some men in the
browser Trojans to understand how they
actually work and we thought that those
would be nice starting point we are
talking
about C++ code and it is not bad you can
get it online it's available but then
the development process you can imagine
it was changed the source code compile
the source code get the binary which is
a builder then run the Builder to get a
dropper then move the dropper to the
victims computer
infect the victims computer and then see
if anything has changed on the victims
environment so it was not quite easy to
move forward fast to prove our point so
there's another another issue all of
them they are binary windows binary
Trojans so the audience is Windows only
so we thought that make it even bigger
and what we can run broadly and browser
extensions you use the browser to access
web so let's run inside the browser in
browser extensions looks really
interesting we master web technologies
javascript HTML CSS so the development
process nice and friendly they also run
on Windows Linux Mac doesn't matter if
there's a browser we can run there so
cool even bigger audience and we have
also some extra points CSP does not
apply to Chrome extensions browser
extensions sorry what is cool but we
want to defeat them anyway and also
browser extensions they are developed by
anyone and they are known to have all
sort of security vulnerabilities PDF GS
have cross-site scripting the early
stage and we can get these also from a
dog extension so it's an interesting
point and if there's something
interesting about browser extensions and
let me choose my words they can read and
change all your data on the website that
you visit the
is cool even if you just want to know
the weather the extension will read and
change all your data on all websites you
visit browser extensions they are
developed on top of a broken permission
model like mobile applications are in
this is cool because we want to install
the mobile application or the browser
extension and we just say yes we want it
we accept it we know it no problems and
in fact they can change completely how
your application looks like any
application ok
all applications all websites they can
inject JavaScript so they can tamper
with data change data still data do
whatever the attacker wants and even
they can pass and notice what is really
cool so then ok let's choose which
browser we want to target and chrome
right now is the most used the chrome
extensions documentation is really good
so easy to go then of course we have to
thought about architecture we are
developing and we want to do a great job
and we started about modular approach
using implants implants are something
interesting you don't have to put there
the feature inside the extension or the
malware you can just pull it remotely so
you can offer a nice extension and then
pull the malware when it's done its
installed
so of course our goals were to temper
with effort because we want to break the
standards but we also want to implement
all the major features we saw on the men
in the browser Trojans and so I would
say that our biggest requirement would
be to have a stealthy extension in this
case Chrome extension and by stealthy we
mean that we want users to download our
extension and use it we want to solve
users a problem they have so they will
download our extension of course we want
to make the maximum
our audience so let's see what users are
looking for on the store and pass
unnoticed of course we don't want them
to notice that we are doing dangerous
stuff and also bypass antivirus and
firewalls so searching on the chrome
store what we get adblock and ad
blockers in general are the most
downloaded extensions anyone has a ad
blocker oh cool so adblock claims 40
million users what is cool and they will
read and change all your data on the
websites you visit cool again so we took
from our imagination to create the ad
block plus extension I would say that we
can get also 40 million users and we
even they asked also to display the
notifications but we kept it simple and
we will just we haven't changed all your
data on the websites you visit so every
man in the browser Trojan has a command
and control server this means that you
have the client part which you install
driven by download you need ad blocker
and this is the best one and we have the
server from where implants will be taken
the malicious part and also the
configuration so this was not our main
focus so we kept it simple but we made
something distributed so we have plenty
of servers spread all over the world and
they can send the stolen data and pull
configurations any plans from everywhere
they send the reports and then
everything gets pushed to an
elasticsearch instance because we were
expecting much data so let's keep it
simple and get the right tool to get the
job done just to give you a brief
introduction to Chrome extensions
because then comes the best part
this is the lifecycle they offer
developers so as we want to break others
we have before us and others and we have
also the others we see as you if you're
familiar with JavaScript on and on our
events they are triggered allowing a
synchronous programming so the
performance impact on page loads and
runtime is really low so it's cool we
will be passed and noticed so our first
question and our starting point was can
we modify others if the developer tools
can read them and show them so should we
and in fact with just a few lines of
code we did it
and as lazy as we should be we went to
developer tools and check whether the
others were removed but they were there
unchanged but this and better this way
they were there unchanged but in fact
they were dropped but because this works
on a chain of responsibility the first
one to read will see the original
message then the next one will change
but it doesn't go back to the starting
point so you will see the other on the
developer tools but it is taken out so
many in the browser trojans they do not
change the Dom but they tamper with
markup this means that they inject like
we saw before the pin field on the HTML
on the wire and then when when it gets
rendered on the browser the field is
already there Chrome extensions they do
not allow it okay cool
maybe we can think that this is a
security strategy but there's a feature
request to allow it and the guys are
just taking longer because they are
concerned about performance so soon we
will be able also to change the response
body in fact we were digging and we
could do it and instead of using the web
request API we could you
have used debugger and we would have
been able to change the also the
responsible but then every time we try
to do it this will break our stealthy
requirements so we gave up about
changing the responsibility because we
can change the bomb and we will do it
even better because no one will notice
this is how extensions work so this is
the overall architecture we have right
now ok so we have the client we have our
implants which get pulled from our
command and control server then we
collect stuff in here and listen to
their command and control server which
then push it to the elasticsearch
database and hopefully we'll make profit
from it so I'd say that everyone wants
to attack not only to be found and what
we have next is we will craft the attack
oh I came together let me have just let
me show you so we said that we would
offer users a feature that they want and
this is something that we don't want to
see on our pages when we are reading the
news
so let's enable our extension and go to
the same website and get the webpage
free of advertisement okay so I think
that we have epic customers right now so
it's time to pull implants and start
playing around with users and let's
choose I'm sorry because I'm not so
familiar with Mac OS shortcuts it's f
how sorry okay cool so let's choose our
okay in this is okay control cool let's
choose our targets let's think a world
where there's only single eventing
solution and all of us we are customers
of beautiful banking okay this should
look like a banking okay this is the e
banking website we will attack okay cool
so what I will do next or we will do
together next so how can we move this to
half screen again okay
let's start from the beginning let's try
to make our attack even bigger and
instead of focusing only on the web
strategy of this Bank
let's also offer the customers of
vehicle Bank fake mobile application
probably some of the users they have
their mobile device rooted or jailbroken
and you'll get your fake mobile
application downloaded and installed so
let's use the homepage to communicate
users or tell the users that there's a
new mobile application ok so what we
need is to tamper with the little Bank
homepage and show them some announcement
of the new application what is in here
is just pop up let me just okay I'm not
on the right side
let's visit visual bank again the full
screen app ok gosh so this is now how
visual Bank user will see the website ok
so what looks a legit advertisement ok
and even you can go to what we call a
web fake a web site where you can
download the mobile application ok
there's nothing here which can trigger
the user that he is being tricked
ok and there's something interesting
here regarding these advertisements now
can I do it ok pop up the debugger
as we said before and let me show you
the network this website is take
security seriously and they use the
latest stand standards available so they
only accept images from their own domain
ok and data which should be built in the
built in the market itself but if we
have a look on where images are coming
from they are coming from a secure
website called lay google.com ok so the
standard is not working but we said
before that it does not apply to browser
extensions so let's just move this again
ok and let's see how beautiful Bank
works so that we can craft our own
attack so a user comes to visual bank
then he has to sign in this is F okay
and doing much better right now they
should login and maybe it would be cool
to gather all visual bank users
credentials so let's update our
configuration file the tamper is done
let's grab all user authentication
tokens ok and let's move on then we will
behave and do the rest
so let's sign in so when user gets in
his account we land we'll land on a page
with our details all the details about
our credit cards account balance okay so
let's place a transaction order ok it
would be cool to also collect credit
card data balances and other stuff so
to do it at the glance let's take a
screenshot from that page alright okay
we are taking a screenshot from this
page also okay
screenshot is then also but what about
the transaction
okay let's place pay our rent
but let's take all the money to our own
accounts okay
and this just requires a few lines of
code let's make it easy what this means
is that instead of sending to the
destination account the user fills let's
send it to our one account so a few
lines of JavaScript will hijack the
submit event of the form prevent user
data to reach the server and we will put
there our one okay I have here what
looks like a shorter version but is
exactly the same let's take this
configuration with us to our
configuration file okay but let's paid
our rent and see how it works okay it
requires a second authentication factor
cool this is something standard right
now but we can see that the user will
have access to the transaction details
so to do a professional job let's do it
right and let's change also in because
if we place there our destination
account the user will see that the money
is being transferred to a different
account so let's do the right thing and
also tamper with the details so that the
user won't notice that we are just
redirecting the funds and so we should
be done with a full attack if we confirm
the authentication code
this is the resume of the transaction so
we have a complete workflow for a funds
transfer what we should do now is see
this in action so what I will do next I
will show you the attacker side by side
on the right side we will see the
attacker perspective where we will
collect data I'm not doing okay
and ice I told you before that we were
lazy so we will use coupon to get live
data on our side let me make it live
updating now totally fresh every five
seconds so let me just clean the
database where is no PC here well
besides videos okay and right now
database is clean so let's start on the
left side where we have the victims the
victims browser
so let's visit the vehicle bank where we
will be shown the advertisement okay
which we will close and just in a while
we get on the right side a report saying
that the user let me think
def F just to make it bigger right now
we know that the user who visit the
homepage we have also IP and other stuff
here
he saw the banner okay
just showing the advertisement to the
mobile application so let's
no no okay let's just disclose this we
don't want to go there but let's make
our identification okay and let's see
what we get on the attackers website so
again we have a report and you can see
my ID and password okay so as lazy as we
were before let's see what screenshot we
got from the client side okay okay this
is not the whole page but it's the
account details so we can get everything
at the glass so let's move on with our
transaction okay it's again on the side
cool I have to put this bigger
okay where other than Ella okay better
this way then so a new transaction and
now it's time to see we have the other
window yes
okay what we have now another report
saying that the form was ejected and
what happens when the form is ejected
let's again pay our landlord the rent
okay and this is what we expect to see
here and when we confirm the transaction
we have also the destination account
there but in fact the funds were
transferred to a different account
number as we saw an eye our eject source
code so I have something else to show
you because our main goal was to defeat
content security policy so I need to
show you how it looks when you have a
policy enabled so this is how we test
the browser this is the official web
page standards so if you have your
content security policy enabled as you
can see here everything is green and
let's just have a look on this test so
this image won't to be loaded because
it's coming from third-party domain
which is not allowed so let's break it
and allow drop the policy what may allow
resources to get downloaded from
anywhere or everywhere and this should
be enough to load the image from
wherever you want okay and break all the
other stuff this means that right now we
can run JavaScript from anywhere what
kind of JavaScript we won't load
resources from everywhere so if you're
relying on content security policy to
hide or at least
feel safe safer due to cross-site
scripting or any other security
vulnerability you're not sure that the
browser is applying the content security
policy because we something can drop the
policy so you should be sure that you're
not the cross-site scripting vulnerable
or any other kind of vulnerability and
then you can also leverage this if you
want to have fun you can maybe keep your
competitors from the game and let's make
the world better again and take Google
out of our Google Beauty and let's use
really search engine who respects our
privacy so how can we move back to the
presentation okay
we had also the goal to pass unnoticed
so we have a tool we can make money do
you saw the numbers of the market but we
had also the goal to pass unnoticed to
all the security tools we have on the
client side or also server side so
laughs firewalls in general and
antivirus most of them they work with
signatures they know something they take
a picture they know how what to look
like to identify what is going on so
taking advantage from polymorphic
JavaScript we can bypass them and how
does this work we just write our source
code we pass them through some tool and
we get different versions doing the same
but looking differently
what makes that even if they have a
signature then five seconds later our
payloads or our implants they will look
different
they will pass easily these kind of
validations so what does this all mean
that you're not safe or you're not safer
even if you're applying the latest
standards either based for security so
you should be sure that your
applications are not vulnerable and you
have companies here which can help you
finding your security vulnerabilities
and fixing them you should also if
you're offering services over the
Internet if you have applications you
should care about your users because if
something happens with user data user
profiles user money your brand has a
problem your company has a problem so we
should think our applications not only
keeping the server and the assets safe
but also all the flow should be safe we
should deliver something safe and safe
safely and you should think about
extensions they will become a standard
yesterday Mozilla was in a roadshow in
East their next November 14th
Mozilla will release his quantum browser
and Mozilla dropped Firefox extensions
and they will implement the same API
which they are pushing to be a standard
than Chrome ok I had the chance to ask
them and about these questions and they
kind of don't know they are implementing
the same API probably they are not
expecting the same issues but I think
that they do not thought about them so
we should think about this as a global
problem if we want to deliver rich
browsers allowing users to do whatever
they want they can compromise our
applications so we truly believe that we
don't need to develop any more binary
malware to offer only to Windows users
mostly to you
Windows users because we can
get a better budget if we deliver
Trojans to browser extensions because
most of the time we are using the
browser not specifically the operating
system but we are not only he we are not
here only today only to show you
problems we want to make this something
more interesting so what can we do to
take security a step further thank you
so we thought what else is there to
defend against this taking a look to
solutions that are not standards but
commercial solutions in the market there
are a few solutions that we thought
about how they could potentially avoid
these type of problems ok what about now
better I'll try to speak up ok so one of
the solutions is device fingerprinting
and geolocation
they don't work against men in the
browser type of attacks because the user
is using his device and it's probably
accessing the web page from his usual
location so there's nothing that you can
gather from using this type of
techniques fraud monitoring might work
in some cases but remember that many in
the browser they can be very subtle on
the way that they change the page and
the way they change the the transactions
the example that you just saw from Paulo
they were only modifying the destination
account number so considered that it was
a one-off transaction to someone how can
the bank potentially know that this
isn't a good transaction that that it is
a fraudulent transaction they can't know
so there are lots of ways for fraud
monitoring to fail and then you have
bought detection and behavior based
detection which won't work either
because the user is in command they are
controlling the the website they are
navigating through the websites so that
the the men in the browser is just
passively waiting for the user to take
the actions and to modify as few things
they can and as healthy as they can be
to modify the user experience and and
commit to fraud and we propose a new
approach which is called application
real-time monitoring in which basically
we are continuously monitoring the
webpage Dom for any modification from
any non expected modification and for
script injections that might be
modifying the native api's and hijacking
events so it just need to continuously
monitor the page
we recommend the white white leasing
approach because we we learn from
anti-viruses that you cannot possibly
recognize everything that is malicious
now and in the future but we you have to
use something like machine learning to
deal with the false positives because
some of the changes they will not be
they will be benign and and as soon as
you detect something you just send out
notifications real-time notifications to
the backend of the application to web
hooks to to any API and that can
potentially trigger reactions from the
web application back-end sides so they
can if they know that something is
beings happening they can stop the user
from logging in they can't cancel
transactions they can do a lot of things
they can call the user and this is a
very powerful effect if this is
transmitted in real time so it allows
the page also to self-heal because if we
know that the Dom for instance is being
modified we can
revert that or try to do it but in order
for this approach to even work it needs
code protection because otherwise the
men in the browser Trojan might just
tamper with with the defense code like
it does with the normal code from the
webpage and for that we recommend code
protection that has runtime application
self protection capabilities because it
needs to be to be resilient against code
tampering and other types of JavaScript
based attacks okay now let's do a short
demo of the this approach and just sit
okay so what you are seeing is the
dashboard where so this is basically
operated by the security team of the web
application is not available for the
end-user and in this page I will load
the virtual banking application that you
just saw okay so the solution is not
enabled yet so you you are seeing the
tampering and I would like to show you
as well a non-infected version a profile
that's clean and with no with no
extensions and to load the same website
so as you can see no banner in this
version okay so let's just quickly
enable the solution and for that I just
need to add the scripts which is
commented out right now like me and
comment it and just start the script
again okay and now let me load the same
web page again virtual banking so as you
could see for a split second you saw the
banner there but it was automatically
removed and here you can see in the
dashboard that we are seeing receiving
alerts real-time notifications of the
tampering that just happened in the code
page so we can see the IP of the end
user the user agents being use the URL
and you can see it in full detail what
was the injection so it's highlighted in
red and you can see details like the
links for play google.com and as a
researcher you can use this type of
approach to have in full detail what the
tag looks like and just pursue these
information
and just follow it to discover the the
command-and-control
and to just try to take the the bots
down and protect your websites okay so
let's continue enter the online bank and
I haven't even logged in yet I'm already
seeing new threats coming in so let's
let's see what's happening here and I
see code poisoning happening in the page
and let's see the full details of this
and what happened here was that the form
the authentication form the non submit
event was changed to this code so you
can actually see the code and it's just
exit rating the credentials to the C -
let me login and here I am in the
account let's initiate the new
transaction as before and new threats
are coming in so I haven't submitted the
transaction form yet so potentially
because of the backend already received
the notification they could actually
prevent the transaction from being
accepted and also they could return like
something is off and even blacklist the
user from doing fraud from from doing
transactions and and while they sort
this out and call the user and we think
that your device might be in fact
infected and and for that reason you
cannot do transfers and this is for your
own goods to protect you from from money
being stolen from your account so in
this case we have new a new code
poisoning the the code is very easy to
read in this case in a real scenario it
wouldn't be
probably the the code might be
obfuscated and and hard to read so in
this case they are collecting the the
original name original destination
account number and just storing this in
session storage and at the last minute
because this JavaScript won't only
execute when you submit the form
they are just creating a new new form
elements with a different destination
account number and confirm the
transaction and like Paulo has shown you
before even the information that's being
shown in so you can see landlord even
the information that is being shown in
the confirm transaction page is being
tampered because the bank received a
different destination account number but
you want the user to see the name and
destination account number he was
expecting in order for him not to
suspect that something off is happening
and this is basically it so wrapping
sorry about that so wrapping this up we
saw that modern man in the browser
Trojans are capable of completely
compromising web applications by doing
Dom tampering and hijacking events and
doing API poisoning just injecting
arbitrary code into the web page and
they can exit rate sensitive information
trick the user into doing other things
like downloading fake mobile
applications and compromising the user's
mobile device they can they can just
steal money for instance in this website
and and and it was easy enough to to
completely defeat most application
security standards like CSP and other
types of standards that are based in
heathers
and other techniques we saw that they
cannot do nothing against this type of
attacks we also established that you can
use extensions for doing this I think I
believe that using extensions can
replace the traditional binary many in
the browser Trojans and they are very
easy to deploy very easy to develop very
easy to test and you can leverage social
engineering attacks like we developed
the adblock plus and it's very easy to
get thousands and thousands of users to
deploy your extensions
we haven't do it because we don't want
to go to jail so don't worry so the
codes we haven't released the code and
we will not but we are open for
questions
not offers for questions and and we
propose a new approach which is
basically if we cannot stop injections
from occurring let's try to detect it
and do real-time monitoring of
injections we think that's the reporting
the real-time monitoring is really
aligned with some of these standards so
we saw that CSP is able to report back
HP GP as well and and this is very
interesting because applications should
report back to to the backend and if
that happens automatically even better
because developers are using usually
they are not that good at knowing what
to detect and what to report so we
shouldn't rely on developers to do that
and as application security specialist
is best that that technology is
installed transparently and reports back
to the backend and then have developers
leverage the notifications to do further
reactions in line with the business
logic and that's it that's all we had so
thank you and we are open to your
questions if you have
[Music]
[Applause]
hi I actually have two questions but one
of them is the first one is dealing with
your method of avoiding the issue just
have you tried to use the technique to
in a fat web app like Gmail that has a
gazillion events happening and money
changing the web application in real
time and what's the side effect of that
I will curation with your solution and
the second one is have you considered
using web workers as a way to avoid the
detection or this log enos of the inter
users browser interface since we're
workers work on the background it's
easier to hide your stuff okay so if I
understood correctly you are worried
about this scale right the number of
events and how it so basically I can
translate your question - does this
scale right okay yes cueing uh-huh yeah
I think that's definitely a challenge we
we defend that the real time monitoring
must be intelligent in order to scale so
you cannot possibly check for everything
all the time so you need to have some
things getting whitelisted and so that
you won't do like follow-up processing
on that so you need to have both machine
learning and some heuristics just to see
if some some modification is malicious
is
potentially malicious and if if if if
it's not you just like just don't don't
analyze it further and and just focus on
the ones that I port potentially
malicious and your second question was
web workers in fact the web worker our
attack is even because when you deliver
the extension there's nothing there and
yesterday we saw a presentation about
file was attacks and in fact we are not
storing nothing on files you are pulling
the malicious code from the command and
control server so we just have to bypass
what's on the network and today the the
implant will start with AAA and tomorrow
can start or five seconds later you can
start with BBB it's completely different
if you whitelist or black which the
first one the second one will pass so we
we don't have to even use web workers or
what else to hide the malicious part of
the extension because it's anywhere it's
all already persistent I mean any more
questions one over there if you're using
if you're using machine learning and
especially you know my affection for
sorry I I'm not hearing you well okay if
you're using machine learning and
anomaly detection for your solution
how are you establishing the baseline
using a training period okay so it's and
it's for each application use real users
but not live data okay okay thanks yes
machine weather is it right or wrong so
even if you have you can you don't have
an environment where you can do the
training period if you allow the
application to run on prediction and you
have someone supervising the the machine
learning you can do exactly the same and
probably even better if you have a lot
of traffic you can do it faster one last
question
No okay so we're we're gonna have a
coffee break now there's per station at
downstairs and I guess you have to run
because they're running out
[Applause]