Oliver are you enjoying the conference I
really like it that's my second time
here last year I spoke myself I
presented my master thesis it was great
this year it's even greater because I
have not the pressure of being speaker
myself I really enjoyed just come from a
workshop it was great I come again next
year for sure we look very much forward
to seeing you next year as well thank
you for any sincerity now so you you
feel like being taught yesterday can you
tell us a little bit about that yes yes
well the highlights was that many people
walked away I hope it was just because
there was food no it was the last one of
the day right no was the first one no so
basically in the past month and actually
years I started to think about many
different things so that's why we coined
it very briefly a philosophical security
talk it's about the phrase security as
an enabler where I started to think
about that phrase because I had
encounters with friends in their work
spaces but also in my work space with
with people mostly project managers to
come and say hey security is an enabler
come on help me and so on and I am all
for this I I in some projects I really
helped I think as security we need to be
open but I started to think about
security as an enable that is does that
fit when you're inside a company or
should it only fit when you have a
product and you want to sell a product
so as a USP and I came to do well sort
of a conclusion I'm not finished I'm
still thinking and reading up on Ross
Anderson from Cambridge University not
mistaken who wrote some papers on the
economics of security so I'm reading up
there and I'm starting to I want Ida to
write an essay or give a talk on that
and the essence is figuring out is the
phrase security as an enable is it wrong
is it good
when is it good when is it wrong and my
feeling is sometimes people try to throw
around the phrase or interestingly not
many people knew the phrase but maybe
you know the feeling the feeling when
people come and talk to you like it's a
quarter to five you actually want to go
home you're tired and they come and say
hey I need this firewall request now you
need to help me if you're not here
thousand people can't work tomorrow so
you gotta kind of pressured into some
stuff and I once had a had a person
coming into my office at literally 5:00
p.m. and I wanted to jump to the Train
and they said I need this five hundred
people hi xx can't work otherwise and I
started to look at it and said yeah well
that's great with my conscious that is
not going to happen he wasn't very happy
about that at the end but yeah that
that's the important thing I think as a
security professional you have to you
have to keep your cool in that situation
because everyone wants to to work for
the business we all work for the bottom
line without a business that goes well I
don't get paid so it goes to that half
half the conscience that you have to
work for the bottom line but you also
have to work for the security there is a
trade-off we all know the trade-off and
it boils down to two risk management at
the end and make sense well which
reminds me of the Builder let's go the
world room yeah so not sure if you want
together and we were to interview people
for security team and we had a guy had a
PhD actually came and he came in and one
question we asked him was okay so you're
in a scenario where the CEO comes to you
and says we were hacked what do you do
and the guy was just said you know his
reply was well tough luck and I'll build
the war room checker you know that was
his answer and you know there needs to
be more to that place there needs to be
what does the CEO mean by hacked the
Perry's phone is it something
like there was a whole bunch of process
that need to happen before build a war
room and it's the exact same type of
problem right you can just you need to
keep calm and you need to put security
on top of probably the all the
priorities that you have at that
particular moment and not well and not I
really think it's about realizing daily
where I am I act
what is if somebody comes to me what is
their goal what do they want from me and
I mean I always worked in in small
companies and I work in a larger company
and I had to get used to the politics
sort of at the beginning I thought maybe
they come to me because they think they
can can play with me I'm not so known to
the politics and but later on I realize
now they come to me because I have quite
creative ideas to help them because I do
feel yes the DNA blur in me I want to
enable the business to do things and
there are many ways how you can do
something in a secure way it just takes
sometimes a little bit more time and
patient exactly and one great thing is I
worked with a with a project manager on
a nice project and I went to him and
told him look something is not right
here I we need to rethink this and he
actually went back to the sponsor and
told them we need more time and we ended
up having I think five times the man
days off of office as a similar project
which which was interesting because a we
had to defend there but we could defend
it because I I kept track I kept track
what I was doing I kept track why I was
doing things I wrote I wrote risk
assessments things that that that people
really liked because it helped them
understand what where do I come from
I come from risk management at the end
for me I think JP said it very good this
morning it is it is about risk
management security is about risk
management
keep that in mind there is I see a lot
of Pam test reports and I love the work
these guys are doing but sometimes pen
testers miss the risk management part of
their work it's it's when when you have
the urge to scream yes I I found
something really cool you did but is it
really that critical for the company and
when you come back to the security as an
enabler I do think that all the
consulting work so Pam testing or
security consulting and advisories
they really are security as an enable
because it's what I sell they sell
security many companies if you work
in-house in security you work more for
the trust the trust that clients trust
in you you don't you don't really sell
security anymore you sell trust to to to
company s to clients especially if you
work in the financial industries right
side that boils down to you trust with
your money that company and if a company
is constantly hacked and this is not
doing a good job
it probably sees it in in the client
numbers I think there's a problem there
which is it's going against this nature
right so you're you're saying that you
know as a pen tester I have this thing
of like I found something yeah you know
and you don't think about risk
management but the reality is that's
their nature like I get paid if I find
more vulnerabilities that means I'll get
called again that it girls like risk
management will not beneficial solution
absolutely they would have to fight
against themselves I have a great story
we when I was apprenticed I had a
customer who who'd is really a good job
and I had three days testing time so he
was a short assessment and I was working
three days like mad I couldn't find
anything on the first day it's like okay
yeah you have to get used to whatever is
in front of you on the second time you
normally start finding some stuff right
and then the third day you find even
more and when I arrived at the third day
I was I was really down I was I was
depressed I was like that it can't be
can't be I really don't have anything so
some low-risk stuff yes cookies with you
always fine but not really something
that I can show off more often yes and
there I think there is important to have
a decent manager that that leads you and
my manager told me look we are doing
work with them for many years now it's
you that's doing the assessment so we
wanted to have a fresh pair of eyes on
it I know that this shows is our
previous work was yes and I had this
situation as a panther so you found
something juicy and you were jumping up
and down and you wanted to scream it
from the top of your lungs because you
found something and I did that as well I
I really did that as well and I think
you can you can defend it by saying well
I don't see the inside of the company so
I can't really tell what is the exact
risk when I was apprenticed I always
told the guys look this is the report
this is what I see as a risk but please
assess the risks yourself exactly I just
don't know if if the companies really
have the time for that or if they just
take take the report and and adapt to
what you have a right in there I can
think of many companies not having the
time anymore because let's face it time
is time is money nobody has time that is
a big issue