and now joining us Bruna Morrison and as
usual Victor Minns man great conference
yeah who needs improving still is
improving please say man well maybe
we've kind of outgrown this fanny
we had 90% of people showing up which is
I think amazing and we not counting the
staff and so on so we have over I guess
300 people here and it's I think we
needed a bigger space get everyone one
of the things that I personally we had
to do this this choice last year and you
did it again was to run the keynotes in
parallel I prefer to have one keynote
you know everyone there but that means
that would have to have us places yeah
very big at the same yeah either a
bigger room yeah to get everyone
everyone yeah it's not even about be
here this room actually could feed a few
people in the g6 it's like a floating
room yeah we can people in every room
yeah but also we can't have more than
like 180 people on that room just like
the office all right that's one of the
things I think I mean generally I think
things are still going very well
the feedback has been quite positive of
course others organization we we do know
a few things that maybe didn't go as
well but hopefully you know one not this
isn't too much so I think it's pretty
cool
my first question will be around women
applying submitting how like how did the
numbers look like and what do you think
we missed or didn't miss honestly I
don't know of for the CFP I think we
have one submission from for a woman as
attendees I think there's I don't have
the numbers probably we could look them
up but obviously a lot less than then
and Men but I think there are quite a
few a woman wrong
so what let's I don't know honestly I
don't have very strong opinion on that I
think if there's women that have
interesting things to to submit them to
come speak I'm sure they will be well
accepted here
I think well looking at what usually is
happening down the Twitterverse and so
on regarding conferences honestly here
and you guys have been here for also all
the editions
I never seen any any any issues on the
men on that regard so I think people
either gender or whatever are all
welcome and relish receives here so I
think it's just a matter of people
really coming up and it's not enough to
vote more comfortable and entertaining
and on and submitting an end coming to
speak because I still remember in the
early days that we both well it wasn't
the besides it was confer it we just the
physician it was it at the Apple store
was it yeah
so what's other kind of sorts of the
Apple and had I don't know 20 seats and
and right now we have a lot of people so
yep so it took some time it took some
patience and you took some also some a
fulfillment from you guys for learning
in said to put this forward and do
actually promoted so it is quite really
amazing and I was just having an
interview with Thomas sure exactly I
tried to to get some some feedback when
many tried to compare this comfort this
besides be done in what in London and he
actually told me that you can't compare
because this is just the community
itself yeah I did it different types and
setups of community I mean London they
have more a bigger one there and then
rather than here and and a another do
believe that as we talked in the first
in the first interviewed is that this is
for the community this is for not just
for the Portuguese but also so so that
we can promote ourselves and can bring
some novelty and some some information
back back into the community which is
very good yeah and I think I think our
main aim
when when he started in 2013 me and
Thiago decided to just do it besides
easy because it was well we've got
movement through that so I won't repeat
it but there was nothing so let's try to
do something interesting in this area
but it's also always about the community
and the people involved and make make
this with with the people who actually
work in the area and you want to learn
more and share and everyone is a
volunteer so it's it's that perspective
and I think in starting with the the
issue of if it's a reissue of not not
many women applying or even giving talk
last year we did have I think at least
two at one workshop and also a speaker
we have women on staff who actually work
also in formation security cybersecurity
or everyone occult let's not get into
that and but but I think it's the same
issue as pitiful as oh was speaking
today and then the last last slide he
was trying to get a lot of in this case
Portuguese talent to to to come forward
and and start speaking and writing
things and so on so I think this is this
is is a general issue that people
sometimes need to feel more comfortable
either because they're shy or because
they they don't feel comfortable in
certain environment that in this case
it's up its its store eclis much more
male oriented or it's a lot more man but
again I think in our case I can speak
for the others I think our community and
our organization here and then the
people that attend our are very
inclusive friend and I hope that
everyone feels welcome and and
uncomfortable link moment speaking
enmity maybe maybe maybe for the next
Asian we can do a bridge or close the
gap between so I'm a young if a sector I
how can I talk about the the questions
that I have or the project I am working
on and how can I expose that to the
community in the matter that actually
they can initiate but also the wider
audience as people that actually don't
know about security
I'm sorry yeah well one thing that
that this event I think it will so well
as I understand this event is also for
InfoSec people but should should we
expand it to the wider audience like
those folks at our web summit or you
just keep it focus on the community
itself so that's a good question I like
that this specific conference is it's
much it's built by and oriented to
people in information security okay and
I think that there's value in that but I
also think that there may be value maybe
this is not the the exact maybe this is
not the conference for ya maybe it's it
is interesting to do something similar
but with a different audience for
developers and so on
next year yeah something more like I
have the security semi maybe people and
maybe developers that have have had an
experience and and contact with Moore's
criterion two things yeah to check on me
and share their experience with
literally a whole different area because
in terms of number of people and all
that it would have to be the guys from
where something tiny they have the
budget for it they have the bathroom for
it you know this probably is kind of
thing for stock events yeah yeah one
thing I would ask if you have to stay
like what still our biggest problem in
my opinion silver sponsors right and for
the conference yeah well it I think it's
each year that we actually that the
conference happens I think next year is
easier to get sponsors but yeah but
again being a somewhat local event
most of the sponsors that that come up
are local sponsors so it's not like
we're a full international conference
that we can get sponsorship from some
big-name
multinational company there's security
whatever so it's no net perspective it's
quite harder here is it's like the
managing how to get some some to to a
certain size which I think should not be
much bigger
but there's different opinions on the
team but yeah but I think the conceptual
is around 500 people not more than that
and actually being something that could
attract other sponsors to help us with
with expenses and with with anything
else again being this is not for profit
or anything so everything that we get
from sponsors even the tickets are have
just the five years that we collect is
basically just to make sure that people
don't not get it for free and not show
up which was a problem on the initial
years since its last year
okay so just wrap up this year event I'm
guessing that Wis we are gonna have
another one next year probably in the
bigger venue as we started the
conversation hopefully yeah
do we have already main theme for next
for next year you know not really we
haven't even discussed it well we have a
lot of ideas always like we need to we
need to look at the sheet yeah
yeah and we have a lot to discuss
furniture that's venue female role
program I think even organizationally we
need to do some changes like start
discussing things earlier and all that
but there definitely an event yeah sure
that's that's I draw it today event
right because this one was like why yes
probably probably yeah you'll see at
least one and a half I think work yeah
really well the CTF yesterday all you
have to know worked really well in the
poke in parallel for people who are not
at a CTF can can can watch the talks if
you get to be a venue with a bigger room
maybe we can do bigger things on the
first day because we are limited like
180 people it's gonna be amazing
yeah yeah it's gonna always like this
every year this year is is is going to
be epic so next year is going to be epic
er excellent thank you very much thank
you see you next year
adopting