hi welcome again to besides lisbon 2017
edition I'm here with Claudia from an
organization called talk the talk is
about the event itself so I ready had a
brief discussion with with Lulu before
about the event to pass the feature in
the present talk about what should I
expect from this event today okay so for
starters this is a technical conference
our focus is on technical presentations
Neteller main goal we that I don't want
people to be scared and okay this is too
technical while not understanding if you
understand some things obviously this is
this is very good to to raise awareness
in completely different areas we have
talks about Wi-Fi we have talks about
our web or Wi-Fi we have talks about web
applications mobile applications so okay
they are going to be some of them are
going to be pretty technical yeah okay
so but it's useful for the people that
even don't have knowledge on those
particular areas they will always learn
something and it's not kind of get
awareness of that issue if they didn't
know it might on the past so when the
things that Brennan told me is that this
is good well this started as a
community-driven event okay so bring the
community together do the events really
is a little bit bigger but it still is
so I'm assuming that if I'm coming to
the event I have some doubts some
questions I can approach the speakers I
can talk to the people around here yeah
during the network and talk about
security right that's that's what we
under there are some aspects of the
event itself all right so today we're
gonna have the first 1/3 of the event
because to the right the event is gonna
be one day and a half so just that just
bit close of the two two event today
event and in Jersey and I don't know if
you blue explained why it's the reason
of that because we last year we have an
serious number of talks okay it was we
basically just by a screening inside
which talks were the best do we have on
that way so infantry they're also good
talks they didn't made it to the final
day this day we even
we're almost the double of the
submissions for talks so we said we have
so
makuu talks we have to find a way to put
more speakers in use all right so it was
not it's not possible to have to
complete days but this was the best that
we can show and and also today we're
gonna have the CTF right so yeah right
now it's going going the duplicity of do
I need to bring my own team or I can
just toggle on and so we have to walk in
typically people gathering the team in a
precipitate we have the qualifications
online so people can afford the other
team online and participate we have some
same people that basically only have two
members and try to find no one maybe
they even didn't know each other but
they try to find the team so we have
that option people don't actually need
to know one another to participate so
it's more risky because at least two
persons is the minimum because yeah we
see it's going to be very hard to
participate honesty effect this but if
there is no no no we meet on that so
people could just reveal is there any
way for me to I don't know watch online
Oh door just on the results I don't
think they are online we have a
dashboard I'm not completely schweiz the
dashboard is online but right now only
unsightly excellent so and tomorrow
we're gonna have the full by gap
speakers three different tracks as I
cancel two main tracks from talks in one
workshop yeah all right so there's a lot
of content to be yeah the dead people
are going to talk about I'm assuming
that all of this content content is
going to be online being a portal to
YouTube I was mainly OkCupid it's just
amazing I need to hire that guy to edit
my videos basically quickly goes flying
all around all conferences of all
besides besides in non besides events
filming this it's amazing in is worker
it's just amazing so we're gonna have
the content quite fast online after
tomorrow yeah is there any from your
point of view as professional in this
area what are you expecting from
tomorrow obviously you have one or two
that you actually want to see on one
talk yeah yeah being part of the
unionization typically I cannot see it
or know sanneh talk and I haven't seen
all the talks all the videos on mass
edition so it it's there is repaired
but I think that we we have a several
talks with completely different subjects
that I think it we are going to be
pretty good the keynotes is obviously
the the I point of today Lian we have
two completely different matters and
when we two bit more technical that is
going to be Amazon talking about quantum
create also but it's going to be a
normally yeah not so insight in so not
not now beat invited is going to be
overwhelm for people to watch so I think
it's going to be a pretty cool session
and enormous wings one of the the
reference saw Anya Terra so III excited
to see is is talk anyway twenty
different theories we have talks about
Wi-Fi we have talks about where we have
twenty of different areas that some
persons might add more comfortable with
their particular subject another so it's
a metal shoes it's not easy I is not
very easy to choose one between on the
other but yeah it's gonna be it's gonna
be that we have video so if you cannot
see what one session they are able to
see many things that ask Bruno is about
this this mm-hmm
and he told me that well this is kind of
trendy because of the V sides and now
all of a yes right personality that we
are we were used to have um should we
expect one of these to have virus or
just so you don't actually you don't
know it's gonna be funny thing because
basically we order them as being all
non-functional sorry but some of them
six mighty in freaking you if they are
pretty no so so
[Applause]
so if someone still has a puppies right
really they have some surprise in our
some excellent thank you very much thank
you thanks