yours thanks Julio de guiche Camuto for
this sake last two shows in the dog the
computer much ago before flying glass
okay no no see kumudam photo cache
touching English okay so yeah I took
about post-mortem crypto and quantum
stuff I just to warn you these are very
low-tech slides you can notice the
handwritten stuff have very bad
handwriting I try to do my best and I
use my my six-year-old daughters during
application on her iPad and a stupid
pencil to draw everything might look a
bit weird but just it was different okay
so to start a cow I was looking for
pictures of quantum computer so I used
Google and stuff and I looked for fear
of fright images and a Google quantum
computer pictures but then I found this
so obviously these aren't quantum
computers is the same kind of computers
you have so III kept searching for
quantum computers and then I found this
the only way is no it's a quantum scalar
pendent energy guard
listen it reduces inflammation it
promotes unclamping upset and it
protects your DNA from damage whatever
it means and of course it fights cancer
cells
it increases energy and so and so and so
on an improved blood circulation
you can find it on Alibaba I don't know
if they have any left it's pretty
expensive but come on it's pretty
powerful there's just one thing that it
doesn't do you check this list it
doesn't break any cryptography so it's
kind of useless
an actual quantum computer would maybe
look like this big fish whereas the
cryptography we used today would be the
small fish so the purpose of this
keynote talk which is the first keynote
I give in my life ever is to explain you
why this big guy would be able to eat a
small guy and how the small guy could
defend itself against the big fish so I
want in turn into all the details of
explaining how quantum physics quark and
the ice
by questions and all this complex stuff
but just try to give you some very
basics of the principles behind a
quantum computer and try to convince you
that it's not that complicated it has
very basic mathematics so what's another
computer work with bits a bit is either
1 or 0 one of computers they work with
quantum bits that we call qubits and
this so we use some scary notation like
this alpha times this 0 cubed plus beta
times 1 this is just notations we use
alpha and beta but I could have used a
and B X&Y whatever but the point is is
that a qubit is characterized by two
numbers alpha and beta and they're not
real numbers they're complex numbers so
all the form for example a plus bi where
I is the imaginary unit and these two
numbers are called amplitudes
and amplitudes are a bit like quantum
probabilities if you will what did it
mean is that if you observe a qubit one
said this is a qubit I've never looked
at it I prepared it in my lab and it's
characterized by two values alpha and
beta and then I look at my qubit and
then it's either 1 or 0 I will observe
it equal to 0 with probability alpha
square and which I will observe it being
equal to 1 with probability beta square
so obviously alpha square plus beta
square must be equal to 2 1
and once I've observed it being 0 or 1
then it stays your 1 forever it doesn't
change anymore so the initial state is
called superposition which is kind of 0
at 1 at the same time but it's a bit
more complicated like you seen in this
comic they say ok superposition it
doesn't remain 0 n 1 at the same time
it's something more complex
mathematically you can see it as a
combination of stuff but the bottom line
is that you can directly explain it
using concept that we're familiar with
it's quantum it's magic it's it's
complicated
now how to compute with this kind of
thing so on a classical computer we have
for example a logic gate or negation
a zero comes in and a 1 comes out
stupid you have one number in whenever
out with a qubit remember a qubit is
characterized by two numbers so let's
say we take the qubit zero which is zero
with probability one so you know in
advance that it will always be zero and
it's equal to 1 with probability 0 of
course and then you apply this quantum
gate and you end up with two different
numbers so in this case 1 over square
root of 2 and 1 over square root of 2 it
means that if you observe it this time
then it will be equal to 1 with
probability 1 over square root of 2
squared which is 1 over 2 and likewise
it will be 0 with probably 1 over 2 ok
but the big observation is that here you
have two numbers to remember instead of
just one now what happens if you have
two objects so 2 bits let's say you have
two bits here two numbers and this for
example one bit comes out if you have
two qubits for example zero and one so
two qubits it can take four values two
can take the value 0 0 0 1 1 0 and 1 1
so each of these 4 values is
characterized by a probability so in
this case we always 1/2 1 here always
you're there so we are this value has
probability 1 and then you can apply
some quantum gate for example the swap
gates which will just swap the values of
qubits and you will end up with 1 0 set
of 0 1 but again the point is that we
have four numbers to remember if we deal
with two qubits now you see where I'm
going if we generalize this to a larger
number of qubits but what's also
important to sis that this quantum gate
it's actually of size four by four
because you can see any quantum gate
like a matrix like you saw in high
school math because the quantum gate is
nothing more than linear algebra
operations if you were to simulate a
quantum computer you would just need
vector matrix multiplications so the
result here is this vector multiplied by
the matrix representing this gate so the
upshot is that any quantum circuit can
be
assimilated by linear algebra operations
which are just Victor matrix
multiplications but the point is that
the matrix will become bigger and bigger
as in abroad qubits grow and if you have
n qubits so my state will be
characterized if I want to simulate it
by 2 to the N numbers and the gate will
be 2 to D 2 times n numbers so is it as
it's relatively practical if you have
maybe 10 or up to 20 cubits but if you
have 50 or hundreds of qubits then
obviously 2 to the 50 or two to the
hundred it becomes very large and
unmanageable was if you had a quantum
computer you wouldn't have to remember
all these numbers these numbers would be
implicit in the in the object you will
have only one one stupid cubed here only
one object but this object because of
quantum mechanics would be kind of the
encoding of many numbers okay
so that was for the surgical part and so
now there is no way I'm here today is
that this kind of crazy computer could
solve some problems much faster than any
classical computer can do in the sense
that in terms of surgical complexity you
would have a clear speed-up for example
a problem that could be solved
classically in at least two to the N
over two operations may be solve might
be with a quantum computer in this
complexity oddity and in a linear time
which means if you will exponential
usually means impossible and polynomial
or linear usually means practical in
practice so this kind of speed-up is
what we call an exponential speed-up you
go from exponential to sub-exponential
an exponential speed-up in practice it
means going from in the impossible to it
possible so that's kind of interesting
property in stuff of just using
approximation algorithms for problems
that you can solve then you might be
able to solve this for this problems if
you had a quantum computer ok now
instead of explaining what is a quantum
computer and me briefly highlight three
points about what the quantum computer
is not
so it's not a super fast computer so
many people come to me say about when
I'm computer it would be building some
times faster say no no wait sorry but it
could likely be slower in terms of
latency in terms of gates instead of
being like you know three gigahertz it
might be much slower than this it's not
too fast a computer sometimes
journalists or people think that it's
something that computes all the answers
in parallel simultaneously and picks the
best one so so it doesn't work like this
again it's there's something called
quantum / ISM but it's a more complex
notion you cannot compute all these
solutions in parallel and then pick the
best it's many very different from this
and maybe the last but not least it's
not something that would solve NP hard
problems so NP hard problems is
typically the kind of problems that have
exponential time complexity for which
you can verify the correctness of a
solution but for which finding
distortion is extremely hard okay so in
terms of complexity sorry I don't know
if you've studied this or if you're
familiar with notions like P and P but I
can summarize it very simply like this
so we have the class of np-complete
problems here which is the the smallest
class of hard problems so np-hard
problems are at least as hard as and P
completes so these are hard whether you
have a quantum computer or not bpp is a
bounded error proneural time pro basic
polynomial time complexity is the kind
of problems that you can find you can
solve efficiently on a classical
computer like this one and bqp is the
equivalent of bpp but for quantum
computers so the kind of problems that a
quantum computer could solve efficiently
now you see that this bubble is bigger
than this one which means that there are
some problems that can be solved
efficiently by quantum computers but not
by classical computers another important
point about what quantum computer is not
there's not this may be heard about the
company d-wave if you there are very
good marketing method are very nice
website did were interesting
by the way but they don't do
full-fledged quantum computers they
tried to use quantum phenomena to do
some dedicated circuits like something
bit similar to a six but using quantum
stuff and even call them quantum
computers but these aren't designed come
quantum computers and they will not be
able to do this to implement Shor's
algorithm short algorithm is maybe the
single reason why people care about
quantum computer at all
it's the gerson that could allow you to
go from n equal P Q to the factors P and
Q you probably know the implication of
this if you can factor in big numbers
then you can break RSA sure will so be
able to solve this problem which is a
bit less straightforward is the discrete
logarithm problem so here you know X you
know P you don't know do you want to
find D and if you find e then you solve
the problem and if you can solve this
problem you can break any difficult man
operation including elliptic curve the
feel man which makes you can break any
SSH connection any TLS connection which
obviously is not what you want so on a
classical computer doing this would take
exponential time complexity proximately
it would be practically impossible with
Shor's algorithm you would go fox from
exponential complexity down to cubic
complexity which means in principle
practical okay so RSA is dead fill man
is dead ECC is dead
wait what do we do now do we wait till
up so then people start panicking we
should switch to post-mortem crypto
lalala just more warning it's not that
bad well from the information we have
today some researchers try to estimate
how costly it would be to actually break
RSA or ACC and they care about this kind
of conclusion the two-factor a 1k RSA
modulus it could take approximately one
and a half million cubed
like you're like okay wait why breaking
something with thousand bits would take
a million cubits so the main reason is
that quantum computers are very unstable
devices there's a lot of error
interference coming from the environment
and within the qubits themselves so you
need many more qubits to to correct the
errors that happen inside your quantum
computer so there are some surgical
theorems that tell you that you can
always correct up to a certain amount of
of yours but it means that you also need
many more qubits and then in terms of
latency in terms of time they estimated
so again based on information they use
available today that to factor a 2k RC
model is so now the RSA you use today
it's at least 2048 it should take
approximately five months so all this
order of magnitude it will not be like
yeah they wait one second and factory
tour will be that easy
okay so how far are we from achieving
this okay let me just drink it's
logarithmic scale so to light the best
quantum computers we have or circuits
that compute some stuff using quantum
circuits we have between ten and twenty
cubits depending on how you count it so
if you read the news you have the guys
of Google and IBM which I am a bit
competing with each other telling you
that they will have 40 or 50 cubed
systems by the end of the year but then
they tell you why maybe they will not
work but will try to have 52 bits just
for no PR and stuff well anyway this is
where we are today and the best
factorization result is that we know how
to factor 15 go spoiler of 15 equal 3
times 5 and this is the yeah of the
order of thousand bits is the size of an
RC modulus or the size of the film and
multiplicative group in to try to break
and this is the order of magnitude of
the number of qubits that we would need
so here we are
and that's number of qubits we need so
how many years so the people we're
trying to sell you postpartum crypto
will tell you five years by our stuff
because now index in two weeks we have
quantum computers and then you have
researchers who want founding to work on
quantum stuff and they also tell you
maybe in ten years
no we need money to go to the research
and then you go to get us do the very
same guy and behind closed doors they
will tell you whenever Sukhram comes on
in my lifetime but you know you know
true story so yeah and another important
algorithm is a cover from the guy who
invented it
it's so-called quantum search so in this
case you don't get a exponential
speed-up you don't get a quantum
speed-up but just a quadratic speed-up
so you go from complexity or to the N or
the square root of n so what's going on
here you have a table of values that are
not sorted and you want to search for
one specific specific value so in a
classical machine
there's no way to cheat you need
complexity that is proportional to the
size of the audio I on a quantum machine
you would take theoretical complexity
that would be proportional to the square
root of the size of the array so again
there's some caveats because there's
constant factors hidden in the Big O
notation but well the approach is that
if you have a symmetric key of n bits
then security would be reduced to
approximately and over two bits so if
you use AES with 128 bits you will
conclude that you will only get 64 bit
security but then okay you want to you
know read the fine print and see what
really means in practice so people try
to do the exercise and estimate how slow
it could be how big would such a quantum
circuit be and they came up with this
figure of a circuit of size 2 to the 80
gates you like it really what what does
that mean so I tried to count even if a
each quantum gate is as small as an atom
of hydrogen which is
but picometers so then this size is the
diameter of the sewer system and then
you're like all right but there would be
some improvement it will make it much
smaller maybe they will end up with
something just the size of the moon
maybe which is much smaller than this
but it would still be you know pretty
tough it will not fit in this room
obviously
so anyway even if you know you're scared
about quantum computers you the solution
is straight for why you just double the
key size and use aes-256 and then you
get 120 bit security okay
now let's switch to the future path on
this how it looks on ax is company's
page how much time huh okay then you
have time so you may know that post
mortem means an algorithm that would not
be broken by quantum computer so
obviously it should not rely on
factorization or discrete log which
means surgically speaking that it should
be the problem of cracking the cipher
should be outside of this class that we
call bqp so RSA is not passed Morton but
AES is postmortem
because we only get a quadric speed-up
we're still in the exponential
complexity domain so now it's not you
know people will tell you okay you want
which post Contin because we have
quantum capture in ten years and some
people who have the order by W they say
no you should not care about it because
it will never exist that's my opinion
so these are people's opinion now to be
more rational and to think about this in
a non binary way well my point is that I
see it as an insurance in insurance like
you pay insurance for you know flooding
or natural disasters against a very
unlikely event and that's kind of risk
management know if you're Caesar you
have some better to spend how should you
prioritize this in terms of investment
if you have a range of stuff to protect
I often say that this should not be a
priority but if you have money left that
they kind of ensure that you may want to
buy depending on what it's offered to
you but it's not it's not binary anyway
why should we you know care about this
from a pragmatic point of view the main
reason why you hear about
quantum in postmortem stuff in the news
especially these days is that these guys
and I say don't eat winters and say in
20 in August 2015 the co-published a
memo recommending that US federal
agencies switch to post-mortem crypto in
a near-future other remember what kind
of turn they use exactly it other
developers and operators of the need to
transition to quantum resistant lures in
the future whatever that means but if
you've worked in the public sector in
administration in some you know in your
countries I'm searching you know that to
make things changes takes a lot of time
and there's a lot of inertia and latency
so in a country like the u.s. might
taken all 30 years to switch all the
systems from free quantum to postmortem
so that may be one of the reasons why
did when it's said this and of course
you have some you know conspiracy
theories who were like uh-huh they have
a quantum computer in their basement and
they want to you know to protect
themselves and there's many theories but
my personal opinion is that you just
from the part of you still insurance
they know the dead Chinese are also
investing in what I'm computing so they
want to make sure that on the long term
they are protected so what's the what
what is in Lincoln quickly is that we
have this projection list is the
National Institute of Standards and
Technology in the u.s. the guys create
the standards and who in particular
create the crypto standards so the guys
who brought you the AES and in shastri
so now if you remember but AES and
shastri they were both developed as a
kind of public project a public
competition we're honest it's very smart
from listen from the US in general
because they would publish in like
enough RFP say oh we want you say first
and then look many cryptographers many
academics and many Europeans would
create new ciphers would as public money
from the European Union to the research
and for years and years hire postdocs
and PhD in organic workshops and stuff
and they would send their ciphers to
nist you know free or fries or PR
three-button free and then
for two or three or four years all these
researchers they would again spend
public money trying to break the site
first and understand them better and
implement them an optimized
implementation and at the end nist picks
the one or the ones that they think best
suit their requirements I didn't say the
best one but the ones that they think
are the best and then we have good
standard I think a yes is very good
cipher shastri katuk is very nice and
the irony is that then the Americans get
for free and then they sell the products
back to the Europeans with a new
standard that your friends developed in
the first place
but yeah I'm digressing so the upshot is
that this kind of project is very fun
I've been involved in induced before and
this kind of demolition derby because
you publish your your cipher and then
your incentive is to try to break the
other guy's ciphers see you try to
attack them in a variety of ways it try
to find weaknesses he trying to create
new artificial security notions and
claim that their ciphers don't satisfy
these security notions yeah a lot of fun
but if you noted at the time nine so it
starts the call for proposals was
published last year the deadline for
submissions is the end of November so
it's really a time you know from this
point of view now you're wondering okay
what are these submissions they're not
been published yet they will be
published in December I guess there's a
few ones that we already know so I put
up this webpage it's past mortem that CH
is totally you know official not a pro
by NIST anyway and there's a few
algorithms that have been published
early so two of which I go design with a
master student and I will talk about
this one later now very briefly this
five type of post mortem crypto the one
stop based on error correcting codes so
IDs that date back to the late 70s
hush based crypto about the same period
late 70s early 80s
latest base it's a bit Morrison sits how
to explain is the most mathematical one
if you if you will motivate crypto is
based on the problem of solving
nonlinear equations
multiparty questions and the one last
one is isogen a basis based on a new
kind of problem based on elliptic on
elliptic curves but that is not the
discrete log that is a bit different so
it looks like it's postmortem but people
are not totally sure so maybe these four
ones are the main ones so in the few
time I have left I will try to convince
you that touch base crypto is a school
and maybe the most secure one not the
most efficient one but the ones for
which we for which we have the best
insurance in terms of physical security
may be the interest of hash based crypto
is that you know that it's at least as
secure as the hash function behind so
obviously you don't want to use md5
because md5 is broken and shouldn't have
use this diagram but the magic here is
that you create public key crypto so
encryption schemes signature schemes and
maybe the feel man
now why do you only create cynosure
schemes for Hajj based but they will
this will be secure as as long as the
hash function is secure and we are very
confident that the hash functions we use
today like shastri or Blake too are
secure that's a good how does it work so
this one is extremely stupid but it's
surprisingly difficult to understand
well at least it was for me the first
time I saw it so here there's something
called one time signature so you want to
sign something in the sense of digital
signature your secret key will be these
two values k0 and k1 so think of these
like 256 bit key is for example and the
public key is the hash value of K 0 and
the hash value of K 1 so you know that
this is the hash of K 0 but you don't
know K 0 and you know that this one is
the hash of K 1 but again you don't know
K 1 so I'm the owner of the secret key
and I want to sign a message I want to
send a message so I want to demonstrate
to you who know the public key that I
intended to send this specific message
so my message is second very stupid it's
either 0 or 1
since your or one and once so if I want
to sign the message zero I publish KC or
I send you kzo kzo M is my signature and
then what do you do you take K 0 and you
hush it and you verify that it's equal
to the hash of K 0 that you have so this
way I prove to you that I own T 0 that I
own the secret key that corresponds to
this public key so an attacker couldn't
switch to 0 to 1 and forged signature of
F 1 because the attacker would not know
K 1 this is stupid enough body's
completely users because you will need
as many keys as there are bits and any
key can only be used once because once
I've published K 0 K 1 then an attacker
no scheduler okay 1 so ok what's the
point now let's say you want to sign
more than one bit you want to sign a
number between 0 and the value W so
instead of washing your secret key ones
you will hush it many times you will
hash it W times so I wrote H subscript
superscript W of K and again K is my
secret key and this guy is my public key
I've been hashing K and hashed the hash
of K and hash the hash of the hash of K
and so on and so on and then the center
of a number X where X is between 0 and W
by between 1 and W is the hash of a K
repeated x times and then if you want to
verify that this match is my public key
then you hush this value again W minus X
time until you go back to the public key
so we're just hashing stuff and again
here the problem is that you can only
use a a key once okay that's normal if
you don't understand everything it's
very counterintuitive but now the
problem is that like I said you can only
use a key once so how do you solve this
problem so like in many computer science
problem when you're stuck what do you do
you use a three
binary tree in this case we use what is
called a miracle tree so it sounds fancy
but it's nothing more than a hash tree
in the sense that the guy here is the
hash value of this and this so you can
catenate
these two guys you hush hush you hush it
and then this is the harsh and again
this guy is the hush of the
concatenation of these two guys and
that's it so your public key will be the
root of the tree and you want to send a
message and you say oh I'm going to use
k1 here so what do you do you will
publish k1 or you will use k1 and along
with your signature you will publish
this guy and this guy which is called
the authentication path and publishing
these two guys will allow the verifier
to hash this to get this one hash these
two and get back the public key and
verify that the public key that was
computed is equal to the public key that
they know enter in the first place so
here I have only four values but in
practice you imagine that you have maybe
now 50 or 40 or 60 values there and a
depth of maybe 40 so if you have it
there for 40 then you will Hodge you
will compute 40 hash functions now
something a bit different so I've talked
about one time signature many times on
eaters
now I'll talk about something few time
signatures it's a bit different now this
is much more recent the ideas from resin
and resin in 2002 and the public key
while the secret key is a bunch of keys
k0 k1 up to key of N and again the
public key is the hush of each of these
keys now I want to use I want to sign a
message I will use a hash function but
that's a little bit different from the
hash functions you're used to my hash
function given a message it will give me
a bunch of numbers so here it will give
me the two numbers 1 and n for instance
so what would I do I will publish these
two keys k 1 and k n because the hash of
M is 1 an N if it were 2 & 3 I would
have published K 2 and K 3 okay
then I repeat this for the messages and
the idea is that I will have as I keep
signing messages I will reveal some keys
but there will still be many keys that
have not been published but obviously if
I keep passing messages and I get random
looking numbers here at the end I will
publish all the keys and it will become
insecure because if I publish all my
secret keys then my secret keys are not
secret anymore and everything becomes
useless so these three types of
constructions taken individually they
look totally stupid and useless but if
you combine them if you combine the
one-time sanctuary if you combine the
Vinton its many times they ensure with
the micro tree and if you add even more
trees and you put your trays and trays
in trees then you create this it's
Sphinx oh so it's a scheme that was
created in 2015 by Dan Burstyn who you
may know and other people and the idea
of this construction was also to
eliminate the state in the sense of
being stateless so stateless as opposed
to stateful means that you don't need to
keep track of a counter the counter
would be like okay I've used this key
I've used a key number one now I want to
use a key too I've used the key number
two now I want to use a key number three
it eliminates this kind of statefulness
by randomizing the index of the key so
each time you pick a random key and
because it's random it's unlikely you
are likely to pick twice the same key
that's the very general ID so it looks
nice but there are several problems with
string or maybe several limitations the
first one is that the signatures are
pretty big to get quantum a and B
security design choice could be about 40
kilobytes and it's relatively slow but
the biggest limitation from my point of
view is the complexity you have four
types of trees so you have the big hyper
tree here and each node is a tree so if
none of the trees are itself so at the
very root you have a miracle tree and
all the leaves of this tree are other
types of trees which are one time
signature schemes or the winter nests
type that I mentioned before and each
node here will sign
the roots of the tree one layer below
and then you have these trees of trees
and stuff and at the very end the very
leaves of the hyper tree will be of the
host type which is the few times on your
scheme I mentioned before and this is
the guy that will actually sign the
message that you intend to sign and when
you publish signatory publish the
signature completed with this guy and
then you also publish the all the
signatures that connect this fruit here
to the root of the root of the hyper
tree that's a mess and we try to do
something simpler but we ended up doing
something that may actually be even more
complex it depends on how you look at it
so that's what I did with a master
student of mine this summer was the
first semester of this year and our goal
was to simplify to improve things to
make it faster or to make it more secure
and we call our construction gravity
Sphinx so gravity why because we saw
that it was as ambitious as the problem
of solving the quantum gravity problem
so it's kind of things with a bunch of
new tricks and the goal of these tricks
is to make senators shorter and to make
the scheme faster or less slow I will
very simply try to present this trick to
give you the idea of what what we did
the first one is to use collision-free
hashing so I mentioned in this few time
stuff you pick a bunch of indy
significant budget of numbers but
instincts if you were to pick for
example 32 numbers then it was like each
number was a random number and a fish
number is random then it could happen
that you get twice the same number that
you get twice M index so it meant that
you would published instead of
publishing two different secret keys you
would publish only one and we realize
that this this makes the schemes a
little less secure so we came up with a
modified version of the hash function
that uses a pillar random generator or
PRNG
where there is no such collision what a
risk of collision is in Terraria and
based on this we analyzed the security
of the scheme and we create a new we
wrote new theorems and we proved that we
have this level of security if we have
this kind of parameters network we use
is that we try to make it a little bit
faster by creating a trade-off between
the key size and and the amount of
computation to do so instead of again I
touch simplify it instead of having
trees of twigs of trees and stuff we
have a big tree here that we pre compute
so that when you sign a message you only
have to compute this small tree instead
of computing a sequence of trees so this
makes the key a little bit bigger but
this says you lot of computations add
another day another trick that we used
was batching so let's say you want to
sign many messages at the same time
let's say you want publish gnu/linux
packages and you want to sign everything
and instead of computing one signature
for each packet you want to to publish
one single central for the list of
packages so to simplify again we would
take all the messages would put them in
a tree so again we solve the problem by
using a tree and then we just sign the
root of this tree so now if you want to
publish the signature of one of these
guys instead of publishing all the
messages you publish the message and
your dedication path a bunch of nods
with industry so again we put a tree in
a central scheme that you have where you
have trees of trees and trees okay so
the internals are pretty complex I don't
want to bore you with all this it's
already starts to be pretty boring but
the the bottom line is that we end up
with these kind of parameters so some
Russians that we intended to submit to
NIST maybe the final versions could be a
little bit different so we have key size
of between 20 K and 34 35 K proximity so
it's still pretty big you might argue
that it's not realistic well I have
maybe like a know know half a terabyte
of memory on on this guy but obviously
if you're on very low-end devices
sure IOT stuff and you have a limited
memory you won't be able to store
thousands of thousands of sensors but I
think it would fit many use cases in
terms of key size of centers I'm sorry
the keys on the other hand they can be
pretty smooth this public key is there
32 bytes only and the secret keys are 64
bytes plus the cache if you do the cache
okay so seriously this plus quantum
stuff it's pretty complicated that just
one type of a scheme hash-based the
other ones latest based squad-based
multi-varied they're totally different
from this and not much simpler so the
the project of this will take casting at
least four or five years because we need
to better understand this kind of
construction and we need to to be sure
that they are secure enough to be to be
a standout so like I said the deadline
is the 31st of November and in what's
the date in in April in April 2018 this
could organize a workshop we're also
meters will come to the stage and
present the submission and co-located
with this event there would be a picture
crypto 2018 which is well the latest
conference but postponed crypto so it's
been running since 2000 ten or seven and
remember exactly but it's the main
conference but if you're interested in
post-mortem crypto that's where them the
best resources is published
it's nice location is in Miami Florida
so hope I will I will go there so yeah
that's pretty much all I had to say
today
don't thank you for coming I will
happily take any question that's my
contact and a very small commercial plug
I just for the book in a it will be
published in the coming days it would be
available in Amazon on November 21st so
if you're interested in in crypto and
you may consider this thank you
[Applause]
question so everybody understood the
hash based goodness that's so by his
book I already did I had early access so
yeah I'm going to bring you lots of it
yeah yeah I didn't okay yeah thank you
guys thank you guys
well there's a question that's a
question ah yeah you you spoke to her
about introducing a work factor to
ashing yeah
isn't that what what the current
password hashing algorithms already do
yes so the question is about what
factors and hash functions so here we
don't explicitly want to introduce you
what factor because the walk factor
makes hashing slower and using memoria
so that's what you want to have in
pascal rushing but here we would like to
avoid this cofactor to be as fast as
possible so we don't put extra walk on
purpose we try to minimize it so this
can be used this cannot be used for
washing password thanks more questions
okay thank you all thank you thank you
JP