[Applause]
votre monde je m'appelle soya a llama
as I cannot speak French I give a
presentation in English in fact I'd like
to use Japanese okay today's
presentation is an inconvenient truth
building the loss of ear protection in
Windows 10
very happy to give our presentation here
first let me introduce myself I'm
security researcher at judicial system
integration laboratories Limited and
organizer at besides Tokyo
I've been working for food it's more
than 20 years at Windows software
developer I wrote a nice driver Brutus
profile we soak application and more
security research about four years ago
my first presentation was at every Tokyo
it's one of the most famous security
conference in Japan and the motto it's
no drink no hug
so I gave a presentation while drinking
to be honest I'd like to do the same
today but I refrain from it
and this is my research history about
local hacking
in 2016 I was researching about jabbsi
yet
at that time I found way to escalate
privilege to administrator so in 2017
I'll give a presentation at besides Las
Vegas
last year I found way to abating the
ransomware protection and give a
presentation at work on track on Derby
Kong and Hawk Miami
this year I found new issue summit CFP
and I am here
however I cannot talk about this issue
because it's not fixed I'm looking for
to meeting you next year
next I'd like to talk a little about way
to escalate privilege to administrator
it all started when I execute the coke
management launcher
it's learning with high integrity level
and
is loading through extension x64 dot da
unbelievably its salt party dear
management rancha does not display the
you se screen and execute with
administrator privileges
which means
it's us pipers
and Lord third-party da in Program Files
order
but prophecies can access program files
folder
about explora
so I such the explora
Rhoda is loading one drives the area
unbelievably it's in the users for them
explora Lord Guan drive the air in users
folder and can access it accesses
Program Files folder which means
I found a way to get administrator
privileges
my basic concept is that we press the
collect deal with Mises one
however if exe chords a function
as virile does not know it
so I thought that Magisterial should
pass through the function to the correct
da
the following in the implementation
necessary to rewrite the concept
load the correct DLL and get its handle
get address of each function using
handle
when code from Exe called the
corresponding function with the correct
admins
but Punk's on the DL a half
it using the damping command
Pyrus inks a fix for dot d Earhart's for
export functions
dear can unload now DL get class object
DL register Sabah DL and register Sabah
and one text test function
and said extension x64 DL has same for
export function
so only need to implement or export
functions
and it's very easy
because the export file
so API described or Microsoft website
oh this is the source code but Marsha
Scott has been removed
then I explained detail mechanism
when user executes mashes program
for example by targets email attack was
watering hole attack
my sass program dname product the air
and copies it self
you
when the system listed
Xtra de los mochis da
you
it's same process but this time need
administrator privileges
because it's Program Files folder for
that however explora can access it
so my SAS program channle name correct
the air
and copies itself
you
further executes the management launcher
the management or entire had us eat
vipers
so execute by high integrity level
and Lord much as the air
Martha's program has get the
administrator privileges
I have a demonstration video please
watch it
you
there are new name and copy command
images patch file
execute Maurice batch file and we start
Windows 10
you
see a MIDI was started with
administrator privileges
you
then Microsoft had the bank bounty
program
I thought this issue is very dangerous
and I want a little pocket money so
I submitted Bhanumati report - MS RC mas
RC state
this does not meet the bar for security
services
so cannot pacer liveth
however
this issue has been fixed
Microsoft's critiques like management
Ananta execute with medium integrity
level Microsoft must not have paid are
you God
let's move on to the next topic
made 12 27 teen
happen do you remember
it's daily fiber attacks by one opera
it's caused tremendous damage all over
the world
Microsoft gave answer for it
it's ransomware protection
that's for Microsoft implemented it on
Windows 10 for creators update
this is lots of a protection screen
laaame protection hearts contoured for
the axis
however it's off by default
stop if thou eat
protected for that and arrow an absolute
control for the axis are displayed
let's look each I think
first he is protected orders
administrator can add for da he want and
the era for the rotated by default
documents pictures video music desktop
and favorite
just a moment there is a strange freight
windows system for de are protected by
default
you jury system holder is C colon
backslash Windows backslash system 32
but there is not include in this list
what is the truth I show you in
demonstration club now
you
first the last of a protection is
disabled yet
now l'm powershell with system
privileged
and create a fire
you
USPS exact six three four
now Who am I so
a parcel running with system freebie
dates
you
so both system for DES and
for the well not rocked
next enable the lanthum ear protection
here
you
I used Aphrodite not rocks because Lance
Samia prosecution does not work for for
the process that the all day being run
you
and this time it was blocked
successfully
in this way last time a protection is
very powerful function to broke even
system free blades
and create fight the system folder
of course it's not about
you
the truth is we no system for that is
not propagated by the heart
next yes
for the access administrator can add
applications that can access protected
for that
however there is no default list just a
moment
strange place too
apps determined by Microsoft as friendly
are always allowed
what does friendly
I'll show you in the most Edition from
now
you
first is shimmery
it's blocked
next it's Microsoft what
you
it's not blocked
next is explora
it's not product
next is 70
you
it's not blocked
just a moment next is a different
version of 7-zip
you
it's broke
so Tracy's
Microsoft only know
and this is
protection mechanism
education can access or folder by
default
when administrator enable the last mail
protection
I wrote up scan
protected orders
but the other apps cannot access it
you ain't seen nothing yet now I found
up
I found a burner VD or a thermal
protection
my idea is very simple
if we can inject Maria
into our own apps
we can access protested for that and the
ice Explorer here
there was similarly such yahoo idea is
using Microsoft Office
this time I use a different method
I show you in demonstration from now
you
it's target fire
it written hello world
you
La Marche us watch fire
as you can see this patch file add value
to the registry and listed Explorer
you
a target file is encrypted
my Mars program is not brought
chicks are stud are set as of f Explorer
explora is loading marshes dear
in addition this IDL the area is on the
network
you
so my method I explain now
it all started I wondered why can
explore erode and onedrive DRL because
the further different every page
so I searched in the latest
it was fun in HK CR
h kc r is that much it's get em with its
Casey you
and it's KCU talks takes precedence from
hklm which means if the explora loads up
dear and it passes written to HCL mmm
we can make extruder loader nicest deal
which deal meet the requirements
and it
it's self a TT dot the air air
then I explained detail of mechanism
when user executes my SAS program
you
usually it reflects the path of self
attitude the area in EDM am to at KCR
however well my sass program light mices
pass in HK see you it reflect to HK CR
when the system restart
explora loads meshes dear
you
it's revenge payback time
I started the bonneville teleport to
make our nsrc again
nsrc said
this does not meet the bar for security
services so cannot there's a lot
I searched the buff of securities
servicing on Microsoft website
certainiy it's not meat
moreover user account control and
control for the axis are not covered by
active bug bounty programs I give up
getting live out
I understand that Microsoft thinking
then how about others aunt Maria
application
this is a market share of Windows and
Maria application vendors
gerrae a bust he said Maria bites mcafee
and more
I took these
first a bust internet security hat
the last time you are sealed
ever
my my sixth year was able to encrypt the
text file with that being blocked
next is its mass security heart the last
time is sealed
Arriba
the same result
next Maria bites
me about premium had the last year
protection however
it's same lizard
next McAfee
McAfee had the last Amir interceptor
however
results
as far as I've ticked aunt Maria
application cannot broke my bar well
finally it's a conclusion Microsoft does
not admit variability and not pain leave
us
well then nobody research it
which means it's not secure
it's time to start taking local hacking
seriously
okay my presentation is over merci
beaucoup
[Applause]
Escada question
hi so my question is is it the first
time that you talked about this publicly
about this issue yes because it's maybe
the photo that I'm not here sorry can
you repeat
absolutely so my question was is it the
first time that you talked about this
issue publicly not fast first I'm sorry
I I talked it cuckoo
another question
to test it with security solution for
enterprise like a semantic a trend or
Kaspersky
we are one more time more lewdly much
more lewdly
you try to test it with security
solution antivirus for enterprise the
enterprise the antivirus
I I tested tickler so no it's O
I took four for a antibody solution so I
I not take other system okay
which keeps the mic near to the Moose
which did you tested which one father
which one did you test it you told me
that you tested with other other
antivirus butter which one
so happy yeah he did it but it don't
remember the context it's good enough
thank you so yeah thank you
[Applause]