breaking or reminding their words not as
hard as you think
Alex Bassanio Jesus amico explicar animo
Stratton come open a table Davi Freya
meant a notable goddess in imagine F F
inverse u e aí EPMC Buena which are
separate unit I can t Tommy control
total visit Emma presidencia elimi tada
yatta disability sistema yeah my name is
Alex
[Music]
is it better okay sounds better alright
so in my name is Alex
we have Jesse here and we have a second
presentation here in a cup I'd say the
first one was yesterday and there was
like some complaints that that our
English is not that good so I switch to
Russian because I don't know much Spain
except couple words I learned yesterday
I don't want to practice that words but
I believe they're pretty convincing so I
know a little bit of that anyway so
we'll talk today about breaking in and
planting servers so over our overall
representation we'll go to the couple
different topic some of you may expect
that it will be focused at onion BMC it
will be it will have couple different
topics including BMC and we will go over
like best practices and what we think
attacker think about in plantings
different plots from different
components as well as breaking the
servers and breaking different different
equipment Wow so typical Enterprise has
a bunch of servers pretty expensive
servers some servers may cost like a
half of the mill and they serve like a
critical critical part of the their
business for the enterprise's it could
be a telecom it could be a banks it
could be like really critical one or two
servers and in typical enterprise there
is of course technology to make a sort
of maintenance period when there is like
one server replaces what another server
and in have maintenance period of that
when you make an updates or check the
harder check your rate controller or
something like that but typically like
even if you have the backup you usually
use the same harder for the backup so
because it's much more easy if you have
like exactly the same card you have less
less chances to have any stability in a
software
you basically get the one hardware make
an exactly the same cocaine you just
redirect traffic and you have same
hardware so and there is a consequences
to having the same hardware across cause
the backup and your production because
if there is any infection could
compromise one of the server over
hardware from that could make the
similar to the backup and make a system
unbootable for some time and it may
damage that critical business because if
you if you assume like ok I have a
really critical server if it will go
down and then I will I will recover my
backup and then the backup come can go
down because that's what similar system
you added and similar like networking
may have similar BMC vulnerability
exploited similarly and compromised it
like a spy controller and make system
applicable so that's that this cop of
the that the problem which you try to
understand what what the ways attacker
may think about break the system make
the system unbootable or what the ways
attacker may use to compromise the
system to in front the system so let's
talk a little bit more we'll jump in
details but before before we'll go there
there is a couple of in a wild attack
was demonstrated that breaking this
infrastructure breaking the system is is
kind of part of the nation-state type of
factors so there was a couple of
examples which is which is wiping MBR
any system to make system unbootable and
if you if you're familiar was what is
MBR is it basically twenty years old
technology which is supposed to never
exist like for the last ten years but
they still support this and operation
system vendors still support this a
little bit as the legacy as a
compatibility and basically it doesn't
have any security so nothing to verify
MBR nothing to prevent MBR so any any
attacker who got some privileges in the
system could compromise MBR and make
system unbootable and ideal it is not
that hard to recover but because there
was no backup of the MBR originally
because there was no one
thinking about that case that the system
was not easily to recover and there was
some of the examples of icy essences
campaigns which was targeting a device
serial over the net which is basically
part of between communication between
ICS and system and control unit and by
targeting that device you also could
make a system break up some of the ICS
or sis system and apparently there was
no backup there was no really easy to
way to verify that exactly this device
was compromised then there was not easy
way to recover so you need to really
press it persist and really precisely
detective each of the component was
targeted and really fast to replace it
or record that so that was kind of
giving us the idea that this type of
threats is the real so let's talk a
little bit about architecture we start a
little bit explaining yesterday about
the architects 86 architecture and why
are we interesting all the different
components in this architecture and what
we need to look for what is the
important part for the security
perspective on the platform security
perspective so in platform security
perspective is important is what the
components in the system how old they
are
does it have any from does this room is
updatable but also we really interested
on two other really important things one
is persistency so we're interested in
the component which has non-volatile
storage so the component which is has
some memory reprogrammable memory
neither for data but for the call which
you can neither read or write from the
software perspective to run integrity or
to update the configuration and you want
to have it because a bunch of components
has the functionality which you want to
have configurable you don't want to your
system boot every time and you every
time set everything for yourself in the
setup screen
so you want to be you want to have the
capability that the buyers save that
configuration somehow
so that's persistence is kind of one
really important aspect for us as
security experts because we want to
understand what
kind of persistent storage attacker can
try to compromise and second is as it's
a protocols and buses so all of these
components is communicating for each
other over the buses and depends which
basket communicated through it may allow
some extra capabilities to the attacker
so they may allow send a DMA transaction
or they may allow you bypass some of the
spy cycles and like fake some of the
values from the spy controller so it
depends on what buses that components is
sitting it may give attacker different
advantage different capabilities so if
the attacker will pick the proper
component which has persistent storage
and compromised that persistent storage
by replacing the key from our
configuration and then use that
component over that buses to compromise
the rest of the system that's the
scenario vishakan was looking fund so
persistency and full control plus
several times of sometimes stealthy
capabilities so and as we as we as we a
little bit get the idea of what we're
looking for we want to understand how
does influence works and how does how
does implant go into the system so
implant implants like a simplest
possible way it will it need to find
that persistent storage which I was
mentioned in a second ago and just to
just to find a method to update the date
on that storage it could use physical
physical presence like physical access
and find a specific controller attached
programmer physically and in plans the
system so that's definitely possible
scenario for the servers for the
desktops and for many controllers like a
spec controller the harder to reprogram
it really cheap so it doesn't cost much
to do it you only need to have a
physical access to the system near the
during their supply chain or during the
maintenance period or during their
samatha some other ways to to get the
physical access to the system second
ways from the software so basically run
in either the tools from the vendors
legitimate tools of the update the from
and be in the middle of that process and
inject the code there
or from the person system just to
investigate some interfaces and find the
way how to go it from the software side
yes sir the talk was actually about that
there is another way to implant the
system it it's not always supposed to be
modifying the code it combo also be just
a corrupting the data or modifying the
data so you may just disable some of the
protections so with physical access
always over software you just instead of
changing the code you change the data
and when you run the code integrity
you'll find you'd need an implant but
because the data was so sensitive like
s3 was killed for example or some other
like a really sensitive configuration
that will allow attackers run the same
privileges as persistency but over the
data and even more implants him could
mean in some cases that attacker has has
to inject a device inside the hardware
so it like for example find the way how
to inject in PCIe bars because of the
some of the PCIe port
he built a custom device plugin it
plugin it really carefully that it's not
visible and then connected to a zermatt
for example and then he has a persistent
device running on the PCI bus which is
the one in the my capability which is
allowing fully on the entire host host
of memory and extract all secrets and in
the same time this device could be a
network device so it could send the data
outbound some invisible for their
further for the monitored software in
the main host system so that was about
implanting what do you know about breaks
breaks a little bit different than in 20
minutes we mostly don't care about you
don't care about like be stealthy you
just want to make system unbootable and
it it's a little bit similar with
implant in the perspective of like it's
always cat-and-mouse game so it's always
like do I know better method to infect
the system then someone who will try to
detect me or do I know the better way to
break a system than someone will try to
recover it so in some cases like a NPR
one or like a legacy system like this
existence from 90s we know
like sometimes system didn't move and we
removed the battery for for 30 seconds
reflected this battery back and system
boot for some magic so you sort of
figure out the way how to unbreak your
system by some harder faults but that
could be much more complicated it could
be more technique which will allow them
the advanced attacker to break a system
and sometimes it's not that easy to
figure out how to recover the system
because you need to know exactly
component and how to record that company
sometimes the component could be sold
and in so you need to unsolder the
component from the motherboard so this
makes the process not that fast so
million that if it is part of the
critical infrastructure it could make
some of financial damage to your
organization so as we going forward we
will go through couple components couple
main components which is definitely easy
way to implant the system and break the
system and the first thing which attack
an attacker will take a look so one in
what is the despite storage the storage
for the system from the main storage for
for them the basic configuration and
basic code which is responsible to wake
up the system when you power in on the
button like when you boot in the system
in going from rosetta vector up to Dixie
phase to boot in the system that's that
code living and that spy controller spy
chip which is controlling bus by
controller also there is another from
which is living in that space storage a
me from Inter manageability and Informer
which is part of the chips chipset
controller which is running in a PC H so
that from is also store it in that
persistent storage and there is also GB
which is a Gigabit Ethernet controller
configuration so basically if you have
integrated network card there's McCarter
story there there smoke is a resonant
configuration there so by corrupting
that for example you make this device
doesn't work so if you rely on
integrated a network card and it will
take you a couple of minutes or maybe a
couple of hours to figure out that this
network card doesn't work anymore and
not work because of the software reason
it has some hardware faults and then you
need to set the external network card to
send traffic over but you will you will
have some time of that device will will
not work and to recover it it you need
to have a legitimate coffee of GB copy
of GB region if you don't that copy you
couldn't recover easily so part of your
part of your heart I would wouldn't be
bootable so and that's why that's PI
storage has something which is called
spy descriptor it's like a first for
kilobytes of that storage which is
responsible to define layout of that
storage and couple additional things for
example it's responsible to set the
permission table which will tell which
of the region would be accessible from
which of the devices it also has some of
the configuration about that spy storage
so in case if you corrupt spy descriptor
dense system at least will be not
bootable but if you try to exploit you
can try to play with the spy descriptor
if the spy descriptor is accessible to
try to enable different modes which may
not be documented or make a privilege
escalation to the spy to them at
override the spy content itself so
that's like a really really quick
example of how you can decode spy
descriptor is some of the open-source
tools there is couple of them there's
flash from the Secretary's couple models
which is given your good visibility on
despite descriptor but then you also
want to understand
can you does the attacker has access to
it or not and then you need to take a
look on that on the permission table
which is part of the spy descriptor and
then you can see like right here like
spy descriptor is read-only so basically
minion that CPU is host basically so CPU
has only read-only permission for the
spy descriptor mean that in this
specific case software couldn't modify
this by descriptor from during 0 it may
be another ways to do it but not from
the software part
but then if you will find something like
this read right here then that's just
like a vulnerability because this
meaning that ring zero could modify spy
descriptor and spy descriptor contain
this table
so if sorter could modify this table it
could move if it could modify spy the
script equipment affine entire table and
mess the permissions here so at least
you will break the system but you can
also make some some nice exploit from
here as well so that's like a one of the
basic mechanism how does Hardware
supposed to be configured properly to
prevent the implant in the system to
prevent them breaking the system but
there is also another one of the most
important thing which supposed to be
configured in modern in statistics
system to prevent modification of that
persistent spice storage is something
which is called bias control register
and this bias control register is the
mechanism implemented in the PCH
specifically designed to prevent the the
right cycle to the spice storage it does
work interest only because it's the this
register it was designed in a way that
you could deliver the legitimate updates
to the bias so you cannot only set like
read-only forever you cannot do it
because in this case you will not update
your bias so you want to have the
capabilities to deliver some of the
update over some legitimate interface
and then you need to play a little bit
in who you will trust so and in this
case there is like something like called
SMM system management mode a system
management mode it is has the
capabilities to override this by content
and this register is configured in a way
that if you're not in SMM you don't have
permissions to override this by content
if unison and then you have the
permissions of riders by content so
configuring this register is highly
important for each system if the service
is not configured correctly that the
system could be implanted or braked
really easily and we saw like yesterday
that a PT 29 what was was presented by
ESET in blue hut that demonstrate that
the modern
the modern UEFA rootkits using exploits
which is exploiting weaknesses in the
configuration of this register so
basically the exploit checks if this not
properly configured then it writes a
special like sequence or send like some
of the cycles during this condition to
override this by content that was pretty
interesting and pretty impressive
because it was in the wild exploiting
the vulnerability to implant the system
yeah so really interesting case study
anyway
move it forward so okay you figure out
the ways how to protect the system if
you guard the ways what you need to take
a look when you in fact in the system
and the attacker in fact in the system
now you need to understand what exactly
you would in fact what exactly you
wouldn't replace so the easy target is
you will try to find a UFO application
or Dixie driver the part of the boot
floor and you will replace that part of
the boot flow so by to doing that you
need to understand the format of the
content of the spider script and there
is a bunch of good technology and tools
which is doing that
thus pretty complicated flow you have
ufi volumes you have compressed sections
and then set the compression sections
you have the PE files so there is like
entire here I could think about this as
a file system so and then you will find
the file in the file system but in that
special file system and then you will
replace that file you just need to make
sure that whenever you will replace it
or will edit any new one and that will
be also the part of the boot sequence
and the moment when you need it because
if it will be too early you may not have
that capability switch you're looking
for it's a little too late
you may the system may be already locked
down so you do not have that capability
switch you're looking for so anyway you
need you need to find the right time at
the right place to in fact your yo-yo
executable code and then you need to fix
some of the some of the checks and you
need to make sure that you have the
proper size size is not going over the
your former volume and stuff like that
it's more engineering work and in this
apt 28 there there was a demonstration
that it could be done all out
matically so any server any laptop which
is existent now if there is not properly
set that protection reserve was
mentioned previously system could be
infected making fully persistent fully
own attacker could make good fools could
could own the system for in for like
multiple years be released else
exfiltrate data from the center from the
servers over the time and there is
another really interesting tools there
same same tools but another capability
under dos replacing the the executables
which makes it even easily in attacker
perspective on the PLC perspective so if
you want to play around
you just run ship check find the
vulnerable platform and then you can use
the tools to to install a PLC implant
from the github so we talked a little
bit about how all the defense supposed
to work in perspective of the
configuration but there is also a bunch
of implementation around and I mentioned
that SMM should deliver the BIOS update
but it's not really like that there is a
special methods capsule update which is
responsible to deliver the updates to
the system and the capsule updated it's
it's supposed to run during the boot
time or on on when you waken up from the
sleep state for some of the other
security reasons so if you will see any
of the tool is doing runtime update for
the buyers they probably did it wrong
because at runtime there is a bunch of
devices running in parallel which has a
button DMA capability which may give a
attacker a huge room to run the attack
against the BIOS update mechanism and
this could be used for other attacker
also to update the spy content if the
capsule audit was designed it not
properly and that was we that was one of
the cases which I will go in a second
but before that a little bit about super
michael well in the part of our study
for this specific curve for this
specific presentation so Super Micro has
the UEFI BIOS update it basically done
over the DOS or Linux utilities like a
DOS
o-over BMC interface you can also run
the BIOS update to update the BMC you
can use also the UI from the BMC or the
local LAN interface which makes it click
more less good functionality for the
admin tool to deliver update but what we
saw in a security perspective that the
BIOS update was not sign it so it was
not sign it neither like a capsule
update but it was not sign it at all so
basically you can just put your own
module use legitimate tools update the
buyers and in fact the system moreover
it it update an entire spice so you can
update every single cluding spy
descriptor and it doesn't have roll back
protections so in case if in case if
that will be some updates
we shall fix some vulnerabilities and
you like that vulnerabilities you wanted
to run our villages back so like
attacker one that ran our abilities for
some other reason they can gesture use
the illegitimate update to update result
version of the buyers so there was no
speed interesting study and that's was
the comment for entire vendor so all of
their harder is this vendor release they
use the same mechanism they are
releasing about a quarter of a quarter
of million server like about a million
server per year and all of that could be
infected by only by running only on the
source tool to repackage the image and
demo the legitimate tool which they are
provided to update to infect the system
and there is a quick demo about that how
to in fact okay so yeah that's really
quick demo so super micro system boot
into the DOS and then we run in from
here yeah utilities from Super Micro and
it basically the image was preparing a
little bit before so we infected this
image it could be done all from the OS
level you just need to figure out which
of the SMI it will trigger and then you
just simulate this tool it was just for
the demo purpose we're just not doing
that
just took the original tool and run it
from the original tool to in fact this
the the system from in the supermarket
server also we use completely open
source that implant so it was like
nation' which you see need to do we just
take it from the github build it in fact
the image and and and you down so with a
little bit more work attackers of cost
can do much more transit stuff like that
was like the idea of how how simple it
could be it could be as complicated as
attacker want in perspective of post
exploitation so if you see here that
will erase on all of the chip it's
writing all the chip including NVRAM
including boot block including bias bias
blog it runs some checks rebooting the
system and during the boot flow before
the operation system start we see that
it is system is implanted so from this
point of view attacker can control
everything in a system make system
unbootable or fully compromised the
operation system and and hook all of the
API they want so let me come back to the
slides there is other methods to break
the system one of that is SPG xpg EEPROM
is basically a persistent memory inside
the gym controller in this in a system
memory it could be in some cases
accessible for the read and if you will
decode and read and will understand what
what is what is inside that that storage
there is a voltage information there is
a frequency information by correcting
the system you make your system memory
not work and you that will be hard to
figure out why the system doesn't work
and the funny part of it that there's a
specification which is telling you how
to lock that that SPD but it's not it's
not always the case that BIOS is doing
that so there's there is a bunch of work
need to be done correctly and advice to
set to set that log bit so you five
variables we already mentioned these
multiple years ago like in two thousand
fifteen sixteen seventeen anyway it's
still a problem but you still you still
have the capabilities to break a system
if you delete the variable or if you
override the variable or if you
duplicate the variable
the fireballs is basically the
configuration of the system former so
that's the example of the one of the
really popular variable setup variable
which is if you will corrupt that
variable in mini system they will not
work the system will not boot it so
another really interesting and not that
popular is flesh over out basically the
the first chip is it's making all good
could capable to make only a certain
amount of Rights during the lifetime and
if your chip is accessible for rights
you can write like two hundred thousand
times over eight hours and make the
system break a system and the way that
someone need to disorder the chip and
solder the new one to record the system
and that's like small controllers which
could make a bunch of damage for the
server option wrong this is a persistent
storage in the devices you can if
optional base exists for some of the
devices like a big network art or
something like that you can use a API
which is vendor provide to you to read
that option wrong but sometimes you need
to write to the option roms and if you
write to the auction rooms you can also
break the device but it's not only
biggest device option on is the part of
the main boot flow so you can put like
infinite loop and then that tunic loop
will not let the system boots
if the device will be setted in in
hardware so with this I will go and
switch to the gesture to explain the
second part of the of the presentation
about being seen
yeah we will fix it in a second don't
want use mine
because this does work I can give you
one
what can we just swap it does work
okay okay there we go
okay thanks Alex so with another another
component in the system that we've
talked about today and Niko Mattias
talked about the BMC also is just
there's this out-of-band management
component within servers and if you
don't know anything about this yet it's
used for sensor monitoring KVM it's
basically a management platform within
the system that's runs on its own you
can use it to reflash the BIOS it that's
one of the the key functions is being
able to flash the BIOS make sure that
you can boot up the system you don't
want to go to the data center and have
to plug in a monitor and and fix the
system that way so here's an example of
one of the interfaces there's a remote
control there's KBM you can power it on
power it off there's a serial over LAN
functionality you can also basically
emulate a floppy or cd-rom from an image
shared across the network and that shows
up it shows up on the seat on the the
target system acting like a real
physical device and your operating
system you can boot off of it it's a
pretty useful functionality you can
flash the BIOS from DAC that's a pretty
key feature this particular one you need
to pay to enable that feature there have
been a number of vulnerabilities
discovered in BMC's in the past this was
one found just last year in HP ILO where
they had a pretty fun it was a complete
authentication bypass by having a
connection header that had a twenty nine
a is it basically overflowed a
particular flag on the on the stack that
determine if who is a local request or a
remote request and if it's a local
request it does not require any
authentication and it will just do
whatever you want so you could say give
this particular HTTP header and say
create a user with and create a new
admin user for me with this password and
it'll just go do it for you so that one
was pretty it was pretty cool here's an
example of some of the information that
you can get from
my over just there's a get device ID
field which is a mandatory IPMI command
and will tell you things like
manufacturer ID product ID device ID and
the firmware version that's in that
particular device and for this
particular example you can you can tell
if it's vulnerable by checking the
device ID manufacturer ID and if it's
below a certain firmware level then it's
it's vulnerable to this we also heard
about the dell idrac issues that nico
and Mattias talked about yesterday
those were pretty cool also remote offer
unauthorized remote code execution in
the BMC is is pretty scary one of the
other older vulnerabilities is the super
my hero x9 back in 2003 or 2013 dan
farmer and HD Mora work together and
published some interesting results
basically they found a lot of bugs in
BMC including like static encryption
keys are coded credentials when they
were auditing the web applications for
BMC they found so many places of unsafe
string handling that they just stopped
even trying to add see the ease and just
gave this whole list to super micro and
had them go fix them so we're gonna take
a closer look at some of the different
super micro bmc's and some of the
different generations x8 and Exxon used
an older type of a couple different
types of chips with firmware from AMI 8n
when they transition to X 10 and X 11
they move it over to a speed instead
with the different basically the BMC
firmware came from a different vendor
and things changed a little bit but
we'll take a look at what specifically
changed so figuring out what's in a BMC
in the image in the first place we'll
just run VIN walk in it and we'll see
some some interesting things pop up like
there's a cram FS filesystem there's a
zip file which the name is Colonel dot
bin which is kind of fun and then
there's another tram FS filesystem and
we found some copyright strings but if
we take a closer look and actually
unpack the trauma FS are
we can find the code that actually
handles those updates and in this
particular example it basically scans
through the the update image to look for
regions using this magic value and if we
then go look in the the update file
itself we find that magic value and
there's essentially metadata at the end
of each region that has information like
there's some there's a key piece of
information called the burn address
which is the address within the spy that
this particular region of the update is
going to be burned to we do have the
name of the region and then there is a
checksum just it's the checksum does
doesn't cover the region it only covers
the the metadata for this particular
region so it detects if this is a valid
metadata so that that burn address like
the base of the image is four with seven
zeros after it and you basically
subtract the base address from the burn
add start offset if you if you remember
the the cram FS from a few slides that
first one was that one eight and four
zeros which matches up with one of our
region's here so our first file system
is at offset one eight zeros and at the
end the end of this region is at nine to
zero zero so we we know how we can carve
out that specific region and take a look
at it if we kind of take a little bit of
a further look we determined that the
the last region in this particular
firmware image is special the the update
code does look for this eight 10s from
where signature there's a couple bites
that are better checked for but it it
doesn't have it it's I think it be
there's a 71 byte and the zero three
byte are the only ones that it's really
looking for other this than this 810
signature at the end but if we put it
all together we basically have our
layout kind of looks like this where
there's a bootloader for the first 64 K
of the image
it's just W PCM 450 bootloader from wind
bond we've got some padding we've got a
cram FS for the rich filesystem as if
journal a crab crema fest for the web
filesystem
and we've got some metadata at the end
of each of those regions let's see that
so this was the the update image and
there's a like a padding region on a
live file system that's actually
replaced with a GF FS 2 file system
that's used for non-volatile storage of
configuration and information event log
and anything that it wants to persist in
the BMC across reboots the X the x8
generation uses the exact same format as
as this for their firmware updates so
for 4 X 10 they did change the processor
entirely using going with a speed
instead also they changed the bootloader
so they're using you booting and they're
no longer using that end of region
metadata but they have something even
nicer they basically have these image
tags that specify exactly like the start
address the start offset and offset this
time they actually have a CRC for the
region itself so that's CRC 30 32 you
need to recalculate that when you change
the region but then they also have the
the name of the region when they they
built this image from their file so the
region is really similar the only
difference is the bootloader region is
bigger and it's not a zipped kernel
anymore it's just a like a standard
Linux image that would be loaded by you
boot and then there is the the image
tags at a particular address after those
two file systems in kernel so they did
something really interesting for the x11
generation so the the part was basically
within the same family just a small
change but the firmware format we can't
tell what's in it by using our previous
methods even if you run been walk it
doesn't detect anything except a ton of
individual compressed streams and if you
try to extract it with bin walk you'll
end up with a multi-gigabyte mess that
is not useful at all but well after some
further investigation one thing that we
figured out was that they basically had
used exactly the same format as the x10
but they used hard-coded AES keys and
initialization vectors to encrypt that
image tag and the very first section of
each of the crammed FS regions so they
didn't encrypt the entire image just the
header of those crammed FS regions and
it's only in the update image if you
actually flash this to the via to a real
system do an update to this it on
encrypts it writes it to the spy in a
real system and then it's not completely
unencrypted and it's super easy to
extract the encryption trees using a
physical flash programmer but also
because the encryption only covers the
cram FS headers it's pretty trivial to
reconstruct the tram FS header and
extract the file system and find the
encryption key that way here's a code
snippet that we found in the the code
that's handling that particular part of
the update basically it checks it goes
and checks each of these two addresses
to see if it's already been decrypted
and if it isn't it goes and decrypts it
so that the region layout is completely
identical to x10 except they have these
slightly encrypted blobs and it's it's
funny that I I presume that they tried
to do this to make it harder to attack
the system but it's just off you see a
shoe at this point so it's completely
hard-coded encryption key it's not a
real significant barrier to any attacker
so we now know how to extract and repack
x8 through x11 generation BMC images
which is from 2009 to the current
generation but how does the update
mechanism work itself so in order to
update the BMC you basically send it I
PMI commands and those can either happen
over the local system interface or over
the IP mi LAN interface and there's
something pretty interesting about that
because the local system interface
between the host and the BMC is
completely unauthenticated so if you're
running code in the system maybe malware
is running on your server it can send
whatever commands it wants to the BMC
and can it can do some pretty
interesting things so we discovered also
that like the UEFI firmware updates
they're not doing any
he signed a signature validation of the
BMC even though the BMC is a highly
privileged management component so we've
got a hopefully quick example of
basically flashing this with a malicious
BMC image and all so we basically have
netcat listening we've created a a
malicious image that basically has a
armed version of a mature reverse
Connect back shell in it and we'll run
the legitimate update tool from Super
Micro to flash one of these modified
images to the system it does have the
functionality to do this remotely over
the network and one thing that's pretty
interesting about the mi I P my spec is
that there is support for IP my group
managed systems where you can have a
large number of servers that all use the
same credentials and that can be really
useful for an attacker because if you if
you own one system you could potentially
steal that password and use it to own
all the other servers in that IP my
manage group and this this process over
the of the ipmi link is pretty slow
because it basically sends an individual
IP mi message for every I think 52 bytes
of the image and this is a 32 Meg
firmware image so it takes a while so
we'll skip ahead a little is I think the
full process is about 15 minutes and
it's basically it's basically just
passing it's like sending ipmi messages
to send each of these different regions
across the the local system interface to
the BMC where the BMC is receiving it
and and
see so at this point we've transferred
the complete image to the BMC the BMC is
validating it parsing it seeing if it
looks okay and and then after that it
goes ahead and writes it to the flash
yeah so this is kind of a slow process
also but we can skip ahead a little ways
so once it's done its rebooting so just
the BMC reboots the the server stays up
and running if you have some application
running on the system and somebody runs
this while you're not looking there
there's no indication there's no
interruption of the server and it just
it keeps running only the BMC reboots
so we got our connect back from the BMC
and we can start taking a look around in
the system this is basically just a
reverse shell so it's a it's an ARM
processor we can we can take a look at
the cpu info field or a cpu info file it
is the a speed BMC so we do have
successfully code basically put whatever
we want in the BMC we can we can have
this connect back to the to a command
control and and run whatever we want so
so all servers from 2009 to extend the
current generation are vulnerable to
this like Alex said they still
approximately a million servers every
year millions of servers are vulnerable
in the field so if we take another look
at a architecture diagram before so now
we know how we can we know a number of
ways that we can brick the UEFI BIOS
boot via software but usually the BMC is
used to recover from this state and but
now we also know how to break the BMC
via software so just in this environment
we can create it's a create we can
create a situation where the server
won't boot up again unless you have
basically you need to go take physical
access and attach a flash programmer to
every BMC in order to recover the system
and that could be hundreds of thousands
of systems in large data center and
that's gonna take some time and some
money but there's also another
interesting thing that you you get if
you own the BMC like this is that maybe
you have a couple different servers one
is connected the internet one is only
connected to the private cloud to a
private cloud there isn't a direct
connection from the internet into your
cloud there isn't a direct connection
between these two servers so even if the
but if the server is
and because this local IPMI system
interface is unauthenticated you can
pretty directly connect to the BMC you
run whatever you want in a BMC and the
the BMC is often shared between that
management interface is often shared
between different servers so you can use
that to basically laterally move within
the environment especially if you're
using IP my group managed systems so so
we have nessam ways to detect some of
these chip suckers like I mentioned it's
a really great tool for exploring your
system and we do have the this whitelist
capability so you can basically generate
a whitelist run that against the the
server periodically see if anything has
changed the spy descriptor there's also
module in ship sect that will go and
read your spy descriptor it'll look for
access permissions it'll warn you if
it's a writable in this particular
example when we did this research there
was almost a thousand vulnerable models
that we identified vendors have started
fixing the spy descriptors but it's
going to take a while for all those to
be fixed so for checking the integrity
to be of the BMC super micro is update
tool actually does have the
functionality to dump the existing
firmware so you can use that take a look
at it and see if it's the version that
you're expect see if there's something
that you don't expect there so we
reported the these UEFI and bios issues
back in January it's a Super Micro and
reported the BMC issues in March and
we've got a little bit of additional
information about the timeline and what
we did at these two links Egan's you
guys can check out later so Super Micro
basically they only fix this for the X 9
and X 10 generation and they they're
making it optional to to update the
systems for existing systems so you you
basically need to go ask them
to to get the update for these systems
which is maybe not the the best for
security but one thing that really was
interesting about this like at least the
last day a day or two was that like the
apt 28 did confirm that these UEFI
implants do really exist in the wild
we've already seen examples of bricking
systems used in like for real
at attack campaigns but server firmware
continues to be a just a big problem and
there have been so many fixes of
mitigations and base basic hardening of
operating system applications that
firmware security is lagging way behind
and you you can still have some pretty
serious damage that comes out of
bricking or implanting systems like this
and that's it
[Applause]