mm-me baby
shanks marker bhikkhus Adela preliminary
data evolution mobile device in
management the Apple device enforcement
program a severe memory loss
administering the same a significant
mucho Berryessa w Travis so hello
everyone my name is James Barclay
I'm a senior R&D engineer at duo labs
which is the research arm of duo
security and today I'm going to be
talking about Apple's device enrollment
program so I'm the only one here today
giving this talk but the it goes without
saying that you know this this research
was truly a team effort
Alaba day and ishe the pine Briana and
Todd Manning all contributed heavily to
this research so I wanted to give them
credit up front so I'm just gonna dive
into the agenda very quickly I will go
over what MDM and DEP are then I'll move
on to DEP authentication and in some of
the inherent weaknesses in it I'll talk
about our research methodology and
exploit then I'll go into Apple serial
numbers in their format next I'll talk
about the impact of this research and
then mitigations and then finally I'll
wrap it up with a conclusion so mobile
device management is a technology that's
used to centralize the management of
end-user computing devices so these are
things like laptops desktops mobile
phones and so on on Apple Apple
platforms specifically it refers to
clients which are Apple devices and
servers that implement support for the
MDM protocol the MDM protocol leverages
apple's push notification service to
wake devices and then communicates with
the MDM server to receive commands the
client will perform the command and
return
the output to the server so what is the
device enrollment program this is a free
service provided by Apple to
organizations that are using MDM to
manage their endpoints it streamlines
the process of MDM enrollment and it
does this by allowing iOS and Mac OS and
TV OS devices that are directly
purchased from Apple or an authorized
reseller to enroll in MDM during the
initial setup DEP also allows
administrators to configure which setup
screens are displayed to the end-user so
these are things like the series setup
or Apple ID set up so if throughout this
talk I'll be referring to the DEP API I
wanted to call out that there are three
different DEP AP is there's the
so-called cloud service API this is used
by mobile device management servers to
associate DEP profiles with specific
devices next we have the reseller API
which is used by resellers and Apple
Retail to enroll devices and check
enrollment status and so on lastly we
have the private DEP API this is an
undocumented API that is used by devices
to write to directly communicate with
Apple's DEP service so unless otherwise
noted throughout this talk I'm only
going to be covering the private
undocumented DEP API that's used by
devices to communicate with Apple so
next I'm going to just go over the
enrollment process so what happens when
a device boots up for the first time and
checks in with DEP so there are several
asynchronous steps that need to be
satisfied in order for a device to
enroll in MDM via DEP initially a device
record needs to be created by the
reseller or by Apple then the
organization needs to assign the device
to an MDM
server in the Apple business manager
portal next the MDM server will retrieve
the device record through the cloud
service API which and then we'll create
the DEP profile then the device will
authenticate to the DEP API and retrieve
what's called an activation record now
I'll be talking about activation records
quite a bit in this talk next the device
will authenticate to the MDM server to
retrieve its enrollment profile so this
contains things like the MDM enrollment
payload a certificate payload and a
simple certificate enrollment protic
protocol payload the device will then
request and retrieve a client
certificate through skep and then
finally it will authenticate to the MDM
server and begin receiving commands so
here's just a more visual representation
of that flow this talk is focusing
mostly on step four the dep check-in
process so this is when the device is
first involved in communicating with the
dep api so before i dive in just wanted
to define some of the the binaries that
we'll be talking about throughout this
talk so first we have the MDM client I
said earlier that when referring to
Apple's MDM it covers clients and
servers that implement support for the
MDM protocol the MDM client binary is
the client side of that profile this is
just a utility that's used to manage
configuration profiles on Mac OS and
then cloud configuration D the so-called
enrollment device enrollment daemon is
responsible for communicating with the
DEP API so I said I was going to talk
about activation records to give you an
idea of what those look like we you know
have a screenshot here this is what is
returned by Apple as a JSON blob during
the DEP check-in process here shown in
like a pretty printed format
so you'll notice one of the things here
is the so called configuration URL
this is the URL of the MDM server that's
how the device is going to know which
MDM server to communicate with in
addition to that we've got information
about the organization that owns this
device so the organization's email
support phone numbers physical addresses
and so on so I'm going to talk a little
more about activation records during
this DEP check-in process the device is
going to retrieve this activation record
from this URL I profile Apple comm / Mac
profile the two functions that are
responsible for this are CP fetch
activation record and CP get activation
record CP fetch activation record
actually retrieves the activation record
over the network and it delegates
control to cloud configuration D through
X PC which is an inter process
communication protocol divined by Apple
and CP get activation record just
retrieves it from the cache both of
these functions are present in the
private configuration profiles framework
so I'm going to talk about how devices
are authenticated as part of this DEP
check-in process so the request payload
that is sent to this Mac profile
endpoint is a json dictionary containing
two key value pairs action which is the
remote action to perform and SN which is
the serial number this payload is
encrypted using a scheme that's
internally referred to as absinthe and
the serial number in this payload is
what determines which activation record
is retrieved so I'll say that again the
serial number and the payload is what
determines which activation record is
retrieved not how the device was
authenticated so in this way dep
effectively only uses the system serial
number to authenticate prior to
enrollment so an attacker armed with
only a valid dep registered serial
number could potentially enroll a rogue
device in an organisation's MDM server
or just glean information from that
activation record
this can be easily verified by changing
the vmx file for example invert VMware
fusion to be that of a serial number
that's registered with DEP this was
originally discovered by the pine
Brienne who I did this research with
Victor of Ranchin and Jesse Peterson so
I'm going to talk about our research
methodology so what were the goals of
this research so once we knew you know
that only the serial number is is
required or what is what is used to
determine which activation profile or
activation record we get back we set out
a way you know wanted a way to automate
that so our goals were to be able to
insert any arbitrary serial number
during the request for this activation
record also we wanted to demonstrate how
it's possible to brute force Apple
serial numbers which could be checked
against the DEP API in bulk we also
wanted to demonstrate how anyone you
know using these methods can determine
which organizations are using DEP and
gleaned information about them like
physical addresses phone numbers and so
on and lastly we wanted to demonstrate
that rogue MDM enrollment is possible
using these methods so as I mentioned
previously changing the serial number in
VMware fusions vmx file to be that of a
DEP registered serial number will you
know confirm that that is you know the
only the only piece of information that
determines what activation profiles
retrieved this can easily be verified by
using either the MDM client or profiles
binary to force a DEP check in so on 10
dot 13.3 or older you would use MDM
client and then 10 dot 13.4 or later you
could use profiles it's worth noting
that the behavior is a little different
here but if you'd prefer to use MDM
client you can simply copy that from a
machine running ten dot 13.3 or older
and and you know run it onto one of the
newer machines it works just fine so the
what MDM client will do when you force a
TV check in like this is print a pretty
printed activation record if the devices
serial number is registered in DEP or an
empty activation record if not with
profiles if you enable MDM debug logging
it'll write the activation record to
this log file at manage client log
additionally you'll see this pop up on
your on your Mac that says this device
can automatically configure your Mac if
it hasn't previously completed so like I
mentioned earlier once once we knew that
only the serial number was or the serial
number is all that's required to like
authenticate to this DEP API we set out
to automate this process and demonstrate
how an attacker might you know use this
to retrieve activation records in bulk
so we considered three approaches we
could reverse-engineer the protocol
between cloud configured 8 configuration
D and the DEP API which is internally
referred to as Tesla and the encryption
scheme which is internally referred to
as absinthe we also considered you know
if it was possible two men in the middle
requests to I profiles apple comm / mac
profile and then finally instrument the
binaries that directly interact with
this API so reverse engineering this
Tesla protocol so you know the the cloud
configuration de binary will request
this activation record which I mentioned
previously contains these two key value
pairs the action and serial number the
the payload in this request is encrypted
using a scheme internally referred to as
absinthe and the is then base64 encoded
and used as the request body and an HTTP
POST to that endpoint in cloud
configuration D fetching this activation
record is handled by the MC Tesla
configure configuration fetcher
so the general flow of MC Tesla
configuration fetcher and enter state is
listed here we explored each of these
you know methods somewhat deeply but
ultimately it just led us further down
the rabbit hole and we decided to
explore other methods of being able to
modify the serial number that is
presented to the DEP API so the the next
approach that we considered was men in
the middle requests to the DEP API the
cloud configuration D does a certificate
pinning but we found that this can you
know pretty easily be you know changed
by flipping the MC cloud config except
any HTTP certificate flag to true but
like I mentioned earlier this this
payload is encrypted so it wasn't
feasible to to modify it before it's
actually sent to the API without having
the keys use required to to decrypt it
so lastly we looked into instrumenting
the system binaries that directly
interact with the DEP API this has the
benefit of being able to leverage the
existing flow or infrastructure and with
with just adding our own little bit of
functionality right before that the
payload is signed it's worth noting that
for this to work because cloud
configuration D is a protected binary
under system integrity protection or sip
that it needs to be disabled we
recommend doing this on a non-critical
virtual machine because sip is actually
a pretty useful security feature so with
SIP disabled we can attach to cloud
configuration D with LL DB you'll notice
that we need to use sudo because cloud
configuration D requires elevated
privileges then we can just wait for the
cloud configuration D process to attach
so while we're waiting we can enforce
the DEP check-in in order to force odd
configuration D to attach and then begin
our debugging session so one of the you
know first things we wanted to do you
know once we have this debugging
infrastructure set up is looking to how
we could just modify the serial number
that's returned from the IO registry
this is you know done in cloud
configuration D and as far as we know
that's the serial number that's sent to
the DEP API so we thought if we could
modify that then it would change what is
sent to in that payload so we were able
to modify the serial number retrieve
from the IO registry by initially
setting a breakpoint for IO service get
matching service then we then created a
new string variable containing an
arbitrary serial number and then just
modified the register to point to that
variable recreated so this can be seen
in this listing here we set a breakpoint
for IO service get matching service wait
for the cloud configuration D process to
attach continue and then just step
through the execution of the program
until we can see that the r14 register
you know contains our serial number then
we just create a new serial number and
then write the register to point to that
new variable but unfortunately for
whatever reason this didn't didn't
actually modify the payload that is sent
to that mac profile endpoint but you
know something did so I'll talk about
what what actually worked so once you
know that initial process failed we
looked to find the closest point where
the serial number is still in plain text
before it gets signed it appeared that
the best place to look was this MC Tesla
config configuration fetchers start
configuration fetch method which does
the following and it creates a new NS
mutable data object calls this set
configuration data method passing at the
new NS mutable data
object calls this profile request
dictionary which returns that that
dictionary that contains those two keys
that we've seen earlier it then
serializes this dictionary to JSON signs
the JSON payload base64 encode zit and
then does a bunch of other stuff like
sets the HTTP header to post sets the
body to the base64 encoded payload sets
some profesora some HTTP headers like X
profile protocol versions is set to 1
and the user agent is set to config
client 1.0 finally it's going to use
anis URL connection to perform the HTTP
request so understanding this flow of
the MCU Tesla configuration fetcher
start configuration fetch this allowed
us to modify the dictionary containing
that profile request before it's
ultimately converted to JSON so to do
this we set a breakpoint for data with
JSON object so as you'll see in this
listing we set the break point for the
regex data with JSON object wait for
cloud configuration D to attach continue
the execution then we create a new NS
dictionary object in memory containing
both the this you know it's that it's
that payload that gets sent to the Mac
profile endpoint so an arbitrary serial
number and then we just update the
register to point to that that NS
dictionary and that works so with just a
few l DB commands we were able to insert
an arbitrary serial number and get that
serial numbers' activation record back
not the serial number of the Mac we were
using so as you can see here the you
know we have someone else's activation
record so one more thing though you know
I think Steve Jobs said it best l DB
Python interface these are not three
separate things no not really but once
we had the initial proof of concept we
wanted to
show how we can automate this
fortunately the ll DB API is available
in Python through this script of ridging
interface which is installed by default
if you have the Xcode developer tools
installed so it may that made it
relatively easy to just write a script
that takes a list of serial numbers and
then in turn you know injects them into
cloud configuration D to check for the
digit DEP profile or activation record
so next I'm going to talk about Apple
serial numbers because we think you know
it's important to understand how how
easily these can be a brute-force so
what you know the this is an example of
an Apple serial number it's you know
just a string of letters and numbers but
through this research we we were able to
demonstrate that the how easily Apple
device serial numbers can be brute
forced so there's actually enough
information in the serial number to
limit the search space pretty
significantly which would increase the
speed with which an attacker could
generate serial numbers and then check
the DEP API for the activation records
in bulk so what would this allow an
attacker to do so if they're able to
prove for these serial numbers and
leveraging this exploit it's feasible
that an attacker could determine exactly
which Apple customers are using the
device enrollment program build the data
set mapping the serial number to the
organization that owns the device or
build a data set mapping the serial
number to the complete activation record
or you know we think it's feasible that
an attacker could use this information
to further target organizations so I'm
gonna talk a little bit about this
serial number format that Apple uses
Apple serial numbers use a 12 character
format they have the following five
components it's it's worth noting that
11 character serial numbers also exist
but these are used on older older Apple
devices so with the 12 character serial
numbers we have a plant code the year it
was manufactured the week it was
manufactured a unique
unit code and then the device model
identifier so the plant code is the
first part it's three bytes at position
zero the the only known plant code on
Mac devices is c02 but we don't know how
many plant codes exist for all their
devices on iOS devices for example there
are many plant codes the year of
manufacture is one byte at position
three and uses the range listed below
bowels and the character B are removed
from that range additionally each year
has two possible characters associated
with it
that correspond to the early or late
moniker sometimes used in Apple product
names so the the epoch associated with
this numbering scheme starts with C
which represents early 2010 all the way
up to Z representing late 2019 so we
don't yet know what will happen in 28 20
if Apple will roll that over or just
stop making computers and iPhones and
we'll see next we have the week of
manufacture the this is denoted per
half-year if the code is in the second
half of the year it indicates an offset
from the 27th week of the year and it
uses a single byte in the following
range similar to the year of manufacture
the week of manufacture removes or omits
the characters BS y&z it's not
documented why but it makes sense or
stands to reason that you know this is
because they're visually similar to
other characters next we have a unit
code this is three bytes at position 5
and it's unique to each device within
its model year week of manufacture and
plant code so this is the biggest source
of entropy in Apple serial numbers it's
a base 36 scheme and it uses the range
listed below
so there are six thousand six hundred
and fifty six possible values within
that range that I mentioned earlier next
we have the device model identifier
which is a four byte ID that is created
from a finite set of codes that Apple
maintains for their further hardware
models they're the most comprehensive
source of these IDs that we've found is
on piker alphas github repository he has
those all listed there or most of them
not all of them so knowing that we can
break apart the serial number I showed
earlier we have the plant code we can
see that it was manufactured during the
second half of 2016 the 48 week of 2016
we see this unique unit code and in the
model the model associated with that
that ID which is for the MacBook Pro
13-inch 2016 for Thunderbolt 3 ports and
yes that's the real product name so next
I'm going to talk about the impact of
some of this research so we basically
see two you know two scenarios where you
know where this could be leveraged by an
attacker to expose sensitive information
about an organization initially just
obtaining the DEP activation record
couldn't allow an attacker to to just
build up a data set or you know just
expose information about the
organization that owns a particular
device next it's it's you know it's
feasible depending on the configuration
of the MDM server that an attacker could
perform a rogue MDM in enrollment so
basically like stealing the identity of
a corporate device so the information
disclosure issue is you know we see that
you know it's possible that you know an
attacker could use this you know the
information retrieved from the GP
activation record in combination with
the serial number to aid in social
engineering attacks such as like calling
the helpdesk and asking for password
resets or
help installing some software or you
know who knows next the rogue DEP an MDM
enrollment so the MDM protocol provided
by Apple supports but it doesn't require
authentication as part of the enrollment
process so that means without any
additional protections all that would be
required to enroll a device in you know
in a company's MDM server would be this
you know the serial number of the device
once enrolled you know a lot of a lot of
things could be deployed by the MDM
server
you know the configuration profiles
which are delivered via the MDM protocol
contains support for delivering VPN
configuration data Wi-Fi passwords
certificates private keys you name it so
next I'm going to talk about mitigation
so we think there are you know a couple
of things that Apple could do to
mitigate this this issue one of the you
know one thing that we think would be
possible is leveraging the unique ID
that is generated in the secure Enclave
on the t1 and t2 chips this is also
present on iOS devices
so it's worth noting though that this
may not be feasible until the until
every Mac device contains one of these
coprocessors additionally we found no
evidence of strict rate limiting on this
Mac profile endpoint this could be
because it might be difficult for Apple
to distinguish between let's say you
know an attacker hammering the DEP API
or an organization that just bought a
thousand Macs and is enrolling them all
at once behind the same NAT router
additionally we found that although this
endpoint is called Mac profile it will
happily accept iOS serial numbers and
retrieve the activation record of iOS
devices that you submit to it lastly we
think requiring strong authentication
prior to the DEP enrollment happening
would mitigate this as well so there are
also things that customers can do that
are leveraging DEP and MDM you know
regardless of some of these are the
risks outlined in this talk so like I
said earlier the MGM protocol supports
user authentication so if possible turn
that on and in addition we we think that
just because a device is enrolled in MDM
doesn't shouldn't afford it any
additional privilege within your network
so require strong user authentication
post deployment before sending down like
any sensitive information and also Apple
documents these best practices in the
Apple business manager help
documentation so moving under the
conclusion so it's it's also worth
noting that DEP still provides value
we're not telling people that you
shouldn't use de PE or MDM because we
think that the benefit of having
securely manage you know manage devices
outweighs some of the inherent risks in
how DEP authentication works also Apple
could be doing more to strongly
authenticate devices but it might take
time for this to become fully realized
for example like with device attestation
that that might require new hardware
last or next don't treat devices as
trusted just because they're enrolled in
MDM you know requires strong
authentication post MDM enrollment
before sending a sensitive configuration
data and then lastly if possible you
know enable a user authentication as
part of your MDM enrollment process
so this is the disclosure timeline
starting with when we initially
discovered this authentication weakness
and reported it to Apple leading up to
the research being published I also want
to thank Jesse and all max Belanger
Victor Ranchin Jesse Peters and Jesse
Peterson for their contributions to the
Mac security community and specifically
their DEP and MDM research as well as
piker alpha for documenting so much
about the Apple serial number format and
that's it
yeah what's a any questions yeah if
anyone has any questions
you
II tecnologías información de
comunicación trabajemos privacy de
trabajo Mo's contra el voto electronic
oh no al goat electronic ona business
any Co party Rogalla McHale cozy no al
vote electronically contam Oso montón de
gente porque no algo toh electrónico
trabaja most EMA vinculum propia
intellectual Conroe Blasi own s internet
etc etc no pueden Oba Carr no esta bien
y en para poner Louis on a pan Tasha
yatta bueno voy a hacer muy brave a
seguramente no V Erina nosotros el grupo
de VA Libre KS tuvimos trabajando Persil
yendo lo con unas Papa Leto's para que
no se en una encuesta tuvimos una
respuesta bastante positiva conseguimos
el número de encuesta de encuestas
responded as Kevin a mosaic our hace que
muchas gracias a todos ustedes que
contest are incapable Marin char Londo
estamos haciendo investigación como de
SIA fides sobre protection legal de la
comunidad de segura informatica porque
no sin 10 de Mo's que en nuestra misión
de prata hard hecho su mano slot area de
la Segura informatique a club a por que
quien nova decir SI un dispositivo de la
cosa esta Boehner and ole opry Vasa dad
see you today no pueden revisar
profundamente ESO se positivo cyber
vulnerabilities severe puntos de ataque
a de nuestra privacy de Vigo esto sólo
por por un ejemplo de por que para
nosotros s clave a la Sayuri
informatique a por que vamos a estar
siempre se va Libre van condo la tarea
Segura informatica in siendo el congreso
mucho no dicen you take a arson yo Sosa
samos lo be brave a mente en resume a no
Sosa samos lova cada vez que el congreso
save acute ear una ley que puede atacar
algunos principio que nosotros defend
hemos Inclusion doe la libertad a hacer
say Guria informatica
nosotros a samos lo v lo hicimos desde
hace DAC Ocho años que vemos control a
rapid Ament a lo que lo que encontramos
en esta página investigación y muy
preliminar porque además podemos Revis
our
say encuesta keV tuvimos centromere Cory
sequela do a todavía no NOS ponemos
processor hace que la información Betar
despues de nuestro sitio boca de una los
imamo se esta primera proximation por
que no es oficial es un Conte Oh muy oh
ho ho de lo que fue emo viendo hasta la
tarde teníamos siento noventa encuestas
ay yo vivo set a resultado venti say por
ciento Roz personas que nos contest
Aaron dicen no connoisseur nada sobre
las regulation a pen a Lay's que pueden
affect our la actividad Segura
informatica un treinta por ciento dijo
poco quiere ser Chianti poco nada
tenemos ooh cincuenta Y Z por ciento de
las personas que NOS respond Hierro deep
ways to vemos own solo un de por ciento
ND air coma cinco de lo que podemos
revisar estos números seguro Vanna a
cambiar okay no creo que mucho dgeren
connoisseur mucho en de da sé la
cuestión Pennell vinculum la Segura
informatica en nuestro boca de una
tambien encontramos que un quincy por
ciento nos dijeron que su trabajo few
effect odd o alguna vez por la
legislation Pennell yo Hollis de propia
intellectual un de por ciento no dijo
que fue a personal mentio empresa de
trabajo objeto de acción le gallais por
sus active ad InfoSec consult ADO's
sobre see su isseo ella legislation be
gente para judical Asik TV della hippie
mas de segura informatica receive emos
un c en un treinta por ciento uni nor
menos a yell no se como mucho Nessie on
Oprah so no say no say es una respuesta
muy interesante por que no se hace UN
plant a Oda situation so Luanne Carter
say por ciento de coche no bueno vamos a
ver como podemos OU / r para que se no
se despues iya
cambia cambia say algunas art a suppor
co porno porque aquí lo que se juegan la
libertad de las personas los delitos
Pinal a's pone en rio la libertad de las
personas no esta bueno kc7 a jugar su
liberty' no se pang si lo que estan
haciendo el Eagle oh no see a t lo que
Vicente
momento en el código Pinal que puede
impact Arlo's esto por ejemplo
loaf we mosaic you tear Indomie Lucho
cuando se Provo a fracas ahmo's en
nuestra intento de que se can be a a
Yuna s tu t'en el código pen Alva gente
decir que esto es hoy un delito que ser
a repre Mido con Quincy Diaz a un año de
cárcel de question says he sells a
communal o cargoes Agrabah antes etc etc
keen LTS true she detrusor a utilizar a
dato documentos programas hace temes
inform Atticus
Oh Wendy err a esta parte Lamas Kritika
p.m. Ben de Vitry Busha a a circular a
intro do can you see T me 4matic o
cualquier programa de Senado que hacer
daño en intercambio alguna vez entry
ustedes algo un programa que puede hacer
asado para que usar an EO o EO que no
hope or supuesto que no esto está
Byzantine Argentine pero tenemos una
oportunidad como mucho UT probablemente
say pan a un código Pennell en debate a
un nuevo código pennilyn debate a en la
parte odd o sobre delitos informatique
o's esto está copyable pagado de lo que
e la oportunidad a cake Isis en una
Reforma el código Pennell podemos 10
algún tipo incidence iya para cambiar
esto cambia no favor Vella Sager EDA
inform Attica yo Nieto este es el último
a la ultima la sorpresa sí mismo
proyecto de código Pennell tre una clue
sulla vinculum con la propiedad de
electoral alguien hacer tomando una
cerveza me see a decir que no van a
poder cheap AR la play sino Rexy Onan
con ESO no Rishi Onan kannada adah
masiha bueno es a become Bertrand Alito
si esto prosper a nosotros la samos algo
cuando nosotros ego todos nosotros a la
practica de aquel k sin la utilización
delta 2 lara de los derechos
fabric a Alma cine Pongal event event
mucho de cualquier otro modo commercial
easy deposit Evo's intro Mentos are
chivos electronic Oso media's
technological cualquier tipo o clase que
de modo principal permiten Lockett a
sein o la vez cenk rotational acetyl una
señal de radio diffusion esto
básicamente por el tema el football no
se que tan interesado en el futbol
Pareto's para ESO a y despues la a la
segunda parte es la posibilidad de Alou
de la medida Technica's de restriction
de capilla de software película musica
juegos etc si esto SE approve IVA Buena
part el trabajo beauties hacen back a
dar convertido en delito toeses lo que
lo que yo querría cantar lays sko montón
de cosas que esta empezando sobre su
campo de acción en el cual syria
muy bueno que podemos trabajar juntos
las organizaciones como la nuestra que
trabaja Mo's derechos humanos
a tecnologías yo Ted A's esta en el
campo de la Segura informatica para que
este tipo de cosas no passin a no
terminan converse en donde leto la
practica koti Dianna de las Segura
inform Attica o la tenancy a Lucille a
distribution a la Sarah Mientus Kate OC
cada uno te Susan seguramente en su
practica koti Dianna en lasa guria
informatica dicho esto muchas gracias a
todos los que contest Aaron a todo lo
que se Sur Karen a todo lo que collabora
rumba Moses air públicos todos los gatos
ko to vemos vamos a seguir con este
investigación y vamos a hacer todo lo
posible para que la Segura informatica a
no se illegal asada y que ninguna
ustedes Tenga que pasar por un proceso
Pinal que no se lo Samos an idea muchas
gracias a Echo party muchas de ustedes
se Fulani ok viene
[Applause]
bueno algunos anuncios esta noche
tenemos la fiesta CA in Galicia Hama in
put together and Kwame justo yonder ha's
en frente paronto pero bueno si Megan a
loss on Oprah decir el nombre say olesya
yaaaa giant Ramos en la última parte de
like okay el entree de premios de toda
today's parallelize a los premios loss a
sponsor's y lamentablemente para ustedes
para Fortuna demente para nosotros vamos
a ser ando lo que que des des Tyco hace
que estamos esperando que que se en un
par de personas mess y con somos sorondo
ki Silencio Chico's tan tama Repetto so
che Noongar a c-note a gricean to Russia
osa birthdays iy y no se C's oven pero
en este pais assistant AC chick en la
página de de tweeter no extra estamos
haciendo una encuesta para la mejor
Charla de este año hace que les pido
cito a no Taryn Vassar rnd a minutos s
habitación vamos anunciar algún adora CK
Agoura su celery Botti promote army
Luisa como se ha hecho para when el
después no vamos cuenta Louise Oh