um at the panelists it's already here i
think we could start with our session
today
um good morning ma'am and everybody good
morning for being here with us
um this is an extremely special day
because it's the second day of shakti
and greetings from everybody in our team
for those who do not know shaktikon is
an international conference
organized by team shakti with a focus on
bringing
more women into the field of cyber
security and we are doing that by
engaging people in beginner level
conferences as well as giving them ctfs
so that they can taste what exactly they
are going into
the top performers or ctf will get a
price worth of almost four thousand
dollars
now again as madam is already here
let's get into a session and it's a
great pleasure of mine
to invite our first speaker of the day
ms preethi srivastav
she is a former general manager software
security at internet corporation
she has managed the security of all
softwares
in the area of operating services cloud
services
security solutions uh performance
libraries graphics softwares compilers
and many more
at intel for almost nine years prior to
working on security she has managed
various products like compilers binary
translation software
pal advisor and other important products
she has done a ms
in computer science at ohio university
us
and ms in mathematics and computer
science at
iid delhi india she's also passionate
about promoting women insecurity and one
of the major reasons we look forward to
hearing your session
i welcome you ma'am into our session to
give us an insight on the pragmatic
approach on software security
and to kick start day two of shakticon
i welcome you to take over man all right
uh so let me just share the
what is the sharing right now
okay it's still disabled would you allow
me to
share
um
just a minute man we're trying to fix
that
[Music]
yeah oh it worked
i think are you on the road yes
seems like okay yeah we are able to see
all right okay i should have thought of
that before
all right so a few minutes lost here i
guess uh
10 minutes lost almost here so we'll
speed it up um
so yeah so let's just start you know um
like the introductions already has been
there
so this is a i'm just going to talk
about you know a pragmatic approach to
software security when i started working
on
in intel how you know i sort of brought
it up
from scratch you know there was no
program on security there was no
security being built into our systems
in our software or hardware for that
matter um
so you know i started this um from
scratch
and so i just wanted to share that first
before i would talk about
you know just promoting women here of
course
uh so you know why security matters i
think most of you already know from
yesterday that you've been
to the conference have been attending
and some of you are already in this
field
so we'll talk a little bit about that
not a whole lot
uh what's the approach then i will begin
to a little bit
about the security development lifecycle
which most of you are from their sdl
and then many tools that you can use
i'll talk a little bit about them
and you can obviously find them
otherwise indicators what one should
track
in order to be successful and making
sure that the security is really built
into your software
and then some key takeaways and
hopefully we'll have some time for q a
given that we have some hiccups here
um so security really matters and
nowadays
it's even more every day you hear about
breaches
right um just yesterday actually i read
in the news google
had a whole bunch of issues but there is
privacy of their photos
and their many programs you know many
accounts were hacked about two years ago
and they did not even tell the users and
yesterday they said they have
legally said that they are not going to
let the users know about this
because none of their important sort of
pii
wasn't impacted pii is your personally
identifiable information so you know
every day we hear about this
in 2020 i have some data here to say
you know how many data breaches were
there there were over 155 million
speeches
you know and the records which were
exposed
were even larger over 1 billion
so you can imagine you know how this is
really
impacting our lives you know not only
personal lives
business finances everything and couple
of these
um major security incidents that we had
just this year
it hasn't been that long right we are in
april
um and so parallel is one of the um
you know a social media app it's kind of
a conservative app i don't know if you
know much about it
so the data that was that they had
was hacked all of the data was gone
and they didn't even know until the
amazon web services which is also known
as aws
they removed their platform from the
servers that's when they came to know
and it was essentially 70 terabyte
of leaked information that had pretty
much
100 99.9 of their post messages
video data time location there were
people who verified their identity
at parallel with the driver license
photo id
everything got exposed so you know these
are like
huge issues this is like the top hacked
issue this year in just in three months
then facebook instagram and linkedin you
know they all three these three
companies were impacted
by a chinese social media company which
is called social arts
that suffered a data leak through an
unsecured database
and that exposed account details and pii
of at least 214 million
social media users from where
facebook instagram and linkedin
and so these are the kind of things and
once you get exposed like that your
email addresses
phone numbers profile pictures your
account login names
password your company name you know
whereabouts location
everything gets exposed so this is why
security is important
because we have these hackers who are
out there not doing anything else but
just
hacking our systems
cloud your platforms your hardware your
devices
your financial systems everything so
security really does matter
you know that's i just wanted to sort of
start with that
um because i know many of you already
are aware of many things
but just to highlight a little bit so
what's the approach we can take
you know to uh oh you can see the whole
screen can you
yes we can okay um
so the organic growth of security
workforce was one of
my theme of building security from
scratch
i said hey you know what we already have
engineers smart people
let's make sure either they understand
the security already
or we teach them and then we also
understand what are the risk of our
products
because not everything is same in the
software or hardware on devices right
some are more hydrazed security profile
things
others are lower risk so let's
understand what kind of products we're
building in intel
for example and you know so that's risk
assessment is sort of the first thing
you do
then you want to assess the security
capability of your organization or your
company
and then i make sure that you have the
right set of training to make them
good security engineers you know and
these security engineers are people who
are implementing security features
who are testing who are architecting and
all of those
and in general you can make people a
security architect
or expert off the back just by training
you need to hire some of them right
there are out there
in public so that's what i
actually put together oh sorry um
that we hire security architects and
security experts
and then we need to make sure that we
have a good secure development lifecycle
that's essential to this whole thing
right if you don't have a good security
development process you're not gonna get
there
so you need that and then the security
program you need to have in place
with the right set of people in order to
govern the process
go on the security development life
cycle how it's embedded in your
development cycle
you know with jira and other things
so managing the sdl process
risk assessments training and
something we called final security sign
off to make sure that the product you're
shipping is really good
and then you want to manage through your
security experts and security architects
so that they are embedded in different
teams different product teams
in making sure that they are lifting
them up
on a security retro scale you know
so that's important so that's the sort
of the higher
level approach on this and sort of the
crack of the meat
but if you go into the security
development life cycle which is the next
slide here um this picture right
on the right side is really talks about
secure development life cycle
that what kind of things it comprises so
i'm not sure if you can see
the whole picture maybe i can do this is
this better
all right so the request starts with you
know you need to understand what are the
requirements for your products
for your software hardware devices
whatever you're building
what what's the design like are you
making sure the design
has the right set of implementation that
is going to
have eventually in that based on the
architecture
so you need to do threat modeling you
need to understand what's the threat
landscape for
your particular product and so along
with the threat landscape and the
requirements that you have
you can have a good threat model i think
you had a class
yesterday from sangli on threat modeling
by the way she used to be in my team
at intel i had hired her anyway so
threat modeling is important and then
the design review that comes
after that on the architecture side
using the threat model
and the architecture diagrams that we
that the product teams provide you
actually do a security design review
you make sure they have the right set of
controls in place
sort of right designed in place so that
the implementation can begin
so this is a sort of a very important
point here in the sdl and this takes a
lot of time
in general to get through then the next
thing is you start developing on based
on your design and architecture
once the development is done you do need
to put some control to make sure
everything is being done the way it was
designed right
either your architects or your experts
sort of
cross-check these things then you get
into the security testing
and code reviews so the code review is
done to make sure the
seek is a security code review to make
sure that the all the security
errors are taken out of the code right
so
it's actual manual code review the
security experts do
and then the security testing we'll talk
a little bit more about the tools but
one other thing i really emphasize is
important to do is fuzzing
and penetration testing i know everybody
out there does static code analysis
and all of that right clockwork or
covarity you're running those every
night
but it's and that's important but on top
of that you've got to fuzz
your software and do the penetration
testing based on your the threat model
based on your threat landscape you've
got to do penetration testing it's very
important
and then the final security review which
is going to basically ensure that all
the security bugs are fixed
right architecture got defined
appropriately implementation got done
appropriately
and based on your security risk you have
done everything that's ought to be done
in securing testing
and make sure that there are no escapes
right and then
you release now of course at the release
time you also need to make sure the
infrastructure that you're releasing it
is so for example it's a cloud app
you need to make sure that cloud
security is built into that as well
so you know you need to sort of make
sure all the
issues are on security are resolved
before you release
and then
let's talk about you know from here then
we let's talk about tools
so vulnerability detection tools and
secure development process tracking
tools these two are
key to making a program of security
successful
so vulnerability detection where you
have to do it during development and
during the release cycle
some of the important things you can do
is compiler flags for example
you know you make sure you're using the
right compiler flats
for example runtime buffer overflow
detection
runtime bounce checking c plus plus
string in containers
uh you know are you do you have the
right set of
security flags that you're using there
increased reliability of back traces
full asr for executable these are
compiler flags
that you can use to you know make sure
that you have
compiled and built your program with the
uh you know without any bugs
now um static and dynamic analysis i'm
sure you may have some other sessions to
talk about
but like i mentioned earlier clockwork
coverity of the static analysis tools
uh dynamic analysis are like appscan
fortify
check marks many others
then for binary analysis for third party
code now this is a very important
item in in a security program the binary
analysis for third-party code means
the third-party libraries for example
open ssl
is an open source library you need to
make sure you're using the right version
of openssl or you're going to have
security vulnerabilities
so you got to do the binary analysis or
third-party code
one of the tools that we were using was
bdba
it's called black duck binary analysis
tool by synopsis
and it's very powerful so that must be
done
during the release cycle you know once
you finish delivering development when
she's done sas
and that stuff you got to be making sure
and in fact
keep doing it during your development as
well as
release to make sure you don't have any
old libraries that you're using from
third party you can either it could be
microsoft or them
um fuzzing now in the fuzzing area there
are lots of different tools out there
they're open source like afl
um there are uh defensives you know
there's
defensives from codenomicon there's
another very good fuzzing tool
puzzy lops spike you know quite a few
um then get into penetration testing now
penetration testing tools
obviously huge lists out there right but
you got to see
what kind of threats are important for
you to detect
based on your posture your product
so verb suite for example for web
right in order to exploit a
vulnerability that you may already
kind of have a sense about you can use
metasploit
um quality for network and wi-fi
you know issues that you want to detect
wireshark is another one
so just like many of them out there but
some of these are really important that
we were using it until and then that's
something you can also explore
now in terms of secure development
process tracking tool
um a latest one which is getting really
a lot of
good reviews is secure development
elements
it's also known as sd elements um
it's one of the tool that security
compass for example
actually has it's very good
in the sense it's actually going to
track the picture i showed you
pretty much requirement design
development testing
um and final security sign off
the risk assessments all of those things
it tracks and also has
capabilities to provide sdl for agile
which is another topic which of the zone
to talk about
so going into now the next slide which
talks about the indicators
the indicators are really uh to make
sure that you're doing the right things
and and you're tracking them well so
internal vulnerability tracking you know
in terms of bugs right vulnerabilities
are security bugs
essentially which could possibly be
above that's what we call them
vulnerability
so during development and pre and post
releases you need to keep
making sure that you are tracking the
number of bugs that are being found
fixed what is the lifetime you know all
of that
um external incidents that are reported
by your customers you need to try
right because you need to understand
whether you're improving your
your product on the continuous basis so
life of an incident how long does it
take to
fix an incident incident is essentially
a security vulnerability right
how long it takes to fix those what are
the severity levels
are they the 24 hour fixed needed type
of you know zero day bugs
or are they something that are low risk
and we can take
you know next at least to fix it so cbd
levels are important
and then time to fix and release now how
long it takes to fix and how long it
takes
to get it to the customer's hand which
is a totally different thing
right and you may have to go through
channels to release a product
and whatnot so you need to track all of
these things and organize
nation's progress now because we have
built this on our approach on our way
there is organization have the right set
of maturity levels and
resources we need to make sure that we
demonstrate the progress
on that as well as training
what kind of usage of the tool we have
are we are they consistently using it
um the level you know what you know
different
variety of tools different variety of
testing they're doing
are they benefiting from the tools and
then
security development process compliance
of course you need to make sure sdl
compliance is in place so these are the
things that you need to
measure and make sure that your
management understands
from time to time like a quarterly
review or such
and and track these metrics to make sure
that you're making good progress and
making an impact
in the security of your product and then
the key takeaway is really that
in order to have a successful security
program you need to
acquire adequate budget you need to talk
to your management and make sure
you have proper funding to be able to
hire new resources or train current
resources or buy
tools or training or by training
in fact there are many you know vendors
which provide
training right and uh so that's another
like sans for example is very expensive
and by the way security training is very
very expensive in general
so you need to have budget to do that
you need to make sure that you have your
resources are skilled
and have the appropriate training for
example if you're doing any cloud app
you want to make sure you do have
a cloud security expert ignorant cloud
security architect
in place uh similarly other areas right
um and then you want to make sure that
you have deployed all of those required
tools
if you if you buy the tools and you
don't deploy them in consistent manner
they're just sitting on the shelf
it isn't going to help you so you've got
to make sure that they're deployed
and you have this as part of your sdl
process
monitoring them on a curtain chase basis
using a metrics then the required
training for all employees not just the
people who are working on security
need to have training for all of the
software
you know development or hardware
development people
all engineers because you want to make
sure they understand why
security is important and then
robust security architecture i cannot
say less things about that this is so
important
you have to emphasize on that in any
company any design you do you got to
make sure it's a secure design
because that's where it stops if you
don't have a secure architecture design
then you're not going to get there
you're going to find issues where you
have to go and redesign
so you want to avoid that and then
adequate security testing
it can never be enough keep doing as
much as you can
you know static dynamic fuzzing code
reviews
penetration testing at the end after the
release testing you know
running apps whatever you can do um
and then adhering adherence to security
development process
is really the key the companies fail
where
they implement everything and then
nobody follows so you've got to make
sure that it's being followed you're
tracking it
using sd elements or some other tools
like that
and have a program which is constantly
monitoring it
um so that's all i have today and i
think we are right in time i don't know
if you have time for q
a at this point
you guys tell me
so uh uh i have a question um
yes you have been leading security
for uh decades and uh
at intel so so you know uh
tell me uh from your experience
what are like the top three things that
you feel
are the most important uh things uh
that any um you can say medium or
small-scale enterprise
should you know watch out for that do
not have large budgets uh
to really secure uh their systems
but you know the key critical things
that they should have you
um yeah so i think uh
first of all a training just for all of
the you know i mean there are
a lot of open source trainings as well
so
for the small companies even for
startups in fact my son has a startup
so i advise him quite a bit um so what
you do is you want to get
free software free training as much as
possible definitely
because you don't have a budget you
don't have enough budget to buy and
they're very expensive i agree
but there's enough uh information out
there that you can get
and you can you know the top ten ish you
know ways of
managing your security through your open
source
uh you know uh sites websites
that you can do you know oh wasp is one
of them right i'm a member of
us and oha's top 10 is something pretty
much everybody that's like all the
people who
you know develop apps for apple for
example they go through that list
um so that's one i mean this is
something minimum you've got to do
is check out our wasp site get the those
bugs out and they're
very good in describing what exactly
you're looking for actually it's like
doing a code review and then
implementing it
uh so do that then in terms of training
there are some
trainings available online that you can
take like
you know um basic training you know for
uh for your mail emails for example
right
uh how do you tackle those you know what
kind of things spoofing you know things
like that you have to
look for so i think some of those basic
trainings are available that you should
deploy and cheaper is fine you know as
long as
at least something is happening and then
the third thing is
you know try to make sure that your
infrastructure is secure
you know when you develop you won't
think about the software product that
you're releasing but what about the
infrastructure
you are using you know the i.t part of
the
company so to speak you know what
networks you're using what clouds you're
using
in your desktops all of those need to be
secure you know at least
spend a little bit of money on firewall
i think that's kind of the basic thing i
would say
somebody should think about securing
infrastructure securing your software
and getting people to have securely
mindset by training
any more questions thank you are the q a
sections
uh here can i ask those questions
yes please yeah so one of the questions
are are there any specific audit
agencies like iso for security
oh hi there are many uh
in u.s at least uh you know there are
many uh
price pwc is one of the biggest one
price waterhouse we have used them um
so there are many out there i'm not sure
you know
uh in india what i'm sure they are doing
the similar things in india as well
um intel india for example i know i was
using pwc
so that's the first one that comes to my
mind
another question there or what are the
recently used security tools that a
professional
should be familiar with
should you be familiar with like okay so
we talked about tools right
different categories of tools so if
you're asking about the testing tools i
think
you know one of the first thing
everybody should know about clockwork or
clarity
or check marks one of these static
analysis and dynamic analysis tools are
very important
um and if you are into buzzing you know
because your software need requires
flooding
fuzzing essentially random input testing
um so fuzzing you can use like afl
open source is pretty good you know i
would say 90 percent of your issues
would be found by that
so i think those those are the ones and
then if you're doing web applications
um you know maybe burp suite for
penetration testing would be good
um you know sort of apps are generally
on the web on the internet
so i think that's a good one to do um
but if you're getting into network
you know then you know then wireshark
and
others come and call us and etc
security audits which must uh
which must have uh security audits
oh i see um
i think in general security audits go
after
whether you have sdl define your secure
development lifecycle are using sdl
that's where they start with then they
look into what tools you're using
and what kind of testing you're doing
and are you consistently doing it for
example if you're running clockwork or
poverty are you running it every night
you know regression testing and so they
look at that and then they look at your
results
it's not like they look at the
progression in it so it's not just like
okay we're using and you're done
check you know it's going to be that
you're going to have to show them the
outputs
of everything if you did a security
architecture review
was the proof the audit's always looking
for proof for everything
so that's you know these are some
minimum things that they're going to
look at
if you have done testing they're looking
at the testing results they randomly
might look at some of them
and they don't look at in your code to
see if you fixed it
that's one thing which is always missing
in audits i would say
but they're looking at the reports so
just by reports that okay
well you had you know 20 issues and now
you know two weeks later okay they're
all fixed you don't have any more issues
because your regression testing shows
your claim
right so things like that they're going
to look at
they also look at if their compliance
with um
you know isil standards and hipaa you
know depending on
where which um area you're in
uh so they will make sure that you're
following those standards and
meeting those standards
one more last question um you said that
when you started you had to build
security from scratch
so getting people to take security as a
major
con seriously is a constant challenge so
what motivated intel to take it
seriously
i think uh yeah i had to do a little bit
of selling
uh quite a bit of selling to the
management actually it's less
engineers than the management but um the
managers don't want to put their people
on security you know they have
development to do and they have released
to do and all that stuff so
you struggle constantly with the
development managers
you know that's where it starts and
that's why emphasize security training
is one of the thing when uh
krishna asked that question right what
are the three things
that you would tell any company so
training even though it sounds kind of
boring thing you know and it's not like
it's such a big tab oh i gotta do
training i gotta spend time
but you know we go to college don't we
we take our degrees don't we so
how did you get there you obviously did
get trained
that's how you are here so it's
important to train
people and people need to understand
this and that they have to have some
security understanding in order to
even find a buffer or flowing the code
right so
since i come from the kampala background
it was a little bit easier for me to
understand the importance of security
because i implemented these things you
know but
stack overflows were like big issues or
heap overflows of
big problems for me so i can i could
talk to people in that sense at that
level and say hey you don't really want
these bugs in your
code you know because first of all
you'll have functional issues as well as
security issues
when they when they can relate it to a
functional issue they get it very
quickly
so that's how i sort of started talking
to people and getting them to understand
um it's a lot of evangelizing you know
the importance of security to people
in all levels engineers
managers you know executives you know
you got to do all of that marketing
marketing doesn't get it they want to
ship the product who cares about the
security you know i gotta just get this
thing out there
for some conference or for some launch
you got to teach them too
so that's you know the training is
important and getting people to
understand the importance of security i
think
it starts at the you know the root level
and then getting people interested in
work on it
it's not that hard what you do is you
demo a couple of hacks
and then everybody wants to find oh
somebody hacked my code you know
so that's the most easy way to convince
somebody and then they know yeah i want
to do this i want to figure out how this
happened
okay you know one of the conferences
here is black hat
which also has defcon i don't know if
you heard of it
but defcon is basically that a lot of
hacking you know seminars and booths and
people just go and learn there
that's how those conferences got popular
and so many people work on this kind of
stuff now
um but my message to women
we need more women working on security
is really important
and i have sent um you know some uh
outlines uh and some statements to i
think it was
one of you but i think the important
thing is that women can do anything
you know and they have a really good
focus good eyes to find things
i think it's really important that they
become good hackers
you know not the sort of the black
hackers or black head hackers but
good hackers you know who can find white
hat hackers what we call them here
so that's important and i encourage you
you know women out there
who are watching please you know if you
already are in security
great you know improve your knowledge if
you
don't have security background you're an
engineer or i.t person
you know get into it get get some
training just go google some or go to
obas
you know i told you that already was
website
really has a lot of information you can
start poking at it
github has so many stuff so many things
on security so many
little things you know people have
released all these open source tools
there is some github right
afl and i don't know um
was that a fuzzing lop and then a whole
bunch of things
i mean i i don't go and code anymore but
and it fascinates me you know if i go to
github and i see all this kind of stuff
out there i'm like wow so there's a lot
of things you know you guys can find
and you just need motivation you know so
self-motivated get into it
thank you honestly honestly it's been a
pleasure hearing you pour in your
knowledge about software security
including the different tools and
indicators and also giving us
a tada framework on constructing a
successful security program
um seriously thank you so much for such
an insightful session
have you as a speaker and we hope that
you join us for further events also
thank you so much thank you have a great
day
and um you know thumbs up for the
shaktikaan
thank you mom bye