moving on further we will be having our
next session
in a few minutes which is by artik
from couchstrike and
um
she will be uh she is a director
engineering at crowdstrike and she will
be talking to you
on evolution of endpoint deduction and
response so
stay tuned with us for our further
session
thank you all for staying tuned with us
and we are moving on with our next
session so
we have here with us our next speaker
for the session miss
artie gupta director of engineering at
godzilla
hello arty and welcome to shaktikan
thanks thank you so much
so before handing over to you i would
like to give our participants
a short introduction about you
so miss arthi is the director of
engineering at couchstrike and
is currently working on the next gen
cloud-based security product
previously she was director of
engineering at college and
was responsible for building out the
quality security analytics platform
she has an extensive experience with
building the web skill systems
and she had previously worked for amazon
and hot star and here today she is with
us to talk about the evolution
and end point deduction and response
so over to you i'm miss arti
thank you so much purnima for the kind
introduction
um so and thank you shaktikan team for
having me today i'm excited to be here
so give me one second to share
my screen
can everybody see my screen okay yes we
can see your screen
okay great all right um so today
i'm going to be talking about um
endpoint
detection and response right so um
endpoint detection and response edr as
we call it
right um is the technology
that is responsible for keeping your
machine safe from malware from breaches
right so um crowdstrike right where i
work
um we've built a number of great
products in the cyber security domain
but uh edr um is our
signature our flagship uh product that
we pioneered more than a decade ago
uh to protect uh computers from always
right
so today um over the next um
uh hour or so um i'm going to be sort of
um walking everyone through the journey
of um edr as it started
from antivirus up up until
uh next generation edr right
so um very quickly um
this is what we're going to be looking
at today um
so we'll start off by looking at
antivirus software
then we look at why there was a need for
edr
right um we'll look at uh what edr
is how it works what are some of the
strategic principles
uh behind edr and then we'll wrap up
with um the future
of edr right um okay
so i imagine that uh
most people in this room um would be
familiar
with antivirus right we've all used it
uh the big vendors
in this space um are semantic and mcafee
right um but to basically understand edr
and why
it was needed um we first sort of need
to go back
in time um rewind a little bit uh to
look at
um antivirus right um
so um this is probably going to be a
quick refresher for
um those of us that are familiar with
antivirus already right
um so essentially antivirus right uh
similar to edr
is meant to protect your computer right
from malware
right that's the end goal and so um
how does antivirus do this right so
imagine that i'm downloading a file
on my computer but before i run this
file or before i open this file
uh antivirus would kick in to make sure
that my file is safe
to run right if my file is
saved it is allowed to um be opened or
executed right
but if av finds my file to be infected
then it would either quarantine my file
it would delete my file
and basically block my file from running
right um
so uh how does av actually work
under the hood right so um
basically what the antivirus software is
doing
it's looking for indicators of
compromise or iocs as we call them
right so what are these iocs
right so iocs
are basically unique identifiers
for malware right um
each malware has a unique set
of iocs associated with it so you can
think of these
as traces of evidence that the malware
leaves behind when it runs right almost
like a smoking gun right that you would
uh
find at the scene of a murder iocs are
somewhat similar
so ioc iocs for example it they could be
file names
they could be um file hashes right
these are files that the malware for
example would create on disk when it
runs
or um an ioc could be an ip address
of um basically
a network connection right that the
malware
is setting up right or an ioc could be a
domain name again that the
malware is establishing a connection to
right so some um
basic examples of iocs so um
what the av vendors do they are the
authority
on all of the known malwares out there
in the world right
so they keep a
database of all the known malwares
as well as their associated iocs right
and they work hard at keeping this
database up to date as you can imagine
it's a hard job
to keep track of all the possible
malwares but there is a database
that is tracking all of these malwares
and their iocs right
so when my file is about to be executed
on my machine
and av's job is to make sure that it is
safe to execute what the av does is it
checks
um this files ioc against
its database of all known iocs of all
known
malwares right and it checks to see if
my files ioc exists
in this database right if the ioc
exists that means that my file is bad
it's corrupt
it's infected so av should block it from
running if the ioc is not found
my file is good to go right um
so again this is just sort of a
pictorial um
view of what i just talked about right
um
so i have a file i've downloaded this
file let's say from the internet i'm not
sure
if this is a good file or not right so i
ask av to do a scan
of my file right so what av does is
it computes a hash
of my um file right so
um the hash is um essentially
um a unique signature for my file right
every
file would have a unique um
hash and um this hash
for the file is checked against
the um ioc database that that av vendor
has
built right um if that ioc
is found that means
that this file is bad right if the ioc
is not found in the database then per
the av
this file is a good file right
and i can execute that file right if the
file is bad
then av would either quarantine that
file
or it would basically uh delete that
file altogether
right all right
so um so we looked at how
um avs work right and
um avs um were
a good first step back when they were
invented
somewhere in the 1990s in protecting
uh users machines from um malwares right
so they did
well in the first few years right but as
you can
imagine um av uh solutions have obvious
limitations right um and basically av
solutions
could not keep pace with increasingly
sophisticated
attacks right so um hackers uh
found it increasingly easy to bypass to
evade
uh the av software right um so we look
at
what some of these limitations are that
made avs vulnerable
to attacks right so um first off
um avs by the nature of uh
the way they operate they are reactive
right so you have to have
um seen that malware before you need to
have that malware present in your
database
of known malwares and only then would
the av
catch a particular malware right
because they are reactive avs cannot
guard against zero-day malwares right so
what is a zero-day malware
it is a piece of
malicious code that has previously not
been seen or previously
not known to the av software which means
that that malware
is not in the database of malware
signatures or iocs
as we call them right um so if
my file is infected with a zero day
malware
av is not going to detect or prevent
this malware
right um so um i think
recent research shows that um
a majority of um
malware um are um
basically zero-day malware right so avs
fail um miserably
in this regard right um and then uh avs
cannot
guard against self-modifying um malwares
right so over the years malwares
themselves became
increasingly sophisticated so we now
have malwares
that can self-modify their signature or
their iocs
right as they jump from machine to
machine so which means that
the malware has multiple
associated signatures or ioc against it
which makes it difficult to track in the
database right so
avs don't do a good job with self
modifying
malwares and then uh lastly
um the avs don't
do well with fileless malware right
um fileless malwares are those
that do not um need to
write a file right on the user's machine
to actually sort of infect the machine
and propagate
right these are file lists and by
definition
avs work on um file based
malwares right av needs a file that it
can
create an ioc for look up this ioc in
its database check if that file
mark that file as good or bad right so
if there is no file for the malware
what is the av going to do essentially
nothing right
um so because of these limitations right
there was a need for
a better solution that could actually
work
to protect a user's computer right
so this is where um endpoint
detection and response edr
came in okay so uh edr
was um pioneered by crowdstrike
um about 10 years ago to in 2011
starting 2011 to be precise
um in response to overcoming
some of the limitations of av as we saw
right
so uh the goal of edr
is exactly the same as the goal of av
the goal is to protect
a user's machine from bandwidth right
the approach
that edr takes to solve this problem
is very different from the approach from
the ioc based approach
that uh av takes right so
um edr uh solutions we'll talk about
what how exactly they go about
uh solving this problem but at a very
high level
edr uses a signature less approach or an
ioc
less approach to detecting malware right
now um so um basically we'll
cover how evr works what over here
um we'll look at some of the strategic
principles that an edr
solution employs right i'll go into more
details in further slides but
to touch upon this right now basically
edrs right the way they detect malware
right is by looking at indicators
of attack io is not
indicators of compromise or iocs right
we'll talk about what i was are
right number two right the principles
that edr works on the focus is on
providing visibility into
all of the activity that is happening on
the user's machine on the endpoint
machine we'll talk about why
visibility is so important um and why um
edr is based on this principle of
providing
visibility right and then um
last um edr
believes in keeping humans in the loop
right so the fight
is um humans and machines
are together uh fighting other humans
the adversary right it's
um good humans are fighting the bad
humans together with machines right
unlike av
where machines are single-handedly
fighting
um the adversaries right
okay uh so now let's sort of dig into
these
principles a little deeper and really
understand what they mean
so um
what are ioas right um
so ios stand for
indicators of attack right
ios are the means by which um
an edr solution would detect a malware
right if you remember av solutions
use iocs or static signatures
to detect malware
ios use io
i'm sorry edr uses uh ios right
um so ios are essentially
behavioral patterns that indicate
suspicious
behavior right that indicate malicious
activity
so uh edr looks for behaviors not static
signatures right
um which means that edr solutions
because they're looking for behaviors
uh bad behavior are more proactive than
av solutions
because av solutions are essentially
looking for static signatures and that
makes them
reactive right um
okay so now we'll look at um
some of the differences um between ios
and iocs and how they solve this problem
of detecting
malware um differently right and how ios
ios are more effective than iocs
all right so to understand um how
ios and iocs work we'll
look at a physical uh real world
scenario
right and try to understand how ios and
iocs would have
um approach this problem differently
right so imagine that
you have a robber who is planning
uh and executing a robbery at a bank
right so uh before
the robber actually robs the bank he
does reconnaissance on the bank right
maybe he
visits makes a few visits a few days
prior
he sort of circles around the bank to
find
multiple entry points he tries to figure
out where the security systems are
located
right and then on the day of the robbery
on the night of the robbery rather
the robber arrives in his um car
right um he disables the uh security
alarms
and he breaks into the bank
proceeds to go to the vault where all of
the money is stored
he cracks open the wall and um
makes his way with the loot that he's um
uh gathered from the wall right now
um so this is the scenario and if um
let's see how we would basically detect
and prevent this robbery
if we were to use um ioses
right so iocs if i'm using
an ioc based approach i would basically
be looking for
evidence um of a robbery happening
based on uh previous cc tv footage that
i have
of a similar robbery that has taken
place right
um so i would let's say look for a signs
that somebody comes to the bank
um driving a mahindra jeep okay or
i would say that a man has entered the
bank and he's wearing a mumbai indians
t-shirt
right um or uh i would say that
somebody has broken open the wall using
a drill and liquid nitrogen
right now as you can probably figure
all of these are sort of very brittle or
sort of unreliable approaches to
detecting the robbery right because
if the robber let's say doesn't arrive
in a mahindra jeep but he's using
some other suv for example my ioc is
going to fail
or if he has a different if he wears a
shirt not a t-shirt my
ioc is going to fail and if he uses
basically
a different modis operandi to break into
the bank
uh my ioc is not going to catch him
because my ioc was looking at previous
cctv footage and figuring out what
the um what his sort of modis operandi
is
now if ioc ioas
are to basically
detect and prevent this robbery how
would they go about doing it right
so an ioa as i
mentioned earlier is looking for
suspicious behavior right which makes it
more sort of
robust right so um examples of
suspicious behavior
in this case would be let's say there is
a car which is circling around the bank
multiple times right
that's clearly suspicious or another
unidentified person
is entering the bank at night right it's
not a security guard it's not an
employee of the bank so who's this
person entering the bank at night
or it could uh another ioa could be that
the vault is not being opened using a
combination lock it's being
basically broken open right so all of
these are suspicious behaviors
that um basically um are not really
reliant on a particular modus operandi
they are more sort of generic they're
more robust right
so um now uh
mapping um coming to a sort of
more um cyber security
scenario of how ios and iocs
would work differently right
so um this is a um example
of a phishing attack right
um so you have an email
a phishing email that is sent let's say
to a user
the email says that
you need to pay up your mobile bill
immediately if you need your
if you want your service to continue
right so
um and then that mail has an attachment
for an invoice
um and it prompts the mail prompts the
user
to open that particular invoice to pay
pay that bill
to settle their views right so um there
is a word document attachment
in that email right which is which is
basically uh
that word document is infected with
malware right
so imagine that the user opens this
particular
attachment invoice attachment and
um let's say they go ahead and enable
macros
on their word document right which means
that
the malware code which is basically um
wrapped up as a macro would execute
on this word document right as soon as i
enable macros
and this bad code would then
proceeds to fetch a script right from a
command and control center
um in uh china all right so
uh this script is basically downloaded
onto my user's machine
right um this is the user that received
the email the the script is downloaded
on my user's machine
it's a powershell script which is then
executed
um on my machine right
now um basically
this powershell script then
essentially ends up stealing and
exfiltrating data from this user's
machine
to the command and control center in
china right
so the the hacker has succeeded
in um his objective of uh stealing data
from a user's machine
right this is the scenario now how would
um
the iocs and ios
help in preventing this particular
attack right
if i was using iocs again because they
they are static they are signature based
they would look uh we would create iocs
based on
um evidence uh based on previous such
phishing attacks right
so for example my ioc would say that i
know that
um an attack is underway underway if i
um see an email with the subject
immediate payment requested right or
um and another ioc could be if an email
comes in with the attachment
uh name invoicefund.doc
or the ioc would know the file hash
of the word document attachment right
and it could check to see if this word
document that i received
is this has the same file hash right now
as you can imagine
again it's very easy to basically tweak
the modis operandi and evade the ioc
right i could change the email subject
very easily
i could change the name of the
attachment right and i could just
tweak maybe the content of that word
document
and change my file hash so that i could
escape
detection for my av system because the
av uses iocs
it becomes very easy to bypass these
iocs
so how would ioa then work to
prevent this particular
attack right so the ios right they would
look for um behavioral patterns
suspicious behaviors right um so in this
case
uh suspicious behavior would be
a windows process right um
because so you op because if you
remember in the scenario
there was a word uh attachment right the
user clicked on that word attachment
and then as soon as that word document
was opened the macro inside of that word
document
launched a powershell process right so
if you look at the process chain
the windows word process
is launching a powershell process which
is clearly a suspicious behavior it's
anomalous behavior because this
typically does not happen
um in in good scenarios right
so if windows word is launching a
powershell process it's bad behavior
that and that would be
basically be modeled as an ioa or
if um my edr technology
detects uh unusual network connections
from my user's
machine to to a server in china which is
basically the command and control center
then it would flag it could flag it as
anomalous behavior because
this user typically does not ever
connect to
any machine in china right so ios are
more robust because
they are looking for behaviors not file
names
or file hashes okay
now um some
um example uh some more example ios that
typically edr technologies would look
for
right to detect malware so the first one
we talked about um so it's basically if
windows uh document is launching
powershell right
that's an example or if a pd when i open
a pdf file
that causes a call to a remote server
right
or if my internet explorer
process is launching a command shell on
a windows machine
right all indications of malicious
activity or
if for example notepad right process is
spawning a child process which ideally
should never happen
if a notepad is working correctly right
so these are just some examples there
are plenty more
that exist all right now um
uh how does um this slide basically
shows um the differences
in approach between again iocs and
um ios right so
um iocs are looking for
point in time evidence of an attack
right um it's the like the proverbial
smoking gun at the scene of a murder
right these are
uh traces of evidence that the malware
has left behind for you
for example it could be file name file
hashes registry keys
ip addresses right the ios
on the other hand they are looking for
suspicious behaviors right because they
need to look for suspicious behavior
they need to record all behavior
or all activity that is happening
on the endpoint users machine
right so um they are providing
a real-time view of all of the activity
that is happening
on the user's machine so in that regard
you can think of
ios as a flight data recorder which is
basically recording all activity
inside of a cockpit right
all right now um
coming to the um second
principle of edr which is
provide visibility of all activity
that is happening on my um
endpoint machine right so this is the
user's machine
on which uh edr is meant to protect from
malware
so edr focuses on providing visibility
on that machine so we'll see why it's so
important
to provide visibility right
why is this one of the cornerstone
principles of
edr right
so um edr right
unlike av is built
on the assumption that it's hard
if not impossible to always stay ahead
of the bad guys
right so um basically um
edr acknowledges that it is
not possible hundred percent of the
times to prevent all attacks right this
is it's
it's simply an unattainable goal right a
more realistic goal
is to make the job harder for the
attackers
right um so unlike av in av
the end objective is i should prevent
hundred percent of attacks
edr says i should
record everything that i see i should
focus on providing visibility
right um and i can make a best
um attempt to detect malwares
and prevent them right but if i cannot
detect and prevent malwares i should at
least
have visibility on the machine so i can
sort of
after the fact at least detect the
malware after the attack has happened i
can detect the malware
and i can uh sort of take corrective
action right so um uh
basically this since edr
is based on the underlying assumption
that all preventions
and detections are not possible the
visib what edr
does is um it collects all of the data
all of the events that are happening on
a user's machine
and sends that to a central place we'll
see how that works
it sends it to a central place so that
humans have visibility into all of the
activity happening on the user's machine
right
when humans have visibility they can
basically
improve um
the base the system right you can have
basically a feedback loop
where humans can do threat hunting on
the data that has been collected they
can manually investigate
the data that has been collected
they can figure out detections they can
do incident response and provide this
feedback
to the system that look you missed this
particular detection and prevention and
then this is how you can automatically
um detect and prevent the next time
around right so it's basically a
continuous
feedback cycle going on because you have
visibility
right also basically um
visibility helps humans to
uh basically uh do forensic
investigations after an attack has
happened
right uh figure piece together
at the activity timeline how exactly did
the
attacker get into the system what were
his entry points what is his modus
operandi
right where is command and control all
of that information
can be pieced together because edr
provides visibility to humans
right um now to meet
the goal of visibility right um
edr products make use of a cloud
native architecture right so um
we look at what the cloud native
architectures
are right um so basically
what is a cloud native architecture and
how does
cloud native architecture uh help edr
why
edr systems use cloud native right um
so from day one ebr products
were built for the cloud unlike av right
um i think i imagine that most people
are familiar with
cloud right but essentially what that
means is that
the edr system is um
running outside of the customer's
environment right it's running in the
cloud
obviously you need some sort of an agent
or a sensor which is running on the
user's machine
in the customer's environment but the
sort of the data collection the
processing the storage
um is all running in the cloud right um
why would an edr um lay so much stress
on being cloud native right so
essentially when you're cloud native
that means that you can sort of
very easily scale to handle
petabyte scale data right now because
edrs are essentially flight data
recorders they are collecting
all possible information on the user's
machine there is tons of data to be
collected right so imagine millions of
users machines are sending data for
processing and storage you need the
cloud to be able to basically handle
this kind of scale
um and to be able and also the cloud
then provides
elasticity and uh scalability right so
if i have increased traffic because i've
added new um
machines that i need to basically
monitor um or
if my endpoint machine starts sending um
uh many factor many magnitudes of
data more right um the cloud can very
easily
scale to handle um the increased load
right now uh
so this is sort of a 10 000 foot view
of the crowd strike um architecture
right uh for our edr system right uh
so you have um two pieces essentially
right on the left you have the customers
environment
right these are customers paying
customers of crowdstrike who have
uh paid for the crowdstrike product
to protect their users machines from
albany right and on the right you have
the cloud platform
uh the crowdstrike cloud platform right
so you have these crowdstrike sensors
um running on the users machines the
job of the sensor uh is to act like a
flight data recorder collect
uh all events all activity happening on
this user's machine
send it to to the cloud for further
processing right so you have the
endpoint data
going into the cloud right now all of
this data
that is being collected is being um
stored in our threat graph
right um so this threat graph right
um is uh in many ways crowd strikes
secret sauce um it's um a
sort of a core um uh
foundation for um our crowdstrike
platform
and instrumental to our success as an
edr vendor
right um so um what the threat graph
does is it's collecting all of this data
that has
uh come in uh from the user's machines
and
it is building a graph visualization
of uh all of the activity happening on
the user's machine
right um so basically um
essentially the threat graph is building
process
chains um right so it's it's saying that
um process a launched process b
process b launch process c right these
process streams are um
what makes crowdstrike so strong at
detecting and stopping malware right so
if you uh
uh go back to the examples that the the
cyber the phishing um
attack scenario that we were looking at
right um
where essentially a strong indicator
of the phishing attack was the windows
uh word process launching um
a powershell process right if this data
was fed
into the crowdstrike threat graph the
threat graph would build a process
change saying that
the word parent process launched
um a powershell child process right and
this is immediately
sort of um suspicious uh
process behavior right and it would come
to the attention
um of our security analysts right so um
all of these process chains are stored
in the threat graph
and you have all of this data these um
this graph data
is exposed uh in our console right in
our ui
um and our security analyst teams
they make use of this data to do threat
hunting
right um to basically manually look for
suspicious behaviors
to um query this data to understand how
attackers are working right
okay so um now uh
this slide um right has some numbers
that show the
uh power of the crowdstrike platform
right
um so this is basically
um as i said our cloud platform
is built to handle petabyte scale data
right so
every day right our threat graph
um sorry every day
uh we are processing 500 billion
events per day right
to put this in perspective whatsapp
processes 100 billion messages
a day so crowdstrike is doing 5x
the number of events per day our threat
graph
stores 2 trillion vertices
right
we have 25 000 breaches
that we um stopped uh in the last year
so it's
it's simply amazing right the the power
of the
crowdstrike uh platform right and um
as i'm finishing up the sentence we
would have processed an additional five
million events
in the time that it takes me to uh say
the sentence
um so all right uh the last principle
um uh for of edr
right um keep humans in the loop
right so um
[Music]
as we were basically um
talking about a av
um says that machines
should be fighting um the adversary
right
what edr says is that machines
alone cannot fight the adversaries right
um
humans are the final and
the best line of defense against attacks
right so in edr
uh machines and humans work together
to fight the adversaries right the job
of the machine is to make
the job job for humans um easier right
so the machines
they provide visibility as we saw right
so they are collecting all of the data
that they can
and they are working to detect and
prevent
whatever attacks they can but machines
cannot detect and prevent 100 of the
attacks that is where
humans come in right so humans are
in the loop right um to basically look
at all of the data collected to
detect any sort of attacks that the
machine has missed
so for this humans are basically doing
threat hunting
on top of all of the data that was
collected and they are also responsible
for incident response right
so um when humans are doing threat
hunting they can sort of
look at uh patterns that the machines
may have missed on
uh provide this feedback back to the
machine so that the next time around
the machines can do a better job at
detecting um
the attacks right so it's sort of like a
continuous feedback
uh loop right and then besides this
threat hunting
um humans are also involved in incident
response right
so um incident response
is basically um what do you do
when you figure out that a particular
machine or a particular customer's
environment has been breached right
so incident response could be maybe
just basically um disabling a particular
user's account because that user
account was used by the hacker to gain
access into the system
or it could be blocking a malicious ip
address right or it could be
quarantining a certain
infected host basically isolating it
from the network right all of these
actions
are what humans could take as part of
incident response right
okay now um summarizing
what we just saw earlier right how
av and edr work differently
to achieve the same end goal right so
um as we saw
av solutions are reactive right uh
they don't look for behaviors they look
for static signatures like
file names or file hashes right edrs on
the other hand because they're looking
for behaviors
not a particular method of attack um
are more proactive they're more
fail-safe right um
so avs are based on iocs while
edrs are based on ios right
avs are focused on preventions av does
not care about providing visibility
it does not care only on detecting
the malware av says i want to prevent
all my malware
right that is the end goal of on the
other hand edr
primarily focus is on visibility and
make a best
attempt at detection and prevention
right but as we saw humans are in the
loop to do detections and preventions
that
um the machines cannot do right um
so uh av right by definition because the
system is fighting alone humans are not
in the loop
while in edr humans are in the loop to
help
to work together with the machines right
okay uh now uh so we basically
covered um what edr is
um what are its principles right how it
works and
why it's better than av right um so
um basically edr is
in many ways considered as next gen
antivirus
essentially right um edr is slowly um
and steadily displacing av solutions uh
in the market
right but let's quickly uh look at uh
what's the road ahead
for uh edr right um
so uh edr right um
it edr does a great job
at uh basically protecting
the endpoint machine right so the scope
of
edr is limited to the end point machine
the
edr the edr agent um or the sensor runs
on the endpoint machine gathers all of
that
uh it provides visibility and
tries to detect and prevent whatever it
can on that machine right
so all of the um sort of the the job of
evr
is focused on a particular endpoint
machine right
however um the endpoint machine um
alone is sort of um cannot
capture um all malicious activity right
it is
um so you have other um
security and networking devices in a
corporate environment you have firewalls
you have vpns you have email you have
active directory right
and all of these other data sources they
have
rich information right about maybe how a
hacker is moving through the network or
a particular sort of
a phishing email that has come in um
right um
so all of this information because edr
is just focused on the endpoint
is missing today for edr right uh if we
were to capture
all of this informat additional
information from all of these additional
devices it would add far more meaning
to the data that edr already has about
the end point right you could add
additional context
you could do a better job at detecting
and
preventing um malware right um
so this is where xdr comes in
so xtr stands for extended
detection and response right so it's um
endpoint
data plus network data
and cloud data right um so you have
um so xdr solutions take
the endpoint data that is coming from
edr and aggregate this data
with um for example firewall data
or your aws data cloud data right
um or emailed logs right
and they build a single sort of
holistic picture of a corporate
network's overall security posture right
so they are providing
single pane of glass visibility into
everything that is happening
across um the the customers environment
not only
on the end point right
so um very quickly um i
will take a look at some of the use
cases
that xdr
addresses right i probably won't go into
all of them but
let's look at the first one so um here
you you have edr which is
running on the endpoint machine it's
telling you that
um there has been um a malware detected
on that user's machine
right now if i'm if i use
xdr in this context i can sort of
enrich this data this detection
that edr has provided me with additional
information
coming from other data sources which
will help my security analysts
do a better job at containing this
particular malware which was detected by
edr right so um what xdr would do
is it would correlate this malware
data that was detected by edr with the
vpn data so that it could find
which user was logged into this
particular machine
at the time that the malware was
detected and it can also correlate
this data with let's say active
directory right so if you're not
familiar active directory is
the system that controls um logins right
for uh
in a windows system so um xpr can
correlate
the um this detect malware
detection data with active directory to
indicate
um or determine if the user
if this particular machine belongs to a
vip user
right so now i have additional context
on this malware detection
right i know that this particular
malware was detected on
a regular employee or a vip user right
which
which will aid my security analyst in
doing a better job at basically doing
incident response right how do they
prioritize this particular
malware incident right uh they have
additional information
to do that right so uh just one of the
use cases where
xdr comes handy and it can sort of
aid easier in doing a better
job right so uh yeah that was sort of a
quick
look at xdr um and i think
that's uh i won't go into the other two
use cases for now and
leave time um at the end for questions
so
uh that's it from my side
any any questions
thank you already for sharing us with
your knowledge on edr
and over to our participants like if you
have any questions please do
feel free to post it here in our q a
and chat window