it is such an honor to have with us
swamini krishnam
prana one of the most senior disciples
of amma
swamini krishna rita prana was born in
australia
she became interested in spirituality
after feeling that there's
something more to life than simply
acquiring material pleasures
she traveled through asia to discover
what life was all about
her final destination was india when she
first saw shri mata amrita nandame known
as amma
sitting in a small coconut attached hut
there were only 14 residents living in
the ashram
today the ashram known as amrita puri
accommodates several thousand people
swamini has accompanied amman all
offered to us
both in india and around the world for
the last 38 years
she has written seven books about her
experience of life with amma
and spirituality i now kindly invite
swamini
to deliver the benedictory address
i offer my prostrations to the holy feet
of oman
who brings her love light and healing to
the world
my pronouns to the esteemed special
guest meenakshi leiki
and mr eric falk and to all of the
brilliant speakers who will help to
enlighten our world
and a very special welcome to all of the
participants attending this wonderful
conference
wherever you may be in the world i must
admit when i first saw the poster that
included the eminent speakers who are
going to address you during the
three days of this conference i had a
very wow
moment all of the women are dazzling
forms of female
shakti making up a very impressive array
of speakers
on all sorts of fascinating topics that
i didn't even know
existed i wish everyone much success in
learning new things
and i wish you even more success in the
complicated task
of translating this new knowledge into
something great
that you can use to help others
when we look at the world today it
certainly has become very different
from a few years ago especially now
cyber security has become so very
important
it is imperative that everything be
protected in these
difficult times threats appear from
everywhere
in so many hidden dangerous ways but
luckily for everyone
we have at our helm the guiding force of
a great soul
in the form of amma amma bestows
blessings and protection for everyone
she inspires millions of people all
around the world to live
meaningful and happy lives filled with
love
compassion and selfless service
amma offers the ultimate true and
genuine protection
protection for our souls hopefully you
will be able to invite something good
from watching the way
she lives her life and performs
wholehearted selfless actions
i have to admit that i really don't know
so much about the cyber security world
at all
in my imagination i see people in their
avatars
climbing into little spaceships and
whizzing around the world
and to all different galaxies under a
cloak of invisibility
just like harry potter ready to battle
all of the evil demons out there
avatars working on the side of dharma
and righteousness
now i know it's a bit silly for my
imagination to conjure up
spaceships but i do know it is true that
you are all battling on the side of
righteousness
and even though i'm not a high-tech
person at all as you can probably tell
from the way i
associate computers with spaceships i
thank you so much on behalf of the world
for what you do
to keep us safe and in that way
we're not so different here at amazon
we're working to help uplift society and
protect it from darkness
just like all of you are working to
offer protection
even though you might not travel in a
spaceship i know you will have a toolbox
full of high-tech tricks and perhaps
even a magic wand in some form or
another to fix thing
i'm here to remind you that along with
all the things that you will keep in
your fix-it
toolboxes just remember to also keep
some of the old-fashioned things too
hard work compassion empathy
and patience with these ethical
qualities
when they become the backbone of your
work you will find
both success and happiness wherever you
go
and in whatever you do women hold the
capacity to be able to do anything at
all that we set our minds to
dharmic tendencies are inherent within
us
so i just want to remind that we should
always try to give something back to
society
especially when our own needs are taken
care of so gracefully
there are so many good qualities waiting
inside of us
eager for the chance to come out into
the world and help the world to shine a
little brighter in difficult times
we can brighten up the darkness if we
really try
a few years ago i accompanied my tour
conference in the middle east
along with alma a few of us were
accommodated in a very magnificent
opulent palace style hotel for two days
it was a picture of absolute luxury the
whole hotel and all of the rooms were
huge
inside our rooms and the wall was a
panel of complicated
almost hidden electronics to turn on and
off the lights
but we actually ended up staying in a
half dark room for much of the time as
we just could not figure out how to
operate the high-tech hidden system
properly
luckily we're used to a simple life in
india so we manage with very little
light
ammo was in a separate room about 30
meters away
with two bodyguards stationed outside of
her room for security
at the end of the first day's event we
returned to our luxury palace
which was really very lonely as there
was not a person inside along the long
sprawling section where we were staying
except for the two burly bodyguards of
course
that evening i just happened to be
standing by my front door
with nothing to do when i saw a filipino
priest in the distance
this priest had been one of the speakers
that day and was coming out of his room
he had the room next to amma on the
opposite side to me
he was about 50 meters away i watched as
he came up to the guards and asked me
excuse me but do you know how i can turn
the lights on in my room they answered a
quick and sour
no so he walked ejectedly back to his
room
there wasn't another person in sight to
help him and i knew that the front desk
was
miles away very complicated to reach as
i'd been there
only once so i made my way over to help
him find the light panel
i said hello to him and admitted that i
hadn't been able to work out the
electrical panel completely myself
but showed him that if he pressed in a
certain place in a certain way
that at least some light would come on
somewhere he was extremely grateful for
my help
i mentioned that i thought it was
actually a lot more comfortable
and easier to manage in a very simple
place and it was in this
fancy palace he wholeheartedly agreed
a simple home full of love is definitely
much better than fancy palace
and that was truly our experience after
dwelling in that large and lonely palace
for two days
simplicity and humility bring more
comfort
than luxury or greed ever can so don't
forget
when you deal with your fancy gadgets
and complicated technological fix-its
always remember that the simple
old-fashioned ways
they had their own particular magic
about them and can make our life feel
more whole
and complete one of the biggest
misconceptions that we have in life
is that we think we are all so different
from each other
while in fact we are all in essence
quite similar
everyone craves for love and peace in
their life
the main problem is that most people end
up looking in all the wrong places for
it
just as you strive to cleanse the
computer systems of viruses
so amma is here to do her job too she's
the greatest cleaner in the world
and she was asked by a reporter once
what her goal was
she said that she would like to be a
sweeper sweeping the minds of
people she wants to clean away the dirt
so that our real divine essence can
shine through
one day while we were traveling we
stopped in transit in dubai
a man working as a cleaner at the
airport recognized him and came to her
to ask her for her blessings he told
amma that he had not been home in a long
time as his cleaning work did not earn
him so much money
he also admitted to her that he was a
little ashamed to be
doing this kind of work alma smiled at
him and caressed his shoulder
she put her hand on his heart then she
said to him
son don't feel so bad for doing this
kind of
work it's not so bad to clean the dirt
of others
amma does this too he was so happy to
hear these words from her
it gave him the courage to keep on going
knowing alma
and he were in the same business and i
think a lot of you
had the opportunity to work in the noble
profession
of cleaning away dirt and helping to
purify our world
at least in some way we all have a small
form of amma
or the divine essence however you
conceive it to be
inside of us this innate divinity urges
us
on to do good things in our lives
one day i was with amma when she was
given the phone to talk to a devotee in
london who had recently given birth to
her first child
amma asked her how the baby was doing
and if she was able to breastfeed
the new mother said that the baby
actually preferred to drink from a
bottle as it could get milk more quickly
so she wasn't breastfeeding the baby i
was a bit shocked that in today's world
even the babies prefer fast food instead
of their mother's
precious nourishing breast milk
here in the amrita puri ashram amma pays
a lot of attention
to the small children she talks with
them and encourages them to learn the
stories in the scriptures in order to
help them develop good qualities
sometimes
sometimes it takes a lot of patience for
us to hear ahmad talk so much to them
about every little aspect of their life
but the other day i heard her say that
it is because she knows that so many
temptations of drugs or different bad
habits or negative choices
may arise for them in the future and
tempt them
she wants to give them the strength to
live a good life
and turn away from harmful behaviors
this is a reason that she's laying down
a good foundation for them now
when they are still young so that they
are equipped to deal with all the
problems that will inevitably arise for
them in the future
years ago when we were traveling on our
tours by room
there was one small child who loved emma
so much that he insisted on traveling in
alma's camper vehicle
along with us one day amma turned to him
and asked him to see a serious question
why were you born she asked
he looked at her with a blank look on
his face as he could not think of an
answer at all
alma told him the answer is
to know who i am and to serve others
then she told him to repeat these words
five times every single day
i was born to know who i am and to serve
others
to say this five times every day
i think that when emma was giving that
advice to the small boy she was truly
giving it to all of us too
while engaged in your technical work
staring at computer screens all day and
contemplating
solutions for major problems try to
remember to take a few moments
now and then to breathe deeply and close
your eyes
consciously slow down the breath regain
your center
and remember the bigger picture of why
we're all here
you have to look after yourself a little
to be able to help others
no matter where we may be or what we may
do
we're all walking the path to become a
better human being
and to serve society so that they may
want this too
many people choose only to strive on the
path towards name
fame and power as their goal but these
people rarely attain a satisfying
life filled with peace of mind and joy
when your goals are purely selfish there
will always be something missing
even if you manage to achieve all your
material goals
the missing ingredient is the happiness
that we get from serving
others dedicating a little of our time
to helping those in need
this doesn't mean that you have to give
anything up
in fact it is just the opposite
we just add a little more you can still
smite your cyber enemies into a pile of
electrical dust with a triumphant cry of
victory
but just remember to add a prayer that
your enemies may find the right path one
day
when our foundation is built on good
qualities and the true understanding
about where we will find an unshakable
strength
from the divinity within then we find it
easier to deal with
any and all problems that arise from
life i pray for you all to find
success satisfaction and joy in your
work
and to be able to pass it on to others
as well
thank you swamini for your ever
inspiring words and sharing your
insights on a balanced lifestyle
as you rightly said cyber security
professionals should strive to sweep
and erase the dirt in the cyberspace
this brings us to the end of our segment