right what are the kind of demand
drivers what
innovation areas are being prioritized
both by startups and the large
global industry members and where do we
see in terms of innovation what kind of
technology stack is getting adopted how
more and more cyber security whether it
is services and products
are going the cloud native route so i'll
be
essentially talking more about what is
the trend that we are seeing in terms of
demand for cyber
security and the innovation ecosystem
that is getting built up
the first thing i would like to start
with uh
i'm being very modest in what i'm saying
that india
has emerged as a global hub for cyber
security
it's not just the premier academic
institutions who are
doing a lot of research a huge pipeline
of phd
candidates and you know mte candidates
but there are three industry
constituents who have
made india into a global app for cyber
security in the last three to four years
it was almost in 2015-16 we had uh some
nascom and dhci had something called as
a cybersecurity task force
where we took on a mission and a goal to
make india a global hub for cyber
security it was not at that point of
time
in fact uh professor krishna sri was
engaged with us
when we tried to visit some other global
geographies where a lot of
cyber security clusters were developed
whether it was in hague in israel
in the uk in london and of course in
some locations in the us
she had joined us in a couple of those
locations so
what is driving this attention to india
as a cyber security provider one
is the global services industry which
all of us know
it's already you know pretty much
the global hub for it in addition to
that
in the last four five years we have seen
cyber security from the services
industry all the indian and the global
services companies
which operate of india for example they
moved
uh their revenues in such a way that we
are almost
at you know 4.3 billion the 2020 number
will be coming up
and even the talent pool they are hiring
and
the number of global customers they are
servicing
the number of global socks they have
established in various geographies in
asia pacific you
europe middle east and in the us also
that's one driver that is making and
they're servicing
the world out of india from india and of
course in some of the global geographies
second is the cyber security product
landscape
what was extremely important is that the
cyber security product
landscapes uh the revenue was about
450 million in 2018 but it grew to 1
billion dollars by 2020 december
and some of the solutions that they're
working on is
whether it is in the next generation
security that we are seeing a lot in
terms of quantum crypto
we are seeing their growth in u.s middle
east and in
asia pacific similarly when you look at
the global corporations
uh there are a lot of global
corporations which were already
operating out of india for shared
services for analytics
but if you look at it now many of them
are actually
setting up cyber gcc's we call them as
global
competency centers which are setting up
cyber gcc's
and that footprint is growing in most
cities whether it's gurgaon
hyderabad pune bangalore these are some
of the locations where
they are really growing so if you look
at
globally why is cyber security getting
so much attention
because of which both academia startups
and large industry are beginning to
innovate and
build a lot of new products is because
particularly post covent
while we've had a lot of headwinds for
economy across
various verticals so many verticals
were really in the red because of the
lockdown but
what is import what is interesting to
note is
covid and the pandemic impact has
actually accelerated the adoption of
digital and online
and because of that the attention to
cyber security data protection and
privacy
has already been improved quite a bit
okay
and globally we are seeing that it can
be
you know at the end of 2020 itself it
was meant to be a 123 billion dollar
industry
because of which there will be
requirement for new talent pool
there will be requirement for new
products new services
new verticals that are getting opened up
for adoption of cyber because they are
going the digital route
and what we are seeing is that because
of the
work from home at scale that has
happened in india whether it's in the
iit industry
or in the banking and financial services
industry even
very critical you know
sectors like oil and gas lot of work was
opening from remote locations
so because of which we see that there
will be a
lot the threat landscape will only
increase
because of which there would be more
breaches and because of which there
would be more regulatory attention
consumer attention to the impact of the
breach because of which businesses
are going to invest they're going to
look for those new products and
technologies
and we are also seeing that because uh
post pandemic before i come to cyber
security the adoption of cloud if you
look at
market reports of the way the large
cloud providers
performed whether it is you know amazon
google microsoft
because of which while there is a cloud
adoption for
the overall i.t and digital there is
also a cloud adoption for security
more security services are being
delivered through the cloud
right the security products are being
hosted on the cloud
increasingly we are saying there is no
new product that is coming to the market
which is either not cloud ready and
mostly
new products are expected to be cloud
native that means they will only work on
the cloud
we are already seeing a lot of examples
of that globally and in
india why i am repeating that point is
if you are a young researcher
right or a phd student or i am thinking
of a product
you need to understand this trend of
where enterprise digital and
t is moving so that if you're thinking
of a new product
you need to look at a product which is
architected for the cloud
right so it is not a regular
it's not a regular business solution
now even if you're building a security
product for vulnerability management for
an iot device
or you're building a security product
for mobiles building a security product
for the cloud stack
or for ot security you need to be able
to
architect that solution which is likely
to be cloud-ready
right if you see i think way back in
beginning of 2020 or 2019 gartner had
predicted that
uh all new entrants into cyber security
which means all the new startups and new
companies which are building a product
for cyber
or any historic vendor who has built an
on-premise solution
is likely to build a new product which
is a cloud-based
subscription-based model and it is
extremely important that if you're a
researcher
you look at enterprise digital trends
i.t adoption trends before you think of
how are you going to build a security
product
because often we see a mismatch that the
i.t industry and the digital adoption of
a large enterprise is going one way
whereas new products are coming
according to the paradigm of the world
world
they're still trying to look at a
building a solution which is likely to
be on-prem i think it's extremely
important
you marry your research and innovation
intellect with what is the enterprise
idea option i often as i engage with
startups
we engaged from dhci with a lot of
academia and we engaged with
all the cios global cios and the large
enterprise cios there is a mismatch
where
enterprise is headed in terms of digital
and the new products that are coming up
where the new products are probably
you know still looking at the old
construct of how it was being done in
how city was being done on prem
that's why i'm spending this a little
bit of time we are also seeing a lot of
new products that means if you're a new
researcher you should look at some of
this
there's a lot around multi-factor
authentication because of
all that is happening in the payment
side even in terms of the user
authentication that is happening
thanks to this entire remote working
there's a lot around user entity
behavioral analytics
and when you do this user entity
behavior analytics can there be
a privacy preserving way or
you balance the demands of privacy with
the productivity requirements of your
workforce this is another one that we
are looking at
and of course everything to do with you
know the web application security
because
why that is important now i think vaf
was always important
why it is now getting increasingly more
important is because
more critical enterprise
workloads are moving to the cloud right
they're moving on to the web whether it
is in the healthcare domain in the man
in the
you know e-commerce domain edutech
domain
how much education has gone virtual
online so as more applications
move online workloads are moving to the
cloud
you know the web application security
and all of that is
becoming very important we are beginning
to see a lot of new cyber security
frameworks coming
whether it is in the zero trust network
architecture zero test
this karta from gartner and in the
active defense there are a lot of them
that are coming up
and when people are building those
products or enterprises are looking at
what they need to do these frameworks so
there's a lot of csos
cios who are looking at all these new
frameworks that are coming up
so globally what we are seeing is um
there is an increased digital adoption
particularly in india because we can
look at it
we are seeing so much digital happening
even in laggard domains
whether it is in small and medium
manufacturing whether it is in
healthcare i think itits
large banking insurance telecom they
were always leaders in it right
and what we are seeing now is there's a
lot of focus around itot integration
because of which as ot networks get
opened up
you know even the validity of our uh
you know confidence in air gap networks
is getting test
is getting challenged now because there
is new research to prove
that uh it may not be adequate enough in
the current scenario
there's so much of remote monitoring
that is happening
on ip networks or on the internet for
uh ot networks they're getting opened up
there is a lot of
uh new devices which are getting
integrated for monitoring with the ot
networks
right and similarly the entire industry
4.0 we've seen a lot of this
in the auto manufacturing sector of
course
in europe and in germany we have seen
this across all
whereas in india if you look walk into
any new plant
whether it's in the auto sector or large
consumer appliances which are man
manufacturing
large consumer implies we are seeing an
increased wave of
iiot or industrial 4.0 broadly as it is
called
and increased attention to enterprise
workloads moving to the cloud
and end user computing moving to the
edge right
because of this workflow so when you com
when you combine these two things off
all that is moving to the edge yeah
maybe beyond the enterprise network
and all the mission critical workloads
that is moving to the cloud
it creates a completely new threat
landscape
and creates a completely new demand for
security services and products and i
don't need to repeat this
there is also a wave of consumer demand
right whether it is because of
contactless payments consumers have
adopted contact contactless payments
across the world in india you all of us
are familiar
whether it's because of upi and all the
new instrument contactless has
become so big the entire qr code based
payment i mean the kind of momentum that
has happened in one year
i'm sure you will agree there is a lot
of demand because of that for
both data protection and for cyber
security we are also seeing
uh several use of sectors whether it's
health and fitness
education and of course entertainment
how much
every indian is consuming content online
whether it's content in the area of
entertainment movies tv shows
because of which we see this then there
is an
entire thing of talent pool there is a
huge shortage there are enough and more
reports i don't want to do
scare mongering on that in terms of the
talent pool
uh demand supply gaps across
various vertical specialists application
security people infrastructure security
people uh cloud security right there's
all of this demanding
and another important thing to remember
is
by 2025 75 of
the workforce will be the millennials
now the biggest challenge is every
millennial has an option of where they
want to go
right there is so much that is happening
on the digital side there is so much
that is happening on the health care
side
how do you attract and motivate
a young engineer an angle or law
professional or an
management graduate young researcher
into the cyber security demand
because in india we have seen that when
you look at the engineering workforce
that comes out 70 80 percent of them are
going into the regular ito digital
very few are getting drawn into cyber
so i will say that even efforts that
need to be made to evangelize cyber
security as
a nice career to adopt whether it's in
young women or young men coming out of
colleges
is not a trivial problem that the
country has to solve
every country has to solve i think we
have a bigger problem because
we have a bigger demand supply short gap
because
we are hiring security professionals not
just for india
we are hiring security professionals for
this i.t services and product industry
which is servicing almost 80 to 90
countries
because of the way our services industry
is similarly we are seeing
that in india particularly bfsi itits
are some of the largest verticals but in
future
i think travel hospitality uh
even you know healthcare might have to
adopt a lot
another thing that we are seeing in the
breaches when you look at any of the new
breaches
we've had some reporting of some
breaches in the financial services or
payment industry
or globally in the healthcare industry i
think
sensitive and personally identified
information
and their breaches is creating a lot of
you know impact for the enterprise not
because of
uh the downtime to the business and the
loss of business but also because of the
regulations that have come up where any
data breach
is heavily fined eu gdpr has set that
example
even in india we have seen reserve bank
of india
imposing fines on some banks where a
breach has happened and a breach was not
reported
right so similarly we are seeing in
terms of
cloud right when um
some workload moves into the cloud it
has not been architected for the cloud
it has not been tested for the cloud
some misconfigurations or the
application
not designed for the cloud creating some
potential breaches
and similarly we see that business cost
there is a lot of business cost and
business cost could be because of
consumer trust
or regulators attention or sometimes it
is also in terms of the fines
in terms of the indian cyber security
landscape i'm just giving you a little
bit and then i'll
drill down a little more on what is the
kind of innovation ecosystem that is
happening
right uh we believe that uh
in terms of the india market india
domestic market
we believe that it will be almost 3
billion by 2022.
the two verticals that are going is
obviously the product ecosystem
which i already told you move to 1
billion in 2020
and services and when i say services it
is not just services
companies which are servicing india
market but it is also companies which
are servicing
the global markets right so it's almost
uh
5.2 billion and it is expected to most
importantly
they're one of the largest hires of
cyber security talent
some of the key products that are in
demand in large enterprises worldwide
and large enterprises in india are
around i already talked about whether it
is in identity access management and
point detection
and response zero trust network
architecture
uh particularly zero trust network
architecture for
applications for networks for workloads
right for users all of that has taken a
lot of
momentum in the last one year postponed
and the entire itu and ot security and
user entity
why this is important for you is that
i think the future demand will not be
for generalists that you can do
network security or you can do
application security i think the future
demand for roles will be
a little more specialized so that as you
complete your engineering as you
complete your m tech
and you are looking at a career in cyber
security it's extremely important you
look at
what is the technology trends and
adoption and future adoption that is
going to drive
so that you build that area of
specialization from that perspective i
wanted to highlight this point for this
audience which has a lot of students
so in terms of the innovation ecosystem
globally we see this we are beginning to
see this a lot in india
with the kind of product companies that
have come into the
market and the number of startups that
have come into the market
is i think the security operations
centers
i mean i think now a large enterprise
having a security operation
center is almost like a hygiene factor
it's similar to the way you know three
years back or ten years back everybody
had a data center
right i don't think there was any
enterprise id which did not have a data
center
right similarly now every large
enterprise has a security operation
center
but now they're getting augmented
through a lot of new general solutions
whether it is this entire security
orchestration and
the soar technologies that are coming up
similarly we are beginning to see
a lot of cyber fusion centers and cyber
different centers that are coming up and
what is interesting is
several of our industry members run
these centers
out of india for their global customers
they're servicing the global customers
out of india
and some of these centers are there
either in hyderabad or in chennai or in
bangalore or any one of these cities
right for the entire threat hunting and
the threat intelligence team
similarly there's a lot around ai and ml
all of us are familiar with this but
increasingly we are seeing a lot of aiml
integration
for uh the user entity behavior
analytics this is a new area that is
coming up to see
particularly to see what is the
behavioral patterns
to be able to identify insider risk
right and sometimes this insider risk
would be just
uh not a properly trained
employee or it could be a motivated uh
employee trying to create a breach right
so that we are seeing a lot of that
similarly in the area of you know the
entire
end point detection and response and
machine
learning that is getting integrated into
a lot of the stack
for predictive analytics similarly if
you see
i talked about it in uh even five ten
minutes back
about how cyber security services
delivery model
is moving from on-site to online
previously cyber security professionals
if an enterprise had a sock
there were those 40 50 of them running
that sock in various shifts 24x7
whereas now socks are being set up and
they're being
managed virtually remotely from using
online
right so we are beginning to see not
only security products
being delivered on the cloud and
consumed from the cloud
we are being we are seeing a lot of
services that are moving to the cloud
whenever we talk to
the cyber security pro practice of all
our industry members in india
this is the biggest trend that we are
seeing similarly we see
a lot given the way the pandemic has
panned out
and probably going to extend for some
more time we are beginning to see a lot
of focus around
remote working uh solutions work from
home solutions
and security around that and and around
the mobile device management we actually
brought
out a report on all the work from home
solutions you can look it up on our
website the national coe team brought
out on that
and the amount of innovation that is
happening on
remote working solutions because people
are working from anywhere from home
you can even work from your garden right
so there is a lot of innovation that is
happening both from the global companies
and the indian startups
particularly how can you look at secure
access
and the entire focus around devices
moving to the edge
similarly i think there's a lot of focus
i hope academia will
give lot more attention to this as
they're building their curriculum and
their faculty
development so that every young student
can be taught around this in terms of
the architecture practices of you know
security by design
how do you it has taken every iit
industry member a long time to even move
to devops
right how do you move to the devsec ops
so that security shifts left
and you start looking at it from from
right from upfront
when you're thinking of a product of a
service rather than you build a product
and then you test it
and then you realize there are these
vulnerabilities let me go fix them
i think that's not going to work anymore
because the go-to-market timelines of a
product development
even if it is developed by academy or
industry keeps
is coming down everybody wants to be
able to take the product to the market
and the shortest time cycle for which
i think security by design is extremely
important also privacy by design but
since this is a security
you know conference i'm focusing on that
similarly i think increasingly there's a
focus on
open standards and open architecture
because when you
are building when when a startup or a
researcher is building a product
i don't think that product is going to
be consumed in isolation by a business
the product typically needs to integrate
into
the enterprise securities track deployed
by that enterprise
or that business or a bank or a telecom
right it's not like they're going to
develop a consumer product if i run a
startup and
process from the academia that my
startup product
and the academia solution is going to be
consumed in isolation it's going to be
consumed
along with the rest of the enterprise
security stack
that that business has um
you know deployed to run their digital
infrastructure
to be able to do that it's extremely
important that
new products are built using open
standards and open architecture
and how do you go ahead and integrate
with the cloud platforms integrate with
the
you know security incident management
platforms they would have already
deployed
this is extremely important and there's
a lot of focus around
zero trust network architecture it's no
longer a buzzword
almost every cso is talking about it
every cso has
either already started evaluating or
already started deploying
or definitely i think 2021 calendar year
is a priority for them
particularly zero trust in terms of user
access network
and devices i think these are the things
going forward
zero trust for applications and
workloads also
should be happening okay so in terms of
uh if you do a scan of the innovation
ecosystem that is happening in india
i talked about those 175 or 180 startups
that are building not not all of them
are early stage some of them are already
five years and 10 years old
who are building products out of india i
think we
see they're all getting you know
clustered into these five domains
identity access management there's a lot
of focus because every enterprise
every large government department is
giving a lot of focus on that
yeah and data security because of
all the regulations around privacy that
are coming up
and threatened vulnerability management
and broadly around email security
self-healing self-feeling of network
self-feeling of
application security vulnerabilities
cryptography is gaining a lot of
attention while
of course cryptography has you know very
severe uh
you know has niche use cases
compared to others but there is lot we
are beginning to see
a lot of it is happening in academia and
public sector research labs and a few
select startups are also working on that
and broadly around
how do you secure your remote access
because
every large company whom you're talking
to at least in the iit industry and
in telecom and others i think while the
work from home at scale
might get reduced as the pandemic
you know problem is completely solved
right
at some point of time i don't know when
that will happen
but i think given the learnings and
experience
from the last one years operations and
its success and its past organization
its ability to attract talent from
remote
locations i think there will be an
increased
work from home kind of a next scenario
maybe a part of your workforce will work
from offices and part of your workforce
will work from that
because of which all these solutions
around
whether it is a cloud access security
whether it is in terms of
how do you make sure that when you are
on boarding a device
right when an employee's laptop is
onboarded onto the network
there was no challenge because a laptop
used to come to office
that it was an office given laptop it
was a certain way in which the laptop
was configured or locked down
so it was all taken care of whereas now
a device is getting onboarded onto an
enterprise network
to do whatever the other employee is
supposed to do
from home and some home devices may also
be getting onto the network
so how do you onboard devices in a
secure way and what all we need to do
similarly there's a lot around the
perimeter
and defining the perimeter and can
blockchain and you know distributed
ledger technologies be used for that
so we are seeing a lot of innovation in
the product ecosystem globally and in
india
around the secure remote taxes you will
see a totally new leak of products
and of course in threatened
vulnerability management
there's a lot of focus but if we are
beginning to see
a lot of focus now in terms of deception
in terms of threat hunting and in terms
of data security one
area that you will see i would urge all
of you all to look at
i think security as an area for
innovation and product development is
now known is known
in academia is not an industry but
privacy as an opportunity area for
technology development
is still not picked up so much in india
there are a few startups who are
working on technology solutions for
privacy uh there is a
you know privacy technology landscape
report that iapp
brings up you should look at what are
the technology innovation areas in
privacy the number of new companies that
have come up in that
because you're beginning to see a lot of
focus around that not because of just
regulator
but the consumer attention to privacy
preservation
uh regulators this thing even the
enterprise is trying to say that
they they're giving enough attention to
privacy
in terms of whether it is in the area of
rights management in the area of
using encryption technologies so that
there can be enough privacy preservation
when you're
you know doing something on the wire so
we are beginning to these five this
and lenny will leave the slides you can
look at it right
so similarly in terms of technology
innovation
uh some trends that we are seeing is
typically in cyber security in the past
there's product development there's some
research in academia
and government is doing something else
they used to work in isolation
whereas across various countries now
and in india we are beginning to see
this there is
a little more harmonized there's still a
lot more to be done
little more harmonizing that is
happening where
industry is beginning to collaborate
with academy or academia is trying to
collaborate with startups
several academic institutions have
incubated security startups
whether it's in the iit's whether it's
in amrita
or even in the a lot of the new private
universities
so academic collaboration we still need
to do more
that means and professor was
done a fundamental research probably as
an ip
he's now saying can i work with this
startup in my incubator or in some other
incubator we're beginning to see that
is there enough of that happening i
would still say a lot more needs to
happen
another interesting area we have seen in
india in the last two
three years is large user enterprises
particularly banks and maybe
some telecom companies who are
partnering with a security startup
for co-creation of a product this is a
very interesting trend we are seeing
where
the uh use cases
and the requirement of a new white space
on which you can innovate
is coming from a user organization and
they are not saying now i am going to
develop it in house because it is not
the job of a large bank or a telecom to
build a product
security product in house they are
saying this is my use case
inviting 10 15 startups trying to match
their competencies with the use case
taking a couple of two startups asking
them to work out of their office and
even giving them some funding sometimes
we need to see more of this happen and
i'm sure there will be more such
co-creation opportunities
another interesting thing we are seeing
in security product innovation in india
is
large system integrators you know the
large
services companies out of india globally
we have seen that whether it's ibm
accenture we are seeing that in india
now infrastructure
tcs all tech mahindra these kind of
companies
trying to partner wanting to partner
with startups
not just by investment and funding but
build a product and jointly go to the
market and take that startups product to
the global markets we're beginning to
see this
and of course several government bodies
like cdac and others do collaborate
and there is also an effort to be able
to do a technology transport
so why am i i'm trying to give this
landscape is that
we are moving in the right direction to
be able to
improve the innovation ecosystem out of
india so that
academia government large industry
players
and the small startups can collaborate
so that we can see more products out of
india
and in terms of technology adoption if i
look at those 180 product companies
what kind of security products they're
building many of them
are built for the cloud about 10 of them
are leveraging blockchain for example
the quantum and post quantum crypto
startups are very few
handful of them three percent of them
and yeah
ml of course almost everybody is using
them
and moving from signature based to
rule-based engines is another trend that
we are seeing
so broadly uh to be able to summarize
where we are seeing
adoption of emerging technologies for
cyber security product development
we are seeing aiml which is almost
you know the foundation in majority of
the products more than 75-80 percent of
the products
rpa is another thing remote robotic
process automation
and we are beginning to see rpa in a lot
of the
you know the threat mitigation
technologies or in terms of data
protection
blockchain and distribution ledger is
some new use cases we are beginning to
see interesting use cases
we have seen blockchain and all of that
in e-governance applications and
financial
fintech applications but we are
beginning to see them in other areas now
and increasingly we will see a lot
around
this things moving to the edge and the
software defined parameter
broadly and cloud of course uh there's
so many new startups in india which are
working around
various solutions around cloud security
i mean some of them is focusing around
infrastructure side some of them are
focusing around application side
okay and if you want to look at what
would be the future
i think emerging technologies whether
it's aiml
robotic process automation or blockchain
increasingly being
leveraged for new innovation in cyber
we believe that all the discussions and
deliberations
and evangelization of zero trust has
happened and now this year will pick up
the
way for adoption banking sector is
talking a lot about it itits and telecom
and its only a question of time and
because of the work from home
environment
there is no way a cio or a cso cannot
focus on this
and uh several companies are saying that
we are going to move towards the
borderless workforce
so many large it members are saying they
will now
have talent hired from tier 2 tier 3
locations and not disturb them to come
to a bangalore or a mumbai because of
which i think this entire focus around
uh the edge computing and in terms of
how do you look at securing devices and
users and
you know this is an architecture
paradigm that needs to change in the way
in which
you manage users and devices we're
beginning to see that
and uh i think there'll be a lot of
focus around
from government also how can we leverage
ai
while i think in the first two years
three years the focus of government has
been
harnessing ai for social good in the
area of
uh healthcare or agri-tech now we are
beginning to see a lot of focus around
domains like cyber
okay in terms of talent pool there's a
huge shortage i will not
really elaborate on this nascom and dhci
is focused on a lot we have a concept of
a sector skills council and a future
skills platform
we partner with government and academic
institutions
we've built a lot of job roles we'll be
increasing
government is doing a lot of training
programs for
government officers and for csos
similarly
we believe in the future where there
would be
lot more interest our current assessment
please understand this assessment
changes
i think uh even in the
you know the peak time of the pandemic
between august to october when we did an
analysis
in india there were 63 000 published job
roles in cyber
between industry members right there may
be some job roles which are not
published because
they're moving people in-house but the
published external job roles
were 63 000 and those job roles are
spanning each of this whether it is
in terms of foreign states whether it's
independent penetration testing or pen
testing
iot security is a new one cloud security
these are some of the job roles that we
are seeing and
advanced you know coding skills whether
and in the areas of architecture
where you're building solutions which
are cloud native
i think some of these will be some of
the
this is based on a survey that we have
done with our security product companies
they're saying that they're looking at
more people who understand device
drivers who understand
you know the hardware design
capabilities proficiency in cloud
security that means
whether it's aws is your google cloud
because the products are being developed
for deployment on the cloud
these are some of the skills that are
looking other than your basic software
engineering and coding skills
i think that's a hygiene factor in
addition what are you looking at
so broadly this is what i wanted to
focus on in terms of where we are headed
and i'm happy to take any questions my
only i mean in closing i would like to
say
that any new security product
innovation research in academy or
industry
and talent development efforts that
happen in academia
should be in line with where technology
trends
are headed both in the overall digital
and in cyber security
over time thank you so much ma'am wow
you really
made this a very immersive uh experience
going through each of your slides and
giving us a full overview this is the
a talk that actually we needed to have
perhaps in the first day to just get an
understanding of
uh you know where india is headed and
there are several questions
um so let's just i'll just quickly go
over it in fact
i wanted to you know assign an hour for
you
initially and then we cut it down to 45
minutes which was i think not a good
idea
so i think the first question is ai and
machine learning are considered a
double-edged sword
so means you can use it to enable or
disable security and
do you see any challenges in terms of
really um
attacking ai and machine learning do you
see any challenges
in terms of attacking ansible so i guess
really
the the it's it's still a very much gray
area and you know how do you see this
evolve ai and
now yeah i mean i do understand that
particularly when it comes to cyber
security attacks
aiml is being leveraged as much as it is
being
you know leveraged by the providers that
is a challenge i think every technology
has the dark side of technology as you
call it
we've seen that in nuclear we have seen
that in biomedical we have seen that
everywhere
so ai has a lot of potential but
unfortunately ai is also
there has been an ethic side of ai and
there is also a way where
ai and ml is being leveraged to
you know kick or launch
big scale attacks in cyber so that cyber
crime
side and the vested interest of the
cyber criminals from
all kinds of actors from you know
fun loving hackers to state actors they
go all that spectrum yeah aiml is
there is a dark side of every technology
and i think it's a question of time but
that doesn't mean that we will know the
providers whether it's the products and
services will not be using it
every product i've talked about that 80
of startups in india use aiml for
whether it's in threat hunting
you know whether it's in self-feeling so
many of those technologies
there is a challenge uh several cyber
criminals
do use aml maybe sometimes more
effectively
than what we in the profession do that's
a challenge i think
it's a question of time we've had those
challenges even in nuclear right over a
period of time there will be some
governance around that
hopefully and you know the next question
is like
how do you think data protection should
be enforced when you have multiple
systems of varying device capabilities
interconnected
so device capabilities you know probably
challenging data protection policies how
do you really cope up with this
kind of scenario i don't think
devices i mean maybe i don't get the
question i don't think the device
capabilities are
challenging i think the entire data
protection first of all comes from a
point of view of
how much of user awareness we are
building right there's
in india there's a lot of user awareness
that needs to be done
second we definitely need regulation
unfortunately in security and privacy
regulation drives
enterprise behavior or business behavior
right so you know how you
gdpr got that compliance mindset
so the regulation needs to come in
hopefully the india personal data
correction bill will come in
but even while that act has not yet come
once privacy was declared as a
fundamental right
at least several responsible businesses
are giving it
due attention because they need to
ultimately
win and retain the trust of their
consumers
right so if there is an there's a user
enterprise
which is completely online delivering
services online
and every now and then if they keep
having the privacy breach
consumers are going to look at an
alternative enterprise which is doing a
better job of security and privacy
so i would believe that a combination of
user awareness
business drivers because the business
needs to protect
you know and retain the trust of its
consumers and
government and regulation and strong
enforcement
uh an independent entity which can
enforce it
will drive the thing yeah there is a
host of
heterogeneous devices operating systems
how do you get all of that i think those
problems will get solved as and when the
regulation and the enforcement mechanism
is something like gdpr
uh going to happen in india
not really gdpr we have an indian
personal data protection bill
which is a 2019 version it was tabled in
parliament but then it went into the
joint parliamentary committee i think
that's a very comprehensive regime
from whatever version we have seen and
the deliberations we've had with the jpc
what exactly is the version of the bill
that will get
tabled for enactment we have to see but
i think it will be a comprehensive
regime it cannot not be a comprehensive
regime because our data protection
regime first needs to meet
the global expectations because we work
with so many geographies
right of privacy and it also needs to
implement
privacy as a fundamental right and
you know make sure those guarantees and
remedies are provided for a common man
and a common citizen
i do believe that it will be a
comprehensive regime
one more last question i know there are
several more but i think we are running
out of time
um how realistic is zero trust
architecture while moving
traditional network environments like ot
to cloud
with remote access see it's
too technical a question for me but zero
see zero dress first of all i would like
to tell you zero trust network
architecture is not a product
it's not one product first of all zero
trust network architecture is a paradigm
that you need to understand
apply it to your enterprise what how
will you apply zero trust network
architecture
in a large online consumer b2c
e-commerce company versus zero trust
network architecture
in a bank in an oil and gas company
in a large itits company with remote
workforce is very different
so first you need to understand zero
trust network architecture is a new
paradigm
once you understand that you need to map
your architecture decisions and your
deployment decisions and your product
selection criteria
what products or what stack of products
you will select to implement zero trust
network
based on your enterprise digital
footprint
right if you're an enterprise completely
in one location in one building
versus your an enterprise which is
spread across the world
and you have people working from all
kinds of locations
or you're an oil and gas company which
has remote oil wells and remote
monitoring stations and all of that
what is zero trust and network
architecture is going to be different
and what kind of products you need to do
that
so i believe now at least most mature
cios and csos by the end of
2020 i believe at least have a good
understanding of zero trust network
it's not a single product you buy from a
vendor and you say now i am
ztna ready you need to understand how
will you apply
the concepts and paradigm of the dna to
your enterprise
which will be different based on what
your digital footprint is
and then go ahead and select the
necessary products
so anyway before we conclude i just
wanted to mention that even though
amrita has not been formally part of the
isea program we've done tremendous work
in reaching out to more than 20
000 students across 21 plus states
and training uh students in cyber
security in in really warming them up
uh and and upskilling them significantly
and
love to work with the sei more closely
on on creating a bigger impact and this
is all been done
um you know using our enthusiastic
faculty and students at our center so
with that i would really like to thank
you ma'am for your
time uh especially on a sunday uh and
really coming and sharing with us this
you know new perspective in fact you
were right when when we traveled
together
uh you know there were about 35 36
companies uh um you know focusing on
cyber security three four years ago
and it's very heartening to see how that
number has really grown so much
uh and you know and and india is reliant
on its own
indigenous products which was absolutely
not the case
five years ago for example so uh with
that again i thank you very much and i
hope to have you as a speaker more
in our forums uh i think you give a very
very good perspective and more
importantly you're one of our
uh really great models as well thank you
thank you professor krsnaji for having
me in closing i would say
if both academy and industry can partner
to attract more
women into the cyber security domain
both in academia and research and also
in our workforce because it's
broadly only 11 percent as of now yes
absolutely that is securities
that we actively try thank you for
having me thank you thank you