hey everyone
i'm going to share my screen
hi bamna hey
so let me give you a quick intro and
then i'll give it over to you sounds
good
okay so moving on to
uh next session try your hand at machine
learning for security
we have vanassam soman here she's a
security
senior security research lead working at
microsoft defender research team
in her day job she develops machine
learning models to classify malware in
real time
so in the past she worked in the field
of threat intelligence and loves to play
with natural language crossing
algorithms
she also holds a master's degree in
computer security from
georgia tech and is also a trainer for
uh
malware who was living with black
foreign it's really
awesome to have you here bangla so over
to you now
thank you so much for the wonderful
introduction namisha and uh
thank you to shakthikhan for inviting me
over uh i was actually very interested
in listening to the last presenter maher
nosh and i was
very like happy that she was talking
about another application of machine
learning insecurity
because that is the domain that i love
and i'm excited to share that with you
as well
all right so i think uh
you all should be able to see my screen
now
so i want to start by talking about how
i got here
um the previous presenter shared yet
another use case of machine learning and
its application and security and i think
i'm seeing that revolution happening
in more and more areas of uh information
security
and the fundamental reason that's
underlying this is that security
expertise is scarce and machine learning
is like a really simple and powerful
tool
to help defenders scale their resources
and you know accomplish their goals
whether it's protecting you know their
customers
or discovering better attacks etc
you know there is a parallel between
what is happening in um
the security machine learning space with
you know what happened a while back
uh with automation so for example like
about like five to ten years ago we saw
this uh you know
secops became a commonly used term
and you know uh it was more and more
accepted that
some amount of automation and coding
skills is really really useful for
security researchers to have so that
they can really magnify
and multiply their impact so i think
from there you know similar to that
we're seeing this movement
to ml cyclops where the knowledge of ml
uh and its applications and security is
becoming much more useful where you know
all security researchers and engineers
are kind of
touching aspects of ml and this type of
is kind of becomes another
tool in your in your arsenal if you will
so this is why i feel very uh
passionately about this subject and i'm
excited to be here today
my agenda for this talk is i'll begin by
giving like a
a a bird's eye view of the various
applications of
machine learning and ai insecurity that
i have seen
in the industry i talk about the common
building blocks of ml based solutions
that are used and then i talk about the
specific challenges of applying machine
learning to security
and then i'll conclude with a few
different examples of different types of
applications
of machine learning and security um
so the first uh so firstly i want to
talk about these
different categories in which you know i
see applications of machine learning and
security today this is not an exhaustive
list you know just some common areas
so um the most common
uh type of machine learning application
that you will see is
classification or supervised ml so in
this use case typically you have
a label data set and then you train a
classifier to identify
similar things so maybe you have a set
of files that are you know clean
some of them are labeled clean some of
them are labeled malware
and then you know you want to create a
classifier to distinguish between other
clean and narrower files
uh this type of machine learning is
commonly used for you know other
entities like files domains behaviors
etc
uh in the technical sense you will see a
lot of linear models applied here
like average perceptrons and also like
there are some deep learning models
applied here but
there is some there is a limitation
there in the sense that deep learning
models will usually
you know they will be heavier in terms
of the compute they require and the
training times etc so
that kind of limits their use a little
bit
and there are others as well uh so since
this is the most basic use case like
throughout my presentation today i will
use this example to illustrate
different uh different you know concepts
and challenges etc like the binary
classification of files
the second most commonly uh used use
case is unsupervised ml
so uh you know we saw this in the last
talk where the author was talking about
anomaly detection to detect
attacks against iot system so that's
that's an excellent example
of using unsupervised ml um in general
it is used in cases where you
you're trying to detect some kind of new
badness uh where you don't have a label
data set
um clustering is another example where
unsupervised ml is used for example if
you have
multiple behaviors entities files etc
that belong to a campaign
clustering techniques can be used to
kind of group them together and you know
maybe present them together to a
security analyst to look at
for instance um uh in in the previous
talk
the clustering methods that were
mentioned you know she specifically said
that hey this is one thing that does not
require
uh the cluster number to be mentioned so
that's like a class of methods that are
non-parametric
and that's really important because if
you don't have good labels you don't
have a good way of saying that
uh you know what the number of clusters
will be so uh
you know that's kind of the type of a
type of technique that's used commonly
now i move to some
uh of you know like more advanced use
cases um
for these uh types of applications you
don't sometimes you see them in product
but it's not very common you definitely
see them in academia and in industry
research labs
um so uh adversarial ml is a big one uh
there are several papers from academia
around
evading existing uh detection systems so
they will build ml models that
you know uh that are able to give an
output that will help
an attacker evade an existing system
like you know there have been papers
around like how to evade an av
engine using adversarial ml and the
converse of this domain
is robustness how can we build better ml
models that are
robust against such adversarial attacks
how can you protect against data
poisoning or
model inversion for instance
another domain is interpretability so
this is really critical because a lot of
times customers
don't directly trust the output of an ml
model
and they want to understand you know why
something was called suspicious or
malicious
so this uh this set of techniques helps
you reason over the outcomes and build
some kind of explainability
into the output of the ml model
and um another domain that i want to
talk about is reinforcement learning
so again this is very research oriented
and i haven't seen
applications in product but there there
is research around
hey how can we provide personalized
protection
using maybe the contextual band problem
or can we build an automated red team
system using reinforcement learning or
even an automated defense system
so these are some categories in which ml
is applied in security today
um i want to open with an example
of how and this is from my work where we
uh we built a classical ml model to
protect against an attack from the earth
sniff botnet
um so this was a small scale targeted
attack and like the graph kind of shows
you you know like over time
um the the prevalence of the files that
were associated with this campaign
uh it was targeted towards small
businesses and the attacker did
something
interesting where um they tailored the
name of the document
to the victim that they were sending it
to for example the dolan care statement
or doc it was a macro enabled document
that was sent
exclusively to victims in a specific
city in
missouri us uh where dolan care is
actually an elderly care assisted living
facility
so they were kind of disguising
themselves as a receipt or like an
invoice from this particular
company that's a real company in that
area and
obviously like the document itself you
know it uh wanted the
victim to enable the macros and then
once you do this obfuscated powershell
will get launched
which will connect to a domain and
download the payload which is uh the er
sniff.net
um and you know you can see that like
the different in the different cities
that they were present they used
different uh lures that were specific to
that city so for example in nebraska
they use dms which is a landscaping
company there
uh in missouri they use dolan care and
then in tennessee they use dockery which
is like a flooring company there so they
were customizing you know
this type of attack that they already
had
um so here's how uh machine learning
helped
in protecting in this specific case so
we had one set of models that were
running on the client like these are
very
lightweight linear models uh that don't
give a verdict but they kind of give
like a suspicious
or not suspicious verdict instead of
malicious or benign so if that model
says that uh the file is suspicious then
it sends like a
a larger section of metadata about the
file itself up to the cloud
and then the cloud will apply like a
series of models to it so the two
specific models that i want to talk
about
uh are the model that are specific to
macro files and the one for non-pe files
uh in this case both of these models
said with a higher degree of probability
that the files are malicious
and then the cloud you know sends a
verdict back to the client
and the file gets quarantined so now i
want to
deep dive into uh the features and kind
of understand
how this model is able to decide that
this file is malicious
this model used three broad categories
of features
expert features fuzzy hash based
features and contextual data
so expert features you can think of them
basically as researcher signatures but
low fidelity researcher signatures so
any one of these signatures
will not really say that a file is
malicious or not but it definitely says
that you know the file is malicious
sorry suspicious so an example of that
is
um maybe like the file has a certain
you know import function or maybe it is
work it is changing a certain registry
key
uh and you can see that through the
strings so that is an expert feature and
you know
it might not always hold true that a
file that is touching that particular
registry key is malicious
but it becomes a signal to the
classifier and says that okay
i need to kind of think more about this
file so those are the expert features
and then the second type of features is
the fuzzy hash features
which is basically you know the rolling
hash of the content of the file itself
and then the third type of features is
the contextual data
and so these features are um
you know where was the file coming from
you know which folder did the file land
into what is the name of the file is it
similar to other legitimate names and
what's the distance between all of that
so those are some of the contextual
features
now you can see here that um the expert
and the fuzzy hash features really
contributed highly to saying that the
file is malicious
whereas the contextual data was not able
to uh
make that much contribution in the
malicious verdict and that makes sense
because we saw earlier that the
attackers
were modifying each file to kind of make
it look kind of real
so therefore the contextual features in
this particular case were not powerful
but as you can see that that's the power
of the machine learning model you know
since it is considering
all of these signals together uh it's
you're still able to detect the file as
malicious
so now i'm going to talk about the
building blocks of
a machine learning algorithm so these
are like the basics that you need to
cover if you want to build a machine
learning algorithm
the first thing that you need is data
and then we'll talk about
various features that can be leveraged
uh
we'll talk about how to fit a function
and what that really means
and then evaluating the efficacy of your
model
so let's talk about getting the data
the most common type of data set that
most people start out with when they are
you know
getting introduced to machine learning
is the toy data sets
these are usually packaged alongside you
know python packages or
um data libraries um so an iris data set
is a there is a really good example you
know
so especially when you read blogs about
different machine learning algorithms
these are the data sets that most of
them will be leveraging
now for our security use case there are
some really good
open source data sets available so if
you want to try your hand at machine
learning for security
these data sets are they have been
released by companies they
uh mimic the real world and in that
sense are very useful for
building realistic uh conclusions
realistic algorithms
uh for security so the first one here is
the ember data set which was released a
few
years ago by end game it has about
a million files and when it was released
it was the most comprehensive
malware file dataset
the second data set is much newer it was
only released i think
uh in december last year or january this
year
uh so force and reversing labs came
together to release
a larger data set which has about 20
million files
and it also has some amount of
behavioral information so it's uh it's
pretty comprehensive and a lot of
research teams have now moved to
experimenting with this data set
um microsoft also uh released a data set
a while back on kaggle
in there as part of their malware
classification challenge but at this
point that dataset is a bit outdated
and then obviously there is you know
real data which is hard to get
but um short of getting actual product
telemetry virustotal is a really good
real world data set that has been useful
in experiments in my experience
um through the api you can get
large-scale data
it is a bit biased towards malware
versus clean
so that is something you'll have to
account for but in general it's uh
it's kind of like a good really source
of data
and then the last one obviously is
product telemetry so
this is this is not usually shared uh
with outside audiences because of
restrictions around privacy and
compliance
but the most realistic assessments and
practical applications come by
experimenting on this data
cool now we're going to talk about
feature extraction
and i'm going to solicit some audience
participation
so i know that this is you know we
started doing conferences
virtually and but i still want to enable
audience participation
so um i want to ask
all of you to go to mentee.com and enter
this code and then i'll ask you some
questions and then
you know we'll make some word clouds
with the answers that you give
i'm gonna uh stop sharing my screen for
a second
and
and go to mentee.com myself
okay so here um
what are some useful features that you
can use to classify malware files
so just uh go to that website enter that
code and then you'll be able to enter
outputs uh enter some words and you know
this will automatically generate
word clouds awesome yeah these are these
are all good answers
import functions pe headers
yep signer hash file extension really
good
awesome really cool
okay so
let the i'll go find it
nice yeah code spyware
i love this thank you all for
participating
yeah linkers
okay there are several several really
good answers here
i'll give it 10 more seconds and then
i'll move to the next next question
nice so yes it's really easy to come up
with all of these features to classify
malware files
let's try one more
what are some useful features to
classify the malware domains
let's think about a different set of
features if you have
if you want to classify domain names how
could you do it yeah tld is a good one
entropy excellent actually that's
relevant for both files and domains
um
[Music]
yeah length who is
domain name registration yep that's
really good
name servers
nice
n grams yeah that's a really good one
too organ for
okay i'll give this uh 10 seconds and
then i'll
go back to the deck
misspelled words also a good one
dig url yeah yeah
protocol http or https nice
okay excellent
i will go back to sharing
my deck but thank you for the
participation and thank you for the
answers that's exactly
uh what i was trying to get
hey well now so i'm reminding you
there's five more minutes
oh didn't i have one hour
oh sorry i said mine sorry my bed
okay good
all right so yeah we all had good
answers
but you know this is just an example of
like hey there are a lot of features
um that you can use uh for you know
malware classification or domain
classification and then some of you also
pointed out that you know you can use
you don't have to do manual feature
extraction there are machine learning
techniques that will do that for you
automatically
uh the downside of that is that you know
you lose out on some explainability
sometimes okay so let's talk about
um curve fitting so machine learning
uh you know sometimes it can appear a as
a daunting new domain but let me tell
you that it's just glorified comforting
and if you've ever done a class in
numerical analysis
or linear algebra then you have you know
you've done some curve fitting and
that's essentially what machine learning
is
at its very core so this is a really
simple simple example
of you know how you would build a linear
model so you have an
input that is the x uh the x variable
and then you have the output which is a
y variable
and you can see it plotted in the green
dots and that's in this toy graph
and then you can imagine that if you
wanted to plot a linear function
to fit the points then you you'd have to
define you know the parameters of this
line b0 and b1
uh and then you would use numerical
analysis techniques to find
these parameters such that the error is
minimized
so that you know the distance between
the points and the line itself because
that is minimized so that is kind of you
know
essentially like this is how you would
fit like a linear regression model
um obviously like practical machine
learning is a bit more complicated so i
want to talk about
just two different types of functions
you know that would be used more
commonly
so the sigmoid function is you know very
commonly used specifically for binary
classification problems
uh like the kind that i usually work on
uh which is
um the reason that it's used is it's
easily differentiable
and also that it gives an output that is
zero or one so you know the binary
problem
uh is helped there and then the second
one i talk about
is the value function which also has a
similar effect as a sigmoid function in
the sense that it's binary
but also the computation here becomes
much more efficient
so when you have a neural network which
has multiple uh multiple nodes and you
have to do similar like computations for
or fitting at each and every node then
the value function
which optimizes or makes the computation
more efficient it becomes
much much more lighter and makes the
training of the model much faster
awesome so the next thing i want to talk
about is evaluation
evaluation is like really tricky
compared for
the security use cases compared to you
know usual machine learning use cases
the first question you want to think
about is where is your ground truth
uh and this kind of relates to the
challenge of getting
labeled data good label data in security
usually you will
you know you'll have noise labels um you
have to decide
how you're going to get it is it going
to be through graders or is it going to
be through
you know some kind of data sets that i
talked about so that's
a question that you have to answer and
then the next
aspect to consider is that your data set
will usually be very unbalanced
um in the sense that um
so for example you know if you're
building a file classifier and you have
10 000 files in your organization
99 99 of those will be clean
uh only one percent of those will be
malware so how are you going to build a
classifier so that it is able to know
that most of the files are clean but
also get enough signal
uh so that you know it's able to say
that okay some files are malware so that
it can identify the malicious signal
and this unbalanced problem also affects
the metrics that you can use
so for example if you just use accuracy
for this type of a
problem then you know because 99 out of
100 files are already
cleaned so if you have a naive
classifier that just says everything is
clean
it would already have 99 accuracy and
obviously this classifier is totally
useless because it's not going to find
any malware
so which is why we use things like
precision recall and fp rate
um so let me tell you what precision
means simply
if your precision is say 0.7 then it
means that for every 100 files that your
classifier says
is malware only 70 of them
are actually nowhere
then recall you know it can be defined
like this so for every 100 files that
are malware that are seen by your
classifier
so if your recall is 0.7 it means that
only 70
of those files will actually be
identified by your classifier and the
remaining
30 will be you know there will be misses
and your classifier will not detect them
um another important metric that you
want to look at is the false positive
rate
um so for example if your false positive
rate is 0.3
that means that for every 100 files that
your you know classifier says
our malware 30 of them are actually not
malware
so this is a very critical metric for
machine learning
uh applications that are deployed in
production because
organizations can be very sensitive
because every time you have a false
positive say you block a file as malware
and it wasn't you know
someone you know they downloaded a file
and they can't use it or there was a
business critical application that
they're not going to be able to use
anymore
so that is considered very very
disruptive
um also we also use like f1 score and
the pr curve can be used to plot
performance characteristics and
determine the probability threshold
all right now i'm going to talk about uh
some of the major challenges that we see
in um applications of mln security
so the first one is labels um the lack
of or the noise in
these uh the scale of the data and the
features themselves
uh measuring actual customer outcomes is
also very tricky
uh i'll talk more about all these
including you know the changing
landscape in the malware as well as
the clean files adversarial evasion um
and then false positives you know which
i mentioned just now where
those are like sometimes a bigger
problem than false negatives for
customers
and then finally interpretability so
let's start with labels um
this is built from uh microsoft
defenders telemetry so
96 of the malware uh that we had on our
systems was
seen only once and never again so that's
a huge huge percentage of files that are
just
seen only once in your system so it's
really hard to get good labels in this
type of environment
so you can see that only three percent
are seen two to ten times
and only point zero one are seen on uh
you know more than a thousand files and
only a small percentage you know you can
get good labels from
from external data sources even so
obviously if you want to train a machine
learning classifier how are you going to
give it
adequate exposure to the diversity of
malware features while at the same time
you know keeping your labels uh less
noisy and accurate
this is a huge challenge for you know
across
the classification or supervised ml
domain in security
the second challenge is um scale
so in uh for microsoft defender for
instance you know when we are looking
only at file encounters on the client
side across the environment we have
millions of files that are seen every
day
so at that stage the model has to be
extremely lightweight and it has to be
able to
you have a small memory footprint so
that you know it is not taking away
memory from the client it has to have a
small compute footprint so that it's not
taking away processing power from the
client itself
and then the inference time has to be
very fast because
you know if if someone is using their
computer and they're you know waiting
for like
two or three minutes to let to open
their file while the av is checking it
or something they're not going to like
that experience
so it has to like uh reply within
milliseconds
and the same holds true for any
real-time model you know even whether
it's at the client of the cloud you have
to
give your inference time is very very
short for it to
give a good customer experience um and
then you know we have
we can have like heavier models but
usually we use them
you know in a slightly offline setting
where for example
you know if a file is suspicious enough
we'll you know collect the sample
detonate it run a deep neural network on
it and then you know send a verdict back
um but usually that takes you know
minutes uh or
sometimes even longer so those models so
that's kind of like how you want to
think about the problem of scale at
different stages
of this defense and depth kind of
pipeline
um i want to talk a little bit about
measuring actual customer outcomes
so now let's say that you have built a
model and then you've deployed it to the
customer and now it's looking at all
these new files and it's giving verdicts
out on that
how are you going to determine uh how
it's doing because you know you might
not
see some of these files ever again you
may not get access to any of these files
because you know they're the customer's
private property
so uh one way to do it is uh you know
manual grading so
in this case obviously you have access
to a certain set of files
and you you know manually have some
researchers look at and say that okay
this verdict was right this was wrong
etc
um another way is to then automatically
extrapolate from that you know manual
grading so for example maybe you grade
instances and then you know you can say
that okay these 50 are similar to these
10 instances so i'll consider
you know applying these grades to this
extended data set
and then you know customer submissions
is always a good option where you know
the customer will say
hey you know this is an fp that you know
you've detected wrongly or this is an fm
that you didn't detect
but obviously if you get to that point
it's leading to a bad experience for the
client
um the changing landscape is very
interesting
in security we're often you know we
often talk about how the malware
landscape is changing so fast and you
know we have to adapt that quickly
but one thing that we don't think about
is like the temporal drifting clean
features
and through our experiments we've
noticed that the temporal drift in clean
features is
actually more than you see in malware
features which causes um
so if a model is allowed to stay stale
for too long
then it will keep having a higher and
higher false positive rate because it's
not able to
judge the new clean features that are
coming in and that totally makes sense
because you know in this world there are
probably more
clean software developers than there are
malware developers
so that's another interesting thing to
keep in mind
so interpretability is a big one uh
usually
people will not trust the output a
machine learning model
if uh you know a supervisor unsupervised
model says that hey
something is bad they'll be like okay
how bad is it
uh is it like ransomware bad so i should
unplug my computer or
is it just like a browser pop-up so that
you know i just i can ignore it for a
few more days and
do something more important and then you
know they kind of want context around
okay what attacker is this associated to
what should i do what's the next thing
that i would expect this
type of attack uh to go so all of these
things can be
uh addressed using interpretive
interpretability methods from machine
learning
um adversarial evasion is something i
touched on earlier
and this is a huge challenge as well now
that more and more
uh applications of machine learning and
security are you know prevalent
uh the attackers are catching up and
they are exploring ml based methods
to evade these models and these
detectors but obviously there are like
the traditional methods as well you know
like more sophisticated packing or
obfuscation
so now that we've covered the challenges
of applying machine learning and
security
i want to share some examples with you
and go into the depths of how we
do some of these things so i showed this
um
example to you earlier where we this
classical linear
model was used to um block the earth's
import net
so um here's how you know the process of
building this model goes
the first step is selecting samples uh
we have millions of samples uh we want
to select like a small subset of known
clean and malware files
and then you want to fine-tune the ratio
of clean and malware
to ensure that you know the model should
understand that
most of the universe will be clean but
also has enough malware signal
to you know discriminate between
malicious and clean files
we might also want to target sometimes
specific file types you know like we had
that macro specific model for instance
then the next thing is feature selection
so you all had excellent ideas on you
know how feature selection can work
uh in general you know features can be
related to any of the machines
attributes
dynamic or contextual attributes of the
files static features of the file
and how we do it is that we extract
millions of features
uh you know for a set of data but then
we have to do feature selection or some
kind of reduction because
at that high dimensionality the
computation
for the training of the model will not
be feasible in a reasonable amount of
time
so we kind of do some meta-analysis to
say which features are more important
which features have more discriminative
power and then we
downsize to just those and then
you know we do the kind of
experimentation hyper parameter tuning
that is
a part of every machine learning model
you try out different models you try out
different ratios and then the one thing
that we have to do again is
tuning the probability threshold because
we know that customers are really
sensitive to false positive rates
and um we have to maintain or we have to
tune the operational characteristics of
the classifier such that
the false positive rate will remain low
and then you know first we ship it in
this quote-unquote experimental mode
where
it will kind of be looking at the
traffic uh but not
giving blocking verdicts and this is
when we kind of evaluate
uh the actual outcomes that the
classifier is able to provide on new
unseen traffic
and then if it is performing up to part
then it will be turned
to a blocking mode classifier
the second example i want to give is how
we use ensembl models for malware
classification
this was this was work done by my
colleagues jubil harley and randy
the idea of ensemble learning is that uh
to build a prediction model
instead of just using you know a set of
classifiers we can
bring these uh classifiers together you
know we use a set of simple base
classifiers and then we bring them
together
uh to this stacked approach so that the
machine learning
one machine learning model can decide
you know based on these signals which
are more accurate which are less
accurate and then give a final verdict
um this is how the architecture of a
an ensemble classifier could look like
so maybe you have a set of base
classifiers you know for example there
was a macro classifier there might be
one that's focused on behaviors
one focused on contextual features and
you have all these base classifiers
um that give their own prediction
in our case you know we were using their
prediction in terms of the probability
of
something being malware and then you
feed these predictions
as the data set into a new classifier
which then you know uh gives the final
verdict
there are several benefits to using an
ensemble model the first of which is
that
it filters out noisy signals
automatically from any
underperforming model so if one or two
models within that
set of base classifiers is noisy then uh
the stacked classifier will be able to
smooth out that noise
um and the second thing that's very
interesting that's an interesting side
effect is that it increases the
predictive power but also adds some
explainability so
for example if i have a stacked
classifier that has a number of base
classifiers
maybe one of them is for contextual
features maybe one of them is for
you know fuzzy hash based features so
then you know after i get the output
from the stack classifier i can easily
say
that okay this file was malicious but it
was malicious because
of you know it was in a suspicious
context or because the fuzzy hash was
looking bad and it was similar to bad
things whereas if i had
you know combined all of these features
directly into one classifier that
interpretability becomes a bit more
complicated
and then it adds resilience against
attacks and individual models so we
talked about
uh adversarial machine learning and you
know how attackers are exploring that
ensemble models because it's a
combination of multiple models it
adds some resilience as well
i'll give one more example and this is
very different from
the stuff that we've discussed so far
which is
an application of natural language
processing for threat intelligence
um so i want to introduce the concept of
named energy extraction here
so this is a blob of text and you know
if i feed this
into like a named extractor from azure
or google
um it can extract like entities like
this
which uh would be say you know sansa
stark is a person
eddard struck as a person winterfell is
you know an organization or a
geopolitical entity
so this is what named energy extraction
looks like you feed in a blog of text
and then you know it automatically
extracts the significant
entities that are present in that text
now if we look
at um a machine uh sorry a security
related text you know this is a
an apt white paper about a china based
actor
uh what happens here is that
the entities that i would like to
extract from this are you know
the names or the aliases of the actor
and the techniques that it's in the
mighty techniques that it's using
but obviously uh you know the
off-the-shelf uh
named energy extractors since they are
not uh tuned
to the to the cyber security domain
they're not
able to do this type of stuff so this
kind of example
is about training a named entity
extractor
custom uh applicable to the cyber
security domain
and um the reason we did that is because
we want to generate these security
knowledge graph type of structures
so for example you know if i can run
like a named entity extraction model
and build relationships across documents
i can
automatically build like a security
knowledge graph so this graph in
particular
shows the overlap in microtechniques
used by imotete which is a commodity
malware family
with some apts and you know so this kind
of
work is something that threat
intelligence analysts do a lot
so building machine learning techniques
to create the security knowledge graph
automatically
is potentially a very powerful thing
um to construct the training data of
this data set
because we're now in the nlp domain it's
a totally different technique
instead of having like clean or malware
labels we have this labeling technique
called iob
or inside outside beginning and
so this is an example of how that would
work so eddard stark is
the phrase that indicates the name of a
person the first
token in that phrase will be b dash
person which stands for beginning of
person
and the second or all subsequent tokens
in that phrase will be tagged with eye
dash person which is
inside a person and all the uh tokens
that are
not in any of the you know phrases that
we care about or entities that we care
about will be tagged with o
which means outside
so uh here is an example of a sentence
from the cyber security domain about the
numbered panda actor
and here is how it would get uh you know
labeled
in the iob context so numbered panda
is the bad actor phrase and numbered is
the beginning of the bad actor phrase
and panda is the inside and bad active
phrase and all the subsequent tokens are
you know outside
etc
so uh again in the future extraction
space we have a different set of
features here
so we use some traditional nlp features
like you know part of speech lemma
word type etc and then we also have some
unsupervised features you know which is
word embeddings
um in very simple terms word embeddings
are
vector representations of words uh in
text such that their
meaning and semantic relationships are
captured by the numerical vectors
so for example if two words mean the
same thing or are used in the same
context a lot
the cosine similarity of their vectors
will be high
so this particular world meetings model
was trained using word to work on like a
corpus of ti data
so think security blogs apt white papers
incident response reports etc
and this is an example of how well the
word embeddings worked in this context
so this is the visualization of the
embeddings in tensorboard
um and since that embeddings were
trained uh on documents related to the
cyber domain
the clusters of points that are formed
here are related to the context in which
the words appear
so for instance the closest four points
to apd 28
two of them are its aliases and two of
them are other campaigns related to it
by attribution
this was the architecture of uh this
solution where
you know we had a corpus of blogs white
papers the text
we had some simple html and pdf parsers
we did some minimal text processing
just to clean out um and then we
extracted the word embeddings
we split it into a training and test
data set
we did the custom feature extraction
which i told you about like the
traditional nlp
features and then added the word
embedding features as well
and then we experimented with two
different models here crf
and lstm crf is
more like a linear model that is applied
to a sequence problem and lstm is a
special type of neural network
that is also applicable for sequence
problems they're both
very widely used specifically for
language models
um this is how we evaluated the model
uh we've measured the positive precision
and recall and here you can see that
the positive precision was pretty high
across the board for all of the models
but the recall you know the lstm was
kind of doing better in terms of the
recall
but then you know we looked at these
metrics on specifically uh
unseen tokens so these are the tokens
where um
these tokens were not present in the
training data set at all so these are
just net new tokens and we want to see
how the model does in terms of
identifying these
using the context in which they appear
so here you can see that
the crf for the embeddings it does it
performs uh the best
um and it was the only model that had
any manner of positive recall
so uh hopefully i've given you like a
diversity of like examples and kind of
piqued your interest
uh if you want to learn more uh
the basic machine learning course on
coursera by andrew eng it's really the
best
he is not only like a great visionary of
the field but also a really good teacher
um the malware data science book by
joshua saxey again a really good
resource
but very specific to the malware
classification problem
kgo is a data science platform where
various organizations provide data sets
and you know kind of
define a data science problem that they
want to solve and then everyone
can try their hand at solving the
problem optimize their solution
and then usually a lot of people will
also share their solutions so it's
a great place to learn uh about applying
ml
and the last thing is canvas which is
the conference on applied machine
learning for information security um
it's a relatively new conference
um the the last edition was in 2019
they didn't do one last year because of
the pandemic but i think there's going
to be one more in
2021 so yeah these are some things that
you can use if you want to learn more
about the space
and with that i will leave some time for
questions
hey so um i don't see any questions
there's the question
we are using ml in security if ml
secure itself yeah so that's a great
question
uh like all systems you know ml is not
perfectly secure
and i think i talked about some of you
know the adversarial ml
and how different machine learning
techniques themselves are used to attack
other machine learning based detection
systems and there are several academic
papers on that
um you know but it's an evolving space
it's not secure but there is
a research around robustness on how to
protect against
different types of attacks for machine
learning
um so yeah it's again it's a powerful
tool but it's not perfect at all
and uh what are your thoughts on using
machine learning for fishing
attacks um fishing is actually
uh one of the pri one of the first
few applications uh where machine
learning was applied
uh so it's definitely very applicable
and you can use multiple different types
of techniques you know you can apply
machine learning to the
you know the context you know the full
email content uh
you know the arrival of the email there
is even
um research around applying machine
learning
to detect brand impersonation so you
know a lot of phishing
emails will try to impersonate like
legitimate brands to get
people to click or enter their password
etc
so yeah phishing has definitely a lot of
applications of machine learning
next question uh what are the algorithms
used for feature selection in malware
detection
example e headers data since the use
case is critical did it
often require manual intervention
so this is a really interesting question
and different people
uh have different approaches here i
think what has worked
very well so here's what will happen you
can usually build a deep learning model
that will automatically select the
features under the hood
and will produce really good performance
but
the problem with that is that deep
learning models tend to be heavy and
less efficient you know they require
higher compute and they have
uh they need more processing so uh
what happens is that usually what i have
seen work better to build lighter weight
models is to have like a security
researcher who is an expert in the field
and who can identify
features so keep in mind that by
features i don't mean like each and
every pe header that you know you have
to like
say whether it's a feature or not but
you can just say that okay i'm going to
look at this field
that contains all the pe headers as a
feature or i might i might extract like
the engrams
from this particular field and use that
as features because i think there is
interesting information here
so there are multiple ways to do it and
there is no right or wrong answer it
really depends on
your uh your use case essentially
next question three reasons why machine
learning security techniques
over other security techniques
why not learning security techniques
um maybe the question
uh i don't quite understand this
question
so machine learning's applications to
security
are i'm not saying that they are
necessarily
going to okay so this is how this is
what i understand the question like why
do you want to use machine learning
based
uh protections and defenses rather than
just using the traditional side
um the biggest reason is that you know
the scale of the problem
of defending you know the internet that
we have right now is very very large so
it's not always possible to um use
like the traditional methods so for
example at the speed that the malware
landscape is evolving like if i had a
huge team of security researchers who
were building
really good genetic signatures but it
would be really hard for them to keep up
with the skill that we have
um so that is the power of machine
learning like it can help defend your
skill
but obviously there is a downside you
know like these algorithms are not
perfect they suffer from bias
and they need you know a lot of work to
uh
maintain and also i think the most
critical thing is that in terms of
discovering new attacks
and in terms of like protecting against
newer attacks
securities like just traditional
security researchers and those kind of
techniques
have shown more efficacy but at the same
time you know there is a large section
where these machine learning techniques
are applicable and you know what happens
is that
applying these techniques can free up
your security research resources so that
they can focus on the
you know newer or higher criticality
problems
okay next question sometimes our data
sets need protection
and can't be known to everyone how to
ensure security of data sets through
ml uh that's
that's a really interesting question so
one way to interpret this question is
that like how can we
make sure that our machine learning
algorithms are not
um breaking the privacy of the
underlying data set
and that is a whole domain uh you know
under
um fairness and responsible ai where we
want to have privacy preserving ai and
ml
but um maybe maybe the question also
means that how do you defend
data that is stored in various servers
using machine learning
um or maybe how do you prevent data
exfiltration using machine learning
so there are definitely series of
techniques particularly using anomaly
detection
uh which look at the operations that are
taken on data sets so
for example i might have a sequence of
uh operations that were
taken on a data set and i might you know
build an anomaly detection on that
so for instance uh maybe i have uh
you know maybe i have a sharepoint
server where you know a certain team
accesses these documents regularly but
then one day i see a person from a just
a totally different team access that
data
and that event uh kind of triggers the
anomaly detection
so those kind of applications also exist
next question could you comment on the
quality of
open source data sets for ml in security
domain
yeah absolutely so that's a great
question because if we want researchers
and academia
to do good research for ml in the
security domain we want we need to
provide them with good open source data
sets
and in the beginning there were a lot of
restrictions around
privacy and compliance that prevented
companies from sharing this data
but recently some companies uh like so
forth they have made
huge strides in that in that regard so
the soil data set that i mentioned
it is a really high quality data set
that can be used uh
for you know training almost real life
machine learning models i haven't
experimented with myself but it seems
really comprehensive
next question in the beginning of the
talk
uh you mentioned contextual based
features can you elaborate on that
yeah so by contextual features i mean
you know looking at the context in which
a particular
file appears so was it downloaded from
the web was it downloaded from an
untrusted website
was it um you know is it which folder is
it
in what kind of uh name does it have so
all of these features that
have nothing to do with the content of
the file or you know what actions it
takes but it's just like
what is the context in which it appears
because for example if like
this file that you have just downloaded
from an untrusted website if it you know
goes into the
if it appears in the system folder with
like a really similar name to a
legitimate file
then that is inherently more suspicious
than you know something in the downloads
folder for instance
next question uh has microsoft explored
computer vision techniques for malware
bytes data
so there have been we have done some
experiments uh
using to apply computer vision to like
just the distribution
of malwarebytes i think i remember
seeing like
some open source blogs as well on it uh
but in general those techniques were not
found to be efficient for the production
context so they're not used
uh in production um because frankly for
malware classification
i mean why would i use like computer
vision if i can just get a
really similar performance using linear
models so
that's kind of been the driving force so
far
um but there are some there is some
research around that space
next question windows defender use
layered machine learning models can you
describe
that yeah of course so uh the layered
machine learning models
in defender you know i kind of shared
one slide on that but i what happens is
that there is one layer of machine
learning models that sit on the client
itself
uh these are typically very simple
models and they will usually not give a
malware or clean verdict they will only
say suspicious and not suspicious
and if something is found to be
suspicious uh it will like a certain
metadata package will be sent up to the
cloud and that is where like the
majority of our machine learning models
live
uh usually they are usually they are
linear uh
machine learning models average
perceptrons uh boosted trees et cetera
but there are some deep learning models
that we have recently deployed to the
cloud as well
so these models will look at you know
this metadata vector and we'll say
whether
uh you know file is now over or not and
so far these models are very
uh you know they'll give a quick
response they're highly efficient
um if even these models are not able to
give a good verdict and
they still you know put that put the
file in a certain bucket of
suspiciousness
then you know we'll request the sample
and then we have some
deeper some neural networks dnn based
that will look at the sample itself
analyze the static
features detonate it and use all of
these features to say whether the file
is malicious or not
so these are kind of the various layers
that we have in the defender land
there is a question in jack can a ml
model be reverse
engineered i think that's what they mean
um so i think it is possible to sort of
reverse engineer an ml model so
one of the things that i have played
around with is you know once
a machine learning model has given an
output or you know a series of output on
my uh
inference data set then i can you know
reverse engineer what are the features
that were important
in that context you know why did a
certain file get classified as malware
uh so and i can see which features
contributed to it being classified as
malware
um in that sense it is possible uh to
reverse engineer
some models but it's not always
meaningful because a lot of times
features are you know maybe like it's an
engram of a string or something so it
doesn't
um give you very much information but
technically it is possible to do that
uh maybe last question okay yeah
uh what can be used to reverse these
models
um so there are there are black box
techniques and then there are white box
techniques i think the stuff that i
talked about was the white box
techniques where
i have access to the model and you know
i can
inference it on a series of data set and
i can see you know
which are the features that are
important uh for the model and which are
the features that are contributing
maximum to the malicious
verdict etc um so
tools are just like you know coding
python
and just libraries so you don't need
like
a specific tool set here
last question what is the latest
machine learning applications for
security
oh wow this is a really fast moving
domain so i don't know quite what is
like the absolute latest thing
um i think the stuff that i have found
most exciting is applications of
reinforcement learning to security
again this has not been seen in the
production context yet but
one of my colleagues recently published
an uh an open source library
uh where you can have where you can
simulate uh
rl based uh attacks and defense models
for security
so that kind of stuff is very exciting
you know how can um
how can you leverage machine learning to
automatically attack systems and then in
the future automatically defend systems
as well
hey nimisha you're on mute
i'm sorry that's it for the q a i think
yeah you answered
all the questions so thank you for the
in information session donna
awesome thanks for having me