okay so I want to talk with you about
her new not the newest but the proof of
concept implementation to solve
computers and integrity this is the
joint work with elements a son who is
here with us a dough bento valise and
all chiesa real Gabaldon daniel ganc in
matin Camillus Afghani a pilgrim and met
until Boston Alan Trammell and Madhav's
Wilson okay so in this talk we first see
what is the goal of a research we will
see other approaches we are not the only
one that tried to solve such problems an
overview of our solution which is a
proof of concept in implementation and
we will finish with some concrete
measurements I offer implementation okay
so what first of all what is our goal
our goal our goal is a system to solve a
computational integrity and it should be
a close to practical ok computation
integrity or known as well as very fine
computation or delegation of
computations is the well studied problem
in cryptography and many work was done
in that field mainly in the theory side
but recently there are so some
applications as well so we want to
produce a practical computational
integrity system the message I would
like you to take with you from this talk
is that practical solution does not
require a trusted setup phase ok which
is a very common solution that I guess
that many of you all know of so our
result our result is the system we call
sy stands for scalable computational
integrity this is the first
implementation of a theoretical
construction that achieves all the four
points it's a publicly verifiable and
does not require a trusted
set up it is Universal Universal meaning
it we can construct a proof for any
general program and it has 16
fortifications its verification and
those of you who are still trying to
fill their bingo cards it is quantum
secure as well okay and now will scan
some other approaches there is a great
line of very good work done in the field
which is based on private randomness
those are designated verifier solution
or trusted set up systems they have
great advantages as a really tiny proof
or arguments technically only a few
hundreds of bytes in the length of the
argument and the verification is very
efficient very fast verification
concrete for if you concrete concretely
efficient they have an obvious
disadvantage that there are designated
very fair system or can can be used with
a trusted set up instead of being
designated verifier another class of
systems is their non universal systems
systems that are applicable only for a
restricted class of program of problem
programs those systems have a good
advantage that they can be implemented
without any cryptographic assumptions
okay but of course the disadvantage is
that they work only with a restricted
class of programs and last there is the
class of systems that have non 16-4 off'
occation those systems usually has the
very efficient concretely efficient
prover but the verification time is
linear to the length of the execution so
what
after we seen what our system is not now
we will see what our system is our
system is based on a classical theory a
theory from the late 80s the theory of
PC pills we use the more advanced
research both in Assam talking recent
asymptotic improvement and more concrete
improvements from theoretical papers and
I would like to first show you what are
our cryptographic assumptions an
important part of all the systems in
this field so first of all our internal
protocol is in the IOP model interactive
oracle proof model it's a model similar
to pcp but in the PCP the prover
generates one big proof and goes away
and then the very far is it queries a
small fraction of information from this
proof in the interpreter interactive
Oracle proof model the prover in the
very far can interact and the prover can
send many many such big proof as
response to verifiers
query queries we will see a bit later in
this lecture how this model helps us to
achieve more efficient systems so in
this model our system is probably sound
no need in any assumptions but
unfortunately this model is not
realistic because the verifier can't
really receive proofs that are bigger
than the complexity that it can run its
time complexity so we compile it to
argument systems which are realistic
systems and for that we use the random
Oracle model or if we want to compile it
to a non interactive system we use the
futuristic eventually when when we want
to implement
the system as we did we treat
cryptographic hash functions as the
random Oracle specifically in our system
we use the sha-256 hash function ok the
protocol overview the protocol overview
is very similar to the classical
protocol of Killian from about thirty
years ago the prover generates some big
proof commits with it with using the
merkel commitments the very Pharisee
--vs the commitment and queries some
information from the proof the prover
reveals the information and the
commitment pads and the very fair checks
that everything is okay the novelty
compared to this a Killian protocol is
that in our protocol we allow
interaction of the very far with the
prover and this is done in order to
reduce the load of the prover we will
now see exactly where we use this
interaction ok this interaction is the
used for the low degree testing which is
an important component in our system I
will give now an informal definition of
a low degree testing so in a low degree
testing a very fair looks and some
evaluation of a polynomial and every
normal human being the very fair wonders
whether it's the grid bounded by some
two to the N value unfortunately the
very first complexity is too low to
verify Ted deterministically okay it's
polynomial in n then prover appears and
tells her of course this polynomial is
low degree can't you see that the very
firm tells him no I don't and I don't
know you why would I trust you so the
prover tells her okay
don't trust me verify and provides her a
big proof that the very first big proof
which is classically called a PCP of
proximity okay so this is a very
informal definition of low degree
testing
okay we use the low degree test of
elements a stone and Medusa Don em and
we are the only known implementation
that really implements lo the great 1600
degree testing and even more we're the
only implementation and all that
implements a proof composition the low
degree testing of mensis on Sudan is the
special case of proof composition in
contrast the very common systems that
use the trusted set up or very furry
designated don't verify an evaluation is
low degree the use cryptography to
enforce the prover to to write only low
degree polynomials okay so this is a big
difference between the two approaches
okay so we'll scan now the protocol of
venison and Sudan in this protocol you
they use a mapping of univariate
polynomials into bivariate polynomials
that reduces the degree technically the
degree of they if the degree of the
bivariate polynomial both in its rows
and it columns is bounded by square root
of D if and only if the degree of the
original universe polynomial is bounded
by D now they continue to use this
mapping recursively on every row and
column of this bivariate polynomial
until they get to evaluations with
degree lower small enough for the very
fertile just verify deterministically
this construction results in something
that you can think of as a tree of of
proofs
what the very first does is a drought
randomly some of the leaf of this tree
of proof and remember the leaves are of
very low degree low enough for the very
first test deterministically and
verifies don't flip deterministically
and verifies locally the consistency of
those leaves to their parents and
recursively up until the very forget
back to the root of the tree so this is
basically the idea behind the test of
menses Anand Sidhant an observation is
that most of the sub proofs industry are
never accessed by the verifier but in
the pcp model because the prover does
not know in advance what would be the
queries of the verifier the prover must
generate the full tree of those proofs
what results in proof size of at least
two to the N times n which of course
bound the complexity of the prover as
well and the complexity of the prover is
at least two to the n times and although
this is a quasi linear in the degree it
is still too expensive for practical
implementations in Si we use the using
interactions to solve this problem and
what happens inside is that every the
tree is constructed layer after layer in
every layer that that the prover is
about to construct the prover asks the
verifier what are the sub proofs the
very firm will be interested to be in
that layer and the constructs only the
sub proof that they very fair would they
really
access okay because eventually the tests
are local in the Leafs and and they
require only to test the consistency to
the route this this kind of construction
does not preserve the soundness of the
system because the route the path to the
route is constructed prior to the
question whether the next sub proof
should be constructed or not okay and
this results in a much shorter proof of
length two to the N a formal description
of this method generalized to proof
composite generalize to the proof
composition technique can be found in a
paper of me together with elements a son
Alessandro Piazza
Arielle Gabi's on an exponent and will
be presented in this cycle I cut this
year okay we will move to some concrete
measurements in order to measure our
system we we construct proof to two
benchmarks two programs both programs
are solving the cuenta version of the
subset-sum problem
technically the prover wants to prove to
the verifier that some set of numbers
integer that is known to both of them
know a non-trivial subset of this set
sums to zero and we use the two
implementations a p-- limitation are
writen in a tiny ROM assembly which is
the later reduced tour proof system so
one implementation is the trivial the
exhaustive implementation the prover
test all possible subsets and the time
complexity of this implementation is two
to the end but this implementation use
the no Ram okay which is an advanced
advantage for our see
stem because in our system using Graham
introduces an overhead it's independent
of how much RAM is used but the fact
that the system use Ram requires blow-up
in the proof size with the
multiplicative factor of two log the
length of the execution
so the second bench benchmark does use
Ram and this is a solution that is based
on an algorithm that uses a sorting so
the time complexity of this solution is
lower in the two to the half of n but it
uses the spare room as well okay so here
we have some graphs that later we can
dive into that by request but what we
can learn from this plots is that those
are the plots that are relevant to the
prover daughter the plots that are
relevant to the verifier and we can see
that the plots this is the time and the
proof sides are as expected by theory
the asymptotic behavior is as expected
and the verifier the behavior is as
expected as well concretely when we not
as importantly what concretely when we
look at the numbers and we compare the
time that it takes to prove a program
compared to the time that it takes just
to execute the program on the computer
we get a slowdown of about a billion
okay
maybe it doesn't sound so good to you
but it's pretty good because it means
that we have a lot of more research to
do in this field M and for the verifier
we have a similar image
we expect that our very fair is
asymptotically succinct
and we expect the verification time to
be much lower than the execution time of
the program itself but for those
executions we see that we save time by
verification only for very very long
executions in this plot we compare our
solution to some different to some other
approaches that solve a similar problem
so the yellow plots are our system the
blue the blue bars is a system that has
a non xvi setup phase the red bars is a
system that has a setup phase but it is
succinct and the violet bars the system
which has 16 computation 16
communication complexity but non sixteen
terrific ation okay in the blue and the
red bars that they require a setup phase
the more transparent part is the
overhead introduced by the setup phase
so those bars show the the proper time
in minutes
those bars show the very first time and
those show the communication complexity
and notice the y-axis is a log scale we
can summarize what we see in these
births by saying that our proven
performance is competitive to other
systems it's not very far the
verification is succeed but slower than
other sixteen trophic ation systems and
the communication is 16th as well but it
is very high compared to other
systems with 1/16 communication
complexity I would like to use this
opportunity to introduce you to a
follow-up work which is currently in
progress working progress together with
elements a sonido bent of ending on holy
Sh
this work uses the same approaches I the
same a classical constructions but with
new ideas it includes zero knowledge
sight does not include zero knowledge
the it introduced new theory and we
reduce the prover overhead drastically
to about a million from a billion it's a
factor of a thousand and for this system
practical set Cygnus is enriched ok we
are much closer to to getting to the
failure verification is more efficient
than just executing the program you can
see that the proving time here is the
lowest among the other systems the
verification is not as low as the system
based on private randomness but it's
really competitive it's really close and
our argument sides are proof size is
much lower than what was inside
ok it went to hundreds of kilobytes
instead of tens of megabytes which is
about a thousand times longer than the
argument size in the systems that are
based on private randomness I would like
to knowledge as well I would like to
thank the programmers that worked with
us
I had about a Leo Greenblatt I shall
feel guilty not and they are known yogev
and finally our summary I introduced you
to our systems AI and we have seen some
concrete measurements of the system and
something just about a minute from the
lecture the code before the lecture the
code is public on the
link okay thank you
[Applause]