hi everyone thanks Brent for the intro
i'm tresh and you represent our work on
decentralized anonymous micro payments
as Bren said this is joint work with my
adviser alessandro matt Jingsheng Karen
and Ian okay so digital payments are a
solved problem right the customer sends
along some money to the merchant the
merchant keeps an amount for themselves
sends along a tiny bit to the payment
network and everybody's happy but this
model breaks down when the transaction
amount is much smaller than the
transaction fee itself supporting such
small payments is important for a lot of
applications however for example
consider that when I visit a web page I
don't want any ads so I give the website
owner some money and get back ad free
web page since most ad impressions and
clicks our fractions of a cent what I
want to pay is fractions of a cent but
since transaction fees are often on the
order of tens of cents
this doesn't make any sense as a rich
history and tripped ography of
constructing such micro payment schemes
and lots of esteemed names I've worked
on this problem but we still don't have
any widespread deployments that involve
multiple merchants and many many
customers I think a potential reason for
this is that all these frier schemes
they require a central mediator to
instantiate the micro payments and this
is an issue because now your customer
and merchants need to have complex
financial relations with this middleman
and they have to meet regulations and
many other reasons so let's look at
what's happening in the decentralized
world here the cryptocurrency Bitcoin
has seen widespread adoption across the
globe and I think one reason for this is
that to transfer money to somebody I
don't need to even have met them before
I don't need to establish relations with
them don't have to meet any regulations
I just signed a message and put it on
some global ledger in more detail let's
say Alice wants to send to Bob save 4.3
dollars all she does is sign this
message from A to B amount 4.3 and put
the message in the signature on a global
ledger
that's maintained by the nodes in the
Bitcoin network
so can we use Bitcoin for micro payments
or actually and the answer is not quite
because you run into a few problems the
first is that even the bitcoins
decentralized and there's no actual
middleman taking a cut you still suffer
from the issue of high transaction fees
these are roughly on the order of credit
card network transaction fees today -
projector that as Bitcoin tries to scale
these fees will only get higher the
second issue is that each transaction
takes a long time to confirm in Bitcoin
on the order of 10 minutes and the
recommendation is actually to wait more
like an hour for your transaction to be
confirmed this is particularly bad for
micro payment applications because
nobody wants to wait an hour for their
webpage to load a third issue is from
like a privacy perspective where the
issue is that Bitcoin doesn't offer any
strong anonymity guarantees in
particular the sender receiver and
transaction amount are all public for
every transaction this has two
consequences the first is that you don't
have fungibility and this has nothing to
do with mushrooms but just means that
even if I have two coins of the same
denomination they might not be treated
equally depending on their transaction
history the second or more obvious issue
is that of privacy and this is
particularly bad for micro payment
applications for instance you don't want
your browser history to be available for
everybody in the world to see on this
global ledger so two separate works have
dealt with these two classes of problems
the first is a work by passed enchilada
ad CCS a couple of years ago and they
use a technique of probabilistic
payments which will dive into later to
implement micro payments for Bitcoin
these this technique solves both the
first two problems by amortize in a
transaction fee and confirmation time
across many payments which don't hit the
ledger to solve the problem of anonymity
zero cash was proposed at Auckland
roughly three years ago and this is an
anonymous Bitcoin like currency which
hides all the information about the
sender receive and transaction amount
for every transaction so the ledger
looks opaque to
some outside observer okay so what we
want in some sense is micropayments that
combine these two worlds in more detail
we want microphones that are
decentralized for the ease of deployment
property anonymous for fungibility and
privacy reasons
and finally offline for the fast
response that is useful for micropayment
applications what we achieve is a
definition of a crypto primitive that
has these properties yeah via the idle
functionality a construction for this
definition under standard cryptographic
assumptions like musics and commitment
schemes and to realize this construction
we use two primary tools the first is a
fractional message transfer protocol
which is in some sense an analogue of OT
specialized to our setting prior
constructions of F and T schemes were
bundled under this umbrella called
translucent crypto and as you'll see
later in our setting we can't prevent
all double spending geographically so we
have to rely on the rationality of the
agents in the system and so we provide a
tight characterization of double
spending okay so the main building block
of both our construction and the pass
and slot paper is that of probabilistic
payments in this model when Alice wants
to pay Bob assent she doesn't give him a
cent for every transaction but what she
does is she takes a dollar and then
interacts with Bob in such a way that
most of the time she gets to keep the
dollar and no transaction occurs so she
doesn't have to talk to the ledger or
payment network and we call this a null
payment but like one out of every
hundred trials Bob gets the dollar so a
transaction occurs either via the letter
or some payment network and we call this
a macro payment why do probabilistic
payments lead to micro payments the idea
is that these 99 no payments they
amortize the transaction fee and the
cost of using the payment network
so your transaction fee and your
confirmation time are both amortized
over your 99 now pyramids okay
so let's dive in in a bit more to see
how class Angela use implement Provost
appearance of a Bitcoin the key idea is
to take a coin-flipping protocol and
combine that with Bitcoin in some way in
more detail when Alice and Bob want to
transact what Alice does is she s crowd
some value V on the ledger they engage
in a coin picking protocol if Alice wins
she gets to reuse the escrow for further
trials of this for the executions of
this protocol but but if Bob wins it's a
macro payment and he gets to redeem the
value and keep it for himself
the key thing to note here is that Alice
s crowds the value only once and she
gets to reuse this escrow again and
again until a macro payment occurs in
Bob redeems it so this is where the
amortization property comes from okay so
your cash is a bit more involved but at
the high level the idea is to use your
knowledge proofs and combine them with
Bitcoin to hide information of our
transactions in more detail now the zero
cash treasure consists not of messages
and signatures but serial numbers of
spent coins commitment to new coins and
zero knowledge proof that link the two
so let's say Alice owns a coin see one
that she received in some past
transaction its commitment appears on
the ledger
as you can see cm won and she wants to
transfer the value in this coin to Bob
what she does is she takes her secret
key and combines it with the coin to
generate the serial number for c1 next
she takes Bob's public key and uses that
to derive a commitment for a new coin c3
and corresponding commitment cm3 finally
she creates a zero knowledge proof that
asserts that the first two steps that
performed correctly and that the value
in the input and output is maintained
they're not having arbitrary inflation
okay she publishes a transaction
consisting of the
old serial number the new coins
commitment and the proof to the ledger
the reason why this gives any security
is that only Alice can derive the serial
number for her coin anybody else looking
at the ledger can't link cm1 with sn1
because they don't have Alice's secret
key
similarly that's the reason why Alice
can't spend Bob's coin that she creates
for him because she doesn't know his
secret key and therefore can't generate
his serial number okay so the naive idea
would be to just take the pass into last
protocol and replace Bitcoin with zero
cash so now Alice s crowds her value not
in a Bitcoin transaction but in a zero
cash transaction they engage in the coin
flip as before if Alice when she keeps
the escrow but if Bob wins he gets to
redeem it this doesn't work for two ish
for two reasons you don't have anonymity
and the customer can double spend so
let's dive into each issue in the first
case what we see is that when Alice she
says since she wants to amortize the
transaction fees she has to reuse the
escrow every time but Bob wants to be
convinced that whenever alice is
transacting with him she's using a valid
escrow so he needs to learn in some
sense the serial number of the s crowd
coin but this creates an issue because
let's say Alice transaction Bob it's an
old payment but Bob still learns the
serial number of the coin next she goes
to say some of the merchants Carol
interacts with her and this time it's a
macro payment so carol gets the serial
number and is able to append the
transaction to the ledger Bob now sees
the ledger and sees oh a coin that
somebody tried to use with me has now
been spent this so the Alice doesn't
have the strong guarantee of anonymity
that we had in zero cash there are other
attacks which lead to even further loss
of privacy so this this naive idea
doesn't quite work what we do to solve
this is to make the serial number
translucent
so what this means is that now Alice
instead of creating a transaction and
appending to the ledger just commits to
it and sends along the commitment and to
prove that the commitment was formed
correctly and the transaction inside is
valid at the time of creation then they
engage in some probabilistic opening
protocol that opens the commitment only
with some fixed probability what we want
is that with probability 1 minus P the
commitment remains completely hidden to
Bob but with probability P he's able to
open it and get out the transaction and
redeem it to achieve this we create a
distraction and message transfer
protocol which has two properties
fractional hiding ensures that with
probability 1 minus P Bob learns nothing
what was inside the message and
fractional binding ensures that Alice
cannot bias the probability that the
commitment is opened it always has to be
P so in some sense what Alice wants this
is exactly fractional hiding and what
Bob wants is his axe is exactly
fractional binding okay we realize the
construction of this on using under the
assumption of DD H and in the random
Oracle model okay so that solves the
issue of malicious merchants that want
to die anonymize customers but what
about malicious cus customers so let's
say we have a malicious Alice and the
attack that she can perform is she can
use the same coin with multiple
merchants at the same time so last year
she's transacting with these four
merchants and two of them became my
macro payments that said Carol gets her
transaction on to the ledger first at
Bob being a bit slow loses out so now
Bob doesn't have con redeem the
transaction the micro payment and Alice
has gained utility at his expense in our
setting there's no way to prevent this
double spending attack cryptographically
because there's no global immediate
consensus among the merchants about what
is and isn't a valid payment at any
given time consensus only comes along at
these ten minute blocks in Bitcoin
whereas here we want this immediate
confirmation so we can't wait for these
ten minutes
so to solve this we disincentivize
customers from cheating by having them
penalized if they cheat the idea is that
now before any transactions Alice
creates a separate deposit coin and this
is put on the ledger and then she wants
to interact with Bob
what she does is commits not only to the
transaction as before but also a secret
share of the deposits serial number the
proof now also proves that the secret
share is formed correctly and the
deposit is valid at the time of the
transaction they do the proper stick
opening as before and if Bob is able to
open the commitment he gets the
transaction and also the secret share
and he posts both of these to the ledger
why does this help us and the idea is
pretty simple let's say Alice is
transacting with Bob it's a macro
payment he gets a transaction and the
secret sure and he posted to the ledger
let's say now that Alice cheats and
she's interacting with either Bob or
perhaps it's not the merchant and
becomes a macro payment again this other
merchant now gets a different secret
share at the serial number and is able
to recover the seeker of the under
recover the serial number and append it
to the ledger at this point Alice's
deposit is revoked and she has some
negative utility okay so so far we've
used probablistic opening and deposits
to prevent link ability and double
spending but are we done and the answer
is not quite we're still lacking in
terms of both functionality and the
security analysis what happens when the
customer they're saying okay I'm done
with the system I want to leave it can
they withdraw the deposit I really want
them to be able to to with other deposit
because otherwise the deposit money is
some sunk cost for them and they're
incentivized to constantly keep cheating
to recover as much as they can but if
you allow them to recover the deposit or
they can do is we draw it just before
the deposit is revoked and this is
clearly an issue because
it's defeated the entire purpose of
asking we ran through similar issues
when dealing with much in Turbots and
they try to frame the customer for
double spending there's some similar
issues arise this is from a
functionality perspective but we haven't
even talked about what the value of the
deposit should be if it's unbounded then
again our system is completely unusable
because nobody will sign up to do two
for this my micro pyramid scheme so we
solve both of these issues we extend
zero cash with some extra features to
allow this this Vetrov will deposit
feature and we provide a tight economic
analysis of how much a customer can gain
by double spending and the main idea is
that basically your deposit value has to
be equal to the financial activity that
you want to conduct in the system okay
so to conclude the key idea of people is
that we used this translucent crypto
plus game theory to construct
decentralized anonymous micro payments
game theoretic analysis is applicable
not only to our setting but also to
others for example the postulate paper
they have they had the idea of deposits
but they didn't specify what the value
should be it's also applicable to
probabilistic smart contracts and
applications hosted by possum slack and
finally as I said before we extended the
interface of zero cash to be more
expressive and programmable and we're
already able to use this added
programmability and some new
applications that are working on right
now thank you any questions
[Applause]
so could you prove from a game
theoretical point of view that the best
strategies to be honnest yeah I think so
now in our case the idea is that when
you double spend you lose all your money
whatever money that you could have
gained from double spending so it may it
makes no sense to double spend so what
are the pros and cons versus payment
channels such as Lightning Network so I
think in payment channels you are
limited to specifically the merchants
that are in your network right and also
I think there was this paper bolt by Ian
and Matt that constructed these
anonymous human channels and they had
not the perfect anonymity that we gain
in in our setting there's basically no
link between microphone
even these now payments between too much
consecutive now vehemence between the
same costume and the same much and yeah
so I think the paper has an a comparison
with payment channels and I think we
have stronger anonymity guarantees I
think there's a question so how do you
prevent the user from giving the same
secrets here to all the merchants so we
have a way to drive the secret share
using some like the public key of the
summer cycle we have a way to make it
unique to merchants and for instance of
the protocol - yeah there's a question
send some purpur instance specific
randomness have a question tell me if I
understand your solution correct I think
that the payment channel used in writing
network is like kind of a one-to-one
channel but I think your solution once
the deposit is done I think it's a 1/2
owed
yeah you can use the deposit once and
then you can transact with however many
merchants that deposit value supports so
it's not limited to say ten merchants
you can do a specific set of ten
machines you can transact with any set
of ten merchants that using this
probabilities payment is realistic in
real applications because entire
protocol is like not very practical at
the moment but I think I mean I don't
think there's been deployments of
probabilistic payments before directly
but I think if you adjust it for certain
applications it might be useful