Thanks good morning everyone my name is
Joanne from University of Maryland today
I'm talking about faster security
computation in the synchro execution
setting it's a joint work with Alex
Molotov and Jonathan had my advisor
so let's first give have a high level
view of two-party computation
implementations so on the one hand we
have a lot of incantations and systems
for Tammy honest to PC when and we have
developed a tons of applications
including privacy-preserving machine
learning matrix factorization genomic
computation and all this stuff another
on the other hand when we take a look at
the malicious to VC we only have a es
shower and sha-256 and that's all so why
this is the case so we can summarize it
in like a complaint so on the one hand
malicious to PC is much slower it's much
less efficient and the other hand it's
very hard to scale to a large input and
when we actually according to our
experience when we directly scary to a
large input it becomes much much slower
so in this work we want to a partially
addresses to point and make it better
so let me first have a some kind of a
high-level view of the previous
paradigms for two PC so we have circuit
level can choose which is based on like
copper circuit we are going to current
chosen circuit level it's start with
linear Pinkas at 2007 and so the most
rigorous and the line of work is able to
achieve row number of circuit with Rose
its status codes occurred here parameter
we also have killed level current choose
start with and TCC o 9 so this line of
work is also known as Lego and we also
have other protocols for the amortized
setting and the pre-processing setting
so in this paper in this work we focus
on the circuit circuit level current
choose and we notice that for our
previous work we either need a large
number of public key is proportional to
the import oh we need another execution
of a two piece the portico
that is in that is outside of the
current current not out of this protocol
to do the imported recovery so here in
our work we are able to reduce the
number of public key to kappa which is
essentially what you always need for the
base dhoti and also we don't need
additional to be the protocol so let me
start with a semi honest to PT protocol
based on carbon circuit so let's assume
that Alice and Bob want to compute a
function with only one input and when
our by input from each side and one
output so the first step is to compute a
copper circuit with its related car both
keys so here the solid lines solid parts
are for one bit and the empty parts are
for zero bead so Alice can first tender
the Garber circuit sent the labels
corresponding to here to her own input
and then they can do a porthole called
oblivious transfer the college Natsume
very nice there's a box they are
supposed to be a quick box around of
leaders transfer and then the the
protocol allows Bob to learn he is only
Bo and without letting Alice to know the
value of y and then Bob can just
evaluate this and get the output however
this is awful obviously not maliciously
secure for many various reasons and so
one of the paradigm is to do to use
majority based current rules so in this
case instead of just and in one circuit
so alice is going to send about three
times row name of circuit and they can
still two are believers transfer to let
Bob learn like the input labels and the
Barbican now like her to a kind of a
current choice and kind of roughly check
half of the circuit whether they are
correctly generated or not so if when
any of them are not correctly generated
then Bob knows the Alice is cheating and
if not bob has a high-level idea that
Alice is mostly being honest and then
like like a day I mean from high level
they can Bob can evaluate all the
circuit that that is not checked and
so they are superb is expecting that
actually the majority of the output is
going to be the correct output and the
mess actually works out that if we kind
of send trees the mouse through Rotom of
circuit everything works out yeah so so
more recently there's a new paradigm
called info recovery based current
choose so in this case the difference in
that we only need to run a mob circuit
which is kind of what the best we can
get and in this case Bob we're still
going to evaluate other circuit and some
of them is going to give some other
result that is the flipped so it
essentially means that Bob is able to
catch both of the labels for one of the
wire and then they are going to run a
protocol something that Bob can inputs
the evidence that alice is not behaving
correctly and the protocol we are
allowed this small box import coveri
violet and Bob to learn the Alice in
products and then pop can compute the
function directly locally so in this
case we just need to current in that at
least one of the circuit is good
therefore we need like a much less
circuit we just need wrote circuit so
there are more they are mostly country
common issues in these kind of protocols
lines to how to design efficient import
Co I just shown and also they are also
attacks that we need to address
efficiently so I will first talk about
imported recovery yeah so input recovery
this little box again please imagine and
there is the creepox around so private
prior works either require a large
number of public key operations or need
another malicious to PC portico to come
through this info recovery so in this
paper we will so we design a new
protocol that is based on TDH and it
just requires six exponentiation per
circuit and then like four of them is
fixed based actually and so from the
high-level idea so it's kind of follows
the non interactive 2pz portico by a NPR
actually so so first the alice is going
to have
keys and seed for each of the circuit
and he's going to use so all the
randomness that I derive from the seed
and the stuff that the that is supposed
to be learned from the evaluation
circuit is encrypted by the key so they
are going to rob leavers transfer such
that pop knows the key for the
evaluation circuit and knows the seed
for the check circuit and well I mean so
very different from other previous works
we are going to let Alice Rob leavers
transfer where Alice is the receiver and
Bob sends some random labels m0 and m1
and then after after after we are done
with this once for each of the circuit
Alice is going to kind of mask the input
mask of the random labels she received
in the previous table this transfer
understand the encryption of this mask
value so in some sense this is in
somewhere some sense came-- commitment
to the axe because Alice's does not know
the other label so he/she cannot really
flip the label and the power can only
get such value for the evaluation
circuit but not the check circuit after
that they can run a like like the
remaining part of the protocol and the
very end they can run a small protocol
that is actually based on ETH such that
if if the value of Delta and Omega are
the same the den pub can learn the see
it otherwise probably nothing so here
so if problems the seed I mean it means
that Bob learns seed another another key
for one of the circuit and and and at
that point then pub can actually strip
out the cube and the stripper of the
strip of the mask tool it to learn the
axe so this is just a me honestly secure
and there are more effort that you need
to do to make it maliciously secure
however it turns out that everything can
be incorporated into the giant current
rules efficiently so MIDI test see the
paper
we're also next issue is how to do this
selectively philia attack so this is a
is another like a new attack it's very
it's very like
femoris and everybody know like this
kind of attack so essentially the attack
is that the cobbler can actually so when
when trying to like let pop know the
input levels karbala alleys can kind of
corrupt when one side of the labels and
such that Bob whether Bob can evaluate
the circuit depends on his own input
because if a lesson in this case if Y is
one populist solid line which is valid
but if y zero problems like a crab to
the red parts that are just like a
garbage so there are so mostly the the
way to prevent like the philly attack is
to use so-called probe probe matrix so
you know following i'm going to
introduce our improved probe matrix it's
a kind of address like some heat and non
cryptographic overhead that is largely
ignored in the previous papers and for
just like a 64k peach input it actually
has a 1000 times improvement in top in
terms of the running time there are also
other ways to to address this kind of
attack but that requires a large number
of public keys so let me first recall
roopam matrix is a is a matrix and such
that if you choose if which was any
subset of the rows and XOR them then
they are at this row number of ones in
the result in the row so once we have
this kind of road from matrix and the
given we have the input why we just need
to find a random y prime such that the
matrix vector multiplication holds so
once we have this this is the old
protocol that is not secure again some
slightly attack we have y we have e this
is e the public and the y is known to
Bob so Bob can first select a random Y
and the field wide into the oblivious
transfer and now the carpal circuit and
instead of computing F XY z--
it were first recover the real input in
the circuit and then to the current
without following computation so if the
if the rapport matrix translate n number
into my input so previous works we say
that okay so I need about M prime number
of OTS and we are happy because
computing the Roper matrix is free
thanks to 3xr however if you actually
calculate the right carefully actually
number of XOR it's quadratic for the
input so I mean epsilon is free it's a
writing instruction but it's still it's
in square and what's worse the roof the
size of your open matrix is also
quadratic so it means that in order to
compute the rope in order to do this
computation in the circuit we need to
compute n square number of X R and in
each step we also need to look up a n
square number of size matrix to find out
whether we should the extra or not so
for example if we have again 64 K P
input it's about 4 billion XOR operation
and the matrix of 4 billion peat
assuming that you have you are packing
all that bit very compactly so this is
our next task we want to reduce the size
of this rope for matrix make it
efficient and still secure so I mean
first it's a first idea is let's just
chunk off the unnecessary part so I mean
so ordinarily it shouldn't be secure
because I mean we lose a lot of
randomness however so notice that if we
make sure that each of the small cream
part is due a rope from matrix then the
large one we are we just put as put
aside everything together is Stewart Rob
from matrix this is because I mean if we
select any number of rows it's either in
the same row for matrix which is fine or
we are they are in different rope for
matrix which is even better because it
won't have any overlap so now the
problem really just reduced to one
single problem how to construct this
small four matrix with the particulars a
particular size because we can reduce
the same group for matrix on this
diagonal so now we have this small root
for matrix so inspired by Linda and
River 915 we first add a identity matrix
which we place the first part of the
random matrix
identity matrix so this is actually very
nice in the analysis because we now know
that if we just saw like our number of
rows we are currently that they are at
least L ones in the in the matrix
because the identity matrix already
contribute you our number of ones in
there in the result so now the so when
we want to calculate the probability
that this is the wrote for matrix we
don't need to consider the case where we
select more than row number of rows row
name of rows because I mean that's
current in to be a true name of ones so
now we only need to consider a case
where they are like smaller set where
the size of s is smaller than row and
very nicely in even in this case the
rope the identity identity matrix
contribute a lot of ones already so the
bun is actually much tighter so actually
after we like to find all the concrete
numbers and stuff so this is our final
construction so we kind of chunk all the
chunk of the emphasize into in two sizes
or into multiplication multiple of 220
32-bit and for each of them we we have
like we have a blow-up of two in this
case okay so in compare compared to the
prior past work we kind of have a
thousand times
giddup in terms of in terms of the one
in time who is like 65 k beat so notice
that actually here so the cause of our
up for matrix is actually much it's a
slightly higher than the previous from
matrix but that is fine because you can
see actually the cost is dominated by
the PI by computing this giant probe
matrix actually wrote some number of
times okay so the last issue is to how
to enforce importing consistency so
actually in the import recovery kind of
paradigm there are two employed
consistency issues so why is that how to
ensure that the import is we are using
the same import across different circuit
in a cut and choose and also we want to
ensure that
so when we do the import recovery the
input is the same as what we embedded
into the current choose so from
high-level this is the old version so
the problem that this axe can all be
different and we want to ensure that
some consistency among them is true so
so the idea of prior work is to kind of
construct a zero knowledge proof that
takes on this input as this takes this
axes input and the proof to Bob that
they are secure are not sorry they are
consistent in some ways so it means that
so the intuition is that I want to
assure that all these lines are
consistent so is it really is it really
like necessary actually no so so in this
paper the high level so the intuition is
that okay so we are not going to enforce
this strong consistency instead we just
want to enforce that at least one of the
coastal kit is consistent with the one
in the input recovery and we want we
just use whatever that is that if we
extract from the empirical recovery as
the import that to define that as the
input of Alice and it turns out that it
is much much better especially when we
incorporates this consistency with the
info recovery protocol I introduced
previously because again this can be
done very efficiently in the in current
choose all together with with the input
recovery okay so I mean now we have
practical MVC of course we need to
implement the protocol so we implement a
protocol and it's as it's a part of the
EMP toolkit and everybody is welcome to
try it so we try so we run the
experiment on a reasonable machine of of
this Amazon in size but I mean however
which has your single core so it doesn't
really matter that much and we use AES
and I so network is about 2.3 gigabyte
and I mean all the other experiment in
the following assumes 40s that histogram
and the 108 competition perimeter okay
so first three examples with various
size the first month every as the
circuit that everybody yours is a yes it
sticks about 65 minute second yeah
and for modular exponentiation of two
thousand two thousand and beat it's a
it's a much much much much much much
larger circuit about with about four
peelings four billion and gate and I
mean we take about five hours to run in
this case most of the cause is is for
the circuit is for constant in the
circuit and we also run another circuit
that is a very very wide and with
reasonable taps for this circuit it's a
so the so this is a circuit that we can
to sort one thousand integers each off
steady to beat so it's about the ten
million and gate circuit and takes about
less than a minute so so this is a kind
of some other experiment we do so in
this case we kind of fix the summer we
fix input and output size and engage and
only change one of the input and see
like how our implement how our protocol
works along with like like in terms of
each of the component and so and it is
actually linear for the input and output
and the circuit size you can see
actually so it takes about 20
microseconds per bit and about four
microseconds and gate and so it's a like
a side-story that actually so this it is
this experiment that we realized that
the cost of rope from a tree is
nonlinear its quadratic because when we
run this experiment we find that the
line when in terms of the petrous input
is actually it's not alliance a
quadratic function okay so compared with
the prior work because like like a most
of the work just to do a yes so we
compare against the AES so in this case
we can see a trend here that it's a it's
getting better we are hoping that we can
get we are getting even better from this
point
so so like concurrent and a subsequent
with this work we are we have tons of
more improvement to the malicious to PC
so we are actually working on one of the
extension of the protocol that support
random seed checking this is also a it
is also town together with similar
ana-lucy and we also we are also able to
chop the chop the TTH assumption
saturday we only need a OTE here and
like they are also people like they are
also like concurrent and they're like
more recent result on Lego which
actually improves the functioning
function dependent cost so for example
these papers put most of the computation
to the face where the two parties does
not know what function they want to
compute and and however for this kind of
protocols they all need a large number
of memories because like a lot of
memories that is a kind of proportional
to the circuit size are even worse
however for the circuit level current
choose we don't really need a lot of
memories it's everything can be
published and the of the memory
footprint size is proposed is only
proportional to the statistical security
parameter so for example for a pillion
size circuit the the size of the memory
you need to make sure it is constant run
is is going to be like hundreds of
gigabyte and and as you want to use disk
ok so that's all for my talk and thanks
and here is the code you can you can go
and try and yeah
we have time for a quick question when
you are talking about the ROA parameter
matrix - for the selected failure
attacks or against this like a failure
attacks there was this s I guess I was a
set but what s is s so it's it's kind of
between analysis you want to show that
for any subset it's going to be fine
okay so that's the set and then you need
to apply a union bond across all set
yeah and in this particular case because
we don't need to consider like said with
more than roll number more than row name
of rose so it's like the Union bond is
exponentially smaller thank you
randomness it comes from when which was
Y prime which was Y prime randomly and
there is like a and have y equals to e
times y prime is a public matrix yes yes
just curious you so so in the yeah
thanks for the chance to give me to
advertise the framework so in the EMP
talk here we also have a on the fly
circuit compiler so you can write so
it's like we have like integers and the
floating point and of all other stuff so
I build I build a small program in that
to compute modular exponentiation and
it's directly yeah it's a it's like
textbook version of modular
exponentiation