great thank you for that introduction
Sam David and I'll be telling you about
some of our work on constructing
functional encryption for randomize
functionalities this is a joint worth
which is Cheng Agrawal at visa research
so in the last 10 years or so functional
encryption has really emerged as a
general paradigm for unifying different
kinds of encryption schemes so as you
probably have heard throughout the day
in a functional encryption scheme keys
are associated with a deterministic
function f and cipher texts are
associated with messages the guarantee
in a functional encryption scheme is
that if you take its message a
ciphertext encrypting a message m and
ascii for a particular function f if you
then run a decryption algorithm what you
learn is a function evaluated on the
underlying message M so more formally a
functional encryption scheme in a public
key setting consists of the following
four algorithms which I will briefly
enumerate for you so there's a set up
algorithm that on input the security
parameter outputs a secret key M public
key for the underlying encryption scheme
there's a key generation algorithm that
takes in a secret key and a description
of a function f and produces a function
key for that function there's an
encryption algorithm that takes in that
message m and the public key and
produces a ciphertext and finally and
most interestingly there's a decryption
function it takes in a description or a
secret key for a function f and a
message and outputs F of M so all of the
most of the existing works on functional
encryption we have considered
deterministic functionalities namely the
inputs of the key generation algorithm
is a description of a function that is
deterministic however not all functions
in this world are deterministic in fact
there are many natural examples of
randomized functions and we may actually
want to introduce or define a functional
encryption scheme where we can actually
give out keys there are four randomized
functionalities and let me motivate this
by giving you two concrete examples
where this might be useful in the first
example so considered a case of proxy
Rhian Krypton so suppose Alice's runs a
mail server and now Alice goes on
vacation so Alice now wants to get her
take her incoming mail which is
encrypted under some public key
encryption scheme let's say a public key
functional encryption scheme and she
wants to delegate some subset of her
emails to her secretary provided that
they're tagged with something
work-related so in particular what the
proxy should do is ever see the personal
email it should do nothing but if it
sees a work email what the proxy should
it's Rhian crypt her ela contents of her
email under her Secretary's key so her
secretary can process the email while
she's on vacation so if we want to solve
this with a functional encryption scheme
what we could do as we come Alice would
provision her email server with a
function key for doing this Riaan crip
shim process but as we know for public
key encryption schemes to be
semantically secure typically the
encryption algorithm needs to be
randomized so we want to solve this
naturally using a functional encryption
scheme we need functional encryption
schemes that support randomized
functionalities let me give you another
example where an application that's more
naturally expressed or captured by a
randomized functional encryption scheme
so this is the case where we have a bank
and suppose the bank is encrypting a
bunch of Records and what we want to do
is we want to audit the records in the
bank so we have a third party auditor
and the auditor is basically going to
sample some subset of these records and
check for their integrity now of course
in order for the audit to be meaningful
it better be the case that Li that the
auditor actually gets a random sample
rather than something that could be
fixed or maliciously influenced by the
bank so hopefully this has motivated you
to think about functional encryption
schemes for randomized functionalities
so the next one next question is that to
ask is whether these schemes exist at
all so in a work by coil chain copula
and Sahai in 2015 they not only define
formally the notion of functional
encryption scheme for randomized
functionalities which I will often refer
to as RFP for short so randomized
functional encryption and in the same
work they also showed that starting from
the general-purpose indistinguishability
alpha station you can actually build
general-purpose functional encryption
schemes for all randomized
functionalities which is a really nice
result because this basically gives
shows that functional encryption schemes
for randomized functions certainly exist
assuming IO exists now if we look at
what we know about functional encryption
schemes though for deterministic
functionalities it actually turns out
that we know a lot more we know that we
have many different classes of
constructions in particular of very nice
line of work has shown that starting
just from public key encryption or from
standard assumptions such as learning
with errors assumptions we can actually
build functional encryption schemes so
in the bounded collusion set
so in particular we can support pound
functional encryption for all circuits
as long as the adversary only gets to
see a a priori bounded number of keys
and of course from multi linear maps or
alpha station we can actually build
functional encryption schemes secure
against let's standard in the standard
model so it turns out that if you look
at the landscape or the existing of
existing constructions of functional
encryption there seems to be a large gap
between what we know in a deterministic
setting and what we know in the
randomized setting in the deterministic
setting we have many different kinds of
results many different kinds of
constructions satisfies different
security properties different
compactness properties and so on in a
randomized setting we really just have
one defining work which is the original
work constructing randomized functional
encryption schemes from IO so a natural
question to ask them where you look at
this picture is whether it is
necessarily harder to build functional
encryption scheme to support the more
general class that randomized
functionalities do we necessarily need
stronger tools or stronger cryptographic
assumptions in order to go from
deterministic functions to randomize
functions so in this work we actually
show that this is not the case so our
main result in the work that I will show
is that starting from any
general-purpose functional encryption
scheme for deterministic functionalities
coupled with some very standard very
well study number theoretic assumptions
namely the decisional diffie-hellman
assumption the DDH problem and the RSA
problem we can actually boost any
functional encryption scheme for
deterministic functionalities into an
equivalent functional encryption scheme
that supports all randomized
functionalities another way to view this
implication is it's basically saying
that randomized functional encryption is
not that much harder to construct the
deterministic functional functional
encryption so in particular if you have
a particular application that nests that
meet where it's more naturally captured
by using randomized functional
encryption what you can do is you can
actually start with a deterministic
functional encryption scheme and
actually generically transform that into
a randomized one so now let me define
for you more precisely what a randomized
functional encryption scheme is and then
I will tell you how our generic
transformation works so let's begin with
the basic correctness definition this is
what I enumerated at the beginning of
the talk but let me just review so in a
deterministic functional encryption
scheme we have a ciphertext encrypted
message we
key for a particular deterministic
function f a decryption operation where
output F of M when we extend two
randomized functionalities things become
a little bit more difficult but let's
start simple so again if I have a cipher
text encrypt your message m and a key
now for a randomized function f the
decryption function is a deterministic
function that should output a random
draw from the output distribution of F
of M so in particular the distribution
is taken over the randomness used to
encrypt and I ran in this uses in the
key generation the description operation
itself however is deterministic and
things get a little bit more complicated
because we can also consider the case
where we have two different cipher texts
so if suppose we have two independent
encryptions and yet we apply the same
function key to decrypt well we should
get in the front in the randomized
nothing it's actually two independent
draws from the output distribution so
even though in our in this case we use
the same key to decrypt two cipher texts
as long as those cipher texts are
independently generated even if they may
encrypt the same value which is what we
should obtain a plan of find the
decryption operation it actually
independent draws from the output
distribution and this is very and
similarly if we have the same cipher
texts but apply to different function
keys again if the few function keys are
independently generated even if they're
for the same underlying function we
again should see two independent draws
from the output distribution but that's
the correctness definition hopefully
it's clear and then for the security I
will just briefly summarize the
simulation-based notions of security
that we work with in our paper so the
way that we usually capture security at
least in a simulation setting as we plot
we say that the only information that's
revealed by a ciphertext and a key is
basically the function evaluation on the
underlying message and the way we
capture that is we define two
distributions a real distribution where
we have an honest encryptor generating a
key for a function f and the ciphertext
for a message m and outputting the
secret key and the ciphertext and we
have an ideal distribution where we have
a simulator so some efficient algorithm
and the simulator here is only given a
description of the function f so we're
not hiding the function f here and the
function output on m so nothing more
about the the underlined message is
revealed other than the actual function
evaluation so the simulator is able to
simulate a ciphertext and key given only
the function evaluation and we can also
generalize this and extend this to the
randomized setting accordingly I won't
get into the details there but another
caveat that often comes up when we deal
with randomized functionalities is it's
actually very concerning
if the encrypter it's no longer behaving
honestly so let's consider our previous
example where we have an auditor that's
trying to audit a bank so the bank is
encrypting records and the auditor is
actually going to sample records from
the encrypted database what happens if
the banks here is being a poor serial
what if the bank is malicious well what
it could potentially try to do is choose
bad randomness or construct these
ciphertext in such a way such that way
you apply the decryption function you no
longer see an independent draw from the
underlying distribution right because in
randomized functionalities the
decryption operation has a distribute I
should output some distribution if this
distribution can be biased or skewed
then that completely compromises the
integrity of the audit so more
concretely let me give you an example
what a malicious encrypter can
potentially do is construct two
different ciphertext encrypting messages
m and m prime such that when you apply
the decryption function using some
honestly generated key what you end up
with is not two independent draws from
the output distribution of F of M and F
of M Prime they could be completely
correlated or even use identical
randomness both of these would subvert
the integrity of the underlying auditing
process so the way that we've captured
this more formally as we give the is we
in a security reduction we give the
adversary access to a decryption Oracle
just like we captured malicious
encrypter in a CCA setting so we believe
just as CCA security is sort of the
natural or the most correct notion for
practical deployment of public key
encryption this sort of robustness
against malicious encrypter is the
correct notion of security when we look
at functional encryption in a randomized
setting so now having defined the
security notions let me now show you how
our generic transformation works so just
to briefly it read review our generic
transformation starts from a functional
encryption scheme for the class of
deterministic functionalities and boosts
traps out into a functional encryption
scheme that supports all randomized
functionality
so somehow we're going to make use of
the underline deterministic encryption
scheme so not surprisingly the
fundamental tool we're going to rely on
is the randomization so we're going to
first construct a d-- randomize function
where instead of evaluating the function
f the randomize function f using
uniformly sampled randomness we're
instead going to derive that randomness
using a pseudo-random function so what
that entails is basically we're going to
construct a D randomize function and the
D randomize functionality is going to
have hard-coded inside it a PRF key and
the PRF key will be used to derive the
randomness for the actual function
evaluation just to make them more
concrete the key generation algorithm in
a randomized functional encryption
scheme will begin by sampling a TK and
then issuing a determine a key for the
underlying deterministic functional
encryption scheme for the D randomized
functionality this will produce a key K
and it seems like we would be done now I
wouldn't be up here telling you about
this transformation if this is all we
needed to do and the problem really
boils down to the fact that in the
public key setting keys do not hide the
function write function hiding is very
difficult to achieve
there are many lower bouncing what kind
of function hiding is possible in the
public key setting so what this means is
that an evaluator who holds a decryption
key can actually look at the decryption
key and read off the bits of the PRF and
once the key was the key for the PRF is
public then though you can no longer a
field of PRF security and argue that the
randomness you're using is actually
hidden or it looks uniform so we need to
do something more and what we're going
to do is we're going to rely on the fact
that functional encryption schemes do
provide us some hiding properties in
particular if we can hide things in a
message so what we're going to do
instead of putting the key entirely in
the cipher in that key in a function key
we're going to split it into two pieces
one of them we're going to embed in a
ciphertext and one of them we're going
to embed in the actual function okay so
let me just make sure this is clear so
on the encryption operation what we will
do is the encrypter will sample a key
share and when it encrypts instead of
encrypting the message by itself it's
going to encrypt the message with the
key share and the key generation
function will also sample a key share
and it will off output a be randomized
function where the PRF key is actually
combined from both the secret from the
basta
here in the function key as well as the
key share in the message okay so there
will be some operation that will do the
recombination there here we actually
need some a stronger property on the
underlying pseudo-random function
because if you look at this picture here
the encrypter actually gets to influence
the key that's used to D randomize the
functionality and so we actually require
pseudo-random functions secure against
related key attacks so but using our K a
secure PRF we can actually make this
part of the transformation goes through
now unfortunately this construction is
still not quite enough and as and for
the precise reason that it actually does
not provide robustness against malicious
encrypter so the way to understand this
or the way to view this as we can still
see that the encrypter has a lot of
flexibility in constructing the cipher
text so let's see where does encrypter
can shortage influence the cipher text
that is produced certainly encrypter can
choose the key share that's going to be
used in the cipher text but this is
actually not too bad because we can just
appeal to our ka security of the
underlined pseudo-random function to say
that this is not problematic what does
turn out to be problematic for a fairly
subtle reason is that the intruder can
actually choose the randomness used to
encrypt under using the underlying
functional encryption scheme and this
turns out to be surprisingly quite
problematic and let me give you an
example for why this is the case so
consider it an encrypted
simply chooses the same key share and
encrypt twice so you there's two
different random values and constructs
two different cipher texts both
encrypting the same underlying plaintext
pair what happens is we now have two
distinct FB ciphertext straight because
they were independently generated and
yet they encrypt the same underlying
message and so what happens is no matter
which key the krypter uses is always
going to produce the same output we're
never going to see two independent draws
from the output distribution even though
we have two cipher texts that look
distinct right that look at the
different and any ideal distribution
sort of if we want to really capture
security against dishonest encrypt earth
what we really desire is that if we have
two different cipher texts they should
produce two independent looking outputs
and the problem really boils down to the
fact that here the encrypter has too
much freedom in constructing the cipher
text so when building functional
encryption scheme for randomized
functionality
there's a fine line that we have the
tread where we try to balance between
the need for encryption and the need for
security and a need for to constrain the
ante to constrain the malicious
encryptor from producing bad ciphertext
so the way that we're going to address
this final problem is we're actually
going to take ideas inspired by
deterministic encryption and the key
observation I think is that honestly
generated ciphertext actually have a lot
of entropy in them so if you look at
what that honestly generate the cipher
text looks like it contains the message
and it contains a key share for a PRF
and because with is the key share for a
PRF it's going to be generated from a
distribution with a lot of entropy so
the key idea here is instead of having
the encrypter choose the randomness used
for the underlying FB encryption
arbitrarily it's instead going to derive
that randomness from the message itself
so in particular the encrypter is going
to derive randomness using the key k1
this might seem problematic because now
the random is used for encryption is
correlated with the message but with a
careful choice of how we actually
construct the scheme we can actually
make the security proof goes through so
let me show you what the final
construction looks like so the
encryption algorithm will unemployed a
message M it will first sample a key
share and when it encrypts it's going to
encrypt a pair containing the message
and the key share and then the
randomness used for the encryption is
going to be derived from the key share
itself and then moreover we also need an
apt hatchery proof so this is resembling
a lot of the how you go from CPA
security to CCA security by attaching a
music argument where and as a proof of
knowledge in this case we're going to
attach we're going to have the encrypter
provide a proof that actually generated
the cipher text in a prescribed manner
okay and so then music will in will
explain that the cipher text was
properly generated and the intuition for
why this works is boils down to the
following the cipher text now can be
viewed as a deterministic function of
the method has chosen a message in the
key there is only one cipher text that
can be produced so if the encrypter ever
produces two distinct cipher texts then
it must be the case that either the
message the first or the key share the
first and if either of these two
components differ by security of the
underlying PRF in particular by related
key security of the underlying PRF we
can
argue that they function evaluation
actually is evaluated using a random
string okay so to summarize ours our
transformation we begin with a
simulation secure functional encryption
scheme for deterministic functionalities
and combined with several ingredients
that can all be instantiated using the
dvh and RSA assumptions we can actually
obtain a simulation secure functional
encryption scheme for our randomize
functionalities and let me note here
that our transformation preserves a lot
of the underlying security properties as
well as compactness properties of the
underlying scheme so prior to this work
the state of thought public key
functional encryption scheme could
really be divided into two parts we have
a lot of different kinds of
constructions different flavors of
security different flavors our
compactness and so forth for the
deterministic functionalities but
randomized functionalities we really had
only one construction based on i/o so
using the generic transformation of this
work we can actually take all of the
existing knowledge we have four
functional encryption scheme for
deterministic functionalities and
bootstrap them and transform them in the
corresponding schemes for a little class
of all randomized functionalities and as
an added bonus we get adaptive security
even against our malicious encrypt errs
so let me conclude with a few open
questions so one natural question to ask
is whether a more direct or more
efficient construction is possible and
we want to look at weaker
functionalities right so here I have
described a generic transformation that
starts with functional encryption scheme
that supports all circuits and we have
come transformed it to all functions
that support randomized circuits maybe
if all you care about is sampling
elements from a database or sampling as
few random entries maybe there's a more
efficient construction that's possible
there another open question is whether
we can do this construct this
transformation from deterministic Fe to
randomize deafeat without making
additional assumptions such as the DDH
and RSA assumptions I should note here
that it is this is possible in a secret
key setting so in a work by coma Karski
Segev and yo F they showed that starting
from functional encryption schemes for
deterministic functionalities in a
secret key setting you can boost boost
staff key functional encryption scheme
for our randomized functionality without
needing to make additional complexity
assumptions and finally another
technical detail is whether it's
possible to do a to have a similar
transformation
operate in the case where we start with
a funky
encryption scheme that's secure under an
indistinguishability based notion of
security rather than the
simulation-based notion of security that
we require in this work and thank you
very much I'll take questions now we
have time for question hi
so the previous construction of
randomized DeFede uses a new style right
that's right so I'm wondering why
doesn't the following work start from a
deterministic epi
do the EFI toyo transformation I would
do IO construction right so yes so
that's one way to you can do this
transformation so then I'm done with the
assumptions right yes but in that if you
start with like a boundary collusion
secure functional encryption scheme so
something from pke where LW is then you
can't bootstrap data i/o so this gives a
new class of randomized functional
encryption schemes that's securing the
founder collusion setting from standard
public key encryption so your open
question is how to store crowbar net
collusion EFI deterministic functions
you can also reformulate it that way yes
so war was now well another way to
formulate it is the FE 2 i/o
construction incurs a sub exponential
loss in a security reduction so maybe
can you do everything out only a
polynomial boss in this appeared record
I think that's also still open