thank you I'll be talking about hashing
garbled circuits for free and this is
joint work with Zhang fan and blackulas
Nichols so garble circuits is one of the
main techniques for secure computation
and today a primitive in its own right
hashing garbled circuits could
potentially come up in many applications
of garbled circuits like cut and choose
for two-party computation private
certified functions for credentials
encrypted database systems like blinds
here and so on a natural way to hash a
garbled circuit is to first generate the
garbage circuit and then use a hash
function like sha on the garbled circuit
string but when we look at the relative
cost of fixed key cipher gobbling and
hashing the cost could vary depending on
the architecture but with fast hardware
AES implementations gobbling is fast and
often times shy is the bottleneck so in
on typical computing platforms of today
hashing or garbled circuit could cost up
to six times more than that of
generating a garbled circuit so in this
work we study free hashing which allows
for hashing a garbled circuit at no
additional cost during the generation of
the GC itself and we see that
eliminating the cost of GC hashing
significantly improves performance in
many applications one of our motivating
applications is an attribute based
credential verification where we have a
proven with an input who wishes to prove
in zero knowledge that his input
satisfies a certain policy and we are
interested in the setting where the
verifiers policy function is also
private so standard cut and choose
approaches do not seem to work here
since the check circuits reveal the
evaluated policy function in a setting
where or certificate authorities
available we can have the CA certify the
correct generation of garbled circuits
so here is the setting we are interested
in where hashed garble circuits could be
applied in a straightforward way we have
a proven very fire and a certificate
authority with the signing and
verification key the CA begins by
generating many seeds to be used as
seeds of a pseudo-random generator and
then garbles
generates the garbled circuit for the
circuit that represents the policy
function of the verifier and he uses the
randomness that is generated by using
the seed s now he computes the hash of
the garbled circuit signs the hash and
sends the seed and the signature to the
verifier later in the online phase the
verifier can reconstruct the garbage
circuit using the randomness generated
from the seed and she sends the garbage
circuit along with the CS signature to
the probe the prover can compute the
hash of the garbled circuit and he
proceeds to evaluate the garbage circuit
only if the signature of the CA verifies
a similar idea can be used in general
yucatan shows protocols this was first
formalized by Goyal maahes allen Smith
in 2008 where a party p1 uses a seed to
construct many garbled circuits and
instead of sending all the garbled
circuits to party p2 he sends many
hashes and if the eyuth garbled circuit
has chosen to be your check circuit or
p1 reveals the seed si and p2 can
reconstruct the I odd garbage circuit
and verify the hash so GM s and all
subsequent protocols that use this idea
use a collision resistant hash to trade
off computation for communication and we
can ask if our free hash construction
can be used in all these protocols so
here is a summary of our results we
begin by giving a definition for gobble
circuit hash security and then give hash
to gobbling constructions both for
standard gobbling and state of the art
half gates construction we then
implement our construction and evaluate
its performance and finally discuss
applications of our constructions so
before I begin let us quickly recall
what our gobbling schemas so we have a
couple of algorithms guard will encode
eval and decode garble is a randomized
algorithm that takes a circuit and
outputs a garbled circuit along with
encoding and decoding information or the
encode algorithm takes the plaintext
input and the encoding information and
outputs a garbled input eval takes the
garbled circuit and the garbled input
and gives a garbled output decode takes
a guard
output and the decoding information and
gives the plain circuit output we want
correctness that is after evaluating the
garbled circuit if we decode the garbled
output it should be equal to C of X and
for security we want privacy that is the
garbled circuit garbled input and the
decoding information should reveal
nothing beyond C of X and authenticity
states that given the gobble circuit and
the garbled input it's hard to find the
garbled output that decodes to something
other than C of X in addition to these
standard properties we also want
verifiability which means that there is
an additional algorithm called verify
that takes a circuit C and the
perpetrate garbled circuit C hat and
outputs one if C hat is indeed a valid
gobbling of C and 0 otherwise so I'll
begin by giving our definition of
garbled circuit our security the
high-level idea is that we take
advantage of the fact that the input to
hash is a garbled circuit which means it
has to be evaluated under the eval
function and our definition is going to
be weaker than the standard notion of
collision resistance so given a
correctly generated garbled circuit and
its corresponding hash the adversary is
allowed to come up with another garbled
circuit G C hat such that the hash
collides but if that happens the
guarantee is that the garbled circuit
property of GC heart is broken which
means DC heart will fail to evaluate so
here we have an adversary who outputs
two different garbled circuits along
with two different encoding information
decoding information D and hash edge now
say the two garbled circuits collide in
their hash now we have that if one of
the garbled circuits say the green
garbage socket verifies then the red
garbled circuit fails to evaluate that
is a decoding the output of eval on the
red carpet circuit fails now the
adversary is allowed to come up with
green and red encoding information
corresponding to the two different
garbled circuits but the decoding
information D is the same that is the D
with respect to which the red garbled
circuit fails evaluation is the same D
with respect to which the green garbage
socket passes verification
and this restriction is essential for
higher security because if we did not
place this requirement or the adversary
can come up with D that simply decodes
any string returned by eval to arbitrary
outputs coming to our hashed garbling
constructions our high-level idea is to
intertwine the generation of the hash
and verification of the hash with the
garbled circuit generation and
evaluation we attempt this by
maintaining a running hash as the XOR of
all the garbled rows so here we have an
example circuit with two gates the
logical values on the wires are labeled
and we have two keys corresponding to
the two values on the wires so we have
GT one which is a garbled table
corresponding to the and gate here so
this encrypts the output wire labels c0
and c1 according to the functionality of
the and gate and GT 2 is the garbled
table corresponding to the or gate here
that encrypts the output wire label a
according to the or functionality and
the gobble circuit itself consists of
the garbled tables and say we said the
hash to be XOR of all the garbled rows
so what can an adversary do now he can
for example mount the following attack
say he changes one of the entries in GT
one so he changes the last row here to
encrypt c0 instead of C one now we have
a different garbled circuit GC hat but
this also affects the running hash by
some offset Delta now say the adversary
knows we're anywhere in the circuit
there exists an inactive row he can
change that entry by the same offset
Delta which now fixes the hash and since
this row is not going to be used during
evaluation the adversary will not be
caught
so our refinement of this approach is to
now make each gates output wire label
depend on all entries of the garbled
table and the intuition is that the XOR
hash correction will now necessarily
involve modifying an active garbled
table entry thus affecting the computed
output wire label of the gate so going
back to our eggs
ample circuit we now treat the output
wire labels as temporary wire labels and
change the way we define the output wire
labels so now we have the garbled tables
that encrypt the temporary output wire
labels and we set the real wire labels
to be the temporary labels exhort with
all the rows of the corresponding
garbled table again we said the hash to
be the XOR of all the rows I'm now going
back to the previous attack if the
adversary changes one row he modifies
the hash by some offset Delta but now if
he changes some entry in JT to to fix
Delta he also changes the translation
between the temporary wire label and the
real wire label but what he can now do
instead is to guess which combination of
values will not be used in the same
garbled table and change that to fix the
offset Delta which fixes both the hash
and the translation between the output
wire label or C without disrupting the
translation of the output wire label e
so this works because the adversary can
modify a garbled table entry and correct
the disrupted hash within the same table
this works since the fix for the broken
hash also fixes the translation from
temporary and real wire labels so the
idea towards our final construction is
to use garbled tables for computing wire
labels and the hash but in different
ways and this means that a fix for a
broken running hash will no longer keep
the output wire label valid so again we
treat the output wire labels as
temporary wire labels and we have the
garbled table entries encrypting
temporary wire labels now we define the
translation as follows the output wire
label C is going to be the temporary
wire label XOR with some function of all
the rows of the corresponding garble
table we against at the hash to be the
XOR of all the garbled table rows and
now we define the translation function f
to be the XOR of all the rows where the
ayat' Row is offset by I bits so our
final construction uses all the garbled
table rows as XOR
it's for computing both the garble
circuit ash and for the translation
function but in a different manner and
this means that a fix for the broken
hash will not simultaneously keep the
vial able valid so if we have two
different garbled circuits such that the
hash collides then the evaluation of GC
hat fails and this means that the
evaluation of GC hat will deviate from
the evaluation of GC with respect to
some wire label and subsequently this
can return to either a correct running
hash or to a correct by a label but not
both we use bit shifting for our
translation functions because it's both
fast and easy to implement but in
general we want functions fi such that
the following property is satisfied what
this says is that if a garbled circuit
is modified such that the XOR of the
rows remains the same then with high
probability the XOR of F of the garbled
rows will change and this is sufficient
to prove security of our construction so
we instantiate the key derivation
functions of our gobbling scheme with
the Davis male construction and assume
that it is a random permutation to be
compatible with free XOR we also assume
that it's correlation robust or to prove
hash security of our construction under
our definition we additionally require
collision resistance of Davis mayor
which can be achieved assuming that it
is an ideal cipher the current state of
the art in gardling is the half Gate
construction of Jahoda toll from 2015
and the half gate construction is
compatible with free XOR and uses to
cipher text to guard will a NAND gate so
the question is can we have a free hash
construction for the half gates gambling
scheme so a half gate is a NAND gate
where one of the inputs is known to the
known to one of the parties in the clear
so say a here is known to be gobbler
this is a generator half gate and the
one of the inputs is known to the
evaluator it's an evaluator half gate
now if we look at the following two and
gates where I here is a value that is
chosen
random by the gobbler and if we can
arrange for the evaluator to learn a X
or are in the clear then we see that the
first and gate is an evaluator half gate
and the second and gate is a generator
Haskett and we can put the two half
gates together by exerting the output of
the two half gates to obtain a complete
and gate here
and the half gates construction shows
how to garble two half gates using one
ciphertext each and we can put them
together to garble a complete and gate
using two cipher texts and we have X all
for free so now the observation is that
in the half gates construction there is
no inactive row which means that both
cipher texts are going to be decrypted
during evaluation and is used to compute
the output wire label so if the
adversary modifies any garbled row he is
going to change the output wire label
computed on that gate this observation
leads us to a simpler hash construction
we can set the hash of the garbled
circuit to be the XOR of all the cipher
texts without having to use a
translation function and in the paper we
prove that this construction is secure
as per our definition under the same
assumptions we implemented our
construction using the Lib Carbon
library on a system that has a yes ni
integrated and this table shows numbers
in cycles per gate for gobbling the AES
circuit so the first column is our
construction and we compare it against
garbling a circuit and then using Shou
on it using the char from the OpenSSL
library and we note that our
construction is very close to the number
4 just garble just gobbling the circuit
itself coming to applications of our
free hash construction since our
construction satisfies a different
notion than that of collision resistance
let's look at the difference between
collision resistant hash and free hash
in the context of contentious protocols
so when using a collision resistant hash
a party p1 commits to a garbled circuit
by sending a hash and he can choose the
gobble circuit to either be a good
eating circuit and once the hash is
fixed he cannot flip between the two
designations when using free hash he
again has similar choices he can commit
to either a good or a cheating circuit
and cannot change this designation after
sending the hash but now in addition he
can do the following he can open both a
good and a cheating garbled circuit into
what we call a broken garbled circuit
which will fail evaluation and the
question is when can P to safely abort
when he sees a broken garbled circuit
and we observed that it is safe for
Peter to abort in protocols in the
covert security model where a party is
allowed to deviate from the protocol but
is caught with the fixed probability
called the deterrence factor this model
was introduced by Ullman and Linda and
further studied in subsequent works
so in these protocols are cheating p1
can already turn a good evaluation
circuit into a broken 1 and p2 can
safely about independently of his input
so we see that in protocols in the
covert model using the three hash
construction we can improve the
deterrence probability for the same
communication complexity and get an
improvement in the total execution time
for the same deterrence so here we
compare execution times we have the
total number of circuits required to
achieve a deterrence of 0.9 and to
compute the execution time we assume
that generating a garbled circuit takes
95 seconds for a billion gate circuit
and for communication we assume a 1 Gbps
channel and we see the improvement in
the second and fourth rows when using
our free hash construction in the covert
secure protocols so can we apply our
free hash construction to more general
maliciously secure protocols we note
that it does not apply to the
state-of-the-art protocol of Lyndell 13
and in general two protocols in the for
Gen loose technique that we saw in the
previous two talks this is because in
these protocols the cheating punishment
fails relies on at least one evaluation
circuit being good and
because p1 can open a good evaluation
circuit as a broken one when he uses the
free hash construction our p2 cannot
tell if a failure in decoding is because
of a hash failure or is a selector
failure attacker and this effectively
prevents input recovery it also does not
apply to protocols in the dual execution
setting because again a cheating p1 can
open all good evaluation circuits as
broken once and since the final output
is the result of an equality test or of
a private set intersection the output of
psi could potentially leak bits of PTO's
input nevertheless it can be used in
protocols that is based on majority
output and moreover when we use a
collision resistant hash and cut and
choose protocols the cost of a check
circuit is cheaper than the cost of an
evaluation circuit in terms of
communication and this results in an
optimal ratio of check and evaluation
circuits that is different from half and
we show this calculation in the paper
for a dual execution protocol it remains
to be seen whether our definition of
hash security applies to protocols in
the amortized settings also our
definition of hash security assumes that
the adversary outputs two different
garbled circuits but the topology
remains the same so we can ask if we can
make our constructions work when the
adversary can also change the topology
of the circuit I stop here thank you
[Applause]