thanks here for the introduction this is
joint work with dampen a you've always
shy and if it's a hot so in the last few
years in this thing we should be late
the office keishon has really emerged as
a central hub for cryptography we have
many amazing applications that you can
all build from a indistinguishability
obfuscation and some very simple
primitives and at a very high level in
it as you've seen from the previous
talks and in this thing we share bility
obfuscation allows you to take a program
and scramble it so that you can hide
secrets within the software itself and
that's it this has emerged as a very
powerful tool but we see if we take a
closer look at it what we end up seeing
is that there are very very big constant
factors so when you want to actually use
indistinguishability Association to
instantiate your favorite cryptographic
primitives you suddenly see polynomial
is this polynomial time algorithm
and yet the constant factors are
something like 2 to the 100 so we want
this primitive and yet it still seems
very far away from being concretely
realizable and let me just press this
here that when we look at the constant
factors as big as 2 to the 100 deploy
indistinguishability alpha station it's
not about an it's not an engineering
problem it's not just about finding more
efficient ways of computing these things
they're actually fundamental theoretical
challenges that we have to overcome in
order to make these things practically
realizable so our goal in this project
is quite ambitious we wanted to build an
office can find an office kitchen
complete primitive that suffice is for
obfuscating any arbitrary functionality
with good concrete efficiency bring io
into practice and what does that entail
well our goal is to identify a
functionality whose idealized alpha
station can be used for general
functionalities and moreover we want
this to be efficient namely if you want
to obfuscate an arbitrary program this
idealized functionality should only need
to be invoked once so it's sort of this
office kitchen complete primitive what's
the physis to obfuscate an arbitrary
program and our solution is going to
look at is going to be basically based
on the original bootstrapping
constructions for alpha station
namely our office creation complete
primitive consists of fhe decryption and
snort verification I'm going to get into
the details on each of these primitives
subsequently in a talk and as a
concurrent goal once we find our office
kitchen complete primitive it really
boils down to finding efficient
representations of these underlying
constructions mainly
OHE decription and snark verification
fully homomorphic encryption seems to be
pretty well understood at this point but
force not but an independent goal of
this work has also been looking at
finding snarks with efficient
verification processes that are amenable
to this existing office keishon
constructions so there are two two goals
of this project one is improving a
concrete efficiency of alpha station and
two and sort of as a by-product finding
more efficient smart constructions so
let me give you a sketch today of how we
build alpha station for general
functionalities there are three main
types of approaches and they all rely on
and all of these constructions rely
under on fundamentally on multi linear
Maps so the first kind of way of
building alpha station for general
Serkis relies on a beautiful
construction based on bootstrapping
introduced by Garth Gentry halevi
recovers the Heian waters in 2013 and a
starting point here is we begin with a
multi linear map and using multi linear
maps we actually build a weak class of
office station namely office km for log
depth circuits for MC wants their kids
or branching programs and then emit a
very nice work what we can do is we can
actually bootstrap and C 1 alpha station
through obfuscation for general circuits
I will describe this bootstrapping
transformation in greater detail in a
subsequent slides so this well it looks
like a very simple very natural very
nice clean clean framework and we
actually want to instantiate it and we
actually use it to obfuscate even a
simple functionality like an Aes or a
block cipher what we immediately see is
that we need a multi linear map capable
of supporting over 2 to the 100 levels
of multi linearity and publishing over 2
to the 100 including this is an
astronomical number and very very far
from something that we can practically
implement using modern computing
resources so that subsequent line of
work by Zimmerman and as well as
Appelbaum member Kirksey looked at
directly office gating circuits and this
sort of resolves the first the second
problem where we have to publish to to
the 100 and codings unfortunately due to
the noise growth in existing multi
linear map candidates the levels of
multi linearity required is still over 2
to the 100 and thus very very far from
concretely realizable in a recent line
of work initiated by Lin in 2016 we've
have now non blackbox constructions of
obfuscation so these are constructions
that rely only a constant degree mode
maths and this constant and the recent
work has been reduced to something as
low as three so you think just try
linear maps we can actually construct
office keishon however there is one big
caveat they require non black box use of
the underline multi linear map and if
you look at the internal details of
existing multi linear map constructions
they are really really complicated and
as a result non black box constructions
are going to present major hurdles in
terms of concrete implement ability so
the focus of this work will be on
constructing office keishon and making
use that make non-patent a black box use
of the underlying moti linear map and
we're going to focus on actually the
simplest or the original construction of
alpha station based on bootstrapping so
this is a suite a two-stage pipeline
where we start with some multi linear
Maps build off the station for branching
programs and then leverage alpha station
for branching programs to obtain
obfuscation for general circuits most of
the prior work in this area have focused
on improving the efficiency of the first
step of this pipeline namely the alpha
station for branching programs in this
work we're going to look at the second
stage of the pipeline and this is where
we're going to extract our alpha station
complete primitive let me just give you
a high-level summary of our main result
in on alpha station front to office gate
AES using our new construction we
require a multi linear map capable of
supporting about 4,000 levels of multi
Luminara T and if you look at it
compared to the existing work this is
many many orders of magnitude of
improvement we went from two to the 100
to roughly 2 to the 12th ok so let me
first remind you how we bootstrap alpha
station
what is our alpha station complete
primitive that we seek to build so to
office gate a circuit what we do is we
first encrypted using a fully
homomorphic encryption scheme now using
a fully homomorphic properties of the
underlying encryption scheme they in
valuator can holomorphic we compute the
circuit on any input of its choosing and
in doing so obtain an encryption of the
circuit evaluation now we need some way
of taking the encryption of the circuit
evaluation and extracting from it the
actual output so what we're going to do
is we're going to rely on our office
Kishin for branching programs and
publish a decryption circuit and in
particular an office keishon of the
decryption circuit that will implement
the fhe decryption now certainly we
can't give the app-v evaluator and
arbitrary decrypt
Oracle because otherwise the evaluator
can simply decrypt the circuit so what
we're going to require in addition is
that the evaluator provide a proof that
when it did circuit evaluation that the
ciphertext it obtains to be decrypted
should actually be one that was derived
from evaluating a program on an honestly
generated input and so the evaluator
includes a proof and lets the end of
bootstrapping algorithm will first check
the proof before decrypting so let's
look at concretely what the program
looks like that we need to office gate
it will contain embedded inside it a
decryption key for the underlying si
cheese scheme and maybe a CRS or some
other verification state use for the
proof verification process and a
functionality that we need to office
gate needs to do two things it needs to
verify a proof and of the proof it needs
to verify a proof and then it also needs
to decrypt the resulting cipher text so
if we look at what kind of Association
constructions we have today the ones
that we at least in this bootstrapping
construction they operate over branching
programs so when we actually want to
build this office creation complete
primitive we want something that can be
easily implemented by a branching
program and that complexity is generally
captured by the length of the branching
program so we need fhe decryption and
snark there and proof verification to be
implementable by simple small and short
branching programs and luckily for us
the existing works on lattice paste sha
schemes and all of these existing
constructions or in most of these
existing constructions at least
decryption can be implemented by a
rounded inner product which actually is
amenable to branching program based
computation so what what we really need
now is simply a way to verify these
proofs efficiently and that's where we
get to okay and that's where we get to
the need for snorts so first let me
remind you what it's nargis
so our overarching goal in improving the
concrete efficiency of alpha station is
building better snart's or better
branching program friendly succinct
non-interactive arguments okay so let me
remind you what that is extinct
non-interactive argument is so this is
also known as a snark because this is
three algorithms there's a set up
algorithm that takes the security
and ALP was a common reference string
and a verification state and then
there's the familiar proven verify
algorithms that takes an approver
algorithm takes in the CRS takes in a
statement and a witness outputs a proof
the very hot the verification algorithm
takes in this proof takes in a statement
and is possibly the verification state
and decides whether to accept or reject
a snark should satisfy the usual notions
of completeness and computational
soundness
but the important property is that it
should be succinct recall that the
office cater program needs to both take
as input the proof as well as verify the
proof so succinctness is paramount to
the success of this work so let's like
sing this property in a sec signal
interactive argument system stipulates
that the proof size and the runtime of
the verifier should all be poly
logarithmic in a running time of the
computation that's being verified or in
a case of circus satisfiability poly
logarithmic in the size of a circuit
more concretely what it means is that
the runtime of the verifier can be
polynomial in a security parameter the
length of a statement poly logarithmic
in a circuit size and similarly full of
proofs sighs so our main result in this
work I'm constructing more branching
program efficient snarks especially
tailored for bootstrapping office
station as we actually obtain new
designated verifier snarks with
qualitatively better properties that i
will summarize below so that designated
verifiers part of this statement means
that the verification station should be
secret and it's also in a pre-processing
model which allows us to basically have
a more expensive set up procedure so the
setup procedure that generates the crs
may not be super efficient it can be run
in time polynomial in a running time of
the computation or the circuit size but
well in this model what we achieve is
the first snark that simultaneously
satisfies what we call quasi optimal
succinctness
and quasi optimal prover complexity let
me briefly describe for you what I mean
by these terms when I state the
asymptotics for our start construction
these are going to be rough numbers or
complexity reported for achieving
negligible soundness error against
provers of bounded size of size two to
the lambda so when I say a proof system
is croisé satisfies quasi optimal
succinctness that means the length of
the proof should be quasi linear in a
security parameter so lambda times some
poly logarithmic terms when I say a
proof system is quasi off satisfies
quasi optimal prove our complexity what
I mean is that the amount of work that
the prover has to do to generate a proof
is only quasi
linear in the size of a circuit and does
not depend say linearly in a security
parameter so when most existing snart
constructions today and I will summarize
those at the end of the talk the
approver complexity or the approver
overhead will be linear or worst in a
security parameter snart would be quasi
optimal prover complexity if that
overhead is only poly logarithmic so we
give the first snart from any assumption
that actually simultaneously satisfies
both of these properties and as an
additional bonus because our Newton
start constructions are can be
instantiated based on lattice
assumptions they are plausibly resist
quantum attacks so we give post point of
secure snart's and they also work over
polynomial size fields which will be
very important when we look at the
concrete example of bootstrapping
obfuscation let me now describe for you
how our smart construction works our
starting point is a building these
process P processing snarks fields on a
very beautiful work by the Penske chiesa
di Ostrovsky and Pinette their
construction takes a two-step approach
first they begin with an information
theoretic primitive called a linear PCP
and they compile that through our two
rounds linear interactive proof system
then on half of the two round into the
linear interactive proof they provide a
cryptographic compiler namely linear on
the encryption that compiles it to a
pre-processing snark let me briefly
revisit for you some of the core
building blocks of this construction
first we have linear pcps first used in
a work by yaku Sheila Vaden Ostrovsky
and a linear PCP is just a long proof
vector and in a linear PCP model we have
a verifier and a verifier is basically
given access to a linear function and
what the verifier can do is you can
submit a query vector to the linear PCP
Oracle and the linear PCP Oracle is
simply going to compute the inner
product between the query and the proof
factor and if this can repeat several
times and at the end the verifier
decides whether to accept or reject the
proof
there are several concrete instantiation
of linear PCP based constructions based
either on a hot mr code or based on a
quadratic span program than quadratic
gators medic programs of Gennaro Gentry
Pardo and reco bot so oftentimes and
very importantly for our construction
the verifier is actually oblivious
namely live vet queries that the
verifier submits to the linear PCP
Oracle do not depend on a statement
being proved nor do they depend on the
previous responses
so what this means is that we can have
an equivalent view where the verifier
instead of submitting many vectors it
can pack all of its queries together in
a single query matrix where the columns
are precisely the queries that they
would have submitted to the linear PCP
Oracle and in this case the linear PCP
Oracle will compute the matrix vector
product now in order to go from linear
PCP is the pre-processing snarks the key
idea is that the oblivious verifier
would first commit to his queries
because his queries don't depend on a
statement being proved or the responses
of the previous results it can actually
just commit to these queries and publish
them as part of the CRS what the Honest
prover would then do is it would take
his statement in his witness it will
construct from it a linear PCP and then
it would simulate the operation of the
linear PCP Oracle namely it will compute
the matrix vector product and send to
the verifier now this is correct great
analogy but it doesn't quite work and
there are so many problems with this
basics construction so first of all the
malicious poober can actually choose the
proof based on knowledge of the queries
that we simply publish the queries in
the clear in the CRS this cannot
possibly work because the approver can
now choose this proof based on what
their verifier is going to check and
moreover the malicious provers not
really constrained to only a to only
evaluating linear functions the approver
can't do arbitrary things when
constructing is proof so we need some
way of addressing both of these problems
so for the first problem it's actually
very easy instead of publishing the
queries in the clear we're going to
encrypt them using additively
homomorphic encryption scheme so the
additive homomorphism allows the prover
to still compute the responses over the
encrypted query vectors and a verifier
at the end would be tripped the
encrypted proof that approver constructs
and then apply the underline linear PCP
verification procedure so it turns out
that the second problem is actually a
more severe one which is that the
malicious prover can actually apply
different linear functions or different
functions altogether to the different
components of the query matrix the way
that we address this and we're actually
going to make a cryptographic conjecture
this is the second step of a compilation
framework where we impose a
cryptographic two where we use crypto in
order to complete the transformation in
art where we rely on a new primitive we
call linear only vector encryption let
me briefly describe to you what a linear
only vector encryptions
so first a Vectra encryption scheme is
just a additively homomorphic encryption
scheme that where the plaintext space is
a vector space over some field or some
ring so instead of encrypting scalars we
encrypt vectors at a time and the
encryption scheme should be both
semantically secure as well as the
additively homomorphic namely it should
be possible given the encryptions of
many vectors to compute an encryption of
a linear combination of those vectors
the second part which is the important
property is the linear only property and
here we have a very we have a fairly
strong non falsifiable assumption which
basically states the following if we're
in any adversary is given access to a
collection of ciphertext and it's going
to down produce a ciphertext there
exists some extractor that can explain
the adversaries behavior namely the
extractor takes this input this
collection of cipher texts and it
outputs a linear combination such that
any ciphertext that the adversary
produces can be also derived by just
simply computing a linear combination on
the underlying plaintext factors so the
way that this works is the following so
in in our when we take our linear PCP we
take our query matrix and we're going to
encrypt each row of the query matrix
using our linear only letter encryption
scheme what and then once the prover
constructs a ciphertext well
linear only property is that whatever
the prover strategy is it can be
explained by taking a linear function of
the query sense of the of the queries
themselves and first this means that by
soundness of the underlying linear PCP
system again linearly bounded provers we
get a secure soundness of the resulting
snarky construction let me just briefly
compare with the framework of the towns
to get all so as I said earlier their
framework starts by taking a linear PCP
and a finding the first applying an
information theoretic construction where
they impose an additional consistency
check to force the prover to commit to a
to apply linear functions to the
different query vectors in our work we
we skip this step and give a direct
compilation from linear PCPs by making a
stronger cryptographic assumption mainly
linear only vector encryption that
balanced approver to only apply a
consistent linear functions through the
verifiers queries so how do we actually
instantiate this construction so what
are the main conjecture in this work
is that reggae phase encryption over the
standard lattices names and specifically
the variant YouTube PI curve I come to
math and waters it provide is a linear
only vector encryption scheme so let me
just show you how the decryption
functionality works because that's the
only part that really matters for the
application to alpha station so in a
decryption in a in the underlying
regular based encryption scheme it's
just computing a rounded inner product
the secret key is a matrix the
ciphertext is a single vector and a
decryption operation just confused the
inner product between the secret key
matrix and the cipher text and then
rounds to a small group small field
element and one way that you can see
this if you're familiar with regular
basis encryption is that each row is
essentially independent regular secret
key and there's one ciphertext vector
that encrypts the all of the entries of
the vector so once we actually take our
linear only vector encryption scheme and
and combine it with existing and known
linear PCP constructions we actually get
a free processing snark and here I give
you some concrete comparisons with other
constructions of snarks today so I think
the takeaway here is that using our new
compiler because it is gives a direct
compilation for linear pcps directly to
pre-processing snarks we actually obtain
the first quasi optimal snark if we
instantiate using a ring learning with
errors base assumption and moreover
because our new constructions actually
rely on lattice base assumptions well
all of the existing ones rely primarily
on pairing base assumptions these are
the first narc constructions that are
possibly post quantum resistant and at
the same time provide qualitatively an
asymptotically better performance in
terms of hoover complexity as well as
proof size so at the beginning of the
talk i presented to you the problem of
improving the concrete efficiency of
alpha station so let me conclude by
saying it by giving a few more remarks
so recall that to bootstrap alpha
station it suffice this to office kate a
program that implements fhe decryption
and snark verification using s existing
fhe encryption techniques and our nuke a
lattice based in our candidates we
obtain an office keishon complete
primitive that requires a multi linear
map and stat this of course 2 to the 12
the roughly 4,000 degrees mot linearity
and we requires publishing about 2 to
the 44 encodings these numbers are
fairly large but
and likely to not be feasible today but
they are much much better than a two to
the 100 needed in previous black box
instructions and we hope that future
work will continue to improve upon these
numbers and moreover by looking into
this problem of bootstrapping alpha
station it actually led us to
constructing better smart constructions
in particular our work gives of new
direct at a more direct framework of
building snart's directly from linear
PCBs and these yield both the first
quasi succinct and ER lattices as well
as the first quasi optimal start from
any assumption in our case from the
bring learnings with various problems
plus this linear only vector encryption
property let me conclude with the
several open problems all of the snart
constructions that I described here
based on lattices are only secretly
verifiable or namely they're in a
designated verifier model where the
sound is only holde and this if the
proof system to verify the proofs
requires knowledge of the secret
decryption key one important question is
whether we can do it in a publicly
verifiable snart's get an analogue of
pairing based us in our constructions
another question is find achieve a
stronger notion of quasi optimality so
at the beginning of the talk when I'd
introduced that our metric for assessing
the asymptotics of a smart construction
the goal was to achieve negligible sound
this error against who to the lambda
pound approvers
you can also stipulate that we should
try to achieve the stronger notion I've
actually to to the minus lambda
soundness against the same kind of
troopers and finally our new model space
nor candidates we should assess the
concrete efficiency of them because they
seem to be lighter weight they have
asymptotic these stronger properties
compared to the existing pairing based
candidates so we're in the process of
actually developing implementations of
these lattice based narcs and comparing
them against the existing pairing based
candidates and with that I'll take
questions thank you very much
thank you David so we have time for a
question or two yeah I have a question
about what do you mean by the quasi
optimal snug could you explain explain
sure
so quasi optimality consists of two
properties so first is quasi
succinctness which says to achieve
soundness that's negligible in a
security parameter against hoover's of
size two to the lambda what we want is
that the proof size is only quasi linear
in a security parameter and the second
property we want is that the prover
complexity so the amount of work it
takes to generate a proof that overhead
should only be poly logarithmic in the
security parameter so namely quasi
linear in a circuit size yes so that's
what our new slark constructions achieve
and is the first start from any
assumption that simultaneously achieves
both of these properties okay time for
one more question I have a small
question so like regarding the proof of
security so currently it's sort of like
strong assumptions right like virtual
black box it said for is there hope to
sort of you know base it on this thing
we should blow the obfuscation things
that we yeah so right now I would do
this construction as sort of a heuristic
construction of obfuscation so in terms
of basing it on indistinguishability
obfuscation I think that basic
bootstrapping construction is going to
be rather difficult to to make work in
terms of a security reduction because
relaxing from statistical soundness to
computational soundness will introduce
problems there so I think there's some
theoretical challenges after even making
a basic bootstrapping approach but maybe
with newer techniques we can do
something about that as well