right thanks everyone for being here so
the name of the game is learning with
arrows and lo and behold here is once
again learning with arrows so learning
with arrows goes back to the work of
already beg F and what you're given is a
tuple a C so where a is a matrix M by n
mod Q and your job as the adversary is
the site of a C is either uniform so C
is also a uniform vector or if C was
formed like shown on the slide so you
have a times S Plus e where e is small
and in this formulation which is the
old-school formulation kind of s is
uniform but as you might know there's a
normal form of lwe where you pick s also
from the same distribution as the error
e so you can also think of it as
somewhat small okay so a lobby is kind
of everywhere but for the purpose of
this talk I only care about two
applications in particular you can build
homomorphic encryption from lwe so for
example the bgv scheme which is
implemented in h e lip which is ibm's
homomorphic encryption library goes down
to lob e and the FV scheme which is
implemented in co version 2 which is
microsoft's on more encryption library
also relies on the hardness of the l ee
problem right so you want to kind of
look at Alawis if you want to convince
yourself that these libraries are secure
so what these libraries do and many
other construction come talk if you do
is they don't pick the secret as I've
just told you all right so the secret is
neither uniformly random nor does it
follow the normal form are either error
distribution in particular what H
ellipsis it chooses the secret such that
you have to guarantee typically you can
you can can change that but by default
or what do you kind of encourage to do
shall we product that is there 64
entries which are nonzero and so there -
101 and every other entry if in
dimension n regardless of dimension n
will be 0 so it's very sparse seal in
contrast pics the secret uniformly at
random from the set minus 1 0 and
right so it's not spaz but it's this
short and so the natural question to ask
at this point is how much security does
this cost right so we have this elder B
problem we have some understanding of
how hard is it to solve and then kind of
here we have an adaptation wait a
variant of it and natural question what
does it cost you any security or not if
you ask theory so if you want to have
some strong guarantees and you want to
look at reductions then the theory tells
you actually in order to achieve the
same security for your binary secret so
that's not even sparse it's just a
binary secret then you have to extend
the dimension to n log Q right so if
quite a bit of blow-up in the dimension
of your other B problem on the other
hand if you look at actual constructions
then this issue is typically simply
ignored right so normally kind of
security analyzed precedes by saying
we're going to pretend like this is a
Adobe normal form and then we're going
to kind of choose parameters based on
that because really you can't do much
better with the binary secrets right and
so again question which one is it okay
so let's look at how you would kind of
pick your parameters what kind of
attacks you would consider you can
roughly for these kind of schemes where
the dimension is very large it really
boils down to lattice attacks so
combinatory attacks don't really play a
role in this this world so you can
either mount a primal attack which means
you find some linear combinations of the
columns of a that gets you close to C
and then so you're solving the bounded
distance decoding problem as mentioned
in the previous talk the way you can do
this as either you run some enumeration
has just discussed or you embed your
problem into another lattice and then
solve some unique shortest vector
problem other approach you solve the
short integer solutions problem also
previously mentioned so you find a short
W such a W times a is 0 mod Q and then
when you take the inner product of your
W with C and C was indeed formed as I
shown you a at times
as plus e then you get an inner product
of w and e w short e is short in a
product a lot because in cryptography
inner product of two short things is
always short Thanks
okay so how do you execute that in more
detail you run some lattice reduction
and in this talk I'm only kind of going
to take a very high level view of
lattice reduction you you run lattice
reduction on this dual basis and then
you get a vector that has length Delta
naught to the M times the volume of the
lattice to power 1 over m and the volume
of the lattices that we construct here
is Q to the N so you end up with this
formula right so you construct this tool
to basis for the lattice you run your
lattice reduction algorithm and then you
check if these inner products are small
and then you will conclude this looks
like an lov instance or you conclude
otherwise and this Delta naught depends
on the lattice reduction algorithm so
the better the higher the block size the
more expensive the algorithm the
smallest Delta naught and this small of
this vector should be right okay so as
I've just described you you try to find
some short V and then you take the inner
product of V and E and you check that it
looks very much not like a uniform
distribution so there's clearly
trade-off here right the shorter your V
the better you can distinguish the end
in a product from uniform but also as
I've just mentioned the harder it is to
kind of actually get something this
small right so there's a trade-off
between running time and distinguishing
advantage and on the slide where I'm
plotting you for some particular
instance under some particular because
that cost model if you pick your
favorite cost model it wouldn't look too
much different then you see if I just
Inc decrease the distinguishing
advantage to say one over a thousand
then my cost in because that drops
rapidly right so for the first kind of
like going to maybe to the minus ten
kind of as been officially going maybe
to minus thirty kind of doesn't really
make much of a
isn't give me much of an advantage right
and of course kind of you're kind of
comparing two strange thing
right so two algorithms that have
different success probabilities so maybe
want to normalize right and so how would
you normalize is there like well okay I
can solve with low advantage for each of
my instance then I run my experiments
efficiently often to the majority vote
to still have some constant
distinguishing advantage we are having a
decision problem so you have to run this
roughly one over epsilon squared times
and then you end up with the plot that
looks something like that
and indeed kind of in each instance you
want to target maybe something to the
minus ten as your individual
distinguishing advantage right okay
brief word from our sponsor okay so the
discussion so far was was premised on
and there the plot that I've just shown
you was premised on the assumption that
if you want to have one over epsilon
squared short vectors you have to run
because that one over epsilon squared
times all right but this is not
necessarily true because right the kind
of outline that I gave you is like take
a random basis kind of D reduction take
the shortest vector that you found in
your new reduced basis and check if the
inner product is short but after we've
done all this kind of hard work of
getting a short basis why don't we kind
of start reran demising there and this
is indeed actually what what we do in
lattice reduction libraries when we do
this extreme pruning and we want to
reran demise you want to randomize in a
way it doesn't completely destroy all
the hard work you've done right so a
very simple heuristic approach is to say
let's take my basis L let's run that
reduction in block size beta and then
instead of kind of starting from scratch
each time I'm starting from this already
reduced basis I'm going to do some light
we randomized ation right some sparse
more unique modular matrix that we
randomized my basis and then I run some
big has that with some beta prime which
is may be smaller than Peter and I still
get something out that's okay right and
this whole thing is very heuristic in
very handy be all I have to offer you
some experimental evidence in blocks are
60 or 70 that tells us actually this is
this is more efficient than just doing
it from scratch and there clearly many
questions of kind of like how it does it
you know how does it really behave and
can you really argue that you get
something that's sufficiently random but
we can give you some empirical evidence
that it seems to be okay at least for
the instances that we looked at okay so
that brings down the cost somewhat right
so instead of running one over epsilon
squared because that instance in block
size beta you only run them in smaller
block sizes all right moving on now this
because boy I've told you so far really
has nothing to do with small secrets
right I promised you small secrets so
let's talk about some more secrets so
the first kind of observation is well
actually we don't need V times a is zero
right because the secret is also small
it's actually enough to find some V
times a such that W is also small right
so if you look at the normal form of the
dual attack then you have some x and y x
times a is congruent to Y and then if
you have something show up there and you
multiply through you get an inner
product of W with S which is short an
inner product of V and E both of which
are also short right so that's great and
then the next thing that you want to do
is S as I've just described it's
actually much shorter than E right so
you want to give the algorithm the
freedom to say like you know what you
get to pick a bigger w because we don't
need W of the same kind of quality as V
because we're multiplying it by
something that's smaller in the end
right and so if you do that then that
means you just scale a few columns of
your lattice and then you can go back to
some work by G by and Stephen Galbraith
where they did this for the primal
attack and this is just kind of applying
this trick to the dual attack right and
then what you end up with is some
constant times u W inner product s and
your V E and then if things are small
enough then you still win and the
advantage of the scaling is that this
has a kind of quite significant impact
on the determinant of your lattice which
in turn determines I can ever pick your
vectors right
so to figure out the C that also is
pretty straight forward right so you
just kind of try to balance the
contribution of the to fight and then
it's kind of some really trivial algebra
to get your constant C out and you're
done and in this
on the slide ages these passes of the
secret right so if you're only
multiplying it by sixty-four nonzero
entries then you can afford to each of
the things that you multiply with to be
a bit bigger gives you not adding up
anyway okay so this was on small secrets
let's talk about sparse secrets and here
the key point is okay so we're working
really hard to find a vector V such as
when I multiplied from the left by a I
get a zero but most of the columns are
completely irrelevant
they would they have they played no role
in the in the final result right because
s at that index is zero so I don't need
to do all this work right I don't need
to work really hard to make the linear
combinations zero if the thing doesn't
matter in the end right so let's just
ignore them like that's literally what
I'm going to propose you let's just
ignore some columns and so if you then
kind of think about well what is my
probability of success well I have to
mention n right so I have n bolts and
then each of them are nonzero right they
are unlucky ones and then I'm just kind
of sampling from these bolts without
putting them back and I ask myself
what's the probability of getting lucky
every single time and you're looking at
a hyper geometric distribution so it's
pretty straightforward to work out how
often can you guess and how much does it
how does it affect your success
probability right so you just ignore
some columns and then you solve the
smaller instance which is easier to
solve right smaller dimensional lattices
are easier to reduce and then if you got
lucky great kind of you have
distinguished the instance if you got
unlucky you have to do it again and of
course then your algorithm that you run
kind of 1 over P K times has to succeed
was sufficiently high probability so if
you can actually distinguish right and
so here's how this looks like and I
should mention like in my world vectors
kind of either column or row vectors
depending on what the dot product wants
from them so please excuse can if that
abuse of notation right so what I'm
trying to do is I do I want to find some
small vector V when multiplied by a I
get something 0 in
in the right-hand side of the column so
from index K to n minus 1 and then and
I'm asking myself to a get 0 and I get 0
whenever the first K entries of s in
this particular instance if they are 0
right so my V eclectic V makes all the
bilinear combination makes all the
components starting at K 0 and then
because as not to as K minus 1 is 0 by
assumption then that kind of zeroes out
the remainder right so I get lucky if I
have my eyes up to K if they are all 0
now let's look at what I get what
happens if I get unlucky right so mean
getting unlucky in the instance that I'm
looking at is either have a one day I
have a minus 1 there all right so let's
assume I have a 1 there well then the
final thing that I'm getting is actually
the my vector V inner product with a and
then I get this a naught naught prime
right which is just the inner product of
these guys so I still get some some
distribution that I can understand right
I have the small thing and it shifted by
something that I know right I know a
naught naught Prime and then I have
something small some small noise the
inner product of W and s and V and E
right so this suggests of you know some
form of post-processing I've done all my
kind of hard lattice production which is
really expensive and then instead of
just saying like oh no this thing
doesn't look small let me look for all
these shifts because that's a that's a
cheap thing to do so again you're
looking at some hyper geometric
distribution and now you're asking
myself is like ok I'm ignoring K minus J
columns and they're all 0 and J of them
actually I got unlucky right the
establishing the probability is easy and
that's how often you have to then kind
of repeat the experiments but now of
course this is much cheaper because you
run your laps reduction once and then
you do this really cheap kind of checks
you check for many different
distributions of course you want to make
sure that the advantage of
distinguishing is high enough so that
you know when you found the right one
because now you have to win against all
these other checks
so these are the three kind of fairly
straightforward ideas that I wants to
talk you about and so if you put
everything together we arrive at our
final algorithm which we call circuit so
the it's a variant of the dual attack
for small and spa secrets and here's
what it does so you run your big hazard
Peter reduction once and then you run
your because I'd meet her prime
reduction for some small pizza prime for
to produce many short vectors from all
the hard work you've done and then the
actual kind of dual attack that you run
you scale it kind of as inspired by she
by and Stephen Galbraith paper and then
finally if your secret Espace then you
play this game where you ignore some
components and you do this
post-processing if you to deal with kind
of getting unlucky all right and then so
putting everything together kind of
here's what you get so looking at seal
so this is I should stress this is C O
two point O so they the parameters were
updated in Co two point one so in C O
two point O the paper kind of contained
values for for log Q that should give
you 80 bits of security right so in all
these instances what you have is this
standard deviation of the noise is
always 3.2 and then right then
essentially if you want 80 bits of
security then the size of Q becomes a
function n right in the saying like well
you can go for Q up to forty seven point
five so to the forty seven point five
and you still have 80 bits of security
okay so for the same instance if we just
kind of using our kind of cost estimates
well how long does it actually take to
run that reduction then we get 83 bits
of security all right so this is kind of
our kind of cost model about kind of how
long does it take just one the dual
attack as it was described in 2009 or
earlier okay and then when you actually
start using the fact that you have small
secrets then you get this down to 68
alright so that's what they circle small
so small stands for we're using
the we're using the small secret but
we're not using this path secret sorry
and then a chillip right so the
difference between seal and a chillip is
that H eel abuses ASP our secret and so
you again kind of lock you is what you
would get kind of using the cost
estimates from the dealer paper and then
you exploit the sparsity could you get
this down to 61 bits and then you can
play the same game for 128 bits security
and the gap is even bigger all right
that's all I want to say thank you for
your attention
[Applause]
okay we do have some time for a few
questions
what does silica stand for
Thanks so it's as you do it's named
after a goddess of wisdom and wit but if
you are looking for a backronym then you
can take comfort in the fact that sis
beaker wlw all the letters are there and
then I'm sure we can work something out
of line of a cool name I can remind us
how many samples from the elder billet
problem do you need and how many samples
the hella panned she'll provide mm-hmm
so you can do it with one sample so one
ringer W sample so that's n LW samples
and this is what you get so there's no
like so this is assuming that using only
a number of samples that is provided by
the scheme
noise are not the same um do you have a
sense of how much savings you get from
each of these ideas yeah so we kind of
we we have a running example in the
paper where we spell this out and then
so to give you the overview like clearly
this fasting doesn't apply to Co right
so we can and so circa small only has
the amortize in costs and the the
scaling and the amortize in costs it
doesn't for these instances doesn't make
that much of a difference maybe five
bits so for this particular instance it
really is the scaling kind of it makes a
big difference it seems but for the
primary tack on the other hand know if
you run she's and Stephens algorithm on
these instance or you can you know you
run your estimator on that you get like
three bits so it really depends on kind
of where you apply and then will you get
up