okay so thank you for interaction so I
miss Asuma and I want to talk about
exact run diversity or become possible
to party computation so to work with
Gandhi okay so let me start from the
introduction and the sense it is work is
about the party competition let me first
introduce what it is so insecurity party
competition we consider two parties who
has a secret input and our Girija to
design a protocol that enables them to
compute a function on the secret input
and of course every coin the requirement
is that they can compute function
security so for example require that
they compute taken compute the function
correctly the function the input to
remain hidden or the feature the input
in the mentally opposite of the other
party okay
and the formally we define the security
of tea party computation by using
simulation pirata so we considered the
air world in which the function is
computed by a protocol and the we also
considered
idea world in which the function is
computed by a trusted party and we
define security by requiring requiring
that for any adversary in the ideal
world they exist a simulator in the
ideal world such that the idea was to me
detection simulate the view of that
ideal world adversary so this means that
we recorded that any attacks in the
other world can be simulated in the idea
world so this is this guarantee that the
real world had same rebel spirit as the
idea what and in this talk we consider a
tea party computation protocol that's at
far stronger notion of security called
concurrent security so in concurrent
guilty because the two parties will get
good many says from the protocol at
concurrently and after we also allow
them to execute a session with another
party okay so here to part it P 1p to
execute this recession concurrently and
Pt also you get to get a session with
another party history okay and the
concurrent security require that
security hold even the setting so in
particular we we require that the
shmitah
exist in this setting so clearly
concurrent security is more general than
the standard standard on security and
actually it is also more realistic
because they are networked correct
Internet Protocol indeed executing
however a drawback of a concurrent
security that is that it is hard to
obtain and in fact in the case of
security party competition it is known
that achieving a concurrent security in
the prime model is impossible so this
means that if we don't have any trustees
setup such as common reference string
then we cannot construct concurrently
security party computation ok because of
this impossibility many researcher has
tried to find a way to bypass this
possibility and in particular several
researchers have proposed an alternative
relaxed security definition on which
this impossibility doesn't work and in
this work we focus on what is it
furnished so namely we focus on economy
time simulation security or SPS security
ok so now what is XP security so USPS
cute-ass SPS security is actually almost
identical with standard simulation based
security but here we allow the simulator
to learn in polynomial time
ok so here the idea of our simulator is
much much stronger than the award of a
sorry so query security is weaker than
the standard Poornima time commercial
security but it is still guaranteeing
security in many cases and this is
because basically guarantees that any
attacks in the real world can be
simulated in the idea where instead of
all normal time so if idea where the
security insist upon a time adversary
then basically ganti meaning security
and indeed idea were secured by the
world in secure against against the
opponent Amada mastery such in many
cases such as when completing the
commitment functionality what would you
function
and in such a case is we can use a
security with no problem okay Sam let me
explain what is known about concurrent
state concurrent SPS secure two-party
computation and actually we also we
already have a lot of positive result
about the concurrent SPS to PC and in
particular it's a sympathetic grant
committee has been expressed extensively
studied so in fact for now we know that
we can construct constant lon concurrent
SSD HTPC understand assumption such a
drop-top annotation and the collision it
is hard function okay so regarding
asymptotic turn to pussy we know how to
achieve optimal rondo pretty understand
assumption so however even though
asymptotic grant of land the complexity
has been extensively studied its exact
run to publicity it is not very studied
so in fact previous works focus on
focuses only on a sympathetic grant
opacity and the depth is after on the
capacity of the protocol has large
constant such as the 20k and this is a
very in contrast to the standard setting
because in standard on setting exact run
the capacity is also very studied and we
already know that the only fibrin is
Optim optimal for for Cecchetti patty
computation so this means that regarding
exact around 50 days and see the graph
between the stand alone to security PC
and the concurrency KTP so motivated if
this this gap in this work will study
the problem of constructing concurrently
secured sp2 PC that has a good run to
complicity so in particular our goal is
cross the gap between the exact or on
the capacity or based on their own to PC
and comparing secured SP to B's okay
so now I'm ready to express a result so
what is our it's out so in this work we
show that we construct
five around the Tea Party computation
protocol that is secured and started
that's not ever compare it security in
the SPS setting so this means that we
show that even in the concurrent setting
the same we run the capacity at the
standard one is sufficient for obtaining
with a party computation and this
assumption we use in this work is a
standard cryptographic primitives that
you drop the permutation and the rows in
question and additionally we use three
random Arabic commitment that had that
satisfy some extract ability broke okay
and we know that from previous words
that sat in amarillo commitment can be
constructed from 12 a permutation that
is secured against that was poornamidham
adversary so our result can be based on
such a quasi hard to rob a permutation
okay and there are some remarks about
our it's out so first our protocol has a
fibrin in the setting that most party
get out of it and because the setting we
are only one party get out of it then we
can reduce run the copy further and in
particular wall protocol has only
foreign in such a setting annexed
currently our memories out because poor
clutch Poornima is harder while we
pumped a shoe because we need sri lankan
no moral commitment but if we increase
round capacity to seven then we can
remove such a cost point of hard
assumption and the word protocol can be
based on Pournami hard assumptions but
currently it is open whether we can
obtain vibrant assumption and the
finally are not that unlikely in
standard setting
currently we don't know whether a fiber
it's optimal for tea party competition
in the concurrent SP ascetic so but if
we use a strong assumption such as a sub
exposure hot assumption then this is a
five-round might be much might be
possible so this is also another open
question okay so in the reminder with
talk eirick spare it
so first of all I have to say that
unfortunately our TPC protocol it's a
quite complex and in particular I
produced based on a lot of primitives
such as copper sake drop the pump around
the argument proper bra so you know
eating orbit is primitive is already
hard so of course we cannot I cannot
explain or detail over here
so in this talk I only explain a
technique a informally and this work to
make protocol as simple as possible and
if we only consider a simplified setting
in which only one party get output and
each party get each party's lore has it
fixed in all the session okay so in
particular in this talk because there's
a setting that the P party p1 so in
particular because the setting that p1
get the output in all the session so and
in this setting a protocol has only four
round and after we don't need to use no
moral commitment in our protocol so
because the setting in which both party
get output we need to get one round we
need to we need to add the wound round
by using a standard technique and it
will be it was inaudible each party is
interchangeable then we need to add no
moral commitment to a porthole
but in this talk really good not this
issue so now let me explain our result
overall approach so from previous work
we know that we already have for round 2
party protocol in the standard sync
route set single output setting okay and
we also know that they exist a compiler
from standalone to party computation is
a concurrent OSP executed computation so
our overall approaches are quite
straightforward so we combine these two
result and we in fact we try to apply
the compiler
and concurrently speak to PC to the 400
T P Sundara pronto and however of
chryses we encounter a problem when
doing this and I will explain the main
difficulty from the next so let me first
because the concurrent SPS Trump IRA /
GG j s or Gargoyle Jane and Sahai okay
so the compiler of GG j s takes takes a
standard on to Semyon stupid computation
tied to PC and compared it by adding
dropped isettas face and witness
indistinguishable through hope knowledge
in which each party proves that they
behave honestly in the tea party
vocation part or they know the trap door
studying setup in the opposite oxide and
then the operator of gdgs works by
extracting trapdoor by brute force from
dropped a set of taste and give a bribe
proof by using trap to us so that it can
it can stimulate to be a part so
actually so just compare lb simulate a
compiler and the simulator which is yes
or military standard and so they are not
so difficult however what is difficult
in CGS is the show is indistinguishable
proof between the real world and idea
world so in particular since now because
the sip opponent time simulation the
simulator line is polynomial time so if
we can consider an IB reduction that in
turn area Mirage simulator such a
limited run is a polynomial time so we
cannot use that evidence to show that
indistinct BT between the real world and
idea world Sam
the key idea by ggs is to overcome this
problem by considering Pournami time
hybrid between the real world and the
hider so in particular they consider
hybrid experiment if it's the similar to
obtain trapdoor in
Poornima time by using a divining this
extraction rather than brute force
extraction okay then
by considering such hybrid we can first
show that idea worthy is
indistinguishable from hybrid and
because they the only difference between
them is a ha it's a way to extract
raptor and anyway we can show that the
same trapdoor is extracted in the hybrid
under inside the world okay and we can
also show that the dear word is
indistinguishable from hybrid and a key
point here is that the boss severe word
and hybrid run in polynomial time so we
can design it action in a standard way
okay so of course today's the there are
much more technique RT in the into
external proof but the most important
idea by JJ g TJ s is easy to consider
Poornima named hybrid between turn your
world and idea what cm let's consider
what will happen if we apply the
compiler which is yes to the stand
around for round 2 party protocol or the
cuts and
Ostrovsky okay oh okay so first I know
that actually designing a sip eponymous
numerator for the ko protocol is not so
difficult so the KO protocol transistor
Semyon is the standard tea party
protocol and contrasting and witnessing
distant proof on the thoroughness
argument and the - emulator work by
extracting a drop or two bitterness from
the WIPO for zero not using it argument
of knowledge property okay so we can
design the top or numerator by changing
by modifying the original simulator to
extract bitterness from table prove what
they're not argument by pure it was okay
so we can easily obtain the step up one
more time simulator what's a so however
even so we can easily obtain sit upon my
simulator we cannot show the distinguish
it in a straight off automatic in a
straightforward way okay so in
particular we encounter problem when
showing the indistinct parity between
the r-word and hybrid
let me explain what is the difficulty so
to see the difficulty let's consider
what will happen if we change the R word
into hybrid in a session by session
order and in particular because the
setting that the adversary is the
adversary is 32 and the two session
execute in this specific order okay and
what is important is this red part and
the other part is it has to illustrate
it in a simplified way okay so same
since we changed when we go into
hybridization Bicester order we first
simulate the session 1 and in particular
we change the witness in the WI proof
simulator two paths accomplish part
while extracting witness from the road
argument by X by dividing it rust around
okay and actually at this point no
problem Harper and the we can still show
that in distinction bility at this point
however a problem occur when we try to
simulate session 2 so in particular when
we divide the the right argument in
session 1 the WI proof in session 2 is
also rewind because they are the
executive combat way and because of it
is very rewarding
we can no longer use the bride property
orbital which is indistinct okay and
this is the problematic because if we
try to simulate the session we need to
change witness in the sub hypu so if we
can't use with Lucinda stickability here
we cannot show then this thing's
building so you might think that for
this specific example you can serve this
province in some way but in general this
problem is not so easy to call so and
accessory of what we want is the witness
in decision about prove knowledge just
satisfy some witness indistinct ability
and even weight is everyone okay and you
might think that we can use disagree
with indistinguishable proof here
because it will guarantee exactly this
kind of
indistinct bTW however since we also
require a pre-op Norwich property we
cannot use a resettable WI here in a
direct way okay so we solved this
problem by observing that we need to
change witness into the piper only on
the main threat okay so recall that what
we want is a witness indistinct is that
word almighty's we want so this means
that even if they the Ministry of
execution like this and the rapper who
is given in each set we need some kind
of meters in disc ability and our
observation is that if we change witness
in all the threat or the threat then we
need a digital table right but but for
you know setting actually we need to
change the Witten's only here only on
the main set and on the other that we
need to we don't need to change the
witness okay
and this this is the because we now
consider super pollinatarium pressure so
so idea so the idea here that doesn't do
to any rewarding so idea where doesn't
have any the idea world has already met
the main threat
so you are the words only the hybrid
user is rewinding so in hybrid or
computer simulation it needed only on
the main thread and we don't need to the
same ratio on the other set because I'll
say it is appear in the idea world okay
so what we actually want is the witness
in addition it is teachable proof of
knowledge that satisfy we chose
indistinguishability in this setting and
we we we construct such a which was
indistinguishable pro-hop knowledge by
combining with zap which satisfy which
is double WI and the extract of
commitment which satisfy X dot ability
okay so I want I won't say the detail of
this one so for if you are interesting
really see the paper okay and the many
menial a technicality in the proof and
each of them is not so significant but
but you know that but taking care of
each of them is not so easy so so you
need to pay special attention to this is
the technicality okay so this is summary
so the result is the fiber and
concurrent security but computation
protocol and what is important is is the
table in the conquer setting
we use the same run a pretty as a
stand-alone protocol okay so this
concludes my talk so thank you very much
[Applause]
we have time for one or two questions
what if you relax the three round to the
four round so you have a so yeah but
actually we need some kind of public
property also on no matter commitment
and a father know I know they to no
public coin 400 number II commitment if
you if we have them we can read up