all right so right so I'm gonna talk
about well the title the talk is
one-shot verifiably encryption from
lattices if you don't care about
verifiable encryption you're probably
not the only one so the talk is really
about zero knowledge proves but it has
applications to verifiable encryption
okay
so zero knowledge proof are well they're
important right so sort of the most
basic way to express that is you have
some relation some function f and f of s
equals TS is your secret F and T are
public and you want to prove that you
have knowledge of s in zero knowledge
right so for example discrete log you
know you have your generator G and your
your G to the S equals T for some secret
s you want to prove that you know s in
zero knowledge
so for lattice problems so that's what
you know it looks like for this great
Lud exponentiations flattest problems
are like sis and although Yi what you
want to do is a is to prove knowledge of
a short vector s so that F of s equals T
so here's an example alright so this is
the Syst problem i say yes so here the
function f is sort of defined by this
matrix a which around the matrix here
it's mod 17 so i'm given the matrix a
and a times s for some secret s which is
T and I want to prove in zero-knowledge
that I know this vector with small
coefficients so that a s equals T this
is this problem elderly problem is you
know very similar so people think
there's a difference there actually
isn't it's just the matrix has the ones
at the end so you want to you're given
some matrix a which one part of is
random one part is the identity and you
want to prove that you know a short
vector a times s equals some team all
right so these are the kinds of things
you want to prove in zero knowledge when
you're dealing with lattice
constructions so now I want to move from
you know now we will before the matrices
were over the integers I want to move to
polynomial ranks it's a little bit more
efficient and sort of our results mostly
applied to them they are more
interesting in that framework
so I'm gonna define a polynomial ring so
this ring R is just this polynomial zqx
so Z X mod X to the D plus 1 it's a
polynomial ring which is just
polynomials that have addition modulo Q
but also the multiplication you have you
reduced things mark you and also mod X
the D plus ones if you've you know seen
ideal idea lattices will always work
with the rings like that so here's just
I'm just rewriting the Syst problem over
the ring are now the matrices instead of
these guys being integers they are
elements in the ring they're just
polynomials in the ring so I want to
prove to you so given a and T and F
a-arrest
I want to prove to you that I know small
talk polynomials with small coefficients
so that a times s equals T ok so now
constructing zero knowledge proves right
so for discrete log relations we know
how to do this this is just the Schnoor
protocol right just a simple Sigma
protocol and can be made not
interactively at the theater of your
transformation
so for lattice schemes unfortunately
things become a lot more complicated and
the main obstacle is that we don't just
have to prove that this algebraic
relation that F of a equals T we have to
F of s equals T we really have to prove
that the the secret that we know has
small length and this causes sort of all
the problems that we have with zero
knowledge proof that lattices
so this is the sort of have some ways to
go around it right so this is the this
theorem here with the board's technique
so let's say you have a relation F of s
equals T the way you do it and you
really use the Fiat should be you use
the Sigma protocol framework with then
use Fiat ramier to make it non
interactive but there are some
differences so you generate this first
to generate this masking parameter
that's the intuition why is you generate
of masking parameter Y from some
distribution then you compute F of Y
that's your W you send that W so I'm
gonna do an interactive protocol first
you send your W and then the verifier
responds with a challenge C in the ring
and then the prover computes s times Z
plus y so without this sort of last
rejection sample
this should look exactly like snart
protocol if you're familiar with that so
now this rejection sampling becomes
necessary because you don't want Z to
leak information about s you'd never
have this problem with with discrete log
based things because your Y can just be
completely uniformly random and so Z is
going to be uniformly random and it's
okay but we can't do the same thing for
lattices because like I said we want to
prove knowledge of short solutions so
this better be short so then Y should be
short and then this you know he's gonna
leak some stuff unless you do rejection
sampling but this actually this is not
the the main point here but you can't do
it and then you end up the verifier ends
up checking that norm of Z is small and
this F of Z equals TC plus W so you need
this function f to be this module
homomorphism just like you need it for a
discrete log right you should have that
it should be linear so f of X plus F of
Y is f of X plus y and also for any
element C f of X times C should be f of
X C ok so if those two things are
satisfied you just get this relation and
it's everything's ok again just like
it's good so the proof the security
proof works as follows you it's just
rewinding then you the why is this proof
knowledge because you're rewind you send
different C prime the the prover sends a
different Z prime you recover a
different and now you have another
equation f of Z prime is T C prime plus
W you subtract and you end up of F of Z
minus Z prime equals T times u minus e
prime if you're working with discrete
log you're done you just divide by C
minus C Prime
unfortunately here with lattices you
cannot do this right so you can make it
non interactive via the future
interesting okay so in lattices you
can't just divide by C minus C Prime
first of all if the inverse may not
exist we're working over some ring not a
field but okay let's let's not worry
about that you can make sure it exists
the bigger problem is the quotient Z
minus D prime divided by C minus C prime
is gonna be there's no reason why it
should have small coefficients Z has
small coefficients C has small
coefficients what the quotient will not
so
that's the problem right okay so there's
two solutions one is say okay I don't
care I'm happy enough with this solution
I'm happy enough with extracting some F
of something small equals not quite T
but T times something small
maybe I'm happy enough with that okay
another possibility is say well and
let's say I'm not happy with that I
actually want F of something equals F or
something small equals T well then you
say okay well then choose your C and C
prime to be 0 or 1 in this case C minus
C prime is going to be 1 or minus 1 and
then you actually have the inverse of 1
minus 1 is just 1 minus 1 and so you
actually have F of something short
equals T but of course the problem with
this latter one is your soundness is
only 1/2 and you don't want to do that I
mean you don't always want to do that ok
so that we thought it was bad so
basically right like I said there's two
ways to do sort of zero knowledge proof
for lattices right so if you care about
practice when I say practical let's say
you know we say less than 20 kilobytes
per proof up you know per proof but you
know some numbers okay that's the
definition of practical let's define it
from now on that's okay so there's two
things you can try to do so this is the
proof that you get right you knew you
knew a relation F of s equals T and what
you can prove is that F of something
that's not quite as you know maybe
bigger than s equals T times this
difference of the challenges so what if
so like I said on the previous slide
there's two choices you can have you can
make sure that the C hat is one and then
your soundness is small or you say this
is good enough for my application I'm
happy with this so if you're happy with
this then you can get digital signatures
so this is how we get efficient digital
signatures and actually can get zero
knowledge proof of commitments but maybe
some others but you don't get a lot of
other stuff so actually very recently
this is a really nice work by first
Batman all of the Kramer at all showed
that okay you know if C is 0-1 you
can't you know the soundness is bad
unless you do amortization so if you
have many samples you want to prove they
have a nice technique that that allows
for fairly efficient according to this
definition of efficient proofs
when you can prove simultaneously many
relations so they do this if you
attribute with the boards but they add
some stuff to it to make sure amortize
complexities is slow is low so that's
quite good so that I think actually
Yvonne is giving this talk in the next
session of the other room it's nice and
so you can do that but the problem you
know what we don't have is sort of this
natural thing is I want soundness for
one sample right and so we don't have
this and my guess is we're not gonna
have it ever it just seems too hard so
there's also I should mention there's
also these Stern type lattice zero
knowledge proof so these are their
combinatorial and based on code based
this the code base turn signal
identification scheme which is related
related to Shamir's reputed kernels
scheme and it can be adapted to lattices
but it's it's horribly impractical I
mean proofs are much bigger than one
megabyte and I think from most practical
applications unless this is done once in
some protocol that's already very
inefficient then it's sort of we
shouldn't consider it relevant for
practical applications so I think the
main open problems are so if the domain
of C is large
can we have more applications you know
right now which you can just build
digital signatures and proof of
commitments oh and in this direction can
we decrease the number of required
samples because I think maybe even being
kind of generous with the ten thousand I
think you might you know to prove a lot
more than ten thousand samples before
amortization kicks in so I think these
are two very interesting sort of
research directions for lattice Paiste
renowned screws because it would be
great if we could get something that's
just as good as what we have in the
discrete log world but I really doubt
that this is gonna happen okay so now
since okay verifiable encryption was in
the title I should sort of explain a
little bit with why why
the title so well I'm okay but I won't
give the actual definition but here's
the scenario that we some time out for
some applications so you have a sender
and a receiver and then you have some
mediating Authority so this mediating
Authority does not ever want to be
bothered by anyone unless something
really serious has happened so what the
mediating Authority does is it publishes
a public key and says look here's my
public key do not bother me unless
something serious happen whatever you
want with my public key okay so then the
sender and the receiver have some
protocol that so the sender has some
secret witness W that X is in some
language okay and what he wants to do is
sent to the receiver a proof of
knowledge that W is a witness and also W
is a witness but the receiver is not
quite sure that he's the sender's gonna
be behaving properly you might do
something bad during the protocol so
what the receiver wants is for the
sender to actually encrypt this witness
under the median authorities public key
and also give the proof of knowledge
that the that C encrypts this witness so
basically if something bad happens if
this if the receiver decides that the
sender did something bad during the
protocol he can tell the mediating
authority please reveal W for me okay so
there are some applications for this but
this is sort of not the not the point of
the of the talk all right so and I don't
even care about sort of connecting you
know this this and statement let's just
concentrate on I give you a ciphertext
and a proof of knowledge that this
ciphertext encrypts some W okay so what
this really is is just the proof of
plaintext knowledge so I have an
encryption I want to prove to you that I
know that I know what you will decrypt
to okay so here's the ring of the
encryption scheme put in the form or
that's sort of a manobo to the zero
knowledge proves so the public key is
usually some polynomial a and some a s
plus C where s and E have small
coefficients the encryption of some well
W
what's called the MW is PTI is you just
multiply AR plus c1 and P times TR plus
c2 plus w okay so in terms of the
encryption in terms of matrices looks
like this right you can just stare a bit
then you convince yourself that this
matrix vector multiplication really does
sort of exactly describe the encryption
and to decrypt you just to V minus us
mark you might be that's not
particularly important but so the point
is if we want to prove that I know the
decryption I just have to prove to you
that I know that this consists of small
elements I prove so you have this public
you have this public key and the
ciphertext I want to prove to you that
this guy has the right randomness and
messages and they're all small okay so
now what can we do with approximate
proofs of knowledge right so we have
this I have this relation and I can
prove let's say I could prove to you
that well I don't know
a small vector vector small elements
such that this times the small vector is
the cipher text but what I do know is
that I know that this matrix times some
small vector is a perturbation of the
ciphertext multiplied by some C right
that's the C you get from the extraction
of the shinola proof of the of the Sigma
protocol right so the implication now is
like well you have this the implication
is that if you intuitive is that it's
not that you prove that you V is the
right ciphertext you prove that you V
times some C which no one knows is the
right ciphertext and this may not be
particularly useful right because the
Decrypter does not know C so if he's
going to decrypt he has to somehow he
actually cannot do it right because he
doesn't know the C which you only get
from extraction which is never run in
the real world okay so that's so this is
just to summarize if he decrypts he may
just get garbage because UV is not a
valid ciphertext right he gets UV and a
proof of knowledge that UV times some c
is a valid ciphertext but that's not
particularly useful for decrypting UV
all right so here is sort of our
solution to this problem right which may
not make too much sense like this okay
so the first
step is to guess the sea okay that's
okay whatever then you decrypt this UV
see and then you output the quotient W
divided by C at that you guys
okay so there's problems right guessing
the sea that seems unreasonable there
could be actually challenged space
squared possibilities because this C hat
is actually the difference of two
challenges so there's a lot of
possibilities for that secondly let's
say you even guess the right see how can
you be sure you guessed the right see
your decryption will give you something
you're like okay was that the right
answer right and you have to kind of
this two and three are the same problem
is this unique having decryption should
give you a unique solution so let me
handle the second the last two problems
first
so actually what we do is we modify the
parameters and the decryption algorithm
other of the bring a lovely scheme so
that the Decrypter now guesses the C hat
and then if he can check something he
does some check and if this check
whatever the norm of this whatever
equation that he computes is small
enough then he says ah that's correct
this is not garbage and I'm going to
output W divided by C W is whatever I
decrypt it divided by the C hat that I
checked and actually what we can prove
is if for any things that satisfy the
above condition this quotient will
always be the same so that in some sense
is your site is your plain text so the
in turn so this is one thing the
somewhat interesting part that leads to
weird the things is this guessing C
right the the problem is this challenge
space is too big okay so we don't solve
it you know it's super well but there is
a solution that that's good for many
applications
okay so first that's the first thing to
notice is that it's the ciphertext u in
V is valid so if the prove is completely
honest then for any C hat in particular
for C equals one this will lead to a
correct decryption on the other hand if
the ciphertext is invalid so the prover
is trying to cheat he did some
ciphertext which will not be decrypted
but he is trying to cheat and he you
know has a hope of succeeding this means
that there's gonna be some subset of
challenges that will really allow him to
come up with a valid proof right so
there's so he cannot just give your
company completely hope to prove a
completely around them ciphertext no he
has to hope he has to pick it in some
way that for some challenges he actually
will be to will be able to trick you
right so if so basically the C hat is
the difference of two challenges for
which he is successful and the encrypter
actually already knows one of these
challenges that's the one in the proof
so the Decrypter sorry it already knows
one of the challenges that's the one the
prover gave and the proof so now he has
to just guess one okay so this kind of
lowers the challenge space from
childhood's possibility for C hat from
challenge space squared to challenge
space ok still you know not great okay
so but those are the result that the
thing we can prove is that the
decryption time will actually depend on
the time it takes an adversary to fool
us so basically if the adversaries
allowed q queries to the random Oracle
then if T is the number of times we have
to guess C hat as the Decrypter then the
probability the T is bigger than K Q is
less than 1 over K so basically the
probability that T is bigger than you
know two Q's the probability I will need
to guess C more than 2 Q times is less
than 1/2 um so what the implication of
this is that the expected decryption
time depends on the number of random
Oracle queries the adversary makes so
this could be very problematic I mean we
don't want this you know this is not
what we always strive for right because
if the adversary is much more powerful
this is bad you know the answer may be
able to make a lot of queries and the
Decrypter is not too powerful right but
the thing is in many scenarios the power
of the adversary could be mitigated
right so so here's you know some ideas
that we had for how you can limit the
number of random Oracle cards by the
adversary so the first thing is what you
can do is make the adverse random Oracle
very very slow on purpose
so the ahh --mess prove err if the
prover is honest he just needs to make
one
query the verification only needs to
make one query decryption doesn't need
to make any queries so the only entity
that will ever need to more than one
query is an adversarial one so if you
make the random Oracle very slow it will
cost the adversary a lot of time to make
these random Oracle queries so you know
you can even make a random Oracle query
know five minutes low you know you want
seconds well then then you know this is
this could actually mitigate the
difference between the power of the
adversary versus the approver so another
possibility is you have an interactive
protocol or use public randomness
beacons so the verifier so the idea is
the verifier just if this is an
interactive protocol she should just
send a random salt to the prover
basically it's like send a random Oracle
to the prover so the prover could not do
any pre computation before it so you
really if there's a protocol running I
tell you use this random Oracle and then
he kind of has TIF he's gonna cheat he
really has to do it online this cheating
um and if you know there it's not
interactive then you can use a
randomness beacon you know by list for
example and you have to use the public
randomness at the time you submit the
proof right so that also restricts the
time you can have so this this other
suggestion right it's actually my code
Greg suggests that it's like you know
what if we just impose large fines for
cheating and AH you know at first of the
car you lived in Switzerland too long
and that's the this is the solution to
everything there but but you know let me
kind of think about it actually works
right I mean you know no one is people
just don't do anything bad there because
there's large fines and in some sense
this makes sense because the fact that
cheating occurred can be immediately
detected right so unless cheating will
you know do something so amazing for you
you're going to you know you're going to
sort of weigh the possibility of sort of
being detected you're detected
immediately you immediately detected
someone's cheating because somebody
tried to decrypt and it didn't work so
like okay now I have to cheat now I have
to guess the C's and you know and once I
guess the C's a large fine will be you
know imposed on you right even if I can
decrypt successfully
and so this is definitely in many
scenarios you know yeah unless you know
it's life and death the situation which
you know most the time it's not this is
a fairly good sort of way to Mitte to
make sure the adversary is not cheating
so another way you can do it you know if
you're really through maybe this really
is a life in that situation put a bound
on the maximum number of guests if you
want to put a bound on the maximum
number of guesses you can just make the
challenge space smaller but this
increases the proof size now you have to
do repetition right so if you want to do
to you know it's the expected number of
decryptions is still the same as before
but now it is an upper bound okay you
can do that and you can also a lot of
these applications require CCA security
and you can easily adapt our thing
because you just used no or Jung
approach and since we already have we
already have one encryption and a proof
you just need can add a second
encryption for you know just it's very
little cost so it's not a bad thing cuz
you already have is your knowledge proof
okay so I think the main I mean there's
a few open problems right still the main
problem I listed before is still kind of
open right what what more can we do with
this how can we do zero knowledge proof
for lattices better but I think an
interesting open problem is basically is
this lemma tight right so is it can you
really is this the best you could say
right maybe you can say the problem
could you say something like probability
that I need more than KQ queries is less
than maybe 1 over K squared right
so our proof is very black box we only
use the fact that there's a zero
knowledge proof but maybe you can use
some algebra because it's not clear to
us what exactly the attack would be of
an adversary or for a for any ring could
you come up with an attack that works
really well that actually where the
adversary can actually make this this
tight so a non black box approach you
know I think you would have to use some
algebraic properties of iron that could
be actually really really interesting I
think if you could decrease this to
something not sure you I mean it'd be
great if you can get this to be to get
this to be negligible but even getting
something like 1 over case
maybe you know just put some constant in
there it would still be quite quite
interesting with maybe lead to some nice
algebraic results so