thank you so the titles the original
title is extremely similar to the
previous talk so for a bit more clarity
as I said differences here we're talking
about in alternating and encrypting
quantum messages with recycling and so
authentication of quantum messages was
the first paper that discussed it was
this paper by a bow no metal in in 2002
and it's up to today still the most
interesting family of protocols for
quantum authentication you know
everything that came afterwards is some
special case of this family of a few
exceptions which I might mention at the
end if I have time made it really
remains the way of encrypting and
authenticating quantum messages so what
we do in this work is that we prove that
very similar to what search was doing
all the key can be recycled upon
accepting the message but here it's a
uniform key and we don't have the the
problems of non-uniform keys that self
had but this actually only works for a
subset of the original family hence the
we have the restriction and if I have
time at the end I'll explain why it
doesn't work for the entire family we
can also recycle part of the key upon
rejecting and you can prove that this is
optimal so all the bits which won't
recycle the address you actually can can
get them and this work we loaded using
the abstract and constructive framework
from our antenna so it's some kind of
composable security proof very similar
to the more familiar you see as just
some kind of simplification and general
a generalization of you see I won't go
too much into the framework just the
minimum so that you understands what
we're doing so Kimmy cycling is not
actually a quantum property the thing
which is quantum is that we can recycle
everything but in classification already
recycle key if we look at just a
standard classical authentication scheme
with the math we have a message and say
we regenerate the tag like this we apply
some hash function to the message and we
one-time pad this and and Alice sense
this if you can modify it
Bob just has a standard check this if
you received the right thing already
1981 the granite Carter mentioned this
and pointed out that we would need two
new K to each time but we can be used
the same k1 and the equation they give
is simply as well one time padding this
easier who observes the tag
she has no information about k1 and
therefore can be used that argument is
actually not completely correct because
when Bob accepts or rejects this is a
bit of information which Eve might
intercept and which might actually leaks
information about k1 so when you reuse
k1 again and again and gain each time a
little bit more information about k1 is
unique but it's very little you can
actually prove that it's it's a leak
limit still remains close to uniform
sort of proportional to the number of
times you use the the key which is some
something I I did some years ago some
years ago now if you look at a well an
authentic Channel what we're trying to
build is basically this Alice sends a
message which goes to Bob but Eve also
gets a copy and what's important about
this channel is that it cannot influence
the message you can sort of passively
read it but you cannot change it or
insert something to the channel now if
you think of doing this in the quantum
case and we change the message with Rho
and Allison's row Bob gets version and
it gets a version this of course cannot
work because there's this theorem which
is no cloning theorem which says the
quantum state can't be copied in so if
Bob actually sees Rho he knows that it
doesn't have a copy of it so you can't
there's no such thing as an authentic
channel which doesn't provide
confidentiality to in the content case
if I when you get or authenticity if
ever Bob can confirm really has the
message that Eve sent that Alice sent
then he knows that he doesn't have
anything so in the quantum case
authentication is actually something
strong and harder to achieve than an
encryption if you get authentication you
can't get encryption for free now
suppose we design a scheme in such way
that Bob actually verifies that he
receives the correct cipher note that
this is not the same thing as receiving
the correct message so it's some
slightly stronger requirement if Bob
receives the correct cipher so he
receives exactly what Alice sent when
they close to that then Eve hasn't no
information about the cipher at all and
in particular she has no information
about the key because the key is kind of
embedded in the cipher so is knows
nothing about the key and therefore the
key can be recycled so we need to kind
of sand all cloning going on here which
is the same principle as quantum key
distribution so it's not really
surprised that we can do this
so before telling you how to do this in
the quantum case I'm just going to go
over the classical case because we're
trying to construct a secure channel so
let's look at how we construct a secure
Channel in the classical case so I'm
going to do it in two parts well first
need to construct an authentic Channel
and then give me the authentic Channel
are going to construct a secure Channel
so I'm going to have these kind of
little pictures on all of my slides in
the next talk and the way you should
think of it is that it's your square
boxes represent some kind of resources
that a place you need in order to run
the protocol they're going to need a
secret key you can't do anything without
that they're looking at information
theoretic security so you can think of
them as having some kind of box which
gives a key to each player and they need
some way of communicating so they just
give them anything an insecure channel
which is the weakest kind of channel
possible whatever Alice puts in goes to
Eve and you can completely change it and
send something else to Bob so they have
these two resources and they're going to
run a standard Mac authentication
protocol so these boxes with little
round corners are simply local
operations that Alice and Bob can do it
there they interfaces so this if you
want this Alice's protocol she provides
it to the message it gets a key she
generates a tag you can change the tag
and on the other side Bob is going to
check if it's a valid tag and I'd accept
ex-prime or rejected so what we actually
want is to construct an authentic
Channel so what we would like is to
somehow argue that what we've done is
you just build an authentic Channel so
this is a bit more formal version of an
authentic channel whatever Alice puts in
it gets a copy and now you can actually
input a bit zero-one to decide if Bob is
going to get the message or not because
we the orphanage Channel had a few
slides ago it cannot be achieved because
you can always jumble a communication so
it always gets to decide if Alice if Bob
gets the message or not so in some sense
this represents some kind of bound on
what power we are willing to give Eva
willing to give eva copy of the message
and we're willing to allow her to decide
who gets it on if Bob gets the message
or not now we want to argue that this
somehow constructs this and if you look
at the Alice's interface the same as
here and Bob's interface at the same
structure using the facial looks
completely different because you have
our idealized interface in every
interface so to argue security we need
to find some kind of simulator here that
is going to construct the real interface
given access only to
to this idealized interface so if we
can't find such a simulator it means
this is certainly not more powerful than
giving more information to Eve that then
then what this does and now to argue
security what we want to say that this
system was constructed is
indistinguishable from this system so
indistinguishable just means you kind of
put a box around it and now we look we
have this sort of black box which can
take an input Europe uses now could take
an input produces an output and when we
give you one of either of these boxes to
someone it has to guess which one
they're holding so we're going to call
this sort of abstract payer
distinguisher given one of the two and
has to take a guess and output a bit so
and we look at just a difference to
public about putting one when you're
interacting with the first system with
the second system and that's the
advantage of the distinguisher so if no
distinguish I can guess what is holding
this or this with advantage more than
epsilon then we say the two systems I
just don't close and if these two
systems I've done closed and what we're
going to say is our protocol so this
part construct the authentic channel
given these resources so the abstract
capture framework really sees
cryptography as a resource theory you
start off with some resources and you
construct some new resources in this
case you started the keen and insecure
channel you construct an authentic
channel this is this sort of written in
English and this is the same kind of
using some some kind of formalism there
the protocol is a map between resources
so uses these resources it constructs
these resources and this is satisfied if
they existed simulator such that the two
systems I distinguish one this is just a
notation to try and capture the picture
so now we have an authentic channel
let's try and construct a secure channel
now we do the obvious thing it's a
one-time pad so suppose that Allison Bob
shared it's authentic Channel and it's
just one-time pads a message sends it on
the authentic channel and and Bob
inverse is the one-time pad on his side
so we want to argue that this constructs
a secure channel which is very similar
to the authentic Channel except that
here it only leaks the size of the
message we can never hide the message
entirely we always have to leave the
size or at least a bound on the size so
so where again we're willing to give Eve
bound on the size of the message and
we're willing to allow her to decide if
the messages received or not and now to
prove that this constructs that we need
to find a simulator which is trivial it
just as
two completely random string here and
you can show that these are they are
completely indistinguishable so now
we've constructed an authentic channel
and then in second set of constructive
super channel we can combine the two
steps so if you just take this picture
and we place the authentic channel by
the previous construction which I put
here in purple this is kind of imposed
construction and then we get on the
ideal side composed construction of the
simulator so these two parts of the okay
it's a little better this time so these
two parts we can view them as one
composed protocol which now uses these
two resources it uses two keys and uses
the insecure channel to construct a
secure channel so simply in this
notation we use these resources you
construct an authentic channel and if we
give it an authentic channel we can
construct a secure channel just the
composition of the two means the
composition of the two protocols uses
these resources to construct the secure
channel okay so this is one way you can
construct a secure channel classically
it isn't actually much help for us
because we used an authentic channel in
the middle which you can't do in a
quantum way so now I'm going to reverse
the order of the one-time pad and the
authentication so now let's start at the
one-time pad we have an insecure Channel
the message comes in we want I'm padded
we send it on the insecure Channel you
can change it and Bob undoes the
one-time pad so now what have we done
here we now have a weak resource and on
my previous slide what you actually
construct is a channel which looks like
this it gets no information about the
message except the size
because of course it's one time padded
here but now you can change it and
should only change it in very specific
ways you don't need to beat flips so you
can basically choose how the message
gets changed so to prove that this is
the case you have to find a simulator
that's the obvious thing it outputs a
completely bad sci-fi get sassy prime
here compute the x over 2 and these are
the bit flips if performed here so then
we do the same bit flips there cos bit
flips commute with the one-time pad so
then you can show that this protocol
either so the one-time pad given these
two E's it's mapped these two resources
to a I'm calling here an X or malleable
channel so now we have an extra manual
channel and we want to construct a
secure channel now an authentication
protocol won't do doesn't do it in a
generic generic way we know that
authenticate and encrypt is not the same
as encrypting authenticate so so how do
we do it to get a secure Channel well
the only thing you can do is bid fits so
we need to somehow detect bit flips so
what we do is we're going to encode X
into some Y using some code which is
going to detect bit flips so this is
just quickly introduce the notation
let's take a code a linear code CK and
then we we think of CK as being the
generating matrix but I'm kind of
patting it to make it square so we
basically take your message we add what
the seams long is going to be which is 0
if we're just trying to generate a code
word and we just multiply to this matrix
and we're going to get a valid codeword
so this is what alice is going to do she
just generates a codeword and sends it
on the channel and on Bob site is going
to decode so he applies inverse of the
matrix he's going to get some X Prime
and some syndrome s if the syndrome is 0
you're going to accept it and if the
easier to accept X Prime and if the
syndrome is different from 0 is going to
reject it so now we need codes which
have a certain property so every code is
going to either detect certain bit flips
or not detect them so we can I'm calling
FK the set of all the bit flips which
are detected by the code with index K so
this basically means if you encode it
you do your bit flip so I'm just writing
the bit flip here as a linear operator
and then you decode it you're going to
get back syndrome 0 these are the ones
they're not detected
so f of K is the set of errors which are
not detected by code K and we need a set
of code such that with high probability
over the K or ever detected with
probability one minus Epsilon so the
poverty of not detecting an error is at
most Epsilon so we can construct we can
find such families of codes and if we do
this well we can show that we just have
a small error epsilon when we're trying
to distinguish these two systems which
depends on the on these families of
codes this error it's just how well our
codes cover all the errors and so now we
compose our one-time pad with these
codes so I'm just skipping a few steps
here this is the protocol which as both
together it gets gets a key you checking
to split it in two parts the first part
we're going to encode it using some code
chosen by k1 and then we do a one-time
pad and then the decryption works in the
obvious way and if after decryption we
get a syndrome zero we accept it and if
you don't get a syndrome zero we output
an error so this is how we construct a
secure channel from an insecure channel
by reversing you also not doing
encrypting authenticate we're doing a
code then encrypt and it's a generic way
of constructing secure channel now still
in the classical case we can recycle key
when you look at what we've done here
we've one-time padded our cipher with
the key k2 and F okay one is completely
unknown so if you do this we can recycle
k1 but now the question is when do you
cycle k1 and this is an important point
if Alice recycles a key k1 too soon say
before Bob receives his cipher c-prime
she recycles k1 it might in another
application leak somehow to even even
get k1 and we'll know how to change the
cipher so the key can only be recycled
after bob has received C Prime so what
we're going to need is a backward
channel so that Bob confirms to Alice
that he has received a message this is
very similar to what assertion he did in
his previous protocol so now what so we
only have to modify the protocol in a
very simple way when Bob get to C prime
sends this bit of backwards confirmation
to Alice he can recycle k1
and upon receiving this bid at least can
recycle k-1 of course Bob Eve could
interrupt the authentic Channel which
means that Alice might not get k1 she
might just abort both like just get an
error and there's nothing we can do
about that this is a generic problem
with any key distribution scheme Eve can
always block one of the message so that
one of the case ends up with the key and
the other one doesn't so now what do we
get
well if we look at our video for the
call we have a message coming in and
message going out and you have a key
being produced so what we actually
construct are now two resources we
construct a secure channel and we
construct a secret key which is trying
to look a little messy but I'll try and
explain so it's a CPU just slightly
weaker than sweetie we have here because
we're giving a bit more power to Eve
first it gets to choose when they get
this tricky because they can only get
this wiki once Bob has received C Prime
and if choose when chooses when Bob gets
C prime so if chooses when they get the
secret key so I've just put this sort of
unary input here and the key will only
be generated once Eve allows it the
resource to generate the key and then of
course you can prevent a list I'm
getting a copy of the key
so now we can prove that the two
indistinguishable with some error
epsilon and basically what we have is
this this protocol given this key a
backward authentic Channel and insecure
channel constructs a new key resource
and a secure Channel and so this new key
resource cost anyway say a uniform so
now I nearly done we can move on to the
quantum case so I've just written a very
quick sort of dictionary of how we're
going from the classical to the quantum
case instead of having messages which
are strings are going to consider
messages to be density operators so
basically you can think of them as yeah
big matrices of complex numbers the
one-time pad in the classical case we
just X so every bit in the quantum case
you have to do bit flips and facelifts
so these are the power operators code in
the classical case we're just added with
syndrome 0 and we multiplied with our
linear matrix to get Y in the quantum
case we add a syndrome 0 we
apply our unitary which generates our
code in the classical case we had to
detect bit flips so we had a set FK and
we said the error is in FK if the code
cailletet failed to detect this bit flip
in the column case we're trying to
detect poly operators so we have a set
FK which contains the power operator if
the coded text fail to detect that that
poly operator we wanted a family such
that at high poverty we detect all the
errors we want a family such a try
probably to be detect all the errors the
cipher we generated by appending the
syndrome applying the code to doing a
one-time pad we append the syndrome we
apply the crowd you do the one-time pad
so really it's basically the same thing
but now comes the difference so we
encrypt as I just explained we decrypt
in the obvious way we end up measuring
we get a syndrome we get an error but
now if the error is 0
we recycle both parts instead of just
recycling k1 you can recycle k1 and k2
and that's really different to the
classical case we are we can also
recycle k2 and in the case of a reject
we can only recycled a 1 so in the
what's different here is what I've put
in purple in the real protocol on your
side they are either going to recycle so
case both k1 and k2 were kind of not
enough space to like k1 and k2 so k is
both or they just recycle k1 and here at
least will either recite ok
or just k1 or she's going to get an
error if if interrupts the back with
authentic channel and now what we get on
the side is if acute is very similar to
the previous one except that here if can
now input a bit which decides on the
length of the key because if decides if
she's going to put noise or not so she
basically decides if they're going to
get a a long key or just a short key and
then justice add a bit for form for
Alice deciding what else gets the key so
the main theorem basically says that
these two systems are indistinguishable
so the errors did if we have this our
codes of this palpable property that we
can catch all power levels with
probability all failed cache with
probably at most epsilon then we think
the two I distinguish with an error
which depends on episode
which is some square root of epsilon and
ya plus epsilon number two so this was
just some some parameters because the
here I've done this in a very abstract
way I just said we need a code now of
course they have in code which I've been
proposed in the literature which do this
the codes proposed by a band went all in
the paper from 2002 achieve this so we
need so our messages length M our
syndrome is length n we need n bits to
choose the code so it's actually very
compact family of codes and this is the
bit we're going to need for the one-time
pad and then we get an error which is
exponentially small in in the syndrome
so we can really just by changing the
number of bits or increasing the size of
the cipher which is getting errors
exponentially small and then we can also
do the unit hairy designs which will
quote which is allow a large or a family
of code then we get an error here which
is kind of a bit smaller and doesn't
depend on the factor M so lost lost
comment to make is I'm going back to the
original protocol because I said we only
prove security for subsets for their
protocols and here's the difference we
require this property that the poly
errors were all called accepted error
epsilon the original protocol has a
slightly weak requirement this is some
property you don't have a classical code
but you have for quantum codes they
exist errors which are not caught they
do not change the message basically
every switch to face lips on the
syndrome for people who know what that
is so if I'm going to call G of K these
errors which have no effect on the
message they did not require that the
focal areas which are not caught are
small they required that the errors
which are not caught and do not change
the message
a small which kind of makes sense
because the goal was that the message
doesn't get changed so if you ever
change doesn't change the message it's
okay we can accept it but an error which
doesn't change the message this only
guarantees that the message is not
changed it doesn't guarantee that the
cipher is not changed and we needed this
strong requirement that the cipher
should not be changed to be able to
recycle everything and we can actually
construct attacks on this larger set of
codes which prevent us from reciting all
the keys for example suppose there is a
code there's a scheme and the existing
signature which have been proposed to
tell this
that some error is roughly in half it
has no effect while half of the code and
it gets detected by the other half of
the codes so now say if does this error
on the message and then she looks
whether Bob accepts or not the the
message that you received
just this bit the Bob either accepts or
rejects is going to leak one bit of
information about the key which is used
because then Eve knows if it's a code
which actually detects this error or and
code which fails to detect this error so
if you go over other codes our second
authentication codes proposed in the
literature that I've picked out here
sort of the most common ones you have
the sine polynomial code which falls in
this category of the same structures
disclosed from barnum at all but it uses
q date so it uses some the dimension is
not 2 to some power the dimension is
some prime power so most likely the
proof goes through but we haven't
actually done it the Clifford code is a
special case of the code some bonhomie
it only goes through there are trap
codes have this sort of weekly testing
code property so we actually don't know
what can be recycled and there's
actually a very recent code recently
proposed to last year and we have
actually no idea of the key can be
recycled or not for that one thank you