okay thanks for the introduction it's a
pleasure to be here so okay so what was
the initial motivation of this work is
to try to think about long-term security
and to try to avoid computational
assumptions when it is possible and so
it's a quantum session so we know that
sometime with quantum mechanics we can
do things like for example quantum key
distribution but it's sometimes for
other primitives it's impossible like
information theoretically even with
quantum mechanics so another idea is to
use relativistic cryptography which is a
fancy name to say that we have to prove
our that cannot communicate so it was
first theoretical idea that kind of
emerged I think in the in the a in the
80s and we saw like multi prove our
interactive proofs and also like what we
can do with to prove earth in terms of
cryptography primitives for example in
terms of bit commitment or other stuff
primitive and there was a recent
resurgence of of this area and people
thought okay like because it was thought
to be something theoretical but you know
can we actually create physical
conditions in order to make sure that to
prove erskine not communicate and if yes
how and the main idea is to use the
relativistic constraint or just more
simply to say that if the approvers are
far apart then the information has to
take some time to go from one prover to
the other one and which has a high speed
limit of the speed of light that
information cannot travel faster than
the speed of light so that was the the
main idea and and so what were recent
result so there were a series of recent
results in relativistic cryptography
mostly dealing with bit commitment so
there was this first paper so there were
these first observations that if you
have to prove earth if you have these
two provers that cannot communicate if
you had quantum mechanics things can go
differently so there's paper from to
prove it in isolation that say that
sometimes even information theoretically
you can have proto
that are securing the classical setting
not in a quantum setting because they
share an entangled state and also there
has been constructions of bet commitment
schemes which are secured against
quantum adversaries and so our initial
motivation was can we use this bid
commitment scheme to do other stuff and
in today's talk I'll talk about how to
use bid commitment to do zero-knowledge
what are things that we know how to do
normally but in when you do this
reduction sometime you have issues so
here you have endow multi blue versed in
and the quantum setting and everything
so it's not clear how all these things
will compose well together and the main
technical contribution of this talk is
will actually be to analyze and improve
tool for analyzing the disturbs of
quantum measurements and how these tools
will be useful to improve the analysis
of security against quantum adversaries
so actually I spent a large part of my
talk of talking about these quantum
measurement problems because like there
are more generic so that will not talk
too much about like to prove ourselves
and talk a little bit about it at the
end and somehow that many people that
try to prove security of classical
protocols against quantum adversary's
can relate to so ok so before again like
being too vague I'll just start from one
simple example and then see from there
like what are the problems and what
solutions we bring in this paper so
suppose any kind of prove a verifier
scenario so here I took like a Sigma
protocol we have a proven that has a
public secret key to verify only has the
public key and the prover wants to
convince a verifier that he knows the
secret key without revealing it so it's
some kind of a proof of knowledge some
kind of a Sigma protocol just a message
a challenge first mentioned and the
second message so and in many cases the
security of those protocols are based on
some property called special soundness
is that if the prover can answer two
different challenges I'd say two
then this would be proved that he knows
the secret key and but what we do is
that okay so of course the very very
good scent well give to the proof of two
challenges I'll turn them answer those
two challenges but then the very shy
will also be able to extract that secret
key
so the verify will only send one
challenge and somehow this will be
enough to prove that the prover knows
the secret key without revealing any
information about the secret key so
these are something we know which are
quite known which are which are pre
which are pretty nice and so the
question is so there is this difference
between one challenge and to challenge
how do you go from one challenge to two
challenges well normally it's very
simple so you have an algorithm that
answers you know one challenge so if you
have two then you apply the algorithm
before the first challenge and then for
the second challenge and you get the
answer to both so somehow it's
relatively easy normally to to go from
one to two and what about the quantum
setting so okay so we do the same thing
we get a first challenge and we answer
and then we get a second challenge or
get the but at the same time but after
the first answering this first challenge
what happened is that the internal
quantum state has changed so somehow the
question is did answering the first
query made it impossible to answer the
second one and and it may complicate
answering the second challenge so this
is basically what most of the of the
technical part of paper delayed and what
I what I will talk about here so just to
get pictures so look at quantum
consecutive measurement so this is
exactly what I said so if you have an
internal state row you have a quantum
algorithm you have a first challenge c1
and an output 1 and if you're given a
second challenge then you're a new
internal state is Rho prime and if you
output and in many cases this Rho prime
can be very different from Rho and
somehow these things are kind
hard to control in in general so okay so
when does the thing work well so suppose
that you have only one valid good
outcome so you give a challenge and you
have one good answer and you get this
answer with high probability then we
know so there is this okay so there are
several ways of calling but one of them
is called a gentle measurement lemma is
that you can perform this measurement
only by modifying slightly this internal
state flow that somehow if your
measurement you're almost certain that
you're going to get a good answer of one
possible answer then you're not going to
change much but in many cases that's not
what's happening so so typically like if
you can answer the the first challenge
only with some not so high probability
or in particular the thing is that okay
let's say I'll always answer correctly
but it's one out of many possibilities
so let's say you know you have many good
answers and you're answering your first
challenge you'll just get one of them so
even if you always get one of the good
challenges then somehow this will have
disturbed the state a lot so you cannot
really like extract one of the good
answers without disturbing the state a
lot and this problem arises in many
problems of soundless analysis when you
look at simulation of zero knowledge if
you want to do I'm not even talking
about rewinding or if you kind of
witness extraction and in many cases
this this this is this is a problem and
so there there was a paper by a -
customization on who write from a few
years ago that truly said that in the
most general case this is a problem that
you cannot solve that you can find
algorithms and measurements so that you
can easily answer one of the two
challenge any challenges if if you get
one challenge but it's very hard to get
two of them so in the most general case
this is the this is really a problem and
we know how to construct
examples where this happens so okay and
so final thing is can we still do
something so okay so if the most general
case is problematic what are the cases
where we can still do something so just
a recap we want to relate two quantities
P one is the probability that if quantum
algorithm a given a challenge to get a
good answer and P 1/2 which is the
public output correctly on two different
challenges and so okay so here we'll
only consider for P 1/2 for strategies
that and when you get the two challenges
when you do this very nice strategy that
look at the first challenge you try to
answer then you get the second challenge
and you try to answer there might be
more clever ways of doing but that will
only let's say improve our results so
let's say that already with this very
naive strategy we have some interesting
results so ok so I'll I'll already show
what are the main theorems so first case
is as I said single good outcome so
let's say that for any challenge there's
a unique good answer and let's say the
challenge size is n n is the is is the
dimension of the challenge space so
meaning that login so log in bits so if
the challenge is of log n bits then we
can show that p12 is larger than this
quantity which is related to p1 so and
if we have as good outcomes if we have
as good solutions for each challenge
then we just lose a factor of s so okay
so then I little bit discuss like
quantitatively like what this means and
there was actually already one one bound
like there were several bounds for like
specific cases but let's say though I
think the most generic case was like
from paper by Luke was actually studying
like proof of knowledge so exactly here
that said that if p1 is larger than 1
over root K ok so case should be end
here then he has a bound which is
similar similar to to the first bell but
for this p1 which is not
so it this would be useful for p1 only
larger than one over root N and not one
over n and okay so just look okay so how
tight are those things okay so it's not
clear how to how to interpret those
bounds so in the single good outcome
let's let's look at this inequality
these are actually pretty tight so first
we see that if we take P 1 which is
large enough then we have P 1 2 which is
larger than some cube version of P 1
which was actually already the case and
you know that if P 1 is very large then
somehow we have P 1 2 which is larger
than the cube and we can't find states
and measurements so we can find setups
where this cube stays somehow so we have
no we have no hope in reducing this cube
to a square and on the second hand if we
take P 1 which is equal to 1 over N
which basically so this is kind of an
extremal case it kind of so you can
think of setups where let's say the
quantum algorithm can only answer to one
challenge one specific challenge that
would give him a probability of 1 over N
so this is this is why somehow we cannot
we cannot go below yeah I mean of course
yeah this this holds only for their way
it's negative so it's fine so and if P 1
equal 1 over and then we have also some
cases where this strategy will give P 1
to equal 0
so it's tight in those two settings so
somehow ok the 1 over 64 is probably not
tight what happens in the cube and what
happens in different behaviors it's
probably not tight in several ways but
at least in these extremal points we
know that we cannot improve so ok so it
was a very natural question so it was a
very natural question and so we hope
that we can use it in several things so
as I said in the proofs of knowledge and
like this small example that I showed
before more generally for a bounding
value of entangle games if that's if
that's your thing
and the original motivation of why we
why we started to study this was
relativistic zero knowledge for NP
secure against quantum adversary's and
so actually what happens is that once we
have this once we had this bound then
the rest was actually pretty pretty
straightforward at least for the for the
kind of security we wanted to prove
so not going into the technical details
of how it works but you know once we
have this then the the rest is fine and
yeah and then okay so now I'll just
spend spend a few minutes talking about
like this multi prove or scenario so
that you can see see a little bit like
where we use this thing so then we did
something very simple we had we know a
protocol for Hamiltonian cycle that we
know is your knowledge protocol for
Hamiltonian cycle that uses bit
commitment and we have a bit commitment
scheme so we just so we just put them
together and we see what happens right
that's a that's a very natural thing and
yeah so it results also just like a
quick note is that typically this would
not work for like for 3-coloring
typically is that like this because of
the reasons because a little bit of this
special soundness kind of issues is that
was only true with only two challenges
somehow the Hamiltonian cycle you only
have two challenges and you can recover
if you can answer both challenges you
can recover the whole cycle whereas in
3-coloring if you're only you know you
it gives you some information if you can
answer two challenges but you cannot
recover the whole coloring so then it's
not clear like what what to do
so okay so okay so here I okay so here I
just briefly mentioned like what are the
requirements okay this is all very
informal now of course but so what are
the requirements of a commitment scheme
so I want to commit for a bit D and so
there are two phases after the commit
phase we want that the verifier has no
information about D and that after the
reveal phase the prover cannot change
his mind so okay so what do we do so as
I said okay so now it's kind of the only
picture that kind of splits those two
provers is that okay so we start from
two so we start from p1 p2
okay they're very they're very very far
away okay
don't have to be very far away but let's
say you know like a few hundred thousand
kilometers and it's see that beforehand
you know they managed to so they they
have a secret they they have a secret a
they have a secret string a and we'll
always be working in some finite field
of dimension Q so all of these strings
will be of size log Q and then again the
verifier so if the two approvals are far
away and we won't like to have very like
sharp synchronization we cannot have one
verifier that talks to the two of them
and somehow I like have something
meaningful right otherwise we would give
more power to the verifier so we'll also
split the verifiers into two and do the
following so the first message the
verifier will send a random string b nfq
to the prover and she will send back y
equals a the secret plus b times d being
the query and d being the the bit so D
is in Jesus and zero one here but you
know it just the same multiplication and
the prover to will just send a and D and
then the two verifiers they will check
this thing but then you know after after
this provers and this message then let's
say the protocol is over and they can
check offline somehow you can a lot of
time can pass and you know you can check
that everything is valid somehow that's
the why and the ad everything
corresponds so and the only thing that
we require from this scheme is that we
could p2 to send this message before he
has any information about before any
information about B can travel to the
second prover so you know if if you're a
hundred you know if you're 300
kilometers away it takes a millisecond
so it's not you know which is not that
which is not that short you know it's in
in 2017 rights
unlike in 19 1918 so and okay so this
was so this is was kids
rescue rescue scheme which was like
proposed by lungsiet al and so they did
an analysis and you know so somehow they
reduced is this protocol to an entangled
game and we know that the protocol the
protocol is secure and the arguments are
in the end the arguments are a little
bit similar than these special these
consecutive measurements is that if the
p2 can answer both can can give two
openings one for D equals zero and one
for equal one that will satisfy those
two checking properties then you can
easily extract B which and B should be
hidden from p2 so this is the this is
the main thing okay this okay so this is
the textbook this is a textbook
Hamiltonian cycle zero knowledge
protocol for Hamiltonian cycle with
commitments okay they don't have a lot
of time so I will not go too deep into
this into this protocol you can read it
the only thing I want to say is that we
said first of all as I said before if
you have if you can answer the two
challenges and somehow you'll be able to
recreate the Hamiltonian cycle but
there's actually also a problem in this
in this protocol is that there are many
possible answers is that somehow there
is this hidden permutation pie in the
protocol and for each pie there is a
valid opening somehow so you have V
let's say if now M is the number of
vertices you have m factorial possible
possible answers so and we said that you
know you lose you lose the factor of 1
by m factor n factorial somewhere and
somehow will it will still work out so
somehow will just work on these very low
probabilities and we'll see how it works
so ok so again all of this is very
informal but just you know just trying
to show you how all these kind of
quantities go together as I said is that
ok if there's no Hamiltonian cycle
somehow you'll have to break the
commitment scheme and breaking the
commitment scheme as I said before it
will happen the from P 1 over Q
and so somehow this p12 somehow breaking
the commitment schemes when I say
meaning being able to have produced the
two openings so this p1 tool will be 1
over Q and if you want p1 to be smaller
than epsilon we need to take Q if we
know if you just plug this in the other
formula we need to take Q which is this
huge thing so if you think but is the
dimension of the thing so actually the
communication is a lot of this so log of
this is actually fine so as long as the
messages you sent our polynomial in the
number of vertices and in 1 over epsilon
then we can we can show the security of
this protocol so ok running late so I'm
just gonna you know this this is a quick
recap so which so just take bound for
consecutive measurements and we prove 0
knowledge and ok so what are the open
questions now so here the security we
prove is very basic so again so we had a
bit commitment scheme that we don't know
how to compose we want to use it for
zero knowledge so we had to redo the
whole thing from scratch somehow and
again then we have a zero knowledge
scheme and again if you want to use it
for something else we have to redo the
whole thing from scratch right another
thing which is kind of a bit surprising
is because we work on these low
probabilities this isn't even a proof of
knowledge so if you can so if you can
win this game we cannot show that you
can produce the cycle actually because
because of this factorial because of
this M factorial thing you can only show
that you can create this Hamiltonian
cycle of probably 1 over M factorial
which is not which is not great and also
like other primitives so also you say oh
well ok so these things work well so you
can use this bit commitment you know you
kind of you can you do it for something
else
typically oblivious transfer you say ok
and the quantum sitting you have a
reduction from bit commitment to
oblivious transfer so I say great let's
use it as well and actually here this is
a case where things don't work out very
well somehow because you have this bit
committment scheme that only work for a
certain amount of time and
no previous transfer you need some very
kind of static security for both players
somehow you can break those schemes and
of course like you know what are other
applications of the bound and I'll end
here thank you