I'm here by one and this walk is a joint
with my supervisor professor on pancetta
in our work we present in a tech on
misty one so some general checked about
it it is a block cipher that published
in design by Matsui in nineteen seven in
God several recognition shinzi it's got
recognition from the Japanese government
from the European NASA project and also
been accepted in is either standard it
most famous successful it called Kasumi
that is widely used in 3G cellular
communication we will return to it later
the structures of 61 is eight round by
state structure with 64-bit block and
128-bit key and it's one function is
called fo that is also a sale on fatty
structure the same is true for the run
function of f 0 it is also say wrong
fast a structure shortly the runt
function of misty one is a complex
function and if it it is not sufficient
the designer added one more function
called F L to make the structure even
more complex the FL function is a fine
simple function that applied every to
wound and it uses whitening layer the
fight of the complex structure several
attacks were published in the last year
in the first row you can see a text on
reduced valiant of the size l and in the
last two rows you can see
the first detect on the full misty 15
cipher we are published last year by
todo Todd of the techs are integrally
Tex that uses in you a new technique
todo invented called division pocketing
so let's start with integral ethics
integral text uses an integral
characteristics and what is that it is a
prediction that an equation all the
equations is called tech equation and it
predicts that the sum over some
intermediate values equals 0 in some bit
after iran's such a characteristic is
called island integral characteristic
and the full name is case of the
integral characteristic of around where
k is a log of the number of values
examine 8 ok what we do with a integral
characteristic so assume you found an
integral characteristic start with a set
of plastic swing which the corresponding
intimate via values some 20 after iran's
you encrypt the relevant plain text and
then you got some key bit so you can
check whether the tech equation old you
check if the tech equation odd and if
it's not you can discard this gigas ok
but how you found an integral
characteristic this is the question el
todo came up with nice technique that
uses what it's called division populi a
division property of a set s
is a partition of the space in our case
f 2 to the power n to two groups one is
all the used such that the sum of X to
the power of you covel all X in s equals
zero in the other set is all the other
views now start with a set of plaintext
that satisfy the division property and
check how the division property changes
through the encryption process if after
island is a set of good use contain at
least one new was coordinate some to two
or more then you get an integral
characteristic of islands total applied
is technique to misty one and found a
sixth-round integral characteristic
start after the first FL layer this
characteristic integral characteristic
is 2100 than the previous in best-known
characteristic and the tech equation
predicts that the sum of two to the 16
three specific values is zero in seven
bits of the input to FL seven this means
that if you get the relevant ciphertext
you need to the Crypt just so the last
round and FL seven to check whether the
tech equation odds and this
characteristic is used in todo x we use
the additional characteristic in a walk
the additional characteristic is a
modification of todo characteristics
both characteristics is looks the same
but while todo characteristics start at
the plane tech side I will collect wrist
so in the modified characteristic start
at the ciphertext slide looking at the
decryption direction the modified
characteristics starts after before the
last F a light layer and end after the
second round it will be a better picture
down on the same picture so both
characteristics look the same and the
question is what is the advantage of the
modified characteristic we think the
answer is one of the weaknesses of misty
one design and the answer is simple
there are common cubits in the first
town in F of 1 and FL one so less key
material is needed to guess for checking
whether the tech equation all ok but we
still have the first round and F L for
function to pass and the first round is
a complex function so let's start
simplifying starting with the FL
function the 30 bit FL function can be
divided to 16 two-bit function that
applied in parallel and there are they
are roughly the same function this is
give us the ability
to split the seven bit attack equation
into up to 71 bit equation and in
addition in some calculation can be
moved before I feel fall instead of
after FL for this is because FL is a
affine function so the calculation is
now in before a cell phone and we need
to deal with fo one for this we use it
until two of the main observation we use
it one of the version is we can ignore
some part of the key why because we some
oval and even number of values so a key
that involved linearly in the tech
equation is cancelled like k of four NK
I for one in the first and the second of
the observation is like this because of
the surround by state structure of the
misty one function the main calculation
can be splitted to separate calculation
for example calculate the seven leftmost
bit of the output of f 01 given its
input input can be done like this
calculate the contribution of the left
side and the right side of the input
separately and only the end joining them
together the picture is like this the
left side ball so f i1 and the right
side goes well soon if I to with feed
forward the left we
that is Excel of this tourism's okay
before moving the next section is
awfully to mention that the designer of
a consuming the successor of misty one
made a small changes to prevent this
witnessing the splitting of FL function
in misty one cannot be done in assuming
due to additional notation ill and here
as for the surround by state structure
in consuming the FI function is for one
feisty structure due to to this changes
and Adele no five or more round integral
characteristic is currently known in
kissimmee and for a section of
algorithms so in our work we use several
techniques one of them is partial sum as
presented by Parkinson a tell in two
thousand the main idea is to get the key
material in several steps instead of one
big guess first you get some of the key
bit then you partially the encrypt the
relevant value and finally you reduce by
somatic the number of value you have to
compute before moving the next steps the
next steps are similar you give some
monkey bits you will
encrypt and reduce the number of value
and so on and so on a second technique
is to dimension within the middle first
presented by the novotel in 2012 we
perform a meet in the middle attack
twice one we split the seven bit tech
equation tuto equation a 3-bit equation
and a 4-bit equation and compare the
common key this is this second we
modified each equation separately
instead of a check if a sum of values
equals zero we split the value to two
groups and check whether the sum over
one group equals the sum over the second
group ok
adding up all technic together we
achieve the following result to recover
the 14 9 qubits we need facing one is a
modified characteristics second we need
almost all the code book and say a time
of 2 to the 64 that is roughly the time
to decrypt the data the rest of the key
can be recovered in two ways one is just
exhaustive search that increase the time
to to to the 79 left-liberal way is to
use also todo original characteristic
for expert filtering this way the time
decrease under the two to the 17 but all
the day all the code book is required ok
to sum it we are significantly improve
the previous best known attack on the
full masti one cycle by a factor of 2 to
the 37 however I will attack is a not a
practical attack due to the amount of
data that require in addition our attack
doesn't walk again consuming in part
because the changes that made in its
design and that is the
you