okay thanks for the introduction hi
everyone so yeah so this is joint work
with with Amit and mark so if you've
been in this room today you probably
already know what IO is but let me let
me just say one slide about it anyway so
IO is this notion of of compiling a
program P in a way that preserves its
functionality but for any program P PI P
prime which is equivalent to it
the compilations of these two are
indistinguishable from each other hence
indistinguishability obfuscation so this
was first proposed by Barak at all in
2001 but the first candidate didn't come
until twelve years later on the work of
Gargan all hmm so at this point we have
many many applications of IO and it has
become a central hub of crypto a holy
grail of crypto whatever you want to
call it it's become a very important
thing and we have many candidates for it
but the security of these is not very
well understood right now okay so you
just sort of talk about multi linear
maps so indeed all of the i/o candidates
we have rely on multi linear maps you
can think of multilinear maps at a very
high level sort of like homomorphic
encryption in the sense that you have a
bunch of encoded elements and you can do
arithmetic on them the difference is
that in multilinear maps there's no
decryption instead we have this thing
called a zero test procedure and and you
can't zero test everything only certain
encodings that are well-formed can be
zero tested I'll say what well-formed
means when it becomes important so yeah
we have several M map candidates
tancredi's just talking about the the
last of these and in this talk I'm going
to focus on the the first of these which
was the original candidate due to guard
gentry and Halevi okay so I just
mentioned the zero testing so ideally in
these in these multi linear map
candidates zero test should just reveal
whether an encoding is zero or not and
that's it
but in practice all of the zero test
procedures actually reveal some sort of
leakage so you can you can visualize
this as follows you have some initial
set
in coatings you do some home amorphic
computation on them and you get a top
level encoding here a top level
well-formed it's the same thing and and
then you might feed that through the
zero test and indeed you will get out a
bit that says zero one but you also get
some some leakage and I'll say more what
that leakage looks like okay but let me
let me first tell you what our results
in this paper are so we give the first
polynomial time crypt analysis of
several i/o candidates and so this is a
distinguishing attack so we you know we
produce two equivalent programs and we
show how to distinguish their
obfuscation and in this paper we also
have an attack on the order revealing
encryption scheme due to Bonet at all
I'm not going to go into those details
because it's very similar to the attack
on i/o also in this paper we propose a
new security model which for the first
time actually captures all of the known
polynomial time attacks on ggh 13 and
I'll say more about the model at the
very end but just to give you a sense of
the high-level structure of the attack
is a very high level so we observed that
the leakage produced by zero test can be
represented or can be thought of as an
explicit polynomial which is computed
over the underlying multi linear map
variables so we you know we take the
obfuscation we evaluate it on many
inputs and 0 tests the result and
collect all the leakage and then we find
what's known as an annihilating
polynomial that basically that cancels
all of this leakage so it takes all of
the results of the leakage and you feed
it through this annihilating polynomial
and it spits out 0 if you had one of the
programs and if instead the Optio
obfuscation was of the other program
then the annihilating polynomial will
spit out something else so in this way
we get a distinguishing attack ok so
this is a let me this is the outline for
the rest of the talk first I'm going to
give a little bit of background on Io
and multilinear maps and then I'm going
to give an overview of the attack and
then finally I'll talk about the new
security model I mentioned and some
subsequent work that's already been done
regarding this model
okay so first of all the sort of model
of computation in this talk I'm going to
care about is what's called matrix
branching programs so there are many
candidates for 4io starting from matrix
branching programs there's also many
candidates for i/o a growing body that
start from just circuits I'm not going
to talk about the ones that start from
circuits at all I'm just gonna focus on
io4 matrix branching programs and this
is enough to to get i/o for all
polynomial time computation via some
bootstrapping theorems but I'm just
gonna focus on on branching programs so
a matrix branching program is is
basically a set of matrices that are
sorted into layers and then you have to
bookend vectors okay and each layer is
associated with some input bit okay so
that's it is just matrices and and two
vectors on the end and the way you
evaluate the matrix parenting program on
some input X so you always have the you
know the first book end and the last
book in vector there and then for the
middle ones you you just pick the matrix
that corresponds to the the value of the
bit that that you're reading right so if
x i1 was 0 then then the first one would
be this matrix and if x i2 was 1 then
you get this one and so on
so each input selects a subset of the
matrices and you and you multiply
through okay and in particular the
output of this function is 0 or 1
depending on whether this product is 0
or 1 right so we just care if it's 0 or
not not not what the actual value is
beyond that okay so what's the standard
recipe for fry Oh at this point most of
the matrix branching program io
candidates follow this recipe with some
different bells and whistles on on each
one but this is sort of the core
technique here so we start with the
branching programs I just described
first we randomized the matrices and
this is a two-step process
the first one is Killians technique
where you we sort of put these random
matrices between the layers
and multiply on on either side and and
then you also multiply with these
independent scalars where there's one
per matrix okay so you can see that this
doesn't change the functionality right
because these will cancel and the alphas
will not change something from zero to
nonzero so so randomizing that way
preserves the functionality and then the
second step is to encode each of these
matrices I skewing the each element of
each matrix in an M map scheme so again
I'm gonna focus on GG h13 but you can
think of in terms of you know I and I Oh
candidate you can think of the other the
other end maps as well and the only
important thing here is that this
encoding is done in a way such that I
can evaluate the branching program so
specifically each honest evaluation of
the encoded branching program gives you
an encoding that's well-formed which
means I can test if it's 0 or not so
that so this is all I was functionality
okay
so I want to have two slides on the ggh
13m map scheme so these these encoding
x' live in a ring of polynomials which
is this I believe the same ring as the
one time crate was talking about so this
is a ring of polynomial has mod some
cyclotomic polynomial and GG h13 has has
basically two sort of important classes
of secret parameters the most important
is is this parameter G and this defines
the the plaintext space okay so in
particular if you take the ideal
generated by G and you mod R by that
that's gonna be our plaintext space and
by choosing G appropriately you can show
that this is isomorphic to a prime field
so you can think of the plaintext space
as a prime field and then the other
important secret parameter is these the
Zi which are gonna define the level of
each encoding okay so what do you do
with these you have a value a plaintext
value and you want to encode it at some
level s and here the levels are going to
be a subset of 1 through K and note this
K here and this K here are the same okay
and to encode a at level s we we
put a in the numerator plus a small
multiple of G so we choose some small
randomness multiply it by G and add a to
it and then in the denominator we
multiply the Z is corresponding to to
the level okay and and we're doing all
of this mod Q where Q is some big
integer so we're taking the coefficients
mod Q and note that without that you
know this this division might not even
be well defined and in the ring are okay
good so so that was the sort of set up
for GG age 13 so how does the arithmetic
work so I'm not gonna I'll spare you the
technical details here but it's exactly
the same as what 10 Craig was saying you
can add at the same level and you can
multiply at walk' this part is a little
different you can multiply a disjoint
level so if you're if you're two levels
are disjoint sets then you can multiply
otherwise you're not allowed to and in
both cases the the new level is the is
the union of the operands level so if
you are adding at the same level you
just keep that same level otherwise you
take the union of the things that you're
multiplying okay and so this when you do
this the sort of randomness grows a
little bit but you can tolerate up to a
certain degree of the computation and
and specifically you can tolerate up to
degree K and again these parameters are
all chosen such that functionality is is
preserved okay so for zero testing what
does it look like so you have this zero
testing parameter which is this kind of
funny-looking thing here and you can see
the reason for it when you look at the
zero test procedure so the procedure is
just taken encoding of zero so note that
it's zero because I'm not adding
anything in the numerator here okay and
also crucially this encoding of zero is
at level K right it's at the top level
and I multiplied by the zero test
parameter disease cancel the G's cancel
and I'm left with R and then this value
H which is just a some small randomness
that we put in the zero test parameter
okay but the point here is that if
you've done this right these two things
are very small relative to the module is
Q right and if
not so if your encoding was not zero or
it was not at the top level then the
output would would have size roughly Q
so you can you can tell if something is
zero or not by checking if it's smaller
or not okay good so what are the attacks
that we know of on ggh 13 so there's
only three including the current work I
believe the first one is actually due to
ggh their team they they observed that
for some distributions on initial
encoding you can actually recover some
of the you can either recover some of
the secret parameters or some
information that you would hope to be
hidden so even in the first paper there
was already an observation that some of
these encoding czar attackable there was
a work by who and gia which attacked
specifically the key exchange protocol
so tenth-grade showed you an attack on
the key exchange protocol using G G H 15
who and gia have one using GG h 13 and
then in this work we would give an
attack on io but all of these works have
the same high level structure first you
start with a set of initial encoding and
you compute some top level zero
encodings using the allowed arithmetic
right though the add at the same level
multiplied two disjoint levels you then
zero test each top level zero encoding
and you you collect the the leakage and
then you perform some arithmetic on this
leakage to to recover an element in the
ideal G right so at the very beginning
when I was saying we're gonna cancel the
leakage this is really what canceling
means is it means you take these these
ring elements that are produced by the
zero test and you you do some arithmetic
over them to recover something in the
ideal G okay so that's the kind of
crucial step in each of these attacks
that element is then used in various
like application specific ways to to
break whatever you're looking at but
recovering the element recovering an
element of the ideal G is kind of the
the core step there okay so let me let
me say what our attack is so think of a
branching program in which every matrix
is the identity matrix okay so this is
probably the simplest branching program
you can think of and this computes the
Aussie
function if you if you choose the
bookend vectors right this computes the
all zeros function this is good for us
as an attacker because we can get as
many top-level zeros as we want by just
evaluating the branching program on on
any input okay so if we called it in GG
h13 the output of the zero test it for a
successful zero test right is this this
element H times the randomness R of the
of the top-level encoding okay so in our
attack the first thing that we do is we
sort of examine what is the structure of
that randomness and we write it we sort
of stratify by this variable G right so
we we write the randomness as everything
that's divisible by G Plus everything
else okay
and so what are these p1 and p2 these
are polynomials over the underlying
multi linear map variables so both over
the the input branching program but also
over all of the randomness that was
chosen by the multi linear map and right
we as the attacker we don't know what
those random values are but we do know
we can you know compute explicitly what
is the polynomial over those random
values that is output by the zero test
procedure okay so once we compute these
polynomials we then find this polynomial
Q and this is our annihilating
polynomial okay and what does it do it
has a property that if you evaluate Q on
the set of all these P ones times the
age it will output the zero polynomial
okay and if given such a Q it's easy to
observe that if I then just evaluate on
H times R this part is gonna go away and
I'm gonna be left with something that's
divisible by G which by definition is
something in the ideal G okay so that
that's kind of the structure of the
attack but saying it this way I'm
actually sweeping kind of all of the
hard stuff under the rug because the
core task is actually finding that
annihilating polynomial right so given a
set of polynomials where I'm calling p1
p1 are the goal is to compute an
annihilating polynomial Q that cancels
them all
right that that that evaluates to the
zero polynomial okay so in general this
is actually seems to be an intractable
problem and if you could solve this
problem in general it implies the
collapse of the polynomial time
hierarchy this is due to kya but you
know it's it's actually easy to see how
to break many crypto applications you
know if you if you could solve this task
right so that you know that seems bad
for us as the attacker but but it turns
out that our polynomials that we're
working with here are highly structured
and in fact they are also simplified by
the by the Cho of our choice of the the
identity matrix branching program but in
general these polynomials have roughly
the structure of iterated multiple
matrix multiplication which is a very
you know explicit well-defined
polynomial but still you know it has
many variables and we still don't know
just you know at first glance how to
find the annihilating polynomial for
that so our technique here is to use
change of variables basically so we take
these polynomials over the underlying
multi linear map variables and we apply
a series of changes of variables that
actually reduce the task to to
annihilating a constant number of
polynomials over a constant number of
variables okay and then we can we can
apply brute-force search which is what
we did and we find a polynomial Q which
so you know even though we're using
computer search here this polynomial Q
provably annihilates the the polynomials
that arise from the zero test procedure
okay so I'm gonna I'm leaving out the
technical details here they're they're a
little technical for this short talk but
I encourage you to look at the paper
it's not it's not that complicated when
you're sitting down looking at it okay
oops oh no oh I just stepped on my joke
okay yeah anyway right so okay so I just
mentioned how we how we recover an
element of the ideal G but we actually
want to distinguish the programs right
so for the second branching program we
choose almost the same thing except we
flipped some of the matrices to be this
reverse identity instead
standard identity this still computes
the all zeros function because this
thing is its own inverse so as long as
you're always multiplying an even number
of these it's still still the all zeros
function right which which is important
because we need to distinguish two
equivalent programs and we show that you
know in the same way that this
polynomial q dozen aisle eight the first
branching program it does not annihilate
the second okay and so if we repeat this
process many times we get many ring
elements that are either all in the
ideal G or they're not all in the ideal
G and then we can heuristic ly test this
with a Gaussian elimination I guess
because these are you can think of these
as lattices basically okay so so you
know by doing this we we distinguish the
programs right so we as the attacker
have one right but we're we're not
attackers where you know we're
cryptographers want to be secure and
this is really bad because we're not
we're not winning anymore right so we
need to do something about this and so
let's make confiscation great again I
wish I hadn't stepped on my joke there
but I did okay so I just have a few
minutes left let me let me say what we
can hope to do in the face of this okay
so how have we modeled multi linear maps
so far actually before I say that let me
let me say a quick caveat about the
about the attack
so our attack we don't know that it
breaks all of the candidate IO schemes
there are many schemes that we can break
with it but there are some that we can't
and in particularly the original
candidate we don't know how to break and
similarly candidates that sort of start
by converting a circuit from
Barrington's theorem we also don't know
how to break these but the point is that
for all of these candidates both the
ones that we have broken and the ones
that we haven't these are all proven
secure in this ideal multi linear map
model right so so even though you know
you have some candidates that are you
can prove secure in this model that we
don't know how to break we know that
this model is inadequate in fact we
already knew this for M maps in general
but we now know it for IO in particular
right there are i/o candidates that are
secure in this ideal model but which are
broken in the real world
so that's clearly a problem so what is
actually the problem with the model and
the the problem is that the model
assumes that the zero test just outputs
a bit right it kind of pretends that
this leakage is not there and so it
artificially prohibits this kind of
attack that uses this leakage okay and
so our solution is to provide a new weak
multi linear map model that actually
allows the adversary to perform these
post zero test computations ok so what
does the model do roughly basically the
model actually keeps track of the formal
polynomials over these underlying
variables throughout all of the encoding
so the standard model kind of just keeps
track of the ring element and basically
forgets how it got there right but but
this this new model keeps track of
exactly how each of these computations
were encoded or we're computed and the
key new feature of this model is that
when you do a zero test you actually get
back a pointer to that polynomial and
you can do some further arithmetic on it
and in this model we say that the
adversary wins if it finds some some
post zero test polynomial Q whose output
is the zero polynomial mod G so so Q is
evaluated on all these post zero test
polynomials and the adversary wins if it
if it gets something Maji which again
corresponds to something living in the
ideal G which as I mentioned all of the
attacks that we know of have to go
through this right so so this model
really captures a crucial part of each
of the attacks that we know of okay and
then in subsequent work there's been two
new i/o candidates in that are proven
secure in this weak multi linear map
model so there's there's the first one
is due to guard Mukherjee and sort of
asan and the second one is due to the
same authors of this paper and again
these are provably secure in this model
assuming a pseudo-random function in NC
one in in ours the assumption can may be
made slightly more general but again
this is a this is a you know standard
crypto assumption and so these are the
secure against all of the attacks that
we know of
against GG h13 okay so
I will I will conclude there and thank
you very much