Thank You bad for the introduction so
this talk is about constructing
authenticated encryption schemes from
trickable brookside so let me first give
you the context of this talk of his work
so the static starting point is the
ongoing Caesar competition for
authenticated encryption and more
precisely the three candidates geox is
Georgia can castle by the same team of
designers jenny.zhang mission college
and tomorrow and each of these
candidates is based on a dedicated
tweakable block cipher and two specific
modes of operation so the first one for
the nonce respecting setting which means
if you're not afraid that not will be
repeated you can use this mod which was
remote which was chosen was receiving
well the generic violent of with ocb
she's called TDI CB and for the nonce
peaceful setting they used a mode which
is called coba which has been designed
by andré Villa and there were some
problems with copper first it provides
only what is called online not misuse
resistance so I will not enter into the
details of what it is but this is not
the strongest nonce misuse resistant yet
that you can help and in bad caracas his
security definition is a bit
controversial so it has been some
problems also with some technique which
is called xls with copper used to to be
based on so which has been broken by
Nnanji so it has been fixed but still
there is diversity program of online us
bishops resistance and the designers
wanted to so find a new new mode so what
were the the requirements for for the
mode so first it had to be based on a
tricky bird rock cycle it has to offer
some fool what I could fully is the
strongest possible not misuse resistance
security notion possible at least up to
the birthday bound and if possible
to get beyond that the band security in
the nonce respecting setting so the
rationale behind that is that if you if
you use your your your mod without
repeat with repeating nonces you should
be able to use this property to to get
beyond both the resistance beyond
birthday band resistance and in case
something goes wrong with insist you
still retain some weaker weaker bound
but still a good bound to the reverse
alarm and if you look at existing mode
for turning a trick ever book satellite
into an authenticated encryption scheme
none of this mod satisfy these two
requirements at the same time so we have
to deci be which is perfectly secure
when knowns are not repeated which risk
which is completely insecure progress is
completely broken as soon as a single
knowns is reused once so there were
scope Abbott as I said it only provides
online not misuse resistance which is
not the strongest form we can helpful so
there is the candidate I easy which you
can recast as turning a trigger box
either into something even stronger than
unknowns misuse basis on schema name it
offers what is called robustness but
only in the only approved birthday bound
even when the nonce does not repeat and
finally there is a mode called protected
ID PIV so the problem with this mode so
it it achieved these two properties at
the same time that the problem is that
it requires a very long three clamps
which was not possible with deoxys and
jerky so the trick ever work suffers dog
this idiotic they have short quick short
weeks or the same size as the block size
and so please mod was not adequate for
for our goal so what we came with is a
new mode which is called SVG for
synthetic content week and this is a
month that i will dis right now so the
outline will be as follows so we use
generate composition so first i will
introduce the new a generic composition
met
that we use which is called n s IV and
which is very close to s ID and then I
will describe the two parts of the mod
the authentication part and the
encryption part so first some quick
definitions about to cable box hackers
and authenticated encryption so the
building block of foam which we are
starting is a true cable box after so
which is quite similar to a standard box
either so it takes a plaintext x + gk
but it takes also an additional input
which is correct week and which is here
to bring by ability to the block cipher
and the twitch is a typically assume
public or even control by the adversary
and from a security point of view each
trick should give a kind of an
independent permutation so you can turn
the are generic ways to turn a block
cipher into a kookaburra book cycle but
usually the security is only up to the
birthday bound for example here the XEX
construction and they are very few block
ciphers which has been which I've been
designed natively to be trickable so
there has been some early designs such
as has deepening cipher mercy three fish
which is the underlying the hash
function skin and since this is a
competition they have been more and more
designs of this kind of primitive so in
that garage just who do kiss advantage
but also in scream and ice cream and in
n alpha so this is our building block
and what we want to construct is what is
called unknowns based authenticated
encryption scheme and so what is this
scheme so it's a scheme which takes
actually unknowns n some associated data
which will only be authenticated not
encrypted and a message a which will be
encrypted and it returns a cycle taxi ok
and the decryption algorithm takes the
nonce the associated data and the cipher
and we turns either a message or some
symbol which indicates that the cipher
is in value ok and so typically the
nones should not be repeated but
time this is something that you cannot
assume so just one slide about how do
you define the security of such a scheme
so you consider an adversary which has
access to tools and encryption about her
in a decryption of occur and please
advise we must distinguish two worlds
the world where it has access to the
radar accounts and the world where it as
access to so the encryption of a girl is
replaced by something which returns
purely random bits of the adequate
length and the decryption or a girl is
replaced by something which always
reject ok and so we will say that the
adversary is not respecting if it never
repeats in ohms here in an encryption
cravat so what we want to achieve
typically in such schemes it what we
call not misuse resistance which
informally means that even if a nonce is
repeated in encryption Kirby's first it
should not harm authenticity and it
should hurt confidentiality only insofar
as a repetition of triplets n-am are
detectable so this is unavailable but we
see the only think that the only bad
thing that we want to happen so in fact
this is quite close to what's called
deterministic authenticated encryption
and notice that such schemes cannot be
online right because if you think about
it it's easy to see that each side a
text much much depend on every input bit
so you can do this you cannot achieve
the security nation with an online
scheme so now I will explain the
generate composition method that we use
in this news in this new mod which is
called nhie so generic composition
is just a way of taking my mac or a PRF
and an encryption scheme and to combine
them to obtain a nonce bay in on-base
authenticated and Richards encryption
schemes so you can encrypt Denmark and
quick n mark and so on and so forth and
before I go further it's important to to
have in mind that the syntax of the
encryption scheme is very important so
and in the one you had mainly two types
of encryption schemes we have what is
called i debase and quicker'n schemes
where the encryption function randomly
chooses andum IV for each encryption for
example in the CBC encryption and you
have what is called nonce based
encryption where the encryption scheme
takes an ounce which in the security
definition is chosen by the adversary
but should be non-repeating so for
example you have what we could you could
call nonce based controller which is
used for example in GCM and this is very
important what this in mind when you
consider generate composition so our
starting point was a mode which is
called SIV which has been proposed by
our way and fronting and which allows to
build a nonce miss Ruth misuse resistant
scheme so how does it work so you have a
PRF and an engine encryption scheme and
you first give you unknowns you're
associated data in your message to your
pseudo random function and please give
you a tag which will be used for a tent
city and this tag here will be converted
well you can forget about conversion you
can just usually take the tag and use it
at the ivy for an IV base encryption
scheme ok and you encrypt your message
with with your tag as I ok and please
give you your circle text so this SIV
construction get provides you in on
Smith use resistance up to the birthday
bound if you instantiate your salon
function a new encryption scheme with
birthday bound secure
constructions okay so it's a good
setting point but what if you want to
add beyond the sea bound security in the
nonce respecting case well actually for
the PRF it's it's quite easy in fact I
will explain in a few minutes out but
the main difficulty is how to obtain an
encryption scheme which is beyond
birthday bound secure when Nazis don't
repeat and actually if you think of it
what is hard is that the encryption
scheme doesn't take the nonce as input
so our only modification to SIV is to
reuse the nonce in the encryption scheme
right and will be used so we will be
able to to leverage on the non-repeating
perpetual announced to build an
unintentional so if you look now closer
at the encryption scheme now it's a bit
weird why because it takes both unknowns
and a random IV right which is quite
unusual and i actually i did not know
any encryption scheme which is built
like this for taking unknowns and random
a but actually it's quite easy to come
with a security definition for such a
scheme right cycle text must be in this
vision blurry from random assuming known
to not repeat and assuming the IV's
around online and actually when nan says
can can be repeated you recover the
standard notion of IV based encryption
or honest and so what is nice with this
construction is that you can prove that
if you're all your components are beyond
the stay secure when Nazis do not repeat
then you are you're authenticated
encryption scheme is beyond the secure
when one sees do not repeat and when one
sees drew a bit you get the security of
your two components when one sees it so
what what what we have to do now from
his generate composition method is to
build to our two components here so
first a PRF which is be secure when when
Don sees do not repeat and which is
secure up to the birthday bond when
Nancy's do a bit and an encryption
scheme which with the same
that is right so for the authentic
authentication part we design something
that we call encrypted parallel beckman
kappa so i will not spend too much time
on this on this design because this will
be the main topic of my this kind of
design will be the mentor because of the
savant or i will give in this session so
just to give you a very small idea of
what is going on in fact we first we
design a PRF of the nonce by withering
two independent permutations of the
notes please give us a beyond does they
secure PRF then we accelerate with some
kind of hash of the message some kind of
so this hash is very similar to what is
only in the pmac scheme so call it p
hash or the associated data and the
message so raphy is this part here gives
you a kind of vague mankatha match right
so this is secure beyond the birthday
bound when Nazis do not repeat and to
get non Smith use resistance we add an
extra encryption I are at the end okay
so I'm not entering into details and we
give more details later and so you can
prove that this design here is secure
beyond the birthday bound when Nancy's
do not repeat and up to the birthday
bound when Nancy stupid okay so the so
this was not so much innovative in fact
we just gather known techniques and
known schemes the what is more
interesting is how to design the
encryption part so this is what I will
explain now so we we explored many
design possibilities and we found out
that what was more convenient what to
start from a control each pod so a
control like might just mean that we we
do something with our trickable block
cipher which gives us a mask and we just
pick saw this mask with the message
rocks to give us
text okay so now the question is how do
we what do we give as inputs to our
trickable work later okay we have
unknowns we have an IV this IV will be
the starting value for the counters so
traditionally when you do a control mode
encryption you give the counters with
the initial value ie as input to the
message back of your block cipher right
so what we could do is so we still have
the tweak tweak input of the block
cipher what we could do is put the nonce
in the tweaking boot right the problem
is if we do that we don't have beyond
batleybound security even when Nancy's
do not repeat right because the others
we can simply do one curry with one
specific notes of sight of length 2 to
the N over 2 message blocks and here you
can just look for collision in the XOR
of the message box and the sack attack
blocks okay and please since the st.
weeks the same trick enters alway the
table that we have the two cable block
data we always have the same permutation
and so this will be distinguishable from
random because we won't see any
collision in the extra of messages and
cycle text okay so this does not work
and the simple idea to make it work is
just to switch the input to that this
means to encrypt the nuns and to put the
contours in the trick input of the two
cable block cipher okay and this is why
we call it a continent which encryption
money and the key observation here is
that when you do a controller the
encryption you want the mapping from the
counters to the to the masks to be a
function not a permutation because being
a permutation is exactly the property
that allows you to distinguish your
cipher text from on them okay and if we
put the counters in the tweak input well
the simple observation is that for an
ideal tweakable block cipher the mapping
from the trick to the cycle text is a
function it's not it has no reason to be
right so this is our design for for the
encryption part so let me just give you
a few I user for you prove that you Atia
of this construction in the first exam
so yeah further bound so so it's a bit
complicated but also n here if the block
length subnet to give a buceta see the
three clanks Sigma is the total number
of blocks in encryption queries and and
if the maximum number of non repetitions
so N equals one in the nonce respecting
setting yep so what we can see Percy
that when Nazis do not repeat this term
here vanishes and we we are left with
them which show that it is secure up to
the minimum of 2 to the n n n blocks and
2 to the n plus T blogs and 2 to the n
plus T other two blocks so assuming the
three clangs is big enough this is
beyond body secure and another
interesting property that security
degrades gracefully with maximum number
of nodes repetitions which means that if
you only only have two or three nodes
repetitions this term here it will
remain small ok you really have to
repeat not a lot of time to get a large
tail here ok but really I think it's an
interesting property of this asking so
how do you prove this bound so first
assume that the adversary never will be
Nazis in encryption keys and we want to
show that cycle text here are
indisputable for Amanda so so HIV so
each initial value here will determine
the seconds of tweaks which are used in
the GBC and an important parameter will
be for each tweak what I call the load
of the twix which is the number of time
the trick has been used throughout all
encryption queries ok and actually it's
quite easy to see that if you think
about what a trigger box icon is
actually it's easy to see that it is
really equivalent to trying to
wish each permutation associated to each
trick from a function so actually you
can prove that the advantage of the
adversary is upper bounded by the sum of
all the PRF PRP advantages for each
tweak with a number of queries which
ways which is equal to the number of
times to what I call the roll of the
twig which is the number of times the
trick has been used in the encryption
codes so now we have to just upper bound
is the maximum value of the of the load
of the trick and actually it's easy to
see that it is a simple balls into bins
problem you can think of each tweet
value as a bin and you can think of the
non sees as as the boars and for each
query the random IV which is chosen by
the encryption orica will determine in
which green I I start and then I put my
my board in the consecutive beans
according to the counters ok and so for
each nuns I will choose a random of
starting bin and put my my balls into it
ok and so this is not exactly a
classical boys into this program because
you you put usually you would put your
board independent here in the in the in
the bins but it's it's easy to see that
putting the balls in consecutive means
cannot help in fact in increasing the
maximum load of all the beans so
actually standard stronger bounds on
this program apply and this gives us the
final bound for the Contra for the photo
and secretive I will skip the what
happens in when Nancy's can can be
reused but it's quite easy to see that
you will have a problem only when the
same notes is we use twice for the same
tweak and it is it with you that it
gives you this parameter here in the
security bond which vanishes when
Nancy's cannot repeat so to computer
so I describe an authentication mode
encryption mud if when you combine these
two months using the NS IV composition
with method you get what we call the HCG
mods or synthetic control and twix so
synthetic here recalls from the edge
comes from the S IV mod okay because the
initial contour is computed as a PRF of
the nones the meds agent and the
associated data and so as I explained
this mod is beyond birthday secure when
Don sees do not repeat and it retains
does the one security in the non Smith
you sitting so actually it's it's quite
efficient so it's not online that you
cannot achieve this you should not miss
U's resistant online it's easy to
paralyze and it does not need the
decryption direction so it was quite
good so the final caveat is that about
instantiating the two cable box after if
you want to get beyond birthday security
when Nazis do not repeat you really need
to instantiate your blog site you go to
cable box either which something which
is beyond birthday secure which means
that you cannot use for example the
standard XD X generic construction can
you really need to use it ideally some
dedicated tweakable block cipher without
any known weakness so for example with
the exists and shortage it's ok because
these black cycles and these two cable
block ciphers have not been attacked now
but keep in mind that you must be
careful when instantiate don't forget
your black cipher increase in kismet ok
so that's it for me thanks thank you
very much