all right so hello everyone again we're
gonna start with my report which is on
the crypto 2016 puzzles solution and
prizes to selected winners so if you
didn't get your solution in by now I'm
about to reveal the solution if you
don't want to hear it
run outside for a couple minutes but
let's go through it so this was the
piece of the text that was included in
your packet that said use the gifts in
your registration packet to determine
the real security quotation and let's
talk about what it was that you received
first you got a t-shirt and this is the
back of the t-shirt and it has a number
of quotations on it and it has some
symbols at the beginning in the end of
each quotation and if you zoom in on
that you saw a little film strip that
was supposed to clue folks that these
were somehow film or movie related now
why are there a bunch of security themed
movie quotes on the back of your t-shirt
well because in addition to being
general chair of this conference I'm
also president the board of directors of
the Seattle International Film Festival
which is the largest film festival in
North America and runs for 25 days in
Seattle from late May to mid-june and if
you're ever in Seattle please come to
the film festival so I thought that a
filmer themed security themed puzzle was
appropriate and I should before I
proceed further acknowledge Josh Ben
ello Joshua I worked on this jointly and
with the two of us put this together for
all of you to enjoy so we deliver and
please kind of thank job ok
so there's movie quotes there is this
thing now called the internet so you
don't have to actually know all these
movies in your head but if you go and
look them up or happen to know them you
would find that the movies that these
floats came from often had a
security-related theme imitation game
ghostbusters didn't although it was
about containment sneakers hackers
inception Spaceballs and my personal
favorite Blade Runner which had to make
it into the puzzle now the second thing
on the shirt was that symbol down in the
lower right which was the picture of the
wine bottle highlighting the little
round thing in the lower right of the
label and then you got a wine bottle
with a custom label on it this is back
door red or backdoored wine and my
thanks to Michael Moniz of libertine
hotels in Toronto who did the graphic
design for me as a favor of the label
again Josh and I gave a basic design and
if you look at that symbol on the label
it says that which is a key to
understanding how to unlock the puzzle
it's a very simple substitution cipher
you take the key
you take the first letters of the films
and remember there was a hint that the
is an insignificant insignificant word
so you didn't look for the T in the
imitation game but the eye and when you
translate that you get theater which
completes the security should not be
confused with theater also a reference
back into film ok so that was the puzzle
we got 15 correct submissions I want to
acknowledge everybody on here who got a
correct submission Owen got and turned
it in by 4 o'clock I particularly want
to highlight shahe levees children Gil
and Sharon Halevi who got a solution
these are in order of submission so they
were they third correct solutions
and the youngest submitters okay now of
these 15 I have pry I have randomly
selected or excels random number
generator randomly and if you randomly
selected three people to win prize I
have real prizes up here for three of
these people and would marshal ball
jeremy jean and iran tremor please come
up to receive prizes for correctly
solving the puzzle
okay so they are identical so Iran there
you go congratulations Marshall there
you go congratulations
yeah there you go and congratulations to
all three of you you're most welcome I'm
glad you enjoyed it and with that that
concludes my report on the crypto 2016
puzzle thank you so I hope I hope the
prize winners and I enjoy their
backdoors to run a number generators
they're getting as prizes next on stage
is far prettiest partly get ready
there's too many people standing there's
an additional room in the multimedia
pavilion and if you don't if you don't
sit down then the Rome session will be
stopped by the fire marshals we really
don't want that to happen so please take
a seat or go to the overflow theater
thank you much okay so good evening its
traditional to start Rome session with a
report from the program chairs behind
the scenes on the submission and review
process
it's my pleasure to provide that for
crypto 2016 we received a new record so
in the spirit of the Olympic ramp
session we have a new record to report
282 submissions reduced to 275 after
withdraws we accepted 70 for the program
which represents roughly a 25%
acceptance rate and here we see the
historical acceptance rate over the last
24 years so we're back to the levels we
were seeing before the year 2000 crypto
now is getting up to around about a
thousand reviews and given that a paper
length can be up to 30 pages that's an
enormous amount of reviewing so we had a
very dedicated and hardworking program
committee that went through all of this
work so thank you to all of them we also
had 320 external reviewers involved so
many of you will be in this room thank
you very much for your contribution
again in the Olympic spirit we can call
out some nation contributions so there
were six countries that provided at
least 5% of the submissions France US
Israel China Japan and Germany and this
translated for us of 65 percent of the
submissions from these countries alone
translating into seventy one seventy one
percent of the final accepted
submissions in your program
of course there's different ways to
measure cryptographic productivity and
the gold medal for the best use of
available land mass goes to Singapore
with one paper for every 350 kilometres
square so the rump session marks the
halfway point of crypto 2016 so you're
probably already thinking about next
year and maybe making some submissions
so it's worth doing little data mining
to see what we might learn from this
year so the number of co-authors I've
presented here the acceptance rate for
papers with single offer papers here you
see it's very hard to get a single offer
paper accepted so congratulations to
those that achieve that and as we eye to
offers things get progressively better
you get a higher acceptance rate until
basically after four it drops off
probably a little bit too much partying
takes place so it seems a four is a good
number for the number of co-authors you
also want to think about your first
impressions the title because remember
the reviewers are going to make a bid
for your paper to review your paper so
it's probably interesting to look at how
you structure your title to the paper
and short and pithy certainly wins the
day so titles that could be
characterized as short and pithy had an
above-average acceptance rate of 30% now
what's interesting is that you don't
want to get caught in this kind of
no-man's land of middle length titles it
turns out if you just keep piling in the
words you can actually move on to
something that's not short or not at all
pithy and you'll find you have pretty
much the same acceptance rate at the end
of the day so it's short or long one of
the other what about some of the words
for there any interesting keywords so
the committee light
the following words in the title so a
green thumbs up means you go there means
papers or submissions with these words
in the title had an above average chance
of being accepted so practical efficient
and cryptanalysis the money word for
crypto 2016 there was applications I had
a very high acceptance rate so that's
kind of interesting for next year
perhaps on the other side which were the
words that didn't quite capture the
program committee's imagination well
somewhat controversially for a crypto
conference I think encryption will do
well and really quite disturbingly new
didn't do quite so well either so so
anyway so hi hindsight's a wonderful
thing and we can you know constructs
what would have been an ideal title for
crypto 2016 oh I forgot I'm so sorry
let me go on some people like to
punctuate their title makes it a bit
more interesting a bit more subtle a bit
more considered so the committee like
parentheses now get a little thumbs up
there so above-average acceptance rate
the committee went bananas over colons
colons were very popular but the
question mark may be it implies a little
indecision or something for some reason
that didn't quite capture the
imagination that program committee so
bringing all this together we can come
up with what would it be in the ideal
crypto of 2016 title as I say with
hindsight and this would have been a
good title efficient cryptanalysis : no
practical in parentheses applications
are secure and it would of course have
been by for for authors so I'm the one
talking but crypto relies on the
contributions of many so a big thank you
to John and Brian my program co-chairs
and Brian the general chair pleasure to
work with you the excellent hard-working
program committee all the soup reviewers
and most importantly everyone who
submitted to crypto 2016 and I hope you
enjoy the ROM session
okay so next up we have something about
Fung Shui by somebody called Barney and
Nigel smart come to the stage please and
can somebody bring me a beer that would
be really appreciated
so unsurprisingly his favorite
discipline is never throwing well this
is a plug for a UNIX paper but clearly
this title would never made it to crypto
so there is in fact way too many authors
and that the team into it actually was
indeed hammer throw because I was
thinking of field hockey today actually
the devlins meat was written by Belgium
in field hockey so I guess my time would
have rejected my paper if I did so I
didn't take any risks there so it's a
very confusing title where many authors
will each choice of words and then we
put it together and somehow it goes into
use next so what we do we really do okay
this
we broke RSA in the cloud so how does it
work
use some very simple ideas and some
simple crypto machinery but very clever
software stuff don't mind court we have
the University of Amsterdam so we used
actually two basic building blocks one
is row hammer and I hope you all know
that Kenny is Scottish so I knew you
actually would accept this paper with
those beautiful pictures of Scottish
people so
rahama is a very cool trick in which you
can actually flip bits in the RAM as a
consequence of higher densities in the
RAM by reading repeatedly at jaikant
drops so you never have to write in the
memory you just read aloud then some
moment you flip bits in the middle row
so now you already understand why there
is flip in the title and why there is
hammering the title and why I chose the
hammer through okay so it's a bit tricky
to find out actually if you're in the
clout which bits flip and practical guys
from our team they spend about ten
minutes of effort to find one bit flip
that works so this is why we don't use
hundred and have a sub bit flips and you
can't completely control the location
next thing is memory the duplication so
what happens in the cloud you actually
can rent your machines with the cloud
providers and actually they try to be
efficient and using this and attack I
can actually map the physical memory
page of the victim virtual machine you
attack a project address space the
scenario is that somebody has a cloud
instance which you want to attack so you
actually also make a cloud instance and
then from your cart it's you're going to
attack the keys of the other copy and
how do you do it based on duplication
and the function we part is because we
have to neatly arranged memory in a
harmonic way to actually get to do it
and this is a crazy thing to be part of
the part so how does it work is very
simple you have this blue virtual
machine you have the victim so you host
have the victim having this machine the
attacker having this machine and so if
each has their own physical memory at
about and so what you do is in attacker
is you put content in your virtual
machine which likely the attacker will
also have can be a list of keys that's
public public keys of course or maybe
some other things in this case the pick
and so what will happen in the cloud is
actually that the plug will want to be
efficient what they will do is they will
actually spot the duplication
it will save memory and put it together
with pointers the next thing is if you
again start flipping bits in your
virtual machine using pro hammer what
will happen in the physical memory it
will be updated and you actually now
flip the memory out of the victim
without doing anything you don't have to
violate any of the access control rules
of the cloud you actually go to the
software stack with your needle and you
flip the bits so what can you do in
practice somebody is running OpenSSH in
this cloud instance you start Asus a
session with the wrong key doesn't
matter what the victim will do is read
Auto ASCII file with an RSA modulus you
now do your o hammer mid flip and you
look a bit of the modulus so it's no
longer an RSA modulus is now a random
integer of 4,000 bits that turns out to
be easy to factor so the method we use
for elliptic curve if the core
factorization depends on the second
largest prime factor and there is good
statistics about this we know that on
average it's about 20% of the size of
the modulus so and if you're lucky of
course it's even much smaller that's it
more or less we used stammered tool this
wrong sport I guess but ok so that
before with module II you can see we can
factor almost all of them with 10 bit
flips what we used was about one hour
time on a big cluster for gigabyte RAM
then we stopped if we abandoned if they
couldn't make that got 48 bit we can do
more or less but we still get very close
to all of them with 30 bit flips and
then 50 bit flips we got up to 80% of
all 4096 bit modulation and of course
was tried on real part instances really
in the cloud we made this work in
practice of course we did warn the cloud
providers in advance that they should
implement countermeasures against this
attack similar thing are GPG you can
actually use the update mechanism in DB
down the window the apt you first modify
the sources.list so in fact malware will
be downloaded rather than from the real
at the moment of the signature checking
you actually flip the RSA keys the
trusted GPG file you factor again until
your forged signature and now install
malware in the victims machine again you
factorize it that's it so we also
extension to development the problem
there is that your publicly available
software for this we log is not as good
as the others factoring so we didn't get
as far with diffie-hellman as for RSA
but the paper has the technical details
we also discuss mitigations and if you
want to find the paper it's on there
thank you very much for your attention
thanks bar with Jeremiah please come to
the stage and next up we have Nigel
smart
there's loads of seats down here for
those standing oh yeah thanks idle
please come and sit down otherwise we'll
get shut down
yeah please you're standing please come
sit here be uh provides the rub session
will be shut right ok in there if you
can meet and we will have Jeremiah and
we will do something to fix Nigel's talk
at some point thanks for your
understanding Nigel great talk
okay all right thanks everyone
like to give you a quick update on the
Olympic Games which as you know are
taking place right now and I want to
talk about my favourite event which is
password frequency list disclosure so
there we go so some of you may be
unfamiliar with this exciting event so
how does it work
contestants start by collecting a large
data set of user passwords and then they
produce a histogram which is just a plot
of the frequency of the most popular
passwords and finally the goal is to
release a frequency list which can be
obtained by simply removing the
passwords and just outputting The
Associated frequencies and contestants
may perturb these lists to protect user
privacy so how our contestants judged in
these Olympic Games well there's three
criteria the first scoring criteria is
data set size so the more users the
better the second criteria is accuracy
if you can release a frequency list
that's more accurate that's better and
the final criteria is privacy if you're
not giving away user passwords that's
also better so you may think this is a
game that I just made up but I assure
you there's a long history of
organisations competing in this event
for example Rock you submitted an entry
several years ago with 32 million user
passwords unfortunately most of the
previous contestants have had to be
disqualified due to failure to properly
protect user passwords so today I want
to tell you about a new leading
candidate for gold medal Yahoo just
turned in a very strong performer
they collected a dataset of 70 million
user passwords and they used tools from
differential privacy to actually perturb
these password frequency lists before
they were released so I should stress
that the status at civ ailable and it
was released with permission
so let's score this entry first criteria
accuracy well we can actually compare
basic statistics like minimum entropy
guessing entropy that you'd get with the
sanitized data set with the same
statistics computed on the original data
set and we actually see that the
statistics match in almost every case
with occasionally we'll get small
variation and what about privacy
well they also had strong scores on the
privacy criteria in particular they
preserved differential privacy with the
value composite value of epsilon equals
0.5 of course a single user might
consult apin tatah sets so you have to
scale epsilon appropriately so what does
this mean well this means we can promise
Alice that you know if we had removed
her password from the data set at the
onset before we ran the differentially
private mechanism the probability of any
subset of outcomes doesn't change too
much when we exclude her or password so
this means that the probability that
alice gets hacked doesn't change too
much you know based on whether her
password was included or not
okay so password frequency lists have
many applications the simplest one is
just estimate the total number of users
that could be compromised in an online
attack where the adversary has beta
guesses per user there's lots of other
exciting applications I hope you'll all
search for the data set if you just
search for a yahoo password frequency
corpus you'll find it please play around
with it
I hope that it's useful for you and for
many of you and your research endeavors
and finally I'd like to conclude by
saying that I hope other organizations
will challenge Yahoo for gold there are
other organizations that potentially
could collect larger password frequency
lists and follow the same pattern and
perhaps steal that gold medal from Yahoo
so thank you okay so Nigel is now you're
going to try again with his second
presentation but Kerri if you're in the
room please get close to the stage
because you might be on sooner than
expected
okay and please take a seat if you're
standing in the back corner I can see
you okay
I call you on your behavior please take
a seat
all right or leave auditorium otherwise
we'll get shut down Nigel okay to work
okay I don't know there's something
wrong with the computer we're gonna fix
you'll see the other talk later I've
been promised okay so this is about a
speed King you're gonna hear me sing so
if anyone gets the reference they're
just far too old really okay okay
except oh okay I'm not actually going to
sing right but if thank you thank you
for the that's exactly what I want yeah
thank you I'm not gonna sing but if
you're interested in NPC this is the
rump session talk for you so we've got
so three or four things to announce
speed is now open source and I'm going
to give you the link to that it will be
made open source it's not actually other
source yet but it will be by the end of
the week there's still some tidying up
they've got to do okay but everything's
ready to go we're going to give you some
timings we've achieved there's going to
be a new conference on MPC and there's
going to be some jobs because basically
every bloody run per session I have to
get up and tell you there's some jobs do
you know where the jobs are which
University Bristol yeah that's it
they're kind of right there we go okay
yeah right okay so it's now open source
hopefully now well it could be in the
next couple of days
the documentation is as we it's a little
shaky if you want to sign up for
announcements and to find out all about
it there's a Google group called speeds
at Google Groups comm and you can visit
the web page which is really long just
like Bristol speeds and you'll get it
into Google other search engines are
available for Brian you can use paying
if you want but Google will do it for
you so that's some that's when you can
see me fly if you're going to have a
party then you need large numbers of
people to come to that party so we
decided we wanted a very large party so
we actually ran well Marcel did he ran a
hundred party auction so this is this is
not sugar beets because they only had
three parties in their auction and it
was only semi honest when they did it
this is a proper auction with a hundred
people fully malicious and we actually
ran so this so when people talk about
multi-party computation the record now
is running a computation on a hundred
parties we hope to be able to push it to
a thousand parties at some point in the
next few months so I'm the goal is now
let's make things faster but to have
more people at your party and we can now
do twenty two thousand twenty two two
hundred twenty thousand sorry blocks per
second of a s this is not as good as
your Hooters record which is going to be
presented at CCS where he can do a
million blocks of a s per second that
he's integrated to into a Kerberos
system but this is a system that will
work for many parties whereas your who
does things for three there we go so
we've got some new kind of cool stuff
coming up there and there's a new
workshop it's it's going to be if you go
to the website
www.marykay.co.uk/awilliam seventh in
Bristol it kind of continued
from the the event that you should be
held every two years in our house but
now we're going to hold it every year
we're going to move around Europe
probably oh I should say that all of my
slides have a sort of growing epitaph
you see to them because we're Great
Britain well we are currently and and we
only excel at Olympic sports where we
can apply our Formula One technology so
we're good at cycling which you'd have
seen in the real world trips I talked
but we're also good at rowing as well
because we could just apply technology -
it doesn't have to be any good at
athletics so that's why we've got the
rowing metaphor in all my slides you see
because we're very good at that and of
course ramming is quite good for
multi-party computation because you need
many people to do a good rowing team you
know I think it's amazing in every year
we have this oxygen Cambridge Boat Race
I'm not quite sure how both of them get
always get into the final but there we
go but there's eight in each team and so
we so when you need a team of people to
do rowing you need extra people on your
team and so what I want to say my last
um slide is I just got paid shed loads
of cash right and so with this shed
loads of cash I want to make a bit a
better bigger rowing team so if you want
to join our rowing team come and help us
spend the money talk to some of the
postdocs who are here they will tell you
travel is no objective and come and work
for us five years apply online now just
come and do it thank you thank you
so if you if you'd like to be a galley
slave in Bristol for five years we we
also have postdocs at Rowe Holloway
please come talk to me and I'd like now
to introduce Kerry McKay or McKay
good Scottish name they're from this
Thank You Kerry next up Marcel hi I'm
Terry McKay from this you may have never
seen me before because I generally don't
like to give these talks but here I am
so I want to talk to you tonight a
little bit about lightweight
cryptography and our standardization
plans so you may have heard of us and we
have these standards like AES
shot-to-shot three but the what we're
hearing from people is that AES is just
too damned hall for the uneven bars we
need something a little bit lighter so
nits initiated a lightweight crypto
project to understand kind of where our
standards fall short so some of you made
might have come to our first lightweight
crypto workshop in July of last year at
NIST and we're going to hold the second
one this October and what we're looking
for is lightweight algorithms for
constrained environments and of course
use cases so how are we going to do this
is the big question it's something we've
been struggling with we did just last
week put out our draft report this IRA
eight one one four and it's posted for
public comment so you know after you've
had a few drinks go and look at it
tonight it gives an overview of the
project includes our plan for
Standardization which boils down to two
essential things we're going to
recommend primitives based on the
application and device profiles and
we're gonna create a portfolio of the
lightweight primitives through an open
process similar to our 838 series for
the modes of operation and the reason
we're doing this is because if we try
and do a competition for this by the
time we finished with the
standardization no one's gonna be using
that technology anymore so the profiles
are really the key to what we have so
or the key to our plan so we're gonna
hit describe we're gonna have profiles
that represent classes of devices and
applications and we're going to build
these profiles based on public feedback
so this is just a template from the
report if you want more information
about what actually goes in these fields
please look at the report but in general
it's we've got a primitive the physical
performance and security characteristics
and also some device design goals but
here's the thing we work at NIST and
we're not actually out in the field
using this stuff but you guys are so we
really need your help in developing
these profiles so we have a list of
questions in the run out draft report
that we need your input on we need your
answers otherwise we're just gonna be a
bunch of people just in a room making
stuff up we'll try our best to make up
something useful but you actually know
what you need not us so right now we've
got the draft report out the comments
are due by October 31st and if you are
going to be awesome enough to help us
out by answering these questions to help
us develop profiles it would be really
great if you get those to us by october
1st so that we actually have time to
draft some profiles to discuss at the
workshop which again is hell being held
in october 17 for 18 again at NIST and
if you want to participate in that the
deadline for submissions is September
9th so if you would like to contact us
or get more information or join our
mailing list we have a lightweight email
list like the hash forum there hasn't
been much activity on it yet but
hopefully that'll change soon as the
project just picking up we also have
information on the workshop and the
project in general thank you
excellent thank you very much I've been
asked to speak up but can you hear me at
the back okay is it good yes excellent
thank you for one thumbs up at the back
and Martin would like a cup of tea so if
somebody could go fetch Martin a cup of
tea that'd be great and if someone could
bring me a bottle of vodka that would be
good too okay okay and that's to prepare
us for Marcel Keller who's next up and
he's gonna be followed by you and Eamonn
so if you and Damon could come to the
stage Thank You Ann hi Owen okay Marcel
thank you
so I'm Marcel I'm one of the slaves so I
come talk to me what I'm going to talk
about today is homeopathic encryption
and I have to say it's a substantially
shameless steal by a working progress
talk from USENIX I think it was Eric
gusto I hope I don't miss the pretty
miss attribute this so yeah come talk to
me if that's wrong anyway homo public
encryption of course it's going to be
round based because that's how proper
encryption schemes work we start
unsurprisingly with a message m and a
key K and there we go first round with
probability 2 to the minus twelve point
eight we're gonna assign K to K
otherwise K is XOR K XOR K we continue
with round two again with probability 2
to the minus 12 point 8 kg o'clock way
otherwise k equal K XOR K and this
already brings us to round number three
which says that with probability 2 to
the minus twelve point eight K is K
otherwise K is K XOR K and oh that's
already round number four with
probability 2 to the minus twelve point
eight K equals K otherwise we assign K
to K XOR K and now you might be
surprised that's wrong number five
probability - - 12.8 kegels clay
otherwise k equals K XOR K and that's
quickly moved to round number six
probability 2 to the minus twelve point
eight we assign K to K otherwise that
with probability 1 - 2 - 2 12 and 8 we
assign K XOR K to K and then there's my
lucky number round number 7 probability
to the minus twelve point eight K equals
K otherwise K okay XOR K yes oh yeah
that's one more than our number eight
probability so we flip very heavily
biased coin essentially in all those
rounds 12 - probably government probably
2 to the 12 minus 12 1 8 we assign K to
K otherwise K is gonna be okay
XOR K kkkk oh yeah that's wrong number 9
yeah I think we have to get go to 10 12
14 a yes style - two - twelve - twelve
point eight resign K - K otherwise K XOR
K K okay ten oh yeah that's one more
you're gonna be surprised - to the minus
twelve point eight K equals K otherwise
K equals K XOR okay and oh yeah finalize
ciphertext is gonna be C equals M XOR K
so that's the scheme let's talk about
implementation so we as you might have
seen that we really rely on fast random
number generation and of course I can
know their chess people here so you're
really concerned about you know embedded
systems Hardware maybe there is no
faster on them generation I can assure
you I don't have time for this but
there's a slight tweak to the algorithm
that makes this algorithm much more
efficient on
crickets systems and last but not least
also were very important the design
encourages constant time implementation
so you if you do if statements on either
the message of the key like you're
really doing it wrong last but not least
there's other special properties so we
hadn't thought about this and it really
are we really sure about the fact that
quantum attacks are really no better
than classical attacks on on this one so
that's like for the post quantum crab
lava community and on the other hand
like for the Fancy Pants community of
course it's also fully homomorphic and
and now here's an akut for the more as i
say like policy oriented community we
think we strongly believe that this one
is particularly suitable for compliance
and marketing because it's encrypted to
after all right and this already
concludes my talk thank you very much
thanks Marcel hilarious as ever
next up we have a talk called kangaroo
12 by you and Damon and if Brian would
like to come to the stage that would be
great you want to get away
yeah good evening so this is a more
serious talk I'm afraid to joint work
with the catch act team and honey so I
call it funny I choose a sports so it's
a kangaroo what they can go do it boxes
but I don't know if it's in a little bit
care discipline maybe it has been
haven't seen any boxing but okay yeah I
can google boxes and I think you will
need it so what is it is basically
hashing based on catch acti a bit like
shot v it's like the shake functions
with them more efficient so what we did
we did the exercise to bring ghachok
more down to where it should be - if you
look at the safety margin and we also
try to exploit parallelism so first the
the safety margin so if you look at the
state of kept analysis
up to now the best attacked the best
collision attack against gataki
is 5 rounds and the best publish there
may be some distinguishing stuff but the
best attack is 5 rounds but it has 24
outs
so you basically have more than 4 for a
factor 4 more rounds than we really need
so Enki actually already took that into
account and we reduce the number of
rounds to half to 12 so let's do also
the washing with 12 rounds so we reduce
from 24 hours to 12 rounds and that
still gives us a factor of 2 safety
margin so then if we look at modern CPUs
we see more and more these same d
instructions going broader and broader
so we have a lot of parallelism that we
can do and as all so many CPUs with
mouths many cores and we would like to
exploit a parallelism but in
it's points basically it's serial mode
so we introduce a kind of triage touch
and that's basically what we did so this
is the structure of a kangaroo 12 so
these blue blocks there are basically
the input blocks of the message so we
split our message into 8,192 byte blocks
and we can do them in parallel so you
see there those vertical bars that are
all inputs to get JAXA to catch X
version with 12 rounds and we can do
them in parallel and then we append the
chaining values to the first block is a
CFO and that's that's also one call so
each of these arrows represents a call
to the underlying hash function we just
sketch our 12 rounds and the whole thing
is a 3 has mods so you see also there
this chaining value that's some more
hashing you have to do but it's
compensated by the parallelism so if you
look at these symbols 1 1 0 and so on
that's in fact padding and frame bits
that complies to the secure mode so if
you do it this way you get a provable
reduction of security to the security of
the underlying hash function so what
does this give us something went wrong
with slide but ok yeah that was there
was a kangaroo there so on the and the
hospital and skylight for short well
short messages you which about something
below around for between 4 and 5 cycles
per byte but so long inputs you can
really exploit this parallelism so for
instance for the house well you get down
to 1.44 or scarlet 1.22 cycles per byte
so they you exploit for level four wide
parallelism and on this new CPU knights
landing basically can get down to 0.74
cycle four bytes so there we put the
paper on ICEA and you can find the code
that has achieved this resolves in the
croco package that's made public by show
thank you that's it thank you so I just
like to emphasize that no kangaroos were
harmed in the making of that talk we
just don't like kangaroos and here comes
Brian okay about this Bank for something
special so for what we're calling the
charity auction or a long jump for
charity so for the purposes of this talk
I am representing the great Great
Britain and their team and the long jump
for reasons that will become apparent in
a moment for as long as Great Britain is
still exists
Iran thanked me for taking you down a
walk on cinema Lane I'm now gonna take
you a walk down I ACR lanes in
particular I want to go back 25 years to
Europe 1991 who-knows-where europe 1991
was held okay Kenny
Brighton in the United Kingdom Mike it
was my first ever you ripped it was your
first year cupped it was my first jerk
ripped as well and it was here at the
University of Brighton in the UK and who
was the general chair it was Andy Clark
that's right and what was the Urich of
1991 special beverage that everyone got
beer in particular something that looked
like this it was euro crypt 91
celebration ale and it was my memory of
this beer that Andy did that caused me
to think about doing a custom label for
something which is why we have a wine
bottle here with a nice custom label
because I kind of grew up from the
period of the wine now I accepted to be
general chair two years ago and about
six months after that I was cleaning out
an old box in the back of my closet that
had been there probably since graduate
school days that I had moved from a
bunch of places to places and I'd never
seen the light of day and I found this
little cardboard box here from Harvin
sons and when I opened it up I found
inside one unopened original bottle of
uric ripped 91 celebration ale
best before end date July 91 okay it was
in April so I thought what should we do
with this bottle since it's a special
occasion that it's 25 years and I
thought the thing we should do was to
have a charity auction to benefit the
National Museum of computing at
Bletchley Park now so I am about to
auction this off for charity open your
wallets up why National Museum of
computing well because that Andy is a
director and trustee of that and it's
his favorite chair knees trying to bring
it back so I thought a way that we could
honor Andy and Yura 91 was to
auction this bottle off so someone here
who bids high enough is going to get to
walk home with this bottle tonight or
make me drink it if they pay me enough
and I hold my fellow members of the
Board of Directors and they have pledged
along with me to match the donation that
is made by the winning bid tonight if
the clicker will advance so we will get
a twenty seven time multiplier on
whatever this goes for that will all go
to charity okay with some limits so that
people don't get too crazy okay so what
I would like to do right now is open the
bidding for this bottle of beer and
since its 25 years old I thought I'd
open the bidding at 25 cents that's all
what offer twenty-five cents ten dollars
okay I've got a bit of ten dollars I got
a bid back there how much $20 $100 over
here and I'm gonna hold you this thank
you very much
Wow fantastic all right
I've got a bid of $100 for a Europe 91
celebration ale how much $200 I've got
200 and back I will offer
he's been 200 250 I got 250 do I hear
300 in the back how about 275 come on
it's for charity too sick come on 275
all right I got 250 over here anyone
else come on somebody wants to go a
little bit higher right it's for charity
256 I got to all right all right Cheers
56 its 512 to you or maybe I'll let you
go to 384 384 I got 384 over here
fantastic okay tom 384 back to you no
you're out you're tapped out
- buddy bit huh okay I have $384 over
here bid for this bottle
good good be fair all night 384 anyone
else anyone want to top it 400 boring
some other weird number added on to it
512 all right I'm gonna take that $384
bin I'm gonna let it go once twice last
chance folks sold for three hundred
eighty four dollars I think we have
grazed well a lot of money tonight for
the Nashua geo computing please meet me
afterwards we're about to go to the
break and we will discuss how to make
sure that everybody gets tax deductions
appropriately for good okay thank you
all again I believe this is the first
break yeah so we'll see you all at 2045
for something special involving
vegetables okay 2045