so thank you for the introduction so as
I said I will present another yet
another cryptanalysis of multilinear
maps this time for the G th 15 candidate
and it's a joint work with John
Sebastian Koch on moon soonly and Medici
version so let's start with multi linear
map application so one of the first
application Multan in maps were
described for was non interactive key
exchange for more than 4 players so you
have 4 players here and you have a
public board with some public parameters
and the idea is that each player is
going to generate a secret value and it
is also going to encode this secret
value in a public encoding and send this
public and publish podcast this public
encoding and these public encodings are
going to be on this public board and
then each of the the the party can take
the free over encoding error and their
own secret value and apply this key
generation procedure so on their secret
value and the free and the encoding z'
of the other parties so for example the
party a here is gonna take the value a
the secret value a and encoding of P and
coding MC encoding of T and apply this
key chain procedure and B here will take
this public is secret value D and then
take the free public encodings a C and D
and apply the same keygen operation and
the thing is what you want is that key
chain in these four cases give the same
result so that you can extract the same
key K so if we look at instantiation of
such key generation algorithm for two
parties it's essentially defilement and
it's it comes back to 1976
so you just the secret values are
element of
EP and the encoding czar g2 the secret
value then in 2001 jus explain how to
use bi linear maps how to use pairings
in order to achieve three parties and in
2003 bonny and silver bird they said
okay if we don't have a binary map but a
multi linear map then we can achieve end
parties for n as big as the size of the
military Maps plus a plus one but also
in this paper they say that it might not
be possible to use the same technique as
we used to obtain parents in order to
obtain multilinear maps so it remains an
operant problem it and it's still enough
from open problem to get the melting in
maps from Bonanza topic in 2013 what we
used instead of multi minimizes
approximate multilinear maps were
introduced and this approximated mention
in the maps they also allow to derive
key generation procedure for n n parties
so we essentially have free candidate
schemes at this approximate machine in
the map so the first one from guard
country and Olivia at your crib 2013 and
then the CLT scheme crypto 2013 and the
Gentry gorbunov Olivie scheme of GCC
2015 and in this talk I will actually
describe Accra palaces on this third
candidate so why do we care about
Malkina map so nearly everyone here know
that they they are really interesting so
they're the one of the first application
that is described is this non
interactive key exchange so it's a
simple application because it's a
generalization of dmn but of course the
key okay okay okay the key
thing that we could build from
approximate match engine maps where was
I oh so industry indistinguishability
obfuscation and this as on itself a lot
of really exciting application a lot of
theoretical consequences and everything
so it's really really the big
constructed construction from
approximate multi minimaps and also we
can build a lot of really exciting new
technologies like multi input functional
encryption optimal broadcast encryption
witness encryption ad for circuit and a
lot more so it's really really
interesting to understand what how to
construct such machine in maps so if we
look at the candidates we are currently
for approximate mention in maps they're
unfortunately based on new ordinance
assumption that are not standard so you
have a lot of assumption so some of them
are named them myself but you have this
multi linear D D H which is a
generalization of the G H in a public
setting and in a private setting you
have decision linear problem subgroup
membership you have this these problems
here that are kind of interesting on
their own from for some theoretical work
to get to construct IO you have this
kind of straddling set induction
assumption that also are used to build
io subgroup elimination or graph endures
inductions and what's what's happening
right now in the community is to try to
figure out how hard this assumption
really hard so if you look for example
at the GG h13 scheme you have some
assumption we know that they are broken
and we have attacks again them some
assumption they're like kind of broken
sometimes it depends on you instant
intern instantiate dams so for example
in this work will show that a graph
induction assumption on GG h 13 is also
broken in a way when you look at CLT
13 it's not exactly the same thing so
this one was orange before now it's red
this one I put it in green but it's more
like we don't really know if it's secure
or not we're still trying to figure out
what's happening and these are all like
a subset of all the attacks again these
are necessary th 15 so it's kind of a
different melting in the map it's mainly
this graph induction Arnaz essential and
in this work we show that there are some
graph for example the graph of the key
exchange that is not secure okay so our
result is the following
so there exists a polynomial-time attack
against the key agram
the D film and key agreement protocol
when instantiated with the g GH 15
multilinear maps so what we do is
actually we don't we're looking at a
protocol that take place and we generate
an equivalent encoding for one of the
user and if we're using this including
in the key exchange then we recover the
secret ok so just small comments on the
result we our attack comes from the fact
that the graph that was used in the
graph induction artist assumption for
the key exchange protocol is there's a
way to attack it it does not mean that
all the graph induction assumption on
ggh 15 are broken and in particular you
can build a candidate for
indistinguishability of education
following a certain graph structure and
we don't know how to break that and also
there's a paper an apron but I didn't
check the detail that says that some of
the graph give sort of random encoding
so you have security for some of the
graphs also so a LaVey in this and this
note and the a print try to X 2 to take
this graph induction thing and to put it
for ggh 14 and in that case also for the
key argument
Cole we can have another attack it's not
really an extension of this one but it's
it's similar in some of the idea that
breaks also in that case the the key
agreement protocol okay
so in the rest of this talk I will
describe multilinear maps what is the
candidate what is the protocol and how
we can break it okay so if we go back to
a symmetric multi-lane maps so you have
an encoding of an element a for in a
group G to the L so that's why that's
how it was described by bond and
Silverberg you can add and subtract
elements in the same group so that is it
that's just the addition you can zero
test at any in any group so the zero
testing it's true so it means it encodes
a zero if it's an element if it's a
natural element of the group so it means
the element that is encoded is zero and
you can multiply so in the symmetric
multi mean map described by Bunyon
Silverberg you can take D elements and
put all of them together and get an
encoding in the target group of the
product when you look at approximate
multilinear maps it's it's it's nearly
the same so instead of being in the
group GL your encoding with respect to a
lab lay a label L and now you can still
add for the same level you can zero test
it's the same except you can only zero
test for a specific label and the
multiplication is slightly different
here it's graded so it means you can
multi you can multiply two including
corresponding to label I and Noble J if
they are in relation in a search for
certain relation and this certain
relation it's what will be different in
the different
the candidates we have and for example
for the ggh 15 candidate that will look
at this relation are given by graph
structure okay so what is this candidate
so first we're working over a ring so
it's polynomial mod F where F is an
irreducible polynomial of degree N and
you're also working in our queues or in
our queue so it's R divided by Q R and
we have some public values and this
public values will be vectors in R that
correspond to certain vertices so what
is an encoding so actually you're
including something with respect to a
label label and this label will be a
path so a path from vertices you to
vertices V and an encoding for this
label is actually a matrix in R such
that this vector times this matrix is
the secret value times the the vector
that correspond to the to the vertices V
plus an error vector not Q so once again
the encoding here it's a matrix and it's
and this vector to this vector
multiplied by the secret value and it's
a noisy encoding so obviously you can
add or subtract so if you're taking two
such matrices for the same label then
when you multiply on the left by a to
the U you get a times a to the D and
plus B times a to the D so it's a plus B
times a D and plus a vector of noise the
question is what's happening for the
multiplication and the multiplication
will be possible if the paths are
compatible so it means if you have an
encoding for the pass UV and an encoding
for the passed VW then you can have an
encoding that will be for the pass you
to W so if you write it down it's
the matrix multiplication so you're
multiplied these two matrices and when
you write it down and you multiply on
the left by the vector a you then you
have a times P times a W and you have an
error term here and these things it
reveals a lot so first we it means we
can only encode small plaintext because
if you're including large min takes and
then you're multiplying then this might
becomes really big so if you keep on
multiplying it will be really big and
then you cannot do anything and the
other thing is that here the encoding
itself is its present so actually the
encoding also are small they actually
are nearly trap doors for these vectors
here there are noisy trapdoors anyway so
if we sum up we can do multiplication
when the paths are compatible it's just
the matrix multiplication and the the
plain things are small and the encoding
is are small it doesn't matter that much
for the rest of the attacks but just I
wanted to point that out also how do we
zero test so actually there's an
extraction procedure and the extraction
procedure is you have an encoding of a
secret S for a path you to D and if you
have the a you the vector a you you can
multiply and you get s time aw plus e
and this thing is this e here is small
so it means the most significant bits of
this value here will only depend on the
secret exponent s so if you have another
encoding that also goes to that encodes
the same value but then but it's
randomized differently it will still
give them the same most significant bits
so it means you can extract something
that only depends on s so in particular
it's really easy because if the F is
equal is a zero then when you will
multiply this two thing you will get
something that is small so you know that
the encoded value is a zero so zero
testing is
means that the extracted value is the
zero okay so if we sum up on this slide
in the graph Hindus Multan in the mouse
you incurred relative to a path it's a
noisy encoding you can add our subtract
such including for the same path you can
zero test
so there's your test is one if a 0 and u
is actually the source there are text
and you can multiply a long path so if
you have a path u to V 1 and a path and
including from the path V to W you can
multiply them as v1 is equal to v2 and
you get an encoding related to the pass
you to W ok so what is the key exchange
protocol so I will describe the protocol
for free parties but you can extend it
you can extend the attack for more
parties so when you were using G th 15
in application you have to specify the
graph that you will be used using so
this is a graph or the key exchange in G
th 15 so the first row will correspond
to user 1 the second row will correspond
to user 2 and the third row will
correspond to user free so what is an
encoding so the encoding is they will be
from this dirt dirt X to these vertices
and then including so I J for example
it's cert that a IJ times this including
its small a times a I J plus 1 plus
vector noise so actually the encoding
will be here on the edges and your
you're doing so you're multiplying here
and you go here and you're multiplying
here you go here you're multiplying here
you go here okay so what is okay it's
here so what is key exchange protocol so
the user are generating encoding love
secret values as 1 + 2 NS free and
they're putting them in the graph in a
round robin fashion it doesn't really
matter that it's a round robin
but it's it's it's described like that
so the the thing is here you can see
that each user can take this first the
user one can take the first row multiply
the encoding and get an encoding of s 1
times S 2 times s free and same thing
for user 2 and user free so what they do
is actually the if they publish these
encoding but keeps these include
encoding secret and then this vector
here they're not public so what they
have is the public parameters contain
these three vectors here and they only
reveal this value here so it means if
you're just looking at that you cannot
you cannot recover as to here because it
you cannot infer it from here or from
here because it's not the same matrices
so the user here but the user I himself
he knows the secret value on the missing
edge and it can compute the resulting
entry and extract the key as a most
significant bit of the result so that's
a protocol and how do we do that if we
don't have all the the small vectors so
actually what happened is that you have
a lot of public and coatings over these
edges and your computing a subsets on so
here user 1 for example it takes a set
in 1 to the N and it generates an
encoding of s 1 it doesn't know s 1 but
this encoding it can generate it on this
on this path here on this path here and
on the path here and user 2 is doing the
same and user free is doing the same
question about the protocol okay so
let's let's try to break it so the
setting is the following we have all
these public parameters so these perfect
parameters just what I have shown here
so it's these matrices C IJ and they
verify that
the vector time C IJ is equal to this
secret value TI t IJ plus etc so you
have all these public parameters and
what you have is that you're actually
looking and an ongoing key exchange so
you have all this relation from the key
exchange but this one you don't have
because these are the secret from the
users otherwise the relation is with s 1
s 2 and s 3 and that's the secret of the
users okay so the goal what is it it's
to recover the shared secret key so it
means you want to recover K which is an
extraction that chichén of s 1 s 2 s 3
over 1 of the path so either the first
row the second row the third row
so our attack is as follows we extract a
linear relation over s 1 over the TI t 1
J's and it's a variant of the shin hwal
attack again the CLT 13 scheme it does
not break the protocol right away
because the coefficients are large but
then we can compute an equivalent
including with a with a small error and
then we can use that in the protocol so
so what is the ID in the nutshell is
that we have including z' here of s1
that are public so we'll just forget
about the first row and we'll try to fix
s2 and s3 at the same for the same value
and then compute this line here and this
line here and compute the difference it
will give an N Kooning of 0 and we'll do
that for a lot of different values of s
2 and s 3 and this will allow to
construct a matrix and then we can do
something with the matrix so ok so if we
look at the public parameters so these
are the public parameters of the row 2 &
3 what I do is first I fix T 3 I forget
about the indices in the index J 4 T 3
and then that's it's going to fast
ok and then I'm merging the two first
equation ok
anyway I'm merging the two first
equations
so it means I can have to encoding 'z
and this time it's from the first vertex
to a second vertex here and it's an
encoding of t1 times t3
or and t2 times t3 and then an encoding
of t2 and t1 and what I do then is I fix
all the G's and that's the thing I will
be varying after so then I get to
encoding x' here and the thing is when I
look at the difference of this encoding
as I told you we have two rows that
compute the same thing so I look at the
difference when I look at the difference
it will give something small that's what
the protocol is so when you compute
exactly and you write everything down
you get that this difference is t1 times
t3 time this error vector plus an error
vector times the including the including
ZAR small minus T 2 T 3 times an error
vector minus an error times and
including but all the values are small
it means we get something that is true
over the ring and not mod Q so then now
if we only look at the first element of
this encoding we can write this equation
as as an inner product of two vectors
and then I can do that for a lot of
different public elements so it means I
can extend that in two matrices so you
have a product of matrix a times B and
so if you're doing that but you're not
building a square matrices you're
building one matrices with one line more
it means that you can find a vector in
the kernel of W and since with I
probability B will be invertible you can
remove that so it means you have a
vector in the kernel of a so it means
you have a linear combination of the t1j
that gives 0 and the interesting thing
about that is that we only use public
elements so if we use one secret element
instead of one public element we have a
relation with s1 and the TI J's and so
once we have this relation the the
problem is that
when we look at the encoding we can
create because we have the coefficient
then the noise vector is really big so
that's a problem we cannot use it
directly in the protocol but what we can
do is instead of using line two and
three as we did we're using line one and
three and we're running exactly the same
thing and then we can correct this error
vector get something with the same error
vector so we can subtract and then we
get an element that is verifying what we
want and then we can use it in the
protocol and recover to the shared
secret so to conclude we described an
attack again the key agreement of GTH 15
even with the safeguards that were in
the papers and it extends in a way to
the violence of Halloween and we don't
know with this attack we don't know to
build a non-interactive
for party exchange that is not going
through i/o but and it gives some
insight on the graph induced assumption
yes so these are some open problems and
thank you for your attention