thank you all for sticking around for
the last session of crypto so I'm
excited to talk to you today about data
independent memory hard functions this
is joint work with joelle all win at ISD
Austria so is a basic motivate
motivating example consider the problem
of password storage often times due to
programmer errors or other security
flaws adversaries are able to break into
authentication servers and steal the
cryptographic hashes of user passwords
such an adversary can execute an offline
attack in which he compares the hashes
of likely password guesses with the hash
value of the users true password such an
adversary is only limited by the
resources that he's willing to invest
trying to crack the users password in
fact offline attacks are an increasingly
common problem in the past years we have
seen breaches at many large
organizations which have affected
millions of users and in fact over the
years I've had to update this slide
several times so we can see that this
problem is not going away now offline
attacks on passwords are increasingly
dangerous for several reasons first
password cracking hard work and can use
to improve and second users continue to
select low entropy passwords this
motivates the goal of developing
moderately expensive hash functions the
basic idea is to create a function which
is moderately hard to evaluate once this
way an adversary is trying to try
millions or billions of password guesses
just runs out of resources now the key
question here is after we've done all
this key stretching on the legitimate
authentication server is it really going
to cost the adversary extra to evaluate
this memory hard function once in
particular the adversary doesn't have to
use standard computing hardware he could
build a GPU or an ASIC for example to
compute this memory heart function
multiple times the question the key
question really is are the costs
equitable
if we do a lot of work to make this
function harder to compute on your
desktop is it also going to be harder
for the adversary to compute this
function multiple times on customized
hardware and in fact obtaining a
function with equitable cost is
non-trivial in particular by looking at
Bitcoin mining pools we can see that the
sha256 hash function is far from
equitable in fact the cost of evaluating
sha-256 there is by a factor of about a
million when you compare the cost on a
cpu versus the cost of evaluating the
function once on an ASIC alright so this
hopefully motivates the need for our
data independent memory hard functions
an object that will introduce in the
next section after introducing data
independent memory hard functions I'm
going to go over our attacks and as a
bonus if time permits i'll describe some
exciting subsequent results that we've
obtained in the last few months all
right so the basic goal of a memory hard
function is to develop a moderately hard
function with equitable costs and the
key observation here is that memory
costs tend to be equitable across across
different computer architectures so the
intuition behind a memory heart function
is basically a function for which
computation costs are dominated by
memory costs a script is one example of
a candidate memory hard function but the
data access pattern for s crypt is input
dependent that means that the access
pattern to memory depends on the
sensitive user input which makes the
function potentially vulnerable to
side-channel attacks in this paper we're
going to consider a special subclass of
memory card functions called data
independent memory heart functions as
the name suggests the memory access
pattern does not depend at all on the
input which makes these functions
resistant side-channel attacks all right
so what is a data independent memory
hard function well for our purposes we
can think of a data independent memory
hard function as being
fine by a compression function H which
will model as a random Oracle and a
directed acyclic graph G which encodes
data dependencies during computation so
as an example here if we have this graph
the input to the function is the
password and the salt and we compute the
label of the first node by just hashing
this password value and the salt now the
label of an internal node for example
the label of note 3 is computed by
hashing the labels of its parents in
this case no 2 and node 1 finally the
output of the data independent memory
heart function is just the label of the
final node in this case note for all
right so and we can describe algorithms
that the adversary might use to compute
an IM hf using language of rappelling in
particular placing a pebble on on the
graph corresponds to computing a
particular data label and keeping a
pebble on the graph corresponds to
storing that data label in memory now of
course a pebble is only valid if it
satisfies certain rules for example we
can only place a pebble on the graph in
round I plus 1 if we had pebbles on the
parents of that node in round I this is
because we need any dependent values
before we can compute the new label and
the final rule is that by the end of
this pebble we have to place a pebble on
the final node after all that's the
output that's what we're trying to
compute now the adversary is allowed to
place potentially multiple pebbles on
the graph during a given round we assume
that the adversaries parallel and the
adversary is also allowed to discard
pebbles at any point in time potentially
to save space all right so here's a
simple example of pebble inning so to
start off we can place a pebble one node
1 now that we have this pebble we can
place a pebble one note 2 now we can
pebble note 3 because we had pebbles on
the parents at the same time we can
remove
couples from those 1 & 2 because they're
no longer needed now we can pebble note
4 and finally note 5 all right so how do
we measure the cost of a pebble
algorithm well the first approach which
is kind of a classical approach is
space-time complexity so here the space
time complexity of a graph is the
minimum over all legal peb wings of the
time that the pebble in cakes the number
of rounds times the maximum space usage
the maximum number of pebbles on the
graph at any point in time now this is a
nice notion and there's a rich theory
with lots of space-time trade-off
theorems that have been proved in this
model but I claim that this is not the
appropriate metric for password hashing
and why do I say that well the problem
is amortization so for parallel
computation st complexity can scale
badly in the number of evaluations of
the function remember that the adversary
is trying to compute this function from
multiple different password guesses he's
trying to evaluate many instances of
this function so consider a function
which requires lots of space at the
beginning and then runs for a long time
with minimal space usage well if we can
execute this function in parallel then
effectively the cost of computing say
three instances of this function really
has space time complexity just about
equal to the space time complexity of
computing one instance of this function
and all would answer Benito showed that
you can construct example functions
where this scaling is even much worse
you can compute square root end
functions with the same esky cost all
right so here's an improved cost metric
which is called cumulative complexity
instead of looking at time times the
maximum space usage you just some space
usage over every pebble in time step and
the nice thing about this metric is it
actually does amortize in fact the cost
of pebble in two independent instances
of a graph is exactly twice the cost of
pebble
one instance so in our previous example
the cost of this pebble is seven because
we just some the number of pebbles on
the graph at each point in time all
right so so the metric we use in in this
work is actually a little bit more
refined it's called energy complexity
it's very similar to cumulative
complexity except we add an additional
term to model the cost of querying H
every time we query this function it
costs a little bit extra energy and so
we want to charge ourselves for that
cost so every time we call we're eh
we're going to charge a cost r and in an
asymptotic sense this is actually
equivalent to cumulative complexity but
in a physical sense it seems to more
closely model what's going on in
hardware okay so a data independent
memory heart function is given not only
by a graph but also by a naive peddling
algorithm this is the algorithm that the
honest party is supposed to use so the
naive algorithm coupling algorithm
should be sequential you should only
place one new pebble on the graph at
each during each round and for example
of many IMA chefs are just defined by
the midnight peddling algorithm and the
nice tumbling algorithm you kind of just
pebble the graph in topological order
never removing pebbles from the graph so
the time here is n takes ten rounds to
pebble last node and on average you have
about n over two pebbles on the graph
during each step so the energy
complexity scales is N squared alright
and we'll define a tack quality given an
algorithm a that the adversary might use
to evaluate this I MHS attack quality is
the energy cost the naive algorithm /
the energy cost of the adversaries
algorithm multiplied by the number of
instances that the adversary is
computing so if the adversary is
concluding a hundred instances of this I
mhf then we'll scale this by a hundred
okay so what are the desirable goals for
a data independent
memory hard function well we want to
graph G which ideally should have
constant in degree so we can actually
apply the compression function and we
want to guarantee that for any adversary
a that the attack quality is small less
than or equal to C for some hopefully
small constant C and finally we also
want to guarantee that the cost of the
naive algorithm is fairly large roughly
n squared over tau or hopefully some
small value tau now this last criteria
might seem a little bit confusing why do
we want the knee naive algorithm to be
expensive well for one it rules out this
type of graph where you can pebble it
with very low space in particular that
graph is bad because you have a low cost
per step users are impatient so the
maximum cost you can incur in a
particular time frame is fairly low and
secondly memory costs turn are an
insignificant portion of the total cost
of computing this function which means
that when you implement this attack con
and asic for example you might expect to
see a dramatic cost reduction so this
criteria is really saying that memory
costs this n squared over cow term
should dominate so we'll say that a i m
hf is c ideal if attack quality is
smaller than c and the cost of the naive
algorithm is sufficiently large for some
small constant cal all right so let me
to quickly describe our attacks and the
key takeaway here is that depth
robustness is a necessary condition for
an IM hf to satisfy in particular will
give an attack on any graph that doesn't
satisfy this combinatorial property
called depth robustness which i'm going
to define next so what does it mean to
be a depth or bust well first of all we
say that a graph G is Ed reducible if
there exists a small subset s of at most
enotes such that by removing the notes
in s from the graph G the length of any
path and the remaining graph is that
most of d so for example this graph here
is 12 reducible in particular if we
delete the node 2 node 3 then any path
has a length at most 2 of course if a
graph is not eat irreducible then we'll
call it ed depth robust alright so
here's a general attack that works on
any heed irreducible graph as input will
start off with a set s of at most enotes
such that the depth of G minus s is
small and will also start with an attack
parameter G which has to be larger than
the depth of the resulting graph so the
attack is divided into two phases late
phases which are cheap and balloon
phases which are expensive during the
light phase of each light phase last g
rounds and the goal is just to make
progress pebble the next G Rho G nodes
and G sequential steps now this phase
uses low memory because we're going to
discard all pebbles from the graph
except for pebbles on the set s and
pebbles on the parents of notes that we
need to pebble in this late phase the
key point is that this phase lasts a
long time now of course at the end of
the balloon phase we need to recover the
pebbles of the parents in the next light
phase before you can continue to make
progress so we'll execute a balloon
phase and in a balloon phase we're just
going to greedily recover all the
missing pebbles and this is expensive it
uses parallelism but the key point is
that because the graph has depth at most
D we can compute this we can complete
this phase quickly and in fact the
attack is relatively simple I don't
expect you to read all these lines of
code but my point here is that you can
describe the algorithm completely using
just 13 lines of pseudocode alright so
our main theorem is that depth
robustness is necessary and particularly
if G is ed reducible then there's an
efficient attack a with the following
energy complexity so the first term here
upper bounds pebbles stored on nodes in
the set s here e is an upper bound on
the size of s and n is the number of
public rounds
the next term upper bounds the number of
pebbles kept fun parents of the next G
notes to be pebbled in each light phase
your Delta is the maximum in degree and
this final term here upper bounds the
cost of blue in phases here n over G is
the total number of balloon phases n is
the number of maximum number of pebbles
on the graph during the blue in phase
and D is the maximum length of a balloon
phase so if we set our parameters
appropriately we get the following
energy complexity and in particular
observe that if Ed are sub linear then
the energy complexity is sub quadratic
which is bad alright so this motivates
the natural question our existing I mhf
candidates based on depth robust graphs
and we'll consider three candidates
katina which received special
recognition during the password hashing
competition there's two variants lewin
hashing which is a newer proposal with
three variants two of the variance in
terms of depth robustness are similar to
Cana and left variant in terms of depth
robustness is similar to argon too and
last but not least we analyze are gone
too which is the winner of the password
hashing competition and in particular
are gone to I the data independent mode
is the one that's recommended for
password hashing I should note here that
in the paper we analyzed argon Qi a the
version from the password hashing
competition argon has been updated
several times and I'll just mention that
our attack ideas do extend to argon to
IB which is the newest version of our
gun okay so brief outline of the attack
first we show that any layered graph is
reducible I'll define layered graphs in
the next slide and this shows that we
can attack Katina because Katina DAGs
are layered eggs and then we'll show
that an argon to ID a gag is almost a
layered AG in the sense that we can
remove just a few notes and the
resulting graph is a layered tag hence
art on queue ID eggs are also
usable all right so let's work our way
up and start with layered graph layered
graph is just n nodes arranged into
lambda layers of equal size last note in
each layer is connected to the first
node in the next layer and any
additional edge in this graph must go
from a lower layer to a higher late
layer so in particular the only thing
you note need to know is that edges of
this form are disallowed now I claim
that these graphs are reducible why is
that well we can break up each layer
into segments of size n to the one-third
and now we'll just add the last node in
each segment to our set s well after we
delete these red nodes I claim that any
path P can spend at most n to the
one-third steps on layer I and there's
that most lambda layers where lambda is
a small constant so the total graphs of
the depth of the graph is lambda times
end of the one-third in particular this
gives us attacks with energy complexity
end of the five thirds or if you prefer
attack quality scaling as n to the one
third all right so what does the argon
to i dag look like well you start off
with a chain of n nodes as before and
for every node I you pick a random
predecessor uniformly at random from all
previous nodes I should note that this
randomness doesn't depend on the user
input it's fixed once and for all so now
if we kind of squint a little bit and
just arrange the graphing layers it kind
of looks like a layered crap well except
that when we arrange it in layers there
are some notes here with edges that stay
in the same layer so the first thing
we're going to do is we're going to add
a node to our set s if its parent stays
in the same layer if it's random parent
stays in the same layer and I claim that
by doing so we increase the size of the
set s by a factor of will enter the
three fourths times log in why is this
well consider layer I and consider a
particular note on layer I the
probability that we choose a parent
and the same layer is that most one over
I so the expected number of notes that
we add to our set on layer I is n to the
three-fourths the size of the layer / I
summing over all layers we get a
harmonic some and we get end of the
three ports times log in now as before
we'll split up each layer into segments
of size n to the one-fourth and any path
can spend at most 10 to 14 steps on each
layer there's n to the one-fourth layers
so the total depth of the graph of that
most root n ok so this gives us an
attack with energy complexity scaling as
n to the seven-fourths or quality n to
the one force which is quite high in an
asymptotic sense remember we want energy
complexity n squared ok so this shows
that existing imh up so it can be
attacked the this motivates the question
do I deal memory hard functions even
exist and an answer that might make the
adversary happy is no they don't in
particular any graph with constant in
degree is sufficiently depth reducible
but it end it's at most at least some
attack in particular energy complexity
can be at most n squared over log in so
in practice against argon we start to
get a positive attacks around two to the
18 and attack quality skyrockets after
this I should note that this plot only
shows up only shows theoretical upper
bound so it's very possible that attack
quality is even better in practice but
these plots show that actually in
practice it may still be possible to
obtain a secure I mhf but because if you
look at a kind of the ideal mhf this 10
squared over log in one attack quality
doesn't exceed one until at least two to
the 50 so that still might be a feasible
goal in practice now we have some new
results basically
simulating our attack and these results
show that actually our attack is much
more efficient in practice in particular
we still get high quality attacks
against the new version of argon to I be
with pessimistic parameters and for non
pessimistic parameters which could
easily be chosen by the parameter
selection process attack quality is kind
of through the root all right let me
take 30 seconds and just highlight some
breaking results so this talk we show
that depth robustness is necessary it's
also sufficient if a graph is Ed depth
robust then energy complexity is at
least a times B and this actually does
lead to kind of optimal I mhf
constructions you can actually achieve
this N squared over log in bound some
more results we can improve the upper
and upper bounds on argonne qi by just
applying our attack recursively during a
balloon phase and in fact you can also
prove some lower bounds so our gone to I
has energy complexity at least n to the
1 point 6 6 and finally a script which
the original beta dependent memory heart
function actually does have optimal
energy complexity so there's a clear gap
here between data independent and data
dependent hash functions so in
conclusion depth robustness is a
necessary condition for provably secure
omhs and i would say the major open
challenge in the area right now is to
improve the constructions of depth
robust graphs we have constructions in
theory going back to Erdos at all in the
70s but as you can imagine they didn't
particularly care about the constants
and their constructions and in practice
these constants do matter so thank you
for listening and I'll take questions
you