Thank You Vance for the introduction so
you all know the classic even Manchu
blocks have a construction which is
built on top of a public random
permutation pie and uses two subkeys l0
and l1 from this one can directly
generalize this to 80 rail construction
based on T public permutations x 1 x 2
and up 2 pi p + 3 + 1 subkeys l0 l1 and
so on so this the key outer dating
cipher of KAC construction introduced by
bachmann up at all this lovely object
has received quite a lot of attention
lately and for the case of 10 rouse you
can view it as an idea abstraction of
AES to capture the security of pee CEE
one typically models is by the
conventional CC is QB notion of block
cipher under this notion anniversary
will be wrought into a reward are an
ideal world in either world advisory is
provided with two Oracle's to encrypt
and decrypt in the real world yo rocco's
who implement the KAC block cipher and
it's inverse with a random secret key in
the ideal world the implement a random
permutation f and it's inverse it boat
was that bursary will get access to the
primitives by 12 PI T so have been quite
a lot of papers dedicated in analyzing
the security of ka see this live work
Cohen eyes in a paper by chance ty
burger that achieves an ice empathically
bow ok
I synthetically tides bow for pee see at
the very first glance the problem is
completely solved now if you look more
closely in that you realize a huge
concrete gap between what is proven to
kill and the best known attacks and this
gap is visualized here or the parameters
of AES meaning they attend rouse and the
block length is 128 so prior works are
with not only quantitatively but also
qualitatively so concerned with only
security to with respect to a single
user but in practice our adversary will
typically attack on mass adaptively
distributing its resources against
multiple users the bursa will be happy
as long as it can compromise somebody so
to model the multi-user security in the
real world the Oracles would implement
many instances of the cases of cyber and
likewise in the idea where it would
implement many independent permutations
f1 f2 and so on if you want to get multi
user security from existing work you
have to use a hybrid adamant but then
there with a degradation factor
proportional to the number of users for
the KAC this loss apiece are necessary
at least I'll when they are only one or
two rouse as recent work have
demonstrated so today we will show
concretely tight boughs for pee CEE just
close the gap between best numbers and
attacks and our results of a both single
and multi user security
I will show that indeed for pee CEE
multi-user security is quite close to
single user case the underlying our
results and a new proof techniques for
information graphics filthy the extent
and refine existing methods such as the
esco vision technique of battery the new
methods are quite general and might have
potential applications beyond the scope
of KAC specifically he had the boughs 4k
AC in a single user case we essentially
achieve the bowels correspond to the
best on attacks in a multi-user case as
expected there's some small loss but our
brazil is do much better than what is
achieved by a hybrid adamant as
visualized here so let me now introduce
our proof techniques so our main
quantitative improvement compared to
challenge Tabitha is due to a
generalization of the edge coefficient
technique that we go the expectation
matter when we combine this with a
combinatorial lemma by chillin cybergirl
and we immediately obtain a complete
type bow for single user security of Kaz
anyone have multi use of security we
give a generic translation from single
multi-user security with strong bowels I
stress that the translation is generic
it has nothing specific to Kaz but of
course because the translation is so
powerful it has to be conditional
otherwise there's no hope to beat the
hybrid adamant in all cases
to understand our techniques we first
need to review the edge coefficient
technique of battery this group method
aims to bow the distinguishing advantage
of two randomized systems s0 and s1 so
when an adversary interacts with either
system it will make queries to receive
answers and this information will be
recorded in a transcript ow the
distinguishing advantage is then bounded
by the statistical distance between
distributions of the transmitted that
the two systems produced open we only
deal with steady systems suggest a block
cipher in that case we can rearrange the
order of the queries in a transcript
without affecting the probability that
the system produces that car transcript
and it's wider edge co efficient
technique is so powerful in handling
adaptivity so if you want about the
statistical distant universe need to
classify transcripts by good versus bad
ones the next step is to bow the
probability that a random transcript is
bad and a maximum over all good
transcript of this formula once we are
done with that that the distinguishing
advantage is bounded by the sum of these
two numbers epsilon 1 and excellent you
to understand they have some intuition
while it is true so recall that the
statistical distance is the son of some
product and now if we plot some
rectangles whose width and the poster
with a product and height add a second
homes
then intuitively the statistical
distance it's just the total area of the
plotted rectangles and in this picture
the red areas correspond to the back
transcript and the blue areas or smart
to the good ones even this the
escalation technique helps us that you
can about the red area by this orange
rectangle and the blue area by the free
one now let's try applying the disco
edge coefficient technique on the case
if problem so record at that verse we
can make two types of queries in either
a construction query to the case epochs
either our premier queries to the
permutations by 12 high p
so the answer of these queries and the
answers will be recorded in a transcript
like this for example here the
transcript tells us that if you increase
you why then you get a sound XZ or if
you query or shrink v2 the inverse of x
3 and you get a string you empat orioli
one can represent a transcript by a
graph like this now to determine if a
transcript is good or bad when the
adversely three discs wearying we give
it a key and expand strangled with that
key in the real world Rocky is exactly
the rupee or a block cipher in the ideal
world the key just some random string
independent of something anything else
now this expand is transcript again can
be represented by a draft for example
here the graph tells us that if you ex
are the sub pl3 to restring be then
you'll get a string z now we say that an
extended transcript is bad if it's grab
contains some part that we call a chair
as highlighted here for Beth transcripts
is pretty easy to distinguish for
example here this transcript must comes
from the ideal world indeed initially
the trestle tells us that if you encrypt
why you should get Z but then when you
actually do the inclusion process by
following the chin then we end up with a
completely different cyber attacks which
is a contradiction
and recorded in the edge coefficient
technique you need to bow to numbers
epsilon 1 and epsilon 2 in this guy
batting excellent one is quite simple
but mounting ya number proves to be
difficult Shannon Steinberger provides a
pretty accurate estimation for the term
in epsilon 2 but when you substitute
that in the maximum popular you will end
up with a very poor Val so channelside
try to get around at by some twit but as
we saw earlier the bow is only a
synthetically tight so let's pause for a
moment and think why does the escalation
technique fail here the reason is that
it demands a single excellent tool for
all good transcripts see if just a
feel-good transcript misbehave you be
school together router in our
expectation matter we just demand that
for there must be some transit dependent
g of town for every good transcript ow
we then computer expectation value of
these val the expectation is taken over
all transcripts including bad ones so if
by doing this if just a feel-good
transcripts messer then our epsilon 2 is
still small and again the distinguishing
advantage is bounded by the sum of
epsilon 1 and epsilon 2 to understand
some intuition while it is true so
recall that the edge coefficient
technique want to buy all this blue area
by a big rectangle
and that can be a waste in some cases so
now instead we'll use some custom met in
a shape to approximate that if you use a
good bow then you can essentially have a
very tight estimation of the blue area
here to use the expectation method are
the KC problem recorded challenge
traveller re provide us with a very good
estimation and now all we need to do is
to compute an expectation value of this
formula the formula is cap complex but
fortunately its expectation is very easy
to compute and we are done with the
single user security of kc now let's
move on to the multi user setting we
will give a generic translation from
single to multi user security the
translation is conditional and we call
the condition point-wise proximity
specifically epsilon point where Spock
simply means that for any good
transcript for any transcript the gap
between the probability that the ideal
system produces this transcript and the
probability that a real system produces
it must be smaller than epsilon times
the ideal probability post why proximity
is a strong requirements because it
really implies that the distinguishing
advantage must be smaller than epsilon
so hours of says that and you can
establish by wise proximity for single
user security that you immediately get a
similar bow for
use of security so I stress that this
result needs some technical conditions
are the function epsilon but they're
these conditions are mine and therefore
open men's to understand why this
caterham is true let's first consider a
non-adaptive adversary meaning that
their constants q1 q2 and so on such
that that Bertram xq1 construction
queries on user 1 and so on so in this
setting if we use a habit admin that
already to do is to create some
intermediate system between the real
system and ID 1 and then use the single
use of security bow to fill the gap in
between X consecutive pairs this is
pretty standard but we need to be a bit
careful in accounting that verse reads
resources for example consider the
system's s0 and s1 now all we need to
care is just the construction queries on
the first user it's why they are only q1
construction queries instead of Q but
the construction queries are the other
users one vanish that easily internally
they will make some calls to the
primitives and so you have to account
for that primitive queries so the hybrid
agamous give us the sum of some epsilon
but what we want is a completely
different formula for the desires bow to
be bigger than the sum of these a salons
then we need the excellent functions to
satisfy some
super happy with the requirement and
that's the technical restriction that I
mentioned previously now the habit
argument that you just seen only works
for a non adaptive adversely for an
adaptive adversely there won't be a
priority Constance q1 q2 and so on to
resolve that if we look at an individual
transcript it will provide us with some
transcript dependent numbers q1 to q2
town and so on so intuitively at a high
level all we need to do is to repeat the
previous habit elements but at a
transcript level so that we can exploit
these numbers q1 town and so on but in
order for that to work you need some
sort of single user security bow at the
transcript level but that is exactly the
point wise proximity requirement summing
up so today we presented to protect eggs
for the KC problem namely the
expectation method and the truth generic
translation the former is very powerful
in getting comparably tight bowels and
it has applications beyond the scope of
KFC for example in our paper we also
consider the axial cascade construction
which is a generalization of death
heights but there must be other
applications for the torrent translation
it is camp elegance but it needs the
point-wise proximity condition not all
constructions meet these requirements
while Simon feistel network that will be
interesting to expand our results for
those unfitting cases
and that's it thank you thank you very
much