thank you for the introduction so this
is joint work with Vika Park ASCII and
Christina busca and when you're talking
about
statistically secure of the station with
approximate correctness the first
obvious question is what is
statistically secure for station and
it's a very short reminder an obfuscator
is basically just a program that gets us
input a circuit see and probably some
randomness and it outputs another
circuit C prime and what he would
usually want is perfect correctness
meaning that the output circuit should
be functionally equivalent to the input
circuit however we can sometimes get
away with much weaker definitions what
we are doing with this approximate
correctness approximate correctness
basically means that for a random input
the output circuit must agree with the
input circuit with probability at least
1 minus epsilon for some function
epsilon that basically describes the
approximation error of the obfuscator
the second thing we want from our
obfuscator is of course that it's secure
and what you would usually go with is
indistinct ability of the station and in
the statistical sense indistinct ability
obfuscation simply means that the if you
have two circuits that are functionally
equivalent and have the same size then
their statistical distance léo the
statistical distance of the obfuscation
must be negligible however we can also
weaken this definition to something that
we know a paper call correlation of the
station and there the difference is that
we no longer want that the statistical
distance was necessarily bounded by a
negligible function instead it's enough
that we know some function Delta that
bounce this statistical distance for the
main part of my talk I will actually
focus on the indistinct ability of the
SCADA simply to keep things a bit
simpler but I will mention how our
result also applies to correlation of
the scalars so the next obvious question
might be why we even care about
approximate correctness because an
approximately correct obfuscator might
seem like a multiple useful thing
it does not even a guarantee that it is
correct on any fixed input however it
turns out that it is in fact still
useful in particular it was observed by
Mahmud II Muhammad knew mati Hutchy Paz
and Sheila that you can still construct
a public key encryption from one way
functions if you have statistically
secure i/o approximately all and this is
basically done by just applying the
construction of the high-end waters that
usually constructs poplu key encryption
from one-way functions niño to an
approximate i/o and then you get
something that you can amplify using an
amplification technique due to Hornstein
to a full public key encryption scheme
and in our paper we show with the
careful analysis that this is not only
true for statistically secure
approximate i/o but this is even true
for correlation obfuscation for
everything for all the parameters
basically in this blue area here so that
means that even correlation Association
is still an interesting primitive and
it's a very interesting question to ask
whether it might exist especially in
this region for with statistical
security because it would lead to a
major breakthrough in crypto giving your
public key encryption from one-way
functions and our answer to that
question is mainly negative what we show
is that if statistically secure
approximately correct IO would exist
then either one-way functions do not
exist or the polynomial hierarchy
collapses and since we do not believe
that either one-way functions do not
exist or the polynomial hierarchy
collapses probably statistically secure
approximate ioad does not exist our
actual proof is more general in that it
also applies to correlation of physician
and it basically gives us a lower bound
on the possible parameters for
statistically correct
statistically secure approximately
correct correlation of the station how
our focal relation of the station we
also have a positive result where we can
for very weak parameters give a trivial
construction and this gives us this
landscape of correlation obfuscation
where in the
right we have a large area that we
actually know a trivial construction
however the construction is actually so
trivial that we are pretty certain that
it is completely useless on the other
hand we have down here the red range in
this range we cannot construct
correlation of the station with
statistical security unless the
polynomial hierarchy collapses or one
way functions do not exist however I
need to mention that we cannot rule out
the full range of parameters that are
actually useful for the transformation
to public image so how does our proof
work basically our the starting point
for all proof is the previous proof by
God Foster and wrote bloom and what they
showed was the impossibility of
statistically secure IO with perfect
correctness and they also rely on the
assumption that the polynomial hierarchy
does not collapse and what they do is
basically show how and statistically
secure obfuscator would help you in
solving set so the set problem is that
you you're given a formula it's either
unsatisfiable or satisfiable and you
have to decide which one it is and to be
able to use an obfuscator to do that we
look at another formula the formula 0 is
some canonical unsatisfiable formula it
doesn't matter what it is just we know
this formula is unsatisfiable and now we
obfuscate all of these formula and what
we get is that because the two
unsatisfiable formula are functionally
equivalent the security of the
obfuscator guarantees us that the output
distributions must be negligible close
on the other hand if we have a
satisfiable formula then by definition
this formula is not functionally
equivalent to a zero circuit because
they exist at least one point on which
it actually outputs one and because you
have perfect correctness in the
obfuscator this means that the output
distributions are actually completely
disjoint and now it turns out that the
problem of deciding where the two
distributions are either very close
statistically or very far
this is called the gap statistical
distance problem and it was proven by is
a high-end Vardhan that this problem is
actually in am intersect OEM which would
mean that we can decide sat in am
intersect OEM which would imply collapse
of the polynomial hierarchy so the next
obvious question is of course can we
just use exactly the same approach in
the approximate case and the answer is
no and to see why just consider that we
have a satisfiable formula that has very
few satisfying assignments I'd say it
only has a single satisfying assignment
then it actually disagrees with the zero
circuit only on a single point and
because we only have an approximate
obfuscator
the obfuscator can just ignore that
point obfuscate this satisfiable formula
to a zero circuit and therefore we no
longer have the guarantee that there
will be a large statistical distance so
how do we solve this problem
our approach is basically to obfuscate
more complicated circuits and for this
we construct two different circuits we
construct a reference circuit see why
and the circuit see X that's indexed
with a PRF key and a formula beside and
we construct these circuits in such a
way that if the formula precise
unsatisfiable then the two circuits are
functioning privileged and the output
distributions are once again negligibly
close on the other hand if Sai is
satisfiable then the two circuits are
almost functionally equivalent however
there exists a point we call x0 on which
they disagree now this may seem
confusing because I just spent some time
arguing that if you have two circuit
that only disagree on a single point an
obfuscator might choose to ignore that
point and that is why we basically have
to hide whether this point exists or not
so to do this to do this we introduce
another circuit see and this circuit is
constructed in such a way that it is
functioning provement to the reference
circuit however the obfuscator cannot
we distinguish between the circuit C X
and the circuit C and this allows us to
to ensure that the while the
distributions are no longer completely
disjoint that the statistical distance
is large and to be able to do this we
leverage the fact that the obfuscator is
actually an efficient algorithm even
though it must be statistically secure
it must itself be an efficient algorithm
to be useful and so we leverage here our
assumption that one-way functions exist
and this assumption is leverage in the
form of punctual surrender functions and
functions of random functions were shown
by Bonnie waters boiled goat versa even
and key ayahs of Otto Poulos treetopolis
aha yes basically concurrently to be
existentially equivalent to one wave
functions and we use a very simple
notion of functional PRF here where we
have two algorithms we have a PRF
algorithm that on input a key and an
input value outputs a single bit and we
have a puncture algorithm that on input
a key and a value x0 outputs a punctured
key and we want two things from a
punctual PRF first of all functionality
should be preserved on the puncturing
meaning that for all inputs that are not
X zero it makes no difference whether
you use the Patchett key or the normal
key second thing is of course security
and security for punctual PRF is defined
as follows you have the attacker the
attacker may choose a point X 0 on which
we should puncture the key we choose a
key K we puncture that key on X 0 and
then we have two cases either we give
the attacker the punctured key and the
actual PRF value on X 0 or we give the
attacker or we give the attacker the
punctured key and a random bit B and the
security states that the two cases
should be indistinguishable so how can
we use this to ensure that two circuits
that are that only differ on a single
point are obfuscated in such a way that
the the statistic distance is large and
to see this we first look at this
circuit this circuit is for now not
indexed by a formula instead we have a
punctured key K star here in value X 0
on which the key is punctured and a bit
B and what the circuit does is on X 0 it
simply outputs B on all other wellies it
outputs the PF circuit the EDPs value
and we can see that if B is not the PRF
value so our PF only outputs a single
bit so this means it's simply the PRF Lu
X or 1 then this circuit disagrees with
the PRF circuit on exactly a single
point on exactly x0 and what we want to
show is that the obfuscation of this
circuit is nevertheless statistically
far from an obfuscation of the PRF
circuit and to do this we look at the
other case we look at the case where B
is actually the PRF lon in this case we
have that this circuit is functionally
equivalent to the PRF circuit and this
has an interesting implication because
if we escaped the PRF circuit then we
guaranteed by the approximate
correctness that on X 0 the obfuscated
circuit will output B because b is the
actual PRF value and it will output this
with probability at least 1 minus
Epsilon however because the two circuits
are functionally equivalent we have
basically this bound carries over to
this case minus some negligible loss and
now we can leverage the fact that the
attacker le the office cater is actually
an efficient algorithm and use the PRF
security because the office gate is
actually not able to distinguish between
the two different cases because this is
exactly the security of the punctual PRF
so this bound also - again some
negligible loss carries over to this
case and this means what we have is that
if we would obfuscate the PRF circuit
then the PRF circuit outputs the correct
PRF value on X 0 with probability at
least
- epsilon whereas the obfuscated circuit
C disagrees with a prf circuit on X 0
with probability roughly 1 minus Epsilon
giving us a statistical distance of
roughly 1 minus 2 epsilon and therefore
we have enforced a large statistical
distance
even though the two circuits disagree
only on a single point now of course
what's missing here is still that we
have to somehow put our formula into
this and to be able to do this we
actually have to restrict our attention
to unique set so unique set is exactly
the same thing as sad except that you're
guaranteed that any satisfiable formula
has only a single satisfying assignment
now unique set it was shown to be NP
hard by valiant and Vassy Ronny
however only by a randomized reduction
and that's a problem because we can't
use the exact same approach as Godfather
and bloom because if we would show that
unique said is in am intersect Co a.m.
this would not directly apply imply that
sat is also in a.m. intersect koream
however we can combine previous results
due to Mahmud II and she'll and Bach
tano faintly to show that it's enough to
prove that unique set can be solved if
we are given a gap statistical distance
Oracle then this implies that that is in
a.m. it to say Co a.m. and the
polynomial hierarchy collapses so this
is what we're doing we are showing that
unique set can be decided if we have a
gap statistical distance Oracle so to do
this we are looking at this circuit here
this circuit CX is indexed with a key K
a random value s and a formula site and
what it does is it simply checks whether
the input value X or s satisfies in the
formula and if it does it outputs in the
opposite of the PRF value and otherwise
it's simply evaluates the PRF now there
are obviously two cases here either
site is uniquely satisfiable or besides
unsatisfiable now if sine is
unsatisfiable then this circuit is
functionally equivalent to the PRF
because well this is simply
a true because there is no satisfying
assignment in on the other hand in the
uniquely satisfiable case what we have
is that CX is actually function
equivalent to the circuit C we saw on
the previous slide for X zero being the
satisfying assignment of the formula X
or s and this is where the s is
important because we need that this
value x0 is uniformly distributed
otherwise the approximate correctness of
the obfuscation scheme does not apply
and of course B is here not the PRF
value but the opposite and what that
means is what that means is that if we
define these two distributions here that
basically only differ in that one
distribution obfuscates the circuit C X
and the other one obfuscates the PRF
circuit then in the unique in the
unsatisfiable case we have that the two
circuits are functional equivalent
meaning that the statistical distance
between their obfuscation z' is
negligible on the other hand in the
uniquely satisfiable case this circuit
as I said is functional equivalent to
the circuit C we saw on the previous
slide and what that means is that our
bound basically carries over again to
this case - again some negligible loss
meaning that we can bound this
statistical distance with roughly 1
minus 2 epsilon and this gives us a gap
between the two cases and this means and
this gap is large enough that we can
decide in which case we're in given a
gap statistical distance Oracle and that
means that if sa arrow and one-way
functions both exist then the polynomial
hierarchy collapses and this concludes
our proof and if we apply exactly the
same proof and very careful to
correlation of FISC action then we
basically end up with this lower bound
that I showed before and I can leave you
with the interesting open question where
the this bound can actually be extended
to also rule out this interesting region
here
or if there's a reason why we can rule
out this region because maybe an
obfuscator in this region actually
exists which would as I said lead to a
major breakthrough in crypto and with
that I'd like to thank you and if there
any questions I'd be happy to answer
them