so hello everybody thanks for coming
here after the run session my voice
didn't survive so bear with me but I
know that you survived it's nice so I'm
going to talk to you about a bunch of
nice properties that we can get in you
see commitments and the new techniques
that we use to get there first of all I
want to give you an introduction about
water commitment so are they good for
and more the properties you're looking
at then I'll talk you talk to you a
little bit about these related words
which are kind of a long line of
research the lads and the result we have
here today and our results the general
framework that we use to achieve that
then yet our actual construction I'm
gonna jump the broom cuz it takes a lot
of time to talk about that then I'm
going to talk to you a little bit about
the concrete performance and the open
problems that we still have in this line
of work so first of all what our
commitment schemes you can think of it
as a box where you can put a message
lock the bolts send the ball to the
other side from Alastair bulb now ball
has the bolts with the message inside
but Bob doesn't know what the message
inside the box is later on Ellis can
just send Bob the keys which opened the
box which allow Bob to get the message
out of the box now Bob is also
guaranteed that Alice didn't change the
message from the time when she actually
sent the box and the time when she sent
them the key so this we call this hiding
property that Bob cannot see the message
and the binding property that Alice
cannot change the message after she
sends the box now why would care about
these things so commitments are good for
a number of applications in different
cryptographic protocols for example
multi-party computation I you might have
heard about that already a lot but just
a quick introduction let me learn his
problem you have to reach people who
want to know who's there
just but they don't want to tell each
other how much money they actually have
so they can run a protocol that just
tells them who's the richest but doesn't
really reveal how much money each of
them has so that's one of the
applications Modi party computation can
be used in a number of scenarios such as
the beetroots auction which I have to
mention of course because i work in
denmark and we also have some new
results showing that we can use this
kind of commitments to get very
efficient gavotte circuits not adaptive
Zarah i was talking about but
aesthetically secure playing y'all but
it was very good efficiency so this is a
nice primitive we have good applications
for that now we also talked about
universal composability so we get this
universally composable commitment and
why is that good for well in universal
composability you can be sure that your
protocol can be executed in parallel
with copies of itself or with other
protocols without losing security which
is a property that we use when you
especially for protocols for schemes
like commitments they're an important
building block of other protocols we
also know that in the UC framework
commitments are actually complete
meaning that if you have commitments you
can compute any other well-behaved let's
say computable functionality and which
is lies so there are very powerful
primitives and if you get that with with
certain efficiency it's nice so you have
good applications so we also know that
in you see you need set up assumptions
if you want to do any interesting to
multi-party protocol so you need
something that was there in the
beginning like a common reference string
to come and random string a public a
registration facility and so on in our
case will we use old tea as I'm going to
tell you later but just so you know that
something you need it's not what it's
not like we're cheating now a little bit
of other properties the title is really
big great one linear time
and efficiently computable blah blah
blah so what is all that stuff that we
talked about first of all homomorphism
we are going to talk about basically
editing homomorphism which is the
following imagine you have two boxes now
one with a yellow-orange message and one
with a blue message and you want to
combine them in a way to get a box with
a white message inside so you can do
that if you have a negatively
homomorphic commitment it means that you
can give Bob both boxes with different
messages and he can add those boxes in a
way that he obtains the result the added
message inside Oh later on you can send
him a combination of opening information
let's say the keys added together in a
way that he can open this box and
obtained only the addition of both
messages but not the original messages
now also rate we talked about rate one
so what does it mean when I talk about
right one let's say you have a message
that sends its long and a commitment
that's elbit slow the rate here is the
ratio between the n bits and the L beats
so in this case if you have a small
message in a very long commitment we get
a bad low rate because we have a huge
communication overhead let's say where
we blow up the commitment size compared
to the message size now in the case
where you have a message that is small
its and beats and a commitment of our
baits that it's also close message size
you get a rate approaching one which is
a good rate which is a high rate which
means you don't have a large
communication overhead now i'll start
with related words pre 2014 what did we
have in terms of you see commitments we
had this work by yahoo darling down at
first and then an improvement of that by
blasi and others where they beautiful
you see commitments from ddh they use a
common reference string as a set of
assumption but there are some problems
they have highest in telecommunication
income
complexity why because they need to keep
doing a lot of modular exponentiation
for every message they compute their
private message they commit you they
need zero knowledge proofs which require
several rounds unless you're willing to
use a random Oracle which we're not
dealing with here so you need several
rounds for proving the statements they
have lots of exponentiation and they
have lots of rounds that are
consequently applied by the zero
knowledge chronicles so we want to get
rid of all that we don't want the high
complexity both computation and
communication and we don't want this
huge round complexity now how do we do
that this is our general framework as a
setup assumption we have ulti we assume
Saturday's we do the center phase where
we do a fixed number of ot's only and
after that we can do it unbounded of
course a polynomial number of
commitments that only use primitives in
mini crypt after the initial tekes which
we can really minimize using with the
extensions so let's say we do 200 OTS
after that we can just use our
correcting codes Citarum generators and
hash functions to commit to an arbitrary
number of messages which is nice because
then the complexity of this 200 OTS gets
amortized over the number of messages
that we commit to now back to who did
that I mean this started in 2014 we
don't work by God I sheikha Morrison and
we inherit where they show how to get
rate one using more or less the general
framework but still they didn't get
linear computational complexity nor
homomorphism then in the same year we
mean me even tomboy in any giacomelli
and yes for booze neason we showed how
to get complete a linear computational
complexity for the receiver getting
fully homomorphism meaning that we can
both compute additions and
multiplication of commitments but still
a straight one so you see we have a
compromise you still on a related note
but I'm don't show this year and pkc how
to construct the similar results who got
I and others where you have rate one but
not the other properties using different
techniques so God I and others used VSS
Opie's and children and generators to
construct this primitive why Oh Brando
started from a standalone equivocal
commitment instead alone extractable
commitment and bound all those together
with collision resistant hash functions
and got efficiency through pseudo-random
generators now last year we showed how
to get full linear complexity for both
the sender and receiver but still no
right one and we got only additive
homomorphism not full morphism but Ellis
we got good computational black City
then this year's TCC yes / booties sen
tov ericsson and roberto facility and
thomas jacobson showed how to get rate
one and additive homomorphism but they
lost linear computational complexity so
we're here in a conundrum can you
actually get all these properties at
once in one single scheme the scheme
that we had last seen pkc doesn't get
rid one we get the other properties but
not right one now the scheme by 80
hellicksen and others this uccc gets
rate what a normal morphism but still
they have bad commutation of a black
city can we actually get both yes we can
let's make commitments great again we
can combine the same general structure
of our results from last year with new
the first actually write one linear time
in Kota Buchholz bless that new nice
technique to check that many strings are
actually cold words and we get that so
on a theoretical side what do we do we
get optimal communication complexity
amortize communication
let me be clear because we need the
initial setup Faisal tease but after
that the complaints that gets amortized
over the many commitments that it can
make we get written one asymptotically
we also get optimal computational
complexity the commitment and the
opening phases are both linear time
computable and we get additive
homomorphism why do we put an asterisk
there because we can actually get
multiplicative homomorphism although
unfortunately when we do that we lose
our other nice properties and we
actually have a very good reason to do
so there is a basic fact an upper bound
of coding theory that we can use the
show that using our techniques you won't
get motor purgative homomorphism with
rate one or good computational
complexity who need radically different
techniques to do that so that's one of
the open problems i'm going to talk
about later we we also round optimal
after the setup phase after the initial
tease the sender only needs one round to
commit and run round to open so that's
also nice now on the practical side you
can actually implement I mean if you
read a tireless a very theoretical paper
but it can actually plement that very
efficiently I'm going to talk more about
that later and the building blocks are
readily available we can use any prgs
based on a yes and I and so on and the
actual error correcting codes that it
can use to implement these efficiently
although without their synthetic
properties are readily available for
example in the linux kernel now if you
compare with the previous results in our
results we get all the properties we get
linear computational complexity we get
rate one so optimal communication
complexity and we get additive
homomorphism one good thing I hope they
will make you look at the paper we can
get rate above one actually if we're
committing to random messages so for
random messages we do this funny trick
and we can we actually reach a rate
above one which seems funny but we have
some words about that at the paper so
please look at that now our building
blocks we need our tracking codes
together asymptotic
sults we built the first rate one linear
time in potable coats we had raped on
coats and linear time incredible calls
before but not goals that had both
properties at once we built the first
such codes from expanded rats I'm not
going to elaborate much on that is it's
a complex matter but you can of course
look at the paper and we need oblivious
transfer any to CLT will do so you can
choose your assumptions these are
basically the main public key
assumptions we need so any if you like
when a marker you can sense she ate our
scheme from ana Moura call if you like
to the age you can instance a shower
skin from the eh if you want both
grunting security you can stay shade our
scheme from coding assumptions or
lattice basic assumptions we need a
cigarette and generator so to get our
asymptotic results we need a linear time
so the running generator there are some
fortunately by um and others and we need
a almost universal hash function that is
both linear and linear and linear time
computable which we also build in our
paper the flu the first such function
with some ideas from Michael's now a bit
of other primitives little T you you're
probably most familiar eyes with that
but in OT a senator puts into messages a
receiver gets only one of the messages
and he's oblivious to which was the
other message now we will start with the
setup phase that is based on OT we start
with several several random seeds to the
pseudo-random generator we put them into
all these so for every pair of seeds we
put them into an OT BOTS the receiver
will be actually putting in random
choice bits and you'll get health of the
seats alright health of the seeds in
random subset now will next proceed to a
commit face basically where we commit to
a bunch of strings let me just be clear
that you don't get to do only one of
these batch commit phases after the
setup you can do a link the number of
the
but of course I'm only describing one so
in this phase you start by stretching
each of the seats with the prg into big
streets now this big strings will be
composed by some random data that we
want to stay random anyway and buy some
trailing data that will eventually
become error correction very very bit
basically so you first get these random
strings that you stretched from the
seeds that's one of the reasons why we
got actually right one you don't have to
send all this information at the
beginning you just send it a small seeds
that get out more times later now for
every of these big screens maybe you saw
here I'm saying are 10 r 11 r 20 or 21 i
have pairs of the strings for every pair
of seats now for each of the spares what
do you do you exhort them together is
something together because this result
actually works for any field then you
get a final string which is your final
random stuff and your final almost
parity bits now what do you do with this
you still don't have a code word because
you're very bits are still random stuff
so you compute the parity bits for this
random string in the beginning of our
long string you build and the final goal
board let's say you have a code in
systematic form so you have the your
random data and then actual parity bits
error correction data then you compute
correction bits let's call them that
when XOR with this random stuff will
actually give the actual parity bits you
compute it all now you end up with this
information as a sander you have several
Cold War's or at least they should be if
you're honest and you have several
correction bits that when X or to the
first random parity bits that we sent
will result in the actual parity bits
now you use that's where the magic comes
in in this paper when the
our main techniques is that we show how
to use this almost universal in your
hash function to to prove that this
strings are actually cold words because
you see a adversary could just send you
random stuff that when X or together
later when you're doing homomorphic
operations opens up to completely
arbitrary messages they're unrelated to
the actual messages they committed to
but then we show this nice technique
that you can use almost universal in
your hash functions to show that these
strings are actually cold words and but
by only sending very little information
only the result of the hash functions so
what do we do we get this matrix of
supposedly cold words and we hash each
row with the almost universal linear
hash functions we get the result of each
probe oui oui of course send it all to
the receiver and other receiver will
only receive the correction bits that
will turn the random stuff you receive
the first into proper parity bits and
the hash values now why is it good why
is it because at first we don't have to
say we're actually sending last
information then the size of the
messages were committing to we are
committing to this big arse but are only
sending the little correction bits so
here we're actually getting rate above
one that's why we can get right above
one for random messages if you only want
to have random messages here now the
receiver gets this and the receiver does
some checking that's far the technique
as well the receiver only has some of
this our values for each pair he cannot
reconstruct the whole community string
he only has half of it but we show that
it is enough for him to have half of it
such that when he does the computation
of the hash values of the roles of the
only of the columns he has which are
only health he can still check with with
high probability later on window
opening happens that whatever the center
committed to was actually a proper code
word a proper commitment now to get the
actual parity bits in he needs to add
the correction bits but you see here
that everything is doing is computing
and an encoding of a linear time in
color book called enter in addition
lyric time operations so we get linear
complexity and right right here what
happens we are committed to random
messages we're committed to this ours
well not these ours the proper ours they
were computed by X sorry each pair but
actually you don't want to just commit
to random stuff all the time you might
want to commit to arbitrary messages so
what you do stand a trick you use the
random messages you're committed to is a
one-time pad kee to one-time pad encrypt
your actual arbitrary message then you
get a commitment of the same size as a
message now again ah now on the note of
our rate one you get you got the
correction bits and now you get the
message but the correction bits can be
really small because we have raped one
codes that's why I get right right one
in the opening we basically check the
error correction parity bits and then we
subtract the random message from this
small commitment and we got the message
standard trick we're linear time and we
get right one by doing that now what can
we do in practice I'm here to tell you
you see commitments are practical you
like ot extensions so you should like
our our commitments we get basically the
same performances of the extensions for
50,000 commitments we can do commitments
in 29 microseconds and decommit in 0.2
we only need bch codes are implemented
in Linux kernel and PR jeez asni of
course you have a trade-off we need the
OTS the satyr protease 50,000
commitments takes 1.5 seconds so summer
here and we have some open problems how
to actually get multiplicative
homomorphism basically
while maintaining our nice complexities
which we don't know how to do right now
let's work on it and thank you for your
attention