okay thank you very much do you hear me
that's just fine good yeah good moring
I'm very happy to be here very excited
to be here at Krypton I really enjoyed
the weather in Santa Barbara I enjoyed
it so much that two nights ago at the
annickap alone I got a bad sore throat
so I will try my best but if you don't
understand just raise your hand wave and
I will repeat good so in this work we
studied the quantum security of
classical encryption schemes before you
start shouting post quantum wait a
second
so just to fix the ideas I'm only going
to talk about symmetric key encryption
scheme or secret Keys encryption schemes
this is I mean there's nothing fancy
here it's one of the simplest
cryptographic primitives that you can
think of you just have one secret key
and then you have one encryption
procedure and one decryption procedure
each of them map respectively plaintext
to ciphertext and cybertek's to plain
text and this primitive is classic so
whenever you see the yellow box it's a
classic encryption scheme okay so what
can we say about the security of of this
encryption primitives so usually when we
model security of the schemes we have
something like this in mind so we have
some adversary and since we look at
computational security here we consider
the adversary to be bounded a
polynomially bounded machine and the
adversary interacts in a classical way
with the scheme and after some
interaction it breaks the security of
the scheme whatever it means so then
when we look at the security of the
schemes against quantum adversaries so
what what we usually do is we give the
adversary access to a quantum computer
so now we model the adversary as a
bounded quantum machine but the
interaction with the scheme is still
Seagal because this game is a classical
object and this is usually what we call
post quantum security now I would like
to show you why this might not be enough
sometimes so there might be cases where
you want to give a bit more power to the
adversary so usually what the model that
we have in mind is something like this
so we have an adversary and the others
are is trying to compromise the security
of some external target some user but
what might happen in reality is
something similar to this scenario so
the target of the adversary might be a
tiny encryption device using some fancy
technology we already have chips using
you know optoelectronics components and
optic fiber so one thing become more and
more like this people start having fun
and become creative so this is what
happens so what you see here is a
commercially available equipment for
performing fault analysis attacks on
chips so you know there are this crazy
hacker people having a lot of fun
shining lasers into your chip and
pouring liquid nitrogen on it and
changing the voltage of the electricity
and by interacting in with the device in
an unexpected way they can extract
information we should not be available
and this is this thing's was supposed to
be you know science fiction until I
don't know 20 years ago but nowadays we
have a whole branch of cryptography
devoted to designing systems resistant
to this kind of attacks so what we
advocate in this case is the following
quantum security beyond post quantum
security what we mean is that the
adversary might be able to get quantum
interaction with the classical device
this is this was our first motivation
but there are other scenarios where this
is this might happen so very briefly for
example you might consider the case
where a classical primitive is used as a
sub protocol or a component or of a more
complex or involved quantum protocol and
then it's not clear how the security of
the classical primitive combines with
the security of the role protocol this
is what's important in security
reduction you might also have this kind
of fort attack let's call it so we're a
honnest user wants to run a classical
algorithm hare quantum computer and then
at the end of the measurement at the end
of the computation measure the outcome
in order to have a classical result to
send over the internet or whatever and
then your adversary might temper and
interfere with the measurement operation
and be able to assess quantum
information before the measurement
finally you might also have obfuscation
so the adversary might receive the code
for performing encryptions in an
obfuscated form but then he might run it
on his quantum computer and then to some
extent it might be able to at least
partially you know interact quantumly
with the widow classical primitive so
this sounds strange we are not the first
one to consider this kind of of model in
particular I want to mention this work
by Bonnie and xandrie from 2013 where
they look at the security of encryption
scheme and of classical encryption
scheme and they model the fact that the
adversary could be able to perform
quantum queries of this form so instead
of asking for the encryption of one
message and receiving back the
encryption the adversary might query the
encryption Oracle on a superposition of
messages and get back a superposition of
encryptions so what's the situation so
far the situation so far so then the
results from their paper look as follows
so first of all if you try to define
reasonable or at least an intuitively
intuitively good notion of security in
this model what you obtain is a Ana chi
is an unachievable security notion then
what you can do is to obtain a
compromise so to switch to an almost
classical security notion and this
compromise works because you can show
that it's achievable and it's strictly
stronger then indistinguishability under
chosen plaintext attack which is the
standard that let's say the minimal
security notion that you consider
classically and the situation looks like
this so on one end you have equivalent
notions of indistinguishability and
semantic security for the classical
world on the quantum side you have a
very strong notion that you can not
achieve and in between somehow you have
this almost classical
indistinguishability notion so what we
do oops what we do is we extend this
framework and we complete the you know
that the framework for analyzing the
security of of encryption schemes by
defining a new security notion quantum
indistinguishability we show that it's
strictly stronger than other previous
notion we show that it's achievable and
then we show equivalent notions of
semantic security and let's see how we
do it so in this thing we shall be
anything indistinguishability is a
security notion for encryption scheme
where you have an adversary the
adversary produces two plain texts of
his choice the two plaintiffs are sent
to a Challenger and the Challenger
selects one of the true plaintext at
random without telling the adversary
encrypts it and sends back the
encryption to the adversary and we call
this the challenge phase the goal of the
adversary is to guess which one of the
two plaintext was encrypted click this
is a classical notion and also it can be
extended to a stronger notion which is
called indistinguishability under chosen
plaintext attack where we give the
adversary the possibility of performing
one learning phase before and after the
challenge faced by learning phase I mean
the adversary is allowed to query a
polynomial number of times the
encryption Oracle adaptively on
plaintext of his choice
so what Bonnie and Xandra did this
almost 1 - almost classical security
notion is they extend the security
notion to a quantum adversary where the
learning phase is now quantum but the
challenge phase is still it is the
classic so why is this so first of all
they show that this notion is a tree
bubble and if 3 it's strictly stronger
than the classical one it and you might
wonder why don't why can't you just do
quantum indistinguishability phase as
well well what happens is that if you
try to do this in the more natural way
you obtain this notion which is
unachievable
it's unachievable because there is an
attack which is completely independent
of the encryption scheme that you
consider and it always allows the
adversary to distinguish the encryption
of difference at our positions if you
have questions I can show you later this
so yeah this notion is unachievable what
we did instead is the following so we
started from this consideration and we
looked at the implicit assumption that
you have to make in order to define this
unachievable notion and then we said ok
can we do something different I mean
whenever we we have to make a choice can
we can we do something different and by
looking at all the options we span this
tree of security definitions and then we
look at it so the by choice I mean I
don't know can we rule out some form of
entanglement
how can we give additional constraints
of the adversary so the first thing we
do is we cut off the tree we cut off the
branches which do not make sense because
some of these options are are not
compatible with each other from from
what is left we remove the notions which
are still unachievable because of the
same attack of the fully quantum notion
and then of amongst the few left
candidates we pick up the one which is
more it's more targeted to our security
model and I I don't have time to go into
the detail of how we do this but very
briefly just to give you an idea these
are the main differences with the
unachievable notion so in the
unachievable notion whenever you have an
encryption Oracle this is basically
assumed to be a gate like a quantum gate
embedded in the circuit of the adversary
and this models a scenario where the
adversary has almost complete control of
the encryption power of the encryption
device or in this case the target in our
case instead we look at this model so we
consider a challenger as an external
device as an external quantum circuit
and the adversary has some communication
channel with this Challenger so he can
query that the Challenger runs a
proposition of of encryption which is
more suited to you know a network
scenario where the adversary wants to
compromise some external target another
difference is the following so usually
what what you might consider is the
adversary selects one quantum state of
his choice this state is sent to the
Challenger the Challenger encrypts the
state and send it back we consider
something slightly different where the
adversary is not allowed to
quantum states directly to the
Challenger but he is only allowed to
select a classical description of a
quantum state then this quantum state is
going to be built by the Challenger
encrypted and sent back what do I mean
by classical description it's it's
nothing terrible it's I don't mean that
the adversary has to specify the
amplitudes of the state I only mean that
the adversary specifies the quantum
circuit producing the state why we do
this the reason is that classically
there is no difference between a message
and the classical description of the
message in the quantum world there is a
huge difference because the former I
mean if you can fiend up if you can
directly feed the message to the
Challenger you can entangle yourself
with the state and this is something
which we consider a bit unreasonable in
our scenario but we can get rid of this
well I will show you later
the last thing is usually when you
consider encryption operations this is
what what is done in this is the
canonical way of evaluating a classical
function as a unitary you you do it like
this because this allows you to revert
to invert the operation even if the
function is not invertible but in our
case we are not dealing with one-way
functions or anything like that we are
dealing with encryptions with by their
own nature they are reversible
operations so what you can do is this
type of operation instead so you can
simply encrypt on the fly you know that
the quantum register now these kind of
operations are very well known and
studied and you might know them as
minimal Oracle's and it is well known
that they are very different from what
we call type 1 in particular they are
more powerful because if you want to
build a circuit computing the type to
operation you need the secret key
despite this we can show that in our
model
they are both acceptable so by keeping
in mind this differences we define our
notion of quantum indistinguishability
under quantum cruising plaintext attack
it is easy to see that it's at least as
strong as the other achievable notions
but we can say more we can say that it's
strictly stronger and how do we do this
well consider the following scheme this
is a very standard encryption scheme
which uses a pseudo-random function to
generate a key for the one-time pad
basically it's a it's a the standard
construction that you probably know from
your textbooks and Bonnie and Zander
showed that as long as the PRF is
quantum secure this notion this scheme
achieves their security notion but what
we what we can show is that this scheme
is insecure according to our notion and
this is a consequence of a more general
impossibility result that we give which
covers a much broader range of
encryption schemes the impossibility
result goes as follows so whenever you
consider an encryption scheme which
works by you know taking the plaintext
encrypting it and appending some
randomness independent of the plaintext
we say that whatever is not independent
of the plaintext is what we call the
core function of the cipher and we say
that a scheme is quasi length preserving
if the score function is a bijection
basically it means that the scheme does
not meaningfully increase the size of
the encryption in respect to the size of
the plaintext and there are a lot I mean
a lot of examples we have
like this so for example I keep spoiling
my slides I'm sorry
for example the gold rect scheme
one-time pads block ciphers in ECB mode
stream ciphers these are all all of them
are of this form and our impossibility
result is if you have a scheme which is
quasi length preserving then it cannot
be secured according to our definition
which is terrible because then you might
wonder okay what do you do with the
security definition what's the problem
here
the problem is that you know whenever
you have an encryption procedure this
works by mapping plaintext to a
ciphertext space in an unpredictable way
but for a quasi length preserving scheme
this mapping is actually a permutation
on a smaller subspace which is somehow
easy to identify so what happens now is
that yes so you see if you have so you
have one plaintext this is mapped to a
ciphertext in this smaller subspace and
therefore if you have a distribution of
plaintext this is mapped to a
distribution on the smaller ciphertext
but keeping the amplitudes and now you
see the problem because if this
distribution becomes smoother also the
target distribution as spread as it can
be it gets smoother and smoother until
you arrive at you know the uniform
distribution and the uniform
distribution is mapped to a uniform
distribution of ciphertext in the target
space what does it mean it means that
there are quantum states quantum
superposition of messages which are left
unchanged by the encryption operation
and this is a consequence of the fact
that in the quantum world if you want to
encrypt one qubit you need
two bits of classical information we
have seen it at the talk by if Kay
before that for the quantum one-time pad
you need one bit
for the form asking 0 1 & 1 bit for
masking plus minus so these states are
easy to distinguish and then you it's
clear that you cannot reach satisfiable
security a security argument if you have
this problem how do we overcome this
problem well this is our solution we
consider an additional randomness space
next to the plain text space and we
merge the two spaces together at this
point what happens is that the mapping
of the quasi length preserving scheme is
broken in the sense that now you don't
have anymore this easily identifiable
subspace in particular now if you have a
uniform distribution a uniform supper
position of plaintext
this is mapped this is spread in a
larger space in an unpredictable way
depending of the of the randomness so if
you change the randomness it's spread in
a different way you change the
randomness again it's spread in a
different way how do we what do we do
with this well we consider a family of
quantum resistant pseudo random
permutations then our encryption key is
a permutation and it's inverse and when
we want to encrypt a message what we do
is we just so first we append some
randomness to the state and then we
encrypt and this construction is secure
according to our definition of course it
does not keep the size of the plaintext
but this is exactly what we need for
achieving this level of security and
yeah the idea of the proof is to
consider the mixer and the mixer state
coming out from the encryption okay so
just to sum up I'm just in time this is
the situation that we have now so we
have
we completed this framework for studying
the security of classical encryption
scheme in in the quantum world there is
more so first of all we show that the
assumption of the classical description
is not necessary we can get rid of that
because all of our results basically
holds even for arbitrary quantum states
the only thing is that this classical
description makes things a lot easier
and it's more reasonable in our in our
scenario where the adversary is not able
to to watermark somehow the Challenger
next what we do is we can show we can
extend our construction basically we use
our construction with some sort of
randomized the ECB mode of operation so
we can extend it to deal with messages
of arbitrary size so we are not
restricted to you know one block
depending on the size of the permutation
but we can deal with arbitrary messages
and finally some other interesting
directions to look at look at public
encryption everything should work fine
in theory but better be careful so we
haven't really looked at that CCA
security again cc1 should be trivial to
extend CCA through as much three here
and finally a patch a general patch to
transform
schemes security according to the almost
classical definition in two schemes
secure secure according to our
definition so this concludes my talk
thank you very much and if you have
questions
you