okay thank you - hello everybody I'm
gonna talk today about Terim a protocol
for oblivious RAM in two rounds
johnross on demand payment so I'm gonna
start with the motivation so the main
motivation forum is private cloud
storage and so the main problem have
there is that we like to store our files
in the cloud without revealing any
information right so okay that's easy so
on solution we can have as we can
encrypt our files with a CPA secure
scheme so that protects the content of
the file but unfortunately it's not
enough we want to achieve more ambitious
goals so we want to if we observe which
files are being accessed this will
reveal anything about the corners on the
file okay so we like to hide the access
pattern where we're accessing the files
okay and this is what oblivious Ram
gives you okay so oblivious Ram
basically is a way to access a
collection of files in a way that the
access pattern is not revealed okay so
let me give an informal definition of
oblivious Ram so we have an array of n
entries and so what I want to have now
is want to access one a tree out of this
array access X okay so I'm gonna use
this Orem protocol to access this entry
X so this Orion protocol is going to
start accessing a bunch of entries and
then it's gonna output a of X okay so
this is the real world so in the ideal
world we have again we want to access X
but we don't give this X to the
simulator with just simulator only gets
to see like the size of the array right
and then he gets to perform some
accesses in this in this array and it
outputs something so now if adversary
observes just this axis and
made a brother simulator he cool she
soon be able to distinguish which world
he's in okay so this and from our
definition of forum so some something
about existing work so before so a knave
way to solve the problems just access
everything so this is basically to
access one blog you need to access like
a linear number of log so this is not
good
so in 1990 by the work of Rafael
Ostrovsky we saw that we can do that in
logarithmic overhead so if you access
like to access obliviously one block you
just need to access a point logarithmic
number of blocks which was pretty cool
that created a sequence of a lot of
works based on this hierarchical
framework I was introduced by Bharathi
and there's a lot of papers since then
there was another framework that was
introduced in 2011 in Asia Creed by
citizens the fan of anime which is a
tree based framework okay and this solid
is phenomenal different than the
hierarchical one and again there were a
lot of papers since then so three based
approaches for oblivious from seem to be
leading to more practical
implementations so in particular a with
a three based approach with Orem there's
no need for the amortization of
worst-case cost so everything is poor
logarithmic in the worst case you can
observe up to 100 X speed-up over here
our process and there was actually shown
that you can also implement it in
hardware and they like secure oblivious
and professional was was being built
called phantom okay so so in essence I
mean since that the three based
framework is more practical than here
article on okay so this work is about
non interactive tree based or on okay
so the problem is that most oblivious
Rams require interaction and typically a
pulley logarithmic number of rounds in
particular when you do an access you're
required to download decrypt do some
computation early encrypts upload a
number of times okay so this creates
naturally this creates some interaction
okay it's not hours of the first one
that does not interactive Orem in
particular it has been shown how you can
turn hierarchical or arms to non
interactive by Williamson in 2012 and by
you know stroke in 2013 since they
follow the here iframe the costs are
linear in the worst case but you can be
amortize them and make them pull
logarithmic in the in the worst case and
you can also have no interaction by just
doing garbled around directly but this
will have a big cost okay so so
motivated by the fact that three based
or am seem to be more practical and in
her columns we want to build a
non-interactive three based Orem our
worst-case costs are poor logarithmic so
there's no need for the amortization and
we use the path Orem design
okay so subsequent to our work that was
also a non interactive or I'm based on
the tree based framework bucket Orem the
stability cause were similar and are
something is either is a bit similar
okay so so let me describe our approach
now and I will start with some path or
am basics so the goal is that we have
here eight blocks okay and we want to
academically viously the way we're going
to do it is we're going to distribute it
at random in a tree of eight lives okay
so we just throw these blocks in this
tree they can go into any node okay and
now we're gonna keep a position map
where it's going to tell us look if you
to acess block one you should start from
leaf three and go up the route and
eventually out on this path you're going
to find this block okay so you want
access block for you so start from leaf
eight go up and you're gonna find this
block okay so this is what the position
map tells you okay so so if you want to
read for example block for now what's
gonna happen is you're gonna read this
path now you're going to download this
path right locally you're going to
decrypt it and you can read the
information now the problem is when you
want to write it back you need to make
sure that you change you change the
position of block four because you don't
want to read the same position when you
read block four again this will break
security so what you do is you turn you
pick another atom number and you assign
block four to leave three okay and you
rewrite this path again so now block
four went up to the root and it can be
accessed by just going up from firmly
three I'm just talking about existing
path or I'm not just okay so that's how
it works I mean this is a very simple
version of it now so there's a notion of
recursion so this is linear space so it
could go up like this but then we're
gonna have to store linear space so you
have to actually do a norm on the
position map so the way to do that is to
view this position map as an array of
four entries instead of eight okay and
now you're going to put that in a
different aura okay so you're gonna this
requires a position map of four entries
itself so you store this data the actual
data or another tree and now you have
another position lab okay so okay so now
let's see how it works if you want to
read block seven you're gonna go to the
first to the position map you have now
and you say okay so seven will fall into
the fourth bucket so I'm gonna be
accessing the fourth leaf of the first
three okay so you go there okay so you
access this
for cliff you start from the root going
down okay you access the fourth leaf and
all of a sudden at the second level you
find the entry that corresponds to seven
okay so you pick that entry so this is
the entry here and this has two values
the left value is from seven and the
right value is for eight okay so you're
gonna that means that you need to access
leaf six in the other tree so that's how
you continue the execution so you go
down this other tree and you're
guaranteed to find actual the value for
leaf seven so this is G okay so you have
a position map for the first three and
the second and the this three stores the
position map of the second tree okay
so now what we observe now the
interaction comes on the following thing
right so you need to access the first
three decrypt the information figure out
what is the next leaf of the other tree
right and then access the other tree
okay so so that creates the interaction
so how can we avoid it okay so let's
abstract the problem out a little bit
and let's consider like a like a morass
the problem that that captures what I
talked about before so the actual
problem is imagine have a sequence of
trees of binary trees okay and then
every node of this binary tree is some
computation right so it's some logical
it stores some data and it has some
logic take some input and it has some
output okay so so now what you want to
do is you have an encrypted input that
you give it you give it at the first
route okay and now you also give it a
path a path number saying that okay you
should go down the second path okay so
you execute you execute the computation
here you provide another out
for this note here and then as you go
down this path you guaranteed to output
the path to be followed in the next
three okay so the computation along this
path will give you the path to follow in
the next three and then the computation
along this path will give you the path
to following the next three and the
computation along this path will give
you the path to follow the next three
and eventually by following the last
path the output of the computation will
be spit out by the last leaf okay so
this is basically what's happening
what's happening with tree around now
with tea or on the with path around the
data and logic is basically you know you
just trying to check if the sink ribbit
input matches the data that are stored
in its node and once it matches there
you can figure out the path to follow at
the next three okay so we want to solve
this problem without interaction right
now this requires interaction because we
have to download the paths decrypt run
the computation ourselves and then
continue the computation from the next
three okay and we only want to leak the
public inputs to one and six which are
the paths but are being accesses we
don't leak any information about the in
credit input we give in the beginning
you can think of physically disabled as
the original index we would like to
access okay so this is so if we solve
this problem we can solve who can do
non-interactive three ora path Aram okay
so let's try to see how can solve let's
try fully homomorphic encryption it's
very powerful so what we can do is we
can encrypt the input with a fully
homomorphic encryption scheme right and
then we have the public key input which
is the the path we need to go down
you run the computation here with a
fully homomorphic encryption input it it
gives you an output you ran it again
here but the output of the fully
homomorphic encryption scheme is always
encrypted right so we expect that this
computation will give you the next path
to to access so I guess it's going
give it to you but it's gonna be
encrypted so it's useless so the server
cannot use it right because fully
homomorphic encryption will output the
next path to be accessed encrypted so
again to continue you have to send it
back decrypt it and say ok continue the
execution from this path so full how
much encryption will not work ok so so
one way to do it is remember who had
this this computation here we have this
computation here so one way to do it is
we're gonna start computing garbled
circuits for this computation on every
node of the tree
remember it's not in the street stores
different data so the garbage circuit is
going to be different right so we need
to compute different garbled circuits
for every node of the tree and it's very
important to compute them bottom-up
right and I'm gonna say why so you can
put the garbage circuits of the previous
circuit that I sent I saw to you for the
leaves of this tree for this nodes and
so on and so forth and you continue like
this right so ok so say we have computed
garbled circuit we have sent the garbage
circuits and I want to do the execution
so what's going to happen is we're going
to send the garbled input for the first
route ok
that's going to execute right but then
it's gonna output something if they're
an encryption of the result of the out
or not but then it's not going out with
the garble inputs for the next thing
right we want garble inputs for the next
thing so one way to do it is to send the
result back compute new garbled inputs
and execute the second circuit ok so
that's not gonna work so we need to
change this circuit that would garble it
it's not a little bit so the way to do
it is that was our original circuit that
we used to garble so it had input and
output now what we're gonna do is we're
gonna hard code in this circuit the
garble labels of the left circuit and
the garbled labels of the right circuit
these are all garble inputs these are
garbled labels ok and now we can also
give us
input to the circuit the path that is
being followed okay so given the path
the circuit now can figure out whether
I'm going left or right
okay so it can pick basically one of the
garble one of the garbha labels either
left or right and then it can combine it
with the out of the logic and it can
instantiate this garbled labels turning
them from Gerber labels to to the
garbled inputs right and then it's going
to output the actual next garbled input
right so there's no interaction now we
just hardcore the garble labels of the
next circuits to our current node and
then the circuit the next circuit is
ready to execute okay and then we also
need to be careful because when we get
at the leaf we don't have left and right
so we have to put outs of the garbha
labels of the next route right to do the
computation on the encrypted three okay
so let's see now how the execution will
look like so we have the client that has
the first path in the index that he
wants to access locally right it
computes a garbled input of this two
values for the route of the first three
these first three execute and it outputs
garble inputs for the write for its
writes out now the garbled inputs are
used to X to execute this this last
circuit it outputs the garbled inputs
for the next route right and then it
continues up the garbled inputs of the
left the garble inputs of the left and
eventually Intel it cut it outs of an
encryption of the index of the of the
actual value we're looking for okay
so this is the this is how the basic
scheme works but now there's a problem
right now remember now I'll have here
two trees for this tree we have to
encode the Garba labels of the next
route
to every node of this tree okay
and of course whenever we access a
garble circuit it cannot be used anymore
so have to refresh everything right so
if we refresh the garbled circuit of
this route since its garb levels are
hard-coded in every garbled circuit of
this tree we have to refresh every
garble circuits of this tree which means
that the access complexity is linear
because you know you have to refresh all
this garbage circuits that are hard
because the hard called the garble
labels of all the routes right so that's
not good and the way to solve it is
basically to instead of hard-coding the
garbled labels of the next route you
just pass them a simple right okay so
the idea is okay initially I used to
compute a garble input for the first
route by having the first path in the
index now I'm going to compute a garbled
input for the first route by having a
simple the first path the index and the
garbled labels of the second route so by
having all this three I'm going to
compute a garbled input of the first
route and then I'm going to keep passing
down this garbled labels right I'm going
to do the computation but here whenever
I will have now to instantiate the
garbha labels of the next route I don't
need to have them hard-coded because I
just get them as input okay and then I
do the same here note now that the
client will also need to come to give us
improve the garbha labels of the third
route which doesn't exist here because
of the picture and then eventually you
get to output the encrypted the actual
encrypted value okay so so this
basically achieves you can refresh
everything now import logarithmic time
okay you don't have to do this this
linear time computation
the cost of our approach is exactly the
cost of path Orem times K where K is the
security parameter and this comes from
the fact that you have to keep this
garbled circuit per node okay so for
example when path or AM downloads a
block of B bits we need to download this
block hard code in a garbage circuit
therefore this is K times B okay and
multiple problem is to remove this
multiplicative K have like an
underactive Orem without this
multiplicative K
I don't know if this is even possible
okay so this is the basic scheme so so
what I presented so far is an
abstraction of hapa farm words I solved
this problem non-interactive
computational on this sequence of trees
and then I saw that you know this
applies to to Orem ok so let's talk
about the application of this thing of
this non interactive forum to searchable
encryption so let me remind you a little
bit what searchable encryption is so
searchable encryption we can store a set
of nwa deep pairs in an encrypted form
and give it an encryption of keyword W
we want to return all like this matching
W and all existing approaches liek a
deterministic function of W which we
call search pattern ok so we saw how to
consider its pattern without using fully
fledged or am mainly d x login rounds
for search we use 4 rounds instead
entire scheme can be potentially
practical ok so again I'm gonna black
things a little bit ok so we have the
notion of adaptive computation you have
a memory you give an input X and what
happens is you know you execute
instructions one at a time ok this is an
adaptive computation you cannot expect
execute things in parallel so this is
one class of computations and if you
just use normal Orem for that you need T
n Times log n rounds right where T n is
the computation
now if you use to run for that you can
do it with TN rounds because you need
two rounds pair access okay this just
follows from the from the previous right
so now if you have a non adaptive
computation here's what's happening
right so you have an input X you get the
result out and based on this result you
can compute F some function f of Y and
then you can figure out in parallel
everything that you can access okay so
let's see how we can make this
computation oblivious so if you use an
interactive forum you need to log in
rounds for the first small array and you
need to log in rounds for the big array
if you assume that you have an arm that
can send requests in parallel right okay
so now if you use to Ram you can do the
first array in two rounds and the last
array in login rounds okay but now we
want to have four rounds right so okay
one could ask me guess it's easy to get
four rounds why don't you use to ramp
for the big array well you cannot use to
run for parallel axes because you need
to refresh garbled circuits first and
then execute the next thing right so -
um can not be used to execute the
parallel yes so basically the idea is
too small to store the small array
interim and then to store the big array
in path forum but without the position
map right and then the position map is
computed as this using the pseudo-random
function and then you you can do
basically everything parent okay in 30
below encryption is a known adaptive
computation because a small array stores
W and the number of keywords document
mapping to it and the big array stores
all this w ID okay so to conclude I
presented to Ram it's the first non
interactive tree based or on our cost is
K times path forum and then
it's application stretchable encryption
it's a foreign searchable encryption and
potentially practical since we only used
to run for an array of size equal to the
number of unique keywords and for the
rest we use this path Aram without the
position map okay thank you very much