hi everyone my name is claire vistagi
and i'm so happy to be here with you
today hacker writes today so that's
pretty exciting right
so before we begin i just want to first
tell everyone that this talk is
completely dedicated to all the hackers
who've been scared to disclose
to all the hackers who've been
prosecuted for trying to do something
good
or doing their actual job like they're
actually hired to do these things
and to all the people who are in the
fight to bring rights for hackers
so this talk is completely dedicated to
those and also this talk
um i just want to give a big thank you
to
um a few people so meet elizari uh casey
ellis
beau woods um and harley gator
um if it wasn't for them i wouldn't be
knowing as much as i do
about the lack of having rights as
hackers
so for those that do not know who i am
my name is chloe message once again and
i'm the vp of strategy over at point
three security but
my pretty much job in my everyday life
is being an
infosec advocate and also an activist
meaning
i don't just talk about it i also take
action
um i am also the president and
co-founder of website which is women of
security
and also the founder we are hackers
formerly known as
woman hackers and when i'm not doing
that i also
do a podcast with alyssa miller and phil
wiley called the itsp magazine the
uncommon journey
and also run a hacker book club with
angela and basically
we read books um every month reading a
new book
and every week at 5 pm pacific time on
tuesday
we gather around and talk about the book
but also those that are mentioned in the
book and the author
does the 10r sessions which is fantastic
because you can actually ask all the
other questions that are between the
lines of the words
um so it's a lot of fun anyone can join
uh one thing that's not on there
is that i'm also the co-founder of
hacking is not a crime
with brian he's my co-founder and we'll
dive a little bit
more about how he's not a crime in this
talk so you have a better understanding
of what we're trying to do
to help out the hacker community if you
have any questions about me
at all about what i do in infosec or
outside of infosec you can find all of
that
on my website at climate.com
my twitter and instagram my dms are
always open but feel free to follow too
all right now let's dive into the good
stuff the real
reason why you guys are here we're going
to talk about the current landscape
and i know this is a really really
really scary subject
but we're going to do this together and
i'm hoping that i can make you laugh
once in a while
even though my jokes are terrible most
of the time but let's do this
so first things first you may have
remembered the equifax breach
well it impacted 147 million americans
but did you know about six months before
the breach
occurred a secure researcher or like i
like to use the term
hacker reported this vulnerability
to equifax but it was ignored and so it
wasn't fixed and so when that breach
made major headlines
the upsetting part was that this could
have been avoided
if they just listened to what was being
disclosed thanks siri
um all right we'll keep going on this
the other thing is capital one so
capital one
in general if you did hear about this
bridge uh back in the day was that the
federal complaint it
showed that the breach took places
across march and april 2019
but capital one was not aware of this at
all until a secure researcher
once again also known as a hacker uh
basically reported this situation that
he or she saw on july 17th
and july 17th is uh
when a public github page was displaying
something that looked
awfully like private data
for capital one so the one thing is to
note is that if the secure researcher
never actually like uh notified capital
one they would have not known that this
was out there for
you know however long and that's one of
the things that we have to talk about
today
is that what happened if no one actually
reported the breach
and the reality of it is that it happens
all
the time because right now
one thing you should know about is that
sixty percent of researchers don't
report vulnerabilities
um and this came from um a discussion
that amit elizari was doing when she was
researching about the possibilities of
having safe harbor for the hacker
community
now one of the things with that you need
to also understand
is that it wasn't just her research
about 60
researchers don't report vulnerabilities
but is to note that the reason why is
because they're afraid
of being prosecuted another report that
came out was hacker one
so hacker one came out report in 2018
that stated that one out of four
hackers are afraid to disclose a
vulnerability if they don't have
vulnerability disclosure policies but
those that did end up reporting the
vulnerability
um ended up doing it through you know
social media channels
and the one thing to note is that those
that run the social media channels are
usually marketing
so marketing doesn't really have
communication too much with security so
they probably don't know what to do with
it
however they do see pr situations
forming
so the thing is is that so that that one
out of four
that do report it and they send a dm
through linkedin or through twitter
it ends up becoming a really really
difficult situation
because what ends up happening is it's
either ignored
which you know that's way better than
the other one
which is being misinter interrupted
now one thing you need to know about
that is that then there becomes the
threats
the legal threats that does occur so
remember that 60 percent raters don't
report vulnerabilities because they're
scared
of being prosecuted it's very much a
reality because right now there is no
laws that protect you
so why are hackers scared besides the
constant fear being prosecuted the other
thing you need to know
about the hacker community is that even
when we try to disclose something
sometimes it takes hours days weeks and
then we get to a point where
is it even worth it because it's gonna
put me in jeopardy regardless
but i want to do my job which is the
reason why i'm in this field still
is that i want to protect people that's
why i do what i do
it's because curiosity of course but
also i like to protect people
and so that is the thing we need to
think about is the fact that hackers are
scared because of
outdated laws and the lack of having
rights
is the other one when trying to disclose
something it's a nightmare
and so that's why we need to
understand this situation a little bit
further because the thing that you need
to understand
at this very time is that the laws that
are
used to prosecute hackers in the u.s
the ones you have to worry about is the
fact that
they themselves are so outrageously out
of date
that it hurts you but it's being used by
companies
so companies are using it to prosecute
hackers
it's not really federal government
anymore since 2013 they've been
uh the doj has been doing whatever they
can to protect ethical hackers
but the thing is at the end of the day
it's happening
across our country and it's happening in
local
counties also state but
big companies are the number one abuser
of this law
called the cfa now if you don't know the
cfa we will dive into it but it's
the computer fraud abuse act it is the
law used to prosecute hacking
even though it does not state hacker or
hacking anywhere in it
but the thing you need to note is about
this case so this is an example of how a
company
can abuse and use a hacker
so the dji as you know is a really
really well-known uh manufacturer of
droids
um the things that you need to
understand about this one
is that um so kevin he basically
came across a bug bounty program that
was run by dji
meaning it was run by them in-house not
through like bug crowd hacker one no
third party
so that's already letting you know there
might be a problem here because
managing a bug bounding program is
really really hard
you need to have at least one person to
manage it all
unless you work with those platforms now
there were signs throughout the whole
thing at the beginning that this could
be a bad thing
but cji they created their own blood
boundary program
and kevin he saw the scope and
he wanted to make sure that that scope
is correct so he sent an email to them
and it took them two weeks get this two
weeks
to respond say yes that is all in scope
even though it was just something that's
already on their website what's in scope
it took them two weeks to confirm what's
already on their website
boom that is your major red flag that
this
could be a problem the fact it took two
weeks that means they're not managing
this right
anyway so then he then proceeds to
submit his disclosure and it ended up
being
him getting well an award of thirty
thousand dollars for his fighting
and when it came to the contract for him
to sign to receive the funds
it offered absolutely zero protection
for him
at that moment kevin had to make the
decision of
do i risk at all for thirty thousand
dollars
or do i walk away from thirty thousand
dollars knowing that at least i will be
safe from being prosecuted if ever
and so he did the probably the most
logical choice
which was not take the money
he didn't take the money but dji
immediately saw him as a threat
because he didn't want to take the money
or sign the contract
they were worried that this could become
a really really bad pr situation for
them
if he were to disclose it publicly so
what they did was that even though he
basically was like okay
fine all right you guys fix that
vulnerability i'm not taking your money
walks away moves on with his life
he gets something which is basically
a lawsuit saying that he went
out of scope and even though he
confirmed okay he had a paper trail he
confirmed it
that he was within scope that basically
that he broke the cfa so computer fraud
be stacked
so he himself then was like okay fine
you want to play this game i didn't want
to do this way i didn't want to be dirty
i didn't want to disclose anything here
but here you go so he puts on a blog
everything
i mean all the communications he's ever
had with dji and you can look through it
and some of the responses from dji
itself
are within the chain of the email which
is hilarious to read
at the same time really scary to read
because they legitimately just called
him
out saying he is a problem he's going to
be a pr
nightmare when he said he wasn't going
to sign that contract
so the takeaway from that story you
should know is that
even when you're doing the right thing
and you're doing
all the right things companies will
still take advantage of you for pr
purposes
now the other thing is to note that
sometimes it's also when you are
hired and you work for a company that
you can also be prosecuted
such as the coal fire case that happened
last year if you don't notice that in
september of last year
the iowa state basically asked coal fire
to do some penetration testing to see
if you know if the staff could gain
access to sense of data or equipment
so two coal fire employees then
proceeded
to try to get into the dallas courthouse
but they found the door was actually
open so then they decided to close the
door
to check to see if it would lock and if
an alarm would go
off and so when they attempted to open
it the alarm did go off which is great
that means they have security there
the problem is is that is that at that
moment of course there's a follow
protocol
and the protocol is that they wait for
the police to show up
and they have their papers paper showing
that they were hired
to look into this situation
now most of the police were like oh
that's really cool how did you do that
oh that's such a cool thing that you do
the bad thing is that a local sheriff
showed up and was like
no you're going to jail so they actually
had to spend a night in jail
because of basically
the sheriff wanted to play his own role
book
um you should note that the charges were
later dropped this year in january
but the thing is it's another example of
even when you are hired
and doing what you're you're doing all
the right things you can still have to
deal with this situation
because the reality is is that still to
this day
everyone knows that you need the hacker
community to help
out to protect you to become more secure
but the reality is it is that we're also
battling this idea of what is a hacker
versus an
attacker and the unfortunate bit is that
most of the public perception still sees
hackers
as devious people and thus organizations
and also program managers are a little
bit afraid to work with the hacker
community
because they are afraid of us but the
other thing is they need to understand
is that we are
terribly frightened of them because they
have more protection
than we do when we try to disclose
something so even though they're like oh
please disclose something to us
we're also scared to disclose something
to you
um but also a lot of organizations still
don't have disclosure policies and this
becomes a huge
problem now i've set the scene for you
to know what the current landscape looks
like and we're gonna go a little bit
more in detail but i know this is a
really scary subject
so here are some puppies to lift your
spirits
there is a cat in there and i would say
it's kind of like a where's waldo game
but in reality of it
it's pretty obvious where it is but you
know
for all the cat lovers here you go and
i'm sorry for all the dogs instead but i
am a dog lover and i have two shivas at
home so
and they're not on here all right let's
continue deeper at you guys
so i'm gonna dive a little bit more into
that public perceptions perception
situation
about the hacker community now the one
thing you should note is that the public
perception of
us is based around imagery
but also language but the thing you
should know is that anytime you type in
criminal hacker versus
ethical hacker you get the exact same
images
dark hooded figures it's supposed to
wear a ski mask
which is very interesting but the thing
is to understand
is that because of these images that are
out there
the public doesn't know that there's two
very very different groups here
there's hackers and there's attackers
and this might be the good time to
explain to you the differences
and what it does it comes down to one
part
what is the goal or the intent of the
person
they use the same skills both parties to
get what they need to get to
but their ill intent is different
so ill intent is for those that are
attackers
attackers goals are to collect money
or data that is their goal
is to have some sort of power in a sense
to utilize
and abuse it for their own needs
now when it comes to a hacker their
intent
is to serve and protect meaning
wanting to help out and be the everyday
heroes behind scenes
so the intent is very different from two
parties
and though sometimes we like to compare
the two parties as
one is a locker the other one is a
burglar because the reality of it is
that they use exact same skill sets to
get to their goal
but the one thing you should take away
from that is that one does it with
permission or doesn't and also doesn't
exploit
so even so for example if i'm looking at
vulnerabilities i'm going to do what's
within the scope and i'm only going to
exploit
if you give me permission now the other
thing
is that if you are an attacker you're
not doing
any of that what you're doing is i'm
going to find that vulnerability i'm
going to utilize that vulnerability and
i'm going to get to my goal
now another thing to think about is that
the uh hackers are the ones that are out
there
trying to prevent the attackers from
taking advantage and having their own
gains
that is the differences of the two but
if you see in those images they look
like the exactly the same
people and this is a problem that we're
facing
because it's not just images that's
interfering here but also the language
as well
we still use the terms hackers instead
of using the term
attackers when we're talking about
someone who's committed a com
like a criminal act and this is the
thing that we're dealing with is that
the media doesn't know
or i want to have high hopes that they
don't know that there's a difference
but the thing i want you to take away
from this is that the language
and images themselves they impact
us because public perception basically
allows us to have rights and not have
rights
it's public perception that challenges
us to be able to move forward
because they don't know and how to
spread that knowledge
is the one thing that is the hardest
thing to do
because that means we have to get
certain parties to agree with us
but we want to talk about right now at
this point of this conversation
is there's this thing called socially
constructed beliefs
and a socially constructed belief is
basically the idea
that well it's not an idea it's actually
a research and it's a
term that's used but basically it's the
idea
that whatever that you look at
or read or watch you're
taking in knowledge and information
about how the world works
so socially constructed beliefs are
these beliefs that you have
created based of your surroundings
and this could be watching the news this
could be reading a book this could be
reading an article this could be reading
tweets this could be having a
conversation
the thing is is that these beliefs that
you have
can become really strong because it's
letting you know how the world works so
you're processing information
to see you know how to play the game
the life game of how the world works
but the thing you need to note is that
socially constructive beliefs can also
be false
they can very much be false
many times and so it's really important
to understand how these socially
constructed beliefs
play out when it comes to fear
and for those that know every time i
give a talk i do talk about the brain
because the brain
is really cool because if we know human
behavior then we know how to work
it so let's first dive into the brain
now i want you to know is that socially
constructed beliefs
tend to be stored in your temporal lobe
which takes sensory information and
inputs it into long-term working
memories
so this is where you start understanding
how the world works around you
but the thing you need to know is that
within your temporal lobe itself
it's also where your amygdala lays now
the amygdala you may have heard of it is
a fight versus flight mechanism but you
maybe
not know that it's also your mechanism
that shot stranger danger
in other words who's like me who's not
like me so if you never met
someone who is a hacker
you would never know what the real story
is because the reality is everything
that you know about the hacker community
is stuff that you see in the news or
in movies or in books or from other
people gossiping so the thing is
is that that is why a lot of people are
afraid of us
it's because of these socially
constructed beliefs that we are
criminals because that's what's
being told and shared all over the place
and because of that they stored us as
not like me
so stranger danger now i want to take
this a little bit further so you have a
better understanding of how fear works
so what i'm going to do is talk to you
about an example
so imagine when you're growing up that
you turn on the tv
and the person with pink hair you
automatically will always assume
is a criminal because the person with
pink hair always plays the criminal
or even when you turn on the news you
see someone with pink hair
and you know that person's guilty or any
time there's a criminal
story out there the person has pink hair
so you have this belief now
that every single person that has pink
hair
is a possible danger and it's not like
you because you don't
have pink hair and you don't talk to
anyone with pink hair
so how would you know so
say for example you're walking down the
street and when you're walking down the
street
there's someone with pink hair behind
you now
at that point you usually do is you
cross the street
you clutch your bag a little bit closer
or you go into the
closest store to get away
because of this fear but the thing to
note about
fear is that it has to be verified so
going back to the pink hair example is
that so
when there's a person with pink hair
behind you your amygdala is setting off
a signal
saying warning warning stranger danger
person would be cares behind you
criminal be careful you should take
action
so the amygdala which is completely
subconscious by the way
then sends a signal to the prefrontal
cortex and the prefrontal cortex of your
brain works as a ceo it basically uses
logic and rationale to decide whether or
not
it is a threat or what actions to take
if it is
it then would send a signal back to the
magnet to calm down
or to react now
the prefrontal cortex at this moment
with a person with pink hairs behind you
that may delicious that message saying
warning stranger danger pink hair behind
you
so the thing is is that now at this
point you're thinking of your three
actions
they usually take cross the street
uh clutch your back or go into a store
now but there's this one moment that
you remember that you came across a
youtube video
and this youtube video itself was
something with pink hair
and this person with pink hair is on
camera basically saying
how hard it is to be someone pink hair
that everyone sees them as a criminal
and that it hurts them
because every time they're walking
sometimes they'll see people clutch
their bag across the street
because they're right behind them and
they're afraid of them
and how much that hurts them because not
only does that
criminal title come up you know come up
every time
the person walks into a room the thing
is
is that even that that also prevents
them from being able to do
a lot of things such as getting certain
jobs
or um being able to go in a store
without someone following them in the
store making sure they're not stealing
something
the reality is is that that story
touched you
in a sense that you realize you ask
yourself
huh i wonder if i ever did any of that
or maybe you goes through mine and like
i think i have
or wait
i had definitely done that before oh my
god i'm a terrible person
um so that's what will go through your
mind when you see a video
not everyone but people that um like to
practice
empathy and feel comfortable being wrong
which a lot of humans
don't we don't like to be wrong we are
insecure
beings that are like all over this
planet and we don't like being wrong
but the reality is is that that socially
constructed belief of someone with pink
hair as a criminal
has now been questioned so now let's go
back to our example
so that makes the sense of signals
improved frontal cortex saying warning
more stranger danger
person will take care you have your
three actions which is across the street
clutch your bag going to a local store
but this other
new one pops up which is hey friend
hey remember you watch that video on
youtube and that story of the person
with the pink hair
and how it hurts that person every time
they see them do those things that
you're thinking about doing
maybe you shouldn't act this time maybe
you should just trust the stranger
and you take that one as going forward
because let's be real we don't want to
be terrible people sometimes
and so you send a signal back to your
amygdala saying simmer down we are not
going to act on this this person is not
right
the only thing that's different between
me and that person is just that they
have pink hair
this is ridiculous i don't believe into
this socially constructed belief anymore
boom and that's the thing i want you to
understand
is that right now we all have the
ability
to question our socially constructed
beliefs
and these socially constructed beliefs
does hurt other people
and that's why it's important that we do
every single day is question our beliefs
get outside of our comfort bubble to
understand the other
party because the reality is that we're
not intermingling with each other enough
we kind of stay within our bubble and it
does make us feel
safe and secure and makes us feel like
okay i'm not wrong
so i feel comfortable in my own skin but
the reality is
is that the more you know about the
world that you live in
the more you don't know about the world
you live in and so
and that's what we're dealing with right
now is that people
don't know about hackers they've never
met them they've never had
heard their story so how are they going
to question
the beliefs that they have of the hacker
community
because once we figure out how to change
people's perception
of us that's when we start winning here
that's when we start getting to push for
legislation changes
it's when we start getting companies
have disclosure policies
because right now where we're standing
right now is that
this has resulted in some serious
situations here
that 94 percent of the forbes global
2000 list still doesn't have a
vulnerability disclosure policy
can you believe that it's kind of
ridiculous so think of all the
the hackers out there that are
disclosing vulnerabilities and they're
either being ignored and then later it
becomes breaches for you
and your personal data getting out there
this is the thing we need to be serious
about
and have companies understand is that if
you don't have vulnerability disclosure
policies
you're gonna basically you're opening
the door for the attacker to do whatever
they want
because the hacker who saw it earlier is
scared to report it to you
or you threatened that person because
they are trying to do the good thing
here
and that 60 percent of hackers don't
report those vulnerabilities
because they're afraid of being
prosecuted because the public's
idea of who we are has been
life-threatening for many of us
not just that the laws right now are so
out of date
and it prevents good hacking the same
way that it prevents bad hacking
because they didn't know the difference
because they don't know these things
especially back then they really didn't
know those things also
the prosecuting ethical hackers is a
real situation that we're still dealing
with to this very day
and not just that because how the public
views us
it doesn't also make us want to always
be the
that person who's like well i will do
everything legally correct
and i because the thing is at the end of
the day
is that you see this with kids if you
tell a kid that
they're terrible that they're stupid
or that they basically are bullies they
do act it out
because everyone believes that they are
so they just basically like fine
then i am i will be that type and this
is one of the reasons why we have
a good number of bad actors still
because if we change the legislation how
it is today
i'm pretty sure we'll get a good number
of attackers switching over
because the reality is if i didn't have
to be worrying about being prosecuted
all the time
and get paid for the stuff that i do you
are
sure right that i would definitely want
to make sure i'm on that side
now of course there are folks out there
in this world that don't feel
guilt so those ones we don't re
you know they they could stay as
attackers but the reality is we want the
ones that feel guilty
about what they do to bring them over
now i want to talk about worldwide
legislation here because the thing is is
that you need to know about this few
things so worldwide legislation you'd
find that there's anti-hacking laws
anti-circumvention laws and acceptable
use policy
now the thing to note about here is that
yes this looks very us-centric
but there's a reason why it's because
the u.s set it
up in a way that they started tackling
the anti-hacking
sphere and so other countries followed
and that's what happens when you're kind
of like a superpower i guess people
will follow you in your direction so the
thing is is the anti-hacking laws so the
computer fraud abuse act
um we'll dive into that in the next
slide but the thing is to know is that
it was enacted in 1984.
what came about was this was that ronald
reagan he watched this movie called war
games which we've all seen and
maybe of us some of us love it but that
movie made him
scared out of his mind to a point where
he was like
we gotta do something about these
hackers they're evil people i gotta do
something about this
and that's how the cfa was created was
because he watched war games
remember those socially constructed
beliefs
a movie can also do that too so
the cma was created and basically what
it does is that
if you basically um access a computer
without authorization or ex
you know an excess of authorization
basically this could be used against you
and usually it happens anytime a
researcher goes out of scope and the
company wants to prosecute you
this is used to prosecute hacking the
cfaa
we haven't really seen it in the dmca at
all
and to my knowledge i don't know of any
cases that have but it does produce a
chilling effect and anti-circumvention
laws are copyright laws basically
basically uh seeing reverse engineering
as a
breach of property so that's why you
have to still be a little bit careful be
aware of it and then you have your
acceptable use policy which
some of us know about which is basically
think about this
how many of you guys ever actually read
your terms and conditions say for an
apple product
i did it once um it was 50 pages long
and it definitely was written for an
attorney to another attorney to
understand it
which is the problem here because the
reality is
is that hackers aren't attorneys
and usually but the other thing is to
note is that
not only are hackers not attorneys but
some of us are english learners too
so yeah we got that going on for us so
the thing is is that miscommunication
can happen
all the time and acceptable use policy
could be
way better if they broke it down into
being more exact and less verbage
so then the everyday person around the
world could be able to understand it
so then they stay within scope and there
is no miscommunication but the thing you
need to know is that
all those laws that you just saw right
before
this slide were are completely out of
date
all right this was before y2k we're in
and yes i do realize we're still in 2020
this is one
hell of a year but the thing is to note
is that
that it's 2020 and that was in 84
the cfa so it doesn't it doesn't seem
right that there has been no reform of
this
not just that the thing you need to know
is that there was no representation at
all of the hacker community
one that was being created and that is
something you need to know
is that when we don't have proper
representation on any legislation
we have a problem because those parties
that are
impacted by that legislation that wasn't
taken into consideration or their
their sharing of how this was going to
impact their lives
you've made a terrible legislation
decision
because the best legislation out there
is when they take all the different
parties and make sure they're in the
same room
to talk about what is needed at this
time that could help everyone at that
table
and that's the thing we didn't have and
unfortunately i hate to be the breaker
of like
more bad news in this whole talk but a
lot of legislators don't know anything
about cyber security
they don't even know a difference
between a hacker or attacker
but the scary thing is a lot of them
don't know about
cyber security and because they don't
that puts us in a very bad situation
because laws are now being created or
have been created
that basically prevents good things from
happening
because they're trying to fix a bad
situation from occurring
so the laws right now they prevent good
hacking in the same way they prevent
attackers
and we need really good hacking
so i want to dive into the cfa and i do
have plenty of notes so
you'll see my eyes going a little bit
more south here
but the reality is is that the cfa is
one of those things that needs a real
reform
at this time because the computer fraud
abuse act was basically passed in 1984
and is very out of date at this time but
it also
offers prosecutors discretion to
threaten huge potential fines
and jail sentences for relatively
underserving violations of the computer
policy
first the cfa azran punishes exceeding
authorized access to a protected
computer
a phrase very vague enough to inspire
some broad interpretations
another flaw in the cfa is the redundant
provisions that
enable a person to be punished multiple
times for the exact
same crime these charges can be stacked
on top of one
another resulting in much
higher jail time but also fines
for the exact same violation and we saw
this with aaron schwartz case which
we'll dive into next
this also allows prosecutors to bully
defense into accepting
a deal in order to avoid facing
multitude of charges from a single
solitary act
it also plays a significant role in
sentencing the ambiguity
of a provision meant to toughen
sentencing for repeat offenders of the
cfa
may in fact make it possible for defense
to be sentenced based
on what should be prior convictions but
we're nothing more than multiple
convictions for the exact same crime
once again i want you to understand as
the cfa
is it gives the right to sue for
basic companies gives the right to sue
the hacker community
um but also is to note that you have
more to fear from companies
than states and and also st
your federal justices so but just note
that states are still a problem
but companies are your number one fear
and i want to talk about aaron swartz
because aaron swartz
is an example of how much the cfa is
needed a reform
so if you don't know about his story
this is
a very sad one so in 2011 carmen
ortez which was the u.s attorney's
office charged wards
for hacking into the mit computer
network to download millions of jstor
articles the thing you need to know is
that this was an
act of civil disobedience meant to
basically protest the restricted access
to
research funded by taxpayers but i don't
think he knew
what could have happened in the end
because of it
so the u.s attorney brought charges that
carried a maximum penalty of 35 years in
prison
i want you to understand something he
was facing
35 years in prison for one act
one thing you need to know is that a
first degree murder in this country
is a minimum of 25 years
atmosphere was not hurting anyone
but yet he was looking at 35 years in
prison
not just that but one million dollars in
fines and they were able
to do that because the way that the cfa
is written that they get stacked
on top of stacking um and that is the
problem here
because what happened was that it was a
17-month
legal battle that he was dealing with
and there was no set trial
date at all
and so through source perspective it
must have been so overwhelming
imagine that your life right at that
moment you have no control of it
and you're being used to set an example
but they don't understand is that when
you use someone by an example you are
damaging that person for the rest of
their life
not just that but the people around them
so every time someone is using a hacker
for
busy to demonstrate this is what will
happen to you if you do this
i i cannot say this even stronger than
anything ever
is that you're being a horrible person
because you do not know what that's
going to be for other people
using people as an example to show how
bad
this can be for you if you do these
things
that's there's no heart in that
and that's the problem here because the
unfortunate bit because of the situation
using him as an example to set the scene
it cost him his life he hung himself
in his apartment on january 11
2013. of course i dropped the charges
but you can't how do you go to a family
and be like we dropped the charges
his family pretty sure stated that
it was because of this situation that he
decided to take his own life
how do you go to a family and basically
be like i dropped the charges or sorry
about your loss
when in reality they were the reason for
it they pushed him
way over the end he had no future at
that moment in his life
so he took his own control the only
control that he had left at that very
moment
and he took his own life
it's his story that still motivates many
of us to keep fighting
for rights it's his story that pushes
for reform to occur
and this is his story that basically
wanted to change the situation
so aaron's law which was created in 2013
was a response to this
but it didn't pass unfortunately because
there were some major
tech companies with some really big
pockets that were lobbing heavily to
make sure it didn't pass
but the thing is to note is that it
would have changed the phrasing
of it so instead of just saying like
exceeds authorized
access to access without authorization
just keep it
very simple that permission was granted
or that it wasn't exploited the other
thing is that allowing those stacks to
stop doing it
where if they did one crime they only
are charged with one crime not multiple
crimes
for that one act
because that's what was going on with
him and we see that
all across the world when hackers are
being prosecuted is that these things
are being stacked against
them and they spend a long time in
prison or a huge
amount of money as well to pay for the
penalties
and this seems really terrible
now besides the cfa you need to know
about the dmca
even though i don't know of any cases of
any hacker being prosecuted used
with this but the thing is to note is
that the dmca basically
puts in that reverse engineering is seen
as a breach of companies and this gives
the rights for companies to come
after you if you basically do something
to their product that
it wasn't designed to do or something
they don't like you to do
it does create a chilling effect so it's
important to note about them
now with improvements of legislation we
can change
where we stand today imagine every
single company
around the u.s had disclosure policies
like it was
embedded that if you are practicing
any business that your compliance
checklist
had to include a vulnerability
disclosure policy
wouldn't that be amazing that bilateral
trust amongst organizations and hackers
could finally close that gap
and we could work so much stronger than
ever before
that we could prevent attackers from
doing so much damage that they do right
now
but also not just that it would
encourage more good hacking in this
country and we need that because
i tell you there are people out there
that
do want to do practice better hacking
and whatnot but the problem is
is that they're only seen exactly the
same by the public
and so the shifting over it's not
logically sound for them to switch over
but i do want to say once again that
those are the people that feel
guilty about what they do the ones that
you know wake up in the middle of night
and are freaking out the thing is is
that there are people out there
that don't feel guilty about the crimes
that they commit they don't feel guilty
if they steal money they don't feel
guilty of taking personal data and
selling it they don't feel guilty at all
then those i will always frame as
attackers
because you gotta have a conscious i
would say to be a hacker
but i want to talk more into influence
in the public cycle because in reality
is is
we want to get rights for hackers we
have to work with these three groups
organizations we need them to have
disclosure policies
and to push for disclosure policies but
also to help
try to bring in the conversation for
legislation to do some sort of reform
but also we need the media to join us
because we cannot change the public's
perception of who we are unless the
media starts reporting correctly
reporting you know the right terms
hacker
or attacker which one is it you gotta be
very
specific also changing the imagery
not all of us wear hoodies 24 7. i love
a hoodie
but i don't walk outside with a hoodie
the thing is is that's the whole thing
is that the public has a weird
perception of who we are they think they
know us but they really don't because
they've never heard our story
and so that's why it's important is that
we have to work with the media
organizations and legislation to change
where we stand
at this point
but the good news is that we can do that
and here are some simple things the
first thing we need to change the
language and imagery
of what's being reported in infosec we
need to work with the media
remember the media is our friend they
don't know the difference
so we have to tell them the difference
but
kindly i want to just reiterate that
be kind you do not know where they come
from or you've never been in their shoes
before
they don't know better so we have to be
kind when we correct them
we also need a society to know as the
everyday heroes we need people to hear
our stories
if they saw our images like those
youtube videos like in that example with
the person with pink hair
think of how many people we can change
of their perceptions of who we are
we can challenge their socially
constructive beliefs granted we can't
change
everyone because like i said if you were
someone who's
insecure about yourself or you don't
like being wrong
you're gonna have a hard time doing that
but at least
then you could get the people around
that person to start pushing
that person in the right direction
see social engineering also we need
organizations to have vulnerability
solution policies
i'm sorry at the end of the day every
organization should have one
it's important because then we avoid
situations from occurring which hurts
both parties
um we also need our representatives to
update today's legislation the thing is
like i said they don't know too much
about cyber security and because they
don't we're still running into the
situation
but the first step that you can take
right at this moment is go to that
website and sign that petition
this petition basically is everything
that i talked about and how all of us
need to understand that
we need to change something so go ahead
and sign it share it with your friends
and family you don't have to be a hacker
to sign this
it's anyone out there who believes that
we should have
rights that is for you now the thing to
know is that when this petition kicked
off at the end of february
i wanted to take action and because i
was like okay i don't want to just do
the talk i want to take action
and so i need to find someone a partner
in crime to help me on this
front so um i came across hacking is not
a crime
which was basically um this guy named
brian
and he created a bunch of stickers
hacking is not a crime based around the
skateboarding
uh image and so i would see these at
conferences
so i reached out to them saying hey um
do you want to partner on something
because i created this petition and i
think you and i are aligned on this
i didn't know it was brian at the time i
didn't know it was just brian doing
everything at the time
so we got on the call and we started
talking and
[Music]
we decided let's partner up and let's
bring actions here now
so hacking is that crime was born
recently and so hacking is thatcrime.org
you can visit the website
what we're trying to do is change the
public perception of the hacker
community
but not just that but also to change our
current legislation
by working with organizations and
politicians to bring about a change
the other thing you should know is that
we just did uh we just launched a
project that you can participate called
hacker stories
um and you can see this on twitter on
our handle which is hack not crime
um and in it it's basically people
starting to do their own youtube
videos basically two to eight minutes
i'm talking to the camera
i'm telling what it's like to be a
hacker the good and the bad
with it and why we need a change and
those are the stories that we need to
get out there in public not just that
we've also been contacting
various large media outlets to correct
them on their terminology and their
imagery
and we've had some great conversations
so far
and next step is talking with
legislators so you can get part of it by
the way we're always looking for
volunteers and advocates so if you are
interested
you know reach out um the second step to
note is that
anytime you see the press reporting um
hacker instead of the term attacker um
let them know remember be kind and doing
it and we see this happening a lot on
twitter
so if a news outlet basically has a
story about a
um an attacker doing something terrible
a hacker in the community does respond
and retweets it out and also
cr like dms i'm letting them know hey
you got it wrong this is the correct
term
um these terminology is important for
you understand because it's hurting us
in the community because it's it's
preventing us from getting rights
so that's one thing you could do also if
you're someone who talks to the press
always let the reporter know the
difference between a hacker and an
attacker so when they're writing and
drafting the story they have a better
idea of
how to actually write it in a way that
is a lot more reflective
of also the hacker community
the third step that you can do is make
sure that every
company that you work at or organization
you partnered up with have
a vulnerability disclosure policy set
because vulnerability disclosure
policies
basically opens the door for
communications between hackers and
organizations
to be more secure because with that
vulnerability disclosure policies
the thing you need to know is you
already know all the other stuff
but something you should note is that
not every secure team is going to catch
every vulnerability
and that's the reality of it you're not
always going to catch things so
sometimes you have to rely on
the outside world to help and it's
always good to do that because
when you rather find out about your
disclosure from a hacker someone who's
trying to do it in good faith
versus an attacker who doesn't tell you
at all and then utilizes for their own
gain
that's why you need vulnerability
disclosure policies it's a lot better
communicative form of uh making sure you
have that door open for
hackers to report something and if
you're an
it's like well we can't do that because
if we do that then we get more attention
to ourselves and they're going to do a
lot of things and we're
we don't want to deal with that i hate
to tell you
this but that is a false claim the
reality is that
any time zone goes to your website
they're looking for vulnerabilities
whether or not you are
stating that you allow disclosure
they're already looking for it
so it's better in your interest to just
do it at this point
also if you are working at an
organization that wants to push for
hacker rights
connect with us because we are working
with other companies because we need to
work with companies to change
legislation believe it or not and also
to change people's perception
of the hacker community the fourth step
that you can do at this time is contact
your local representatives
know who your local representatives are
because it's so important
is that we have to let them know they
need to update their current legislation
because
it's hurting you not just you your
family your friends too
because if anything happens to you who
is that going to impact
exactly so it's important that we stop
are
talking about it and you could set up a
call basically with them
but the remember that the angle isn't
telling them
how to do their job the goal is to find
out what
is the thing that they're they've been
wanting to fix
and how can the hacker community help
them with that so you want to find a
common ground of pain
to help each other out don't go at this
alone
if you have set up an appointment with
your legislator
contact me or hack not crime on twitter
dm us or
email us from hackinessnotacrime.org
website you can put it in you can send a
contact
and we will join you on that call so
you're not by yourself don't go by
yourself on
anything in reality whenever you have to
change something you need to have more
presence in the room
or the virtual room um also keep a note
of the van buren case because the van
buren case is going to be revisited not
revisit it's going to be visited on
november 30th
at this time of course that might change
because of the election that's going on
but the thing you need to know is that
this is the first time in a long time
the cfa
is going to be revisited but the thing
to note about it is that
under this um expansive interpretation
of the cfa for this case
it become a federal crime any time a
person violates a website's term or
services
it finally in terms of services is a
crime you need to understand this this
is the most important part right now
private companies then get to decide who
goes to prison
and for what which then puts us at a
huge risk for everyday online behavior
so it's really important is that we keep
an eye on it and if you want to get
involved to make sure
um you know we have a voice in the
hacker community when this is happening
i'll reach out
the fifth step that you can do is always
volunteer your time or resources
to support i'm the calvary disclose dot
io
uh cert coordination center also known
as cert cc eff and cti league these are
great organizations that are trying to
change the situation that we're in
or to provide some sort of rights or
advocacy for you
so the main takeaways from all this is
that hackers deserve
protection and rights period
it should not have taken this long to
even
have this type of conversation that
should have happened a long time ago
and it has been but the thing is we
haven't been able to move more forward
but now is the time for us to move
forward
we need to update our current language
and also
our imagery that's being used by working
with the media
we also need to work together to change
public perception
because we got to influence
organizations legislators
and the media so working together is a
beautiful thing
and that's why hack is not crime.org is
exists because it's a grass-rooted
efforts to
change the situation um but
of course with as much empathy as
possible too
feel free to sign and share that
petition push for change share this talk
these are all things that you can do
right now
also go to hack.crime
on twitter if you want to follow find
out what we're doing our latest things
also get involved we're looking for
volunteers and advocates
but i just want to first remind you once
again over and over
because it's so important is that change
starts with you and me
and we cannot give up on this fight
because
i never ever ever want to read another
story that's similar to aaron swartz and
i'm sure
you don't either i think it's about time
that we start
being a lot more protective of the
people in our community
but also being part of the community to
work together
to bring about a change
so thank you guys so much for existing
thank you for catching my talk
um thank you for having me here give
this talk it's really important that we
do
and if you have any questions i am here
to answer any of your questions i'm
gonna stop sharing my screen
um but if you want to you feel free to
dm me at any time also
my dms are always open on instagram and
on twitter and also feel free to follow
any questions i was watching your talk
and i realized i was dressed wrong
so i ran it changed but uh
seriously that was a great uh great talk
chloe uh and very timely
um you know i was on the board advisory
board for
hackers for charity for a long time and
um
you know one of the things that johnny
long uh and us always struggled with was
how do you take the name hacker back
and john had spoken about that many
times uh you know and there's no more
compelling story about hacking than his
story of how he started his mission at
uganda
uh you know and how he used uh hacking
to support that charity
uh over there and you know so many times
i would wear a
ihack charities t-shirt into a
restaurant and you know the
conversations that those would start was
always
uh interesting and engaging but uh you
know
i know i personally loved your talk i
think it's very timely and
very necessary for the community thank
you and you did make a valid point it's
very hard to take back
a name that you want to use or a label
but we've seen it happen
throughout history for myself um
for example my family is iranian but the
thing
is that we don't support the regime at
all we
left before the revolution and during
the revolution
because we don't want to have anything
to do with that government so we use the
term
persian so you may hear this is that
iran's will use the term persian
instead of iranian to reinstate that
they supported the
um they don't support the regime at all
and what has happened
so it's it's always important to note is
that you can always reclaim a title
a name or whatnot it just it's simply
just taken the first step forward
well we really appreciate your talk and
i enjoyed having you with us
and look forward to maybe having you
here in person next year
i hope so too thank you for having me
thank you hi everyone stay safe