thank you so much um thank you everyone
it's great to be
with you with information
countermeasures
my name is ali mellen i'm a security
strategist
i've been in tech for the past 10 years
i'm a computer engineer by training
and um i've spent a lot of time
doing a lot of various engineering and
tech roles over that 10 years
but more recently i've been working in
the security space
i've presented my research at places
like black hat and defcon
and hope um and now secure
wb and um over the past two years in
particular i've been working very
closely with the fbi
secret service dhs and
local and state law enforcement in order
to
test the security of our elections in
order to make it better
and so this has been done through
tabletop exercises
where we put hackers against law
enforcement and government officials
in order to really see what processes
are in place
and how effective they are so it's not a
lot of hands-on hacking
but it's actually looking at the
processes that the government has in
place seeing how prepared they are
and seeing if what different things
attackers could do that they might not
be prepared for
and this is all about the things that
are really surrounding the election
it's not so much limited to just those
voting machines but really
what else can someone do to suppress the
vote or to
affect the election
but before we really dive into that i
want to start by talking about what's
truly critical
to our daily lives because it's really
way more connected than we think
and of course the first thing that we
think of when we think of
what's critical to our daily life is
maslow's hierarchy of needs
maslow's hierarchy of needs is a pyramid
that represents all of the things that
we as
individuals need in order to achieve
self-actualization and really that
ability to be the best that we can be
at the bottom layer you have the
physiological needs these are things
like
air water food the really important
things that you need just to
be a human being on the next level we
have
safety this is things like personal
security
employment and resources you really
can't achieve
the top of that pyramid without safety
next and this one is critical comes to
belonging
things like friendship and intimacy
really that sense of connection that you
have with others in the community and
others in the world
above that is esteem of course that
self-respect that respect from others
status and recognition and again all of
this is leading up to self-actualization
and you can't have self-actualization
without all these other layers of the
pyramid
so where does voting fit into this why
is this important in the context of
voting
that's what we're going to talk about
but more
i want to break down things like the
defender perspective
and the daily life of a voter as well as
diving into
what the attacker perspective really
looks like
so we can take that information and
think about it in the context
of what you could do to both stop an
election and how we can use that to
protect an election because that's
what's really important
and that's what we're looking to get out
of both of these exercises that i've
done
but also as individuals how can we
contribute to election security
so let's dive into the defender
perspective get a good overview
of how we got here and what that looks
like so that we can really understand
how we can best attack that
so according to the dhs election
infrastructure
includes all of the things like voter
registration databases
associated i.t systems um
voting systems polling places all of
these things that are really about
counting the votes but what i
am thinking of as i think of the
maslow's hierarchy of needs
is is that really all that there is to
ensuring election security
and i don't think that it is in fact i
think that
much more than that we need to consider
what i call the voter hierarchy of needs
and this is really a pyramid
of things that are critical for
individual citizens before they feel
comfortable voting
and it aligns really closely to maslow's
hierarchy of needs
in order to show the real connection
that
voting has and people's willingness to
vote has
with um the existing systems
that are related to their daily lives
so it starts with things like the
physiological needs
of course we're talking about if you
don't feel safe
if you don't if you feel like your life
is at risk because you don't have enough
food
for example you're much less likely to
make the decision to go out and vote
similarly if you don't feel safe
if you feel at risk because someone in
is um trying to hurt you or
for example you don't feel financially
secure
you have other priorities that may be
more important than going to vote
another great example a really important
example that we're seeing
time and time again be really critical
to people actually choosing to go vote
is belonging and it's really all about
that belief system and it's also about
feeling like you belong in the community
and like you have a connection to the
country that you are part of
and then of course esteem feeling like
your vote matters
feeling like you have a voice in the
country that you are
in and ultimately leading to
self-actualization
and we're talking about
self-actualization not just for yourself
but for your country as well you want
your country to be the best
it can be when you feel that sense of
belonging when you feel connected
to the country that you're in so all of
these are critical in order
to really make sure that individual
citizens
feel compelled to go vote feel safe
going to vote
and are not um
able to be suppressed by another group
of people
so this is why when i think about
election infrastructure
i think that having a narrow definition
that really just encompasses
the physical infrastructure associated
with actually collecting the votes
is far too limited and that's not to say
that
governments or um election committees
should be in charge of a bunch of other
facets that contribute to this
but they should be thinking about it
they should have a plan in place they
should have partners associated with it
so they're more prepared
to handle these types of election
threats because
all of these layers these become systems
to that we really need to protect
in order to ensure the integrity of the
vote because they are
all layers that can be a target
and we're going to go through a lot of
these different all of these different
layers actually
to see different ways that you can
attack these layers
in order to affect an election
and it's particularly stark when you see
that
40 percent of eligible us citizens
choose not to vote at all
we're already down 40 of people
so any um bit of election interference
or any bit of election meddling or
tampering
can have a really large impact when
you're already missing so much of the
vote
so when i think about election
infrastructure i'm really thinking about
three core elements things like
maintaining faith in democracy
which is critical for nations that
support the vote
the second is all about preventing voter
suppression
which could be done on a domestic or
international scale depending and the
third
national security because again if you
don't feel safe
if you feel like your life is at risk
because another country is interfering
with your election
you're most likely not going to go vote
you're going to
start to see a crumbling of people's
belief in the country
and willingness to contribute to the
country
so now i want to dive into the attacker
perspective now that we have
that point of view and really i want you
guys to start brainstorming as well
what the attacker perspective might look
like in the modern day given what you
know
about our election system given how you
go to vote
and i want to emphasize that
this is an evil and i think that a lot
of us know that a lot of us in the
security space which
pretty sure is most of the people here
we know that this isn't evil
we know that this is why we read team
this is what's so important is that
we're able to
understand the attacker mindset so that
we can really use that
to make the systems that we have in
place better
so please keep in mind as we go through
this that
there's no need to demonize people who
do look for
um what threats could be effective
because really it is just meant to make
us stronger
so when we're thinking about the
attacker they typically have
three motivations the first is of course
to gain power
a lot of um especially at the nation
state level
these are going to be the three core
ones that we're thinking about with the
second
being spreading a particular ideology we
saw this a lot and during the cold war
between um uh
the soviet union in the united states
and we'll get into some of that a little
bit later
and then the last is really maintaining
that global recognition
and support we see a lot of countries
using attacks on people's elections and
tax on their government
in order to really maintain their global
recognition and support
especially as a superpower
when i think about attacks specifically
cyber attacks to
anything whether it's elections or not i
think about them in three different
layers the first
is the infrastructure layer that's all
the physical components that people are
actually attacking
this is what makes a cyber attack have a
kinetic impact the second
is that information plane this is really
playing off of what people
know to be true giving them quote
unquote facts
that aren't true whether you do it
intentionally or not
and the last is the ethos plane
this is targeting that belief system
this is where we really start to see
things like democracy things like
governments and the foundations that
they're built on
start to crumble when people target the
actual belief system
of a country the belief system of the
individuals
and turn these individuals against the
government or against the community
so i want to start by looking at some
historical examples
of attacks on that belief system plane
and we're going to look at some that
don't have a cyber component
as well as those that do and what's
important to note here is that
even though some of the historical um
examples don't have a cyber component
they
very easily could in modern day the only
reason that they don't
is because they're from so long ago so
and
there wasn't the option then so when you
think about this
another great thing to think about as we
go through these is how much easier
these types of attacks would be if
people had access to the internet at the
time because
that's what we're really getting at here
is that these attacks are not new
they're just taking they're in a new
package and the package is
the internet so i want to start with the
italian elections of 1948.
in 1948 the u.s government
um and the soviet union was intent on
psychological warfare
the u.s was of course really pushing
democracy they were spending
millions of dollars both on
christian democratic parties but also
on the um on the
soviet union side really pushing the
right-wing socialist agenda
there was a massive propaganda campaign
against the communist socialist
coalition and the goal
on both sides was to really change the
perception of the election
even though these two countries are not
in
supposed to be involved with the
country's politics but they really
wanted to change the conversation
into a battle of democracy versus
totalitarianism
christianity versus atheism america
versus the soviet union and ultimately
what they really wanted is a
conversation about abundance
versus starvation and what was amazing
is this was so effective
that they ultimately repeated the
process
in guatemala in south vietnam
in afghanistan and indonesia
and many more
another example i want to talk about is
the 1996 chinese influence on the u.s
election now in 1996 a chinese general
interested in influencing the us
presidential election funneled
300 000 to the clinton campaign
now immediately you think well this is
um this money is funneled to
the clinton campaign because they want
the clinton campaign to win absolutely
however there's more to it than that
because ultimately
u.s citizens did find out about this and
this is the type of thing that makes
people start to lose faith
in their government and belief that
their votes
and their money and their choices are
what are deciding
elections in this country
so now i want to take a look at some
modern day examples we're going to look
at examples from 2016
and i'm sure in a few weeks i'll have a
lot from this year
for you um but let's take a look at some
social media examples
on the right you can see a like and
share if you want the burka band in
america
stop all invaders this is a facebook
ad um a facebook post that's promoted
and it's really meant to push this
narrative
of there's conflict in the united states
we um have invaders quote unquote in
america
and this is someone who feels that way
who is american however
the reality looks very different this is
not a um site that is
or a group that is actually a group of
americans
this is a group of people who is looking
to spread disinformation in the country
and to cause
chaos and ultimately conflict on the
left
you can see a great example as well from
twitter
which is supposedly a very helpful
notice from the clinton campaign
saying vote from home text hillary to
this number and
you'll be able to vote now this could be
a very compelling message to a lot of
people especially right now
when tensions are high you don't
necessarily want to do mail-in voting
you don't necessarily want to go into
the polls because of the pandemic
there's a lot of confusion and conflict
caused by this
and so having a texting option would be
very convenient it looks very official
it has hillary on it it has her campaign
logo in the corner
but in reality this is not an actual
way to vote of course it's not a way
that you can vote
it is from someone who is obviously
trying to
mess with people and trying to make sure
that certain people's votes don't count
and luckily
we have seen over the past few months
many social media companies start to
step up in some capacity
to address these problems
however we still have quotes like these
from some
where they're talking about how this is
a free speech issue
and how this is not something that they
can control because they don't want to
police individuals on their platforms
however one thing that i hope will
become clear throughout the course of
this talk
is that election security is everyone's
problem
it is not just the government's problem
it is not just
businesses problems it's not just social
media companies problems
it is for a problem for all of us to
address
and we need to do what we know is right
and what we know is the most
reasonable and beneficial way to
approach the situation
and framing this as a free speech issue
is not benefiting
the community and the country that
you're a part of
and i don't mean to say that we should
um oppress certain groups or not talk
about what certain groups are saying
but we need a solution that addresses
fake information being put out there and
we need it at the business level we need
it at the government level we need it at
the individual level
we need to work together to find a
better solution
so let's dive into the information plane
and this is all
of those things that um those fake
fake comments you see online um those
fake
videos get deca posted online and i want
to start with a historical example
that's
personally really important to me
because i didn't even know about it for
a long time
you certainly didn't hear this growing
up but
the foundations of america and
that really starts with sam
adams which is crazy to think about but
ultimately america was founded on the
premise of a conspiracy theory
where the british were trying to enslave
us sam
adams argued britain's taxations were
part of an elaborate conspiracy to
eventually enslave american
colonists he actually spread that and
other early disinformation through
pamphlets and speeches
that had information that he knew was
untrue and he actually
used the boston massacre to further that
message
so when we think about disinformation
and we talk about it in the context of a
oh this is being spread so quickly
through social media
in reality this is not a new problem
this is a human problem
and this is something that we've seen
for as long as the country that i'm
a part of has been here and
probably much longer and so instead of
thinking about it as a
this is a problem with social media's
virality
or this is a problem with people posting
things without having to back them up
we need to think about this as the
actual human problem that it is
another great example and this one i
actually
find very interesting is the cia
and the propaganda asset inventory so in
the 50s
60s um and early 70s
during the cold war era we
saw the cia have a massive propaganda
asset inventory they had
so many newspapers and radio stations
and
all of magazines all of those different
things that they were using to spread
propaganda across the world
and i'm going to call out two specific
examples that i think are very
interesting the first
being radio free asia so radio free asia
was a radio station controlled by the
cia that was used to spread propaganda
specifically targeting different asian
countries
and at the time they realized that the
average
citizen of taiwan probably did not have
a radio
because it just wasn't it wasn't
something that had taken hold
in that area yet they weren't
technologically there the whole nine
yards
so what they did to address that problem
was they strapped balloons with small
radios
and tried to fly them over to taiwan
needless to say that did not work the
wind changed direction and took them
away
but it's an interesting example of how
before
we had really the internet that we do
today
they were trying to get propaganda to
these people to get disinformation to
these people ultimately
the second one that i find really
interesting is a magazine called
the forum world features this was
magazine again
where the cia was placing
propaganda articles unfortunately
the magazine became so popular that it
was also distributed to the
uh to the us ultimately and so the cia
had to be very careful
not to place false stories in the u.s
version only in the other versions
so two very interesting stories about
how the
logistics that go behind trying to
um put disinformation in the areas that
will benefit
the country that you're working for
another great example is the u.s radio
in moscow
from the from 1976 to 1982
um rock music was really popular
in russia but um not very accessible
and the only way that you could get it
was through a radio station controlled
by
the cia and they actually so they would
play
rock music like elton john and the
beatles and they would follow it up with
editorial content quote-unquote which
soviet authorities considered
disinformation
but it was the only station that people
in moscow could get
rock music on and so they continued to
to listen
now i want to give a more recent example
from
ukraine from the 2014 elections in
ukraine
now these elections were highly
contested
on the 21st of may in 2014 this is about
four days before the election
attackers actually were able to
compromise the cec network which is the
election commission network in
ukraine and they disabled the vote
counting
on that network so automatically this
can make people
really start to lose faith in their
government of course
and in their election what they did next
um even though so that compromise
it made the network go down for about 12
hours
but four days later on election day
because that was really just the start
um
the attackers started a continuous
denial of service attack
on that same cec website and 12 minutes
before polls closed
the attackers actually posted a picture
of the former leader of the right sector
on the cec website which is an official
website
claiming that this person won the
election
and that was then shared widely and
immediately
by russian media so this is fascinating
because to me especially because it
really feels like a combination
of different ways to attack a target
of course a few days before the election
you start to really degrade their faith
in the election
but then the day of you not only make it
very difficult for them to actually use
the website but you publish this
information
on this official website just 12 minutes
before the polls close
and then you use what
i think most people uh attribute to the
russians
you use your own social um your own
media networks
in order to share that information as
well and give it even more validity
and now i want to give some examples
of communications attacks which really
again target that information plane
and two examples come in the form of
text messages this is again
from the us presidential election in
2016.
on the right we have an example of how
um an individual citizen is receiving a
text message from someone claiming to be
associated with government and it says
you
vote at this um this address and the
hours to go vote are
6am to 9pm needless to say
this is not a legitimate polling place
it's it's not even a place that you can
go vote
so imagine being a citizen and getting
this message
that oh how convenient the government is
helping me get to
vote tomorrow and they're giving me the
address i don't even have to look it up
but it's not actually a polling place
and you go there
and you see that it's shut down it's not
an actual polling place
you're going to be frustrated you're not
necessarily going to want to go and find
the actual polling place and then on the
left
you have an example that's supposedly
from president trump saying you haven't
submitted your ballot yet
submit it here this is not um
this is not a message from president
trump or his campaign or anything like
that
but it is meant to shame people into
going to vote for a particular candidate
lastly we're going to talk about
infrastructure plane attacks
and these i find the most fascinating
because it really does have
the potential to impact our physical
realm through a cyber attack
but again we'll start with some
historical examples
and work our way to real life
i want to start with the assassination
of lumumba
this was um in the democratic republic
of the congo
the drc was actually
um made a independent nation in 1960
and the person that they that they
actually elected as prime minister
was lumumba so he elected him in 1960
they became an independent
nation in 1960 but then he was
assassinated
one year later in 1961.
now having your brand new prime minister
in your brand new nation be assassinated
would be politically fracturing
for any new country
but it's made even more so by the fact
that
he was actually assassinated by a
combination
of american and belgian governments
working together
to assassinate him because it didn't
meet to their interests
now imagine that you are
part of a brand new country you're
voting for the first time
as this comparably very small
country to a lot of countries in the
world and the person that you chose
to run your country is assassinated a
year later
by two superpowers these are the types
of things
that can really fracture a new nation
and really make them feel like their
votes don't even matter
because ultimately they're not the ones
in control
another example is
the indonesian elections and subsequent
massacre
so in 1965
the um communist party finished fourth
in indonesian elections and they were
offered a proportional representation in
the government
now this did not fit with u.s interests
and so they actually secretly supported
the purge of suspected communists and
thousands to millions of people died
over the course of months
ultimately the military took over as the
most powerful institution
now this is the type of thing that
obviously it
it kills people um on a massive scale
but it also terrifies the public who
is voting freely after this happens in
their country who is speaking freely
about their beliefs after this happens
in their country
and this was all through consistent
communication on the part of the u.s
to actual members of this country
and consistently making them feel like
the rest of the country was
with them like they needed to purge
the communists it was all through a
massive
disinformation campaign
another example more recent example is
the bronze night
though not on election day it's a very
good example of what
could happen and what has happened so
the bronze night
um is a night in estonia in 2007
when the estonians decided to move a red
army soldier
to a soviet cemetery because it was
previously
in the center of a town they didn't want
it there anymore for obvious reasons
um now immediately as they started to
move this statue
fake news began to spread especially
with russian news reports
they were all claiming that the statue
and the soviet war graves were being
destroyed
in mass this resulted in
two nights of riots and looting 156
people were injured one person died and
a thousand people were detained
which is horrible in and of itself
but simultaneously banks media outlets
and the government was hit by a denial
of service attack
it actually was so effective that cash
machines
were um unusable online banking was
completely out of service
government employees were unable to
communicate through email
and the newspapers and broadcasters were
unable to deliver the news
so the only news coming in was through
these
fake russian news reports
this is a great example of how you can
really combine
an infrastructure attack with a
disinformation campaign
in order to ultimately cause a lot more
confusion and chaos and damage
but what's also really important about
this is you're able to do this in such a
way
where you stay below the level of an
armed attack
and you can't necessarily um
say who or like attribute them to one
person
it's very attribution is so difficult
with cyber attacks
so even though you may suspect one group
you can't say
this is an act of war because again most
of it
to your knowledge is your people
excuse me
so let's talk about some potential
attacks that could happen on the
electorate
in 2003 a four-day power outage left at
least 100 people in the united states
and canada
dead imagine a scenario
where a power outage was caused by a
cyber attack
this is the type of thing that as we've
seen
could kill people but in addition
if that happens on election day you're
much less likely going to go to vote
because you have other things to worry
about like if what's
in your fridge is going bad or if your
parents are okay
if your siblings are okay a lot of
people
have a lot of things to worry about when
an entire city's power goes out
and voting automatically becomes less of
a priority because of something like
this happening
and it can cause a lot of division as
well because if it happens in certain
districts or certain areas
it can seem like intentional sabotage
the second is transit now
in 2016 san francisco's transit system
was infected with ransomware
i want you to imagine a day
an election day where we are thankfully
out of this lockdown um
back going into the office you take the
train
into work you say that you're gonna vote
after work
you um go into the office and you have a
normal work day maybe you go on twitter
during lunch you scroll past some
disinformation
hopefully you don't share it and then
you make it to the end of the day
and you go to get back on the train to
go vote and the train is shut down
it's not working what are you going to
be thinking about
in that moment are you going to be
thinking about how
you get to the polling place are you
going to be thinking about how annoyed
you are and how much you want to just go
home
and relax and how you have to pay for
that uber instead of just taking uh
taking the train
which you already have a pass for these
are the types of situations that can
cause people
to either just choose not to vote
or not have the time to vote or the
ability to go vote
and we can see that these types of
attacks are really across
all layers both in the infrastructure
information and ethos planes but also
all layers of the pyramid and
when you're thinking about this like
these are just a few
examples but think about all the other
possibilities in your daily life
that this could affect and i want to
dive back into the defender perspective
now that we have this point of view
on what different attacks could actually
be perpetrated
[Music]
so where does the current system leave
us
right now we have this very limited
definition of election security
we're talking about again databases i.t
infrastructure
the actual polling place itself and
here's what we've got
we have quotes like these where
top government officials are saying we
cannot exclude such activities
for example in germany we have
quotes from presidents tweets from
presidents saying that
the election is a scam we have quotes
from
congressional democrats saying that
they're deeply concerned about
disinformation that's going to be used
to
influence the presidential election
and while these are not necessarily
bad quotes because at least they're
referencing what's going on
they don't offer a solution there is no
okay here's the situation and here's
what you as an individual should be
doing right now
this is just a statement of fact
and that is where we are at right now is
there's no comprehensive solution
that's thinking about this
so where should we really be going where
do what do we need to be thinking about
in order to actually make our elections
more secure in order to
make sure that these type of attacks
aren't as impactful as they are right
now
and the answer is really we need a
broader definition of what election
security really is
it needs to take into account the things
that
really affect voters both willingness
and ability to turn out as well as their
faith in their country because that is
so critical
to making sure that people vote and i've
included a few examples based on what
we've talked about today but there are
others as well
that are not being taken into account
here and i'm sure that you guys can
think of some
when you think about what your typical
day of voting looks like and i want to
want you to think about that so that you
can think about
how you can defend it better like what
do you do on election day do you
vote before work i know that right now
for example a lot of people are using
mail and ballots
which i'm a big proponent of even though
it's taking so long in some states
and that's exhausting um but what's
important is
think about what you do in a normal day
think about if you're fact checking
everything that you're posting
think about um how modern events
can change how you choose to vote one of
the pluses
of early voting and of mail-in ballots
is
a lot of these time-based attacks that
are really limited to that election day
are now not as effective because we have
so many people who are able to vote
before the actual election day but of
course things like early voting and
mail-in ballots they have everything has
its own threat model
we just have to figure out what is going
to be what is going to reduce
risk effectively
so when you think about what your
election day
looks like or looked like this year
think about it in the context of an
attack
how would you attack each level of this
pyramid
how does each level of this pyramid
really affect your
willingness to go vote
and use that information to think about
what change we need to drive
both at the government level but also as
individuals
as organizations think about how
we need to change our current systems
how we need to adapt
to face this threat
and ultimately how do we actually defend
each one of these
because as i mentioned earlier it is not
the government's job
to make sure that no disinformation is
being posted on social media sites
or to make sure that um the electric
grid isn't hit by
a cyber attack necessarily because some
are privately held
but what is important
is building partnerships with these
groups considering how this could
impact the election and communicating
that to these companies
so when we think about what we can
really do to protect democracy
i want us to think about things like
first off
securing your systems as an individual
and
at work whether you work for the
government or not
because ultimately if you are a part of
an organization that's a critical
infrastructure provider
you are most likely a very good target
when someone is trying to affect the
outcome of an election or
to cause a breakdown within a government
this and as an individual of course you
are as well
the second thing i recommend is to work
with the government
there are a lot of great organizations
out there that allow you to work with
the government one is infragard i'm a
member of infraguard i'm a huge
supporter of that group
um find ways to partner with the
government so that you can go to them
and say hey i'm worried about election
day
i think that my company could have an
issue on election day because of xyz
and i want to open a communications
channel with you
so that if something happens we can have
a process in place to address it
and then the last is to fight
disinformation as much as possible and
this can be many forms
ultimately it's about being a trusted
and kind resource to those around you
especially when they're
sharing this information if one of your
friends or family members
is spreading this information the best
thing that you can do
is try to understand their point of view
and then be there to communicate the
reality of the situation
because there's a reason that they're
communicating and sharing
what they're communicating and it's
because it's deeply tied
to their emotional state and it agrees
with what they feel emotionally
and you're not going to get anywhere by
trying to shame someone
out of believing in disinformation the
best thing that you can do
is be there and just it's constant work
it's constant effort of trying to
make sure that they understand the
reality of the situation
in a way that they feel safe
so i have written a white paper on this
and it
is totally free to download whatever you
like
um just go to that url
and it's all about everything that we
discussed here today so just some more
reading for you if you're interested
and i want to thank you guys so much for
attending my talk
if you have any questions at all i'm
here i'm happy to take some now as well
um you can also find me on twitter at
hacker bella
thanks thanks a lot aly that was a uh
interesting talk i do have a question
um i mean you and i both bank
online every day and we trust the bank
to handle our banking transactions over
the internet do you
ever see a point to where we'll be
voting like that
um i do i think it's very immature
and it is many many years away
like probably i hope it's
15 to 20 minimum um
it's it would be very
beneficial in order to get people access
to vote more
but things like what happened in iowa
which
wasn't even affected by a cyber attack
are very scary and i think
the way that i like to talk about this
is there's a culture clash
between the tech space and the
um the government space so basically
when you think about it tech they have
to move fast
they have to build features and they
have to get features out because they
have to win
against the competition government is
very different
government is about especially when it
comes to elections
they have to build a robust system
that's going to maintain the
integrity of the count that's going to
keep the ballots confidential
and it's going to be very reliable and
so when we try to use new technology or
even sometimes old technology
within a government setting there's just
a huge culture clash between the two
and until we get that figured out until
we can really make
the tech more robust we're just not
going to be able to use it in that way
there was a pilot program here in west
virginia
that was specifically geared to
a very small population of people and
that was
active duty military members that that
are from
residents in west virginia then and what
the secretary of state here did
was they pushed out an app to those
people to allow them to vote
uh through the app now of course you
know that's a very small
group of people you know less than a
thousand so you know there was no way
that
spongebob squarepants was going to get
elected governor because
you know nobody was going to be able to
spoof you know
thou tens of thousands of votes because
they knew that they were only going to
be
this x number but that but that test was
very successful here
that's awesome i'm glad to hear that i
think that those types of small tests
are the best way to start moving towards
that
you know and really like to experiment
with portions of the population the
thing that scares me is when they're
like we're just going to roll this out
for
an entire state or for an entire country
and
there just hasn't been the testing that
we really need in order to make sure
that that's safe
let me check discord here to see if
there's anybody has any questions no i
don't uh
i don't see any uh ali we uh we really
thank you for your uh for your time and
your talk and
we appreciate you uh coming to secure wv
hopefully next year you can
come back and maybe we'll get to be in
person but
yeah thank you thank you thank you so
much for your talk and we really
appreciate it
thank you so much it was great to be
here and enjoy the rest of the
conference