hello everyone welcome to my
presentation
today i'd like to share my new tool
named as
ida2obj
it is designed to
implement the static binary
instrumentation
first
let me make a simple self introduction
i am a security researcher from trainer
micro
my main job is analyzing all kinds of
mobile awareness platform before
but now i many folks on the mac os
and ios platform
i started to dig zero day
vulnerabilities since last year
currently i have submitted more than 80
vulnerabilities to zdi
and got more than 50 cvs technologies
from apple and google
i also enjoy finding the root cause of
some real issues
by reversing and debugging
edit pro is one of my favorite tools
last but not the least
welcome to follow me on twitter
my twitter id is patch it
this is the background of my topic
nowadays many popular fathers are called
courage guided
including asl
home fast
scholar and so on
it's a piece of cake
for open source project
because we can just add some special
options to compile to do the
instrumentation
but how about the closest binaries
tbi is the most choice
such as dynamo rio frida scholar and so
on
but i think sbi is cooler
and faster actually there are some
existing sbi tools
but it seems no perfect solutions yet
and i have new ideas for the
implementation
so
what is sbi or dbi
the phone name is static
or dynamic
binary instrumentation
instrumentation means the act of adding
s-code
to
a program
to measure its performance
diagnose errors and write trace
information
binary means analyzing program at
machine level and machine code level
without having access to the source code
dynamic means analyzing program at
runtime
static means analyzing program at a
compile or build time
we can see the compiler instruction as
the special case of sbi
so sbi is as fast as compile
instrumentation
in syria
next i will describe
how i implement the sbi step by step
well
let's start from scratch now
this is my first idea
we can load the binary into adder pro
first
and wait for the auto analysis
when the analysis is finished
export it to the assembly file
which can be seen as the source code at
a assembly level
then
we can simulate the instrumentation
process of compiler
so
we got an instrumented assembly file
finally we can build the assembly file
to generate a new binary
this is my first solution
just for pe binaries
i implemented another tool adapted as
ida2 masm
the input and output are both te
binaries
and the assembler is the
masm from microsoft
now let's export the assembly file
we can export all instructions
to one assembly file by using add-on
menu file produce file create asm file
however
mma sm may cost many hours or days to
discern
example one
asm file
luckily we can use the script api
to export from an address range
one more tip is before exporting
we should use the item menu once all
as just said
masm has difficulty to process one big
file
so we must slip them into small ones
splitting by segments is a good choice
we should manually load all segments
including header
and the resource segment
then eliminate all segments to dump
use that for header and the relocation
segment
segments may share the same name
so just append their address to be
unique
after the segment split splitted
we need to process symbol
in masm we can use the keyword public
to expose
a symbol
to linker explicitly
especially for the labels
we need to note the double columns
and we can also
declare the external symbols by using
the keyword extern
here is the symbol example
we can see there is a cross reference
from the pdf segment to the text segment
then in the predator assembly file
there is a declaration
and in the text assembly file there is a
public keyword
notice the double columns here
so this is the processing logic
first scan all the item
from minimum address to maximum address
for each item guest or
cross reference list to its address
if there is no cross reference
script for the item
otherwise make the name public
for each item in the cross reference
list
if it is not in the same segment
add an extern declaration for that item
after got the assembly file
we can insert some
assembly instructions to do the
instrumentation
here is the code to find the
instrumentation points
scan all functions from segments
for each function scan all code blocks
for each code block make a comment
instrument here as a hint
during the post processing of the
assembly files
insert the trampoline instructions
before the comment string instrument
here
now is the time to resemble
which is the most difficult stage
there are too many
grammar errors to handle
and this cost me lots of time
i have written a passing script to to
them all during the assembly file
pre-processing stage
and there is another limitation for the
simulants
so i have to rename the long name to a
short one
masm is too ancient
maybe i should consider
try other assemblers
there is a longer list to tune the
grammar here is just a small part
note that i have to change all the short
jumps
into the long jump
because it may break the short jump
range limitation after the
instrumentation
now we got some obj files from the
assembly files now
it's time to link them
all
this is the key issue at the linking
stage
the api symbols from the imports table
are undefined
we must link with the properly files
but
but for some special api
i don't know what's the leap file to
language
maybe some import symbols are from
private sdks
while we don't have the private leaps
so we must generate the lib files
by ourselves
fortunately i found the lib.exe
from virus studio toolkit have the
function to generate lib files
according to the def file
so this is the solution
for the link issue
i just illuminate all important models
and create a def file for each model and
write the
import symbols into the def file
finally call leap.exe to generate the
lib file from
df file
after the linking stage we got a new
binary
but if there is one more step to run
we need to patch the pe header
such as this directory
for example
we need to patch
export date directory
to make it support to the location of
the symbol export dir
and we need to patch exception data
directory to point
to the location of the symbol
exception dir and so on
and then we need to fix the data entry
in the resource segment
the data entry value is relative to
image-based address
all of these fixed operations are in one
script
for automation
then we can draw and test
but i got some crashes
there are three kinds of issues that
lead to the crashes
all because of
the incorrect analysis result from ida
first is the unrecognized pointer
such as dq offset a symbol
the second is unrecognized image-based
relative value such as ddrva a symbol
the third is the unrecognized
function-based relative value
it is a compression encoded value for
the exception handling
i will talk how to fix these issues
later
either to msm
now works fine
but it's not suitable for full
automation
due to some corner case of grammar
tuning
thinking deeper i have another idea
let's think of the essence
a binary can be divided into two parts
the code and the date
for the code part
there are two kinds of instructions
one is the pure machine code
such as push
or move
the other can is like this
jump a label call a function
and
reference a data
segment
further data patch is similar
the pure machine code has no cross
reference
which means it can be dumped directly
the retina instructions has
cross reference
which means it needs to be fixed for the
symbol reference
therefore one binary can be divided into
two parts
the green part and the red part
the green patch can be dumped directly
however the rather part has simple
references
which need to be relocated
so the key point
of sbi implementation is finding out all
the cross references
which are represented by the red errors
in the picture
and the main task is to fix them all
correctly
so this is my second idea
scan all the instructions from minimal
address to maximum address
and record their addresses as the old
coordinate system
then during the scanning
output the machine code for ins for each
instruction
if the instruction has no reference
output is motion code directly
otherwise
output is the op code first
then output dummy bytes as a placeholder
and record its address and reference
type into a fixed table
during the scanning
insert the trampoline instructions
before the instruction with the comment
hint
instrument here
after the scanning
the size of the temporal output binary
file will be larger
then we will compute the new coordinates
for each instruction in the temporal
binary file
and record them as the new
coordinate system
then we need to fix the placeholder
according to the fixed table and the new
coordinate system
finally we got a new instrumented binary
file
next let's review this idea
it rewrites the binary directory
regardless of the file format
so it could be cross platform
in theory
the key point is fixing all the symbol
references or regulate regulations
and it seems too complicated to
implement
let's thinking of either to masm again
what does the masm do
what happens during the build process
why don't have to fix the
references manually during the process
of ida to masm
msm just
translates the
assembly to machine code
and adds the symbols to the obj file
actually it is the linker that helps to
fix the symbol reference
in the final binary
so can i directly
generate the obj files and make the
linker
help me to do the fixed again
this will bypass the dmasdm
and avoid fixing the symbol reference
manually
so my second solution comes
the tool ida2obj is used to do this
the difference from the first solution
is in the middle part
i will directly dump the obj files
instead of the assembly files
obj file is commons object file format
and this is the file structure
first is the file header
and option header the instruction
headers
the row date is used to
store the executable code and the
initialize the date
then
is the relocation information
symbol table and string table are at the
end of the file
after making sense the file structure
we can write a tool to generate the obj
file
luckily i found a ripple on the github
which meets my demand
avoid reinventing the wheels
the install
process is symbol just use the pip
command
and here is the symbol tutorial for the
python library
first create a module object first
and then create a section
write the machine code to the section
then add the section to the model
next
create a symbol record
and set its value to point to the offset
inside the section
here is zero
then
add the symbol to the module two
finally
serialize the module
object into the test.obj file
next i implement a class segment
to encapsulate some primitives
string method is used to add a ask a
string
to the string table
and a single method is used to add a
symbol record it will call the add
string method
add the relocation method is used to add
a relocation record
public symbol method and a reference
symbol method will call the method
the above
the class example has an abstract method
field
data
close the example and date example at
the start classes of the second number
they just
override the first data method to
implement the dumping logic
both the dumpers have the similar
dumping flow
it iterates all the instructions inside
the segment
stack by the current item size
and if the current item has a name it
will publicate
then it will compute the cross reference
list
if there is no cross reference it will
call the api get many bytes to dump the
data directly
if there is one cross reference
it will dump the
symbol
with this reference type
and if there are
if there are multiple cross references
it will dump many symbols
and they'll cross with the reference
type
during the dumping process
if it meets the hint comment string
instrument here
it will insert the base
code of the gemini instructions
and then increment the new address
pointer
it will use the link.exe
along with the virus studio
there are several arguments for the bat
command
the first argument is the module name
the second argument is the output binary
type
it's a dynamic library
an application
or kernel driver
the third argument is the payload type
choose af your payload or trace
payload the remain arguments are
optional to the linker
now it's time to integrate with a wing
afl
the key point is passing the bitmap area
to the instrumented binary
afl
used the api clarify mapping to create
the shared memory
harness user api open file mapping to
fetch the shared memory
i just do some
modifications from a good example
this is the
symbol architecture diagram
one more tip is enlarging the
math size
when you instrumenting
more modules
the function afl may be log
is implemented in afl payload dot
assembly
which will be linked into the target
binary
and will be called as each code block
to collect the code carriage
the main algorithm is the same as the
traditional afl further
by the way it supports the multiple
threads and multiple modules
as their previous locations
is an array
with the thread thread id
as is in depth
and will be cleared to zero before
each fast
iteration loop
as your area pointer is exported
and will be set to the shared memory
address by the harness
the harness is simple enough
initial function is used to do some
initial initializations before fuzzing
it set up the shown memory and named
pipe
pre and post function are called in each
fuzzing iteration loop
here is the code to fetch the shared
memory address into a global pointer
in its target function we'll set the afl
error pointer to the shared memory
address for each target module
now
it's demo time i will play the video
recorded before
this is the demo for my tour namely as
ida 2 obj
first clone the code
the ripple is private now i will
open source it later
i just put the code on the desktop
then create a workspace
such as demo
then copy the
target binary
which you want to fast
to the workspace
and then load it
into the
edit pro
note that you should choose
menu load and another resources
it asks me
whether to load the pdb file
yes
the
tour still works without pdb
okay auto analysis is done
then
execute my
script
first i want to execute the
leave impulse dot py
to generate the leap files
now
let's check the live files
we can see
there are
32 new files
which corresponding to the impulse table
check this one
these are the important symbols from the
import table
next
execute the script to dump the obj files
now
selectmen or type
okay the pump
is finished now
let's check the bobby device
yes let's link these obj files
into a new binary
just to use the
link command
we will see
the
new binary is generated
more step is to patch the
binary
okay
the patch is done let's note it again
then we will try the new generated
binary
for buzzing
just back half this one
replace two
before the class we can use the command
to check the
instrumentation
yes we can see
capture the
719 portuguese
next
next we will obtain the
multiple arrays
and this
plus
okay we can see
we captured more troopers now
then
run the first command
the r disk is the
i just create
there are four covers
and make
the output
of the directory
then run this command
we can see the further
is running now
before ending the demo
let's check the new generated binary
we can see in each code block
there is a piece of tracing code
that called seo maybe log
and this is the code we write in the
payload assembly before
thanks for watching
okay let's come back
let's make a summary first i just let
the linker hear me fix the symbol
references
however
the linker also generated some redundant
date
such as the pe header
which makes me counter use the old pe
header
maybe i can hijack link.exe
and only exploit exploit its functions
of fixing symbol allocations
second it could be cross platform in
zero
but i just make it come true for
64 platform
pe it is as fast as the compiler
instruction with the source code
finally the new binary could be
equivalent to the old one
only if all the cross references
analysis is right
so
the real challenge coming
the challenge is
the precondition of the solutions is
that the analysis results from ad
is correct
however for some reasons
sometimes
either can't
recognize some pointers or relative bad
values
and it may lead to some crash issue
issues
the solution is
creating assistance group scripts
to help ida
analyze before exporting
the script is used to scan suspicious
pointers from
this segment
it reads a keyword value
if the value inside the pe adjusts
range then it is a suspicious pointer
this script is used to
help some
relative values
there are some image-based relative
values
not recognized
many exist in the jump table of switch
case
the fixed logic is a bit of complex
maybe you will
cost some minutes to read it
but now let's check the fixer effect
we can see the difference in the red
rectangle
it was immediate value before
and it will get the character cross
reference after the fix
i'd ask force to analyze the exception
handling data structures
since the version
however there are still some
data structures
that can't be recognized
maybe because of the undocumented data
structures
there are some function relative values
in
sh4
the core logic of the script is writing
a password
according to the referred header file
here we can see the data reference is
recognized
correctly after the fix
c plus plus frame handler 4
ws fh4
it is a new feature to reduce the binary
size of c plus plus exception handling a
64 platform
some function relative values are
compressed
and saved into
update segment
the relative values will be larger
due to the instrumentation
so it means the update segment could be
enlarged too
it compress the value into one to five
bytes
depending on the value
these two functions
get
get a net encoded
and the decompression
are used to com decompression and
compression
the solution is simple i just rename the
compressed location to the concat of a
hand string
fix me
and the two targets adjust string
then
update the real value when the target
address changed
take away
i just introduced
two
static binary instrumentation
implementations
one is either two msm
the other one is added to obj
and then i introduced the
one
sbi algorithm
it will just
rewrite the binary directly
it could be cross-platform in serial
and either is not implemented yet
then i wrote some ida person scripts
to assist the analyses
the reports will be open source later
they are private now
future plan first maybe i will do some
bug fix
welcome to report issues and pro request
then i will try to integrate it with
other fathers
finally
maybe i will try to make the cross
platform idea come true
this is the references list
thank you
if you have any questions you can touch
me on twitter
or email me at mikijin at trendmacro.com