hey guys so we're back q a time with
paul vixxi uh if you guys don't know who
paul vixx is like i think you can google
that because he's like one of like the
most famous people for dns
in fact i think he's inducted into the
internet hall of fame probably like
seven years ago or something like that
so
uh
paul is actually going to be joining us
with uh boris tara team
so boris and paul are you guys there
hey come here
oh thanks man long time no see
i
am
uh you know
wishing that this had gone off in person
like i did last year but beyond that
life is is okay
can't complain i suppose right i mean it
could be worse
we are alive to compliance we're the
lucky ones
that's one way to put it yeah uh hey
thanks so much for staying up man i know
it's like relatively late for you on
where the other side of the world so
yeah thanks for for delivering your talk
in person and for also joining us here
at the q a
um before we get started though uh
i understand we're missing your slides
so if you have a second just like drop
that over to me when you're when we're
done over over here so i don't forget
also
but cooper says that you are going to be
doing a demo
you want to read your demo first or
what would you like to do
well i said that we would be doing a
demo i didn't say i was gonna do it oh
okay okay okay so boris and you are
gonna do a demo okay awesome man
hey boris you want to give us a little
bit of a introduction on yourself man
since uh yes absolutely yes uh boris
stratton i am in uk sun is just coming
out
uh it is a middle of the world between
you and paul
i'm with farsight for
for a little bit for over a year i love
it
i i join just because i share the vision
of making internet a safer place for
everyone
and i think this is something that keeps
us all
uh excited and awake
and
and here we are
so just reading your bio uh and it says
here you you publish stuff under the
nato high tech project man that sounds
hardcore man
oh yes everything else you can read on
internet google can
show you things that
i may not even know about myself
anyway paul you ready for your demo
thing or what should we just chat or
what you want to do but i mean this is a
informal session anyway so you know it's
just kind of relaxed
i would like boris to uh give us a few
minutes of uh
shell scriptory
worries no no pressure
yes
uh host disable participant screen
sharing can you let me know once again
how to share my screen sure
just give us a second the studio guys
behind there are like frantically
clicking
let me see
yes i can
perfect
let us recap a little bit uh what we
learned from what paul mentioned about
protective dns there are many
definitions and
what we need to
know for this specific uh engagement
that protective dns
it's an umbrella term
for the security solutions
that will inspect your
uh
which will inspect your
dns query
and give you the answer to prevent you
from accessing malicious resources on
the internet
this is all we need to know and there
are many different ways to do it
who was talking about um cloud
providers which can offer you
this these are cloud providers you can
go you just uh
make a query and you will find
a lot of bunch of those
so
maliciousness
as you probably know there is a lot of
studies has been done which discovered
that newly
observed or created items on the
internet or assets on the internet
statistically
are not safe to deal with
from 60 to 80 percent depending on study
depending on exactly what was started
the data set the time from 60 to 80
percent so it is better than flip of a
coin
[Music]
so
new stuff on the internet not
necessarily safe to deal with from time
it appears or you learn about this
to the time you understand the behavior
it requires some efforts
but if you statistically know
that majority of those are not safe to
deal with
and there is no legitimate reason for
those to be accessed immediately once
they appeared on the internet
the idea is as paul mentioned in his
keynote
just to prevent access to those until
you know
how good they are
what you see on the left side flying or
pausing this uh our life observations
of newly
[Music]
observed items so
we have not seen anything of this
from the start of our observation
and we started observe it
back in 2010.
once it flies over
it will be put in our database we call
it dnsdb
and just to demonstrate that this is the
case i will make a query
and you will see that it was observed
very recently
one time
now
let's take another one for some reason
it's just uh internet is probably
sleeping because it's early morning here
in uk and then it started once again so
i took another random
and once again
this is definitely newly absorbed by us
so we have not seen it before we have
over 500 sensors across the globe but
this is something that
we never saw before let's try another
one
just to make sure that i can
reliably convince you
see the date
see the date this is 7 00 am here
i'm british time this is ugc so one hour
back so three minutes ago
this is what we saw
look
this
asset already has an ip
we observe that being query
so let's see now
something
interesting
let's take
any random dns
and make a lookup
let's say we do want to resolve this
stuff
tell me which dns to take let's say
dime i know that dyn actually
does some form of security protection
and this is what i do so i ask time to
resolve this
and it is being resolved
perhaps it already knows something is
not right because it gives 127. let's
see other domains domain name servers
would be able to resolve it let's do
google
google already know well that's good
that means it's so bad that this cloud
providers actually know about this let's
take
some other stuff maybe this one
and try to resolve first i demonstrate
to you that this is newly absorbed by us
we see the asset already has an id
and let's do very same thing
with google first
right so google doesn't know whether
it's good or bad
okay
let's try
some other
open dna sneak let's try code 9
9.9.9.9
[Music]
it also knows about this
but statistically
this is greater chance for this
asset to be
not safe
rather than benign
a lot of studies are there and we can
give you the links to those studies they
are done independently on different data
sets during different period of time etc
so what it means is if my household
because i'm at home now everyone works
from home or many of those
us i work from home
if i used
this dnss from here
right
i would be able
let's get another one
norton i would be able
[Music]
to reach
this resource from the internet
me my systems my family
and we even don't know whether this is
also good or bad so now let's see what
we can do as you remember
paul mentioned about some of our
projects uh here
uh
which would consume rpg response policy
zone
one of this
we put on the
raspberry pi
at home in my closet
and i consume here 24 hours rpg zone
from far side
so whatever you see here
would be here i already demonstrate i
will demonstrate the stream so whatever
you see whatever we observed
will be pushed
through the internet right to my
raspberry pi
so
one solution
is
bind dns with rpg on it and under
quite nice uh gui management from ioc to
our pc project
the same
is under pichol so i have raspberry pi
with bind on it and my pi hole
works with bind which consumes the rpg
feed so at home i have six client this
is my statistics as you can see here
right now let's see how this stuff would
work
i
am trusting farsight to tell me what to
do with all those assets that's why i
put given everything else it's just
different configuration you don't need
to go into those uh deep stuff what you
need to know is very simple thing
if i now try
to resolve this asset
for one of my dns servers at home
192 168 that query directly
ate
this one
i will not be given any ip to
reach
if that asset indeed was not safe to
work with my household would be
protected
you may say well you were talking a lot
and that's why it's so cool and then you
now show us this stuff
let's take this one
okay
and
let's make it
real
so this one is still on the screen right
but my dns at home
will not let me go there
let's try uh
the one so yes let's try the one
192 168.
okay my typing in the morning is not
night time is okay 192 168 8 100
right
so that's clean
so something which is going still
from here let's take this one
let's go in here
and very very same domain
which was flying right on my screen
not quick enough
let's try another dns
one one one one which is mine
that's true there would be thermal fail
if we kept this up
yes all right you'll take another domain
that's not a big deal
no i think one demo fails enough let's
put well we're behind
want to fail is enough
too failed enough
yes okay
that's what you get from working from
home man
comcast has
really messed with me during demos um so
anyway i'm not going to worry about that
it does work
and um
we i just um
uh just published the video
with the where there were no demo
failures so that those demos were
successfully rigged anyway do we have
any questions i don't have the discord
client operating i could if i needed to
but
uh trusting at the moment uh there are
no questions from the audience however i
think sriman had a question that he
wanted to ask you guys a while ago yeah
so like you should in a demo right
people are more people are looking from
home more and more nowadays since kowitt
and all of their stuff and an rpg option
for
employees working from home is a bit
hard to implement how do you see dns or
dns monitoring sync holding
evolving in in in this situation
well i think right now
um
we're moving from one model that we knew
about to another model that we either
don't know about or don't like
um because it used to be that to work
from home you had a vpn
and vpn software used to go you know
reach its claws into your os and
it so that if you were connected to the
vpn then you could not reach anything
but that vpn and that would somehow keep
i don't know the kids gaming pc from
infecting you while you were attached to
the corporate mothership and so forth
um tricks like that don't really work
but they all sound good so they show up
as checklist items for endpoint and vpn
and so people buy the one that has that
then they depend on it then hell breaks
loose but
um that we didn't like
uh what we're going toward now is uh the
kind of uh god what do they call it
um the the trust
free you know where you you you never
have special access
to some of these servers like this is
the beyond corp or the zero corp or
something like that um where you never
have access based on where you're coming
from or what you can reach with a packet
that everything you do is certificate
based it's it's based on you know what
tickets you're holding and
as a result you know you could
conceivably run that corporate
network without a firewall other than
for ddos protection
and you wouldn't worry because none of
your file servers or printers or
anything would be willing to do anything
for anybody who didn't have
the right you know key material the
right certificate material
and
the people who are pushing that are you
know
i gotta say i i love the vision i don't
know where to get the crack that they're
smoking but um
it's um
you know what we're going to end up with
is a bunch of people who actually
believe they have that and um
that they're not going to even try
to worry about um the multiple horizon
problem where you're connected to the
corporate network and to various other
networks that are full of untrustworthy
people who might
somehow be able to masquerade as you i
don't know maybe it's
uh
[Music]
arp poisoning or something like that so
um
i am
i am concerned
but uh i think that for work from home
uh we're gonna have to have hardened
configs uh there there are ways to make
sure that your whatever your windows pc
cannot have its configuration changed by
somebody who doesn't have the
administrator password um and i think
within that i know apple has something
like that i'm sure smartphones are going
to have things like that within that
umbrella
i anticipate that the dns server will be
wired down to one that conforms to the
corporate security policy
that is unfortunately economically
infeasible for a family they are never
going to pay for that version of windows
or that version of mac os or any of that
but at least for the work from home
crowd for the bigger companies
or the smaller companies who can afford
to buy managed service provider you know
real i.t support in other words i think
we're going to see it i think
it'll just be that
when you are
using your work laptop you are using
some
name server that was uh approved by
works sysadmin
and works sysadmin may decide that the
way they can make their phone ring the
least
is if you have
personal dns on your laptop running rpz
so that you don't call them because
there was a network hiccup you can
actually do a lookup using your normal
isp but enforcing policy inside your
corporate laptop i think that model has
got legs
sorry long answer to a short question
how long do you think that's going to
take before we see that happening is in
like 6 months 12 months more than that
and would that be another agent running
on the machine
or
um
well moore's law has been kind so
fortunately the cores and the gigabytes
that are needed
to do all this extra stuff are all there
the unfortunate part is that they're all
full of buggy software and polluted
supply chains but
you know you asked a question you know
how soon before we see this
i
want to ask a different question would
we have seen it
so i think
an interesting question is how long
before this is not news
how long before
administrators everywhere are behaving
this way and know that this is in the
bag of tricks i don't know uh probably a
couple of um
usenix meetings
or whatever it takes to get the word out
uh and maybe for the folks at home that
just want to stay secure or increase
their privacy right is it is it
is it something easy for them to
implement a bind server with rpg
filtering on it or
did you have a recommendation on that
so
um i do
um
and you know what i'll say is that for
somebody who goes to your conference
ever
this is easy
um and
you and i both wish more people would go
um
and
so
my problem is that the
your average
person where the assisted men for their
company's chief claim to fame is that
they have certain certifications and
they've got you know
a degree and they've got whatever cisco
network security
certification or microsoft review
whatever those people
are really going to be using a bunch of
off-the-shelf stuff
and uh they probably will never think
that they have to come to a conference
like yours which i think is too bad and
will slow their career development
as well as holding the world back from
getting safer sooner but um
you know until microsoft and apple and
the rest of those folks decide that they
want to start training people to this
model and documenting it not sure how
much it matters what we do
that's encouraging
[Laughter]
but it's yeah i mean that's the reality
we live in right unless there's some
kind of commercial viability and need
for them to actually push this agenda
they're not going to do it i mean who's
going to pay for that right
but um
what's your plans for i mean at first
sight right like what are you guys up to
for the rest of the year any like
anything interesting planned or stay
safe stay home
well i'll be at uh thick and little
as will boris because it's a short
flight for a train ride for him across
the channel
um
so i will be in france next month
um be back in london for
black hat europe which i guess is in
november yep um
unless it's cancelled you know i was
scheduled to speak at the wild west hack
and fest and that went all full virtual
yesterday ah so
um
yeah so the the company did go to
oh god black hat las vegas
but
there it was kind of an interesting
turnabout where they didn't cancel it
they didn't make it virtual but we
decided we weren't going because we
looked at the numbers from
you know the various government websites
and said you know we cannot in good
conscience ask employees to go there and
we don't think anyone else is going to
either and so yeah it was ghost town but
we did uh we did do a virtual thing and
we did talk to some folks we made some
announcements we made an announcement
about protective dns
to say you know thank you dod um
and you know this is what protective dns
also means kind of the same as the talk
i just gave
but we also indicated that um
you know we're about to roll out you
know a handful of new
subscription feeds using this particular
system so that
certainly the appliance vendors were
likely to put our new feeds in their
catalogs
and um
the the customers that come to us for
newly observed we can now say hey look
look what else we have that you didn't
know about
nice nice nice
well fingers crossed that you know
nothing else gets canceled for the rest
of this year it seems that most things
are starting to open back up at least
like it appears that way europe uh i
mean our dutch guys are netherlands they
don't mean like nobody's very much you
can just walk around i'm like whoa
that's amazing man
it seems so like a you know
so i want to say
this delta thing is catching a lot of
people by surprise and so a lot of
my news has turned out to be old
um i had a um
a business trip to
germany and denmark
uh last month and it was great and uh i
keep a motorcycle in each of those
countries and that also was great but um
in fact i keep a motorcycle in in london
not far from boris as well
um
but um
the the time since then it looks like
germany has gone back to quarantining uh
people who who come in from outside
country yeah because their numbers were
just too high this delta thing is taking
uh
making a big reset in what we all
thought our plans were going to be yeah
i know man tell me about it i mean we
have plans for trying to do something in
november in uae for cyber week right
uh right this point in time like today
right everything seems fine but you know
tomorrow's another day and this thing is
just so unpredicted right i mean nobody
could have written this
this truth is stranger than fiction but
yeah i mean i remain hopeful fingers
crossed you know we'll be able to chill
out again soon rather than later
me too but i'd rather do it later and
have both of us uh be there for it so
i think
caution is indicated indeed indeed
anyway gentlemen thank you so much for
joining us uh
always insightful nice to see paul again
i mean it would be better if we were in
person but hey you know what can we do
right
thanks to
yes and at the end the screen was
showing uh everything in life and those
who were watching they were able to see
it
and this is going to be recorded anyway
man so it's right they'll watch it after
the fact like
we'll release all of the thoughts onto
our youtube as well so
yeah they'll be able to watch it there
and like yeah it'll be fine it'll be
fine