hi and welcome to uh probably one of the
first
uh presentations about
ai practical ai resume
and with an example of fashion
recognition
systems
uh my name is alex i'm
in
cyber security for about 18 years
starting from networks
up to databases applications
business critical systems and
ai i'm a founder of adverse ai
member fourth technology council wrote a
number of books
been in
dozens of different security conferences
and presented my
research i'm also very excited in other
uh
technology areas such as synthetic
biology neuroscience and
psyche
and
how i come up to the
ai security field i'll tell the just a
short story
so
about five years ago
uh we used to develop a user behavior
analytics system to
detect anonymous behavior
in critical applications
uh and at that time and we used a lot of
ml
uh and ai we we actually had a like a
brain system with multiple algorithms
and dedicated are on the team to for uh
for researching in ai space and
cybersecurity space
and then i found the research paper that
ai systems and basically neural networks
have a vulnerabilities and you can you
know uh fool the system
and at that moment i realized that we we
cannot
you know develop the
ai driven cybersecurity solution
without solving the task of uh
securing ai itself
and then i found out that's that the
only way
to do that is to
create a company that
basically will
put all the efforts to
uh
solve this mission and this is how
adverse
ai was created so we are startup with a
mission to increase trust in ai systems
actually by protecting
ai from cyber threats and i believe that
uh by making ai systems more secure we
can
actually make them uh
better in
any other areas as well
and we work in three different
directions uh in awareness area in
assessment area and insurance
in terms of awareness we
created a report on
ai
vulnerabilities we
provide like
newsletters and uh weekly digest on all
of these areas
uh in terms of assessment uh we do air
rate teaming uh this is what i will
tell about the more details and in terms
of assurance we uh have solutions and we
provide solutions to actually protect uh
the system ai systems from
uh various attacks and
uh in this presentation you will get a
bit more details on what kind of attacks
i'm talking about
so in this presentation i'll
briefly uh tell you about the ai
security in general so that you can just
understand uh the problem
uh then we will
uh continue with details on ai red
teaming
uh then we will
learn a little bit more about the
attacks in digital world and the most
important part we will uh continue with
attacks on the physical world
and uh cyber physical security and this
is
what ai returning is mostly
all about
and in the end of the presentation we of
course will uh touch defense part
uh and
some takeaways so
let's go
secure ai
so why securing ai is essential and
what's what's basically the difference
uh and i'm
i'm sure that the difference is uh
tremendous it's really it's really huge
so in the traditional software we have
some kind of fixed program logic and we
interact with this software with help of
uh different commands
and those comments
are usually structured
so
in most cases the typical
vulnerabilities in uh traditional
software are
improper validation such as buffer flow
sql injections squares or shifting like
name
any uh mostly it's like it's improper
validation of course we have some access
control
things like misconfigurations but
you know most of the most critical uh
attacks are improper validation
in ai
we have a solutions that are basically
powered by some kind of flexible machine
learning
training
and we interact with this software
with help of uh some cognitive uh
ai interfaces like a vision
audio language and so on so this is like
unstructured data
uh and the
in this in the applications we have new
types of attacks which are
basically uh
similar in the
uh in high level
they also have like
they also have invasion type of attack
poisoning
exfiltration
but those attacks are
in the different
uh
areas in the unstructured data
so while we kind of know how to protect
our systems from sql injections uh
because we can you know sanitize input
we have no idea right now how to
sanitize input in the
video flow like what is okay in the
video and what is not what is okay in
the language comments what is okay in a
audio like it's a completely different
uh
type of software it's completely
different type of interfaces
it's completely different
uh
types of vulnerabilities and and so on
so the threat landscape is changing
and
it's like uh
in the 90s we had a network security
uh
then in the 2000s we have uh we had a
endpoint security and like in 2010
there was an era of application security
and now from 2020 we will have an
era of ai security
and why it's it's critical
right now uh
because we already had examples of
uh confidentiality integrity and
availability
uh problems like um
personal data was extracted from a
netflix data set that was shared for
uh machine learning uh contest
uh in terms of integrity uh there was a
real vulnerability in silence ai driven
malware detection engine
that was bypassed because of the
vulnerabilities in machine learning
algorithm
uh we keep hearing a lot of
news about uh
tesla uh problems uh autopilot problems
in other other
uh examples so it's already
uh
critical and we already have problems
here
so what are we talking about in general
uh what are the
ai applications so in this
slide you can see the
list of
applications ai applications that had
the biggest number of uh
research papers devoted to security of
those applications
um
so we see that
obviously the image classification like
facial recognition uh
malware detection and all those
applications
already have a lot of
real vulnerabilities and real attacks
so who is affected uh actually the
both the
the new types of uh
new industries like autonomous driving
like robotics
uh they obviously are are
uh
potentially uh vulnerable to
uh like ai attacks but also we have a
lot of old school industries like
healthcare
finance
and they have more they implement more
and more uh ai things and
uh
obviously maybe uh
vulnerable to
uh various ai driven uh
air driven attacks
um
a little bit on the history of um
attacks on ai
well well it's basically started way uh
before 2010
uh but the the real
like attention to this
uh topic probably started in 2014-15
after the the first uh
presentation about the uh post research
about the adversarial attacks
um
and then uh we started to see more and
more our research papers
uh
either
on
one of different types of attacks on um
ai applications or different
uh
approaches to protect uh ai applications
and
now even after more than 4000 research
papers published we still don't have any
um
uh proper protection from those types of
attacks so it's really
a
critical problem
and it's
it's still a big problem
so what what are we talking about what
are the the attacks uh in in ai uh
we uh we try to create some kind of
awasp top 10
um
list of attacks on our ai systems based
on the number of
research papers published
about those types of attacks so
the first one is evasion when we
are trying to uh bypass a normal
behavior of ai system
uh like
uh
misclassify a
dog with cat and something uh we have
poisoning attack uh this is where we
uh inject some uh data into the training
set
uh we have membership inference attacks
uh where we can disclose uh the
information of uh if this particular
uh data
example was in the training set
um
back doors
like a
similar concept
uh as in traditional systems
model extraction attacks are attacks
uh to extract
the
uh model algorithms
uh attributing inference attacks it's uh
like disclosing information uh some kind
of critical information
about the data
uh trojans it's a kind of backdoors but
more uh
like if you if vectors are
uh
if you have some access to data and the
model so the trojans is basically when
you can inject some
malicious behavior
in already trained
system
model inversion attacks
uh when you can find
uh information about the data
entire water making attacks like bypass
protection controls and for
copyrightings etc
and reprogramming uh one of the most
interesting uh
types of attacks like we
uh
actually repurpose ai models
to
execute like different tasks
so this is the very brief list of um
most common attacks
and
uh since the patient attack is the most
uh popular one let me briefly describe
you what
what it is so basically we have for
example the image classified
classifier
and
we have an image of peak and we want
this image to be classified by ai as
something else
uh the the typical way in in a very high
high level is to understand what are the
most
uh
critic
important pixels
uh and then
change those pixels in a such way that
uh it won't be
uh
uh it will be imperceptible for humans
but it will change the uh
behavior of ai algorithm and there are
many uh
different
ways how to like mathematically
calculate
the uh the
amount of changes and actually the
the
the the pixels itself that you
have to change
um
and this is not just an academia uh
there were
uh a lot of uh
research papers devoted to the real
software not just only the some uh ml
algorithms so
here you can see the
the huge list of uh different types of
uh real applications
which were
uh
somehow uh bypassed uh because of the
vulnerabilities in ei systems
um
and also we already
saw a lot of
uh real attacks by
some
malicious actors
and here's here's a big list of of them
like uh infection of
microsoft board
uh evasion of spam detection systems
uh
different manipulations of
search engines it's a very old
thing
so attacks on the uh flash recognitions
for uh tax fraud
uh and so on
so
all this uh
information
uh
it's it's really a sign to
devote more attention to
some kind of uh
testing for uh ai systems for
vulnerabilities and
the the new term uh
uh was created uh we were called ai red
teaming um so basically it's kind of
penetration testing but for
ai systems uh and there are like
regular security uh
teams who exploring the
uh
field of uh
ai red teaming
uh
there are air teams in uh
some ai development company
uh to test the systems internally
and there are air like specially
dedicated air teams are offering ai
security advisor like like we do
uh and more and more companies uh
currently have dedicated air teams like
facebook microsoft uh media
open ai and so on
so uh
you can find uh
more details on like
high level information about ai
vulnerabilities in in our report called
which was called uh
the roar to secure trusted ai
uh and here we collected information
on uh
10 years of research
in this area
so let's
jump into the more uh practical part
uh like
basically the ai red teaming
and let's start with some air teaming
scenario like how to basically uh
perform it
uh and let's start with the problem
so as i already mentioned uh we have
currently over 4 000
research papers in the field of
adversarial machine learning
and every day we have like five to ten
uh
more research papers in this area and
they
they are more and more
complex so uh
the the second problem is that
it's we have a countless
number of different
uh conditions and combinations
uh on which those research papers were
uh conducted so for example like
one research paper is telling you that
this algorithm
uh
can be vulnerable to this vulnerability
uh in
uh this environment
and another algorithm telling you about
the same vulnerability but in other
environments so you cannot really like
compare it so there are no like
um
uh
good uh
databases and comparisons and statistics
and so on to understand like
what kind of vulnerabilities are real
what kind of vulnerabilities are just
like research papers
uh and so on and the other problem like
there are no real uh real understanding
of if those uh
potential of vulnerabilities
uh
are transferable to the real world
applications
you know so we decided to propose our
own approach
how to
test the ai systems and be sure that we
covered
the the most
uh
possible
ways to
attack so it's basically our
uh
say uh
ai threat model
so first
step in the ai threat model is to choose
the attack goal like what you want to
achieve
uh
so for example we take the facial
recognition system
and what we can do we can like produce
the confidence uh
reduce the confidence
uh
we can uh
miss
create misclassification like to avoid
person detection
uh or we can make targeted
misclassification like to pretend to be
another person
so
for example uh let's say we choose
our goal as a target misclassification
the next step is to choose the attack
form
uh
and it depends on the
on the threat model uh it depends on the
what kind of uh flash recognition system
you want to bypass is it's like a
airport system is it a
online banking system
um
so it depends like what kind of uh
physical patch or digital patch you can
apply
because sometimes you can
wear glasses sometimes you can't wear
glasses uh
and you need to create something
more complex some sometimes you can have
a
band aid and it's okay
so
the next step is to choose the form
depending on your uh
thread model
next uh
we should understand what who is a uh
a potential attack actor
uh if attacker have some access to model
if attacker can have some access to api
or uh he can have access to device and
not more
and
it so we either have a white box testing
or grey box testing or black box testing
uh in our particular example we decided
that we have a black box testing because
we like
uh
we just had access to
like device but we have no
information about the
algorithms and and so on
uh then you have to choose attack
conditions
uh
like
the environment
so it can be digital environment like um
uh some online system
uh and
in an online system uh
our goal is to
uh avoid whereas pre-processing of
things like compression clipping and so
on
uh it can be physical environment like
3d
so uh
we should take care about the printing
issues because if you construct
the
uh attack like
uh glasses
uh
you test them on the digital world but
when you print them the colors may
change and they can may change like
completely and your attack will not work
and if your attack doesn't work in the
physical world it doesn't mean that it's
not possible it just mean that you
uh
did not pay
attention
to this printing issues
so if you don't do that you may have a
false sense of security that yeah i just
printed those glasses but they doesn't
work
in the physical world so this is not the
attack is not possible
no it can be possible but you have to do
uh we have you have to take into account
that there are printing issues
um
or
if it's a dynamic physical environment
uh
if you
need to move
uh your head if you if you need to if
you have a different uh
angles if you have different type of
light different environment
uh
all those things are
affecting your uh
let's say exploit in in our case like
glasses are the exploit
so you you have to choose your attack
conditions
um
so then and only then and it's like a
final step you can choose the actual
method
uh for your attack and there are
different methods
uh
they are usually like different
mathematical
algorithms how to
um
find the
proper
uh pixels to change how to construct
this patch in such a way that it will
bypass the system so here you can see
like
some of the uh most common uh attack
methods
uh but uh pay attention that there are
hundreds of other methods and
i mean even
like in the time between
recording my presentation
and you
uh looking at this presentation i
guarantee
uh
that there will be at least one or two
new methods
published
so it's really a
very emerging area
uh
and finally
um
there are three success criterias for
your attack
uh
like first one is of course
misclassification like the attack
success rate like how your
potential attack is uh working is it
possible to achieve the goal the second
is imperceptibility like
how difficult to detect
this uh attack uh by humans or by
some algorithms uh and transferability
like uh how stable this attack
in changing environment or
if you try to apply
uh
attack that was constructed on
uh one system if you try the same attack
on the other system so how transferable
is your attack
um
so
what we achieved uh
is the attack that is
transferable uh
very uh
have very good misclassification rate
and uh
kind of
uh
imperceptible
uh and
in the slide you can see the uh
some article about the
uh
our previous attack in the digital world
so you can see uh the photo of
journalist
which we slightly changed
and then we
checked
this photo on primeise
it's a
face search engine
and when we put his photo on the face
search engine uh it's
uh
this search engine decided that he is uh
mark zuckerberg
uh
so it was uh
uh done intentionally so we changed his
uh photo in such way that system the
fashion recognitions search engine
decided he's
mark zuckerberg
so as a home task you can uh
guess uh
who is on this photo so
this is screenshot from the uh hack in
the box conference and you can see that
it's me on the photo but
some facial recognition systems will
think that it's
uh
somebody else
okay so that was a a a digital attack
which is uh
uh
impressive but we decided to
make a further steps and
test physical facial recognition systems
um and it started with uh
basically the um
one of the engagements where uh the
physical security solution provider
uh
asked us to test their uh
slash recognition
software and hardware
so our goal was to demonstrate uh
that the threat is real
uh and we wanted to achieve
a number of goals like
first it must work in the physical
environment
then it's
it must be transferable
as a it's a it's a black box attack so
uh the goal was to construct
the
physical attack on the facial
recognition system
that can be transferable to
uh other facial recognition systems so
we had no
uh knowledge on what kind of algorithm
they use we only uh
had
uh
our own uh
facial recognition engines that we
downloaded from the internet
and we tested all of our attacks on on
them
uh and the third goal or
we tried to make it
uh
imperceptible as much as possible uh
like
but it was not the
the final not the the main goal
um
so as for existing research
there were
around 100
research papers on
various attacks on facial recognition
some of the uh potential uh
potential attacks uh
were mentioned in me in media
uh
but there were no
uh practical
uh live demos that they
really can work in the physical world
uh and there are no like code
uh that can prove
that it's really working
and as i said before uh
we wanted
uh this to work not only uh in uh
in the white box scenario but also to be
transferable
uh
so why it's important to test in the
real environment because reality is like
it's much more complicated than uh lab
conditions
uh there are different uh camera
environment and pre-processing features
and all that should be taken into
account
and as i previously mentioned so if you
just try to to
transfer
a digital attack to physical world it
may not work and you may have false
sense of security that it doesn't work
uh
so what are the uh the main environment
conditions
uh first of all it's uh in what uh some
environment things like uh lights and
brightness and distance to objects you
if you should take into account it
when you construct the
patch they exploit
uh
then we have device features
uh of of camera itself like uh
resolution quality and color rendering
and believe me the color rendering is
can uh can break like most of your
uh attacks because a lot of cameras like
uh
have a very different color red
rendering
and you may have a
a red color but it can it will recognize
this color as a pink color and all your
efforts to construct the adversarial
patch
uh will not work
and also there are pre-processing
features like different codex
compressions
and data data transfer compressions and
so on
so
a few approaches um
how
you can work with such
problems
so you can use some uh
fine function for
a big pixel difference when you
construct the attack
uh you can train your attack take into
account that
that
uh there can be very
various sizes and angles
of your uh patch
you can act or subtract color changes as
for example as i previously mentioned
that
there is a camera that
think that red is pink so you may take
into account this
while constructing the patch it may work
but it's not transferable
uh cheat but it uh you can achieve some
uh
something with with this
uh you can use some gaussian blur
generation eye to be more transferable
or
color randomization and so on so there
are
different ways how to
overcome the environment things
so
uh
the working combo and it's one of the
possible working compass
that worked for us
you can see the
many examples that we tried and
um
you can see the one
example with the physical glasses that
actually worked uh in our case
uh
and
here are the
the tricks
so for a better accuracy
uh
we choose
to
calculate uh adversarial attack
uh on each layer of neural network uh
and we use deep full algorithm for that
uh
then uh we use the ensemble of networks
uh to train our model so we train
oh to train our attack
we try to uh perform it on the ensemble
of models
simultaneously so
the idea is like the more
uh
models you try to
uh attack
the
more
accurate and transferable will be your
exploit
then for better transferability um
we used uh random noise while we
constructed the patch
uh
and the other thing which is uh
very important
uh in fashion recognition system you you
not only have a
face recognition you also have a phase
detection
uh it's also neural network which work
before fascia recognition
uh and
basically you need to attack two neural
networks
uh
so you need to attack one neural network
but in such way that the first neural
network
uh
will work and basically detect your face
and detect your face properly so your
attack
uh should not
uh break your attack on the second
neural network should not break the
functionality of first neural network
so it's like a chain of attacks and to
better transfer ability across different
uh phase detection engines uh we have we
use different uh
phase frames
to uh transfer between different uh
phase detection engines
uh
for better uh imperceptibility in the
physical world uh we use two things the
smoothing
functions so that the colors will be
more smooth
and more uh
realistic and we
we use black and white
glasses because
in uh
some of the previous research papers uh
the glasses were
uh
they had uh
some acid colors
and
that's obvious uh that if you have such
uh
acid color glasses
that's something wrong
uh
so we try to avoid that and uh
create the black and white glasses and
it it works so you don't have to
have a color exploit basically
uh black and white
also can work
so
here is the uh
[Music]
okay so uh
i was inspired by tik tok videos and uh
the latest song so
sorry for this stupid music music uh
intro but here you can see that it's a
real um
physical attack
uh it works in the physical world uh
you can
uh just you can smile so you can do
different activities with your face in
such way that you basically can
bypass
the
biometric systems with liveless
detection uh because those systems can
ask you for to make a smile to blink
eyes to
shake head a little bit so all this
possible
uh with this physical example
so yeah results are first of all
we successfully fold the effect
recognition system
secondly uh glasses have uh
the best mystification rate but
uh other patches are
also possible
uh
the
exploit also work even in uh men to
woman combinations so
in the in this uh slide you can see the
uh other example where we which we
changed the the guy to
jk rowling and the further optimization
is also possible so we can make uh
glasses a little bit smaller and
and so on but it was out of scope
uh well um
let's talk about defenses
um
first of all
uh the biggest problem
it's not as i said before it's not a sql
injection where you
know how to protect
and it's not that like a one sql
injection it's
um
hundreds
thousands of
injection uh injection vulnerabilities
uh in the model so uh um i mean that
you can create a patch
uh
to detect
or to bike
uh
to detect
the glasses that we created like this
particular example but i can create the
new ones
and they will bypass the ai algorithm
and so on so it's not that easy to
protect even if you have exploit
secondly there are no
one-size-fits-all
protections
uh
for
your ai algorithm because
there are different threat models
so if we talk about the
digital apis
attacks can be
like small changes to a face image
as you saw in the
first example
if you have physical uh attack uh
it's glasses so those are
different types of attacks
and
there should be different types of
defenses depending on your
application and your threat model
[Music]
and third there are no hundred percent
reliable protections because
uh
you must test various combinations of
potential defenses and you must accept
potential trade-offs so
sometimes
uh if you have
some uh
patch for your neural network
to protect from this attack in it may
affect the overall accuracy of
uh
your ml system
so
it's a trade-off
okay so but what we can do
um
there are three uh high-level uh
approaches
uh
to protect uh the system
uh you can modify your training phase
like
create make adversarial training also
basically you can add the adversarial
examples to your training data set
um the other thing you can modify the
model itself
use different activation functions
uh
different types of layers and do
some tricks in the
ml system
this very uh it's kind of hard uh
especially if you want to
be sure that the other functionality
won't be broken after
uh
this modification
and other way is to modify the the
inputs like do some kind of
pre-processing jpeg encoding compression
any other things like before uh before
your model
um
[Music]
so what we can say about those
approaches uh
at the high level of course because uh
there are different ways
uh and you should test it but
uh modifying training
uh is expensive way
because you have to add a lot of uh
adversarial cases it may be even more
cases than the number of uh
real cases so you can multiply
your training time
uh
and your
training costs by
at least two
or
ten
on average
uh and
also the
this approach can be bypassed because
you can generate the other adversarial
example
uh on trend network
uh you can modify models uh but the
problem is it may lead to decreased
accuracy and
uh other problems that you
don't even have a way to detect
uh and you can modify inputs uh it's
it's uh probably the best one of the
best approaches but
it's complicated and it's task specific
so if you create some algorithm to
detect and and modify inputs for
facial recognition system it may not
transfer
even to phase detection system and i'm
not saying that
uh
and
it's hard to transfer between like other
types of systems
so as you can see all types of defenses
have their advantages and disadvantages
uh but what you can do
uh is to
implement some kind of secure ai
lifecycle
uh
and start with awareness like
educate stakeholders in the ai and
security teams that the threats are uh
real
and study relevant policies and
practices
to secure
your ai
then uh you can perform initial threat
monitoring to understand risks
and you can use our threat modeling that
was presented in
in this um
in this talk
and
then you can conduct the uh
initial
air teaming
uh for mission critical ai systems
um
but the the most important part is the
assurance so
then
understand then uh respond to
uh the findings
uh and most importantly uh integrate
those activities in in your ai
development life cycle
so that it won't be just a one uh
uh one-time job it should be a
a life cycle
where you continuously uh analyze it
so the next steps uh
there are a few things
which i recommend is first like
uh educate your uh ai and security teams
uh perform initial threat modeling
uh
test your system like conduct error
teaming
understand uh security findings and
integrate them into your yeah security
lifecycle
um
so thanks for for listening and uh
i hope you
enjoyed and get some practical knowledge
from this presentation
uh i know it's very hard to put all this
all all the
ai returning um information into
one hour presentation so uh you're
always welcome to uh
download the latest uh
details
uh
on our website you can subscribe to our
newsletter and you can read our weekly
digest about the new attacks threats and
and so on and you're always welcome to
ask any questions about
uh
everything that you want to know about
vulnerabilities in ai because
it's really the future
so thanks for listening
uh and goodbye
you