all right i think i think that's pretty
much everybody who's going to come right
now
uh
other people might be joining a bit late
they might join us a bit late so
um hello
everybody uh again my name is yusuf and
uh alongside me is my partner ahmed and
welcome to the day two of training so
today is going to be exciting today
we're gonna move on in the material
we're going to have a lot more fun
and we're finally going to get to
hacking
services submitting flags and moving up
on that scoreboard all right so let's
start by i'm going to start by sharing
my screen
right and you guys just give me
any signal that you can see
yes we can see
all right thank you so let's take a look
at the scoreboard which is the biggest
thing that has changed all right so
it as you can see there are some teams
who were very busy all night and they
hacked all services so you can see that
all four services have been hacked and
flags are being stolen from them and so
they moved up
on the leaderboard some teams only
managed to exploit two services some
teams got one service and it's fine for
the rest of you that you didn't do much
which is fine some teams are going to
jump a little bit ahead maybe they have
experience with the platform they've
done this sort of thing before
and that's more than fine okay don't get
demotivated don't think oh we're going
to get destroyed now there's no point no
there's always a chance all right if all
of you are put on equal ground things
would be a little bit more different all
right especially since some of you
attended the training so late at night
and you had to sleep after it so don't
worry about it now i can see that a lot
of you guys have your services as down
like
a lot of teams have their services down
and i think i know the issue behind that
so i need everybody who's here to ssh
into your
your virtual machines okay as i am right
now and i need you to do
df-h slash
now
if your virtual machine tells you that
you have no space left
you have 0gb of space left
then
you probably left your tcp dump command
running all night and it just made 150
gb pcap file
and so the system has no more space so
your services are down
so if that is the case
go into your tmux sessions or go find
the tcp dump command that was running
and kill it and remove the pcap files
all right now for everybody else if
you're now now once you guys i'll give
you a couple of seconds to remove the
pcaps and fix your space issues if that
is what happened because that's what
happened to me as well i logged in and i
had 0gb of space so i was like oh i left
the p-cap running all night by accident
so here we go
usually in the competition you would
remove the p cap every once in a while
you would clear it just empty it
obviously nobody needs 150 gbp gap
so
i'm assuming now that most of you have
logged in and you've started to you know
fix up everything so the first thing
we're going to do is we're going to
restart our services now you have two
ways of doing this you can either
restore the snapshot that you took
yesterday the initial snapshot that you
took yesterday
from the cloud console
but you'll lose anything that you might
have installed on the machine especially
current so if you set up quarant with me
yesterday you will lose it if you
restore your snapshot however
you you can reinstall it if that's what
you want if you feel like it's better to
just go back to a default state
especially for those of you who might
have issues essentially into their
machines in the first place
if you can't even like your machine is
not even responding to you trying to log
in it's best to just restore the
snapshot
all right and you can install carrant
again you guys have the slides and you
have all the materials so speaking of
slides i'm going to drop in the slides
here for some people actually i'm going
to wait a bit before i drop the slides
because
i feel like some teams are going to just
get too excited and go and start
exploiting and that's not quite what i
want them to do right now so i need you
guys to stay with me as much as you can
i promise we're going to get to the
exploiting part as fast as possible
so let's restart our services since most
of our services apparently on the
scoreboard are mumble and down
so you're going to go to slash home
you're going to see all your different
services you're going to go into your
services one by one so i'm going to
start with coffee pot and you're going
to run the following command docker
compose
up dash dash build
dash dash force
recreate
and dash d so what this is what this is
doing is that we're forcing the
container to be rebuilt from scratch
again and we're redeploying it and we're
putting it in the background so we're
letting the container run in the
background this is to restart all our
containers back to the initial state so
that any exploits any issues that might
have happened are now gone so i'm gonna
copy this command if my terminal would
let me
and paste it here okay
all of you go one by one into your so
i'm gonna do this on coffee pot
and that just rebuilds the coffee pot
container it's recreating the service
right now
and it's done all right
and now i'm going to go back so i'm
going to go back to home
and there's another service free life so
i'm going to go to free life i'm going
to paste the command again i'm going to
rebuild free life that's it free life is
done
we're gonna go into the next service
health monitor we're gonna rebuild
health monitor
there we go
and
nope i wanted to type ls
we're gonna go into nasa rasa our final
service and we are going to rebuild
asarasa
all right
now i have a feeling someone must must
have probably logged into my quran
overnight and just destroyed it so i'm
just going to stop my current service
you guys can feel free to leave your
current services running as long as you
guys just double check on your current
services double check that you guys
added authentication and everything is
going well other than that i'm going to
take mine down because i don't need them
anymore
if you guys also feel like you don't
need your current services you can do
docker compose down inside current all
right
and we're back
to how we were
so all my services should be up if i go
to the scoreboard i am org one
where is org one or guan and you can see
all my services are green up
and i'm gonna explain what the
scoreboard means you guys are seeing a
lot of numbers here and i'm going to
explain
what all these numbers mean
okay
let's start with
let's start with with the colors you're
seeing here all right
so
let's look at green so these arrows at
the bottom under each service that means
the service is up and this is the
percentage sla
okay
so this team
this team
has 94 percent
sla kind of all right they've been up
94 of the game all their services have
been up 90 plus percent some people
for example like team number six right
now
or in the sixth position has most of
their services are down and they've been
up only 26 of the game
some teams their services are mumbling
so they're sort of working
you know mumble i thought we did we
discussed mumbo yesterday which means
that the service isn't working properly
so this is probably they tried to patch
their service and they didn't patch it
properly
um
most of services are mumble these could
be as a result of exploits like bad
exploits that destroyed the service and
that's fine all you got to do is reset
your containers and you're going to be
as good as new so you can see a lot of
teams now have started to restart their
services and your sla is going up as you
can see
your sla sees here so the average sla
you can expand your team you'll see the
average sla is 52 and flag points
and this number right here is your flag
points that is your score and it's
affected by sla
now flag points are separated on each
service right here so they earned 34 000
points
from coffee pot 240 points from free
life 188 health monitor 283 nasa rasa
and you can even see these smaller
numbers under each
surface these these this is how many
flags have been stolen so they stole
1084 flags from coffee pot they stole 8
000 flags for free life 4 800 for health
monitor and so on
and in the red that's how many flags
they lost how many flags were stolen
from them
all right and you can see here in the
bottom a total so in total they stole 22
8 22 000 flags almost and they lost only
175 so this team really patched up their
services as fast as possible you can
even see that there's a team here that
never lost the flag in coffee pot so
they probably found the bug first people
patched it and they called it a day
all right
so let's let's keep going so this
scoreboard is definitely going to change
overnight you guys can ignore these
teams that were
busy all night okay
and you guys can just
focus on yourselves you keep going all
right it's just the training anyway so
stay motivated it's all about the
experience it's all about the fun it's
all about finding the exploits and
writing them and getting used to the
whole thing
so
with that being said let's move on to
our material for today
this is yesterday's material and welcome
to day two material
so
let's get started
today we're going to be explaining what
you should expect when you look at a
services code base what we mean like
what what files do you expect how you
should expect everything to be assembled
then we're finally going to get to the
good part which is finding
vulnerabilities in our services we're
going to be exploiting them and patching
them and then we're going to learn about
something called an attack defense
exploit farm and these are amazing tools
just like quarant that really really
help and can make a big difference in
how efficient you are in capturing flags
in an attack defense competition right
so let's move on so let's talk about
flags although we kind of did talk about
this yesterday flags are usually found
and stored in databases in services but
can also be found in the file system in
some cases it all depends on the
vulnerability so remember i told you
guys when your services start up you
should pay attention to when the check
system inserts flags into your system
and where do they show up so for example
let's let's take an example here let me
login to my nasa rasa surface
so
10.60.100.3 nasa rasa runs on port 80.
okay where are the flags so i can go to
users
oh boy someone had a lot of fun here
how am i supposed to okay well this is
what happens when you have 20 000 people
exploiting your service
things happen
i have no clue how i'm gonna be able to
find the service right now find the
actual uh user
please
you know what we'll we'll check on this
in a second
we'll come back to the service in a
minute
this is this is all automated exploit
scripts that are signing up for the
service
uh because part of the
part of the vulnerability is pretty much
signing up
come on
waiting for the check system to drop in
a new
so
we know that the check system drops in
new flags every 60 seconds which is how
long a round is
okay here we go finally so we see a
bunch of exploits happening here and
then we see
a user that got put that's out of place
called you know it's just two names
so we see this user we see that they
registered as some random generated
username
and
if we somehow go into the database and
look at this user you're gonna find out
that this user actually uploads a flag
in the description of their profile
okay so you somehow have to find a way
to log in as this user and take the
secret private message that they can put
under their profile that's the flag so
it's we're looking for some sort of
authentication bypass authentication bug
all right you can find out more and more
by exploring the code but you have to be
familiar with your services watch where
the check system uploads flags into your
services carrant can help with that you
guys can watch when the check system is
putting flags in and just track where
they end up landing in your system all
right
so moving on we know that the flag
format is this regex so 31 random
characters and it ends with an equal
and this is an example
and your goal is to steal these flags
from the other team's services and
submit them to the check system to gain
points right
so the game time is split into rounds
all right and in hacking the box these
rounds are one minute long so every 60
seconds
check system is going to add new flags
and the check system is going to check
your services every minute
and the flags that are valid for being
submitted for submission are the flags
that have a lifetime of 15 minutes
so
flags expire 15 rounds later so if you
try to submit a flag and it's been
in the game for 14 minutes it will be
valid but once it becomes 15 minutes old
it stops being valid so you should try
to limit yourself try to ignore any
flags that are older than 15 minutes all
right and we'll talk about this more
when we're talking about building
exploits and exploit farm and all that
so service code base structure
each service as we know has a docker
compose file and a docker file which
contain information about how the
container is built and deployed what
libraries are being installed what
system packages are being installed all
that stuff you can find in the docker
file and docker compose
and depending on the language that the
service is written in the logic can be
in a few files for example you might
just be lucky enough to have
main dot pi and that's pretty much the
entire service or you might be unlucky
and you'll have a big django service so
if you've ever dealt with django in
python you know that it's like 300 files
all over the place
each doing a different thing all right
that's why it's recommended that if you
see a bunch of files you see a framework
that you're not familiar with or a
language you're not familiar with it's
best to google because sometimes some of
these files are going to be
you know just
they're they're not useless but they're
generated by the framework or by the
language they don't actually contain any
logic there
all right
and you're going to see examples of this
in a second so what are the services
that we have
we have nasa rasa which is a php web app
with an exposed mysql database
we have health monitor which is a web
app written in go all of these are web
apps you have coffee pot it's a cgi
script written in bash and free life it
is a django web app written in python so
we have php go bash and python four
different languages four different
frameworks it's all different but
they're all
they have one thing in common they're
all web apps
so the first thing we're going to do is
we're going to
talk about techniques to finding
vulnerabilities but before that let's
take a look at the code shall we let's
just let's just double check what i just
said so let's just go
let's just go to home so i'm gonna go to
home
okay and we have
the four services i'm gonna list copybot
and you see that there's a second folder
inside it called coffeepotservice so
when i list it there's another folder i
see a dockerfile which can give me an
idea so let's cat this docker file let's
let's read this docker file so i see
that we have ubuntu 16
and we're just copying a bunch of
so we're adding a the coffeepot folder
into the container we're running some
permissions and we're basically just
running the coffee pot web server
wow that that's pretty much simple
okay let's take a look at the source
code so coffee pot coffee pot surface
and coffee pot you'll see here that we
do have a cgi script so that's how you
know you can tell you just see
coffeepot.cgi
and
and that's pretty much all you need to
know so take a look at coffeepot cgi
and it's essentially a cgi script
written in batch bash and we'll talk
about this we'll explore this later all
right
next service free life let's see what's
inside free life we have another docker
compose file so let's open let's open
free life we see that free life is
actually just straight up a python
docker container so we know it's a
python web app they're adding and it
says right here install django and just
pip install django and they just run the
django web app so you know you start to
see keywords django and python you know
it helps you google let's look at health
monitor let's read health monitors
docker container
so cat health monitor docker file
we see immediately it's a go line
container it's straight up it's a go app
you can see that they're initializing
and they're building the service and
they just run
health monitor after it's been built so
now you know that it's go
so you see the docker files really can
give you an idea
about what what what to expect and
what's happening so in nasa rasa it's
not that simple we have to go we have to
cut the docker file we see again it's
php
it's a php container running apache and
they're just copying code in they're
installing some extension php extensions
like mysql and that stuff and they're
just running the service
okay so these can give you hints and
it's always important to look at these
docker files what if they're installing
like for example that ubuntu 16
container does it have any default
packages that might be vulnerable does
it have any are they doing anything
specific in the docker files are they
installing any specific libraries that
might be outdated or you know they're
doing any specific practices and we're
going to talk about that so first thing
you should do is check the docker
related files
also look at the docker compose files as
well is there any specific version of
any libraries being installed are they
outdated are there any specific system
settings that are being applied that are
insecure are there any exposed services
with weak or even no authentication or
even hard-coded creds
the second thing you should do is just
go through the code like any normal
defender would do open the code in your
favorite code editor and just walk step
by step look at look at all the lines
try to find something that just looks
out of place
or the third option is well if you kind
of give up on the service or you just
don't want to bother going through you
know trying to go through the code wait
for another team to exploit it and then
just steal their exploit
three of the three of these are
perfectly valid strategies so
for our first thing first break for
today i know the break came in a little
bit early but we're going to give you
guys a hands-on activity i want you guys
to go take a look at the nasa rasa
service okay use the three steps that
were mentioned in the previous slide and
i'm gonna i'm gonna keep it like this
okay
and
go ahead take a look at the nasa asset
service i'll give you guys 15 to 20
minutes come back in 15 to 20 minutes
take a look and
try to see if you can find the most
obvious vulnerability now don't patch it
yet don't touch anything if you find out
that's great don't touch it because
we're going to need it in a second but
find out what it is all right and we'll
be back in
15 to 20 minutes all right i'll put a
timer for 20 minutes see you guys at 20.
hello and welcome welcome back everybody
i was literally eating a sandwich and i
saw that we had 30 seconds i had to eat
the sandwich faster than i've eaten
anything in my life
so
let's
come back to the come back to the
presentation come back to the zoom call
everybody so
what you guys think the vulnerability is
talk talk to me what do you think the
vulnerability is in nasa nasa most
obvious thing
nice that's correct the exposed mysql
database everybody has the same
credentials everybody has
access to the database why even bother
trying to hack the service you can just
log into the mysql database and grab the
flags and that's what we're going to be
talking about that is our first
vulnerability good job guys
so
by looking at the docker compose files
you found out that hey let's look at the
docker let's look at the docker composer
they are specifying a mysql user and
password directly in the docker compose
file
to
the um service
like
that means all the other teams have the
same username and password combo and all
the other teams
have the same docker compose file
meaning that we can just
so we can just log into other people's
databases and call it a day i will share
the powerpoint now so now that we've
talked about the first vulnerability and
things are going to be a little bit
chaotic now
but i can share with you guys
the day two here we go
that's day two training
so
now that you guys know this i i know
some of you are going to just go and run
to your databases or run to your command
lines and try and log into as many teams
as possible but i need to i need you to
stay with me
for just a second okay because we're
going to talk about exploit writing
all right so
now in the case of nasa rasa the flags
are stored in the message column in the
planets table and we can check that so
i'm going to go
mysql
i'm logging in as nasa
the password is and i'll just copy the
password from the
docker compose uh should have another
ssh terminal here
let me just let me just cat nasa
let's run mysql
do i even have the mysql client
please my skill no i don't so sudo apt
install
dash client
thanks hamid for the password
so now i have the mysql client
let's
yeah you sent the password here thank
you so mysql let's first connect to my
own database so nasarasa password like
this i'm connecting to the nasarasa
database
oh i forgot to include the most
important thing dash h host
127.2.0.1 i'm connected to myself and
i'm logged in there you go
i can say show tables
and i see that there's
planets so i can do select star from
planets
and there we go you see all these flags
right here
all these flags in the message column
all right you can see some people are
also trying to test on my service for
some sql injection all right
so
i see boon stars and other people left
messages here that's nice and
that's that's basically the flags
so you can do select
message from planets
oh who dropped my database
thank you guys
someone just logged in and just dropped
my database
i mean makes makes sense
so good thing that someone did that we
can talk about that so
uh let's say you find a vulnerability
like this like an exposed database okay
are you allowed this is going to be
important are you allowed to go in and
mess with other teams flags
the answer is no
all right because it's not fair because
right now i'm going to lose sla
why am i going to lose sla because my
flags are and my service is going to
show up as corrupt because i lost all my
flags right the serve the check system
is going to try to retrieve previous
flags but it can't do that anymore
because someone dropped my database
all right so
i'm going to start losing sla and that
and another thing we're going to talk
about
you can't
put in fake flags as well so let's say
you have a regex right here right
i can't just start copying this regex
and flooding people's databases with
flags you're not allowed to do that
and and this is funny and everything we
can laugh about it that's that's i
actually did not see this coming so good
job to ever drop my database but
one very important thing
if you do this in the competition it
might be fun for a couple of minutes but
then you'll get banned
all right because it's not fair
you can't drop flags and you can't add
flags either right it just confuses
other teams it causes them to lose sla
and it's not their fault and it's just
it's not okay all right
you can steal flags silently go ahead
live life
uh but you can't
start you know ruining their their
service on purpose
all right and be careful all traffic in
the competition is monitored
so if you start doing this and teams
start complaining that oh my database
keeps getting dropped every round what's
happening
very simply the game admins they'll go
to the game router they see all the
traffic and you'll be found out in a
couple of minutes and that's it you
don't want to be disqualified over over
something like this
and in attack and defense a very big
point so i know that was a little bit
serious just don't worry that that's
fine for now but
in
in in the actual game attacking defense
the goal is to be as stealthy as
possible you don't want to be found out
you want to be silent imagine how loud
it is to drop another team's database
imagine how loud it is to just
wipe their database or fill to flood
their database with flags right so
you're not allowed to do that okay in
any way shape or form even if you have
code execution all that stuff don't do
that all right
so moving on
uh
i'm gonna have to wait so whoever
whoever dropped my entire database i
have to rebuild my service now hoping
that
it comes back up
so build
all right
so
i'll wait for my database to come back
up and we'll give it a couple of seconds
so how do we patch this but moreover
instead of talking about patching let's
talk about exploiting right so we want
to automate this typing in mysql every
single time and like changing the ip
address so i want to log into a
different teams database 10.60.101
for example.3
i think 101 might not be up
or maybe they change the password maybe
maybe
any other team anyone 20.
no
51 okay 51.
no you guys you can't change the
password you need the password to be to
be unchanged so if i can't log in
because the password is different
there's no point
30 to
all right so i locked it to 45
immediately so as i was doing select
message from planets no why is it also
empty did someone
is it actually called message or
yeah it's called message
ah someone someone emptied everybody's
databases
someone just someone just destroyed
everyone's database
that is interesting i wonder if that's
automated that can't be automated
because my database was filled
a couple of seconds ago
come on i need to just find any team
whatsoever anybody you know what i'm
just gonna find a team
team seven all right thank you guys
all right let's see did someone really
just wipe out
everybody's database no
okay so you guys can check your own
databases if you got wiped out just
follow what i did which is the i rebuilt
the database
all right and hopefully they'll just
leave you alone for now so see the
reason why this is unfair you'll go
right now and you'll check the
scoreboard so right now you'll see that
most of our services see see everybody's
nasa nasa service corrupt corrupt
corrupt corrupt corrupt and you're
losing sla
and you're gonna lose sla for an entire
15 rounds
because remember we said that valid
flags
are 15 minutes long so this the check
system needs to find those flags so i'm
going to lose flags for the next 15
minutes i'm going to lose sla for the
next 15 minutes and that's not fair
so
when you guys find a vulnerability like
this like an exposed database like an
exposed
um
a nosql database or even an sql
injection
you know like an sql injection
vulnerability uh anything at all you
can't mess with existing flags right you
can't you're not allowed to just go in
and wipe the databases clean that's not
fair
okay so right now we're gonna talk a bit
about exploiting so don't patch it yet
it's a very simple patch but don't patch
it yet because i want to show you guys
the exploit how it works and how it's
like you know
how it actually works
uh
ahmed if you're here with us
can you please make sure that the
organization too
can you go into the vm and restart all
their services because i think if
everybody patches at least i can have
one person to hack
i think
organization two is me right
yeah yeah so i'm telling you
[Music]
fix all right
uh
let's get started all right okay okay
thank you so let's move on
we need to steal flags and we need to
submit them to the check system all
right and we're going to need that same
secret team token so you guys remember
that token that you guys used to log
into the cloud console you need that and
so this is this is the curl command so
how do you submit flex manually let's
just assume you want to submit a flag
manually
you have to send an http put request
to 10 10 10 10
flags
okay
with your team token in the header
and the flags in the form of an array in
the body what does that what does that
mean so let's come here so i'm going to
take this call command and i'm going to
put it here let's see what does that
mean
so you see this you see this command i
am adding a header here to the scroll
command called x theme token
okay
and in this i'm going to put my token
okay so i'm going to put my token in
front of you guys because i trust you
there's not really much you can do with
the token anyway
where is token
token okay
and
you see this array right here this is an
array of flags
right
so i'm going to come here and i'm going
to
remove this
and nope okay i accidentally submitted
it i didn't want to do that
okay
and i'm going to put here a real flag
instead okay so let me log in for
example to some random person's database
select message
from planets
okay let me grab one flag the latest
flag thank you
go back to my call command
and replace this
with the flag all right and it says here
flag accepted i got 37 points
37 flag points
and that's it that's how you submit
flags so if i go to the scoreboard now
i'm i am marked as org one
all right when the scoreboard updates
next round i will jump by a lot of
points because i just submitted a flag
we can even refresh right now just to
force it to update
all right so the check system needs to
catch up
but yeah that's how you submit flags
that's pretty much it you grab flags and
you send them with a curl request or an
http put request and that's it now i
know you guys are going to be busy right
now trying to steal everybody's flags
everybody's trying to steal everybody's
flags and submit them for some points
and you can you can go ahead but if you
stick with me if you stay with me for a
second i'll show you how you can get a
lot more points much faster so you don't
have to do it manually yourself even
with even faster than a python script
okay you can see right now that i jumped
to eighth place you know and it even
says i stole 38
38.26 flag points okay notice how my
service is still corrupt i'm still
losing sla
can you imagine so again deleting flags
and messing with flags is a very serious
thing don't do that right so let's move
on
so we just successfully submitted our
first flag we stole our first flag and
we submitted it that's great awesome
what now i want to automate this i want
to write this in a script so let's talk
about writing scripts obviously the best
language i can recommend is python
however
you are more than welcome to write
exploit scripts in any language you pick
hell if you want to write an exploit
script in assembly i mean you're going
to waste a lot of time but nobody's
stopping you you're more than welcome to
but you're just going to waste a lot of
time and python is great because it has
a lot of libraries for very quick you
know let's say you want to interface
with the data with the
database very easily you'll just google
database python library and that's
it you'll be good to go so i recommend
python python two or three that's pretty
much your choice i would recommend three
but python is the best language but if
you write ruby for example another
scripting language that's fine you want
to write go for concurrency you want to
write
javascript i don't know why you do that
any language up to you all right just
python is best you should always learn
python so let's talk about the format
how should you write exploits now i'm
specifying a specific format you're
pretty much free to pick whatever format
you want you can write your scripts in
whatever way you want but the reason why
i am telling you to use a specific
format is because we're going to later
import those scripts into something we
call an exploit farm and you'll see how
amazingly useful this exploit form is
you'll see how important it is
all right
so the exploit script
should take a single ip address as a
command line argument
and print every flag that it steals
separated by a new line all right and
it's recommended it's very recommended
to include some hard-coded timeouts in
your script so let's say timeout of 20
seconds 10 seconds because some teams
might slow down their service on purpose
so some teams might make it so that
their service responds in 40 seconds
you know they they throttle the internet
on their service
okay so that means your script will just
stay there waiting waiting forever
hoping to connect to the database and it
might take 40 seconds which is a lot of
time
reducing the chances that you exploit
another team all right so
let's let's move on so this is the
exploit script that i wrote
for nasa rasa's open database right and
i'm going to open it up for you guys
right now because i need to change
actually a couple of things about it
so
it was a
right let's open the exploit folder and
visual code my favorite code editor
so
nope not the service exploit we want the
database exploit so
you can realize here that this exploit
connects to exposed mysql and steals
flags okay
i import a pi mysql library and i import
sys and the reason why i am i import sys
is like i said the argument the ip
address is the first argument on the
command line so i take the argument
which is the host we're going to attack
and i save it i have hard-coded here the
username and password that we're going
to use
very simple script i just connect
with to the host with the username and
password
i'm connecting to the database the nasa
rasa database i have a connection
timeout of 10 seconds
and don't worry about cursor class this
is just straight up from the
documentation all right if any exception
happens incorrect password or timeout or
anything just exit the script i don't
want to waste time
okay and then i'm selecting message from
planets
where and then there's a field called
edit at
and this is just me checking that the
flag is one minute old and you know what
we can remove all of this
all of that you can remove all that give
me all the messages so give me
everything
all the flags and the planets table and
we're going to talk about why you might
be wondering right now oh what if the
flag is expired what if it's old what if
it's duplicate we're going to talk about
that all right
and all i do is i i execute this sql
statement
and for every single flag i print it on
a new line
and then i end it with this print
nothing flush equal true and this is
important it says i have a note here
that says important for destructive form
and that's the exploit form we're going
to be using okay it has in the
documentation that you should always
flush std out
at the end of your script okay and this
is just you know if just remember to put
these always at the end of your scripts
this print whatever
print nothing flush equal true okay
again you'll have the links to
destructive farm you can go read their
documentation and i'll show you how how
that works okay and this is the exploit
script right now i can i can genuinely
run this right now
i can take this
and i can say python
and
i want to run this db exploit on 10.60
let's run it on myself for example
it connects dumps all the flags on a new
line and leaves
okay i can point this at tm51
it's taking some time
and again it has 10 seconds so in those
10 seconds if it can't connect i tell it
to give up
and it gives up okay so something went
wrong uh but a different team at team 12
again log in dump their flags and that's
that okay so there we go we verified
that our exploit works and that it's not
going to waste time on on on databases
that might be patched or or there's
connection issues or it's dropped or all
that stuff all right
so now what now what we wrote our
exploit script again and we want to
automate this even further i want to
automate this python exploit such that
every 60 seconds
every round
it will run the exploits again
and grab all the flags automatically
read those flags and submit them and
only submit the non-duplicates okay only
submit non-duplicates and submit valid
flags so how can we automate that that
is where exploit farms come into play
that's where the most vital component
which is exploit farms comes into play
all right and you guys don't worry about
trying to screenshot this and copy it
down you guys will have all these
scripts at the end but if you want to
follow along you're more than welcome to
okay
so
using an exploit farm in an attack
defense what are they exploit farms are
tools that allow for the automatic
exploitation of discovered
vulnerabilities and the submission of
the stolen flags
this allows teams to easily grab flags
without having to worry about syncing
exploits with rounds running them
manually validating flags and all that
stuff the exploit farm that we are going
to be using in this training is
destructive farm now it's called
destructive farm and
one person told me this and i think it
was andrew i think it's it's it's called
destructive farm not because it destroys
but because the person who wrote it is
part of a team a ctf team called
destructive all right
and this is their documentation and it
comes in two pieces and we're going to
talk about exploit form right now you
guys are going to set it up with me
we're going to do it together we're
going to have it running all right
so setting up destructive farm server so
destructive farm comes in two pieces a
server and the client so i need you all
to pay attention with me all right
follow my commands first thing we're
going to do is we're going to grab this
i'm going to paste it in chat
we're going to install python 3.
so go into your vault images
and install python 3 right
give it a second while it runs
and i'm done
so i'm done and i'm done installing
python3 okay might take a couple more
seconds for you guys but that's fine
next thing we're going to do is we're
simply going to copy again this git
clone command and i'm going to paste it
in the chat
all right
and we're going to clone
destructive farm make sure you're in the
home directory okay you don't want to be
in slash home slash you know some one of
your services sub directories okay be in
your home directory and just
get clone destructive form okay
now
for we're going to cd into destructive
farm
server so we're going to the server
folder of destructive farm okay
and we're just going to install
the requirements so pip install
requirements.txt so we're installing all
the requirements
all right great so we installed all the
requirements right here installed all
the libraries that it that it needs
and how do we get it to run so one very
important thing is that we have to
configure a destructive farm we have to
tell it how to talk to the check system
and how often to talk to the track
system and how often
to and like how to recognize our
exploits
all right so
you're gonna find a fold a file
in this server folder called config.pipe
so open that up in nano or your other
favorite editor
and you're gonna notice that there's
already some things happening here
so let's start with the first line it
wants to know how it can attack
different teams what's the network and
nano has the formatting a little bit
wrong so nano is a little bit confused
about this and has this marked as a
comment but it's not a comment don't
worry about it we're going to come here
to this 10.0.0.0.
you see how it's it's looping it's
replacing the last number
with the team with the team name with
the team number that's not how it works
in our network our network is 10.60
and the variable that changes is
actually this number right here so we're
going to put the curly braces here
instead and we're going to change this
last number to three
so this is how we successfully loop
between
all the different teams all right and
you can even change the loop right here
so you see how it's only looping between
1 and 30. we don't want that we have
like 50 teams here so you can change
that
and make it for example let's go to the
scoreboard and see how many teams are
here although most of the teams are down
so i'm going to say you have about
well we can't really judge it like that
because all these teams are all over the
place
uh
let's just you know what for now let's
just keep it
60.
okay
you're looping on 60 teams you're
running the exploit on 60 teams okay
so let's save
we have 53 teams exact all right i'll
just keep the 53 teams here
thanks mohan
so
the flag format is essentially the flag
regex and this one
actually works this matches our regex we
have a number of characters either
letters or numbers 31 times and an equal
sign at the end so i know some of you
are going to be like oh but it could be
where's the backslash w it's supposed to
be a backslash wl if you guys know regex
backslash w essentially means a to zero
to nine
okay
so i'm just going to leave this without
saving all right and it's back all right
now this is where this section down here
is where we configure the protocol that
no no lower case
flags don't contain lowercase it's all
uppercase have you ever seen in any of
the flags lowercase no it's it's a to z
however backslash w in python does
contain lowercase letters yes that
that's correct but
the actual regex is actually all
uppercase
if you're feeling if you're feeling kind
of panicked you can just add a to z
lowercase here it's no worries
right
okay so moving on from the flag format
you can see here that there are some
presets
okay the presets for check system
configurations you can see this the one
that's uncommented right now is ru ctf
tcp all right and that's not what we're
using you actually want to come down
here to ru ctf http and that is the
check system that we're using
and
change this ip address change the system
url
to the check system so 10.10.10.10
and the system token well
you
need to drop in here
your secret team token all right
that's what it uses to authenticate to
the check system
all right and you can come down here and
let's look at other things here
so
the server will not
will submit not more than submit flag
limit every submit period seconds so
every five seconds it will not submit
more than 50 flags and that default is
perfectly fine
and we have to tell it here how long
does it can a flag go on until it's
considered expired
okay
and
we can say here it has it at five
minutes we're gonna just tell it the
actual expiration of a flag which is 15
minutes flags expire 15 minutes okay
now this is the password for the web
interface now it's important for you
guys to have this
uh to put this to a strong password
because your server is going to be
exposed to everybody on the game network
okay
i'm gonna leave it to one two three four
because we're all going to have the same
service running and there is nothing
greedy you can benefit so
go ahead if you want to log in i mean
you shouldn't you should kind of focus
on your own service but
what what can happen
all right
so
now we're done configuring config.pi
i'm going to close this
and
now that we've configured config.pi we
can come here
and run startserver.sh
all we're going to do is do start
server.sh like this
and it's running
okay of course you might want to put
this in a tmux session so let's do that
so i'm going to open a new tmux session
or tmux and i'm going to run
the
start server script there
if you guys are stuck inside tmux and
you don't know how to leave and you're
like what is happening you just do
control b and then d
for detach okay for those of you haven't
used i would highly recommend you get
used to tmux or screen both of them do
the same thing
because you want to be able to run
things in the background all right so
now we have
our server
running in the background and we can
access it on port
well i don't remember what port let's
let's find out i must have written it in
the slides
board 5000 yes so you can come here and
go 10
60.
100 in my case port 5000
all right so
huh what is the username
that is great i don't remember that
let's just come here down to the farm
server more details
credentials credentials credentials
oh you can use the password one two
three four and any login to enter any
login work so any username all right
so
10.60.100.3
port 5000 for i'll just use admin
and as long as the password is one two
three four and you're in
all right
so
you get this nice
you know interface and nothing's really
happening here okay nothing really
happened
there's nothing happening here this is
just where you would see where your
flags are being submitted all right we
have to add exploits how do we add
exploits to our amazing
nice
and interesting
exploit form well
we are gonna talk about that
so you guys are gonna have to and set up
the the destructive farm client on your
own machines of course you can run the
destructive farm client on the server as
well but for now we're gonna run it on
our own machines so
destructive client destructive farm
client this is where you will run your
exploits so you run your exploits on
your own machines and this is better
uh just so that you know you don't have
to worry about uploading your exploits
to the server and all that stuff
although obviously if you want your
exploits to be running overnight you
would upload it to the server okay but
in a real competition uh usually they
don't leave the game network open 24 7.
usually there's like oh well you're
going to play from
8 a.m to 9 p.m and then we're going to
close the network so
you don't have to worry about that but
anyway
for those of you using windows i
i'm sorry
you really shouldn't be using windows
for these kind of competitions anyway i
hope you have a linux terminal somewhere
wsl or a vm or absolutely anything at
all but if not i'll try my best to try
and accommodate you
and
teach you how this runs so essentially
because we're going to be downloading a
python script onto our machines and
running it so if you're on windows and
manually go to this link so i'm going to
copy this command right here
if you're on windows manually go to the
bitly link and just download that python
script and save it somewhere that you
can run all right if you're on linux run
the command as is so since i'm on mac
and that's pretty much
linux in disguise
i'm going to go to our nice
folder that we created
um
i try to be training and download the
script
right and i downloaded the start display
dot dot pi i'm gonna just make it chmod
plus
all right just so that it's it's
executable
and now we have to start
the exploit okay we can start sploit and
we're going to take a look at the
arguments
okay let's look at the arguments here
so what are these arguments
so you can see here that we're running
startsploit.5 okay that's our
destructive farm client
we're giving it as an argument
the exploit this is the exploit file so
this is the exploit we're going to run
in this case i called it exploit.pi but
i'm actually going to pass the full path
to my python exploit
server url is where the
where the destructive farm server is
okay so in my case it's dot 100 okay so
you got to point this towards your
destructive farm server
and
in my case
an alias is what you want to call this
exploit what is this exploit i'm running
right now so let's let's fill this out
what do i mean by this
so where is my exploit my exploit is in
workspace
ctf training
services nasarasa exploit db exploit.pi
that's the full path and the alias what
do i want to call this exploit i want to
call this nasa
rasa underscore mysql that is the name
of the exploit and i hit enter
okay so this the dash dash is weird
there we go
and it's connected and all of a sudden
you see you get this wild output and
what it's doing is that it's looping my
exploit script immediately across all
the teams immediately stealing all their
flags
and sending them
right now to my destructive farm client
so i refresh i see that all of a sudden
i got all this
i got all these flags stolen from so
many different teams some of them are
queued so you can see that destructive
farm is waiting for a couple of more
seconds before it sends more flags
and you go to the scoreboard you're
gonna see i should be flying higher
right now
let's go where is org one
orgs1 why didn't it update yet i'm
pretty sure i stole more than one flag
trust me i think we just have to wait
for the check system to kick in
come on check system
i stole more than one flag i promise
i will wait for it to wake up there we
go where did i go holy crap i jumped
four positions i immediately gained
7 000 points
from stealing 168
uh
168 flags hey ai that's all right i
shared the the slides earlier uh i think
i can copy the slides again for you
yes yes i can do that for you no worries
no worries my friend
here you go
i hope that works yeah so that's i'm
uploading the slides again
there you go
you can follow along catch up to us
no worries so as you can see right now i
am jumping on the scoreboard immediately
destructive farm is receiving all these
flags and i can go back to my terminal
and my exploits are just gonna keep
running
every 50 seconds
my exploits are gonna run just before
the new round or just near the end of
the of of the round and see now it's
launching attack number two
and i'm gonna
steal a bunch of and i'm gonna get a
bunch of flags all over again as it runs
my exploits all over again
okay
and that's that's the whole point that's
the beauty behind an x and exploit farm
all i got to do is just keep this
running i can forget about it i don't
have to worry about anything i don't
have to worry about no duplicate flags i
don't have to worry about expired flags
you know why because the exploit farm is
actually the one that submits the flags
to the check system so what's what's
going on here my client is running the
exploit
gathering all the flags and sending them
to
the
exploit farm the server right here the
server receives the flag
checks if it's already submitted this
flag before checks if this flag is valid
and then submits the flag
you see so you don't have to worry about
duplicate flags you don't have to worry
about anything the exploit farm takes
care of all of that for you it does all
that for you
all you got to do is just feed it flags
and it'll just keep
throwing and i can even see i can take a
look at the rejected flags right now
like i can filter show me all rejected
flags and i can see you know there are
some flags that are already submitted
some flags that are too old and so it
will remember it will remember that oh
these flags are too old if i get them
again i should never submit them again
and that's that again
i cannot emphasize how important it is
to have these exploit farms running if
you try to play an attack defense ctf
and you don't have an exploit farm
running you might as well just
manually keep running your exploits
every 60 seconds and
may
god have mercy on your soul
you know because it's going to take you
forever to try and catch up with these
teams who are also using exploit farms
all right
so i'm giving you guys all a second so
now let's talk about patching so quickly
people are stealing flags from each
other what can we do
well you can patch
how do we patch
well that's very simple so first before
we talk about patching let's talk about
effective exploits so when you build an
exploit you have to keep these questions
in mind can you ensure that your exploit
bypasses some simple fixes
so this this doesn't apply in this case
but what if there is some sql injection
bug and you wrote an exploit for it and
you notice that some teams
are simply filtering the word select or
union
from the payloads
you should make sure that your exploit
bypasses all these simple fixes
encode it and hex encode it in base 64
change spaces to comments all that good
stuff pretend like you're evading
a web application firewall make your
exploit as
complex as possible encode it many times
if you have to so that you can make sure
that the only way a team
can stop your exploit from running is
that if they actually actually fix the
core cause of the exploit okay
second very important
how can you ensure that your exploit
isn't wasting time on broken surfaces
what if a service is just dead it's not
responding you don't want your script to
stay there for 60 seconds hung up
hoping that that you know it's just
wasting your time or you could be
attacking other teams
and how can you optimize your exploit to
run as fast as possible time time time
is important
okay trust me you do not want an exploit
that takes five minutes to run you gotta
keep keep trying to squeeze every
millisecond
right you don't have to worry too much
because the flags again expire in 15
minutes you have 15 minutes to grab the
flag but you don't want to waste time
okay you don't want to waste time
all right let's come here so how can you
guys protect yourselves so a lot of you
guys are like oh my god my flags are
disappearing out of thin air what can i
do
all right very simple i'll tell you what
you can do let's talk about patching
so we can either prevent the database
from being exposed to all players
or we can change the password to the
database or both
all right
so the database doesn't need to be
exposed everybody knows the number one
rule of databases is you never expose
them to the internet let's change that
all right so let's go into our nasa rasa
service
let's look at the docker compose file
okay
you see this ports
this ports right here
what does this mean
this means that it's taking
port 3306 inside the container
okay
and it's forwarding it
to port 3306
on the host
but if you don't explicitly
specify what ip address to listen on it
will listen on zero zero zero zero which
is exposed so we can simply tell our
database hey why don't you listen
on localhost instead okay
still keep the same username and
password if you want to nobody will ever
be able to touch it anyway so why bother
just make it listen locally
all right and i gotta check if this
actually works
so let me make sure so i'm going to say
again build
force recreate
and dash d
mysql
okay it's not called mysql it's called
something else but here we go
and i do docker ps
and you see mysql
mysql it says here that port 3306 is
forwarded but locally if you guys try to
log in i want you guys to try and log in
now you guys know the mysql command
i'll send it over
see if you can
log into my database
okay so i'll give you team three like
this
there you go and run this
this is you attempting to connect to my
database right now
you can try
but you shouldn't be able to
it'll just tell you that you can't
connect the ip address the port is not
open
am i right so
tell me
can you guys connect or you can't
connect
tell me in the chat
you can't connect
and that's and that's and that's one
thing we just solved the database from
being exposed that's a simple line all i
did was change the docker composer and
you can see all i did was add this extra
line i made it explicitly listen on
localhost which means my service my
service can still access
so nasa so the php service can still
access my database
but they can't
other teams can't access my database so
now people are i'm essentially i patched
myself and i'm going to stop losing
flags
all right so i'm expecting all of you
are going to start doing that really
soon and it's going to be almost
impossible to
steal flags from other people
regarding this specific vulnerability
and that's that's more than fine that
that's how the game works
right
and let's say you want to change the
password let's say you want to change
the password right just for the sake of
security if you do change the password
you're going to have to remember you
have to change the password somewhere in
the code so if we look at the code
let's say let's go to
[Music]
inc
you see there's a db.php there's a
database.php right here
and so this database of php again the
credentials are in are in the code so
whatever password you change outside you
have to change the database
credentials right here
okay just to make sure that my service
is running fine that nasa rasa is not
complaining i'm gonna actually go to
nasa right here
and check that it can actually access my
mysql database and again i get no errors
everything's working just fine
right
and so that's that's one that's one
vulnerability we just patched right now
if you change the password or host the
database locally is that the legal way
to patch
yes
so
that you you you are allowed to patch
any way that you want okay that's that's
fine it's fine you joined a little bit
late you you are allowed to to patch it
like that change the password and host
it locally that's more than fine
again why are we changing it to locally
because the check system the check
system
never almost rarely cares about your
exposed database so you're going to
notice i'm not losing sla why am i not
losing sla because
well
because the jack system doesn't care
it's not about the database it's about
the service
okay now let's say let's say that for
some reason the check system is actually
checking whether your database is up for
some reason
okay in that case
don't make it listen locally just change
the password and you're that's more than
fine you're allowed to do that it's even
better to change the password and leave
the service open because that might
waste time in other teams trying to
connect to your server because they
actually have to connect and negotiate
and be like he's using my password oh
that's incorrect which is a few
milliseconds
a few milliseconds slower than getting
an error
that the port is just closed
yeah
so you got to think about it like that
will there be multiple vulnerabilities
like more than three on the application
well
that's pretty much up to the service
sometimes there are unintended
vulnerabilities sometimes you can patch
a vulnerability and introduce another
one sometimes you can
sometimes the database is exposed and
there's just one more vulnerability
apart from that it's really up to the
service it could be anything
you just have to keep looking keep
stealing exploits from other teams keep
an eye on what's being exploited keep an
eye on what's happening and
you'll you'll you'll be able to find out
so
moving on so we finally we finally
exploited our first service and we
finally patched our first service but
guess what
there's another vulnerability in
nasarasa we're not done yet we are more
than done i mean not more than done
we're not done yet
okay we have a long way to go
right there's an actual vulnerability in
nasarasa
and let's talk about that so looking
again
look again
again at the
dockercompose.yml and db.php
is there anything that catches your
attention
well let's go let's take a look
i want you guys to take a look and tell
me does anything catch your eye is there
any specific settings that are being
enforced
that usually don't that you usually
don't see when you're just trying to set
up a database
there's no wrong answers you guys can
keep asking that's fine
keep guessing
just tell me in the chat do you see
anything anything catches your eye
something that
that
okay root password so what are they
doing with the root password so the root
password they're just setting an
environment variable here random root
password they're sending it to yes
and if you go look at the documentation
for docker mysql
you'll see that this just randomizes the
root password every boot so that's fine
that's okay but good job you paid
attention to something all right what
else
are there any specific options
that they're setting any any specific
options that they're overriding
i'll give you a hint it's not in that
it's not in the nasa www at all it's
it's here it's right here
more importantly it's right
here
yes
so something in the command they're
enforcing a specific character set
okay i know you can't see the full
command but the the last part doesn't
really matter the the
skip character client handshake that
doesn't really matter it's this part
right here so they are setting a
specific character set
and you might not be familiar with this
that's fine you're like okay maybe this
is hard to catch how am i supposed to
understand that
how am i supposed to catch that but you
should always google everything and
you're about to learn about the very
interesting vulnerability that you can
have in mysql if you pick the wrong
characters at that
okay
so there is a vulnerability that exists
in mysql
well it's not exactly a vulnerability
it's kind of a logic bug and you have to
it's not available by default it's only
when you pick a specific character set
so you can change the character set
okay that the database is using
all right you want the database to use a
different character set and we are
enforcing a character set right now
called utf-8 mb4 unicode ci
all right and if we google if we google
this
so let's learn like
is there anything is there anything
happening here and you can read and you
can try to understand what's happening
okay
but for now let's look let's look for
the actual mysql reference okay from
let's try to control f and look for our
so we see right here
that
there is an attribute called pad space
and other versions other other character
sets don't have this pad space
attribute you can even try to set up
your own mysql database through docker
you'll realize that they don't set
pad space by default now what does pad
space mean well
its results can can can be very
catastrophic especially when trying to
do authentication
let me log into my own database
all right
so i can log in with my to my own
database
uh with the same credentials okay
because again i don't i didn't change
the credentials i only made it listen
locally
here i am
so in sql if you do select hello
okay equals
hello
what do you think the output of this is
this true or false in sql
it's true yeah hello is equal to hello
one you get a one hello is hello that's
correct now what about this
hello equal to hello space
in any other programming language hello
equals hello space would give you false
right because it's not the same however
because of the specific character set
that we're using and it has an attribute
called pad space when you run this you
get true
can you imagine what that leads to
imagine the following statement select
star from users
where
and then
username equals
admin space
you can now using this you can now log
in as other users because mysql thanks
to the pad space attribute it will
ignore you can add so many spaces here
you'll still get one
do these two strings look the same to
you they don't look remotely the same
hello equals and then hello in a million
spaces but because of pad space it
ignores
white space it ignores trailing white
space when doing comparisons
and that is the main vulnerability
inside of nasa rasa how does that
vulnerability work why is that a
vulnerability i can show you right now
let's go to my own service all right i'm
going to go to my own so this is my own
nasa asset service and i'm going to go
to the users
and i can see that the check system here
is
is has inserted let's go to this user
because we know this user was created by
the check system
this user signed up with this username
i'm going to take their username
okay
and i'm going to sign up i'm going to
make a new username same first name same
last name and the username i'm going to
add a space
at the end of the username i'm actually
going to add two spaces for goodmeasure
and the password is just the same
username and i'm going to sign up
when i click on my username
the database gets confused it thinks
that i
am the same username that the check
system placed in and i can see here
message visible only to you and i get
the flag
thanks to pad space and this this this
is this is vulnerability is known as pad
space collation
right i'll type in the chat add space
collision
all right because of the character set
that i'm using in mysql i can now bypass
authentication because i can simply sign
up with the username that has the same
username as the user that i want to log
in as and add so many spaces to the end
and then just log in
and when the database comes to show me
information it will get confused it will
think that i
am that original username with no spaces
and it's going to show me it's going to
give me access to their private the
private messages right here
and so that's why if you go right now to
users this is what these people are
exploiting they are creating random
usernames all right they are signing up
with the same they are signing up and
you'll notice look if i select this
oh well it won't show me but there's
actually a space okay there's actually a
space that is what the exploit is
taking the latest username
okay taking the latest username that the
check system placed in and we know it
comes in the form of like two names like
this
okay
and taking reading the username
going to going to the main page
creating a new user
while adding spaces at the end and
signing up and then you go to your own
page and you'll get the flag
that sounds a little bit complicated and
you're like wow i gotta run this every
second and we have a couple of issues
so many people are running the exploit
look the number of users is just it's
just a bunch of garbage right here
right how am i supposed to filter the
garbage from the actual from the actual
users and i'll tell you something even
sneakier i'll tell you something even
sneakier if we take a look at my exploit
okay
let's take a look at my exploit
this is my service exploit right here uh
i'm using a couple of important
libraries i'm using
beautiful soup which allows me to parse
html if you've ever done web development
beautiful beautiful soup is kind of like
jquery
right or
document dot you know get element by id
get element by that stuff lets you move
through html all right and i'm using the
requests library to make http requests
and this faker library we're going to
get to it so again this the script works
the same way
i got the host ip address
okay
host ip address right here
and i'm starting a request session so
any the reason why i do this is any any
cookies that i get or anything are saved
and i'm
going to the slash users page the first
thing that my code is doing is it goes
to the slash users page and it takes the
html and it feeds it into beautiful soup
and i look for the cla the div
a div with the class user how do how
does that look like well let's go to the
users page let's go to view
view source code i'm looking for a div
right here i can see this div right here
with class equal user
okay
that's exactly what i'm doing
div class user and i find all links i'm
trying to find all the different links
right here
so these guys slash users 1790 slash
users1789 slash users all that stuff i'm
trying to get all that
all right
now the next step
is that i go to that users page so my
script
starts going
to these links right here starts going
to them okay only the first one though
it only takes the top which is actually
a bad thing in my script i shouldn't
only take the top user because what if
the top user is something like in this
case it's not the check system the check
system didn't put this it's the this is
by another team trying to log into my
service right so i should actually try
to loop over all of the links that i get
okay but in any case let's just focus on
on this right now so
i try to get i look for a span with the
class label success
let's see how that looks like so let's
click on any of these guys let's click
on this guy
and that's a view source code let's look
for a span
right here i see here span
label with the class label success
okay
why do i look for this html element
because it contains the username look
they registered at time blah blah blah
as and then their username and that's
what i'm looking for so i'm extracting
their username you can see here that i
split by the space
okay i split by space
and
i get the last the last element in the
array so if i if you split this string
right here by space
and you do of element minus one you'll
get this one
so i always get the username
then
i initialize faker
why do i do this because look how i'm
signing up i'm signing up so i go to the
sign up and i send a post request i send
first name equal fake first name
and fake last name i am making my sign
ups look like as if they came from the
check system
okay
what does that mean let me show you
so i'm gonna do python okay
from
faker import faker i'm gonna do fake
equal faker like this and then look at
this fake.unique.firstname
it's giving me random fake
first names
and i can combine this plus space
plus
fake.unique
dot last name
and look it's fake full names
just like the check system
my exploit signs up rather than this
obvious
rather than this obvious chaos that's
happening right here if i go to my users
list
okay
rather than this very obvious chaos
that's happening right here i can
clearly tell something is happening
i'm being sneaky i'm trying to stay
under the radar i'm signing up with very
normal names
okay why would i
try to
scare the people who are running the
service by signing up with a name
that very obviously looks like someone
is logging into my service
get me
so that's the idea so i'm using this
faker library to sign up with fake first
names and last names
so that i'm stay under the radar and you
can see right here that i log in
with latest username plus space
i add a space and you can actually i can
multiply this space for example with a
random you know like a random a random
number each time just in case i want to
evade any detection in this case i'm
just going to multiply by four i'm just
gonna post four spaces all right and i
generate a random password again using
faker right here so fake dot unique
password length equal 30 special
characters equal false
okay
and
and that's pretty much it
i sign up
and
i log in with the new user okay i log in
and i immediately grab the flag
from a div i find a div called with a
class planet message
and i just grab the text
and that's pretty much it
now let's loop this let's loop this
because this might be this might be
wrong so far so
what i'm going to do is
time to do some some development live on
stream
okay so find all and i want to print
latest users href
comment out the rest so i want a loop
i want to loop over
all
the
the users that have signed up okay
domino services nasa rasa nope
exploit
service i call this exploit service
and i want to point it at myself
okay
none type object is not
callable what what is happening
why is this not working
okay it found one what if i want to find
all
hello
oh it's f find underscore all okay yeah
you got to be careful
and i get an array
what that that doesn't make sense
yes development i love development guys
don't you love development
why is it not giving me an array of all
the links
ah here we go
beautiful soup
get all links
oh it's find all right i tried find all
i swear if it gives me an error
i still got
that makes no sense
why why i'm pretty sure i have more than
one user
look at this i have like a billion users
why are you doing this to me
find all on the first
find but i don't want to find all divs
you get me
i i i don't want to find all divs
i want to there's just one div anyway
you get me
if i come here and i open the source the
source code
there's only one div on top here div
user oh there are many users oh i'm so
sorry
you are right you are right you are
right oh i am very stupid
thank you bless you
all right
so now we're gonna have to loop over all
these guys i see thank you so much for
making me pay attention to that so for
user
and latest
user href
i have to take user link for example
equal user dot find a
dot and then how did they do it here
dot get
href
you know and let's just try that user
link
you know there's a way of automating
this right because if you notice
something
there's kind of an eye door
vulnerability here right
you know how to go to every user and
there's just a number right here
i can literally just take this number
and loop like 20 numbers back
so there are so many different ways of
writing this exploit
i don't need to worry about you know i
don't even have to do the the whole
parsing this html i can just literally
just
come here and just you know start
messing with this number
but yeah
let's let's just continue what we're
doing though so let's let's run the
script one more time
wow and i get a link of all the users
uh on the on the board that's nice
so i'm just gonna come here and i'm
going to uncomment these guys and i am
going to grab
the code this code and i'm going to
paste it right here
got to be careful with python because
they loves it loves its indentation
so we are
going to
user link
and it grabs the username latest
username and we're going to print
latest
username
so this should get us a list of all
usernames
all right it didn't work all the time
and that's weird
why did it not work all the time
let's just print
this
that's odd it should have worked
why is it working sometimes and
sometimes not
i mean i i mean maybe it's filtering
duplicates
i can't
oh some names have extra spaces on the
back you're right wait that's actually
good
that is actually good that's actually
good we can that means we're ignoring
the usernames with extra spaces in the
back
isn't that isn't that good so i can come
here for example and say i'm going to
make an empty array here called
users
let's say check system
users and it's an empty array
and
if
latest username
all right does not equal just a space
right if it's not just a space then we
can add it to our array
of usernames to exploit so now now you
can print
check system users
and you'll have a
list of users that you know for sure
what happened here
if latest username is not
you know what okay
let's just say is i think there's dot
empty
how can you check if
we can just do dot strip
to be honest you know we can just you're
actually right you can actually write if
yeah yeah that's that's actually good
that's good oh you guys are python
experts right here everybody is i
thought i was good at python
there's a billion ways to write it
thankfully yeah i'm going to go with
that one so if lan
if length and while it's stripped is
still greater than zero then we append
yeah that's right let's do that
nice there we go we got two usernames
directly from the check system we know
that these usernames were generated by
the check system
and just for debugging i'm going to
print
just for just for debugging i'm going to
print this
okay
and there we go so these guys probably
have a bunch of spaces at the end yeah i
can i can well i don't think my terminal
is accurate
but yeah
there you go you grabbed users that are
only that were only placed by the check
system
again if you guys are like panicked and
you're like oh what if these were not
placed by the check system what if you
know what if you actually uh what if we
actually wanted to try and exploit them
that's very simple all you got to do is
just come here
and strip the text itself
okay
and i think so this is this will give us
a complete list of usernames even the
ones that might be fake and put by other
people okay that's fine
see but what we want to do is we want to
make sure they're unique so i'm going to
create a set over here a python set
and i'm going to say
check system
users dot
uh
how do you push
does it append
append into a set yeah i mean it's not
it's complaining
but you should be able to append into a
set
oh that's a dick oh my god sorry i'm
just gonna do set like this yes yes
there we go why why are you complaining
set
see it's not called it's not called that
i think it's uh
add add
in a set set its ad yes yes yes there
you go
thank you there we go we have a unique
set of usernames
all right so now now we increased maybe
the potential of our script finding more
even more vulnerabilities uh even more
sort of usernames to
to hijack okay so what are you gonna do
very simply
you we are still going to do this so
we're going to loop over
i'm going to uncomment all this
all right and i'm going to loop for user
again
in check system users all right so these
are the users we want to exploit
we are going to
sign up with that user so i'm going to
do user right here
and four spaces we are signing up with
four spaces for every single username
okay
and with a random password every time
and we're just we're signing up with
that user okay
if the signup doesn't work we leave
immediately okay then what happens next
is we log in with that user let's come
in here let's let's tabulate that we log
in with that user if the login doesn't
work
we exit the script immediately oh what
happened
all right
there we go
no please
okay
uh
and last but not least we are going to
uncomment this part and we're going to
get the planet posted by the user we're
going to try to find
the uh
so we're going to take this
i'm going to separate this on a
different line i'm going to put a try
catch okay
because what if if we're accidentally
logging
in i'm i'm so confused i'm trying to
write like three different languages at
the same time
okay
so if for any reason
there's an exception that happens for
example this user doesn't actually have
a flag
okay
then we will just continue otherwise we
can print it
okay so sometimes some users will will
be fake users put in by other people and
we don't want to worry about that right
so there we go
now we can try running our script
everything looks good everything feels
good
oh god
failed to parse whoa what is happening
here
i think we need to call it
something else other than user maybe
let's just call it uh
exp user just for the sake of
you know
and we had to change it right here as
well i think
ooh get the planet posted by the user
and we have to go
to there
oh that's going to be interesting how
can we do that
i need to somehow
get their profile number
how can we do that
how can we get the profile number
so there are so many ways to do it but
i mean you could do a
it could be a set
we can do a dictionary
so you could be pushing dictionaries but
i don't i don't think that would work
though
so let's say for example user
is this
and then we're pushing an id
and let's say
user
link
okay
so for axp user
don't worry about what i'm doing i'm
just mumbling to myself but i i know
what i'm doing
for those of you who are
fast enough to understand what i'm doing
that that's that's amazing news
id
i think that might work
unhashable type dict of course
of course i was doing this to myself
use a tuple yeah yeah yeah yeah so we'll
use another tuple like this it'll be
user link and latest username
so essentially what i'm trying to do is
i'm trying to save the usernames and
their link to their profile page at the
same time okay that's what i'm trying to
do
so that when i do the second loop of
only unique users
i
have access
to both the link
and the username
thanks for that so let's see what
happens now
there we go
and we're grabbing flags
that's great so we now have a working
exploit and that's amazing and you know
what i can immediately copy that same
start exploit command remember for the
for the check system sorry for the
exploit farm
i can just copy that same command again
let's let me copy it
where was it somewhere here
come on where are you start split that
bite there we go
okay
and i can actually just come straight up
here and i'm going to change these
dashes and so what is this exploit this
exploit is nasa rasa
um web okay
and my server is at that ip address and
it's called
server url and the exploit is located in
workspace
uh ctf training
services
nasarasa
what was it called service split
there you go
oh sorry i wasn't in my temporary i
wasn't in my
hitb
training and there we go a brand new
exploit just like that
and that's fine some people have their
services down so you're getting this
connection refused bug
and that's okay there we go i'm stealing
flags from other people
some teams have their services down so
i'm getting this these exceptions
that's pretty much that's fine
yes thank you andre so uh your exploits
can output so andre is making a very
good point that your exploits can
contain output other than flag you can
print other stuff that's fine because
the farm will actually use the regex
to only pull out
the flags from your output
okay
and so there you go now if i go to my my
exploit form
let's reset the zoom on this
you see that i now have two exploits i
have nasa rasa web running and stealing
flags and i have nasa rasa mysql running
and stealing flags and like again like i
said again the beauty of the check
system is that i don't have to worry
about any of that i just i wrote the
exploit and i launched it and i can
leave it going on exploiting the other
teams
okay
go back and look at the scoreboard
i have i've stolen 500
562 flags and i think i nobody nobody
stole
any more like no i think i'm still
losing flags thanks to the pad space
coalition so let's talk let's talk about
the pad space collation what is what is
the easiest way to fix this bug we still
have we need to fix this pad space bug
right how do you fix it well the best
way to fix it is just to come down to
this command part
and just
stop setting a specific
character set why are you trying to set
a specific character set
just use the default and the default one
in mysql doesn't have pad space
collision by the way
so just
turn it off
and there you go i'm going to rebuild my
database
so docker compose
up dash dash build
force recreate
d
it's rebuilding
and it's up
and i can even go like this let me again
connect to my database locally and let's
let's check can i do can i do that trick
so can i select
hello
equals hello space
i get zero you get
false
okay
you've successfully patched the path
space coalition although by the way
you might think that's it but
there's this there's another secret
somewhere in here all right if you look
at the db.php
you can see that
in all the in all when it creates tables
when it's creating tables
look it's forcing a specific collision
look here
it's forcing that collate it's it's
forcing that character set on the table
so you're not done yet you should
investigate the code so the final final
piece of the puzzle is to remove this
and keep it like this now i have to
rebuild my service as well so don't just
remove from the docker compose and think
that your life is okay you should
investigate all the code see if that
that word that that phrase you know
this ut
mb4 unicode ci see if it exists anywhere
in the code try to look around so now i
can fully 100 patch my surface
so
i bring it up it's rebuilding
it's going to take longer now because i
actually changed the code for nasa rasa
and i'll show you that my service runs
perfectly fine
yes ai you will have access to these uh
once the training is done yeah you guys
will be able to see all these
and there you go my service is running
let's just let me just make sure that my
services actually haven't destroyed my
service so let's go to nasa rasa and
there you go it's it's running perfectly
fine
service is up and running and i'm
patched and i'm gonna stop losing flags
while still grabbing flags thanks to the
thanks to the exploits that are
continuously running
from other teams
and that's
and that's and that's pretty much the
beauty of attack and defense you can
even see by the way see right here how
often attacks happen so you can see that
coffee pot there are 14 attacks per
round happening or 14 flags being stolen
per round
72 flags per round 50 to 66
this gives you an idea about what
services are most commonly being
exploited
all right
we can move on with the material now we
still got services to look at
so
i'm going to give you guys another
can you try running my exploit again
against my own service yes that is
actually a great idea since you want to
make sure that it's fixed now
please move away zoom
thing all right
here it is right ready to guess my own
service
nothing this is the this is the database
exploit right let's use the service
split right here
it's just probably waiting waiting
waiting it's going user by user user by
user trying to sign up and nothing
happened
there you go
i get no flags anymore for my own
service
that's proof that we patched it
when other teams try to you know mess
around and you have to keep exploring
maybe there's an extra bug i mean right
now we know that there is no i'm telling
you there's no extra bug
but you never know
right so there you go you're patched
and you're you've saved yourself from
your flags being stolen
so now we're gonna go on quite a bit of
a long break here we're going to go on a
30-minute break okay
just because i've been talking for a
while
and i want you guys to go ahead go look
at coffee bot all right
and try to figure out what the
vulnerability is so we're basically done
with with material
okay
but
i am going to
walk you through the vulnerability and
coffee pot as well okay
so i'm gonna put us again on a 30 minute
30 minute
break you guys can go ahead
and take a look at
coffee pot or if if you feel like you
know
you don't want to take a look just at
least go drink water freshen up and be
back here in 30 minutes alright we'll
see you guys on 30.
all right welcome back everybody from
our 30 minute break
so
tell me guys
what have you found so far what
vulnerability have you found in the
coffee pot service
nobody
anybody at all
command injection yes if there is a
command injection and that's fine and
that's fine antoine uh we'll we'll get
to it right now i'll explain it to you
so
there is actually command injection
in
coffee pot all right so let's take a
look at the code together and
i'll point it out for you alright
so let's go to my machine
let's go to
ctf training
and let's look at the service
all right
so coffee pot surface
and let's look at coffee coffeepot.cgi
okay
so
let's see here so it says here that the
coffee pot is implementing rfc2324
okay
what is rfce2324
if we go on google and you find out
this is the hypertext coffee bot control
protocol all right
it was an april fool's prank but it's an
actual rfc how to control coffee pots
using hd
http it's a protocol
used similar to http to talk to
coffee pots all right
and
we can see here
and and let's try to find out where the
bug is
right do you guys have an idea where
directly in the code the book is you
guys have a line for example
if anybody found it
line 81 where it is taking your input
and running echo next to it that may be
correct
so we can verify because i have the
write-up right here so we can actually
walk through the write-up
let's see here uh
can i get my hands
on the write-up
so it turns out it turns out that the
only bug
or the only known bug
is this line actually
echo edition count plus one
okay
well it's 87 on my annoying which is
this
this double
double brackets you see how all of them
are curly brace except this one is
double
double bracket double curved bracket so
that indicates
that indicates that that this is not
being filtered properly okay and so to
exploit the bugs the attacker could send
this value as an initial ingredient
count
okay
it clears out the file due to error one
plus one well
what happens is that you could you could
pass this as an ingredient count
you can cut all the pots grab grip the
flag
and store them in a pot that you control
pot one two three four
okay
and then
you have to add you have to ask the
surface to add one more ingredient and
then that command gets executed
okay
this is a very simple very simple
example of the exploit all right is that
you're you're trying to create
a
you're trying to add
an ingredient rum how much of that
ingredient are you adding well you're
adding this and you're injecting the
command cat pot slash grip flag and put
it in a pot that you control pot one two
three four
okay
then you're creating some random pot and
you're telling it to create that that
cough that coffee pot with that
ingredient and you can now go and grab
pot one two three four
okay you can now grab
the pot one two three four and take
the uh uh grab the flags from it okay
you guys sometimes you're just like what
is happening so let's just go to coffee
pot okay it's on port three two five
five right so 10.60.10.3.3255
okay
you can see that you can add
all right so let's choose a part let's
choose part 100 okay we're going to set
right and we should actually open open
the network here so we can see requests
that are being made so you you did set
okay
and
you can just look at the headers so
you use the prop find method okay
and
you just you just initiated part 100
you're like i'm going to create a part
called plot 100 and like okay
and now we're going to add
we're going to add
so 1 2 3 4 of rom and it's trying to
give us give us a sample a sample flag
a sample flag okay we're just going to
keep this as is
and then we're going to start
so you can see that we see brew
and then it does profile one more time
and and there you go okay so it's
brewing right now so pot 100 information
brewing
okay
any any other questions and we can stop
it
and it just says nope okay looks like we
can't look looks like we can't stop and
we can keep adding
adding ingredients right here
okay put using the put we're adding rum
and that's pretty much it
because i probably like what and and
what is happening right now
well
let's see what is inside so let's let's
try to do this so curl thank okay we're
going to do dash x prop find
okay
10.60.100.33255
pot
100.
this tells us it gives us the
information about this pot that's what
it does so we have one almond milk three
one whole milk three almonds four risky
six rum the flag temperature and the
state
so you can if you can do command
injection and you can create your own
pot you can change one of these to
contain just a list of flags and that's
exactly what we're trying to do
the amount that we're adding
we're injecting into the amount that
we're adding okay that's that's where
the command injection happens
here
it would be better if i had burp or
something
uh
let's try to find the put request
okay you see this accept additions
so we're trying to tell it to brew and
what are we brewing
we're brewing and then there's a header
called accept additions
okay
and it's putting whole milk one of old
milk almond 2 whisky 3 rum 4 all right
and so the x the vulnerability is this
count this number this number right here
as it tries to process it
okay it comes here and when it comes to
run it that actually creates a command
injection
that count that you send
i might not be making sense am i making
sense i don't know if i'm making sense
do you guys get me do you not get me
are you kind of confused are you like
show us the exploit and we'll understand
confused okay
all right okay i saw that coming um
okay so
uh
let's let's let's map it out in text
okay
what can we do so we can prop find
okay and a url pot
and some number here this
gives information
about
what okay
what else can we do
we can
looking at these requests right here
we can use the request brew
okay slash pot
xxx
starts
brewing the pot
okay
however when we brew pay attention to
brew when we brew there is a heading
called accept additions which lets us
specify the initial number
of
ingredients so this i'm going to tab
here and make accept addition
lets us specify the number
of each
ingredient
then finally
we have
the put method
put right here somewhere right here come
on
put we have put
slashpot xxx
allows us to add
ingredients
into already existing pots
what header does it take it takes an
addition header which
the type of vulnera the
type of ingredient
to increment it just increments it
okay so maybe let's just put some
separation here between these lines
there we go okay these are the three
things that you can do
okay
you you do http request prop find you
get information you can brew a pot and
it takes a header called accept
additions and you specify the number of
each ingredient
or you can and then you can while while
something is already brewing or before
it even brews you can put
and add ingredients into that existing
pot
okay and the addition
addition header let's specify the type
of ingredient
so for example for example
let's come here i'm going to set my pot
to 500
all right i'm gonna have zero of
everything and i'm gonna start brewing
okay
then i can i want to add let's say one
milk okay so let's look at the latest
request that's going to happen
click and i can come here to try to find
the put see what do i want to put i want
to put
whole milk
so that's the type of ingredient and it
will increment it in the code in the
code looking back at the code
okay
if you are trying to put
something okay and it's a pot that
exists
okay
then we read the pot
for every single line
okay we split this is splitting this is
splitting by the
the the column okay because look when
you when you looked at the output at
prop find let's let's open another
formula let's open another terminal
and let's make this big
curl prop find
10.60.100.33255
slash spot 500.
right it's splitting every line by that
that that colon right there okay
so the addition is what we're trying to
add okay
if addition
is not equal to what we're trying to add
so remember how how we send we send the
http edition
in the uh
in the header this one the addition
header
addition header so it's checking
we we sent for example in this case we
sent whole milk okay uh homework is
about example let's talk about ram we
sent to rom is this
ram no is this wrong no is this
rum no is this wrong yes
and then it executes so this is what
it's checking finally when we get to the
thing we do want to increment
it doesn't escape it properly as you can
see
this this is bad escaping
okay this allows us to run this actual
command in bash count the variable count
remember how look count is user input
it's reading our count command
count so when it comes to pass it to
this expression right here
this actually executes it as a bash
command
so that's why that's why the first thing
we have to do is specify
the
vulnerable count that's why the
vulnerability is in the count
and then when we try to add that
ingredient one more time our command is
executed
now are you getting closer
to understanding what's happening
yes
yes okay that's that's great so let me
let me show you this in practice let's
do it from the command line step by step
okay i want to
brew
i'm going to create a new part okay i'm
going to call this spot 1337 for example
okay
i want to brew a brand new pot
and
my headers
are going to be the ingredients so i'm
going to make
i just want to take a look at how the
ingredients look like
there's a brew okay accept additions
okay
so i'm going to come here
accept
additions
and i want to add for i'm going to use
the ram for example okay to exploit
all right so i'm gonna say rum
and then we're gonna copy the exploit
no don't launch this code that's not
what i wanted to do i want it to go grab
the exploit
this right here you see this
instead so usually what we put here is a
number you put a number here
but this time we're not putting a number
we're putting some sort of command bash
injection
okay and what does this do this will
cat parts
and grip the one pots that contain a
flag and it's going to put them in pot
one two three four
okay let's actually change this and make
this one three three seven zero okay so
a part with just one three three seven
and zero at the end
okay
no please
just let me run this in peace okay
that's what this is going to let us do
all right and i actually actually almost
injected myself because i was doing it
in double quotations and my my shell was
was trying to classify that okay here we
go
so now we created a pot
pot 1337 oh my god it exists okay
i'm gonna create pot one three three
seven one
okay
now
usually you would put a number here
okay but now we put this weird injection
thing all right this this bash injection
now when we tell
coffee when we tell coffee pot we want
to put
we want to put we want to increment that
ingredient okay in this case we're
incrementing in gree in the pot
what are we incrementing we are
incrementing and then we have to come
here and see
what header does it take
where is put
come on show me i put
oh there we go there's a put here no
but
it's called addition the addition header
okay
what
what ingredient
are you trying to to increment we want
to increment from
and so it's going to go to rom it's
going to read this
as a number and it's going to attempt to
increment it which is actually going to
end up executing our command
so let's run
it's kind of frozen for a second there
that's that's not
good i think i might have
messed up something but here we go we'll
wait for it to come back
do you think so you think data it's
waiting for data
you can make it verbose so
let's make it verbose
added thank you thank you so
much and there you go now if we go if we
go prop find
that new part we created
okay 13370
we get a list of flags it read all the
parts and it dumped all their flags
we did it command injection there you go
and so you can you can very easily very
easily write this into a python script
and you're going to do the same exact
thing again we can even run there's
already a python script for this so i'm
going to run
i'm going to run it i'm going to show
you
workspace ctf training services coffee
pot exploit
coffee pot exploit okay i'm gonna
exploit myself
and there you go
and i can immediately immediately take
this exploit right here and do the same
thing i did with everything else so i'm
going to cd into my hack in the box
directory and i'm going to do start
split and i'm going to take this okay
and
server
what was it was it actually server
address let me just pause this what was
it
server url and alias okay so i'm going
to go
server url
http 10.60 100.3
on port 5000 that's where
destructive farm is running
and alias
this is
coffee pot
and so it's already complaining because
it's like please use a shebang at the
top of your script so let's take that
and please print the new line and call
flush
okay
so
let's edit our exploit very quickly to
do that
so at the top here you're going to put
the shebang
and at the bottom
you're going to print
you're going to flush
equal true
there you go
okay
let's just make sure that got put yeah
all right there you go
now we can try
and there you go that is a lot of flags
oh dear god
and there you go again go to your
destructive form refresh now you're now
i'm stealing flags from coffee pot
i'm stealing a hell lot of flags from
coffee pot
that is oh my god that's like eight
ten pages of coffee pot flax
what happened
oh wow okay
that is that is that is uh that is
impressive of course most of them are
old flags as you can see you know
but that's fine
all right so we'll come here and
you'll see that i am now capturing
coffee pot flags
so i'm still constantly exploiting
again nasaras of nasarasa flags both
from the database and from the service
and i am exploiting i am now exploiting
coffee pot flags now you might be
wondering
how can i fix this well
no no they did fix it look
uh red rocket they only lost 33 35 flags
this team only lost no flags they
patched it immediately and the other
teams are losing much less flags
okay so very quickly i can just come
here and i think the way to fix this is
just to
make this
double brace like this if i understood
if i remember bash correctly
is my bash knowledge correct
i think that's the way to fix it
just make it the same as everything
well i'll leave that up to you guys to
to double check
you guys can see why this is a a bug in
google how to make it uh
uh
how to make it patch but i'm i'm
assuming it's the curly brace again my
bash experience is not it's not amazing
but yeah
and that's coffee pot for you so again i
i know i know this might be a little bit
scary you're like okay one second we
were dealing with openmysql databases
and
you were we were we were dealing with
mysql databases and just very simple
obvious things now all of a sudden this
is very scary i don't know what's
happening how was i supposed to find
that how was i supposed to understand
that but most of you had the correct
idea most of you knew it was rce you
just had to find the proper place where
it is and remember
this is a very obvious exploit in your
pickup logs you will see this exploit
and you can very easily see like okay
i might not understand what's happening
but i know they're sending requests that
look like this
okay and they're sending a request right
after it to add that ingredient that
they just poisoned
so i'm going to just copy the same thing
all right so you might you don't need to
always constantly understand what the
bug is
there's always the defensive side you
can run so most of you right now i'm
running these exploit scripts right now
most of you right now can just go
and have uh
you you can't uh
current
current running okay
and you're gonna catch these exploits
from me from the other teams you can
even take a look at how the other teams
are exploiting it
all right
try to do simple fixes try to do some
regex like twy said he's fixed it with a
regex filter maybe there's a way to
bypass that regex filter maybe there's
maybe you know regex is not the way to
go
so there's always there's always a way
you know there's always things to do
okay
okay let's let's come to the slides i
think that's pretty much it so we're
going to email you or drop in the
discord please join the discord again
we're gonna we're gonna email you or
drop in the discord a link to all the
services and the write-ups soon
right after this training okay please do
join the discord because the discord is
where you will be able to ask questions
when this training is over like how how
much longer the network will be up how
much time you guys have before we take
down the network and all that stuff
feel free to use that though that link
to all the write-ups as a guide to help
you find exploits and other services
that you might get stuck in however i
would tell you there are two services
that we still didn't touch right now
health monitor and free life go take a
look at them try to find the exploits in
them steal the exploits from the other
teams all the exploits are running right
now so you should very easily be able to
steal experts from other teams
and you are encouraged to do the to do
it yourself
write the exploits yourself launch them
on destructive farm and just see the
flags pouring
all right the network uh as far as i
remember will be up maybe for one more
day maybe two more days again so get to
work on this as fast as you can do you
know that this stream and the previous
stream will be up on youtube you guys
can re-watch this as many times as you
want i i'm gonna upload the
powerpoint onto discord so everybody can
download it off discord in case you
missed it
and feel free feel free to ask questions
on the discord if you guys run into any
tools you want to use if you guys run
into any any other
uh you know questions you have about
ways that you can block services or
defend or stuff like that go ahead and
remember there are so many services out
there that you can practice on you don't
need to stick to these five you guys can
go to the ru ctfe on github
so let's just go
and you can go to the hacker dom profile
and you can see that for they have a lot
of ctfs that you can just go
and see every ctf has
um so let's go for example
ctf cup they have services
they have three services and you guys
can deploy them again it's just docker
they're all docker containers in the end
so go ahead run the docker containers
and
look at the write-ups look at the
exploits and everything and try to try
to solve them yourself look at the code
you have an endless endless repository
endless account of of endless
repositories filled with different ctfs
filled with different
services that you can keep endlessly
practicing on okay you don't have to be
stuck to these four c these four of
course you won't have the entire system
that's true
so you won't have a bond image and you
won't have all that but still you can
practice on on what's important which is
finding vulnerabilities
all right
any other questions guys
i'm gonna move my exploits very soon to
my server so they're running
uh all the time okay so even if these
other teams stop exploiting you guys
don't worry i'm gonna keep running
my exploits for coffee pot and nasa nasa
all right
but uh if you guys have any other
questions i'm uh i'm right here you can
ask them before the
before we call it a day
any questions right now
hey no worries i'm glad
okay i'm gonna assume that uh
uh i'm either
i'm either very good at explaining
or you guys just don't have questions uh
right now
thank you guys so much for the for the
kind i i enjoyed getting this session
with you me and ahmed so thank you so
much for being here we can't wait to see
you guys at the pre-qualifications and
hopefully in the next final round
uh hopefully so work hard go on the
discord ask questions we hope to see you
there
and thank you guys so much for attending
this session see you next time
you