hello everyone my name is jeremy brown
and this is my presentation summer fuzz
fuzzing mac os
quick run through the agenda um
do a quick intro
uh walk through some of the different
debugging tools
talk about sip and app sandbox how that
affects fuzzing
talk about crash reporting
what to do
for machine sleeps and ssh types issues
how to monitor process process execution
enumerate handlers different file
handlers and things like that on the
system for attack surface
and look at uh some of the clients and
network services enumeration as well
and then we'll get into the fuzzing so
fuzzing
command line apps fuzzing gui apps
uh fuzzing network clients the servers
and some of the bugs from that and then
wrap up with a conclusion
so who am i
mostly interested in bug hunting fuzzing
offensive security stuff
you know worked at a few different
companies before doing that
really like breaking stuff these days
different native code web services cloud
containers type
attacks
and yeah getting in good shape before
release has been a lot of what i've been
doing
so before uh getting into mac fuzzing i
didn't know much about mac security um
max for
you know i didn't use one on a
day-to-day basis for a long time until
recently maybe the last year or so and i
didn't know much about how to do
debugging and things like that so a lot
of this stuff was new to me so i was
sort of learning as i was uh you know
getting more information about it
uh but i've been fuzzing for a while now
um
and there's a lot of events these days
with afl plus plus and you know really
doing state-of-the-art fuzzing build up
on afl
but i want to look at it at a different
angle
honestly i just forgot a lot of what i
knew and what was conventional wisdom
and things like that and i wanted to
build something
from scratch that really served a
purpose for what i was looking for
so that's what i'll be talking about
today just the various tricks and and uh
going over some of the tooling for
fuzzing uh userland specifically on mac
so um
mostly looking at the core like the
default
applications on os x and os x 11 which
are pretty similar
you can look at the client and gui apps
uh network apps things like that
essentially what once you take away from
this presentation is how to set up
debugging how to numerate targets how to
make
volume research easier
this is not about you know scaling
fuzzing for a huge fuzzing farm
and a lot of stuff you can do with just
a mac at home
a lot of the prior work uh that is is
related or relevant is some of ben nagy
stuff it's pretty great
uh crash wrangler um
and then uh the temp tempo sh uh
zine which was a little bit of
inspiration to get back and fuzzing
so for debugging
xcode and xcode tools
you can there's a head script that i've
referenced down there to install that um
and you can enable developer mode
as well to make sure that you can
perform various uh debugging operations
as far as debugging goes guard malloc is
something good to turn on when you're
fuzzing essentially you can get free
bugs
from um you know inserting this uh malik
helper library that
can can help
find more of this subtle bugs when
fuzzing they maybe you wouldn't find
without the extra helper
uh stuff in it so you can read more
about how it works um but it's
i mean there's different uh things in
different platforms um as far as
uh malik helpers go and heap debugging
goes but garden malloc is something good
to turn on when you're when you're
fuzzing and this this is uh you can do
with dyld interlibraries
variable
for lldb
you can automate a lot of the crash
triage and bucketing stuff um just by
passing command line args
it's really flexible for a lot of
different things
um
and yeah this is how you can get
when you're
fuzzing and you want to get
automatic you want to produce logs of
you know doing triage and things like
that you can easily do that with lodb
sip is a very important one to
to know about when doing research
for you know fuzzing and debugging and
stuff like that a lot of times you
either want to turn it off completely or
disable it
disable
certain parts of it
because otherwise
you're not going to get too far
running the debugger headless for
example
on a physical machine
you can just reboot into a recovery mode
use csr util
to to disable it completely or just turn
on debug stuff
if you're using vmware fusion which i
recommend for a lot of research because
of course you know
vms are great for snapshotting and uh
you know
taking snapshots of different states and
replaying things
um you can do that it's a little
different between os x and os 10.
sorry os 11. so this is os x 10 and then
os x 11 there's a little more trickery
involved
but you can still get it done
that sandbox is another thing to
consider when fuzzing
again you can read more about it it's
not talk about the sandbox itself
but it does get in the way sometimes and
um
you need to
be aware of certain things uh to you
know where to put files and things like
that to to make sure the sandbox doesn't
prevent you from you know getting
coverage on targets
for example say mutated files and put
them in temp and then you you know your
target takes files as a command line to
to open you know whatever it is pdfs or
or or things like that
so if you try to do that with certain
targets um
you it you know it just it won't work
it'll say oh you know you're not allowed
to open it or don't have permission or
things like that if you check the logs
you can see the sandbox is kicking in
and it doesn't like uh where the file's
coming from
so uh you need to find another place to
put test cases uh for if you have some
if you run into some of those
restrictions
there's different container app bundle
uh directories for a lot of different
apps on mac and you can browse that
directory and see the different ones for
example for the books app
you have a com.apple.ibooks x and the
data directory which also has a temp
directory inside of that
of course you can still double click in
an epub from from wherever and open it
in ibooks um but if you're gonna be
fuzzing from command line uh you just
need to be aware of where to put it uh
so the sandbox doesn't block it
for crash reporting um most of the time
i would say it's okay to disable report
crash
um just because it's it's um may get in
the way of your triage program and uh i
mean what it does every it
when whenever there's a crash that
happens it creates a crash log and
triggers a bunch of other stuff um
but uh there's actually some ways to use
it to your advantage because for certain
targets
uh maybe you're fusing something
remotely and you don't have a good way
to check for crashes
and you're not running in a debugger or
something
if you can run it in a debugger and
attach to it of course
you can create your own crash reports
but if you can't
you can actually leave uh crap report
crash on and then you can just monitor
the diagnostic diagnostic logs directory
uh and just you know parse those for
crashes and stuff like that so comes in
pretty handy either way
sleep uh that's another problem i ran
into especially you know fuzzing on
commodity hardware
if you're fuzzing on a macbook macbook
air and stuff like that um
they are set up to be super eco-friendly
so that becomes a problem when
you got remote
fusing sessions running but they're like
hey let's go to sleep because
that's going to save you know energy and
hardware cycles and things like that
so you need to disable a lot of
different sleep modes
to make sure they don't get interrupted
there's different programs that can help
you with that
i learned a lot about system
administration with max just trying to
figure out is there a way to make sure
this thing never goes to sleep and
different systems are
easier to work with than others
but especially if you're using ssh and
you're doing remote sessions
which you know makes a lot of sense in a
lot of ways you can you know those guise
over ssh because they just pop up on the
desktop and uh things like that the way
mac is uh designed
um you can also try uh
uh sending you know some of the things
built into fuzzers uh you could do is
like you know just basically
send control sequences to make sure that
the session always thinks you're alive
and
it doesn't have any reason to want to go
to sleep
this is a battle i'm i'm pretty tired of
fighting
um
and uh but you can do that and you can
also uh mess with the ssh deconfig
i tried a whole bunch of different uh
configs just to try to figure this out
and this is the one i came across that
was been fairly successful so far so you
can use that tcp keep live
for monitoring process execution
if you you know once you disable sip and
you have debug
capabilities and privileges
you can use a handy dtrace
script that's included on mac called
newproc.d
uh if you run that it seems to be like
this
this secret or something that this this
exists um it's really great for looking
at what commands are being executed on
the system um you know it's especially
useful if you're if you're
looking at a back-end system like a web
app that has a front end and it's doing
admin tasks you know there's
ways to find command execution
to get visibility to find command
execution bugs like that
but uh for us it's just interesting to
see how things are being launched and
what commands are being executed when we
maybe flip on certain stuff
we're running different apps on the
system
so if you run a command and you grep
stuff you care about or stuff you don't
care about you can see what's going on
as far as command execution goes on the
system
looking at the different handlers on the
system there's a pretty cool
app called
swift default apps
there's a script swda that you can run
to get the schemes and that will give
you
the different uri handlers
on the system
so you can see there's quite a bit
when i ran this
on a test box
and it maps you know each one you can
sort of get an idea of the tack surface
as far as uri handlers go and
and you know what the
what is what you can execute on a system
like that
as far as file handler goes you can also
get the utis
and you can map those to the different
apps so you can see okay you know as far
as file formats go what is the attack
surface we can get a pretty good picture
of that
quite a few of those 420 different
formats again as
yeah it is the
multimedia
world for sure
it doesn't necessarily tell you the file
extensions though for example with
applescript
you can see it's com.com apple
applescript script
but then if you do some more research
you can figure out that this actually
dot uh
scpt file
and and things like that so some of
those you have to dig a little deeper
into
another way to look is just asking
questions like what file types are
included on the file system like what
what different files are they already
exist if they if those type of files
exist by default then there's probably a
program that can read them in some way
um
and then you can just uh if you see
stuff you don't uh you don't know what
it is the different file extensions you
can google for it and
i can give you clues to what apps may be
handling it
and did you know there's a notepad
equivalent
program on mac that parses doc and rtf
files
so another interesting thing about
looking at tack surface
you would think text edit
just opens
txt files which usually don't have a lot
of attack service because
they're parsing text
but actually it also it opens doc and
rtf files which are more complex formats
and definitely increase attack service
another thing that's interesting i came
across is some files are actually
directories so
i was looking at the different file
handlers on mac and
i was looking to see okay you know for
example for a calendar app there's a
backup file test dot icpu icpu format
if you
double click it it opens like a file it
opens the calendar app it you know
everything works fine
but if you look at it on the command
line it's actually directory and that
makes fuzzing more difficult because if
you go into it thinking okay
everything i'm mutating as a file you
know you can do you know file
manipulation is pretty straightforward
but if you give it an input that is a
directory
that is being used as a file uh that
gets a little more complicated so you're
not you're not just mutating a file
you're opening directory and then you've
got to figure out what the right files
to modify are that are being parsed
because there's a whole bunch different
you know the directory structure is
uh contains a lot of different files
some of which may be important some of
which may not so
other thing to consider when looking at
fuzzing on different targets
and the numeric network processes
there's again d trace it's pretty
awesome comes in handy here
we can
use different
features of it to look at um
what processes are
calling receive which means you know
they're they're taking data off the
network essentially
so we can um you know look at a receive
log let that run for a while and then we
can see what processes are actually you
know
parsing data and that gives you an idea
of the attack surface
as well
as far as on the network side
uh and then you can just you know run a
good old netstat um so if you just grab
for a listen you can see a whole bunch
of stuff running on different ports
and you can run lsof which is pretty
nice as well that can give you more
process information and more protocol
information
about what's running
so
you know you can see different stuff
running here
cup statement
screen share launch d has some different
listening services
uh kdc all that stuff
so as far as fuzzing goes um
you know afl
it's uh if you try to run it on mac um
it's not going to work very well
this you know a lot of the new
developments on afl plus plus and they
figured some of these but different bugs
out
and added a ton more features can't say
enough good things about that project
they're really you know continuing to
push state-of-the-art for fuzzing and
standardization um on that
so um that's great but what about gui
apps you know that can handle command
line stuff but
you know if you try to run if you try to
fuse fontbook for example with different
fonts
um
it's not really meant for that it's not
designed it's designed for you know
things that exit
exit quickly
by default
not so much for gooeys which can stay
open as long as you you know don't click
x right
and then network housing uh windows
stuff
there are different projects to try to
you know handle that corner of fuzzing
as well
but they have their limitations too
so uh lifos this is a project um
i've been working on that just works
that's the key thing i wanted something
that would just i don't have to install
different
you know um i don't have to install
different tools and different fuzzers to
2000 different platforms
um i want to keep the same libraries i
just want to have something that i can
you know run a setup script or whatever
and it just works on linux mac and
windows
uh so that's why i created
that supports file network fuzzing um
you know clients and guise even has some
features to do network uh interactive
network apps like postman and filezilla
and stuff like that
it has automatic crash triage and
diffing so
once you
once it comes across it once it detects
the crash
it will you know do it do a rented debug
session it will do diffing for the uh
input file to show you exactly what
changed
uh and a whole bunch of other uh
artifacts
so it's most useful
for closing
fuzzing closed source applications
for example if you wanted to fuzz a
cli
that's open source i mean of course
you're going to get
uh you'll be able to get coverage data
and instrumentation if you just use you
know fl plus plus the instrument
instrument and things like that if
that's possible if you don't run into
you know issues for that
so this is more for you know it's kind
of perfect for fuzzing mac because um
you know most stuff in mac is close
source right
it's really built for bug hunters
it's not
it's not yeah i'll go over some of the
trade-offs as well but
it does some pretty neat things uh in
orthodox fashions
but it breaks a lot of the rules of
modern fussing uh it doesn't do
instrumentation that was not a goal of
the project
again afl plus plus is great of that
other frameworks are too
it's not meant for speed
you know again instrumentation is going
to give you a lot of the speed and
different kernel tricks as well
or os tricks the afl employs
not meant for that
it is meant to
cover a ton of different domains and
work across platform
it doesn't have you know automatic i
mean not natively uh devops integration
where you can automatically file bugs
and and run in you know every time
there's a build and things like that it
can certainly be things can certainly be
built around that
but most importantly it was built to
find bugs
and that's exactly what it does
um yeah how do you know if fuzzer is
doing a good job
does it find bugs or not that's that's
what we're going with today
so fuzzing some of the mac intricacies
uh
you know we talked about before the
sandbox stuff
some gui apps you know uh they like
unique file names um that's another
thing i ran into which was if you try to
reuse you know temp slash
you know fuzz dot temp slash fuzz for
example
um
not all apps like that they they may you
know bail if they if they don't if they
literally don't see the right extension
or you know they've seen this file name
again so they tried to cache it or try
to refer to it back in some way
again reading within the sandbox we
talked about that
and some of them are just hard to find
directly
there's you know xpc proxy proxy and xpc
type stuff that comes into play and some
things just um
i feel like there's at apple there was
um you know this traditional and this uh
new
app
uh process that probably came out a
while back i'm if i'm just speculating
that a lot of apps got converted to yeah
we're just not gonna let anyone pass
commands uh files has commands to them
to fuzz
um so
i'm just dubbing that like the classic
way because there's still a ton of apps
that work that way but some apps do not
so um yeah future research is to look
into some of the ipc uh stuff that
happens with with certain applications
because that could be interesting too
so
for targeting applications
yeah you basically pick a
cli pick a gui
collect the test files
if the target doesn't exit on on its own
uh measure reasonable timeout like we
said um command line apps versus gui
apps that's the biggest difference
you know a lot of
command line apps will exit after they
try to parse the file or do whatever
operation
guise often times do not
so measure timeout and then you can
start fuzzing
so here's an example a command line
fusing light fuzz
where you're doing local fuzzing or
passing the command which is the app and
then the fuzz placeholder which just
means
put our fuzz file here replace the word
fuzz with our first file internally for
the for the fuzzer when every every
iteration
and your input directory is a files and
epub
which is just our input files or epub
input files for the in this case
you can select an output directory
we're gonna be using a special temp
directory uh instead of using
the um you know slash temp uh slash life
fuzz slash you know it's its own um
directory uh for each uh session uh you
wanna specify a special one to make sure
that um the application actually opens
their file properly and doesn't complain
uh max running timeout again 10 is is
pretty high
but that's
uh you know on on my test system that's
how long it took for the books app to
open this file so if you have faster
systems and things like that that's
going to be different but
uh just giving example it you know
things not meant for speed
it is you're literally executing
iterations uh one by one
then the number of iterations you can
put any number you want there just use a
hundred thousand for
a reference and we'll talk about easy uh
in a moment
and then with fontbook uh pretty similar
um
yeah so easy essentially the dash e
command is just a feature of light fuzz
that says recycle any of the crashes
that you found
make those as inputs
once you're finished with the
iterations
that we're running so in this example
after 500 000 iterations
it would say okay did i find any crashes
if so
copy those crashes to a new input
directory
use that input directory for a new
fuzzing session for 500 000 iterations
so
that way it's possible to find even new
bugs because you're basically you're
recycling crashes to
you know still mutate and you know you
could you could find potentially new
bugs using that because of you know how
crashes work and and memory corruption
and
mutating files that are different can
trigger you know different kinds of
crashes different places in the app so
it's a neat little feature that's in the
fuzzer
and then fuzzing package util um it's
you know a cli so you don't need a
max timeout for it it just
you know stops on its own after it exits
on its own
um
and
you know with console apps and stuff
like that you can also use fl fl plus
plus and non-instrumented mode on it too
so the the you know the primary purpose
of life fuzz is to handle situations
that you know afl can't handle or
you know well i guess making afl work on
all platforms it's pretty pretty good
feature too
as far as you know purpose goes
um but you could also you know fuzz
command line stuff on mac with in
non-instrumented mode with afl as well
so fyi but this is just an example to
show you that live photos can do it too
and uh you can also look at the output
so there's like a global output when
fuzzing that
is written just so you can monitor the
app just make sure it's working
correctly make sure you've got command
line args good
you can see with this one we were filing
package util um it looks like it was
fuzzing xml and it mutated xml and
um
package util is complaining
you can see that it is
being fussed
minimizing crashes is a is another
interesting feature um so it's super
simple the way it works
um it literally just uh when you want to
minimize a crash it just removes one
bite at a time and runs the target with
a new repro if the target crashes
the new repro
the new minimized
test case
if it crashes
then
continue removing the bytes so remove
that by and then go into the next one if
it doesn't crash
restore that byte and or you know don't
don't remove that byte because
apparently it's important because the
target didn't crash once we removed it
the point of minimization is to get the
smallest possible crashing test case
um simple by byte minimization uh just
goes one at a time
and um
and then for uh
superman mode uh which i've dubbed
it does that but it repeats the process
until all the bytes are exhausted
rather than a single pass
it will go from the top bytes to the
next one it'll say okay let's take that
one minimize it again take that one
minimize it again on and on until
uh the the there's no more bytes that we
can remove we've exhausted the
minimization and to achieve maximum
minimization that's the point
um i want to mention too the kanto app
also can give you some visibility into
the target application so in this one
for example if we're fuzzing the sips uh
app
um you can
open a console app uh start streaming
and you can see the different messages
that
the application is
putting out
that you can view
so the console app's pretty handy too if
you want to get more information about
what's going on during fuzzing
so fuzzing network clients so a couple
examples here s b util and cups
essentially you just capture pcap
you export the uh the bytes for each
request or
well in this case for each response
from a valid server
and then you pass them to lifos
to fuzzling
so for this one we're using a local
client mode
that way we can
launch each one and check for crashes
pass the command line we're trying to
view use smb util to view
at four four five five we're using four
four five five because uh that is the
address of error um
our fuzzing server
and we don't wanna interfere with 445
which is the actual real smb server
running on the host
throw in our responses
dash p
is just saying we're doing a session so
we have more than one
input
we want to use everything that's in smb
response directory and use that as a
session sequentially
so in in that directory you know we have
like one dot bin two dot band three dot
bin and it will play each one of those
uh in order and randomly pick one of us
and all that stuff
um and then uh that's z here oh sorry i
didn't explain that c before with ez so
dash e reuses the crashes um if it finds
any dash z um it enables malik debugging
so it enables uh you know the uh guard
malloc to
to check for more subtle crashes so i
just like to put easy together because
it sounds like easy and
that's why
uh and then with cups we can use lp
admin you know check for different bugs
in it for example
again we change the port to make sure
that
we don't conflict with
the real cup server on port 631
and
uh yeah essentially we're pretending to
be a malicious uh cup server to fuzz lp
admin
client
as far as servers goes um
we have a couple here and probably one
more uh so we have the ard agent which
is a vnc type server
we have screen share daemon which is
actually a vnc server
you can read more about ard agent if you
search for it online about how it works
pretty interesting um how how apple uh
you know modified that and sort of came
up with
something for uh for a solution for for
different vnc stuff
um yeah essentially same thing as
clients capture the data
uh export it
and then um
use it to fuss
so we look at ard agent
um
we can see that
know it's listening uh udp 3283
also uh it's sued root which was also
interesting in this um
so that's uh that's an interesting fact
when looking at it see what kind of
privileges it may be running at
with light fuzz
we
can instead of doing it
as a local server mode with a command
we're just going to do it in remote mode
so just s
we're going to specify the address uh
there and then the particular packet
because then and this one we just wanna
we don't wanna do a session we just
wanna do the initial packet uh that was
captured
for this
and uh
yeah catching crashes can be interesting
for this you can enable report crash as
we mentioned before
and monitor the diagnostic logs for
stuff um
you can you know just do it
you can implement other things if you
can get a ard agent to running in a
debugger of course then you can you know
attach or
and you know send a signal when it
crashes
things like that
and then if we see
if we use dtrace to look at receive we
can see that while we're fuzzing you can
check to make sure the aod agent is
actually receiving messages and you know
fuzzing is going good and things like
that
screen share demon uh looking at port
and then for this and other processes on
mac launch d actually runs them
uh only upon connection
um so
if you didn't have a connection
uh you may just see that launch d was
just listening but once you once you
just connect to it it will actually
start the screen share d uh
you know other apps work that way too so
something to know um
as well when you're when you're doing
research
and for this one pretty straightforward
uh similar to
uh the client side except we're doing
server so again we're doing a remote
server
and uh
passing that along
and then uh there was a
remote uh so this is you so you can also
use report crash so mentioning forward
crash before
there's a feature in light fuzz where
we can
specify a process that we're looking for
that would be logged for crashes
and
in this way we can turn on report crash
we can fuzz
we can turn we can say remote mode but
still fuzz locally because we want to
utilize report
crash and if there's any crashes that uh
that occur
in uh the report crash directory
it will save them
uh and so at least we get some kind of
crash log and and of course the repro go
along with that
so um there was a potential bug there it
wasn't really reproducible uh but there
was a you know a cpu resource exhaustion
um log that uh that was found for that
uh which was uh yeah you can know that
the fuzzing the buzzing is working at
least
if nothing else
and then we have ods agent so um
ods agent
is another example we're going to use
here it's an xml based web service
it
uh essentially you can use it to share
uh cd and dvd uh type stuff across the
network
and the default prompt uh default is to
prompt on request for access
so you can see here just wanna give an
example of if you want to throw some
format string specifiers in there
it seems pretty timely with the wi-fi
stuff going on with uh apple
so you can uh
when you're fuzzing that make them
across the prompt because it's just
asking if if the remote person can have
access to it of course that can be
turned off as well
so for fuzzing this it actually has a
dynamic port so you gotta figure out
which one that is but we're going with
56156 today
and then give it the input files tell it
defines a session there may be two or
three packets in the session
and then again use dash report crash to
look for crashes that involve ods agent
and i have a bonus one today
so there's the say app which if you're
familiar
will read
text files and things like that
and say them uh through the speakers on
mac
so um
you know i said i thought what the heck
let's try that pass pass the file
through
let it read it
and
um yeah i thought i would fuzz that just
to see if you know funnily enough there
was any bugs
i haven't found any yet but um
you may want to mute your macbook if you
try this at home here here's here's what
it sounds like
yeah so
i'm just curious it's actually possible
to crash this thing but just got a bunch
of
you know uh bad text uh output from that
when i was looking at it
anyways just a bonus here uh fuzzing the
say app on mac and listening to it try
to pronounce uh fuzz text
so some of the bugs actually came out of
this
i can mention right now
applescript
colorsync syslog
there's some more upcoming cvs uh tbd as
well for different stuff
um but uh yeah there's
there was uh some interesting bugs that
came out of this and uh
sure apple will
have advisories and stuff for that later
on
um
so for conclusion yeah maybe you're more
interested in fuzzing on mac now
hopefully there's you know lowered the
bar as far as that goes i haven't you
know going into this project
again i didn't know much about mac um i
just learned a lot just just going and
doing it trying to figure out a lot of
the converting all the linux technology
to mac you know
gdb versus lldb and
how to do you know various activities on
mac and how you know i was curious if
any of this stuff would actually work
the same way but there's actually a lot
of crossover between linux and mac for
fuzzing which made things a lot easier
as well
yeah there's uh there's some you need to
work around certain things turn some
security features off if you want to you
know use it as a test box
but there's also a lot of good tools out
there d-trace was a great tool to use
for this
mac itself has a has some interesting
tools to give you visibility
um there's some more frameworks out
there such as hook case that can give
you some more
um visibility and and things as well
and yeah applying some unconventional
techniques and fuzzing you can still get
some good results so still shake some
bugs out
so
that is the end thank you very much for
listening appreciate it