what's up guys hello good afternoon
welcome to day two
uh i'm dylan this is screaming
uh i hope you guys enjoyed uh
yesterday's conference and the uh the
talks that we had uh for you guys
yesterday plus the labs we had some labs
yesterday evening
uh
i heard that josh strosskind's lab which
was supposed to ended at midnight
ran till i don't know like nearly one
o'clock man so big up to him for for
going the extra mile
love josh uh so yeah stay tuned man uh
we're gonna be kicking off with a
keynote with uh paul vixx in about 15
minutes uh he's doing this live as well
yeah so
uh he's going to join us in the studio
later but he's going to deliver this
keynote um live i believe it's 12 hours
different for him so it's almost one
o'clock in the morning
uh
you know we'd love to fall for staying
up and doing it
uh and then throughout the day uh this
is the studio track in case you don't
realize what you're watching and we'll
be having catch-up sessions and
interviews with uh speakers so like for
example we're talking to paul when he's
done
and in between that you know um we've
got some catch up with some usual
suspect guys
uh later on in the evening the ctf folks
will be joining us in the studio uh and
we'll be talking a little bit about
the edu capture the flag uh game that's
supposed to be happening uh after the
conference ends today
um what is the cdu game what is the edu
game that's a good question that's a
good question so
uh
we
we wanted to do obviously an in-person
conference right so normally we do our
capture the flag and it's a single
player or you know a team-based
jeopardy-style game
uh however when we do our final contest
in uae it's actually uh
attacking defense
and a lot of the student teams um who
have tried to participate in the past
find that a huge challenge because it's
completely different from playing
jeopardy right i mean japanese style gtf
is
kind of like a walk in the park in
comparison to attack and defense where
you have to collaborate with it with
your teammates and communication is kind
of like key and then you know having
predefined roles it's very much like
e-gaming if you guys follow like dota 2
style right like each player that's on
the team of five right has a has a role
uh and so the edu ctf uh for this round
is actually um going to act as a
qualifier so the teams that that have
played the capture the flag that's going
to be running uh this evening
are the top three teams right we're
going to fly them over to disciple week
so that they get a chance to play with
uh with the big boys right with the pro
guys uh who are going to be hand
selected so we're kind of like you know
working this out to have a platform for
them to kind of like move towards so
we're calling it like road to pro ctf
finals
uh so it should be quite exciting i mean
uh there's gonna be a scoreboard you
guys can follow that along uh i think
it's like 125 120 odd teams uh
registered
um can they still register or no no
registration is closed unfortunately
there was some issue with the
registration form yesterday and there
was like some like yeah a bit of a
scramble that's it
but uh yeah the guy's audited obviously
so uh yeah join us this evening so we'll
be catching up with like the hacker dom
guys
sorry and for the folks who haven't uh
resent their form to the ctf guys don't
forget to send that in because otherwise
the information might not be there yeah
yeah do that do that yeah also join the
discord right so uh if you're a ctf team
i think you would have gotten the link
to join discord so please go in there so
that the guys can get your details and
make sure that you guys have access to
the cloud infrastructure
uh so yeah so desktop will be joining us
constantine from acadom uh youssef and
ahmed from ctf.e as well
it should be fun we'll find out more
what what they've got in store for these
teams
i don't envy them because it's always a
challenge especially uh you know hrtv
ctf is kind of known as uh
not so easy
so yeah uh
i guess that's pretty much it take a
look at the agenda if you guys haven't
already looked at it um
as i mentioned we'll be talking to some
folks in between uh in between talks so
you know if you don't want to watch
sometimes you can join us over here
uh if you have questions for the
speakers go to discord so we've got a
discord channel there's a kind of like
ask our speakers channel or you can ask
it the general channel whatever
and we'll ask them here when they join
us for the q a
in the meantime enjoy the show uh
we got like roughly 10 minutes before
paul goes on stage so i'd recommend you
know give yourself some coffee
or whatever else
we'll see you guys later uh we'll be
having to catch up with paul at uh just
after his talk so yeah join us back here
as soon as paul's done with his keynote
join us back in the studio and we'll
like have some q a
all right see you guys later bye
ciao
you