so maybe we could open the floor just
very briefly to any sort of comments or
concerns how do you like that our
program is done now let's turn to the
most important part of it the audience
me read it perhaps you could join me
here instead of eating a section
Meredith has been dutifully live
tweeting so that the Internet's know
what is going on
maybe we'll be streaming the next
workshop look for it hopefully we could
so feedback
path analysis reconstruction yeah well
we saw you know some work earlier today
like in extracting session languages
from you know from binaries and and also
in going forward from me okay okay we
have a state machine we have the message
format your percents work we generate
the protocol from that so yeah you know
what you just have some code we don't
even really know it's parsing wrong idea
right absolutely
I'm reversal here few pages with our
inputs and follow them you accuracy the
undercoating a state machine has people
in
okay so we've been focused on the
cutting and research or we step back
where do you see land deck in 10 years
and what do you think need to happen to
get there I'm actually so focused right
now I mean what needs to happen to get
there that I'm that where there is
actually a little harder to describe I
mean there was there was so much work
this year on on on session languages you
know on on the state machines of
protocols you Perry and I were sitting
that we're talking in whispers basically
about is it time to go to the IETF and
basically require not only you know an a
B and a B F grammar for message formats
but also a both human readable and
machine readable state machine
description for acceptance on an RFC
I mean 52-34 is the APNs definition and
it certainly like recommended but I'm
thinking like you know can we make a
push or acceptance criteria let me
supply yet another item last year out of
this roundtable came the idea to
formulate cwe's that would be useful to
code editors our Falcon you can wait we
presented a paper on this at the first I
Triple E SEC def conference and it
received some interest and of course now
we have to forge the language and
persuade the GWT people to take it but
we have broken ground on that work and
we want laying sack to be a part of
every code audit so that's a pretty good
goal for ten years and then of course
looking more ambitiously we want other
parsers that they're written in ten
years to be written and parser
Combinator's any memory state languages
and in memory safe languages okay more
all these ratchets that Perry's been
talking about I mean you know these need
to become part of build systems tooling
needs to exist to support these
you want to elaborate on that some whoa
I like what you mean by ad hoc languages
exactly
we did a wait you're talking about in a
way here you're talking about dsls right
I mean which people are going to need to
learn good DSL design equals the urs
instead they are extruder success that's
a good point
okay personally I would like to sort of
get off the popular parson basically
Parsons person's parsing but I mean I've
ever 1996 there were some nice sleepers
or fit operating systems bitch language
teachers
Billy is offering with the Pearl and a
paper about what features need language
ability and that sort of thing is pretty
pretty nice using language for much more
interesting purposes and I'm sorry we
seem to have given up on things like
that
happily we haven't really but of course
it's easier to concentrate on that very
code that comes into contact with
untrusted inputs and gets exploited you
know this is where most of your weird
machines are but as you recall our our
starting paper the formal applications
the applications acuity applications of
formal language theory it also branched
out in the languages of events passing
through a reference monitor and similar
concerns of systems designed I mean we
didn't have anything else back related
work this year but I mean a big part of
the whole point of elf back is that
loaders have languages to write and of
course not everything that people think
of as parsing is parsing right and not
everything that people don't think of as
parsing isn't actually parsing so your
loader is definitely a parser your
driver is very often a parser as we have
just seen there up well okay so let me
give you a let me give you a specific
example what about the Intel management
engine which turned out to contain a
parser and we should be apparently like
gos by
like pulling a particular audio input on
the dot connector high which I find
hilarious you can that you can even you
can shut off the webserver by it by
tossing the entire management tension
yeah but even the even video with
admitting an empty credential because
parsers parsing in see what could go
wrong indeed indeed I think aiming
higher is what we're trying to do but we
have to have the shoulders of giants to
stand on in order to do that
another ten-year goal is that every data
protocol that is being proposed to some
sort of a major application such as
vehicle-to-vehicle communications equal
to infrastructure communications any
other critical infrastructure get its
data reviewed for complexity and for the
gotchas that will make interacting with
that protocol a very very painful see
huge experience for all you lose the
security game at the point when you've
designed a design an overly complex data
format this is where your partial
differentials nest this is where they
will come to roost
so putting the humans out of the way by
automating all the things and very where
do I start I mean if we go Crimea if we
just go chronologically from yesterday
right like incorporating fuzz testing
into you know into in to build tooling
you know like like rust is done automate
automate generated automate generation
of both parsers and on parsers automate
generation of state of state machine
languages I mean if we have the like if
we have a machine readable spec to do it
from and not necessarily what to make
but make it easy to express grammars in
the language it's if you think of it
it's a shame that your most typical
element of your most typical Network
protocol a sequence of variable length
options or headers has no standard way
of being expressible in c and requires a
stepping pointer to go through the
goddamn thing and dereferencing that
pointer am casting that pointer where
you can't be declarative about a
structure and input structures is this
simple meanwhile in Erlang you know that
kind of stuff is first-class language
operations right so this is not strictly
speaking automation but if this has made
a part of the language by way of the
language design by way of the library
will be much better off yeah and the
autumn automation you need when you
can't express things cleanly in the
language itself I mean this is why Java
has a giant code snow all over it
because it's because it's not just like
you know parsers for yeah like look at
look at Jack's key right like look at
look at pretty much anything that that
deals with with EJB right it's it's all
like code gets generated from XML
specification type crap you know because
the lang
which doesn't provide good support for
vo4 for four ways to configure these
things absolutely
platform-independent way to specify
protocol which obviously we have
Sullivan's
verification so that we could sort of
build a standard and Bill tool supported
where it sort of says you know oh you
want to implement a protocol well what's
your fine is a machine whether you're
you know say regular expressions for
your messages and firstly wouldn't force
anybody to use that but it's that's
that's what I'm aiming towards yeah
that's the kind of cooling I want to see
yeah I mean ultimately it would be
really awesome to be able to just like
rip to appendices out of your out of
your RFC and just feed them to a couple
of code generators in you're done but is
that can become sort of a you can get
people to start thinking about of the
default way to build a protocol right
you don't even have to say go analyze
the protocol regular because you just
have this thing sitting there saying
give me your regular expressions give me
here right and that is a goal that is
definitely at all traditional be bold
here again I'm really encouraged by the
piston moves you have all the talk about
being derailed Berg about writing the
purser to memory state languages and
linking that into an existing
application I make very drastic
functions I wonder if we might be able
to leverage the power that language
Italian collagen people adopt - adopt
the most iconic way or the most proxy
you a if you will of giving opinion
actually get some language developers to
include this content libraries and
experts of their language I know that
for dental attention were working
currently on the piece of data eight at
a time we're very interested in the work
that we're doing and Scala at least used
to have parser combinators in the
standard library I mean I don't know
what are you guys what are you guys is
feeling about the rush standard library
like do you think could be folded in
[Music]
okay so like it's something that we
could work towards I mean because I was
standing here thinking god am I gonna
have to friggin port hammer to rust and
do all the llv all of the LLVM JIT crap
like in rust I'm sure we could I'm not
sure I'd want to
library Rakitic really right and
probably very little to do without it
public employment which is one of the
reasons that like the would seem great
for example like live in compiler and
while it comes with one how to get naked
seeing flower barrettes but if you want
to confirm with see it compiler to try
to because I would one you have to veget
perfect auger right you can if you
actually didn't up today great
entertainment like patch the complex
solely Brophy speaking with high
dimension stuff like anything clever
human could use it but at this point
like now we have a friend sorry so if
that's the state of fact on the ground
in the rust world how do we work with
that if not more formally verified you
mean
the black bean between semi-trailer
again so three feet lower than but by
definition will be I I should make a
logistical announcement if you have a
car part to the hotel
apparently at six some sort of the timer
rolls over and they might charge you a
lot extra
so just done if you need to move your
car now move your car yes okay it was so
wait we we make it so that whenever
whenever do is consumed is parcel
whether you agree with that I'm just
looking at seven days with doing some
zombies and or or reading one bumper
into another they're the old way of
doing them with the camera with the
naval gun sir coffee or or start
coming and when you do people be out
since to vote some number people are
still going to use the old one they
think you know this one's good enough
for me I do think it works
I think the only way the wind is to let
everybody only use the focus they know
how to use and on with that - places
always doing the Space Station yep
assuming we had talked about them is
because you build hammer in such a way
that you can basically provide a grammar
and then you can poison for example skin
if you can only use in it one providing
the grammar then with automatically
generate a liquid nail does going from a
data specification you only weight into
a TN or scan is to go through you can do
that
walk to the people that we want to be
corrected
you
[Music]
is what we've seen the TLS
implementations and guide will just be a
litany of hokum back overflow thing why
yes
just tell it that its grammar is dot
star and it will be regular everything
will be fine to make it very easy and
integrate parser computer with the
language movement and tackling familiars
and elders some of their pace and then
tell them that they don't need to use
closures anymore I hate every single
character of the code that has walking
pointers
I had to write some recently and I felt
unclean through the whole process I kind
of feel like a question that might help
us like explore the the issue just
raised a little more would be why don't
more people user life but I mean if
you're talking about like essentially
moving a new syntax for like Seon or F
read into the standard library of the
saying like that's a that's a that's a
bridge you have to cross somehow
I think we've talked had a very relevant
piece on this right how do you throw a
essentially a functional language piece
of control code over to the people who
actually do write the control I did find
it really fascinating it was basically
see type signatures and Haskell bodies
that was rad yeah so this is what we
have to do I mean the answer why people
are not using a language that they don't
know for a code base that they do know
is kind of obvious they don't know it
they know the code base they're scared
is a kill you had I did get hammered
I did get hammered to compile under and
script in I just have no idea what to do
with the results I got
okay so basically like it's not useful
to in script in a library
oh yeah I know I mean like this the
syntax that we used for the Combinator's
in hammer was actually inspired by a
JavaScript parser Combinator library
this gets us back to the question of
formal formal semantics because the the
the the body right of the of each
Combinator you know of course would need
to would need to satisfy the same
preconditions invariants and
postconditions
in order for the behavior to like well
and also the same side effect in order
for the behavior to be to be identical
well there's also the aspect of if your
language is too complex then you're
doomed to partial differentials but I
mean I have I have been talking with
Prashant and and Mike about about
getting some some formal verification
into hammer and we're like evaluating
tools for that and maybe we should talk
with you about that some Perry I mean
just it cuz I need to start with there's
there there's you know some underlying
data structures they you know that that
we can prove some variants about
representation and then have five
irrational transformation so you want to
see one that goes into what reducing the
JavaScript wonderful
the point is because I wonderful
connections if something right said you
javis that's what they're familiar with
they can automatically translate that
job is pretty close the standard one
between their gender on the back end if
they're a formal semantics of JavaScript
and if you have a single strip Silver's
the user writing JavaScript in a quarter
time away it's gonna be completely
honest with one stop this grammar as
long as they they always template
essentially then some characters who
have mostly Windigo the tricky bit is
that the tool needs to generate
equivalent code the Queen seriously to
answer to your question but you're not
quite although the answer is interesting
it's not what you wanted here okay so
there is in fact a formal semantics for
JavaScript as a
in English a which is a really cool
system and an executable formal
semantics and it passes the entire
necklace 5.1 conformance testing but
here's the problem
you know what other JavaScript
implementation even passes 90% in the
suite so they're cost effective problems
many many differences of language
version skew so the formal semantics
that someone has done for JavaScript
applause exactly none of the versions of
JavaScript that actually existed here so
every JavaScript right yeah I get where
I get where your own on the front end
I'm just worried about equivalence on
the back end since you mentioned
protocol buffers protocol buffers are
actually exemplary in that what they
actually implement is a a very simple
and minimal context-free grammar if you
are writing a protocol buffers
implementation then you are forced by
this API to North create anything more
complex than a context-free language of
course you can absolutely screw this up
by creating or implying dependencies
between the objects that you extract and
you can add all kinds of context
sensitivity to your resulting language
but fewer protocol buffers where you do
not create any or imply any dependencies
between what you unpack is in fact
context-free and it's that language of
designing your data packaging that could
be translated to other languages because
it's intuitive I mean essentially it's
simple productions each production being
regular
ah well I I asked this question I asked
these questions of Googlers who of
course she quite a large code base and
protobuf and people do create
dependencies between object completely
breaking the nice property of protobufs
and so yes and this is of course where
fathers have a few de protocols are
essentially the protobuf api you can
look at it as essentially a way of
descriptively writing down a grammar as
code this is important I mean if it
looks like the grammar it well it is a
grammar in some sense it is a grammar is
the most important sense well I mean
both norm and hammer have their own ways
of describing in grammar the parts of
combinations but yes this would be very
simple parser Combinator's you could
write a grammar in either Nam or hammer
for the protobuf wire format for
instance yeah you totally could
I'm not sure um well so the question is
where is getting them and it's
apparently saving them quite a bit of a
development effort should this approach
be applied elsewhere it should save
other people quite a number of
development hours I mean the problem I
see though is like vendors NGO vendors
and vendor consortia in particular tend
to you know tend to not want to write
protocols that are simple enough to be
described in the form of photographs you
know and some of that is you know
competition from you know each vendor
trying to get their their special
feature into the you know into the into
the control system spec or whatever but
it ends up there's piling epicycles on
top of epicycles and so you end up with
like me long distance data dependency oh
yes
here is another 10-year goal try to
instill in industries that have no
critical infrastructure such as energy
the idea that designing protocols by
committee and that the protocol is
somehow a vessel for accommodating
everyone's features and this is the nice
thing to do because you're creating a
consensus you're being nice to all of
the members of the consortium this is
exactly not the nice thing to do
actually hard game theory problem right
yes here we're going to have to fight
human nature here and that's never a
good idea so I kinda don't see your way
around but this is the very opposite of
nice because you're dooming everyone to
a hair 11 security for who knows decades
of course your typical piece of
infrastructure equipment is supposed to
serve twenty years at least so you know
where's the liability right you know if
a toll fraud was a big deal to the
analog cell phone operators because
somebody had to pay for that
well the losses are more evenly
distributed and modernization is lost
maybe the pole want to think kind of
work that you could be done secretly the
levy endgame eager Ethan again finds
like concise list this is the offense to
which that pattern that very describing
increases your red I'm not sure how like
linearizable that is but but it's worth
exploring yes absolutely I mean I think
I suspect it will probably be more
qualitative than quantitative but but
there has to come a year when protocols
as just a repository of everyone's
desirable features just stop being that
when the strength is reversed when the
fight is for getting the least amount of
fields in the protocol and this was seen
as the nice thing to do that in fact is
my personal program for talking to power
industry in a couple of weeks the cost
the cost of a length field traditionally
has been quite high the cost of the
variable with structure is quite high I
mean look at mommy he'll like the np3
literally had a billion dollar mistake
in the spec there was that zero length
that zero-length string result or a null
pointer I'll give you one more I pee
before options which now you would not
really find in the wild because it
turned out that they were just trouble
and then of course ipv6 extension
headers with their chains are costing
people a lot I've heard from some
operators that they're dropping
forty percent of all incoming packets of
a certain kind in ipv6 on the floor who
was the have a good conversation was
about insurance earlier today may have
been you I think it was actually
somebody else but maybe that person is
still here you're addressing right now
is something that I hoping were taken
recalling the premature acceptability
and I are just going to be premature
optimization anti-pattern this is the
same place from which we get a bit what
is reflection Java frankly it's just
push that people have to ensure forward
compatibility and incredible even moving
don't yet know what their what they
think they're going to build I'm almost
done of these hooks ever get used and if
you look through old are speed you'll be
a little graveyard of extensibility
features that were never used some
statistics on how close to none that is
would be useful if you could start
keeping track yes I am very busy well
unhappy reminded of something which was
said when it was time came decide
whether I 86 that he would get the
things internet packet right because
there is the field in p4 that has the
Pantheon key version of Graces we
decided to know you could use the IP
version of distinguish different kind
different types of IP because there's no
all of the older versions they function
such as any other EPO value in that game
is too dangerous so the most decided
people actually do things like that and
leave them battle too long they can't we
use anyway that you come up these
because there's too much fear that goes
English was confronted with with any
different value in the ability they
surely know that's right and really the
foot side of that thing that is an
instant Parker differential in the next
versions review we did start we did make
an attempt to start speaking the
language of patterns and anti patterns
our Sega Dev paper without anti patterns
our login article in the past issue was
about how we can represent
recognizers and non parsers as design
patterns familiar to people who actually
do decide that the interpreter pattern
literally I mean there's an entire
chapter on this and game for ah
we're coming up on the end of our time
oh are we turning into a pumpkin
okay well we could we could go on but
it's been a long day because the other
traditional everyone goes out drinking
it
at what is that police called yes yes
and Peter score market yeah clearly have
the last slide I think I remember which
button to press but nothing needs to
Jack but nothing is projecting should be
formally and concisely specified but for
some definition of performance besides
because it makes me crazy when I'm
looking at a specification and you have
to read four paragraphs of English to
understand the exception to write you
think I do it in just a couple of lines
at a b NS exactly yes or something wrong
because you get four paragraphs anybody
and when you're doing later to say that
your status actly something where you do
have these diagrams in there that
explain you have this critical work but
then you actually redeem the set there
are other features that are explained
but not shown in this video to XML like
it was right
crazy Sonia's weird weird rules and then
I went to the logs of error reports at
the beginning and some of the attempts
when I do this missa missa does made the
robot so they almost verbatim took his
message and said when this happens this
sure that that way that became part of
the definition and we shoot to the heart
where are the things we would have
machines you know what we never has
machine readable definition and in which
and there's a conflict the machine
readable self should always be order to
keep every agree to use the English is
where is informally a human being yeah
if you screwed up and you explained it
correctly in the in the English but
incorrectly in the formal education too
bad you get to revise it
that's why there's a comment period you
think it's likely this blue curve we
sure talk about this today so I don't
know all of the poet centimeter
respectively well define how you expect
anything about what I mean have another
line I know I don't feel like that's a
very pleased to start to expect to find
written and I think a lot of it comes
down to Detective Inspector design speed
is very palpable and perfectly like me
it's three everyone is upset
well there's a lot of standards bodies
out there to write I mean like you know
we can go talk to the IETF and III my
feel for that is like I think they'll
probably employed a receptive probably
be reserved but like I Triple E that's a
standard body to use at the santa's body
hey that believe me sometimes a keyboard
in everybody
you should do the campi actually
abilitynet in process means active
efficient which means like going and
packing committees which always feels
kind of like sketchy to me but like I
guess we're trying to propose that
higher dimension is very depressed
that's true we get mightor to pick that
up
nothing else
proximately a year's get image itself
yeah yeah I mean that's that applies to
every standards body alright so I guess
we're pretty much done for this year
thank you all very much for coming this
has been a really fantastic workshop the
papers were like a cut above this year
this was really really great work huh a
round of applause for the authors
and for the remaining audience if not
for you have no workshop thank you also
to our sponsors white option dr NW gmbh
and the previous sponsors who helped us
i get off the ground and thank you for
coming