yeah thanks thanks Iggy for the
introduction this is basically the thing
that I want to say so we made up this
glorified title explaining what we want
to do actually this is I should mention
my co-authors here thanks to them I'm
just presenting here so this is the
title actually but actually it's all
about unprocess right so we actually
have facing things in application
security so the web thing that can be
simply solved by um parsing correctly so
glad to see this year the OS released
another top ten list so I can reference
this here actually from the last time to
now the first three do not really change
so looking at those one can see that
there is number one and number three
which are both injections right so they
are no different injections exist in
with which every language you basically
unpassed so the point is here I mean
keeping those two things different then
just confuses people right crosshead
cooking's nothing out but injection so
the root cause here is basically that
when unpausing some things it's really
difficult to correctly do to do this
correctly and context sensitive encoding
in this case so basically in HTML it's
really hard to respond to spot the right
encoding for the right context so to
bash a little bit bit more about the the
over thing and the epic so basically a
mess the keynote already pointed out and
well doing it like we did before might
be not too good a year so basic Johnson
trading on new things it's a good thing
so basically throwing static analysis
and dynamic analysis all the time
against
turing-complete languages might not end
up in being a good thing because yeah
what could we expect from this right
it's true incomplete so it's not going
to let them to bring us much and so it's
like this this unfair thing which which
are noted here in exchange over it's
just like I mean if you're just using
some string coconut concatenation your
program does not state what it's really
doing there it was it's trying to
achieve so you could not do anything
about this or make it any any better
actually the thing is it it's easy
that's the only point why it's used
right so just printing it is easy so
people do and so coming from a length
tech perspectives learn the the idea
must be to actually specify what what we
want to print out or unfairest makes you
before cutting it all together so on the
other hand it needs to be used right so
the the average soft we develop the
civil developer just does not care about
this right it needs to be easy as string
concatenation yeah otherwise they just
don't care so as I just discussed the
first point we want to solve actually
those injections coming from the
application security thing with lengths
like tools and now I want to tell a
little bit more on how we actually try
to do this and then afterwards coming to
some some listings about how we actually
define binary grammars which our grammar
to yourself so first a little bit more
into the into the problem then so
basically what is what is injection
injection you usually have this this
thing where you have an attacker which
is using one language talking to a front
and
this front end being a web server also
uncrossing some message into language
and then one is then sent over to a
target mostly database this is a
classical setting but this might be
anything right so every two systems
communicating with each other where the
target is trusting the front end is
basically prone to two injection if yeah
if the language supports injection so to
say so what actually is injection exit
injection means that within the past
three so basically I assume always that
we have something like the path tree
within the component this is this is
basically sending the message because
otherwise I'm always screwed right if I
don't have a structured representation
of this thing that I want to send and
screwed it the very beginning so having
that one basically there might be some
some syntax within the leaves of this
parse tree that actually do not belong
there right so from a from a definition
of this office path tree they should not
be there because the token definition of
this Leafs should not allow those tokens
to be there so what we actually want to
achieve is what I've written down there
with with some some formulas is
basically that we want to ensure that
those those messages that we on Paris
basically end up in the same ast or in
the same parse tree as the one which
which sent over the line this is
basically the one we want to have and
there's encoding actually required so
encoding basically being ripping out
those characters or those keywords that
are messing up basically those tokens so
F this here as an example again to
clarify you can see these those arrows
right right so basically you have this
path view of the left and then unfairest
List
with a string representation and then
parting it again and I just want to have
as I just said the same path tree again
so what happens if I add there some some
things that do not belong into this into
this token they get unhorsed and then
manipulate the we pass tree on the other
side so basically what I actually want
to do is I want to detect this and
basically just only detect okay here's
an injection and how do we do this we
basically check those tokens again with
with the T power Combinator as we are
using hammer underneath we are basically
checking those those tokens there with
the part of the Combinator which was
used which should be used to actually
derive this and this token and check if
this when we parse this this is still
the same just in the same content there
is the same token type and afterwards we
double check that there are no keywords
within this one so yes the parts are
good that does not get confused um so
now about well now we detected this and
now we want to actually automatically
derive an encoding from from grammar so
basically the challenges you just plant
the language there as over there with
this MC G's Multi multi core grammar
thing and we want to extract all those
key words and then we split those key
words so we might not end up in some
cases where some neighboring nodes
within the path tree have some parts of
the key words and ends up in the same in
the in this key word then
and afterwards we wanna actually
identify from this grammar which symbols
we could use to actually create an
encoding so um in this example here
there is this ID token the only one
which actually allows some more symbols
and this is why we only have there some
free symbols we could actually use to
create some encoding
including hearings and that you can put
some other keywords within this within
this token be not any more keywords and
for our the others
we are good because we don't have any
free symbols and then actually we need
sure need to take out those from those
three symbols those those keywords that
were that we are having over here so
basically the part of the keywords that
do not need to be part of the of these
symbols which that we can use for
encoding entry so then we actually first
choose a baneling basically we choose to
two symbols and do a binary encoding of
all key words so they be numerate all
those key words choose two symbols to a
binary encoding of this one we know
actually when processing the grammar how
many key words are there so it's just e
to the mystically clear and how many
keywords we have how long this encoding
might end up and we can basically
generate all the stuff and here's an
example for this very grammar how some
of those encoding looks like and we
would basically choose here capital a as
as our escape symbol and B as another
symbol for encoding here we actually
experience it a little bit with some
option called seesaw which means stuff
inside stuff out so basically not only
using not only encoding those key words
but all symbols which are not defined
within this grammar which means that you
could basically stuff anything in there
and it still ends up so Steph anything
into your pass tree and then it's
serialized and Dec parsed at the
receiver and still ends up in your your
path tree from a yeah if you just want
to transfer data this is nice but from
another point of view is this like okay
you actually define your grammar as a
receiver you define your grammar and
stay
okay I want just expecting those kind of
those kind of things to be read and then
you end up having some different things
in your past tree which did not specify
within your grammar which might lead to
some confusion and some other kind of
yeah secondary confusions within this
application there so actually as I
already said we we used hammer for an
implementation which is called MC hammer
coder actually I guess Segway was coming
up with this name so we had a control
and he was like okay MC hammer would be
cool isn't it I guess
yeah yeah yeah you you're you I okay
yeah it's the combination of Monty Corps
which is the which is the framework for
actually designing to make specific
languages for all those Java guys out
there and we actually integrated this
with a hammer browser back-end and
integrated our encoding decoding
generating for this is actually
providing a parse tree with in Java and
you could actually specify those actions
in Java
ripping them all through that they are
triggered by hammer and then executed
again into Java you can find all this
code on get up have fun and now I'm
going to show you a little bit more
about those grammars so those multi-core
grammar binary languages how we can
define this so basically what we have
here on top is straightforward just some
tokens and some some productions where
so this is our starting point basically
this is what what multi-core provided
before and we actually extend this by
adding some binaries some binary
construct for actually extending the
alphabet for binary
representation - over there so down here
you can see you have these D integers
where you can specify it in those Gregg
brackets
how they if they appear how they must
appear and then afterwards you can
specify some other alternative so you
have the idea you can basically specify
what you expect there this is in the end
of this is translated to a hammer so
should somehow the concept should should
match over there and then we we added
those concepts also present in hammer
versus offset in length field and
actually with these offsets we can
specify we can specify a linear function
so basically we can when we parse we
have this office rule or you how this
how this parsed value translate to the
to the offset we could have actually
implemented this as well for the length
width which was the comment actually for
the presentation right before so we
actually support kind of the same thing
that we just heard about the same speeds
with mrs. caleca records so basically we
name those length fields and afterwards
you can basically use this very values
you just parse twitches I hope kind of
the same thing so we are ending up in
the right direction over there so we did
some evaluation basically some
functional ones for generators hema
browser which we fast with peach fuzzer
and thanks to hammer we had no crashes
which is great I mean I have no clue
about how to to really do this right so
thanks
we we had no crashes and then we
compared this to so we threw those
inputs to to our parser into two DNS
puzzle which is finding this way and
then our language was just the same from
these samples like the like the pine
powder which accepted right the same
packet section and then we do what all
those web guys do with when it comes to
encoding to actually have a look at if
this is correctly encoded we basically
use those specialized Fathers for web
languages so basically we we have an
HTML language with JavaScript and try to
try to fast this one with with Def IBM
FCN and fast DB and we actually did not
find something which well might be ok
but I hope we really did not miss
something over there and actually we
compared those path trees because
actually we have different encoding then
which was specified within HTML so we
came up with a generated encoding which
browsers definitely do not understand
but our own decoder then does and so
when we compared those path trees we
sent in those past history parse again
we did not find any differences for all
those inputs so to sum up we we have
this situation where the injection
vulnerabilities are still yeah kind of
not really understood by those guys who
care most so basically the OS Pro 10
seems to be broken and those guys should
really catch up with some legs except I
suppose and we delivered here some ideas
on how to actually generate some
encoding if you're if you're running a
new protocol on your language and you're
not building up on all those stuff that
is available for for the web and you're
running a new protocol you actually want
to have something that provides you
these kind of encoding
and so you don't mess up those things by
yourself yeah and yeah the last point
actually from so reflecting back to the
keynote is basically I mean if we get
this right so these parsing and
unplugging if we actually get this right
we might end up in a solution where
where she can verify some things right
and decompose security again which would
be great I mean we would have been at
life for the last thirty years with this
would be great
so some some points were one could
actually work on is definitely positive
wrenches which we definitely do not care
about I mean we when we have different
fathers and they've definitely behaved
differently and this is what we did not
did not travel in this approach up to
now on the other thing for for doing
some more offense research might be
interesting to actually learn those
learn those languages that programs talk
right so basically extracting those
those grammars from existing
implementations and looking for and look
for injections so basically extracting
those keywords and try if we can inject
things over there might be interesting
to find some things and yeah as I said
before I mean we need to get these
things those things more easily and
bring this more to the heart of
developers so they actually use this
stuff this would be close to my heart so
perhaps we can do some things about this
and that's it thank you some questions
three very very quick points first of
all on your early slide where you show
you are your invariant for the parts of
mania of the un-- parts you know
that's the theory about to prove in
order to just show that your your
imitation is correct it's right there if
you were working the system what that
would be what you have to prove yeah we
know and then you would know that this
the rest of us our second brilliant
question so you almost are doing this in
some ways - well you just by by getting
the invariant in and out even in the
presence of something that clearly pops
top code this down the line and it's
badly written will be vulnerable even
the code that used that using more
technical you will not be protected by
codes it's using your techniques or if
your kögel is work fine regardless of
what you throw it and then something
that's badly written down the line will
will will risk will still receive you
know the embedded stuff and you know in
some Soviet yeah baby needs just
unplugging right it's not caring about
writing and really good parsers right
the other way around right so and this
is kind of the Cecil things so if you
enable the CTO mode yeah definitely your
father is all your your path tree which
is generated from your father contains
stuff that you're not want to have it in
there so this is was just an option and
we actually do not enable this just
showing this my describe parsers as
deliberately well providing extra
ammunition extra computing power yes to
the adapters refusing to decode run into
their execution model but of course you
know other's performances let's real
quick
very something that looked really really
fascinating on last part of the last lie
which is the notion of providing
programming languages with built-in
reasonable representation for forever
yeah yes we done yeah if you if you have
a good idea for this I'm very up to
getting this done but I'm actually not
sure how this really is the right thing
right I've seen some some guys writing
grammars with in XML things so this
might be not the right thing terribly
what you're writing here is much more
general the same you know the point is
that if the code that used would induce
doesn't look like the grammar of those
inputs that code is trouble that code
has no business existing right I open it
yourself you look at this and you see a
pointer style right you know static with
integer arithmetic this is definitely if
it doesn't look like the grammar
it is trouble pretty much helpless so
what would you say and what largest said
is again a portal or corollary of that
we want make it easy for developers to
make the code look likely expect valid
grammar parser generators are that but
other means are portable as well
so regarding to the bi-directional
property of partisan announcers I think
it might be too strong with them believe
in the politics on the source code
attracting a tree and yeah we skipped
actually this problem actually in the
first implementation we tried to
actually incorporate asta abstraction in
there but yes you're right and then
basically this construction of the
umpire is really a tough things also we
basically stick with the past redone
person yeah yeah we don't want to solve
it again right yeah thank you
[Applause]