okay so what I want to do to kick things
off is like on the next slide put
together a graphic to kind of summarize
where we're at with the state of the art
in terms of security for embedded
systems and it looks like this in my my
point here is that with respect to
embedded systems and security we're
stuck in the 70s right the disco era and
why is that well the reason is because
we're still using the same tools and
techniques for building better systems
that we've been using since then so
generally this means doing development
and C or C++ you know building these new
tools if you're lucky and you've got a
JTAG header on your board you can use
gdb to debug it otherwise you may be
blinking LEDs or sending data over the
you are so um although we're still
building systems the same way we've been
doing it for decades now the complexity
of embedded systems has grown
exponentially so there's a name for it
right
you know it's fashionable now not to say
embedded systems but cyber-physical
systems and the emphasis here is that
what we think of as embedded systems
really has grown in terms of how much
they're networked in the complexity of
the system so if you take in a modern
automobile for example inside a modern
vehicle there are dozens maybe up to a
hundred now of electronic control units
or ECU's so microcontrollers scattered
throughout the vehicle and they're all
networked together on data buses
primarily can bus and there's also a
whole bunch of external interfaces so
radios connecting to everything from OD
D obd2 port for the mechanics to plug
into short-range radios like Bluetooth
long range telemetry systems
entertainment systems and so on and so
forth so it's not surprising then since
we essentially have you know complex
networked computers on wheels that this
is a ripe target for attacking and it's
now pretty broadly known you know some
of the early work happening in 2011 even
earlier that we can
HAC and automobiles so there's a New
York Times clipping also more recent
work by Charlie Miller and Chris Valek
so here's a table from some of the work
from University of Washington UC San
Diego that was mentioned the New York
Times article and I really like this to
point out a couple of points that have
been made here already today so the
first thing is that so this is a table
talking about all the ways that they're
able to penetrate a modern automobile
remotely so through these different
interfaces like things like short-range
radio and long-range wireless and the
first thing you'll and draw your
attention to is the full control column
and what this means is that no matter
how the attacker got into the vehicle
were they able to take over any other
functionality in the system so you know
if I can through bluetooth still able to
disable breaks still able to lock the
seat belts still able to change Lane
Assist etc etc and then every case is
yes so it's a really squishy insights
right like once you get in it's game
over the second thing I want to draw
your attention to and this was mentioned
in the keynote at the beginning is that
what kind of new esoteric vulnerably
security vulnerabilities that they use
to get into these systems right well
none right it's buffer overflow buffer
overflow buffer overflow so you know
we've got a new more complex system but
it's the same old problem that we've
known about for a long time so you could
say well you know um you know aren't be
solve problems don't we know how to
address them and you know there's
approaches like sandboxing you know
things like hypervisors and chrome
Native Client these are open source ways
to sandbox high-level programming
languages with powerful type systems
that are you know in particular type
safe and memory safe you know so two
ones I like functional languages or oh
camel and Haskell we've got a number of
verification tools but I would say in
the space of embedded systems these are
not sufficient and why well first of all
um even though you know it's the modern
era we still use very small impoverished
microcontrollers so everything from you
know 8-bit microcontrollers with just a
few kilobytes of RAM and
and and flash for program memory and
without any kind of virtual memory
system and you know even though a
microcontroller might be this small like
an Arduino for example people developed
you know full auto pilots that fit on
these things you know on with just a few
kilobytes of RAM in contrast you know
something like hello world in modern
Haskell compiled it down it's about
requires about a Meg of RAM to run and a
Meg of size for the executable
not to mention unpredictability in the
runtime system for garbage collection
and furthermore even if these systems
are really small in terms of lines of
code they can be extraordinarily complex
you've got interrupts with device
drivers you're running on a real table
and are toss so you might have high
levels of concurrency with periodic
tasks and sporadic tasks and so and not
to mention you linking in Lib C so
modeling and verifying these systems
post talk is very very difficult even if
the code sizes are small if our problems
not hard enough
additionally in these embedded systems
it's not just like I have to worry about
network security or crypto or you know
control systems everything's thrown in
together right so this is a block
diagram of a autopilot and I'm not going
to go through it but I just want to draw
your attention to give you a sense of
the complexity of the kinds of
properties that we add the diversity of
properties we have to worry about so you
know statically linked into one binary
you have to deal with a device driver
correction correctness sensor fusion so
you know Coleman filters we've got
control laws so DeLaval you know
correctness of dynamic the vehicle
dynamics the comm systems networking
crypto and all this is together we want
to reason about the correctness of all
of this so as was mentioned to address
this and see if we can live up to the
Challenger or at least make some
progress
DARPA began the highest Shore and cyber
military systems program so this is
the brainchild of Kathleen Fisher who's
now Tufts and she was the original
program manager and we were one of the
performers and we worked with a team
that included Rockwell Collins
University of Minnesota a Boeing and
Galois where I met and so the idea was
let's start small let's try out to build
if we start take a Greenfield approach
and let's say let's try to do things the
right way and build secure systems from
the ground up can we do this for small
systems think like quad rotors and then
work with Boeing to transition this to
large complex systems in this case
they're unmanned little bird which is an
optionally piloted helicopter so human
can fly around this helicopter it can
just fly on its own so what I want to do
is just tell you a bit give you a sense
of the story of you know how we went
about this so let me take you back to
the beginning of the program so is a
long program is about four years long
but at the beginning we knew we had to
address multiple airframes so quickly
moving from you know small auto pilots
to large military systems we were
developing four brand-new hardware's of
boards that we would be manufacturing
and as part of the program and we wanted
to be able to compile our applications
to multiple operating systems so for
example with in terms of the real-time
operating systems we used free are toss
which is a available art artists to do
some initial prototyping but in this
project we are working with Nick does
mention the morning keynote they
developed STL 4 which is a formally
verified microkernel which we also want
to target as they are developing it as
well as their verified artists called
Acronis so we need to target multiple
operating systems oh yeah develop a
fairly sophisticated autopilot so all
the application code develop a ground
control station to communicate with the
system with an embedded encrypted data
link and we wanted to also have some
properties about the system that we
could you know give to a red team for
example to say hey here are the claims
that we're making and we wanted to have
some architectural models to explain at
a higher
level what the system supposed to do in
terms of the the hardware and the
network buses and we were stuck in the
middle so developing this system and the
approach we took was one of building
domain-specific languages or DSL so that
we could generate from one from a family
of DSL the security properties the
architectural models and the software
and so this is what what at the end of
this this was given to a red team in an
iterative fashion and I'm kind of
spoiling the surprise but they said this
is a that it was free from the normal
defects that they found so I'm not going
to claim it's perfectly secure but it
was it was more hardened than any of the
other systems that they had looked at in
a bench to benchmark the kinds of
security that they see in these systems
is one government official remarked this
was the most secure UAV in the world
that we'd built and by the way we did
this in 18 months ok so what I want to
talk about is how we built via cells for
coaching this problem and so at Galois
we are big fans of functional
programming and in particular Haskell
and so we thought you know would it be
nice if we could do embedded programming
using the benefits of Haskell so you get
a powerful type system type inference
type checking it's a pure higher order
language without side effects and you
get the modularity and the composition
that that functional programmers have
come to know about and and love however
as I already mentioned you know I can't
fit a Haskell program on one of these
embedded microcontrollers and so you
know there's a couple options we could
consider one would be writing a whole
new language from scratch this would be
all kind of if you squint you could
think of Russ taking this approach and
when we began this project actually rust
was a pre 1.0 release so there's just
not the time to do that you know to
basically do a compile er development
from scratch the other approach would be
let's try to hack down the runtime
system but the runtime very little
secret of these functional languages
right like you know oh we've got all the
purity and then we've got 50,000 plus
lines of C or C - - sitting underneath
that functional language to implement
the runtime system and you know trying
to do that in in a short order and
guaranteeing correctness is just too
difficult so the approach we took was
one of building an embedded DSL or edia
so so the idea here is let me build some
Combinator's in my functional language
and this is going to implement my my
safe programming language and what this
will do is it'll generate safe embedded
C so the nice thing about taking this
approach this Eid ESL approach is that
your new language that you're designing
is just quote-unquote a library in
Haskell and you get a bunch of things
for free
I get type checking for free I get all
the syntax and parsing for free and most
importantly I get to use the the host
language Haskell as a type safe turning
complete macro language and I'll talk
more about that in a few moments so the
language we developed is something
called ivory embedded in Haskell and you
can think of it as a high-level
functioning program language for
low-level embedded systems and there's a
few features I'll draw your attention to
so one is it's you know effectively it's
a safe C language in embedded at Haskell
and specialized for embedded systems so
the primary there's a few trap doors but
the primary use it is you know sub
turing-complete
however the way we are able to get
usability as I mentioned is is this type
safe macro programming so I can kind of
fake turing-complete
programming at design time at compile
time by using Haskell and I'll give you
some examples and we've also got some
verification tool integration including
of symbolic simulation if you're
improving back-end facl - as well as
automated test case generation ok so let
me just give you a quick taste of the
language you know just so you can
concretely see what it looks like so
here is a loop that operates over an
array adding a value to each element in
the
Rea so first I'm going to show you the
type I've written it here explicitly but
there's actually type inference for free
so I didn't have to explicitly write
this and I've got a type level list and
it takes two arguments corresponding to
the two arguments that the function will
take so the first is a reference so this
is a not guaranteed null null pointer
with a type variable S which means the
allocation scope of the array in this
case it's a type variable means it could
be locally allocate or globally
allocated it takes it's a pointer to an
array with four elements and in each
element is a unsigned 8-bit value and it
takes another unsigned 8-bit value and
returns void so if we walk through this
in the implementation I have a lambda
binding that corresponds to the two
arguments the function will take if you
think of it as a CF function the array
and the value and then we have a
Combinator array map which maps over the
element so guarantees I can't walk off
the array and for each index it's going
to dereference a value this is
guaranteed mil-mil by type checking
dereference and then store a new value
there okay now as we you know did this
even even if you're a Haskell programmer
like if there's a lot to to lot to take
in there so one of the things we
realized especially one of the goals of
the program's to transition this to
engineer systems engineers who are not
Haskell developers we wanted a concrete
see like syntax so we developed a
concrete syntax over this where if you
squint it looks quite see like so here's
the same function again in a concrete
syntax and there's just a few
differences I'll call out so first of
all in C of course you know you pass in
the length of the array that you're
going to map over we'd have to do that
in the concrete syntax we still have
this map operation which which instead
of having a for loop over the array and
as I mentioned I've got different
allocation scopes and so I can decorate
a pointer and say this is for example
global allocation and this is really
important so
we started the program and did not have
a concrete syntax like this and we're
trying to throw this over the wall to
C++ developers at Boeing there's just no
way that they're going to be able to use
the language so but by doing this by
having us see like syntax we could throw
it over the wall and as far as they are
concerned this was basically you know a
strange C with different type errors and
some cool macros and so they are able to
basically rewrite many many thousands of
lines of codes rewriting their flight
controller and mission computer with
very little help from from us okay so
I've mentioned this idea of typesafe
macros a few times so let me just give
you an example so the the language
itself is very impoverished so for
example I in ivory there is just one
construct for doing control for for if
and else controls so there's no
conditional statements and so you can
have if you've got a lot of nested
if/then/else is it can you know if your
list programmer this might look familiar
but it can be quite cumbersome now one
of the benefits though is that the
developer because it's an embedded DSL
does not have to be stuck in the
paradigm of writing in with just the
operators that we provide so for example
a developer with just a literally four
lines of code can define a datatype cond
for conditional can define a couple of
smart constructors so here we've got a
fat arrow that returns something that is
equivalent to the data type and then
constructors over lists and what it will
do is construct new syntax in the
language and so ivory has not changed at
all but I'm able to now generate a much
more pleasing depending on your
perspective conditional expression that
is equivalent to the original without
having to bake this into the language
itself okay so here's a very simple
example a more complex example is one we
used in a developing sensor fusion so
automatic differentiation is that how
many people are familiar to automatic
differentiation programming okay
it's a you know a maybe underappreciated
but fairly ubiquitous approach to do
automatically computing differentiation
for programs that's neither symbolic
differentiation or new murica
proximation the idea is that it's that I
can automatically transform a program to
compute the differential using different
techniques and this is quite useful for
for writing programs that have to deal
with continuous dynamics so let me just
walk you very briefly through you know
forward automatic differentiation and so
the ideas I'm going to walk through a
program automatically transform it so
that I'm going to take variables and
replace them with pairs where I keep
track of the original value and the
differential with respect to that value
so as I there's a few rules so for
example you know to do addition on these
pairs I'm going to define an algebra so
I just do addition point wise for
multiplication I've got an expression
like follows where I multiply the
original values and then like you do in
differential calculus I'm going to take
UV prime plus the times u prime etc etc
for the arithmetic operations and so
like as a little example if I got f of x
equals x plus 2 times X plus 3 I can
transform it variable if I take that
derivative of the variable I get one
derivatives constants are zero and
follow the rules i I get there the
original value at plus the differential
the derivative okay so um what is all
this all mean well because in haskell
we've got type classes and which means i
can do operations as long as anything
satisfies those type classes in
particular so for example I've got a num
type class that tells me how to do
addition subtraction etc etc if I have
any instance of this including the ast
for the ivory language I can use these
operations for free so in Haskell like
in other languages automatic
appreciation has been defined and
because of this I can use these use the
libraries that compute these things for
free to automatically develop new C code
that that computes the derivative and so
the upshot of this is for example in
developing our inertial navigation
system we can write just a few hundred
lines of code for M in use these
techniques for example to compute the
Jacobian matrices which are used in the
column filters we developed so this just
to give you a taste of the ways we're
able to build these abstractions up
without having to bake them into the DSL
we could keep this smoke small and lean
allowing us to do things like static
analysis etcetera on the language and
and not have to extend it to a journal
purpose language okay um let's see so
what I'm going to do is I'm going to
just briefly talk but not go through in
detail given the time about the approach
we took to two concurrency so you know
this is all well and fine we can use
ivory developed to write our application
code for our individual threads in the
system whether it's on SEO for or on an
artist but um when you start looking at
the problem of all the glue code all the
inner procedure communication handling
interrupts we start running into all
this was written in handwritten and see
and it becomes a nightmare and this is a
problem even if we're developing on a
formally verified operating system so
you know if I'm writing everything by
hand on SEO for even you know the kernel
if you say I want to communicate between
two threads that shouldn't communicate
with each other it will perfectly let
you do that right so it's up to you to
have the right kind of specification
requirements and furthermore we want to
easily be able to port from from one
operating system to another so um we did
it this story is exactly the same we
built another DSL on top of ivory that
handled generating things like the IPC
and the glue code
to guarantee safe concurrency the
implementation uses a whore monitor
style approach and we can also do this
to generate architectural models so in
particular we generated models in the
ADL which is an architectural modeling
and design language which allows you to
do verification at the architectural
level right okay so I'm going to skip
through some of the examples of this and
let me skip here so with ivory in our
we've got a number of backends we uh
so targeting POSIX as I mentioned free
are toss and ADL and then we there's an
in-progress
target to the cell model checker and
through ADL we target Acronis and SEL
for which I mentioned were verified
operating systems and this is what we
called our trusted build which which we
used in the program and this tied in to
a larger story of analysis which I won't
go into of using various tools that are
developed and that are in the
open-source domain for doing things like
model checking at the architectural
level but also doing requirements
analysis so for example this resolute
tool allows you to develop a safety case
so I'm a I always have unform apportions
of my program that I want to be able to
talk about why I believe they meet the
requirements even if I don't have a
formal proof so by building a safety
case you stitch together the informal
with the formal ok so um this is just a
eye candy slide we took this our our
project on a road show
so this included probably being the
first UAV to fly the first pictures in
the courtyard of the Pentagon what we
learned there was that the most
important rule is do not step on the
grass at the Pentagon
and we also there was a briefing of this
on 60 minutes so here we are flying with
Lesley Stahl and there's Kathleen Fisher
in the in the foreground and as I
mentioned in the red team analysis they
were given all the code all the
requirements on all the specification
the hardware and two months to analyze
this and this is actually in
inter-process the main result they said
you know we cannot penetrate the network
in the vehicle and there's definitely
you know issues that they discovered so
things like for example we left a
debugging port open which you know if
you had physical access you could attack
I'm there's an unverified assertion so
we were especially brave for assertions
that we had not verified away a design
time we still provide left those in and
said you know please let us know if you
trigger Navy's so as I mentioned this is
much better than the baseline systems
that that have been that we're not
analyzed in both open-source and DOD
systems so I just want to end by giving
a couple kind of lessons learned from
this project so the first is is that you
know while this was a formal
verification project it's also a
research project and that was almost
that was at odds in some sense right so
you know we know how to write high
assurance code even without formal
methods it just takes a long long time
right but you know people are writing
code for the space shuttle before
there's static analyzers before there's
model checking and widespread use and
it's fairly bug free but you know you're
talking a a very much lower programmer
productivity and you know you can't
expect formal verification to magically
make the process go faster and let you
alive the other kinds of things to
improve your your sister system so um so
you know one of the things is that you
know if I'm developing around a verified
microkernel I need to make sure that the
rest of my system has a verification
story for it as well I can't just assume
that oh I verified this one little piece
and everything is going to be fine
and we need to do all the easy stuff in
addition to verification right
regression testing fuzz testing
continuous integration codes or code
reviews and so this is why you know I
build truly secure systems you can't
just just rely on formal verification
even though it's a critical part as
we've heard a number of times today we
need to do the other things like you
know one of the simple things that we
did which you know is filtering
filtering the the network communications
on this thing which has a huge effect so
originally for example in an open source
auto pilot
there was a convenience quote unquote of
allowing you to reflash the code over
the data link with the ground control
station which is you know really great
if you're developing by yourself and you
just want to you know you don't want
have to plug into the USB to reflash the
code but you know what anyone who has
access to that can do it even in flight
for example and you know also we need to
handle all the possible errors in the
interfaces tool integration this is an
unsolved problem you know there's
multiple tools and how do we pull them
all together to combine the analyses and
get a global view of a system is still a
very difficult problem and one that has
to be addressed and there's definitely a
number of things that you know we did
not I don't have a good answer to so you
know for example um this is a system
that is hovering above you with sharp
edges and when something goes wrong you
know you might you know five an IT
system and someone's attacking my my
server well I might just power it down
that's not going to work for a UAV
that's right you don't want to just
power it down so how do i gracefully do
a failover if there's a security
vulnerability discovered in real time or
I I'm under attack okay everything's
open source we've got a website for the
language and the autopilot so you can
build everything yourself and go fly and
with that I'm happy to take questions
thank you
[Applause]
so that's a good point
so in fact we did two different versions
one from a one from a ADL where that was
the the primary design language in the
other direction so in fact so it's our
language I glossed over as if you can
think of it as a Haskell version of a a
BIA which is morally equivalent one one
advantage of going the other direction
is that it enforced so because Tower has
tied has the same shares of type system
with ivory it guarantees that every time
you recompile your system I rebuild my
architectural model of the system and so
I wouldn't don't have this possibility
of my architectural model that I might
have done some nice formal analysis on
drifting apart from my compiled code so
that's one advantage of going that
direction okay
all right thank
[Applause]