okay thank you
so hello everybody we are care working
in the French MC so kind of like missed
at French and I work a killer cloud the
French hosting company we've been
working on passes and we're all here for
the kind of the same reasons and we've
trying to think about what what's the
relation between our tussles our memory
set languages everything the new code
and old code so I can write now right
production-ready code enrolled in or
Cameron whatever in safe languages and
it will be all right because it's
correct for memory point of view we have
good technique to write tassels we can
even use formal methods but does that
solve one problem is that a lot of the
code we use is actually legacy code
written in unsafe languages with bad
practices so most of the time that will
be written C or C++ with handwritten
authors most of the code will be a
highly code like when you see protocol
implementation that's not just a busser
nicely written in one place and then the
protocol implementation but some things
like this huge state machine where
everything is done by hand and it's
usually very hard to test really hard to
reflect on very hard to extract from the
program so we could try to rewrite the
Linux kernel all of our web servers SMTP
servers I'm trying to think like the PNG
jpg that leave all those thing like I
could spend my life on this it's not
it's not a good idea because this
project are usually very large the
codebase is old and hard to navigate and
even if it may be but in return it's
already performing its job there's a
huge domain knowledge in just like it is
imagine like
we want to rewrite we were talking about
dlc dlc is already an old project and
lots and lots of bugs have been fixed
lots and lots of techniques are there to
mangle like any format possible we if we
try to write all of this we will
introduce bugs and that's not something
we want so we want to avoid regressions
and we also want to avoid political
issues because if we try to rewrite
everything that means it's a whole novel
project and all of the developers must
learn a new language a new architecture
and they are already working on the only
greeting project with an architecture
that they familiar with most of the time
there will be a beast so it's already on
the free time so we want to reduce the
the cognitive load on the day listening
developer in projects in logistical
basis if you want to fix the security so
what we came up with is can we just try
to remove the unsafe part and replace it
with something but we've left the least
impact possible so for this we need a
few things first something that will you
may be safe because like if we try to to
go that way
we might want to avoid see and it's
issues we want language that can
interact well in we see so that can call
C code but can also be called by C code
we want something that will integrate
inside the software not something that
will wrap the the current application
and something that will be just right in
there if possible no garbage collection
we want don't want to inter introduce
pauses and we marginally we don't want
to mess with the allocation in C
applications because Moses I maybe there
will be a custom alligator or we in
embedded settings or we don't want to
have like our part of the application
that try to do too much with the
with the memory we were just guests
inside an existing program and last but
not least we want to be like fast enough
because most of the time C developer are
very specific specific about what they
they expect on a performance point of
view so maybe not the fastest thing but
at least in the same runs as C so rust
rust is kind of a good tool for that it
unloads memory every not under
everything for the memory point of view
for you so there's no garbage collection
like the compiler knows where to put a
malloc and free everywhere you don't
handle that and if you're in let's say
in the case that's not safe it will just
if not compile into just a tell you okay
there's an error there you have to fix
your type so the way you use memory it's
type safe it goes to two wigglin to make
sure that there will be no that erases
that all of the threads like they made
might only be one mutable reference to
anything at all like recently there's
been a grid framework for embedded the
multitasking has been that's been
released where you have privilege and
everything and the type system
guarantees there will be no data race
without mutex is everywhere so it kind
of really what can you so it's easy to
talk with C code it's easy to write
low-level code with the rock apish like
you can you manage memory very very
finely so you can just avoid a lot of
copies you would do in other languages
you can write a safe code if you want
the language will not stop you just it's
a contract between the compiler and you
you say okay when you have the unsafe
part you guarantee to the to the
compiler I know what I'm doing there and
assume that it will be okay we and check
the rest of the code most of the time we
can still make mistakes in there it's a
very very small footprint there's no
runtime no
you know anything and good community the
new language but it's it's getting there
so it's not enough to write safe passers
like this is the kind of thing people
would do with hundred and tassels in
rest like the the rest for the project
as a big list of trophy cases with a lot
of tassels returned by hand like this
finds a lot of tissue unchecked web
bonds access that kind of thing or
integer overflows or the unwrap which is
like I'm supposed to have value there so
I will just unwrap if it said instead of
checking it's already there and the
fozziwig Finder can in that case that's
why I wrote known a few years ago it's a
faster community of library that uses a
lot of macros in interest it's basically
every pastor is a function that takes an
input and returns an I result I resulted
in the name that contains ever highest
value and here's the remaining part of
the input or I have an arrow or I don't
have enough information to know if I can
pass so I return incomplete and maybe I
need more data
so the passes look like this this one is
kind of easy you apply alpha and digit
and return the result of alpha and it
will just generate pattern matching it's
just like branches if the first pastor
gets a result I could get a store the
result I get its remaining part a pass
it to the next cetera all of the codis
looks a bit like this when generated
well it looks more like this because
there are lots of things to do but most
of the time it's quite straightforward
so it's perfect metal like most of the
things we can expect there you can
handle zero copy passing because the
compiler will know that we when we will
return references from the input like I
have a large input I want to have just a
few bytes in the middle the compiler
will guarantee that the data is still
there still available when we return the
the result so it can be quite hard with
this design with dreaming in mind so I
said if the pastor has not enough data
it can tell you okay accumulate more and
come back later and it's made for reward
format like you can sometimes avoid the
good theoretical ideas and write an ugly
part and just plug it aside better
because most of the format's we see are
just bad design so there are lots and
lots of format available and now we see
how we can integrate that inside
existing application so to regather on
the negativity bear okay so we want to
try all claims in real world project so
project that has a many lines of code
that have constrained some performances
and stuff like that and we want to help
that make that first step towards
security it's important to show people
what has to be done correctly instead of
just blaming them from from writing
insecure stuff okay so we want to help
them improving things without breaking
all of this of their software so I'm
taking sericata as an example so ricotta
is a network idea so it's passing
network traffic at very high speed it
has to support lots of passes so we are
not talking about one or two but we are
talking about 100 of them it's heavily
multi-threaded and that a huge
constraint when you're writing a pattern
because you have to worry perfect code
and it has to do that too to pass a 10th
of the of gigabytes per second so we we
have to prove that it can work in real
life application and not only for small
examples so let's build a hardened sorry
Jana so this this is my version of the
hardened serger
I'll give you another view of the method
okay so we will try to isolate Christian
function we want to rely on the existing
code we want to avoid rewrite
the helper functions of the program
itself we want to use them the login
function the detection function and so
on and we want to keep performances and
thread safety mode mostly so we've done
that on several protocols I just used
here lesson as an example it's a good
example of an important protocol that
almost every single implementation is
wrong so I'm not like claiming mine is
wrong but as I'm only implementing
detection well it's not so bad but still
we want to avoid memory issues right so
yeah also I'm the one who wrote the
previous implementation in c at the time
i was thinking i could do that correctly
so now I know so the methodology is to
read a few RFC so if you're jet-lagged
it's it's a good way to solve the
problem you try to read all them and
then you start from this specification
which are done like that and you try to
first define the structures okay so we
define the structures in rust here I did
the higher level structures I have not
defined all of the protocol but only the
higher level and for example we don't we
pause only the server hello but not the
extensions inside so we pass only the
first layer of the of the packet then
we'll declare the the structure we write
the pattern so this is the actual passer
for the server hello so I I think it's
rather small and thanks to Nam and
thanks to rust it is a memory safe and
it also adds all the error checking code
which is really really important that
usually where parsers written in a safe
language fail you have to check every
single failure that can happen for
example incomplete reads here all of the
code is completely tested for every
single possibility of error
so once you did that you returned the
structure so the actual code is only the
two third lines because the two last
lines are because you only returned the
structure then you refine the parser as
I said we've not DTLS extensions so
let's now declare the extensions and
then instead of talking the a slice
which is a buffer in the first level
structure will now return a vector of
TLS extension which we can see in in the
last line and if we do that on an all we
just implement the full protocol having
a very simple implementation that works
at every time so it's a very easy way
very fast way to develop parser and and
to do that in a memory safe way once
you've done that well it's not enough
because TLS is a kind of protocol you
you encounter in real life that is a
stateful protocol meaning you have to
know which stage you are to know how to
pass the next packet and I'm really
talking about packet so this is one
keyless state machine because there are
as many as implementations in fact the
specification did not specify the state
machine but we've been trying to think
about how to specify that in a way that
is easy for developers to write and to
ensure that you can verify that the
statement state machine is correct
so the state machine is simply an inner
ocean of possible states and we've
decided to implement it as a simple
enumeration of matches which is you just
compare the old state and the new
message and given that you end up in a
in the new state so the entire kls state
machine which is usually almost 1,000
line of C code now fits in 270 lines of
roast code right so it's not only a bit
better but if you look at the last line
all of the error 'invalid transitions
are handled in just one case so I think
it's pretty nice and for example the
evolution to TLS 1.3 was really simple
writing that way so this is only the
first step right we we write a parser we
need to test it so let's try to see if
we if you be testing correctly and why
is it important it's important because
the first question if you want to
replace something in existing code the
first question people will ask you is
that it works exactly the same way as
before so you have to prove equivalents
in tests of in terms of performance and
in terms of functionality so we'll use
two tools for that we'll use benchmark
communities well benchmarks I won't go
well I won't detail that because you
know the the method just know that for
example in the specific case of TLS I've
achieved being I mean between five and
ten percent longer than the C code so
there is only a very small difference
which is I think a good result but after
performance you have to use unit tests
so when declaring you a unit test you
just declare well what you expect
you just part later and then you just
compare to one useful tip is to use the
project existing unit test sorry cat has
a lot of unit tests that are embedded in
the code I just wrote a single layer
that can extract this unit test and
already use them for the parser to test
security well mostly there are two ways
I won't detail it because details are in
the paper manual Shaikh we did
disassemble all the ir and assembly code
generated to verify that some properties
are in and there are some missing
properties and some are here and we use
fading because fading the great way to
first cover to explore the possible path
so to get maximum coverage of your code
and also to catch unexpected panic and
kind of debug code you insert in your
puzzle when developing it and you forget
to remove it only expected stuff so the
tools where you know reading tool these
these ones are based on a little Adler
and AFM they are available for us and
now that we have process one problem is
how do we integrate them into the main
program so I'll draw a describe that so
I'll click VLC as example so lots and
lots of puzzles in there it's basically
a call that's a big event loop and then
a few plugins that are each their own
dynamic library the idea was to write a
dynamic library in rust with exactly the
same API so it exports a few functions
registers canonical bugs when talking to
VLC and then we just plug that inside
the vehicle design should work the idea
is that we must interact with the C code
so we must have the same functions the
same structures and everything so we
have to take that kind of C code that's
kind of object like C good idea maybe
and write read structure so we can have
structure that can match exactly memory
the ones we have in C so it's very
useful to do it's a bit concerned to
write but we have tools for that this we
must have a way to export functions from
the C code we can write safe wrapper
Saudis so the function takes a pointer
under and I manipulate by slashes which
our structure with a pointer and grant
but I don't have to manipulate that
directly in my Roscoe rosemon joined the
tool I can automate most of the
conversion from C to rust
versa also have a rest each other we can
generate C header from rest code and
exported function delivering
so the first ID we make a small posture
for FLV files so the pleasure
you stuffed just the header and this is
one of the function that's used in VLC
and during the plug-in so it emulates a
C function let me get the D max
structure and then it will read a bit of
the data past it and then tell VLC okay
now we go there in the file from here to
there you have your your decoding data
and everything so it does not own the
data it's just a guest inside a C
program even if it could do somethings
better than C we're not there to replace
all of the business logic just a small
part to integrate it's kind of easy in
fact you can make an object file with
the res compiler and just plug that
inside the director of the build system
we could make a library but lick tool
wants to tell us that Gil knows better
how to make a library I disagree but
whatever it was easier that way for
sericata
we made the knockout file and you can
just link that inside the project so
Russ it kind of makes it easy to connect
the rest part inside the C code just we
plug with the the interface where we
import and then we plug this in the B
system and so I will let PR go to
conclude well so this is just another
view but the details again are in the in
the paper so to sum up we encourage
writing stand alone and isolated process
because that not only simplifies
verification that also makes them
reusable in other projects as well so
this would help building referenced
answers that could be correct so first
you write process but that's the easy
part
once you have thousands you integrate
them so you have to write a small
abstraction layer and when your puzzles
are reusable you just if you want to use
them in another project you just write
another abstraction layer which should
be as sane as possible so isolating and
safe api is also a great thing because
for code reviewing you just well it's
just like the unsupported just na
work with a red light so we just have to
look at unsafe code let that's great for
reviewing and once you've done that you
just have to replace the person the
project hoping that you won't break
everything and and that's nice but
really the nicest result of this
methodology was not only to write safe
passes the the well one of the most
important result is that writing parser
becomes way faster the the first answer
we had to wrote was a bit slower maybe
because we had we had to define the
interfaces learn the language and so on
but the second one were really fast
really quick writing and no more sexual
you spend less time in gdb well that's
great so the feedback from other people
I've been for example trying to convince
other people to try that themselves so
the biggest difficulties are not
technical it's just trying to convince
them to use the tool to try them and
also see people especially doesn't like
first because it's a straight language
but it it's for their own good I mean
strong typing well readability can can
be hard sometimes it's just like
learning a new language so you can find
the product on these links the codes
will be integrated upstream very soon
it's just being discussed and that's
great for them because they want to try
something and that's also a good result
from the methodology I mean we've been
trying with succeeded in convincing them
to evolve from their previous code to
adding security by small steps into the
new code and bringing it more and more
and more and that's great so to conclude
we'd say that well it's time to do
better it's time to really change things
I really agree with the the keynote it
was really it's very important to change
things right now we have to to make them
something and we also try to encourage
building a community around safe parsers
and around safe code if we had
referenced also that could be used in
other languages and rust can be used in
other languages if we could build a
library of sales process we'd make them
available for more people and maybe
they'll change their own tools to just
use them instead of writing them again
and again so thank you for your
attention we'll go to questions if you
have some
[Applause]
being able to safely run
HTTP so there are already a lot of
project to the web servers interest I'm
walking on the reverse proxy and I've
spent like most of the day
studying the HTTP parser that was really
numb it's still holding apparently then
it's I think it will be more useful for
the libraries because we could like find
a way to make a library that's API
compatible with existing c1 you can just
replace that one key point here is that
we we don't rewrite the entire project
and that is way easier for making it
accepted by developers yep state machine
that was really absolutely disgusting
and with a much more systematic much
nicer representation one of the things I
feel that this difference is quite
stunning one of the things that I'm
thinking about in the background is
whether we're also as a lot of shotgun
state machines in our car because there
are lots of instances in which you know
you take an enormous horrible hairball
and
it really what it is concealing is a
small much more easy to add a lot of
state machine micelle there's a
professional language paper two years
ago yeah so the question here is whether
whether raise it formalizing state
machines being much bigger
representations it is that you will do
the to the formalization languages and
generated and anger that in business
looks like a beautiful example yeah the
issue is real I totally agree I showed
the best part because sometime here you
have to match the content of the packet
to decide on the next set so it's not so
easy to completely describe in a very
formal way at least I've not thought
very long about that so I surely missed
a theory or good representation on that
this was just a intuition I mean that's
just the first code I wrote on the on
this specific state machine and it just
proved to be quite easy enough I just
removed in fact the some of the keywords
just to make it fit on one slide but
that's exactly the distribution and yes
we need to work also on state machine
because not only the parsing is a very
sensible problem the state machines in
clients or servers for example are
really often badly implemented so
sometimes we've been trying to fill the
state machine and achieve good results
especially in calais
University certainly there's I left
come on take em up it no thank you
[Applause]