please join me in welcoming our to
Deloitte Argentina speakers
Valentina Palestine and Ruth Barbra
still show you how to build your own
first we are going to go to what exactly
the library then we are going to cover
how to build one cheese pickle it about
the problems that we encounter and
finally we are going to end with some
lessons we learned that you can take
with you but first I'm going to talk a
little bit about our backgrounds so Ruth
is that a library team project leader
she started with the project around
almost four years ago she is an
information security specialist an
information system engineer and myself I
have a background in translation
so I contributed the project around for
two year almost few years now with 30
helping with the editorial process and
I'm also using my programming skills to
help me automation and data analysis a
little bit about what why we came out
with this project when I first started
in cyber threat intelligence one of my
first tasks was to collect indicators of
compromise from public sources this was
a really exhausting job it was really
messy but we learn a lot about in the
way and now is luckily everything is
scripting so now we don't have to do
that anymore but we learn a lot in this
process so one of the things that we
have to do in those extra spreadsheet
that we use for a indicators collection
was to describe the malware that we were
a conducting indicate indicators from so
what is interesting about this is that
the description often mixes were where
the
were there adductors and the campaigns
and pivoting through this data was
really difficult if I wanted to know
what other and malware pieces were using
a 3dr it was really difficult for me to
do that so one day we were with Shay
blog and we were talking with the
director of sensor intelligence team
which is susana Martinez and he and me
we were just thinking about how we can
improve the information that we were
already collecting but showing in an
interesting way that you can acquire in
an easy way
so this is how the library started but
what it seems to be like the solution to
all of our desires and needs may that
end up destroying us if we don't do it
well so let's start a little bit
managing the expectation of a process of
this kind so it's not a solution by
itself the project is meant to be for
analysts so they can dig into data
regarding the threat vector Sigma in an
easy way but they are the the main thing
thinkers about what the output is going
to be also this is not a collection of
all existing attacks there is too many
information there is too many things
happening out there so we focus only on
highly targeted attacks and focusing on
industries on which the load has clients
on this is also not an indicator field
you may find some indicators but it's
not meant to be as a field for a stock
or something like that it's only to
check the information and validate the
information that we are ready putting in
the page and also extracting some useful
things that can be helpful for a threat
hunting it's also not perfect people
that is writing the reapers that we are
consuming is people we are people so we
are prone to errors and we are not
perfect so we can't we have to put a
workflow which includes the Quality
Assurance to be able to put the most
information that we can in the most
meaningful way and it's also not fixed
in time because think how this is the
way as Frankenstein monster information
it's alive so what to do aspect of a
project of this kind is to have our
normalize and catalog
information so you can't find
information that you are trying to spot
in a particular specific place of the
report also you can see this as an
activity Journal we have a key
observables for each one of these
threads we gather a lot of operations of
the apt so this is a way that we can see
the evolution of them and also the idea
is to have all in one place so you don't
have to worry and go through a multiple
sources and dig through a lot of
information because we already done that
for you
so when we started with this we we are
seeing this huge monster which is a
composed of bullet resources private
spin-offs in services naming conventions
and a lot of things that overwhelm us
and we feel really tiny again against
this huge monster some of the issues
that we came across we are still
struggling with and we are not going to
to get rid of them sooner but we have
observed a lot of diverse formatting and
distribution of the information even for
one organization they have different
formatting a between a one report and
another so you don't find the
information always in the same place
also we observe a lot of overlapping and
attribution so we can't really validate
because we have a lack of context or
indicators and evidence of what they are
reporting on and that is really
difficult for us to put a confidence
level on that but this makes us feel
really like we are going to be crushed
by stress and fatigue but don't worry we
are not going to die moving forward with
this Indiana Jones analogy with some
time thing like being a very intelligent
al aliy analyst is a little bit of like
going through a jungle of information
open our way with the blade and finding
ancient data trying to dig and find the
treasure in it so what to do to not get
swamp a barrier but all that that huge
ancient information so what we do is to
follow a structure pretty similar to the
one mightor
using the webpage we distinguish the
banks and we kind of organize them into
AG against what are the industry they
hit mostly based on Deloitte's
industries of interest we also relate
them with the threat actors and with the
tools and we use the attack framework to
identify the tools the tools tactics
techniques and procedures well let's
talk a little bit what you will find
when you get into the shredder library
so the first thing we do is to our offer
all the campaigns around the day they
happened or if we don't have that
information at around the day they were
released we also try to follow the same
structure for all the titles we try we
will like to be able to see at a glance
the apt involve what was the target
could be the industry the country or
even an entity and with what and we find
that this structure is pretty useful
when you are doing analysis and also
when you are trying to prioritize or our
European process then when you get into
one incident this is like the scorecard
so you can see the campaign period the
release date a confidence level also
which regions country down industries
were affected and a little summary about
the incident and then if you don't like
enough and there's some information
about the victims like in the other case
this other case well you will see that
to you and we follow sticks terminology
to classify the campaign's according to
the intended effects behind them and
finally we provide a brief description
of the associated actor and a link to
the threat actor page then all these
scorecard is followed by what we call
the main information and the main
information is a structure in three
sections the first one is the initial
access section in which we try to
publish everything related to how the
threat actor gainful whole into the
victim system we provide
and also the files that were used
information about the files that were
used and a list of all the tools
involved with the description and a link
to the tool page also after that we
provide a technical description about
the campaign
finally the page closes with what we
call the analysis attribution at
geolocation information so for example
we put there if we have something that
could be meaningful to you know where
the shreditor is located or if there's
are similarities with other campaigns or
other groups and in the last section
which is the analysis we gather all the
information related to why the
attribution was made or it wasn't made
and also when we can we also provide our
own assessments about the incident we
call it those because it's not only my
word they are also legitimate tools
being abused for this kind of stuff but
we are following some some patterns
similar to the attack software pages but
we added a couple of additional things
we added a description and a details in
the details we put a specific technical
stuff that they are using in that
specific campaign and we put a column of
campaign on which that Manoir was seen
and was reported so we do this because
we think that is the best way to a spot
when a procedure is changing when a
procedure is is changing the way that
the technique is being applied so you
can further understand how the traductor
is evolving we are also adding
information regarding the indicators
that we seen in those campaigns mainly a
network and file-related but this again
is not an indicator field this is only
to validate information that we are
really putting there and to also further
extract characteristic that may be
helpful in hunting after reporting for
three actors talking about having all in
one side in one page I think that this
is the most clear way to see it the
three actors has interesting scorecards
in which
we put all the things that we think that
are really important to spot at first
which are the affected regions countries
and industries but we also try to
understand what are the traductor types
if there are state sponsor if there are
a cybercrime actor also the
sophistication level of these reactors
and the motivations behind it and to do
this we follow again the sticks of
vocabulary because we want to use the
same language across all the industry
and if you seen the right part of the
screen you're going to see the content
table one of the things at the bottom
are the tool set and campaigns which are
just a summary of the to stand campaigns
that we are already mentioned but you
can see everything that it's related to
this sector and people to the data and
we have also a part of relevant
information this is done because
sometimes we find information that it
can't be fit in any of these sectors
that we already mentioned or we can't
link them with a specific campaign but
we think that it's really important
information to have for example you can
see there we have the zero they will
really teach us by abt 28 and then it
says point of entry why okay so when we
started this project we thought that
understanding the initial food whole on
the factors that did in the organization
was really important to our clients
but the tactic initial access leading
assist at the time so we came up with
this point of entry tactic and then when
I attack added to it with abrogate that
one honesty stick with the framework now
that we talk about what and the how
let's talk a little bit about the
problems we encounter so for sure the
most difficult to identify our the
fulfil flag campaigns the analysis bias
we have to remember that we work mostly
with Western sources we'll try to do
otherwise sometimes but it's difficult
and time-consuming and also we have to
carry with our own bias too and also the
misattribution because I saw Bruce
mention sometimes a report general have
information about what why and
attribution was made or they don't have
indicate of compromise that we can
download to carry out our know on our
analysis but remembering that we are all
humans there are other things that
sometimes we spot and we have some
examples to show you these are some that
hit us in some way or another so we
identify and we're going to share with
you for example in this case we find
that allegedly there was a threat actor
target in Argentina so we were really
curious because just our area of work so
we went there and it turned out that
actually what happened was that
indicators were uploaded for by our
research team so it's it's important to
remember that not all the time where
where our file is uploaded is that it
means that the attack is happening there
but I'm sure this reduction is going to
hit us sooner rather than later
another thing we find problematic and
this is especially tricky one yes we
cannot know it all and the people that's
published in the report neither asked
some sometimes we find things that if
you can't be the other side thick thank
you like disk in this case which is
referring a phishing campaign that
happened a long time ago
so some beautiful soul found and the
Spanish expression which is actually an
swearing which is pronounced like which
I do mother
so now we can stir it like an
Argentinian but this beautiful soul
translated as the shell of your mother
which is durable but is
but it's not exactly that as a clean set
meaning would be something like your
mother private parts and why why we are
talking about it why we are showing you
this well if we go to this map there are
20 countries in which Spanish is spoken
officially and I'm stressing officially
because there are more countries in
which Spanish is spoke but from those 20
that expression is used only in seven
countries and we know this observable is
now enough on itself to assure that the
three lecture comes to from these places
but maybe we have another indication
indicators that we can add up to you to
say well it's from here and especially
considering that we have a fairly thread
actor fairly active trade actor on the
region and finally really we left the
biggest headache for last which is the
overlapping attributions that it's the
way we call a multiple name and for the
same fair actors so the way we dealt
with this is to create something similar
to the attack matrix for tactics and
techniques but with benders and aliases
I'm sure you all really want to see it
but I'm not going to show you that it
takes a lot of work it takes a lot of
research at really complex and refine
work so we have to especially mention
one of our team members Francis even now
that couldn't be here with that that we
need him Freddy this you
he's helping it along with it and what
also do you is to steer a the sources so
we find a way to Rae the sources
consider considering its type
also the using the matrix we raid the
vendors according to the best
miscibility by region based on public
reports remember we are always talking
about public reports also we rate in the
independent researchers by the
reputation and also we judge
the is the search has a you see so big
levels to carry out our own analysis but
even though having a formula is awesome
and we encourage everyone here to come
up with your own formula to do this it
is important to remember that you need
to be able to overrule it as you see fit
when necessary I want to teach you how
to read The Book of Secrets so let's
keep in mind when you're reading a
source you have to identify if they are
reporting about a threat actor a
campaign or a malware piece or maybe a
combination of those in this case we're
going to focus only on what our malware
reports because we are going to struck
the TTP's from those first I want to do
to read the source and identify the
paragraph describing the behavior I
think if someone was yesterday they did
a CT I CT I training here that was great
and they explained this in a pretty neat
way but you have to it's basically the
same the same process you have to read a
source identify identify the paragraph
they are describing their behaviors and
then you can move and identified the
tactic think just one second we have
already a attack has a 266 only
Enterprise techniques and only 12
tactics so clearly identifying the
tactic is going to be much easier than
aspiring the technique once we have the
tactic that it belongs to we can't go
through the attack navigator for example
and look for all the techniques that
fits in under that a specific tactic and
being able to spot what are the
description and the technique that
belongs to the description but you can
maybe don't find what you are searching
for and in that case you should create
your own so let's move to a couple of
examples of this this is a piece of
malware that the threat director is not
really using a lot of evasion but they
are using a Ballack certificate to sign
on this malware piece so this is clearly
a defense evasion technique and under
the defense evasion we can find a lot of
techniques but there is a specific
technique that suits the specific
description of this which is the
code-signing technique okay so we can
see it's saying the same the signing
certificate to emasculate the malware
and make it appear as legitimate so it's
clearly this technique that we are
trying to spot we have another example
with a little bit more tricky in this
case this is a local Gaga abstract of
the report and in this case the three
lectures behind the smile were are
changing the default the credentials of
the illustrator accounts so the users
can't access to their system they can
work of course they can even read the
ransom note and have it adjust to pay
which we don't recommend at all but this
is clearly an impact tactic at the time
that we were writing this this
presentation we couldn't find any
technique that suits under this a
specific description so we came out with
our own in this case we are going to use
the naming convention of a attack on 0 1
which is our first technique rated you
should do the same you should stick with
one specific format so you don't get
lost and also we put a clear description
of the name so you can understand more
or less what we are trying to saying
with that technique but week ago I talk
other this technique and with our name
so now we can duplicate this one and we
can stick with the taxonomy that they
are using and stick with the framework
and move on so now that we talked about
what and the how and the problems let's
summarize everything with some lessons
we live that you could benefit from
first just that good technology to build
on think that information again
information it's alive the framework is
constantly evolution it is changing and
it has to be that way so the platform
you're going to use must support this
kind of evolution and this kind of
changes also do not misunderstand the
objectives again there is a lot of
information and a lot of attacks going
on so you have to understand that you
don't have unlimited resources you have
to focus on something so it's not
collecting everything again in our case
we are specifically trying to cover what
our highly targeted attacks against the
industries on which we have clients all
really important is to define good
quality work clips so think about this
poor display content a percentage
content is the same and not content
presented at all so what we do is we
have a simplified version of the datoria
process so first someone goes into
production and creates a report after
example extracts the tactics and the
technique then someone else review it
and maybe it could add something some
maybe they're the producer forgot a
technique or missed something the
formatting is not right and then we will
be sent back to production until until
it's it's sufficiently good enough to go
to the proofreader which will be the
final set of eyes that will review it
the older content before it gets
approved and it will be accessible to
the client so sticking with good
presented content it's important that
you should all be choosing a taxonomy
and is sticking with it in arc for
example if you want we call thread
actors but miter uses adversary's and
you may want to call cyber actors or
enemies if you're actually it's your
choice but the important thing is that
you are not changing between terms in a
whimp
so in our case we chose sticks for
vocabulary and we structure all our
content around the attack framework also
it's important to think how the
information is going to be consumed we
learned this the hard way so when we
started our first reports were really
messy and complicated to go through but
then when Valentina join she really
helped us to put a template and a
structure for the information so now all
the reports are really easy to
understand and are really easy to spot
the important information that you are
after and also think about how all the
information on the Internet
your collecting can be transformed into
more information so you probably may
want to know which are the most active
red actors in a specific region maybe
the most targeted industries or maybe
what are the most used techniques for a
specific country or maybe you want to
only know what were the most used
technique in periods of time so having
that in mind will allow you to
understand better how to structure the
data and also about just like a summer
of everything you have to think what
that is really really really important
to be consistent part before finishing
we want to thank all the thread library
team members that couldn't be here with
us but it wouldn't be the project
wouldn't be possible without their help
we also want to think the attack team
Katy Adam Blake Debbie and all the
people behind my tag for all their
support collaboration and well thank you
all for listening to our presentation
and if you have any questions you can
ask or you can hit us with our social
media
[Applause]