- [Announcer] Please join me
in welcoming Richard Struse.
- Idea guy, yikes, yikes.
So thanks all, thanks
all for sticking with us.
Before I get into the meat of my talk,
I just wanna do three
shout outs for some folks
who have done an amazing job today.
First, our gracious host, Katie Nichols,
I think she's done a fabulous job.
(audience applauding)
Second, our soon to be
on the Today show anchor,
Jamie Williams, wherever Jamie is.
And third, maybe a little less visible,
but definitely very
important and much loved
is Adam Pennington
manning the tweet station.
So I just wanna sort of reward
you for sticking through
with something that's really
gonna be easy to digest,
I unfortunately have no cat
memes, no magic unicorns,
no ninja cats, but I do really wanna talk,
step back a little and
think about what it is
when we start to think about
threat informed defense,
what does it really mean and really
what's our call to action.
So I really think if this is about action,
this is a community made
up of practitioners.
This is a community made up of doers.
So I'm the idea guy, in
quotes, standing up here.
I'm exhorting you to
action and it's really
kind of an easy job because you all embody
such an amazing spirit of can-do.
And whether it's Olaf and
what he was talking about
or Alan Wischiff talking about, John
what he was talking about,
it's just an amazing
amount of energy and that's great,
but how do we focus and challenge that?
So about a year and a half ago I started
using this term, maybe
it was two years ago now,
of threat informed defense.
And it's not a new
idea, and maybe I wasn't
the first person to even
actually use this term.
But to me it was helpful,
you are all practitioners
of threat informed defense,
whether you call it that or not.
But I thought there was
some value in actually
putting a name to it, to actually help us
as a discipline start to
understand and communicate
better with each other, and
also help people understand
the value and the extent
of what we're doing
because it really is a
different paradigm, right?
Gary in his remarks earlier
today did a nice job
of talking about the evolution
from sort of a vulnerability
centric model to the world we're in today,
at least in this room, and
there's a lot of people
who still need to catch
up and that's part of what
my message is gonna be.
But you've seen that great
shift from vulnerability centric
and if you're fully
patched you're good to go
to an understanding
that that's not enough.
So threat informed defense
is that recognition
that just understanding
what your assets are,
just understanding that your
vulnerabilities are patched,
just understanding what
your configurations are
is critical, it's necessary,
but it's not sufficient.
One of the cautionary notes
when I go talk to groups
of people about ATT&CK and
threat informed defense,
I often try to be really, really clear.
And I'd ask each of you to
do this 'cause I see you all
as ambassadors of this
community, and that is
ATT&CK and threat informed defense is not
some sort of Panacea, it's
not some magic pixie dust
you can sprinkle on an
otherwise insecure environment
and make it all the sudden better.
If your environment has
single factor domain
administrator passwords, you have a flat,
unsegmented network
architecture, you have any,
you don't understand what your assets are,
you don't need ATT&CK, you
need some basic cyber hygiene
and a lot of other things.
Once you're at that
level of sophistication,
once your tall enough to ride that ride,
then and only then are
you ready to actually
start to go to that next
level, to really start
to get inside the
adversaries decision loop
and figure out how to be
there waiting for them
before they get there.
So it's a critical message.
So when you're talking
to colleagues and friends
and coworkers and they
say, "Oh, I think I need
"the ATT&CK thing," just make sure
that they're really ready.
Just make sure that they
really are tall enough
to ride the ride because
the last thing we wanna do
as a community is to
turn into a hype machine
and sort of a self-perpetuating
motion machine
where we just talk to each other
about how awesome ATT&CK is.
And I think it's awesome, but I think
we have to be really responsible.
So threat informed defense
is about taking the things
in ATT&CK and beyond
and using that knowledge
systematically, and that's
I think the key word
to understand and prioritize and define
our defenses, one of
the interesting things
that if you ask me what are the primary,
what's the primary use case of ATT&CK,
you know, and we could talk
about coverage assessment,
we could talk about adversary emulation,
we could actually number
one is communication.
I think ATT&CK fundamentally
is a communications tool.
It's a way of thinking
about and describing
and talking about what
adversaries are doing,
what you're doing in response
to those adversaries,
what a product can do,
what your red team did,
what your blue team found,
and it's such a simple idea,
but that's where the brilliance is, right?
It's a brilliantly simple
concept and I think,
you know, just the size of this community
and the acceleration of the
adoption of the ATT&CK framework
is testimony to the
brilliance of that simple idea
that we've created here
just a few years ago.
And so this is really the point.
The fact that I can color a square,
pick out a puzzle piece, and
I hope you all appreciated
the puzzle we had out there.
And have a unambiguous,
concrete, tangible conversation.
Again, simple idea, but really powerful.
So, in this world of
threat informed defense,
is coloring in those
squares to mean the things
that are meaningful to you
in whatever context it is.
And so that's the other
great thing about ATT&CK
is it can be used in so
many different context
and so many different ways.
And any time you have
a tool or an approach
that can be repurposed
and reused so many times,
all the sudden it becomes
worth the investment.
And I think that's the other
thing we're seeing here.
That ATT&CK has proven
to be a great investment
for individuals and for organizations.
So, is Shane Stiger here?
So Shane did an amazing thing
some number of years ago.
He created a game, basically
modeled around ATT&CK.
And when I saw this game
board, so literal game
with like literal pieces and
I was so blown away by it
and that sort of inspired
me to start thinking about
ATT&CK as a game board, right.
And if I'm an adversary and
I'm looking at this game board,
and from my perspective as an adversary,
green means that I can land on that spot,
I can safely move from that
spot, I can do what I want
from that spot.
I wanna play this game, right?
I wanna play this game every day
because it's a low cost, low risk,
low uncertainty environment.
And the unfortunate reality is,
this is the game adversaries play.
I'm sure not in any of your
organizations, or here,
but in far too many places throughout
critical infrastructure
and our supply chains,
and certainly small and
medium size enterprises,
and even some larger enterprises,
this is the game board
that the adversary sees.
Don't you wanna play this
game if you're the adversary?
So, that's something
that must change, right?
If we wonder why we are
always playing catch up
as a community, I would argue
that that's one of the reasons.
Because the adversary
has so much room to move,
so much freedom.
And they get to choose the time and place,
they get to move wherever they want.
So if we recognize that must change,
we should start thinking
about this as a game, right?
We all like to play games, games are fun.
It's not work.
So how do we start as a community,
and we're already doing this
today, but how do we really
provide focus to our
efforts to begin to change
the rules of this game, to
take those safe landing spots
off the game board for the adversary?
It's not something we're
gonna do overnight.
And if any of you think
you can do it overnight,
please come talk to me later.
But it's something that
we can and should do,
we must do, our imperative,
our call to action
is that we must begin
to remove these spots.
We have to do it every week.
We have to do it every month,
we have to do it every quarter,
we have to do it every year
and we have to continuously be working
to get to the point where that's all red.
Now, are we ever gonna
get there, probably not.
But if you're an adversary,
do you wanna play this game?
Not nearly as much as that first one.
Can we go back to the first game?
'Cause this is, from an
adversary perspective,
a high cost, high risk,
high uncertainty environment
where most of the time the stuff you try
doesn't work, when it does
work, you're then beginning
to question, did this work because
my victim wanted it to work?
Am I in some sort of
deception environment?
You start to be able to
play with the adversary
and manage the adversary.
That's the world we need to be in,
that's the world I believe we can be in
if we continue the great
work that this community
has been doing, if we accelerate that work
and provide focus to that work.
So again, I wanna be clear,
we're not gonna get here
tomorrow, we're not
gonna get here next year.
But we can certainly all work to start
to move in this direction.
We must be as relentless as the adversary.
Adversaries, they don't
give up, they're advanced,
they're persistent, and
they represent a threat.
We have to be just as persistent.
We have to be advanced,
persistent defenders, I guess.
Guts, please don't turn
that into an acronym.
That's a meme.
But, as important as it is
for us to be relentless,
I think the more important
point is that we have to do this
together and again, the great news,
is that this is a testimony to the fact
that we are already doing
this as a community.
I just came back, as Katie mentioned,
I came back from Luxembourg
in the European ATT&CK
workshop last Friday, and
it was a really great,
sort of a similar idea,
group of community members,
all practitioners, talking
about how they're applying
ATT&CK in their environments.
How they're using it to actually improve
the state of their
defenses on a daily basis.
So we're already doing
this as a community,
we just need to do more
because the threat is real
and the adversaries aren't going away.
So, from my perspective,
we have an opportunity
to bring the best security
teams around the world,
and you folks I think are great examples
of those best security
teams from around the world.
Whether you're parts of
large financial institutions
or global manufacturers,
or health care concerns,
or IT security companies, or
professional services firms,
or ISACs and ISADs, whatever you are,
you represent sort of the
tippy top of the pyramid
of organizations and
individuals who have the skills
and the insights and the
resources and sophistication
to actually begin to make a difference.
And then it's no surprise or coincidence
that we're here at MITRE, which, you know,
for over 60 years has been
this trusted, objective,
independent, non for profit,
place where deep thoughts
are thunk and then good
things happen as a result.
And we believe that if we can bring these
best security teams from around the world
together with the kinds
of folks that you've been
hearing from from MITRE
over the last day and half,
that we can actually begin to execute
on research and
development that will begin
to deliver impact at scale
that's in the public interest.
So that's really what my
focus has been of late
is how do we take those community members
who have the ability and the resources
and the time and the
expertise and the commitment
to the public interest to
try to focus our efforts
so that we can deliver impact at scale.
So, threat informed defense,
where do we go from here?
What I can tell you today is stay tuned.
Some time in the next few
weeks you'll be hearing
some more announcements from us about
some of the really concrete
actions that we're taking
to move this community forward.
If you're interested in the meantime,
please come find me later on
or you can always reach me
via email, but I wanna leave
you just with this thought.
We can actually change
the game on the adversary.
We can actually, I can foresee a day,
maybe it's not tomorrow,
maybe it's not next year,
where we're actually
inside the adversaries
decision loop, where we're
actually beginning to win
the battles, if not the war.
So let's all keep doing what you're doing,
let's keep this community
going, and let's remember
to be as relentless as our adversaries.
Thank you.
(audience applauding)