thank you so today I will first talk
about caches so some general
introduction then I will short very
really briefly talk about cache attacks
and after that about row hammer
especially rohan Egeus so let's start
with sketches right away of course I
speak about CPU caches I'm I work on
micro architectural attack so here
caches always means CPU caches the idea
of CPU caches is that the CPU speed
always increases so you have moves law
and the DRAM latency doesn't reduce in
the same amount to the same amount so we
get the problem that we have a
bottleneck here the DRAM is slow the
solution is we introduce smaller
memories inside the CPU earlier they
were externally but now they are inside
the CPU and also we have different
caches that are in of a different size
and have different speed properties if
we perform memory accesses on a computer
in C and JavaScript in any language
basically every memory reference will go
through the cache we cannot avoid avoid
that unless we use specific instructions
for that but usually every memory access
goes through the cache and this is
transparent to the operating system and
the programs they can't work around that
except using non temporal accesses for
instance but that's not the regular case
if we measure the access latency for
memory access we see that almost all
cached
exits are excesses are here around 50
cycles on this machine this includes all
the measurement and the non-cash
accesses they are mostly here around 250
cycles so there is a huge gap and also
we have a clear a clear difference we
can say if something is below 200 cycles
it's very likely to be cached if it's
above 200 then it's very likely to be
not cached how does the cache work I
will start with the most simple cache
here
that's a directly mapped cache and we
have a memory address here
we have the cash the cash is divided
into two halves the first half is the
first column is the tag and the second
column is the data so we have some data
and the tag is used to identify that
this is the data that we actually
actually are looking for next step the
Ameri a dress is divided into different
parts so the last part is just the
offset and that's B bits so we have a
cache line size of 2 to the B bytes
that's just how the how the bits are
used it's similar to the offset with
paging that you also have these 12 bits
that are used for the page offset here
it's just the cache line offset the next
end bits are used as the cash index and
the cash index is used to find the right
line in the cache so you see that there
are multiple lines in the cache and we
can now look up which line we want to
where this memory address is cached in
which line and then we can verify
whether the tag is fixed to this memory
address in our process so given that we
have n bits up for the cache index we
have 2 to the N cache lines finally the
tag is computed using some function that
can be the identity function of some
address bits it can be an XOR of address
bits we don't know that but it's used as
a tag and then we compare if the tag is
if the tag is the same then we will have
a cache hit if it's not the same we will
have a cache miss so the obvious problem
here is if we have two addresses that
have the same n bits here they will go
to the same cache index and if we all
the time work on to such addresses it
will actually be slower than working
without a cache because every every time
we access it is that it has to be copied
back to the memory and then copied into
the cache again
that's when we introduced the set
associativity so in this case we divide
the cache lines into we change the cache
lines to cache sets and each cache set
now contains two so-called
ways so we can we have two identical
ways in every cache set so they are
equivalent and we can just store the
data in one of the two ways and when we
want to retrieve the data both ways are
checked and the correct one returns the
data and if we don't find it then it's
not in the cache if we have multiple
ways in a cache set that are equivalent
then the replacement policy gets very
important I will I will not go into
details of the replacement policy right
now but we will talk about it later
because it's relevant for row hammer jas
so how do these caches work I write
memory address here that's on purpose
because it's not clear whether it's a
physical or virtual address caches often
use physical addresses but some use
virtual addresses and if we use physical
addresses we have to translate the
virtual addresses to physical addresses
first and that takes some time so here
we'll just go a bit into TLB and paging
so you should know paging that's that's
a mechanism that translates virtual
addresses to physical addresses and we
have some translation lookaside buffer
that's also just the cache that
translates that that caches these
translation table entries from which
were to physical mapping and the TLB of
course has some latency so it's
expensive to use physical addresses here
the worst case for the cache would be
that it's not in the translation
lookaside buffer and we need to load the
mapping from the DRAM and then load the
data as well from the DRM that would be
the worst case so the solution is to use
virtual addresses instead of physical
addresses if possibly so if we think of
the index and the tag
of the cash we can think of these four
combinations and I will just go briefly
through these four combinations so the
first one it's that's very similar to
what we already saw so here we have the
n bits the B bits and the tag is
computed from the VPN the virtual page
number here and the data is then
retrieved based on the virtual pasted
page number the obvious problem here is
that the virtual page number we have
virtual addresses so if we are if we
have multiple processes they will have
different data on the same virtual
address so that's bad the advantage here
is that the virtually indexed virtually
tagged cache is fast the virtual tag is
not unique that is bad because it's a
slow upon a context switch and also
shared memory can be more than once in
the cache that's also bad because then
we waste the expensive cache memory the
other extreme is physically indexed
physically tagged so here we have to go
through the translation lookaside buffer
and then get the physical address and
then we can compute the tag so this is
very slow yeah slow because of the TLB
lookup and the advantage is shared
memory is only once in the cache yeah
next one I will not talk much about this
one because it doesn't make it make much
sense because it has a disadvantage that
it's slow and also the virtual tag is
not unique because the virtual tag is
computed from the from the virtual
address so shared memory is once in the
cache this is not used in practice
virtually indexed physically tagged this
is used in practice because you can do
this entirely so we will do the cache
index we compute the cache index from
the virtual address we look at them in
the cache and then in parallel we can do
the TLB lookup get the PPM and compute
the tag and retrieve the data so this is
almost as fast as the virtual index
virtually tagged cache no restriction
here is that we can only go up to 12
bits for the for the cache index and if
you think about it we have things since
more than 10
we have 32 kilobyte level 1 caches now
and the reason is that it's fast and you
can do this with 8 ways if you add more
ways it gets it gets slower again so I
think we will stay with 32 kilobyte
level 1 caches for a while so as I said
virtually next virtually tagged for the
virtually next virtually physically
checked for the level 1 cache and
physically next physically tagged is
usually used for level 2 and level 3
caches so shared memory is shared in the
cache this is an interesting observation
because if we have multiple processes
running that has have some shared memory
they can influence each other through
the cache although they shouldn't be
able to get to do that if you look at
caches today they will look something
like this so you have multiple cores you
have level 1 course in level 2 11 1
caches in level 2 caches that are
private to each core and the level the
level 3 cache the last level cache is
divided into slices for one for each
core and it is shared across all course
so every core can access all the level 3
data but it has it takes a different
amount of time and you can also exploit
that to do some other attack that I
won't talk about today another property
that's very interesting is that it's
inclusive so all data that is in the
level 1 or level 2 cache is also in the
level 3 cache there cannot be any data
in level 2 or level 1 that is not also
in the last level cache then we have
some mapping to the slices this function
here is based on the physical address
and it computes where in the last level
cache our address is actually cached and
this function has been reversed in China
yet by different research groups in the
last time finally the last part of the
background is cache maintenance so Intel
provides or also arm and AMD these CPUs
are all provide cache maintenance
instructions that is first prefetch to
suggest the CPU to
data into the cache actually prefetch if
you if you use it not in the right way
it would actually consume more time than
you can save with it so you should be
very much aware of what you're doing
when you're using prefetch and the other
one is even worse it's CL /
with that you can throw data out of the
cache if you look at this or look for a
CL flash on github you won't find many
projects that use it CL search is rarely
used I would say it's used it's
necessary sometimes for a cache
coherency memory coherency related stuff
but it has very often been suggested to
just remove CL flash to get rid of all
the problems it has so both instructions
are based on virtual addresses and as we
just heard shared memories shared in the
cache Co flash is based on virtual
addresses we can throw out shared data
from the cache and that leads us
directly to cache attacks so what can we
do with cache attacks yesterday someone
asked me ok well why why is this
relevant no one is interested in this
because you cannot do anything
practically with that actually we build
a cache based key logger or partial key
logger with that so we can just run an
unprivileged program maybe in the chrome
sandbox and we can spy on keystrokes and
distinguish some letters from other
letters so this is this goes very much
into the direction of a cache based key
logger also in several research papers
they have been attacks on AES on RSA on
ECC algorithms for instance in the flash
and reload paper by Yahoo I mean fagner
there they have recovered 7 97% of RSA
key after a single encryption so that's
really bad if you can do that after a
single encryption just by monitoring
what happens in your cache and these
attacks have been demonstrated cross V M
cross core we have seen cross CPU
attacks on Intel even on arm cross CPU
attacks and yeah they work on basically
any arc
so most attacks have been performed an
intel on arm we have seen someone we
have performed some attacks recently
also cross cpu attacks have been
demonstrated on AMD so yeah it works
pretty much everywhere across cortex how
do they work
yeah there we exploit the inclusive
property and that the last level cache
contains all data from level 1 and level
2 cache so if you evict data from the
last level cache then you're also
evicted from level 1 and level 2 cache
of all cores so also of the other at
level 1 course you can evict cache lines
from from a private level 1 cache of
another core and this brings us to to
the flush and reload attack I will today
I will talk briefly about a flash and
reload and prime probe and prime
properly within leaders to row hammer so
with flash and reload you have an
attacker and the victim and the cache is
here in the middle and in the first step
the attacker maps the shared library and
accesses it and then in share then it's
cached for both the attacker and victim
because it's shared memories so it's
shared in the cache then the attacker
flushes the data then maybe the victim
at some point will load the data and
then when the attacker reloads the data
it will observe a low memory latency
just as we have seen in the histogram
right in the beginning and then the
attacker has learned that the victim
just accessed this particular address so
with prime and probe this works pretty
similar just at this time the attacker
uses much more addresses and uses these
addresses to fill the whole cache set so
all ways in in a cache set and now if
the victim accesses some memory
locations it will evict data from the
last level cache replace some ways the
the attacker previously has primed has
filled with data and then the attacker
will reacts s and the the memory that he
believes
is still in the cache and then he
observes the slow access because one of
the ways has been replaced and then the
attacker has learned that the victim
accessed a memory location that maps to
the same cache set so the attacker can
derive the middle n bits for the cache
index so I will I will just go straight
away to this example here on the
keystroke examples so here I just ran
this on on a non key up and key down
events and this is very nice so you can
now see the length of my pseudo password
that's not good so the challenge here is
of course how do we locate these key
dependent memory accesses we can of
course look at object dumps but that's
very difficult because it is very time
consuming and the lessons I learned
while doing this staring at object dumps
for several weeks will give you severe
headache you shouldn't do that
so automate everything right from the
start and that's how we started
developing cache template attacks and in
cache template attacks we have two
phases first the profiling phase and
second the exploitation phase and the
profiling phase we will do some
pre-processing and locate which
addresses are interesting and in the
exploitation phase we just perform a
standard slash and reload attack so the
profiling phase will look something like
this so in the beginning the cache is
empty and then we trigger some event
here it's a keystroke a and then it's
cached for both the attacker and the
victim and the attacker now can check
whether the address is cached and if the
address is cached and the attacker will
store this in some matrix too to learn
that this address is used for this F
event then we flush it and we repeat
this for higher accuracy then we repeat
it for all events and then we do this
for the next address so finally we will
have a matrix for all events and all
addresses and know which event triggers
a cache hit on which address and
in the opposite direction Akash it on
which address means which event so how
hard is it to perform Akash attempted
attack we just recently did students
attack this student-led attack different
programs and they typically found
leakage within 30 minutes and different
programs and this is really a wide range
of programs although most students just
they just kept doing keystroke attacks
so we found so the students in this case
found keystroke side channels and nano
quasi client X term pidgin gk2 Firefox
Emacs mousepad and here the user 32 DLL
on Windows so it also always Emacs all
on OSX we can monitor our keystrokes
specifically in the password field in he
pass X that's also very interesting
because if you if you see okay
we had 11 keystrokes now and then for a
long time nothing then probably this was
the whole password we have the font
rendering in live half pass which is
used by many Linux applications we can
monitor action buttons in VLC we can
monitor when net Kadri sees characters
we can distinguish key groups in GK su
and also monitor when the checkbox in
the case who is clicked so you can do
pretty much with that so the conclusion
is that we can use this technique to
find any side channel leakage cache
side-channel leakage in feasible time it
works on all these CPUs and with unknown
binaries so even on Windows and you can
automate this and perform this in a
large scale but it still requires shared
memory so why don't we do this with
prime and probe prime and probe would
have the advantage that we don't need
shared memory but it's much more
difficult to do that because it has a
lot of noise so I won't do that with
priming probe although it should be
possible
we'll do something that's mmm yeah
that's more fun with Prime intro or
evict and reload evict and reload if you
take Prime and Probst so this does some
cash eviction and if you'd now perform a
single memory access with then you have
evict and reload so it's just a variant
of Prime and propane killing so row
hammer if you look at the DRAM then you
will have multiple channels you will
have the dim will have multiple ranks
and chips and if you look at the chip
then the chip is separated into multiple
banks and you can access these banks in
parallel so if you want to access some
memory location in the DRAM then you
first have to activate the row and copy
the data into the row buffer the cells
by themselves they leak voltage over
time so the voltage drops over time and
therefore these cells need to be
refreshed frequently if you perform
excesses in physical proximity then the
cells leak faster and that's what we
exploit in the row hammer back so in the
row hammer back we will just activate
one row and copy is then copied to the
it is actually not copied to the row
buffer but we can just think about it as
if it would be copied to the row buffer
in the row buffers again some sort of
cache and we always activate the
different rows and if we do this often
enough then we will have bit flips in
the middle row so here we need to
perform non-cash accesses to reach the
DRAM and the original attacks you still
flush for that so they basically clearly
just do a flush and reload attack I once
did a I wanted to do a measurement on a
flash and reload attack and buy that
destroyed some shared library on my
system and then the window manager
crashed and interestingly it linux
decided to
the changes back to the hard-disk so
even after rebooting I still had these
corruptions in the shared library on my
system that was not nice so yeah I
really wonder why it does that because
the shared libraries usually read only
so Linux should know that this data
can't be modified it's weird
so we flushed the line from the cache
and then the next access has to reach
the DRM the row hammer box so that the
row hammer back is some sense of
relevance force security was first
observed by Kim a tile who showed that
you can do this purely in software and
they suspected that this can be used for
some security exploits and then see born
in 2015 March 2015 showed that you can
actually do that you can actually gain
root privileges or kernel privileges on
a system by using the row hammer by
exploiting the row hammer back and
therefore you need the non cached
accesses and this is very similar to
flash and reload if you have a
vulnerable system and you do a slash and
reload attack in a high frequency you
can probably induce bit flips without
trying to okay so how does row hammer
work simulate in the flash and reload
attack we will flash data from the cache
and then we will reload it and we do
this with two different rows here so in
this case we have some blue row in the
middle of the blue page in the middle is
in a separate row than these other pages
that we access and if we do this often
enough then we will have the bit flip in
the middle row so how does row hammer
without CL flash work and the idea is
that we use prime and probe or evict and
reload rather than Schlessinger instead
of flat and reload and this will works
like this we just access a lot of memory
locations until the target memory
location is evicted
then we reload it and that's it and then
we repeat
for a while and then we will observe a
bit flip if the system is vulnerable of
course so the challenges here are if if
we want to do this in JavaScript
especially how do we get accurate
accurate timing in JavaScript so
actually that's not that much of trouble
because JavaScript provides you very
accurate timing so we can easily do that
how do we get physical addresses in
JavaScript we will also see that this is
very easy with physical addresses to
access this has already been solved
because we had this sliced reverse
engineering we have this reverse
engineering of the DRM mappings so this
part I would consider this as already
solved this is not part of our work but
our work focuses on in which order to
access them because this is actually not
that trivial so let's just speak a few
words about the timing here in the
native code you would use our DTC in
JavaScript you can use
window.performance now and it's
sufficient to get the attack working
physical addresses in JavaScript is also
easy because we just before we worked on
roham rjs we did some page these
application attacks in JavaScript and
there we exploited that the Opera
operating system optimizes the usage of
memory by using two mega byte pages
whenever possible so in this case if we
allocate a large array in JavaScript
then the last 21 bits of the physical
address are identical to the last 21
bits of the virtual address and also the
last 21 bits of the JavaScript array
index so great physical addresses for
Java JavaScript what can possibly go
wrong this is also very interesting
because erm rows on on a typical system
are 128 kilo bytes or 256 kilobytes
apart from each other so within a two
megabyte page you will have several
DRM rolls and just can hammer right away
on these DRM rules which addresses to
access yeah we use eviction we focus we
use the slice mapping that has been
reverse engineered by Clement in movies
and from this we know which addresses
are congruent in the cash and then we
can evict them from the cash
the remaining challenge is in which
order to access them and if we look at
the replacement policy on older CPUs
like Sandy Bridge that's more than five
years old now there would work like this
I they use an LRU replacement policy and
there we evict of the oldest entry first
so if I just add a timestamp to every
entry in the cache set so each way in
the cache set then we have some then the
replacement policy will when we load
some data stored in the cache set and
update the timestamp and always the
youngest the the oldest way is replaced
and then we have the new timestamp here
and finally the targeted cache way is
also replaced so the replacement policy
on more recent CPUs like Ivybridge
or newer and also on arm CPUs or AMD
CPUs they work differently so they don't
use LRU and if you try allow your
replacement it will look something like
this yeah okay this was not very
successful and we tried this on Haswell
and we had a success rate of 75 percent
and that's not sufficient to do row
hammering if you only succeed in 75% of
the cases and you have to do something
like 2 million in victims in a very high
frequency 75% will ruin the attack it
doesn't work so we can just do more
excesses then we will get a higher
success rate but actually this will be
too slow
when we started working on this we we we
crafted these eviction patterns by hand
so here you see address 1 address to
address address 3 and the black box
marks that we access this address in at
this point in time and if you represent
this as a sequence of numbers it would
look like this so 1 2 1 2 2 3 2 3 3 4 3
4 and so on and this can be a very long
sequence and then we found that and we
observe different properties of these
addresses too to go step further first
all the addresses that we are working on
they are congruent so they are
indistinguishable in terms of the
eviction strategy we don't care whether
we label an address 1 or 2 or 3 as long
as the strategy is unique it doesn't
make a difference so we can we can give
any number any number into sequence of
accesses it just has to be unique so if
you look for instance at at this pattern
here 2 5 4 6 3 1 & 2 5 6 4 1 3 and so on
they are all equivalent we can just
label them 1 2 3 4 5 6 we don't care
about the labeling of the addresses
that's that's all I want to say to this
point so we can do two things now we can
add more different addresses so for
instance at address 7 8 9 and so on that
will increase the or it can increase the
eviction rate or we can add multiple
accesses to one address and there we
observe that this also can increase the
eviction rate so the sequences that we
generated they often had repeating sub
sequences and they are we decided that
we could represent the sequences in in
form of a loop so I wrote this loop and
it will just iterate over the different
addresses in the inner loop and access
these many addresses
and then it will perform see repetitions
of this inner loop and then we have a
total set size so this is a number of
different addresses that we actually
access that's here and then an overlap
parameter so for instance if we have 1 2
1 2 & 2 3 2 3 then the overlap parameter
is 1 but we could also do something like
1 2 1 2 3 4 3 4 then the overlap
parameter would be 2 and then we can
write eviction strategies in a compact
form by just we just have the P here to
mark it as an eviction strategy or an
eviction pattern and then the different
parameters of the strategy so for
instance if you look at the pattern 1 1
1 4 it would look like a look like this
1 2 3 4 and if we have 2 2 1 4 it would
like look like this 1 2 1 2 2 3 2 3 3 4
3 4 and then we generate a lot of
strategies based on this scheme so in
total we evaluated more than 10000
strategies and here I have some examples
that are very interesting or at least I
find them very interesting so here we
have P 1 1 117 that has been suggested
and and also been used in previous work
and we also start with this and then we
have P 1 1 120 so I already told you
that this one has an eviction rate of
approximately 75% do you expect the
eviction rate for the for the second one
to be higher or lower higher whose for
higher okay whose for lower some some
are for lower okay actually I do too I
do three more excesses here that are
congruent that go to the same cache set
so the eviction rate should be higher
here and if we look at the eviction rate
it is actually much higher so we here we
have an eviction rate of ninety-nine
point eight two percent and that would
be high enough for Oh hammer if we look
at the
execution time of this so I do this like
20 million times in a loop this excess
pattern and this excess pattern which
one will be faster on average the first
one because it does fewer memory
accesses so its 307 nanoseconds and the
second one is 934 nanoseconds on my
system that's very bad because 934
nanoseconds is way too slow for a row
hammer now if we look at different
strategies for instance this one here I
do this this first parameter this means
that I do the one two two three and so
on
so here we have 34 excesses and the
eviction rate goes up ninety-nine point
eight six percent that's high enough for
Oh hammer now for the execution time
would you expect the execution time of
this loop it does double the amount of
excesses would it be higher or lower its
lower so 191 cycles so optimizing
programs by adding memory accesses could
work so here works for a row hammer and
I can actually use this to do the aroma
tech and if I for instance look at this
one this strategy here it does 64
excesses and the execution time is even
lower than for the first one so we just
measured the average execution time and
it gets lower by adding memory accesses
one review of our paper said yeah that's
that's that cannot work you
made a mistake there but you can measure
that so replacement policies on modern
interest CPUs so we just have seen that
LRU doesn't work and that you have to
access addresses multiple times so in
which order to access them we solve that
and if we look at the bit flips that we
can achieve with that then we see that
okay in JavaScript we have a bit slower
but in native code we can trigger bit
flips using eviction if we can do this
with CL / so systems the
our vulnerability or hammer with CL
flash should be considered vulnerable to
RO hammer without CSS as well we also
tried it on arm so here is a regular
smartphone but we attached the cooler to
it so that it doesn't overheat we also
evaluated several thousand strategies
there but we found no bit flips so I'm I
take three more minutes I think that
should be just in time right so the
operating system groups pages and page
tables into two megabyte frames and
that's actually bad for exploiting
because we said we want to trigger a bit
flip possibly in a page table because we
can exploit that but actually the
operating system prevents that by
grouping pages and page tables into two
megabyte frames the operating system
just deviates from this strategy if it's
almost out of memory and it's very hard
to get there without crashing the
browser so we introduced a new technique
to do that actually it has already been
described in previous work but not
studied in detail and we did some tests
on that and we could even use it to
induce bit flips on a ddr4 system
default configured so amplified single
sided hammering works like that we again
evict the data from the cache and this
time we don't have the the target memory
location between the two memory
locations that we access but it's
adjacent to it and here I have drawn a
dashed line to mark the two megabyte
page frame borders so we have our two
rows that are directly at the edge of a
two megabyte page and if we do that then
we will observe a bit flip here and that
even works on ddr4 and if we use this
then we can we don't need in near out of
memory situation and we can try this
until the memory mappings have changed
and then we have a bit flip in our own
page tables and if we try this until
we find that the new mapping is one of
our own page tables then we have full
access to the physical memory so the
conclusion is that we can do cat
addiction instead of CL flush then we
are independent of programming language
and available instructions we can even
do that in JavaScript and we
demonstrated probably the first hardware
fold attack through website using
javascript and that's very nice because
you can just put a website online and
see which systems on which systems it
works on this laptop it works on this
laptop we verified that we can get root
privileges for web apps so thank you for
your attention