okay then thank you very much good
morning everybody welcome to the first
edition of it was a conference here in
this nice a little place nearly
everybody is ver ok 50 or 100 people are
missing right now but this is maybe
because of your early morning who knows
when you're not on the right side you
can maybe see our river war maybe or
when you go upstairs and this is why we
call this conference will check because
it's a pre-war Rivera and security so
SEC will say and you have maybe ask
yourself who is running this conference
who are the guys behind this conference
and so let me just say a few words most
of us are from the chair of network and
data security which is a part of the
whole skirts Institute which is maybe
400 meters in this direction here we are
also having our company Varrick manitos
also i'm organizing this and what we do
especially vejo skirts institute is that
we have a lecture which is called at
least my lecture hack pro or in german
practicum fajita technique and as most
of you maybe know this lecture is about
two things so first of all we have
people international speakers from all
over the world from the USA from belgium
from russia and so on and what they do
is that they talk about security we talk
about new things and V speakers I
exactly the speakers who are also here
at this conference so what we did is
that we invited yeah let me call the
best of speakers from the former hack
pro but there are also many many more
maybe in the next editions who are
really really great trust me and on the
other side so this is point two we tell
the people something about web security
so how to hack back applications how to
attack them how to defend them and I
think this is a really cool idea and
this is maybe also one of the reasons
why was this lecture is so highly
frequented well
accra is actually more of an electro
because we have an evening event at g
data as it is the case today and we have
the speaker which is unusual for
university and it's vatten not a
surprise that we also have an expansion
of hack drug called hack pro all-stars
so what we do is that we have an own
over spear up chapter in the past in
2014 and amsterdam and also in 2015 oh
it's 2015 in EM sedan and 2013 in
hamburg and rebels nearly the same as
well sick but was like is this time here
at you were in university a separate
conference for itself without other
stuff with about crew people like the
OVAs people where tendra i can really
recommend most conference for them well
the idea behind will check was to have a
hacker alike but an old conference which
is more than a lecture but we want high
quality talk as a justification fagtron
and we have a few goals so our first
goal is that we want to be independent
and we also want to reach those goals in
the future and future of rhythms so we
don't want to promotional even you can
maybe see some roll-ups here and some
advertisements but just a little bit so
we don't want any salesman who sell you
some web application firewalls which are
actually totally worthless because they
don't filter the interesting stuff right
that you can bypass our second colors
that we want to be low price you may be
solve it as most of you did that our
ticket prices maybe 10 prospered from
the ticket price in comparison to other
conferences the thing is that we did it
for free here we organize it for free
and that we had a lot of sponsors who
believed in us from the very first
second i will show you some in the next
slide the next slides and we are
actually a community even service even
should be from friends for friends so
when I look into the audience I can see
that maybe 60 or
seventy percent of you are already known
so I know you because we had some
security trainings or we have tested
something for you or we adjust
colleagues and drink a beer together in
the afternoon or evening who knows and
our last goal is to charity aspect so
all of the money which we will make sort
of profit from the tickets when we spent
or an organization which helps children
and this organization is called gains
ablution and RV and what we did is fed
way help children with cancer they help
children in emergency situations so you
can imagine that they are nearly dead
because they are ill and vast Vagos
short pain waivers of musicals and so on
and I think that yeah helping children
is one of the best things what we can do
and next to it we can enjoy this evening
which is quite one of the best things
right and this even wouldn't be possible
without our sponsors of course this is
the advertisement part but just very
very short thank you very much to hack
my need so you will hear my next thought
talk one of your coroner's professor
shrink thank you very much for to
Christian and you lie who helped us to
organize this fing thank you very much
to contact security who believed in us
for my very first second we had a
awesome really awesome speakers on earth
in the last day and also thank you to
jdate edgy data you will see it on vient
that Fay we we have a cross with wine
and maybe some beer and whiskey and so
on and if you are able to drink some
alcohol you will really enjoy this event
but if not you can also enjoy it with
other stuff it's quite a nice thing
believe me and it's they are really
really cool guys you will see I also
thank you very much to yuba crypt and we
host girls Institute for IT security
from the University site one of the
biggest Institute's they are paid for
you for me speaker crossed and also be
booked on my via transfer the wrong who
allows us to have a video
calling and to put few things here on
YouTube after one month or so on and
also thank you very much to V supporters
so thank you to deep sec a conference
which is awesome actually it's in Vienna
attended very my last year thank you to
SBA research I did a lot of
advertisements if one is also sitting
here somewhere she's organizing the next
CCS conference so the academic she won
conference in Vienna and I think that
she's really a person who can do a
really really good job so if you're able
to go there do it and last but not least
an hour w who is yeah who closes the gap
between the industry and academic side
and of course this even wouldn't be
possible without you if you out via
attendees and with other speakers these
speakers are listed here we have one
exception one of our speakers got ill
and the last night and I told me that
it's not possible to come here Felix
Lintner but I hope that he will get
better soon and we have an awesome other
speaker for him so he will talk about I
think so Firefox extensions and how to
break them and how yeah how dangerous it
is to install themes on your browser so
you actually shouldn't do this at least
bought in firefox and chrome and just as
a short reminder here's the grid for
today we are in the red face when we
have a coffee break we have lunch when
lunches upstairs in the men's ahsoka
polls and your envelopes and you pay
with your coupons fear so you put your
meals on the donut or tray and drinks
and pay with your coupon that's it so
and we have maybe on our own area where
we can stay together but you can sit
wherever you run upstairs once again and
during vvv coffee break all of the
things are free you can drink as much as
you want you can eat as much as you want
there will be some biscuits and at 5pm
the flight from udo you shouldn't miss
it
the social event today an absolute
recommendation from my side as edgy data
and V Academy this is not here this is
the reason why you have some tickets
stood for betrays train station and our
planets to be HD data at 6pm and the
non-food will be at seven thirty so
we'll be able to serve some wine and
beer beer which is also from bo home
which is exclusively made for for this
event and yeah we go there by train we
both groups after unos talk but you
receive us just look what we other guys
do and follow us or if you drive by car
you can drag to this address that's it
so then on Friday the same procedure we
have a coffee break a lunge a coffee
break and a closing time if possible be
on time I know that V parties are still
hard and that they actually also them
but if you can be on time n yeah and now
I have the pleasure to introduce you my
my professor who's given the keynote
yeah I think an expert at least in TLS
and many many other things and as I said
the co-founder of our company hack my
need and in the last year's a very good
friend of mine so given em applause
please
you