next up we've got Edward who's going to
be talking about artificial intelligence
in spirit Ian the way you break things
using an AI n is a university student at
York so yeah my name's Edward and poles
I am currently in the middle of doing my
PhD in New York but I stopped for about
a six-month period to work full-time so
fantastic for sec one name ET and going
to are going to be moving to part time
what my PhD is as far as using some of
the techniques which i'm going to be
talking about to find interesting and
cool and ultimately totally useless
attacks against program however the
techniques themselves are quite useful
and they're the ones which you don't
really tend to didn't come across in the
industry quite so much one slide summary
so that some of you can still make the
patient old and some problems in
security are really hard
there are many of them finding folks
to me to a finding in somewhere really
difficult to put decent ids rules really
really difficult some of the techniques
which I'm going to be talking about can
help you the techniques aren't really
not hard they there's some there are
some long words and some of the
explanations that you're gonna find a
wine already using ultimately and once
you kind of dig deep also there are lots
of tools you can use admittedly most of
them were written by academics however
they have been used a lot I'm not saying
contest against itself I suppose and why
why should you be here are still
artificial intelligence it's a very big
deal it's unfortunately not it's rather
a collection of various interesting
techniques some of which are clickable
security some of which are not I'm gonna
be talking about ones apart
ultimately think about artificial
intelligence is it real it really boils
down to a problem of search and you you
have some kind of problem you you want a
tool to do and think and you you can
kind of recognize when your tool is
doing the right thing
okay yourself get a tool to generate one
for you some people have done exactly
that that's a really interesting stuff
I'll talk about those to give people
some inspiration and also all and I
won't quite give you pseudocode but I'll
give you enough information but among
technical people understand other
technical people team building actually
influenced chebula is everything more
balanced artificial intelligence in
general for those who don't know and AI
is essentially the science of it'll do
there are really difficult problems we
don't know how to solve we don't know
how we might be able to solve small
variants of those problems but the kind
of instances of those problems that you
get in real life are just too complex
some some of these problems are and
they're in the complexity space of NP
which means they can't be solved in
biomatter monistic Turing machine in
polynomials and polynomial time what
that means is you can't solve them for
big and the big instances not possible
whatever you see NP just replace it with
those two words
make sense for example and one is called
the Traveling Salesman who's heard of
the Traveling Salesman problem yeah who
knows how it works
as in who who doesn't need them to that
explanation okay well for those of you
that do imagine you've got I mean you've
got a map but bunch of the decent bunch
of roads connecting them and you want to
start off from the city or any go to
every other city once and come back to
where they started in the most efficient
way possible if you have we can
generally solve them for about a hundred
thousand cities but we're talking
massive amount of computing power
required to find ideal solutions however
we don't necessarily need the best
solution especially if it's gonna take
you decades to come up with you can use
some of these search techniques to find
what our goal here is the exclusions ie
they roughly approximate the best
solution they they're pretty efficient
maybe only like two or three percents of
difference between the best solution and
you can use the pen search techniques
I'm going to talk about to find some
them you depending on how long you look
you might end up with one which is just
really bad similarly you might also get
some good ones ultimately you're trading
off time spent looking for a solution I
mean a memory compute power and all that
stuff for the quality of your solution
ok so that's why
a reasonable solution for problem how do
we find heuristics the answer is with of
course medicine heuristics there they're
also different types and ultimately what
they belong to is these are ways of
searching a really big search space
imagine Ivica
all the possible solutions to a really
difficult problem like a book finding
algorithm or fuzzing or IDs rule to stop
people from sending viruses across the
wire or something like that if you can
if you can just represent them as a
point on the line and you can vaguely
measure how good of a solution that is
you can end up with a with a really
awful ground sorry I suck at paint in
real life obviously unless you've got
like how many is that what seven
different possible solutions it's gonna
be a lot more volatile right anyway
imagine being carving weirdly a weirdly
nice-looking search space like this you
can see you know some solutions suck one
solution is the best and there are a few
others which are vaguely good right so
what you can do is you can use technique
called hill climbing you pick a random
solution on this graph say pick this one
here what you do is you take a look at
your neighbors okay what is the solution
over here like what is the solution is
this one better than this one I'm also
better than where I am currently it's so
we start moving up this hill and
eventually you keep running that
algorithm until you end up here it's
like well the neighbors next to me both
suck harder than out of you therefore
return this is the solution of Windows
there you know and and you have a
reasonable solution won't be the best
but yeah it's fine however what if
you're stuck you know here Brady I've
got this solution wonderful I have to
drink what you can do is use a variation
of hill climbing all simulated annealing
which is a little bit like that except
you have have another variable called
temperature and what that does is the
higher temperature so inversely
proportional to see you temperature you
might jump from randomly just like well
also check out that guy at the far side
or over here or whatever and then
eventually what you end up doing is you
might start off here and then rapidly
jump there and they may be here and then
back there and then gradually along here
you run the simulation for the
likelihood of you jumping somewhere else
random drops and so it ends up evolving
climbing but you're relying on the odds
of actually ending up
or Peaks being quite low that
unfortunately is not always the case and
besides we have multi-core right and
phones have multiple persisters these
days so why just look at one particular
solution why not look at one over here
and one here and one over there and see
how good they are
so just generate a thousand maybe a
million billion see how good they are
and then make them fight to the death
that was actually a really difficult to
find I have this image actually mean is
get the really big ones and then
gradually fill out like your of your
next your next generation so generate a
thousand ones paint the best ones fill
out the next thousand with and with
twitch versions and bread versions and
the baby generates a new rapid ones to
repeat it's a really simple algorithm
come up with a bunch of random solutions
see how good they are and pick the best
ones combine the best ones you take the
best ones fill out with surrounded ones
repeat until you've until you've got
bored run out of time or you or you
found a solution which is sufficiently
good that you don't really care about
getting a better one and there's a whole
bunch of things that you can do with
like come up with uses crypto
vulnerabilities but in terms of the real
world it's actually really good for and
for fuzzing and by fussing what I
actually mean is this is an American
fuzzy look which is a type of rabbit
it's also a really good tool and it uses
this testing technique which is through
around the garbage of API until the
application crashes I mean exercise the
applications internal state you you want
to come up with some kind of test or
input or some set of environmental
conditions or whatever that causes the
program to enter some unusual or
never-before-seen state and you can
measure that and you can generate test
cases which means you can generate test
cases that give you a higher degree of
new status which means you can optimize
for it which means you can use genetic
algorithms and that's cool because if
you come up with application crashes
that are novel that's an O date possibly
you might come up with what's really
cool exploit American car swap uses
genetic algorithms and the whole bunch
of other techniques to to develop these
kind of crashing custom aces trophies in
the American fuzzy walk you know
programs they mount on the wall in terms
of we found the critical vulnerabilities
in these software includes things like
open SSL might be new PG good new TLS
you know major major programs that are
supposed to be developed with some kind
of quality so I heard anyway if you want
to do this yourself and there are whole
bunch of libraries I use this or
it's pretty heavyweight but it's really
robust and has a whole of options the
tutorials are really good and if you're
doing academic related stuff this is a
good one to use because everyone uses it
and so when used to make your paper and
you get a review one of the things I'm
not gonna complain is you use the
library heard of therefore it's rubbish
use this other one instead which which
is fine it's um it's on the fastest and
it's Java based which may or may not be
a deal-breaker for some of you it's
pretty reasonable or you could use place
them I really like pison and I used
inspired which and which is quite cool I
don't really know anything about pi ball
or page a PI other than people seem to
like it because it's Python it's really
simple to get up and running it's pretty
fun or rather using someone else's
implementation because the whole you
know generate mutate thing all these
tools will deal with all that for you
you just have to say I'm looking for
this kind of thing this is how you see
how good it is and I want you to
generate a thousand of them and run
through twenty generations see what you
find so you don't necessarily need to
understand very much about how genetic
algorithms work and trust me there's a
lot of theory known which is interesting
but the tools are really easy to use so
yeah you have some kind of problem you
know what the solution might look like
you can tell the computer how to
generate it go and then you wait and you
wait and eventually it's
which is fine but what if you don't
really know what the solution is
supposed to look like you know you and
maybe when it comes to and keep coming
back to this idea of ideas rules because
I'm who went to steal come earlier this
game okay who sold a talk by David day
and I like Sheffield about generating
ideas rules to love you excellent which
means all this will be new so anyway
well one thing you can do is there
techniques where you and you produce a
program and you teach it how to
recognize the kind of stuff you want to
recognize you want some kind of
classifier this is good this is bad
here is a mystery set is it good or bad
you know that's a really good for that
and so as this diagram very clearly
states you've got and you've got three
different layers maybe one set of input
neurons one or more hidden layers and
then some public neurons and so let's
say you wanted a classifier that could
give you it just gives you a feedback
one or zero good or bad maybe you'd only
have one of these on Fitness because the
way it works is you you take your input
your image or your peacock or whatever
you feed it's here in the notes like one
bit at one bit at a time those input
nodes far off a water zero of their own
based on some probability which you said
I say some probability because what kind
of probabilities is
research question in a minute those and
see those arrows coming off the input
that's when they fire they'll transmit
their signal down each one of those of
those arrows to what's called the hidden
layer and those hidden layers will take
those ones are juniors based on their
input and again far off a 1 or 0 of
their own based on another probability
that's in a dimension and then finally
after potentially many hidden layers you
get output notes who will get some
collection of signals and we'll go 1 or
0 or 0 the point and output based on
based on their input just before we get
started there's a pattern in the whole
field of AI and evolutionary computing
and all this kind of stuff genetic
algorithms is to actual Jetix as hot
dogs are to an actual dog who's over
warm they share terminology but the way
they're actually likely very very
different neural nets are a little bit
different in that you know a neuron that
which might not look very different this
is to our actual brains is much like my
bookcase in the British Library except
at the British Library ^ something they
and this is very much about being
inspired by nature rather than trying to
just imitate it so you want to build
something that replicates a brain
because you're dissatisfied with your
own the thinking about the ordinance is
while they're really good for
classifying stuff it is kind of
difficult to know but it's actually
classifying on just as a great deed for
my mentor this talk was
was excellent right here he gave me lips
I'm really good feedback I had a line in
here I'm called the Russian based
problem I said it's really important I
actually explaining but that is a
problem just having you care so I'm
going to explain it now first today's
problem problem the US military the
English National Reconnaissance Office
they wanted to to identify camouflage
ocean bases from satellite imagery
really important so and they builded me
on that and I had a set of images that
they knew contained hidden Russian bases
and they have another set of images that
didn't and they fed it through to the to
the classifier and so I have both sets
it's like okay it's doing pretty well
here is and here's notice that where we
know what the answer is but the deal
network doesn't how does it behave with
this and with this third set of data
okay fine and then they tried to run it
and it was rubbish absolutely awful and
couldn't hit in Russian faces and it
turned out what the neo network was
actually doing was looking past the
images and spalting which satellite
took the photo they had the stop lights
over Russia where the universe spaces
were and that has a lens wall which made
the images look a certain way and ones
which you didn't have basis
or over the US and I have a different
satellite with a different lens pool and
so it's important to make sure that you
actually having clear ideas to what your
classifier is doing and to people who
didn't know what the classifier was
doing it was and David day and action
field from Sheffield talent and their
problem was we how can we get support to
tell the difference between shellcode
coming over the wire from presumably
people doing this actual workouts and
things that look like show code like
JPEGs with your house any thing coming
they came up with this my idea of just
getting a computer to figure her so they
generated an eel Network gave them you
know the known bad peacocks and no good
caps good you see how they even given
the unknown set of packets they knew but
it was a mix so I haven't you know did
with that third set picture and then
decided what they needed to change
anything here repeat in terms of
actually coming up with numbered input
neurons number of output neurons
the waiting's probabilities of firing
and the number of hidden layers they
actually used
they're coming mechanistic stuff they're
talking about earlier algorithms to
generate the neural networks to then do
the summer stuff so these techniques
work really well together and so you
know you're happy to go back you have
you known good
you have mystery pockets
magic those here and the nectar falls
out how this actually works I'm not an
expert in new networks but my
understanding is we don't know they seem
to work and you know we're all carrying
around their heads and mostly but the in
terms of how they are how to actually
construct them to solve is the big
problem that we know about is very much
an open research question but ultimately
all of this kind of stuff pulls down on
to two things can you tell if you've got
the answer mostly right and can you
compare two solutions and see which one
is better even if they're both wrong if
they are if you can do that
my Tara sticks might be for you which is
great terms of actually figuring out
which one to use that's a little bit
more difficult it requires and it
requires one information about about
what the problem we are trying to solve
is if you have two very similar looking
solutions with very different Fitness
characters things like they was really
good it was really bad but they're
almost identical that you probably don't
want to use something like genetic
algorithms which relies mostly on like
small tweaks and combining into big ones
because if you've got two similar
solutions that they hate very
differently why do you think that would
give you something better so what you
can't do is
use something like genetic algorithms to
try a bunch of different and
metaheuristics to generate solutions and
then see which solution what solution
finding algorithm works best at finding
solutions yeah
difficult also another area a very very
active research so you don't really need
to worry about it and seriously I have
been working on this stuff for about two
years now I have never found a single
case where this seems like a good idea
anyway so journal takeaway is hopefully
this talk has convinced you that some of
these techniques are not too difficult
to understand all this with me all the
technique this one sorry but if you do
have any questions you can either ask me
by email or order of these but
since obviously a lot of tech companies
out there sponsors and they're all doing
threat intelligence they're doing all
sorts of women think it sounds like the
feels you're looking out there is
absolutely what they should be applying
in there back then just think about
threats in so this is the sideline
participation you're pulling the patrons
more over the show and you don't know
what that data is bad things about dates
and what it's about right actor you
don't know not your openly classified
later in the middle so she gonna make
yet make it out for you anything exactly
what you're talking about its industry
actually taking that seriously usually
well my understanding is that and David
Alex we're doing this the answer is
almost certainly not really but at least
a few people are and I'm not so
important because ultimately a lot of
generating a lot of this stuff and just
requires knowing how to configure
digital something that's really
straightforward so really anyone
eight-year-old her sticks for antivirus
this is exactly exploring I mean part of
the problem is you can't guarantee how
good your solution is actually going to
be you can just say keep going until
it's good so but it's at least worth a
shot to research your pores yeah as far
as threat intelligence is concerned
that's interesting because and if you're
trying to spawn delicious eight years
you don't necessarily know what a
malicious behavior looks like I knew all
Network chances are they are going to be
able to spot things which we as humans
will because we just don't work it could
be literally a case of malicious traffic
tends to have the bits in these
positions XOR the bits from the
immediately preceding packet in these
other positions all legs work together
equals there I don't know maybe that's
true
that's something which I'm a really
stupid and naive classifier so this is
actually my second security conference
ever
like industry secure difference there's
been a couple and academic ones they're
a lot less interesting all this a lot
fewer t-shirts and beer but okay so this
is the homepage of a CJ it looks like an
academic webpage I'm sorry however this
book essential submitter hair sticks
it's actually really really good
the guy who wrote it is he is not clinic
but he's like he's a very good
communicator and
plus it's free if you want Naumann free
resources
and anyway anything by this kind John
noser is going to be this book is about
this thing and tells you everything
means about genetic algorithms and want
to study you know and so if you really
want a resource for learning programming
that looks good on the desk
that's why however in terms of actually
learning stuff I hold and pull hardly
recommend going to the ECJ website and
doing their tutorials and reading these
this is an interesting I have the kind
of research I've been doing and this is
brand-new and published research so it's
not the kind of stuff I've been doing my
PhD in polls and attacking attacking
ciphers the way that classically you
attack a block cipher which is just a
sector that takes to fix input just
stuff to it the way they eat classes
they took those using techniques called
linear or differential cryptanalysis is
essentially you have some kind of
relationship between the message and the
final round of doing stuff to your
message because what you then do is you
guess part of the key party secret you
kind of partially decrypt the encrypted
message that you have and then you see
whether that relationship between the
message
and if this relationship that you
already know exists holes or doesn't
hold with some probability that's
different from just random chance that
means you have the correct round because
what I'm trying to do is use genetic
algorithms to come up with types of
relationship so it just has I have these
functions which I can change like oh the
message relationship one way when you
guessed it came correctly I'm a
different way when you guessed the key
in currently is that way you can
actually try and apply that relationship
try and get some key and if and you
should be able to tell whether your key
guess is correct or not because if you
can tell the your key guess is correct
before that one small part it means that
it's having to guess all of the key ones
you can guess one part so that's that's
the kind of stuff I've been doing and
the end result is this is kind of an
example of why I mentioned her socks are
weird I rediscovered a linear
cryptanalysis I also haven't found that
the late-night program curtain works is
it seems to get fixated on a statement
where this relationship always evaluates
to true
message this ciphertext if he is in this
set and then always equates the
falsification mass which gives you one
bit of information I need your keys and
so I'm currently currently kind of stuck
because I can either try and change the
codes of the more general-purpose
approximation this like it gives you or
come up with the whole sequence of
statements where it's like okay well
this table tells me he's in that pumpkin
and of that bucket this statement tells
me something sound this ha and so on in
turn the search tricky into and what's
called a binary search which again is a
lot faster it's like looking at key
yeah and in terms of actually coming up
with actually useful security results
underneath but other people have and
hopefully some of you Facebook any other
questions I understand the only thing
between you and also me and coffee