hello my name is Antonio Ramos / firstly
and you have to be a grateful person
alive I'm here because you are here I
thought that there will be only five of
us I only got fired friends so thank you
very much people from inside of you for
your support that people supporting me
behind me i'm here because there are so
many people they hire me sometimes that
these are not visual people i am what I
am because I owe you I owe this to other
people I want to watch a video with all
of you to meet outsourced batters and
less will start about this cyber
security cyber security is distracted to
only one year ago it's a cool thing but
with short time 05 of the better hackers
in spain's launched an online show focus
nitey security a few years later they
change radio for GV and discovery
channel put its eyes on them this is
covering Mac's now they perform the only
computer security TV show in the world
welcome to Monday rocky Roe hacker the
world of the hackers
dubin by internal ram is one of the most
recognized hackers and span and south
america by his side a team composed by
university teachers security books
authors and ethical hackers trainers
they show and teach how to prevent the
main current cyber attacks around the
world they show how governments and
institutions make a spy on you they
could even compromise almost any IT
infrastructure they held the police to
resolve cyber crimes laceup or armies to
train cyber soldiers they are hackers
mundo hacker expect us
I wonder hacker next season coming soon
so far so good I wanna do Shh I want to
show you this no not now on discovery
channel is gonna be on the Spanish TV
this can mean februari the next station
of mundo hacker my friends I couldn't
refrain myself from st. suffer make this
big announcement but this is me this is
me making announcements before I should
so I want to share with you this is
going to demystify the made of new
scenarios in first on cybersecurity I'm
not coming here to talk with you about
hacking where because I know us been at
least eight hours a day spending on
testing hacker orbs or practicing
vulnerabilities Assessors I don't have
to teach many things to many of my
students they could think that a student
see things better than that their
teacher which means that either you are
great with teacher or and you suck you
are not an imbecile or an idiot I want
to display about metal exploit it
explore are there are so many causes
manuals tutorials on YouTube you can get
so much in about meta might exploit
people working that our field dab of
seeing the scenarios managing this
choose I don't have too much to say
about it much less about a filthy filthy
the father's father's the famous 0 of 3
i'm gonna be paid 300 years and i'm no
one hand 1000 euros and somebody will be
paid 1 million one minute here after
working as a day lon on Father's I'm
gonna compete on a computer bath I'm a
math teacher I'm not working very well
within some Boing pieces into a computer
and not an engineer when I talk about
big data big data the biggest hard on
existing frame the year of the beginning
of the world big day term the models in
use learn
she is as they say I cannot talk about
that because many people are using these
big leader models are working properly I
have to demystify that it on big data we
got learning machines the machines learn
themselves this is a lie dor-win
said it I got a big dated to 1994 where
we can see almost happening with writing
machine with over start it's not money
talking about they talking about
analysis of the discriminating the
theory of grass logistic regression
multivariable regression these are the
really learning machines as of today
these models existed take it back from
doreen area when when Darwin found a
species in the jungle opinion on that
the petrol the size of the flower this
this flowers were subject to this models
and make figured out if this flower
animal belong to one species are other
in the exchange talk prediction models
or exponential jams predicted the exact
exchange movements no no this is not no
not new this is not mutual what it would
that exists is the capacity of computing
outcome making computes instead am
managing 100 registers we can manage 1
million euros the the registers in real
time this is marvelous didn't big data
but the thing of predicting the future
seeing things contrasting with learning
models is not newest it's common is
belonging belongs to the legacy so be
patient with me please my friends
because I a spear a quickly I'm not a
rude person but it is I'm very open and
straightforward person
hacker everybody now wants to be a
hacker by the way this women's
specialists in computing the hacker has
to be correct and politically incorrect
you have just had to be politically
incorrect incorrect you girls is the way
I'm I'm politically incorrect and I urge
you to be politically incorrect oh this
is awesome loud what the is
this is the glad thing hotmail economy
was based on glad rapidshare was also
cloud-based what's the cloud the real
world works in a different way there is
a type there's a guy having an excellent
datacenter trading on nasdaq the his
company is worth 1000 millions or as
what can I do with the my extra free
space in my digits enter so I mess up
the cloud it's like I'm a data cloud
because I had extra money my money
somebody from ftp hotmail Gmail rapid
shirt Dave flooded with me love concerts
the cloud is the bomb sure my goodness I
said is the bomb because cloud is
working because God is dates back to 50
years ago all this so-called suppose
concept are born to lies cybersecurity
impervious Maltese monitoring this is
the dream of cloudless put forward is 20
years ago when this pattern on screen
was very simple there were two visitors
on website sending out email I'm an old
person you got an email I got an email
to the years ago EML guy
I I was so surprised by the time but
this morning I got within 100 EMS
that sending off Amos was controllable
in terms of security because tempest was
not that complex the stone was a
starting 20 years ago as it happens
usually we move at breakneck speed and
we come from an environment that within
the past and back mmm to the years is
changing constantly under talking about
them to centres ago so my laptop talks
with the bank in the banking goes to the
telly there the teletag with the
verification in Miami and my friends are
chatting through what's up with somebody
if there is a guy here understanding how
this awesome thing what please
explain to me spell it out this is
absolutely impossible for us understand
we are managing plots and fragments of
knowledge brand new frequency Wi-Fi
ready ready ready frequency data centers
connectivities network pieces and chunks
of knowledge but the thing we messed
around with over the past 20 years
nobody has the remote is the slightest
idea this is matrix going on
really we are we are we through evolving
to 100 years back in a short time of 20
years in a very short time only short 10
module this is is untreatable is
unfeasible we cannot manage we created a
real matrix living matrix on this planet
how can I explain this to my children
when I explain this to my children with
gloves this major sky will die on a
video game so I started seeing the
maximum fam this this is the bombshell
this is the closeness this is the
categorization of digital threads in the
intensity and approximation this data
made up to be honest I'm a
up yes guy because by appointment can
bear with everything my friends I
started to swim office having a customer
inclined a big confession this appliance
make toast it was a good commercial seed
person what can you tell can you tell
you of course temperature that you that
this appliance reaches allows you to
have toes every single day if you put
the bread and that is its smoke steam
lincoln call you Superman you can draw
lines on PowerPoint and you do this you
put marks and you reach the planet Mars
of course this way me myself it's like
an awesome I will tell the computers
I've lived through that I make I'm
making a living out of cabbage but the
I'd made up I made it up this malware
delicious software the virus if at the
small ball a soccer ball the two 1980s
safe vision is not bad fishing is a
human medicine ape and monkey this is
the one falling into the fishing
penetration hacking networks a
non-secure code attacks mobile attacks
this is a turret travel terrible
panorama table worst-case scenario oh my
god apt was that advanced persistent
threat advanced persistent this is
spic e is like premium gold
investment I would invest on that I put
my backs on that but it is if it's not
advanced persistent threat it could be
very careful be they be afraid of bad
and the National Cyber Security against
threats plans much more heist it's
working this is a real live show my
friends this is a life cycle of birth
system add tag advance against us we
have to recognize the target advance
first we have to drink on it we have to
reckon recognized to wreck on the attack
we had to exploit the Ballard is the
system is compromised recognized and the
boundary's did the among the positioning
on this compromised system this is
superb awesome you have been monitored
there is there is that means traitors
are behind you the locks are better
scaling privily is out in windows are
consistent but it's difficult to just
scaled privilege and linux internal
recognition you start knowing who is
behind you on the network lateral muchos
you're jumping from one mission to the
persistency we have to be permanent we
have to remain it's a scythe is a cyber
defense attack we are doing
cyber-espionage of tension information
we steal information from X filter
information this is the bomb show and
permanence or end up the mission oh ma
this is awesome this guy is
dealing with this over the past two
years and somebody discovered who did
apt1 there is the company discovered a
bit in one where it's a beginning of the
time there's gonna move into a case
study practical film listen the lies a
practical case back to the year 2000 an
important government institution any
institution is a real case i have a
friend a friend of mine face stitch
number one this my friend is not being
paid those jobs made and down for the
government my friend deliver he's just
probably he full field and was committed
with the deadlines my friend
made a complaint through the natural
institutional procedure oh you'll ever
have to pay for my job is so much money
stitch be my friend and made in report
through scanning the recognition of the
target and analysis of the institutional
aim I'm going to off and mess
around with them this ministry face to
do compromise exploit sure we have
compromised immune Street systems pays
300 pack them off let's go to the back
door into the system pays for it I'm
verification of privileges this is it
this is the way it is recognition of
accessible machines when I can get into
I cannot find what I'm looking for and I
need lateral movement recognition of the
compromised system Oh another back door
just in case let's see what happens just
in case the back door does not work
properly localization of the back half
of this organization and the exchange
because corruption goes through email
because of somebody people nobody's
going to riddle people thin and when you
send an email nobody's going to read it
just the opposite with talking about
cryptographic systems bad PSP is working
with the PCP was invented extraction of
interesting information from the system
reconstruction of the server redeem
threats with the back and black clothes
for the next day end of the mission my
friends did apt in the year 2000 it's
the same the same applies
the in the cars change the fact that ok
that the monitor is the robot the robot
on board changes the methodology in
vehicles like this we may not know how
to name it it was not categorized as apt
d but this dates back to stems from the
beginning of the times another it fam
this is awesome mic pres
resilience when I hear this term for the
very first time I freaked out resilience
means in such a way that they have
backup system when a gift packing guys
are destroying you create an infinite
loop of recovery in the back cap this is
resilience around these we can talk
about a validity of critical data and
applications business applications
stable stability of the recovery
recovery of IT structure and capacity of
recovery within a disaster if you are
backed off every day you cannot recover
this is life imagine we are savage
beauty is a business the fish get is a
multi-millionaire business we're talking
about how much money is going to move
through cyber security is the new
bubbles the new virgin so we have too
many new things you need to have a
backup copies otherwise they won't pay
attention to you if I tell you you are r
is you have resilience oh the marvelous
way you are frightening the guys play
hard resilience in my building I don't
know so you have the child appetit you
to put 200-600 things to a guy that has
an extra backers but they dispersed on
these continue to business availability
soil zone I forgot about 10 by the way
the malware this malware I can't even
tell it
these sophisticated Juarez is invading
the antiviruses my god oh the original
had poor crack Ted ticketmaster and
Victor i bought the original ones maybe
maybe may nguoi this one with the typos
and mrs. spells chapter chapter one
chapter one of output grab your first
Troy young undetectable by viruses
discreet the first ring that no viruses
can detective d stick back to 2000 for
you jump over antiviruses this is not a
new thing that is always the same all
the same so if we tend to give these new
labels and names because the business
must go on and on and on own this is all
about money on business there is I can
do this with the learning machine of
machine learning another example o
people fader hackers was invented
there's some guys who wrote this book
hackers year 2001 this guy for me is my
hero because one of them it's super
important he's super important let's see
if I can find it passwords
in berkeley in the genus berkeley
assistance instead of having a 10
characters they mix them at capital and
small letters in characters
heterogeneous characters and some
numbers this have been working for so
long in time that consider is saved
passwords I in but we are telling the
same staff in 2015 password is still
Antonio point comma 1 2 3 / same style
as they said in the year to 2000 there's
another boot dating back to the year
1991-92 in hardening policies and data
centers they tell the same story same
style but it's so cool for the human
means it means not to know something new
we are too repetitive we are repeatedly
we are repeating the same stuff over the
past 35 years oh no the artists real
safe and secure passwords so
technological solutions for these IT
issues there are so many solutions they
are not too bad manufactured technology
is technology period as vehicles nobody
trading in the Nasdaq some of the nard
Babs only some of them the normal
things that technology exists in you can
do fabulous things if you get into lab
computer technologies exist period
secondly perhaps these rigs are not the
rig's that we have to face in confront
in the days in a grassroots movement but
we need to discover the corporate rigs
at a planet institution organization
we're going to enter the Citizens
Council thanks to the existence of these
rigs that we cannot vision as a no
decision we're gonna do this we're over
the next 15 years i'm going to spend
less time with you about within 15 years
in time we'll be doing the same style
The Rake's what are the rigs I said we
have to acknowledge ease
and we are having more and more
technologies trying to avoid ABT they
did to the year two thousand and two so
here's comes to play oh the part I
really want to do to mention as they the
other words molarity succeeds top ten
humankind polarities human being is full
of bangla villages the many of asking
members not only have won balor team at
many of them and their beans that have
all the possible molarity is facing the
tyrant this superb nurse the greed the
born responsible or pseudo
responsible person charged organization
who does not who does not listen to
their employees because this head is
supposed to be in the universal truth
when I start talking with this so-called
not your person especially things okay i
have so many certifications here he
prides himself in down in that in the ad
in that it would what the are you
calling me sphere supposed to know
everything is boring talking
with you i'm gonna stroke i'm going to
scrub antonio this happened these people
are superb no not super they are
conceited conceded if we create if we
create soldiers in origin let's purify
these conceded people let's try to get
rid of their people who believe above
the rest of one discrete ethical groups
collaborating honestly with their fellow
members greed which is another capital
of sin oh I want everything for me
accelerated as for me courses as for me
this exists in any organization
especially is so greed so mean so
tight-fisted but he plans to sell
in a bottle for their own children my
goodness we are able to are you willing
to sell your daughter
yes if you buy my daughter now I will
tell you my daughter she gonna like it
my god is the greed the greed 00 luxury
and lush lush is another that matter
Harry matter Harry exists since that
very first world war a guy and a lady or
a man with looking pretty awesome
beautiful get into any kind of web
season this is the way it is this is
life the super booby girl or the super
manly a guy jumps off and over any fire
word innovation and end up in the table
then I don't know why but and that's on
the table I'm not I don't know in what
position but this person ends up on that
table and sending out emails with the
guys in my account well those working on
that out you know the lazy people lazy
people Oh specialist in simulating that
he's been something with the team oh you
know that is the the laziest person they
were in people champion that he worked
but it's not like this and this is
worming through your mind this is Oh
attacking your help so many lazies 0 MV
now MV in Spain part I'm MV in Spain
should any cyber security challenge in
existence in in the Europe of course MV
is the capital stayin in Spain the one
writing practice putting fire on that
diskin people
these kind of people are typical I was
having a lack of self-esteem they were
robbed of their sandwiches at school and
some somebody like me um I stole some
sandwiches when I was a teenager but
these dis envious people shake hands
with you this happens with your team's
work instead of still as a friend
success or a college success you see it
as namely how the worst thing is that
somebody about you I can only see one
thing I only had my intelligence and
talent the word the is thing in
life is that you have somebody above you
a cheat that shutter you scream at you
and many of us feel reflected Oh
wickedness intrinsically in the human
being here's a son of bitch period
there's Peter people who buy net by
nature genetically are evil destruct
they like to destroy like scorpion a
scorpion will always fight in a stealing
you they're bad guys villains in
organizations les legs X to pay them and
they're also there is also in vicinity
all faculties schools and who replaces
have either an imbecile people this is M
link in the chain because they are
innocent okay they tell somebody and do
you think that you're gonna date a
russian girl common sense please how is
this russian blue girl it's good to have
you this is spamming sequentially stab
you cannot offer her a nap at all is
that double click magic
he um he ate the date poor guy this
imbecile and Edith person and that
treason treason towards the organization
in the group if youth if we were able to
create IT security groups avoiding and
minimizing these failures because we
cannot extirpated from the human race
you will end up having indestructible
people highly trustworthy team not
secure we always say this is trustworthy
acquitted man and we should need an
infinite cost guardian total security
but treason treason in the best of the
moment the one who betrays the the team
and this happens the coolest guide able
to die what you having beers and today
I'm going to die for year having beers
this is this is like to rent an actor
playing with a spain soccer did
them hooligans through the scarves on to
them and we lost we missed one women
strong this is so I'm fed out with the
Millennium boys and native things people
that were young in the nineties thing
okay internet belongs to us those who
were young in the eighties nineties and
in the first two year two thousand years
there's an intricate power of being the
first nation able to change the world in
a real way the trees on mb and private
ladies are behind this is not going to
happen unfortunately but we are the very
first generation able to change the face
of this planet but we are missing the
native digital guy I'm fed up with this
naked date of this guy moving a mission
around the tablet oh there's gonna be
awesome this is grown and
growing more and more at a higher level
on the YouTube star they watch so many
your advice and all of a sudden they
grow mature and they study decent little
wig university degrees because they have
to monetize education education becoming
a business and they want to make money
out of your your parents plot by doing
business oh you first do a little degree
than the master postmaster but the main
thing is to be a literate person how to
learn to write and read everything on
the internet everybody things I can
reach everything people on the dole
unemployed Oh many of these D
terminators will be limited because our
degrees the fact of the system but there
is one we can savage and reach the CEO
position and these see this guy in
Dustin SCE oh this is the biggest danger
internal substitute security in a
company my friends this guy can freak
out with any coolest thing with from is
indeed connected and start changing the
orientation because I like the coolest
Ubuntu I couldn't do it with debian
ubuntu means i couldn't having all this
stuff with debian of a sudden
accompanied with 5,000 employees
everybody has no more idea down open
office I'm a digital native these this
guys have to be a stop and referendum
from the season let's stop them let's be
selective don't create cards done they
fight God people and super hacker you
have invented the vaccination against
the AIDS have you save and savage the
life to fight thousand five hundred
million people know so don't don't
vernacular is don't be don't be been a
glorious don't they fight somebody don't
consider that person a God be God is not
a man out of time I will be expelled
from the room
this affects my team the Europeans
sophisticated challenges not disclose
something awesome very important
I didn't see this is common sense
lattice come on sis technologies are
come on send eighty percent people
thinking 20 lines of codes not 80
committing mistakes of combination no no
80 people drawing 20 lines of course and
Damien book node which is super
important object there is no guy being a
hacker having this object they have to
have this object put it on trial with it
is tested proof on the European
sophisticated changes has been tested a
guy when the the bridge and the god
service to crack I don't know what did
the cryptographic defiance they're gonna
plan and Danny my friend daddy gave me a
notebook and a piece of paper and a pen
no he said a pen a pen because he likes
you something that is over there and
common sounds in Danny they in the
Indian the creation and the talent have
been an engineer of writing down on a
node will they freak them out they
freaked out Brits and Romanians this is
a dainius notebook I want to keep it
like this as such the product is to
think in to rationalize to abstract the
promise and technology will have will
give us the technologies and the tools
to resolve the sort things out there's
nothing new the word is more and more
complex compared to 20 years ago you
have the big chance no party to sorting
sounds to create a better deterrent
secure lies because I'm gonna leave the
flow as soon as possible thank you for
your participation for your time should
have any questions please raise your
hands thank you
so I splichal muy bien I'm a good
explainer do a spell things out properly
please proceed hello my comrades brain
teresting and talk if we educate the
current future generations do you have
an knowledge in some colleges schools
are you added taking this into account
very good question the investment of a
country they're the real asset is
education the minors in Spain we are we
are specialize in creating snow where
smoke creators in at reds in props
behind there's nothing in iconic ins
conceived teachers at school my habit 20
year old the child who knows much more
under his teachers educational effort
has to be if we live in detail work
let's make investment on the digital
world which is education now school
network teachers pupils is not worth and
having a super technology college could
eat the teacher hasn't have my idea of
touching the power it does my answer
this is that's what see it that was it
okay got it that guy the bag he's
written his hand
I have a question about the digital
natives I would like to tell a short
story I'm a networking technician my
company a girl i came in i had to do
repair Oh computer by her side and he
was but she was putting in and back a
USB they're putting in and out what is
she dis lady doing he expected that the
automatic start of the competing with
lunch and do you think sir that did it
tell nate is maybe something been
invented by us to justify that they had
been born with technology but they don't
know how to manage it that's the point
native detail needed do not exist that's
the point least a lipid natives do not
exist if I were born with a tablet but I
wouldn't I I was some Superman at a time
I will now be able to manage the talents
my son the one who is in this and if you
with it tablet is going to be in pencil
with the talent they won the smart guy
with the tablet is going to be a smart
guy with the tablet but if we had to
keep things moving this way please don't
be too trespassing people otherwise we
have stopped working any more questions
please
no more questions st. Thomas of Aquino
niche Plato Aristotle it's very
important to read philosophers we are
losing this habit especially Nietzsche
some Thomas of Aquino are taught to play
to the big philosophers of antiquity
Antonio my question refers to the mobile
hackers um smartphones how are they
connected to the computing through brute
tooth in what way your model phone can
be hacked through a computer through a
computer you know the attack it would be
usable through your intelligence about
the reception I would attack the object
the target that is the same if you try
to compromise your computer by
introducing and malicious software that
will be launched when you synchronize
with your iPhone in your backup copies
is more complete than visiting internet
from your vodafone websites and
compromising the mobile security is your
smartphone the possibility exists but
things are easier than with all how am I
going to collapse against a tower if I
can get into the house through the
kitchen the mole phones are real
computers that can suffer the best same
attacks as any kind of computer but they
target is easier to compromise through
their mobile phone through navigation
reception the reception's of mms
messages yes rather than the opposite
through a computer ready for you to run
into plug in your Android or iPhone
which are very different can get into
your computer another question for
example just tell this telephone career
very late Lane has been off friend for
free smartphones
it's very simple from a smartphone into
extract all the phone contacts in what
way what do you suggest I would what
would be your recommendation for people
having and smartphones and they don't
want to risk and compromise their
contacts information this is going for
many people I'm fed out of helping
people that they don't want to be helped
that's true many people don't care about
them did not like being helped we have
to invented this concept of privacy that
good professor can you reclaim when you
have the fight house and friends on
Facebook many people don't want privacy
or intimacy but you want purposing
intimacy in the sense is that there are
tools there are enough technology to
safeguard in such ways safeway in
information on your mother phones
containers privileges with
authentications before and against that
access with all these apps you can some
extent the alternative markets because
official markets about being in a
committed to do this from Charlie milord
and the cooler full of malicious app I
need an app to check out biography is
please don't ask me for my graph is
don't ask don't ask me for access in my
contacts attendin apps trying to contact
somebody within 25 meters away from you
that can be a serial killer they start
asking for access to your friends
contacts agenda your friend may be
around you geolocation we need to jee
loke locate you you can add application
only for reading something and you
volunteer and you excel so many things
that have nothing to do they make no
sense with what you wanted to use with
that like this the things about
sensitive data on your mobile phones and
the premises
oh I'm worn out with so many questions I
talking talk about philosophy they are
deleting philosophy in the schools no
pupils study philosopher any longer he
manages this is just very important I'm
working in in the in in freshman
critical infrastructures within a
security department I want to ask you
because you have a longing Spears what
type what about mistakes things we
engineers on the critical
infrastructures week how can we improve
critical infrastructures yes I'm working
within I'm working as an engineer for a
spatial base critical break on a space
station out kill few people about
critical protector if you are this is a
joke and you know this critical
infection is a Chow period I have
experience with ritalin fracture
infrastructure when I'm getting through
these channels and tunnels I want to
lead these channels as soon as possible
many more things do not happen because
God does not want it we need to feel
discomfort actors with thinking
engineers not with civil
servants engineers promoted to level 29
are still turret who cannot understand
what you are telling him the most stupid
things is talk to a human planned and is
by the way there's the chief when the
big issues cam we have a steaming smoke
balls on the newspapers on the TV we're
going to invest on talent in here but
you are still doing the same thing you
are doing the same thing but the very
truth is my answer pretend
infrastructures our priority are not
well protected and they need talent and
good engineers and engineers have taken
care of everything they hope you have
embedded everything and they have to be
the commanders of the protection
the critical infrastructures period yes
oh no shoot an arrow a pissy faucet and
I'm not an engineer myself I'm a map guy
any more questions please oh please let
me wrap up please please tell me hey I
want to ask you we are within this world
of hackers you are broadcasting this
program on the Discovery max Arden are
you not showing more parts of Wi-Fi ah
did some other embarrassed because you
you were prohibited from doing so or you
have are having afraid of bad use when
you are on TV when you are broadcasting
programs on TV you need to do you have
to transform it complicated this course
to the normal everyday people you need
to address our everyday people on the TV
we need to simplify contents on TV
that's the reason let's get that if
we're starting the googling enough to
see the chain of connections or database
and the user the viewers will stop
seeing this product so we need to come
they complicated stuff in a very simple
way we need to get things across the
beat to the people in a simple way the
one who knows the thins know that this
is replicated this way as I'm a double
check that this is replicable in
whatever environment by a know how
person but on TV you need to speak in
plain terms TD is not a textbook or a
professorship of engineering or mmm
static odd projective geometry this is
not to be any more questions let me go
get trans players we're gonna leave you
around we're gonna let you go drown
yourself I struggle the philosopher very
firstly
have you ever seen the little egg we saw
during my presentation should be able to
see I'm not a jihad persons huh I'm not
a Deaconess if they know the order and
dilemma and then not the macho and then
low I will give it away i will get away
a collection of this red channel say
keep this little egg that the fear of
some mommy time on the picture the order
religious order and the macho that this
little this little egg appear once on
screen during my presentation I will
give you away sambit Fukudome
documentaries from my TV show