bienvenidos de novo a fever cam doors
milk in say oh sanam and hacer este
ultimo dia este gran event oh we're
going to start the third and last day of
these marvelous event this without
finish so many activities workshops
still to be conducted the first paper
Marc Emery he is competing an engineer
and he got a master and sciences of
information and telecommunications doing
to this last year of studies he focused
on cybersecurity is working on the tools
as to detecting and responding to
incidents and over the past two years
it's been part of the advanced European
cybersecurity standard is really a
pleasure to have you here abduction
basically I don't speak Spanish silenced
I don't know to say anything but hola
como estas so I don't need to hell this
presentation on English so yes how come
that I am into into bitcoins well
basically as as a member of creation
national cert we had a lot of situations
that lot of situations of blackmailing
for example recently we had one hackers
group in Croatia that that was doing d
dos attack on on some firms in Croatia
and they were asking for ransom in
bitcoins and as well we we often know
that there are many runs somewheres
around the world and ransoms are always
in bitcoins and of course as my my job
is to to catch criminals I started to
wonder myself would it be possible to
the anonymize the Bitcoin addresses that
those criminals are giving to to do to
the firm's that the addresses they at
which they want their payments to be to
be made and yes basically I started to
research what what are my chances to D
anonymize to the anonymize some Bitcoin
address so I suppose everybody here who
is interested in this presentation know
something about Bitcoin but for those of
you who does not know anything I made
just a brief introduction just for the
sake to to introduce main elements that
one needs to understand to to be able to
to understand the an elimination methods
basically there are two complementary
dan a musician methods one is
transaction graph analysis and another
one is real-time network analysis and I
will say something about how each of it
works what are the chances to D
anonymize anything and can i have some
realistic expectations of of those
methods ok so let's start with
introduction so what do what is bitcoin
bitcoin is a peer-to-peer network where
users are transacting after sending
digital money between each other and the
appears that our actual users are
generating transactions and broadcasting
them on network and they are
broadcasting those transactions to
to each fear that is neighbor of the
pier in question and as and then
subsequent peers are transacting further
so in the matter of few seconds the oil
network is aware of of some transaction
that took place thank you wrong
so on the other side there are there is
a subset of all those beers coal miners
that are collecting those transactions
and putting them on the pile and
together together with with those
transactions they are adding some random
data that in such way that that the
hedge of of of those collected
transaction + + beta is generating is
generating cash which meets some
specific condition those that search is
not easy to find and miners need needs
to be fast and need to be lucky to be
the first one who will who will generate
who will generate the block minor that
first generates the book is broadcasting
that block to the network in same manner
that our transactions are broadcasting
and so basically basically block is
containing transactions and all peers of
our learning are learning blocks
individually every pill for itself but
at the end at the end there is consensus
which I will not talk about it is
outside of this of this talk there is
consensus that that put state that every
peer actually has a same same sequence
of of blocks on their computers and that
sequence of blocks is called blockchain
the blockchain is basically a set of all
transactions that ever took place in the
Bitcoin network
ok so now I start with the first method
of the anonymization and that is
transaction graph analysis so here I
need to say something more about
transaction itself so in the picture you
can see that transactions are are split
on two parts that is input part and
output part on the input part are all
Bitcoin addresses that are sending
letters ending the bitcoins and the
output part are all Bitcoin addresses
that are receiving the bitcoins so wise
transaction graph and I was possible
because the blockchain is a public so
everybody can see but though he is the
public identity of those Bitcoin
addresses is hiding so Bitcoin address
is basically just hash of the public key
of the user of the user that is that is
owner of that of that key pair and and
as picture suggests there is there is
three main three main concepts that you
need to be aware of to to be able to
speak about the anonymization so the
first first concept is that input is
always equals output so if you have 10
bitcoins and you want to pay some to
somebody something worth of seven
bitcoins you actually need to pay us to
spend all ten but three bitcoins that
are left over you need to to pay to
yourself back so therefore therefore as
if you look the second rejection
you have always you he'll always one
additional bitcoin address that is
actually changed address and that is the
address when you when you paint the
coins back to yourself except except
that their resolves or transaction fee
as you can see on picture and
transaction fee is the reward for the
miner for his effort to to secure the
network and if what if transaction if
transaction fee is what is the section
feel bigger the miner is is taking your
transaction as as privileged transaction
to to be included in block what is
complimentary if you don't pay the
transaction fee then you may wait quite
a bit to to get confirmation that you
really did you really paid something how
to do anonymize using block chain so how
is possible to the only anonymize
something if you have only Bitcoin
addresses that looks like random random
data so basically to there are two
concepts that allows the the
anonymization first concept is wallets
so basically every user is his owner or
is very often order of multiple between
addresses and when he is doing big
payment to somebody some big payment and
he have no enough enough coins on one
address he need to use one input side he
need to use many you need to use many
addresses in order to execute
transaction so basically when we see in
block chains on transactions that have
multiple they have multiple Bitcoin
addresses on input side
that means that all of those addresses
are owned by same user so that is not
the anonymizer user but it is something
to know that they are all owned by by
same user by same entity so in that way
the wallets are actually proof or
SharePoint drove so if you see that some
transaction is assembled from multiple
between addresses they all belong to the
same user second thing that that enables
the D anonymization using block chain is
the fact that many many people are
publishing their Bitcoin addresses
publicly on the web so for example on
many forums you can find people people
making signature using their their
address and on blockchain that info
which is main block chain Explorer
there's an option to tag itself so you
can if you are running some service or
some website you can you can and some
service where you are somebody needs to
pay you something you can add your
Bitcoin address to to the text so people
can can use this this registry to find
you so basically what we can do is by
crawling the web by crawling the forums
by crawling the bleep block chaining dot
info they are not have some specific AP
so it is need to be done by crawling we
can collect all tagged addresses other
way of collecting of collecting tags
ebah is by to say active pinging so for
example if there are some merchants
places on
web and you want to know which which
Bitcoin addresses they are using for
payout you can on purpose buy things
just to generate transactions to be to
collect all those addresses okay so now
when we when we are aware of concept of
wallet and on concept of tagged users we
can use method of clustering to actually
produce even more even more Doug
addresses so there are three there are
three main three main things about
clustering to remain methods that that
are to be used first of it is leaking
different inputs to the same user so if
you have two transactions one with
inputs a and B another one with inputs B
and C it is obvious that and E and B and
C are belonging to the same user so in
this way if you have users with a lot of
Bitcoin addresses on time by time you
can achieve very quick expansion of that
cluster another thing is tagging
clusters so when you have a way with
when you were doing the the first step
of licking different dimple inputs the
same user you achieved very big cluster
and if you are able to find any of
address from that cluster to be
associated to any of doug's you can
immediately you can immediately tag all
cluster to belong to the same user and
finally when you have clusters different
clusters that are tagged with same user
you can combine all these clusters two
to one single user as I exactly such
approach was done by the researchers of
university of california in december of
2013 so it was just in the time of
bitcoin boom when price rise
exponentially as well as hashing power
they passed block chain and basic people
now there is on github few different
available projects that are that are
doing data doing softwares for for
efficient parsing of blockchain and in
the analysis of December of 2013 they
managed to extract 60 million resections
and 12 millions public is that is 12
millions of Bitcoin addresses and when
they did clustering based on the method
I set on previous slide they managed to
produce 5.5 million of clusters and when
they combine clusters using using the
third method they end up with two
thousand clusters less which is not
something but but there there was for
example a lot of clusters that were type
2 then main crypto crypto currency
exchange empty box and that they
excluded so-called sync addresses for
this from this clustering sync addresses
are our addresses that that on some
bitcoins and those bitcoins haven't been
spent since 2011 so two years after
Bitcoin was invented so though those
addresses are belonging to users that
was a part of Bitcoin experiment and
actually they probably thought that it
will it will never worth anything so
they just lost their wallets and add at
that point in December 2013 sixty-four
percent of all bitcoins
were actually in sync addresses so
unable to use so in circulation was only
like thirty six percent and now is in
circulation about sixty percent okay so
there are some privacy recommendations
taking into account that everybody is
aware that the animation is possible so
use new addresses to receive payments
this recommendation is there to enable
somebody to see to see what types of
what types of transacting you are doing
other one is to use multiple bullets for
different purposes so if if somebody
enforces this privacy recommendations in
that case i'm unable to i'm unable to
expand the cluster quickly and third one
which is the most important one bitcoin
address should be only used once that
means that whenever you are paying
something and you have leftover that
leftover you should you should pay to
newly generated address and not to
already existing one why is that why is
that important so if you if you have
change and you return you return change
to your own address then it is obvious
from the picture from the picture then
it is obvious that a paid be and if you
in the case if you if you if you paid
something to to to party then it is
obvious that you paid to B and C but if
you use the newly generated address so
in the in the second row first picture
then it is not it is not obvious if you
if you paid to to Bitcoin address B or C
and even further if you if you use the
same privacy recommendation and then
from your change see you pay to to to
party d and leftover is e from the
perspective of somebody he doesn't have
any clue who is who is the player who is
to pay so that is the most important
recommendation and it is possible to go
again sir and this the same researchers
from University of California managed to
actually to add change address to the
inputs no matter it is so much it is so
much hard to recognize so basically
there is there is multiple multiple
types of change handling methods that
wallet software are implementing and but
but basically they are they're all
they're all following same policy that
change is always added to newly
generated address and user can user can
turn off that option which is not good
for him because then is easy to to
recognize the change address obviously
so there is no any exact algorithm how
to recognize change address but there
were there were some efforts first
efforts was to use the fact that user
really issued transactions to two
different users and this is completely
obsolete now because for example on
gambling sites where you have game that
wins multiple people then they are
making payouts to to multiple persons so
you can't use that fact the second the
second fact change address amount is not
greater than lowest input amount now
this is
to see illogical because if change
address amount is greater than lowest
input amount then it means that you
could execute that payment without that
lowest input amount but well it's
authors are aware of that and their
office getting that in the way that they
are always always using the shame of
taking the set of input addresses in
such a way that you can't use this dis
approach and the third one heuristic
approach is change address is used only
in one output overall pass transactions
this is the actual the best approach and
only one that can be used nowadays so if
if the change address is used only only
once is use only if change if change
addresses use only one output over all
pass transaction that means that
actually the you are you are tracing you
are tracing this this third privacy
recommendation but a question is is it
safe because maybe somebody made payment
to someone who still didn't do any drugs
acting at all so that is the only
problem in this approach so now we're
going to see results of change address
heuristic that that took the third the
third approach so edge to input list all
addresses that is used only once it
output overall past transactions and
this kind of experiment resulted in four
million change addresses and it was
thirteen percent of false positives they
managed to recognize false positives
based on the fact that when you are
looking into blockchain
when when you are looking into block
chain in one point in the time all
transactions that are up in the in the
in the blocks are actually read sections
that took place in the future so you can
see if that output address was actually
used again if yes that means you have
false positive but when the when they
started to to to take a better look of
those false positives they under stay
managed to understand that twelve
percent of those addresses were actually
paid back addresses so it was used by
the service that is that is paying back
the money on the on the same address get
you use to two by two by whatever that
service is offering so it turns out that
actually it is only one percent of false
positives and if they they try to
further it with some improvements and
they actually try to wait for one day so
they can see if the address will be used
again and in that way they reduce false
positives to zero point twenty eight
percent in one week if they wait for one
week they reduced to zero point seventy
percent but even with zero point seventy
percent they end up with mega cluster
retaining all these services so what
happened is that there was a few of
addresses that managed to link clusters
together and they were actually not
change addresses so you have complete
disaster only because of few addresses
but then they they actually took another
another view on the on those specific
addresses and what happened with them
and they realized that some addresses
were used twice as twice two times
exchange which is completely
not something what would you will not
see every day and so they excluded those
case and they end up with 3.5 million of
change addresses there was no mega
clusters again and they managed to tag
to talk two thousand and 197 clusters
which is eight point one point eight
million addresses and they started with
1000 of target addresses so with the
approach of collecting addresses from
from forums of active pinging of the
collecting tags from blockchain fo you
are able they collect 1,000 of Doug
addresses they end up with one thousand
eight hundred times more so it's really
good result how this can help me in my
work so basically I hardly doubt that I
will we dis method directly the
anonymize the the the adversary did the
attacker the the criminal but what what
is possible is to is to find rejections
where for example crypto currency
exchange made the direct payment to
today to their criminal of all the
criminal did direct payments to to
exchange if there is investigation open
about this case in Croatia then I can
with the effort to flow for law
enforcement agencies I can basically
catch the attacker in in in that way but
without investigation I am probably not
able to do anything
okay so that will be that will be it for
transaction graph analysis now I'm going
to tell you something more about
real-time network analysis which is I
think more more interesting excuse me
so real-time network analysis it's
basically methods to linking Bitcoin
addresses to IP addresses so this is
something different than leaking Bitcoin
addresses to some tags find find on
internet this method is possible to
distinguish different users even if they
are behind network address translators
so if you have multiple Bitcoin clients
behind behind not this method is able to
to label to label different different
clients even if they using same public
IP address i will i will say later why's
that possible and method is able to link
different reactions to same user even if
they look completely unrelated in
transaction graph analysis so if i was
unable to to link some addresses in the
transaction graph analysis real-time
network analysis can do it so basically
real-time network analysis is can
enhance the the transaction graph
analysis ok so what is the problem
problem is of course using a proxy
because then you do not the undie
anonymize the the actual IP address of
user but you DNT anonymize the IP
address of proxy and actually there is a
solution for that and that is to simply
shut down bitcoin overt or functionality
so i know that it sounds amazing but
actually it is possible to do you can
shut down the whole Tor network and it
is it is quite simple to to be used by
any users and i will explain that in the
moment so actually we need this we need
is this shut down so we can observe the
real-time network analysis on cleanit
like there is there is no anonymization
techniques used bitcoin is fear to be a
network but actually we could use we
could we could share the the the peers
into different categories when is the
peers that our clients and other the
peers let our servers i put under the
the codes because it is not really
client-server architecture but rather
the thing is that clients are the peers
that are able only to initiate outgoing
connections so those are home users and
servers are peers that are able to
receive incoming connections and each
beer whether use whether server or
client is trying to connect to eight
entry nodes so bitcoin have network
discovery mechanism that is used for
each for each client to to be connected
to eight entry nodes entry nodes are of
course always servers because clients
can't see each other so basically a
bitcoin does not use any natural
versatile technique but clients can
reach each other across the servers and
what is what is important to remark that
is that servers can take at maximum 117
incoming connect connections from from
clients and and everybody is initiating
eight outgoing connections so in total
there is 125 connections possible for
each beer
in this case only four servers so how is
possible to distinguish the clients with
behind not it is possible because this
approach of real-time network analysis
is is actually labeling clients in the
way that it is it associated it
associates clients with each entry nodes
so every every every client in this in
this technique is presented as its entry
nodes okay and just information that
currently there is 8000 servers and the
100,000 of clients in the network okay
so how to disconnect tour and in that
way actually have to say a clear
situation of dealing with with real-time
analysis on planet disconnecting tour is
possible by exploiting bitcoins does
protection building does protection so
basically when one peer is delivering
malformed messages to some other peer
that other peer is banning him for 24
hours so he is cutting connection for
with him and he is not allowing him to
establish another connection so now I'm
talking from the perspective of attacker
actually I will be attacker when I will
be doing this and the anonymous a shin
attacker needs to to establish
connection so first to say in this in
this scenario I'm observing that there
is only two exit nodes into our network
and only three Bitcoin servers so
attacker is establishing connection with
each server and sending a sanic
malformed message and he is doing so
going through each of exit nodes so in
this way you have the situation that all
servers banned all IP addresses of exit
nodes and now when when when we are
looking the plans of the the client part
of Bitcoin network and if they are if
they try to connect to to to network
using tor that they will be unable to do
it for the next 24 hours because all
servers are banned through all possible
exit nodes and I was watching recently
at store metrics there is around 1000 of
tor exit nodes and times a thousand
Bitcoin servers you get that you need to
upload one gigabyte of traffic of
malformed messages actually to exclude
all Tor network from usage for the
Bitcoin okay so first first part of
first part of real-time network the
anonymization is to learn entry notes of
clients to do so I need to explain
something about Ed address propagation
mechanism that is part of natural
discovery protocol in the in the Bitcoin
so what you say dress propagation it is
basically the mechanism that that is
making the network alive so nodes are
all the time coming and going and coming
to the network and go away from the
network and basically the Pearce needs
to learn
all the time which which are nodes
available so if their entry nodes are
lived if their network nodes leave the
network they are managing to find
another entry nodes addr message is a
message that every beer sends to each of
its connections after after after the
pier connected to the network so every
of his entry node is aware of of of it
address and those entry nodes are
propagating further in the network addr
messages so basically in the matter of
few seconds you have plenty of nodes in
the network that are aware of new of new
clients that that approach to to the
network that made connection to to the
entry nodes there is there is one detail
that is that is very very important and
that is that others are propagated in
the way that always is used to
responsible nodes each each node is
choosing to responsible nodes that will
receive the addr message and that will
forward the the addr message further in
the network and basically when one node
propagates some addr message with with
with IP address included he will not
propagate over that connection addr
message ever again so it happens only
once ok
okay I promise I will not go deeper than
this this is technically the deepest
thing of the presentation but i need to
say in order to explain the the attack
so how to how to choose responsible
nodes so when some peer receive addr
message he calculated hash for each for
each peer he is connected to and heshes
hashes the function of four variables
and that is the address X that is inside
addr message some random salt current
day and the address of peer structure of
the old appear that is that is candidate
to be choose as responsible notes after
that all hashes are sorted and first two
hash are chosen to be the responsible to
the responsible knows that the peers
that are associated with to first hash
when when heads are sorted okay so now
now I'm going to explain how to learn
entry nodes of some client see how the
tech are able to learn those entry nodes
in this very simple configuration where
you have only five servers and only
dozen of of clients so what attacker
needs to do is maintain a very big
number of connection with each server in
the network this way when the client
connects to to the network he chooses
some entry notes for example this case
client chooses entry notes two three and
four now when client start to propagate
its addr message with his IP address for
other nodes to know for his existence it
is to expected
that node number two will choose will
choose the attacker as responsible note
that because the fact that we have a lot
of connection of course so this way the
attacker will receive addr message over
over the entry notes of client c and
then the attacker notes that client with
with the address CA has entry knows 3 4
5 2 3 4 sorry but what is the problem
with this approach yes chances are big
for attacker to be chosen as the as the
responsible note because very big amount
of connection but also there is a
possibility that server choose some
other node as responsible and he sends
addr message to node 1 in this example
and let's say attacker was lucky with
other two and he received and he
received addr message over notes three
and four so we now have the problematic
situation where attacker learned that
address of client with with the address
see a has entry nodes 1 3 & 4 when that
is not a true he have entry nose 2 3 & 4
so we have a false entry inside the
inside the Associated list of of that IP
address we are trying to the anonymize
a solution to this problem is based on
the fact that same address is never
recent / same connection so the next
strategy is proposed it is proposed for
attacker to broadcast addr addr message
of the address he want to d anonymize so
that so that the responsible nodes which
are which are not a tackles one are
excluded it's hard to understand it
bye-bye words so I'm going to show it in
picture so basically attacker connects
to all servers and he sends addr message
of client c and servers are choosing
responsible nodes in this case servers
are having only one or two connection
and therefore they will they will choose
as responsible connections all the
connections on the on the picture now
the attacker disconnect and he connects
again with a very big amount of
connections to each server and now if
server decides to to have a responsible
node node one he will not be able to he
will not be able to to send the idd our
message over that connection because he
already did so and he's never doing it
twice as I said before so what is going
to happen is that attacker is going to
learn is going to learn entry nodes of
the client but only the subset of entry
nodes so he learned that that client
with address see a have a subset of
entry nose three and four now
some meth why is still the Animas ation
possible if we have situation that we
are unable to learn all entry nodes of
of some client we're basically peer can
be uniquely identified if we know only
three entry nodes and that is because it
is very unlikely that you have collision
of of two different of two different
client having the same seven the same
treatable subset of entry nodes so it is
very unlikely so the conclusion is that
you need only three entry nodes you need
to learn only three entry nodes in order
to 2d anonymize the de client another
thing is that if you if you are able to
maintain 35 connection to each server in
that case you stand fifty percent chance
to become the response responsible note
and that addr message is forward toward
over the attacker so that means that on
average of eight entry nodes you will
receive four addr messages and as I said
the three NT nodes are enough how often
to broadcast address experiment done on
University of Luxembourg show that 10
minutes seems to be reasonable choice so
the first part of strategy when you need
to broadcast the I ddr message that you
are trying to that contain the address
you are trying to do anonymize it's so
resending of of that address is needed
to be done each 10 minutes if you do it
if you do it more rarely than that if
you do it each 20 minutes you are
putting yourself in situation that that
that server can can change the
responsible nodes and then you can again
have the full century inside the inside
the set okay so what do we have at this
point at this point we have example as
example we have we learned we learned
entry nodes of three different of three
different clients CAC be and CeCe and
now is the question how to the Animas
transaction so how to know if some
transaction is belonging to node CA c b
or c c well this the animation is
possible thanks to thanks to next
propositions client and attacker are
connected with one hope over entry node
so entry node is only one hope and all
other connections between them are two
hopes or more so it is it is reasonable
to conclude that attacker will see
transactions coming from entry node
before then from any other of course
this is the reasonable to conclude but
for example network latency on the on
the links of between the entry node and
that end the end the client can be much
bigger than over some other parcel
network and in that case you may receive
transaction before from some non entry
node then from entry node of the client
randomize the anonymize so that is the
problem
but let's just see what what are used
for such thing to happen if if we
observe the situation when client is
directly connected to attacker through
entry node then we have a situation that
five messages needs to be exchanged 16
checks needs to be done by by the entry
node before he sends transaction further
because every node is first checking the
well is making the validation of
transaction before checking it further
and we have some random time that needs
to do pass before the transaction in
sent and if we have two hopes then we
have eight messages 32 checks and two
random trickling delays so basically it
is it is to expect that we will receive
the transaction before from from the
clients entry node then from some other
node okay and some final things for the
anonymous ation how is it possible to be
so
I'm going to demonstrate example where
we successfully the anonymized
transaction transaction 1 and just to
remember the entry no sets of clients
EAC be and CeCe were as follows okay so
we take first 15 transactions because we
are expecting that between first 15
transactions should be the entry nodes
of the of the client that sent that
transaction and when we are when we do
intersection with with entry notes that
we D anonymized we get situation that in
the intersection have so big personality
it's so big sets that it is and because
if CA or CB or CC generated transaction
so basically you can't know who
generated because you took too much big
to big set to bring set of of entry
nodes and on the other side you can take
very few of the nodes that first sent
the transaction and then you have
situation that intersection is very
small in this case cardinality of each
set is too so there is no enough there
is no enough cardinality to distinguish
client and I remember you that I said it
is needed to it is needed three entry
nodes it's near three entry nodes to to
distinguish some client the same
research from University look simple
show that best balance is actually first
ten first n nodes so if we take first 10
notes from frost and notes from the
ordered list from ordered list all the
all the transactions we received we have
situation that
only address CA have cardinality of
trees so note ca ca generated the
transaction in this way we actually we
actually managed to associate IP address
with way the transaction okay so
basically what what the guys from the
Luxembourg did they set up a test net
with 250 Bitcoin servers they wrote
custom attacker client using the model
that is available online writing in
Google language and they use the
standard Bitcoin core clients and from
such experiment they from from any
experiment they run they came up with
the numbers that I just talked about so
propagation of addr message h 10 minutes
is enough account for only first 10
notes to for a transaction entry entry
notes for a notification is seen from
the pure math it is not important to run
experiments as a result they manage to D
anonymize sixty percent of all
transactions okay and using statistics
for from such experiment using
statistics for such experiment they
actually calculated that successful the
anonymization in a real Bitcoin network
would be eleven percent in other words
you should you should wait for for a
client to send one average nine
transaction to be able to the anonymous
him how this can help me in my work so
direct the Animas ation which is highly
unlikely because that user is probably
using tor and of course I can exclude
tour but then is the question if he is
going to transact at all in directly on
animation so basically is somebody paid
if I manage to the anonymize somebody
who paid money to to to the to the
person that I am looking for or vice
versa and again I need to I need to have
the assistance of law enforcement
agencies for to come to informations
about about those persons just based on
the IP address and time stamp otherwise
I can do anything and also in
combination with transaction graph
analysis real-time analysis can be very
useful ok in just some final words so
network real-time analysis requires IP
address beforehand so basically I can't
be unwise anything if I don't have the
IP address already available so only
thing only thing basically what i have
is Bitcoin address of the of the
criminal even if i know in in in which
network he is situated i would need to
advertise all IP range of that network
just to be able to do naanum eyes him
estimate a success rate of eleven
percent for the animation is very poor
and I mean it's very hard to expect
somebody to send 99 transactions during
one session
and the 33rd thing is that I'm not
really comfortable with comfortable with
with doing so much connections on
servers doing 35 connection to each
server in Bitcoin network means the
group aggregating its quality of service
and I'm not really the person who would
do such thing and as I said success rate
is very poor however but I needed to do
this this research in order just to to
know what what are my where am i
standing with is and what are my chances
to do it and I thought it is it is very
interesting theme to talk about but I
think that I will stay on transaction
graph analysis for for for the purpose
of the anonymous ation and for sure
argonaut I will not use this network
approach so basically that is all thank
you thank you very much come on Rick
thank you