can you hear me it's a bit better okay
first what I would like to apologize for
the technical problems it's not their
fault it's my fault i had a mistake or a
problem with one of the ports here so
the idea that i have for today for this
speech is for you to leave the session
with a greater understanding thank you
learning to of how to think badly about
applications that's what i want i have
some tests prepared i brought them with
me to prolonged or to extend black
friday a little bit making the most or
exploiting faults in commercial websites
and I've brought an extra computer with
me to make sure we can do that so let's
hope we can have a look so if we don't
have for example if they don't have our
size it says our sizes ins available to
insist and ask for our size anyway and
then they'll the ones that'll have to
find it
and we need to show the fact that their
application could be improved so we're
going to talk about motivation if we can
get the cable I need because I think
it's actually very interesting for you
to see that the organizers can bring me
the cable I need but the motivation then
we talking about here is all about these
everyday subjects for in a conference
where Steve Jobs presented one of his
eye products they they people got VIP
entries VIP entries for free and this
was because the application didn't
behave correctly appropriately and
virtuemart extension for joomla this is
an example in which they managed to get
super user rights through execution of
her variable which was not validated
here this is one of my favorites Alex
holding managed to avoid the payment of
the ISC to how many of us he have the
certificate of you think so it's real we
is torture every time month of january
comes around and you say oh this year
how much is it going to be it's madness
hundred and twenty dollars i have a
match so in this case is c2 which is
what's requested by the cissp there was
an error and before the payment period
do you got validation and you managed to
get in without him to pay which is you
know which is great for us I've got more
examples here somebody in Illinois who
had their application for online
shopping somebody replaced the price
with a 0.1 and so they paid one cent for
all kinds of products these things
happen here we have another of my
favorites it's a bug in bugzilla so it's
like a kind of a repetitive bug and it
allowed you to achieve me or to kind of
leap over the validation of the email so
they got administration rights in the
application and here we're going to have
a couple of characters with us
accompanying us we are going to be
accompanied by a couple of people in
this presentation one of them is called
Paul on the left he's 27 years old he's
working you know he's been working for
five years already he works as an IT
engineer for a company which provides
shopping baskets solutions and this is
going to be really the essence of this
talk and what people can do with the
shopping basket and he's never really
paid attention to security issues and
his boss hasn't really either he wasn't
bothered about them although he was
aware that he wasn't really doing things
quite right here we've got Mike he's 22
he doesn't work he studies he's at
University and he kind of attacks the
applications that he finds on the web
because you know he enjoys doing that
and he's very aware of what it means if
your website is not really secure so the
story begins when Paul receives a
communication from his boss saying that
a customer has complained because
somebody is reporting web
vulnerabilities that have been detected
in our shopping basket you know do you
know anything about that Paul well well
he thinks well that's been there right
from the very first version 00 you know
he's never been concerned about it he
just wanted to make sure that the
application worked it was the much mum
too much hassle to think about whether
it was secure and obviously he something
would have got through to him and well
he had in mind what he would do in
you know in the event of having problems
and so it's pretty clear about what he
has to do and this is the application
that Paul has been using up till now we
can see the this car here from the
flintstones and now we decide he's going
to have lots of security is going to do
security he's going to go really
overboard he's gonna do everything use
everything even the stuff he doesn't
need is going to codify the entry you
know we're gonna eliminate non valid
characters we're going to codify the
exit everything we're going to cover
absolutely everything i can think of
West Tom it and of course shield measure
myself against everything here look at
the sessions and many other things and
I'll become this hotel from wrong stream
to the other and no one can get in here
it's impossible to override my
application bro were missing something
here and Mike is aware of this he knows
one given day
yeah well he hunks a 3am because he
can't sleep yeah you know these things
kind of happened you can't sleep when
you say okay we shall do tonight well I
look for some vulnerable machine she
going is there oh goodness i reported
this one month ago I see what happen
here and Paul enmity his application I
think if similar things got solved
because at least people listen to him if
I change a little number here and this
illegitimate to regret these might break
something will happen here
away
this will not render a pretty
but do you know you deserve some credit
when you get there and say well I found
a vulnerability after everything you've
done security-wise you're doing good
designers not not bad here I just got
something through new all the shelters
will after you shelter a total failure
shall fill with water we have abby's on
that is usually not explored which is
knowing how the application is
supporting the business processes and
going against this going against the
steadiest machines that are on the line
and this are the business logic attacks
and this is how Mike somehow managed to
own the pulse application so what are we
looking for in this room which color do
you think is the symbol our security
problems within an application regarding
business logic who goes with Bordeaux
green come on raise your hand ring over
there over here green yes it's green
actually
the application shouldn't have this
function but it is do it it is there and
we're going to veil of it for our own
profit so the business logic needs to be
tested and we're going to see a tool
there will hours to prove this I'm going
to look at a systematic methodology that
allows a suit at sighs my intention with
is beach or this presentation is to do
in half theoretical and half practical
so that right here you can see how
everything is that but I don't have
think I'll have the time to do
everything even though I will try to
explain how everything works and also
explain real cases are found that worked
really well so what is an abuse case
yes okay
let's see whether we now lacking can
look at practical aspects so regarding
the usage cases for those of us who
finished our degrees you've already seen
this we know how they work they are just
lists of establish an etek to make sure
that the application is functionally
okay and next we're going to have a
negative thorn burden I'm gonna have
someone evil there otherwise application
will go to production and so wrongly
evil out there we're trying to look at
the vulnerability it's not one but
100,000 evil people so we need to do
this before the applications go into
production so the abuse case it's just
an equivalent to the usage case he
doesn't even have a special symbols it
just artists a psych holder to that
negative thought there is no no no
symbols or a specific methodology that
are introduced this way is there anyone
here from the testing world not from
Ventus timber from testing so this is
basically a transcription of what should
happen within a cloud model with a
waterfall development regarding tests to
the business logic you need to look for
the key requirements we need to use the
usage cases available to assignment the
abuse cases whenever they exist if they
don't exist that can be created from
scratch we can do the workflows we can
look at how the brocation operates we
assess the vehicle data and we test here
because if this happens there might be a
mess in the company
I also need to detect to get a deep
understanding of the application to do
this we need to detect implementation
weaknesses and finally we need to put
them into practice all of these blunders
a lot of taking us to about so let's
look at a pulse of the catcher I'm gonna
stop here change the pc here and changes
at the end and check if everything works
so the application is a Bay version 001
this is from the vulnerable website
application haven't really touched
anything and you'll be useful to assess
this type of failures that might not be
included within the applications
development as such because he's
assigned us some sort of CTF where you
get different challenges and this one
wasn't there but I installed it and i
discovered that is it wasn't working
well you may disregard so as you may see
here the application
has basically a set of vitamins it is a
shopping basket application shopping
cart obligation with certain items with
a price and you keep piling them up you
just add them to your karting is just a
normal application source let's look at
what we can do to truck to test this
because we need to work harder night and
see what it does just having about a
contacting on an item search a part
where we have a shopping trolley and we
have a central core for business
processes which is logging and account
registration you access is left
detection you select an item you can
increase or decrease the number of items
you can add them to the cart you can
increase the decreasing number of items
and then you come update the card of the
basket the can't of the basket so he's
using normal application plug and within
this flow we have several critical
points where there are there may be an
increase of privileges and bonds with
content access where the class is
altered and this is a key parameter for
all these points
with Mike's thinking
thinking well I want to break this could
have access to private sections maybe
some of them are publish button i cannot
see them will happen see if i add a
negative number or wrong type in da
sections Lecter we're happy Singh I
Philly in the sessions are actor with a
number of more than 100,000 deeds could
I modify the price of items could I
modify the number of items without
altering the total price I need to add a
negative number of items it will be
possible to request non-existent items
with all items we published we're a
request a non-public one which would be
the maximum number of items to request
good a feeling filthy art yes you pay
for it great try and change the price
you enjoy update what happens if I do an
either update on an item that is not in
my cart there's something you can think
about in just two minutes you get there
and see it because you don't say okay
how can you break it but you need to
have a mindset set on breaking things
crying include a negative number of
items for an update this is equivalent
to that abuse case that's an abuse case
designed for this to ride around the
update for the number of items should we
select three items who will add them to
the car to would update the number of
items hanging this flow there is someone
who is a security tester who includes
these negative thinking includes a
negative number of items our house is
done because if it's limited by the
interface how do we do it by having
interception proxies which is bar suit
emboss we chose up so let's see whether
we manage to show how how this works
keep your active is to get a better
trust level in the treatment of the
items on the server side we have certain
preconditions things need to be in the
wrong place and the categories if you
have the items we need to execute this
case we have saying holders such as the
user in the tester in the description
let's say it's a place that will need to
follow in practical terms we can think
of this anyhow we want anywhere we want
there's an axle with this and we shoot
up you should assess abuse cases that
should be available right after the
requirements stage because the
development department needs to be aware
but they don't have time in development
but I need to be aware of the most
critical parts of the application if I
tell development well these are your
critical points development will take
into account in mind all of this just
like if they give them a set of security
requirements are gonna say ok validate
all the data inputs we have on server
and the sources vs special captures and
reject the request you can have that and
they will take that into account from
the beginning otherwise they're mine are
now about it because in development
they're not especially its own security
given I don't know how to program this
kind of application
think you would have the first half
maybe we can try to put the cable
meanwhile I'll sum up the three demos
will do a first mo with an application
that I've got hearing a trump card is
application not supposed by Paul
my booking even leave it here as you
wish nothing might be easier I do
apologize
estaba Civetta men
this goes through USB two breasty Babbo
or a este before way hey Aggie reston
enduro we connect this through vga
is that the hit
like you want to tell about Matt oh oh
I think it to get into if you got on
girls
I'll get it from tonight
oh yes I give Ric intimate with me
chief no no
this is working
okay might not be able to see it at the
end but we're going to show you a video
that I recorded and when we have
something we like in the back fire they
did all this we could ask for our size
and is not that because if I want it I
want it and on this heart we have
exactly the same thing we've seen in the
abuse case we don't have it here on a
video we have it locally and we assumed
he was enough of a guarantee the famous
is capture Amish ave deqing cuando vamos
a fair Emma here we capture the request
when we do an update we change the
number of items to a negative number so
what happens here the application gives
you money back because he calculates
there's a calculation with that number
you sent her and he gives you money back
and this seems funny but you may see my
yahwah's presentation which is online
you can see or about things zero cost
this is quite funny because I bought 20
counts there not recently I could still
do it and I was bringing my mum my demo
to keep buying a zero cost until
yesterday
yesterday I did the last test and I saw
that they had changed everything it's
wonderful
and I said okay so what now and I was
there until 5am and managed to
restructure the presentation in a check
that they were failures in the business
logic in other places that were quite
important well this has happened and how
I notify dancing it was a big commercial
but how did this happen all this happens
because very similarly you got there
with your shopping trolley to the latest
step to this step before the pavement
you get with that can't there you put
everything through a proxy recording all
the requests one by one he located on an
update request them with a forum account
and you did the update directly
nevertheless latest step of the last of
that being our lead the item to the
shopping cart with a number of items
that you have selected in the former
requests are zero cost because he didn't
have it he had an update operation or an
element didn't have there yes a business
it was not right and you could go to the
payment gateway with all your items you
could add whether you wanted socks or a
gym t-shirt and you got everything at
zero cost
that failure was in a commercial product
later I saw the same product or more
webs in the last one is this one this
was hit this one here was on exactly to
check how the same engage by his work
and these are most quite funny because
we can modify our requests you get to
the last stage and when you have
everything in your cart you go to the
Gateway for payments with your cart
casting with all the requests that you
did on the line that would happen here
always seems he's not it's not working
eventually but well let's continue here
we get to the last stage and then you go
to payment gateway and here you may
change the description and the M here is
to do a two by one so that we change the
description we kept the same route order
identification and we say okay instead
of a bedside tables you don't have to so
you change the description no one
validates it they do collect the prize
oh you change the price and they
validate it if you change the
description they don't validate it while
you are at the payment gateway the re a
service that is saving the cart which is
like can always punish son where's my
card what the cart is there a shopping
basket is there but you don't do a
controller in bars foot to repeat
through quests and you get another code
and what may happen here two things
first of the request does a callback and
when they come back they validate
whether you did any of these dirty
little things otherwise you're there
with your two items but a young paid for
once you get two for one two for the
price of one
and this was example that I might not be
able to show you that i do how this one
I was like oh this is so bad I can't
believe everything is fairly well nearly
si si le bajo money how much handing
down low okay let's try it when I show
you the video and if you agree we'll do
this online because it's quite cool if
you're in a hurry let me know but this
is really cool so when we get here we
are there a spoon for this website not
making anything up and you may say okay
there is a vest I like Black Friday
silver you know they're not many sizes
so here's like some mullah looking like
Justin Bieber he is a guy who can select
this it's not really my style
you know I'll get a green so it stopped
this here I think yes I did swap until
you change it yes I did change out I
like it better in green so here you have
lots of sciences you can't get why can I
not get these sizes why not who tells me
which size I should get so you get here
and you select an exercise your electric
cart and not there we see an item why do
we do this because we have a suite
behind we have a proxy requesting all
the recording all the requests and its
really doing among in the middle
operation to see everything so this is
one sweet and we got two requests we
look at them and be saw I hate two
different sizes vary to cart because I
want to know how to have things on the
one hand and whoa i want an hour's
underlying how these application logic
works so i want to know what is the
difference of having one item or a
different for us so if i can an item
that is limited by interface allow it
and here we have a number which is 05
and if we go again to the interface will
see that this number corresponds to size
m now the size we want this is mine I'm
not gonna get any other ok this is the
aim and what happens here and careful
because this spring full website was
okay until recently I don't know what
happen here wanna stop working and about
the other one but on a Springfield 12
website this house i will always worked
fine how they have sequential
identificate oohs and you can get a
repetition replay I want the MXL was
five XS plus one so mp3 I send the
request I get 200 ok so they're gonna do
an f5 on the page I get my new item up
there and then we go to the back
we go to our shopping cart he says well
are you trolling me how come you give me
these requests I don't know how to stop
well you don't have a stock tell me this
will work welcome to say earlier I said
well this is really good this is really
good but I don't know what happened here
access please eliminate the article is
not longer no longer available but well
but if I got here I do not intend to
eliminate it I in time to buy it so the
topic here is and he disables the
finished perch is buttons are okay I go
I live here with a humbug go 1212 you go
here you look for the field you modify
it because this is a static hm HTML and
since I have it I can do anything I want
with it so you get to hear you look for
the field will look up a feel little by
little locate it and we're nearly there
here is a disabled
and I don't like it so here it is we
have button will go to finish purchase
and obviously if there are other things
you don't want just a larger vests and
jackets you can give it to your uncle
over to everyone you can take them out
just leave your size and this is it you
got through there but then you can say
ok when I do an anonymous purchase sure
and you go to your car to your am in
everything colors but I'll report this
because it's been group is not good
anymore I don't know why and obviously
there's I would like to say this clever
here I'm not responsible for anything
that you do out of this presentation
this is last
demo all right let's see where we can do
another one online because it's a lot
more visual so you can see how
everything is done gradually let's just
try it and see whether we manage it show
it right once more
can we change you to hear
okay well thank you very much with away
let's try to approach with a cali
virtual machine anyone here there's no
cally well Carly is a line oxy solution
used to be evil and do evil things all
good things in my case
we can do it for the online shop for
means of payment let's do one of them
since on the video you saw the jacket
let's try to replicate it very quickly I
just take a little seat here think I'd
be more comfortable and make less errors
so here's our jacket yeah we have some
more here let's look at the sizes of
each of them
let's check whether some jackets are
missing some sizes this one doesn't have
XXL let's look at some lighter colors
let's go here I had look at one this
morning because I don't trust this
anymore
when I stage bad sweet Molly que hacer
por su un programa this boss with a
program that is placed in the middle of
the browser
and to continue we got a mother era
a ver vamos a entender Ferrari proxy or
you'll all read
na Shakara gay but to open this close
not
let's see if these works
so we have it here now
you just gotta live against me
so let's look at this here
and look at whether there is any problem
regarding the cookies
let's try to lead this
so cookies here yes maybe it's due to
this let me just check this whether it's
a connection problem well it's
impossible to get here because network
cable is not connected as simple as that
fire on with you salio el fil a for
Univision logic if you don't connect
network cable you can move not do the
demo cause I see almost
corinthian segundo cool pad
but how do spray
sighs y esto esta function so we're
gonna see if this is working
but they're not with you on the run it
okay so we got it working now here we
have the proxy recording requests we
have a proxy we can intercept things and
you come here and well we've got all of
the requests that are being made from
the website and we've got what the
website we've done it in the background
we've got the men's section we only go
to the coats and here we have our
favorite model here we're going to
choose this one just by way of example
and good they don't have my size so
we're going to simplify the
demonstration we're going to choose the
one here which is extra small xs we've
selected it we add it to our shopping
bag and here we have it but I want the M
I want we saw before so we go we take
the m we come here we can look where the
request is where it adds it to the
shopping bag or basket and here we have
the identifier since we have excess
there are two sizes between that and the
m size the medium size so we increase it
by two numbers which would be the
corresponding code we take this request
can we say
not we want a three which would
correspond to em we launched that
request it says okay that means it all
went fine we do a five
so let's see here we have it we've got
our two things in our shopping bag and
here we have it we have the M we go to
the bag
we have the proxy there we don't need to
telling works I put it there yes it's
mine
I mean come here and what we have is the
problem that we talked about earlier we
have this problem in the logic
it's not
while it's telling us that they don't
have that article and I just want to
order it anyway because I don't care so
this one I eliminated because it's not
my size what am I going to want an extra
small one for it's much too small for me
so from here we say we've got the
product that we want and now we want to
what we have to deactivate I'm sorry
wobbly it's deactivated we want to
activate it so we find it here we come
down here and we can look for the this
framework on that particular button
little by little it it's okay let's see
this is one bits over here around here
here we have it down here we keep
looking for it I'm getting closer this
one this one this one down the bottom
here we have this one
the table just below it
this one and then this one here we have
the filled set fieldset sorry and we're
getting closer to that button here it is
here we are disabled
that's not what I want let's see if I
can get rid of that
there we go so we've got rid of it so
now we have our purchase operation you
know it's activated and here we have a
shopping basket and I said I'd rather
buy like a guest I don't like including
information so here we are we have our
item and this is the address for them to
send it to us we can ask for it to be
wrapped as a present but here we have it
we have our item
hits in our website and they should send
it to us
so with this demo we've got this far and
now we're going to do the demo for the
means of payment because we're going to
do it quickly because I've registered
with my own information yesterday I did
that in advance
and here what we have is a bizarre
website you know I like tea sets I like
them I like tea houses and everything
related that and I want to have one of
these tables that they have how long let
me see if i buy some table slightly
having the tea houses
I'm gonna buy one it looks great doesn't
it snow beautiful it's really cool the
way whizzes across the screen as well it
looks great so I've got my little table
in my shopping basket and what we want
to do here is a two-for-one we want to
prolong Black Friday you know we want to
get one for free so we go to the proxy
and we're going to look at this one down
here this is what adds things to the
shopping basket and one option is to use
this request to add things to the
shopping basket once we're in the very
last step in the process but we're going
to go beyond that even we're going to go
to the shopping trolley we're going to
confirm
here we are here we're going to record
two requests one witching cruces it by
one and one which you decreases it by
one so let's have a look we've got to
post requests they go straight this one
increases in this one decreases so here
we want the one that increases they want
two for the price of one not one for the
price of two so here we go we continue
with the shopping process with one
that's the idea and we say yes I come
from Santiago de Compostela I'm called
mr. fake fake from nowhere street and I
go on to this follow step here this is a
commercial product I doubt that the
fault will be specific here
we carry on me carry on we can talk
about the invoicing method etc we come
to the last step which is delivery
conditions for delivery another thing we
could do for example the policies are
very important could anybody try you
know skipping the policies if you manage
to get a user without signing the policy
and you know I mean how do you get rid
of them if they manage to enter the
system without signing your policy I
mean obviously if they broke the law
would be a different matter but that's
another thing that people might try to
do too they might try to bypass anything
that seems important to the business so
the next thing we're doing going to do
here is to pay and as I said we're going
to pay with the registers safe
connection because we like security
I went again we're going to come here
we're going to leave the proxy this is
good for you to get this first before
going anywhere else so we say this to
the proxy okay I know yes I know I done
this this is mine it's mine this proxy
so we confirm the exception and we send
it
and here
let's see whether it works here i have
the interception ok and here the
description the description where it
says at one table note i want two tables
two tables
okay so we click on forward let's see
we're going to switch the intercept off
let me get rid of that intercept and
here we're in the means of payment and
then we need to know where my basket is
you know it's got to be somewhere I've
got associated with my payment
identification I've got to associate it
with my order what we're going to do is
take our request that we recorded
earlier we have it here this is the one
we're going to take it we're going to
repeat it in the background and we're
going to say add another one who says
yes I've got it here good well with this
request that we've added we've got two
things on the one hand what we've got to
have the description which states two
tables and on the other hand the basket
has two we've got to see that the basket
has two and if not well
I'll show you
there they are 22 products so what we
have to see is whether it's going to
validate it what would we would expect
is that it would be validated I wouldn't
imagine that that be measures to to
think otherwise and if you do validate
that you get a two-for-one I found this
on occasions that it goes through a
payment gateway that they've created
they have a back end of quest and all
that kind of thing and then either you
can just jump over you know skip the
payment phase or add things to the
basket once you've got to the payment
the step these are important
considerable problems okay so this is
we've got so far with the demonstrations
and I don't if they can change me and on
the computer please thank you
bueno que cosa que se Messiah ok yogi
Kelly do anything that goes beyond what
I've done here is a crime so be careful
with that so let's move on to the
conclusions what's going on with all of
this is anybody test this in the
applications they develop do you test
this business logic over there one
person will have a coffee later I'll pay
for it i'll invite user coffee nobody
else well that's one person so hardly
any tests are done with this these are
really important fault sir you know so
the conclusion is that these light up a
dark area in security which is a source
of bugs it reinforces the application
security increases the trust of
customers in application security and
it's included in negative thinking in
the testing process so as we had
functions we can include more cases and
it will have a largely reusable
repository in the case of the abuse and
no security or perimeter perimeter
security device will protect you against
this kind of attacks you can prevent a
lot of things but not this so you have
to test this and guarantee that your
business logic is really well designed
and here we've got some event references
and any questions
now is the moment this is the good you
know this is the moment now I never any
questions
between between the two Bourbons up
there any times when one is better than
the other is it a price issue does it
just matter on personal preference it's
just a matter of personal preference
what I prefer back for several reasons
I've had problems in virtual
environments with zap and burp is more
agile zap is a bit heavier with the scam
the burp suites can I have better
results in general and it's a payment
application in produce very cheap I mean
this version is the free version that
we've seen and it's good for many things
you can do many things with it the
paying version i think it's 240 euros
240 sorry two hundred forty dollars and
you know you get your money back you're
the very next day it's really good it
works really well the functionality is
very similar between the two but there
are things that are better in zap for
example the interception of response
requests which is can be more selective
so there are things that I like better
but in general it works really well the
functionality is very good I prepare
prefer burp almost hundred percent of
the time
I think I casino so do the emotional
winners Dean I have two questions first
of all the version of prestashop that
the pay the the page used all of them no
well this is very recent this is just
from last week so I can imagine that the
version would have been the latest
version I'm not investigated I've not
done grabbing to see what there is there
and the second question is when it comes
to finding vulnerable when you find a
vulnerability in business logic how do
you react when it comes to informing the
company what followed you what process
sorry or what procedure do you follow
normally we look for a contact address
for that person and we have the payment
solution with shanna which well I don't
know if any of you some of you may have
got the response but I haven't received
a response but that you know they end up
solving it they know that it's there and
sometimes they might answer them
sometimes I might not and in this case
you look for a contact in the book
company and you can
can look through for that through the
domain through the administration
normally there's an associated email or
you can open up an incident and in that
way the support services should give you
support another what they should and
they may not always do that but they
should anything else anybody else no
well thank you very much we're just my
apologies to the organization that was
my fault the problems that we had and
I'm really grateful that they've managed
to give me the means to show you this
and do my presentation in the end and
again thank you to the organizers for
inviting me here I hope to come back
next year it's really cool thanks