hola buenas tardes a todos a SI como va
nandito so i am captain Tom Bogut Alice
I you know I work in the unit of
telematic crimes from Vargas wheel and
first of all let me tell you what we do
to fight cyber crimes and now I'd like
to share with you an example of the
operation that we Carrie's house and at
fighting cybercrimes cyber crimes that
are in drawing in the Tor network as I
say so I'll tell you what we do from the
Civil Guard and against cyber crimes
then our operation then I will tell you
about the process of investigation that
is to say all the steps that were taken
in up until we find the authors of the
crime and then I also would like to
finish by sharing with use most
frequently find problems so for you to
have some context as I say I work in
these units of telematic crimes this is
a group that depends from the operative
central unit perhaps you heard about it
before in the news the UCL and then we
are Civil Guards so Civil Guard and
technological crimes and fight of it is
divided in several branches and we have
we have the judicial police working with
the courts with the judges in all the
investigation tasks that are Cavett's
out to find the attackers so within that
we have departmental electronic and IT
department so they take care of carrying
out forensic analysis
and day that evidence is later on sent
out to the court then within the
technical challenge we have specialized
crime section and this section deals
with coordinating all the activities
carried out at the different units and
departments within civil guards so to
prevent overlapping so because in sams
but there may be the case that several
units are investigating on the same
topic and then we'll have the operative
central units taking care of
investigation about more complex issues
and international issues there are
several groups in here we have the drug
group the organized crime the economic
crimes and then that's where we are
telematic crimes and then in each of the
regions on his pain we have team the
team specializes in technological crimes
so they investigate this type of crimes
according to the competences some of
them have regional competences ok and
they investigate those cases that are
not very complex and then we have our
colleagues from the information system
through the technical area from the
electron group they deal with the
unfortunate and well unpleasant task of
converting of fighting cybercrime and
when such as jihadism so our mission
within the telematic group are very easy
to explain so the main one as you may
imagine is investigating those questions
that are related to IT crimes
the factor to find out whether it is an
investigation to do it ourselves to be
done by another one has to do with the
level of that research then whether it
is national or international and we also
help out our friends and the rest of the
UC 0 units to carry out the
investigation to give you everything
example any such warrants that we may do
for instance due to corruption latter
council for instance municipal
authorities well sometimes they find
difficulty in doing that sir choking
analyzing those files so we also deal
with training the stuff in the
departments that I mentioned before we
keep them updated so that they are more
efficient in what to do and the work in
a more coordinated manner so we also
attend several foreign we also
collaborate with FBI in child
pornography we are also members of an
Interpol group we are also members of
the FIGC group in South America so we
get lots of information from these
groups where we belong and I'm sure you
had word cybercrime very many times
before actually this term was defined
for the first time in the Budapest
agreement that took place in Budapest
back in two thousand and one that was
organized by the council of europe spain
ratified the agreement but what did not
implement it up until two thousand and
nine then it took nine years to
implement that agreements and base
the agreement defined cyber crimes cyber
crimes as such could be easily divided
in four major groups will have the more
unpleasant side which is the child
pornography each and every one of you
present here know very well what I'm
talking about then all the crimes that
we have all witnessed or suffered
ourselves will be internet fraud for
instance is stealing of banking details
or reese's fraud in website of websites
or any illicit activity on the internet
and then we also have all the crimes
that we have all committed at least once
in our life even if you don't admit it
and i'm referring to hacking and then
the purely crimes okay although
intellectual property for the previous
one and this one be hacking okay that is
to say no authorized access to IT
systems disruption of IT systems etc and
i'm not making this up okay all these
have been described and classified under
the Budapest agreement so after
presentation about who we are what we do
and why we do it we move on to our
operation anonymous animals operation
animals operation started kind of like a
practical joke so it says okay well a
person from the APA that goes and says
once I was comfortably my office when I
got a call from my FB an FEI colleague
and he told me the monk we need your
help from spain and i want to say yeah
okay mass but but would you need us for
but set of help do you need and
he said ok we are going to fight to cut
to launch an operation against or pages
one then when you hear that the first
thing that may come to mind is tor
holding this hammer but those of you who
don't know about or is that is not
doctor this is the tour that I'm
mentioning here so the second one that
have shown on the screen so how will
summarize it for you when you connect to
the internet often to do it from your
home and then you connect to the website
for instance el mundo Tess which is a
newspaper and then all the my IP address
is registered in the seventh so if
someone wants to see who has access and
window dot s my IP will show and then it
would also show the time and the date
when I connected door works like that
there are at least three in the memory
equipment intermediate equipments and
these equipment will not always will
change all the time they will change
you
a very difficult because that will go
through a server that is located in
China Brazil whatever and then 30
seconds later those three servants will
change their location across the world
and then Matt from the FBI told me that
they wanted to launch an operation to go
against tour and then they he said that
the target was the Silk Road it was the
greatest online flea market for buying
and selling drugs it was what the
administrator was arrested in the US and
his name was Robert and he has given he
has been given life sentence in the u.s.
they offer Canada successes opioids
boosters so when after that after that
u.s. operation them some juicers created
silk road to and they continue to offer
the same type of stuff any type of drug
available from anywhere in the world and
would you well the currency used was
Bitcoin and the objective was to crush
all the tour pages that have any type of
float there were very many other online
sites to sell drugs or illicit weapons
or any illicit things you can think of
for instance agri market revolution
cetera diese just some of them and
weren't FBI contacted us gave us in
Spanish I'd be
that belong to the control panel where
the administrator of your l2 websites
just to connect himself okay so they
gave us the URL onion so tour domains
are onion domains and then the second
let us go and look at it however
disheartened problem the thing is that
we got those data on the thirtieth of
sep tember and it sold us at 21
countries will be taken joint action
planned for the 27th of october as you
can imagine I don't know what I do being
involved in any court cases or not but I
can tell you that trying to resolve this
type of situation in over in only 27
days it's very difficult thing to do and
it happens a bit like happen to the
Alice in Wonderland rabbit that is to
say we had to hurry up okay yes to meet
that deadline for the joint action so
when we got access to the URL this is
what we found
so the website and that was controlled
from Spain it was known as fast cash I
did offer the buying and selling of
false Europe notes so this is what they
offer 5 10 euro notes for 25 thousand
euros 110 euro note for 60 etc etc so we
looked closer into the website and to
the contents of it and we could also see
that they were offering the delivery of
this false currency anywhere in the
world the currency to pay for those
items was bitcoins and also hear the
were good reviews positive feedback by
users so they were just saying that that
was a good website to buy false notes so
we could clearly see that either
currency was being tampered or forged or
perhaps this most as the fraud website
trying to
to fraud anyone visiting it that is to
say scum however those reviews the use
of Bitcoin and finding it in turn took
us to think that this has to do with the
forgery of coins and notes because we
were very much in a hurry we just all
those data and we went to the IT
criminality office and we told them
everything that we were involved we told
them how much in a hurry we were because
all the Isaac crimes and that's it
placing toward nowadays our kind of they
go on kind of unpunished so they believe
that they can do whatever they want to
do and go unpunished so our friends also
reach the same conclusion they said that
yes that did was over cedar like forgery
of notes and coins or just Sutherland
sites so we went and talked to them
judge and he gave us a judicial order a
court order Saudi IP was located in the
municipality in Barcelona however when
we looked at the details of the person
link to that IP didn't really make any
sense to us because it was just a
plumber advanced age man and he was not
he didn't look like highly experts in
terms of managing working with Bitcoin
center etc so several questions came to
us so the first one is as you may
imagine is whether the Wi-Fi had been
committed or not whether that home and
Wi-Fi hotspot had been compromised
that the security of the Wi-Fi have been
breached and then the IP of that plumber
was being used pull this data made us
doubt made us a few doubts and then we
decided to go to the spot to go inside
and to analyze the traffic the Wi-Fi
traffic of the connections in the area
we went over there reduce Jones such as
acrylic Wi-Fi and what was actually what
we were very very much surprised okay
because we couldn't really find any
illicit use of the Wi-Fi of the plumber
so we were taken aback by that somebody
still we thought that this person was
not related to the actual dream and I
say okay let us go beyond that and let
us try to find someone who meets that
profile and then we asked ourselves well
did we find the plumber in the social
networks did we researched about him did
we find out about his friends and
actually yes this person has a facebook
profile then we looked into his facebook
profile and they were there was no
clothes nothing took us to what we were
looking for but we wanted to gossip and
then we wanted to find out who he has
engaging in communication with so this
device is
that was a medicaments that was a drag
medical drug and he was wearing this
bitcoin bitcoin t-shirt sake look more
like a freak now so if you were a
Bitcoin t-shirt means that you love or
that July that coin at least you are
interested in it and then I said okay
let us try to find more information
about him so we didn't contact the NSA
or anything so all the information was
open so sometimes crimes or attackers
home eat this type of mistakes and then
we found news that are being uploaded by
this person that was the piece of news
that was broadcasted on TV and then this
person has just also posted a comment a
comment saying now you know a gay so we
could see that notes and thank his
comments and that you about saying that
you already know about it so then again
we became more more interested in the
pestle we continue looking into his
profile and then he had also posted this
cartoon and he was kind of making a joke
of FBI and the activities that were
launching against tour and then we said
okay he is very much like the person we
are looking for now okay we had his face
okay but we didn't have his action name
he had a false profile on facebook and
actually he was using a woman's name so
we could have
investigators the no keys register the
municipality etc but he made it much
easier for us he had a bloated and
photograph he had been involved in a car
accident with the registration play in
the clear and we just entered the
registration plate and we found this
person he was an in Argentinian man and
he lived in the Barcelona municipality
and actually he was living quite close
to the plumber and there was a
relationship between the two because he
was he was the brother of the boyfriend
of the daughter of the comma okay well
they knew each other again to keep it
short once we found the person we
continue looking into him and then we
could also see we found conversations
with other Facebook users the were Wi-Fi
intruders and were just mentioning oh I
cracked Wi-Fi hub Wi-Fi networks etc and
he was showing off she was showing off
about reaching Wi-Fi security still we
didn't have any evidence so he also
talked to a person who had a printer so
it was a t-shirt printer it is true but
when you are looking for a person that
forges coins and notes well
seeing that he was in contact with a
person who had a printer took us to
think that perhaps if they try sided
printing facility were to be printed we
have to be changed well it could easily
end up printing notes so therefore we
focused more moon on him and then from
that we asked for a search warrant so we
asked the judge to give us a search
warrants so that we could go to the home
of that person and then to confiscate
these devices that are related with the
crime that is being investigated so we
asked for two search warrants one for
diploma and the other one from him so we
expected to find at least some clues in
the router of the plumber and also on
the Argentinean man so what we've been
looking for something very simple as a
nevada you have tried to open up a web
site on the web on the tour web so to do
so you need a private key file the same
as when you use PGP or any encryption
program accessing the control platinum
is that for a private key file so we had
all these clues all this data or these
details however we needed to find the
file to say that he was actually linked
to the crime so for us finding that
public key was key the key for us so
first of all we went to do the domicile
of this person and we found very many
things okay kiha good money cash
he also hard like virginal blank credit
cards he also had a card writing machine
he had also bought and sold drugs on
tour website so we could really see that
this person had a good knowledge about
the use of new technologies and actually
we were most interested in looking into
his IT equipment so the first thing that
we did was to prepare some strips so
that by the time we will go into his
computer we could find any file selling
us that it was a bit fine Bitcoin thurs
any bit coin purse that would allow us
to see the receipt of pump transfers
that would be a very good evidence ok we
just the script and then right away we
could access to the Bitcoin purses but
still we didn't have the private key
file that I mentioned before ok so this
looks like a joke but actually this was
true and actually we scan the most
widely used
folders and then we found this mp3 file
it referred to over whose name was you
already know this okay and this was not
in the folder to of downloads or it was
just in a different folder folder that
also included some txt files etc and
then we did right click on the file and
then we looked at the size of it was two
megabytes so often mp3 files do not are
not to megabytes files often there are 4
8 12 megabytes so exactly two megabytes
make us made a suspect that was really
really strange and then when we asked
him well this file is not what it looks
like it's indeed he didn't give us an
insanity he refused to give us an answer
so we decided to download the ram memory
because we wanted to extract the
password of applications that were
recently used and well when he could see
us that he told us this is a container
of truecrypt that i created when we
opened that up with a password that he
gave us because he gave up so we found
the public key Oh private key to the
website so let us say that our work was
kind of well finished than or completed
still I had a question a question that I
wanted to answer and as I said we
analyzed Wi-Fi
password on site to vent out with us
some of them had been breached or not so
we went to the home of the plumber and
we found exactly this on the left the
laptop was configured with the website
and our real suspects the Argentinian
man connected himself to the server of
the father of the girlfriend of his
brother he used to connect remotely and
then when we ask the plumber how to
reload allowed for that to happen at
your home and he said look having asked
to do that favor to them and I let them
do it so the plumber had the server at
home as avatar was accessed remotely by
our suspect man and then on the right
you see those three green lights and for
those of you who don't know this is like
a small farm of bitcoins these are like
a small carts of bitcoins that have been
prepared with the GPU cpu to process day
data of blocks of data for Bitcoin and
to mine to do Bitcoin mining so that is
not a crime but still we were surprised
again as how passionate this man was
formed about Bitcoin and as I say we got
the last answer to have a last question
and then well the but we could not
understand in the beginning was later
not yet because we could see now that he
was acting remotely I what did we find
in the home of the suspect so we found a
txt file of his equipment with access
key to more than 120 Wi-Fi networks
around his home we checked them one by
one and we could really see that they
were located in the neighborhood because
we wanted to identify possible victims
also very important the security of
Wi-Fi networks please improve them so
that people like himself do not reach
into your network and get you into
trouble we also found credit card blank
credit cards so someone who moves about
in your juicy store is very likely to
buy monkey tails just to trade or to
copy credit card then the balance or in
the Bitcoin purse was around 17 perhaps
that doesn't look very high amount to
you but a bitcoin is 341 euros so the
benefit or the profit the profit that he
had made with a make him rich but still
he had made a profit so we also find the
private a key to access the panel of the
website which was a key evidence and
also very important this person has good
technical knowledge when you take it the
position to person that you're arresting
you kind of feel like sympathetic you
know to that person and I talking to are
too smart to do this kind of nonsense
I love the nonsense that he did is that
he breached the encryption of the Metro
tickets that are using Barcelona
actually because he wanted to save like
a euro and I said why don't you use all
due respect ease for something else
which is more important than just to
breach and metro ticket and he had
bought a drugs on tour and then we also
got all those details for further
investigation this is part of another
investigation that is being carried out
today so we also found two thousand
euros in cash in principle with what we
can confront in a very severe criminal
to act upon it style doing buying
selling of bills nodes with bitcoins but
in the very end we end up knowing that
sadly anything we are this we are like
this instead having big criminal we we
found a simple hamster and froster we
were able to confront an act on this
scam headlines on the newspapers are
today's operation the newspaper by is
they reflected the RMS operation to wrap
up I want to reflect on this boy I want
allowed out even a scam case like this
as of today can have complications a big
scale / firstly how its it tremendously
easy for users not to use secure eyes
their Wi-Fi networks this super easy to
bond rate your neighboring Wi-Fi people
surrounding us you can accept them and
it is more difficult for us to keep
track of the connection
so we can use say the big godless
networks asking using remotely infected
networks sorry for this some caffeine
more and more frequently we can find
encryption tools which make difficult to
obtain any digital indexes of science or
do tips in this case the password was
around but for many other cases if I
have the computer switch off and the
person does not want to cooperate that
is so difficult to access all that this
e ciphered in a container tricky typing
any encryption application and is the
very same difficulty to break password
with the encryption program having a
cipher and algorithm cipher pretty good
it takes cells if it's 80 if he's eight
Carter takes eight months but it is over
more many more characters Texas years
and centuries millions in this very case
is person obtained a benefit of 16-bit
coins and cash money but regardless to
say needless to say that certain big
organization had found Bitcoin the two
that as per se because is useful but in
the hands of the cybercriminals allows
to do money laundering of capitals very
quickly rather than going to the
traditional banking and if you start
moving money the fruit of the crime
through Bitcoin base models and you use
certain criminal companies taking out
this vid cons and put it in different
purses with intermediate process to make
hard to track him it's difficult for us
gives it the track of everything last
lame 40 or are any anonymous navigation
browsing to these are flattened that on
their own do not damage any volume the
update they were born with objective of
guaranteeing the privacy freedom of
speech in countries with to suppress
prison but in the hands of criminals
they make difficult to locate the
criminals compared to the claim
navigation with anonymous operation we
and dad making criminals knowing that we
can act against an on tour we found any
person accessing any of the pages
intervened gearing is carrying out and
the global action sometimes we make
mistakes and we're humans and the action
clash of global action with yet that day
we see is 430 size on tour besides we
intervene over 1 million euros in
bitcoins over 180,000 euros in cash
drugs weapons shows such a big effort
to be carried out by the international
community in order to release the
messages no matter what kind of break
point and break through to two years you
have to act on it police sighs before
this is it should be interested in
asking questions we can open the floor
to you I can see him over there good
afternoon items I i I'm gonna consider
myself an expert a bit about what does
scam mean in English sometimes we use
we're usually you so many English lingo
I need to calibrate fans scam is a fraud
website a scam did you see the delegate
a lot tree where the bitch a Leo bill
gate will give the way to use 1 million
years scam are all these comms on the
internet in this case was not these
obvious but is it was a camp base some
con you accessed your face with the
proper because it was open should it be
em in a private profile should be asking
permission from NSA let's do it out
let's spit it out I want I want to know
should I have a private profile on
facebook you can access this private
profile face with Renee of police
investigation it was it was a joke many
people believe that the loan form is
good hot free access to all the
information available so many times on
the newspapers we get it information NSA
is monitoring connections this head
distance make happen in the state I can
tell you about Spain which is the better
the case and yeah everything which is
all pan it's accessible as you know but
if I want to obtain information from you
from your facebook profile because you
might be conducting criminal action
I can do so by an injection issued by a
spain's huge judge the chairs the mary
confess with company players you have to
facilitate me this information so you
need a judge order to do so in spam any
more questions hello I can see my hands
to the back of the room congratulations
for your mobile station ah at the back I
want to ask you a question it told does
this person had to find this computer
with over 100 passwords from their
neighbors in you loyally checked out
that these passwords corresponded to the
Wi-Fi password how can you do so without
going into these Reuters did you connect
these waffles to something what kind of
permission the obtained for that what is
it what it was much more easier I
normally you giddy with it to which
crazed mapping a hello when you know
that a point access is accessible or is
close to you in this case we walk around
around data in this trigger on Barcelona
and we saw that the access point was
close enough to us so we knock at the
door are you the owner of the access
point WL and what's your password is you
have to know that you're that's where is
as bond rate is attacked it's as simple
as that
this week last week a new scandal came
out the FBI used a nut company to make
the tour protocol anonymous this
intervention was part of this
investigation I don't know we when we
receive information from a country we
only ask something like is this
information obtained in a legal way the
American info from Americans will obtain
an illegally we apply the principle of
Europe lucidity of the proof the way the
makin they did you have to double check
with them I cannot help you in decision
actually Americans I could even once the
scissors of bitcoins made our day store
nerves Bitcoin the folder or our chains
into euros Oh somebody while tapping on
you that's a very good question how can
I answer back to you when we see is the
two thousand euros in cash is easy what
we had to do you take the two thousand
euros the judge officer very fact there
is cash two thousand you put it in an
envelope you go to the the physical band
in the with the neck down administered
by the administration of justice and you
deposit the money physically in this
banking around with the UCSB continuing
the Bitcoin pocket the you went to the
court and you said oh your honor the
bitcoins are in this USB this is a file
Your Honor if you put it in circulation
through out this programs is worth this
money so keep it there and let's see if
I can move it after that after we can
have conducted
several meetings with prosecutors in the
Minister of Justice us to the fact that
the administration has to create Bitcoin
pockets and purses to transfer the
bitcoins seeds into the administration
of justice there are two kinds of purses
basically speaking there is the physical
top first which is a file a top of five
should you intervene it you the criminal
kind of access with their other
synchronize purses on email accounts if
you want to block them you need to
transfer them into an account controlled
by the ministry of justice but also you
have to change the access password that
person had otherwise that criminals have
the opportunity to recover drop out the
generalization and mr. Patil have to
create Bitcoin accounts to seize them
any more questions is it true that this
thing's state has spanned many many
millions of euros in hacker in hacking
hacking team applications are you
talking about the Italian Italian press
I'm gonna tell something we were with
material I'd like to have as much money
as they say to buy so many things as
they say in my particular case I can
tell you that the Spain and cigar didn't
didn't buy anything from the hacking
team not natural
anyone else wants to do to pose a
question hello I would like to know if
the civil servant was accused of
complicity as it happens with the
conventional crimes I can't hear you I'd
like to know the planner the plumber the
planner was accused of be accomplished
of complicity now when the plumber was
the pillows in US charts person today it
would be an investigative person because
the criminal operates change at first
moment in time you can't know that the
fact that the city was at is other
plumbers how was weed or without the
plumbers knowledge because the plumber
should have be deposing with the
president of the lawyer and for the
person should be charged with them in
our opinion the report we notice that
the planet did not have criminal
connection with the fact the glamour
didn't do it nothing wrong this is my
opinion plumber this plumber who was
unaware of the condition system in his
house this is another crime this is
ignorance simply speaking
thank you very very much I would like to
ask you something yeah give us said that
by using these bitcoins and you other
companies can use it for money
laundering all kind of laundry nice ice
and I seem o bells ringing I know we're
in a junior talk with Chema along so
many people use those tortillas
applications they upload gain or some
types of game where you can buy things
with virtual money and they do this
money laundering through buying these
kind of applications how can you act
under the in this regard and how can we
help you out of the situation how can
you how can give you how to detect this
kind of them wicked people you're asking
me that there are some money laundering
to such as using virtual currency and
online game platforms yeah equally
equally likewise how can we combat that
in fact how can we avoid it is so very
very briefly there are some games where
they start giving away virtual money in
indiscriminate away directly the users
start them downloading the this hacking
fans by enabling a virtual unlimited
money you know I don't know hide words
how engineering is working in this
regard how can you justify this from the
from a gain engineering viewpoint video
games uploaded on facebook I wouldn't
tell you in private which ones are but
I've actually cheerly specific that the
day is that on facebook bear in mind
something and the validity of virtual
currency to depends on the value that
the user gets it if you have a virtual
currency but it's not acceptable the
value of that is not as void so
for those some virtual currency tools
which real are worth money the brief
first virtual currency was that the
dollar Linder aye you know familiar
about that for the geeks of second life
for the virtual world being the very
first created all these companies using
virtual currency with the real
distribution decree are obliged to the
normal obligations applicable way the
r18 and tendering they have to be
control of the deposits made in real
money transfers out outside the inside
but we discover a big hole to manual
laundromat now I develop certain
measures that allow us to detect very
easily if these holes are used for money
laundering I'll give you an example it
has to do with poker online if I got
there and I put two thousand euros on a
lyin town and I take them out
some years ago if I put in three
thousand years on on poker online
account would be it be to play around
with the bed on bad if i take it out
automatically this is this makes all set
I'm putting an intermediate patching to
manual under all these strange models
are automatically detected by verifying
cookies I be the credit car connected
with the sale there are some big
vacation factors when we detected
strange movements the company is
normally detected report this to the
money laundering service and they
distributed information to the place
officer the long huge enormous groups
and the Ministry of Justice anyone else
wants two thousand Western
thank you very much should not have to
deny have more questions we finished we
need to move on to the next step