- Hello, and welcome
to cloud configuration,
mitigate risks from
cloud security failures.
If you're joining us live,
our speaker will be answering questions
in the post session discussion forum
immediately following the presentation.
The forum link is available
in the networking lounge.
For audio, video issues,
please click the technical
support button below.
I'd now like to turn it
over to Niles Pyelshak,
for the presentation.
- Welcome to this virtual series.
It's really good to have you
guys join our discussion today.
I'm Niles Pyelshak,
and I'm super excited to
spend some time talking about
cloud risk and mitigation
with you guys today.
You may be wondering
why I chose this topic
and why I want to have
this discussion with you.
Well, you know what,
I'm really glad you asked .
Trend Micro's research
finding indicated that
cloud misconfiguration was
the most prevalent cause
of cloud security issues
for businesses today.
What they also find was that
about 230 million misconfigurations
happen on a daily basis on an average.
Okay, and even beyond that,
what they also found was that
95% of IT decision makers
are super concerned about
cloud misconfiguration
because they consider it a
data security risk, right?
So these are fats that have
been researched and reported
and you can actually look it up yourself.
To take it out a little bit further,
DivvyCloud also did a study
and what they discovered was that
in the years of 2018 and 2019,
that companies paid about $5
trillion in data breaches.
Okay, so that's $5 trillion dollars
that was spent by companies that reported
not to mention those that
did not report, okay?
That's a lot of money, okay.
So that's one of the reasons
why I wanna have this
discussion with you guys today.
But first I wanna talk about
who am I and why am I qualified
to have this discussion with you guys?
My experience come from
10 plus years of IT work,
spanning a broad range of disciplines
from systems engineering
to network engineering.
I've designed data centers.
I've implemented data centers
for Fortune 500 companies.
I've also be able to do virtualization
So I have a vast amount
of experience there
and obviously now in cyber security.
Currently though, I drive
cloud security adoption
for Cisco systems.
And as you can see there I'm also CCIE.
All right, so let's talk
about cloud configurations
and what are some of the
issues that we're seeing?
Well, first of all we cannot deny the fact
that enterprises are adopting cloud
and they're adopting cloud
because of a lot of different benefits
that are available to them, right?
Some could be for agility,
some may be for the reasons of
driving down operating costs.
It could be to gain competitive advantage,
or for whatever reason
that you are adopting
cloud infrastructure solution,
you should do so securely, right?
There are different kinds of
service providers out there,
you know about, Microsoft Azure AWS.
Google has its own.
Many other companies
have their own flavors
and they all provide
this to customers, okay?
So if you think about a
traditional data center,
what you would see is that most
customers had a data center.
They had to acquire the
hardware for that data center
that will bring it in, that burn it in
and then they will roll
it out to production.
By the time they will adapt to production,
maybe it's a server that
they've made available
for engineering, okay?
At that point, that engineer
that's using that server
is not concerned about
security at all, right?
And typically they just start, you know,
they hop onto the servers,
they load the application,
do whatever they need to do
and they feel pretty secure doing that.
Now, when you shift to
operating in the cloud,
what has essentially happened
is that you've shifted your perimeter
and you've shifted back
to what's the cloud
and essentially you've expanded
your attack surface, right?
And now when you're operating the cloud,
things are a little bit different, right?
It's really easy to just within
seconds create an instance
in the cloud and do
whatever you have to do.
But you know, there is a
responsibility for security
that you have to make sure that you obtain
for your environment, right?
So usually there's a huge
question about who's responsible
for what, okay?
Is the cloud provider responsible for this
or am I responsible for
that as a cloud consumer?
Well, we have this particular
slide that I have up here that
basically uses a picture of
the shared responsibility model
that's out there, okay?
When we're talking about
the cloud service provider,
the bottom there is what you see
that they're responsible for.
Okay so let's unpack that a little bit.
So if you are a cloud service provider,
you are responsible for
securing the compute.
You're responsible for
securing the networking.
securing the storage
and everything that runs the cloud.
That is the responsibility of
the cloud service provider.
So the hardware, their
software that runs to cloud.
the databases, all of that stuff
it's the responsibility of the
cloud service provider, okay?
They even, for the physical data centers,
they have physical security,
that's the responsibility of
the cloud service provider.
Okay, now if you pivot
that to the customer.
What is the customer
responsible for in the cloud
infrastructure, right?
The top picture right here
that you see is what are the...
These are the items that the
customers are responsible for.
Basically everything that's in the cloud.
So you have customer data,
that's your responsibility,
the applications that you
use in the environment,
that's your responsibility, okay?
Identity and access management,
that's your responsibility
to configure operating system,
your networking, your virtual firewall.
That's the responsibility
of the cloud consumer, okay?
So that's essentially the
model that we need to follow.
You may hear some people argue about,
Oh, it really depends on
the services here and there,
but essentially in my opinion,
you should also always consider that
if you can make any
change in the environment
as a root user,
the general rule is that it's up to you
to secure that, okay?
Now let's talk about some common
types of misconfigurations
that we see in the cloud infrastructure.
So what are the common misconfigurations
that we see in cloud?
The first one I wanna talk about is IAM.
Okay IAM stands for, identity
and access management.
And these is actually a tool
that the cloud service provider
provides to cloud consumers,
so that they can create users and groups
for their enterprises, okay?
It's called IAM.
And what we found out according
to research is that IAMs
or identity and access
management is an extremely common
security weakness in the
cloud infrastructure, okay?
So that's why I wanna talk about it today.
Yes, IAMs are you know, you are
responsible for that, right?
This tool is provided to you
by your cloud service provider
and you have to configure it.
Then you have to make sure that
configured in a way that is
safe for your enterprise, okay?
Take for instance, a root user.
They should never be anyone
in your environment that has
access to everything, okay?
If you use, take for instance,
they have their root user,
they may have assess to create services,
implement services, configure them, right?
That person, they should not be someone
using the user root username and password
to make configuration
changes in your environment.
But this is actually
happening with you have users
that are able to perform
all kinds of action
in your entire environment.
That's extremely dangerous, okay?
Why?
Say for instance, that person,
what if they share those credentials
with other people, right?
In a traditional IT environment,
I remember a password that
was stuck on a sticky note
and everybody all use that same username
and password, right?
You want to avoid that
and if you have one person who has access
to a full reign to your environment,
it's really hard to avoid that.
That's one thing, right?
Number two things, how
do you perform audits?
How do you know who's doing
what in the cloud environment?
Right?
And let's say something happens
and you piss that employee off, right?
So you piss that employee off
that person has full reign
in your cloud infrastructure,
guess what they could do?
Well, they may open up back doors
in your cloud infrastructure.
They may open up services.
Essentially they may
become an insider threat
to your organization, right?
And what are you gonna do? Fire him?
Well, let's say you do that.
You fired them, what you
are essentially doing
is making them become an outsider threat
because they have full
reign in your environment,
what they have, they may
have created some back doors,
some inside doors,
start some new services
that you were not aware of.
Well, it's just really, really
it's one of the problems
that we're seeing is that people
are giving full ban access
to so many single users
in their environment and
that is a misconfiguration.
The second thing I wanna talk
about is the lack of MFA.
MFA stands for multi-factor
authentication, okay?
Multi-factor authentication
is basically a simple tool
that gives you an added
layer of protection, okay?
You will be so surprised
to know that a lot of
cloud platform consumers
are not configuring MFAs.
There are not, right?
We are accustomed to, in the
traditional IT environment,
we are accustomed to the
server admin, you know,
using the active directory
to create a domain,
create groups, create users.
That groups maybe like, you know,
your HR group, your marketing group,
or perhaps your engineering group
and then grabbing use and
dropping into those groups
and giving them the permissions
that they need, okay?
Well, when you shift
into the cloud, it's...
Well, first of all, once you
give them those permissions,
those are the user
credentials that they use
to log into those services
in your environment, okay?
But it's important to take
that additional step and say,
okay, well, I know that
you can verify, you know,
use them in password,
what else can you verify?
And MFA allows you to add
that layer of protection
for your environment.
And you can configure it for attendance,
you can configure it for our service APIs,
you can configure it for
IAM users, it's important.
And you can actually put a
soft token on your following
that people can use or
you can actually provide
a hardware token that
there users carry about.
But you know what?
This is one of the
misconfigurations we see
in the environment.
It's just that people are just
not configuring MFA, okay?
But that's just the word on the street.
The next thing to talk
about there is unsecured
credentials, right?
Are you creating strong password policies
for your enterprise?
Okay, I know some people
like the government agencies,
those are required to
actually use complex passwords
and they use that and they
follow those protocols,
but there are some enterprise
that are not doing so.
And so it's important
for you to evaluate that
and find out if you are using...
Well, first of all, do you
even have rules in place?
If you don't, what do you need to do
to get that created, right?
Do you create groups in your environment?
Do you add users to that environment?
Do you appropriate permissions?
Do you perform audit?
Because if you're not doing these things
then, you're setting yourself
up for an opportunity
to be attacked, okay?
So that's four IAM.
Those are just really quick
things that you may be able
to go back to your environment
and be able to quickly make some changes
and provide some added
benefit in terms of security
in your cloud infrastructure.
Now for security groups.
Security groups are
basically firewall, right?
In a traditional IT environment,
you may have your data center
and when you have that data center,
all customers that I
have not met a customer
that don't have a firewall in place, okay?
That firewall is basically the
guy that stands at the gate
and say, well, you know, your
protocol 22, you can come in.
Your protocol 23, no you can not come in.
Basically it filters what goes in and out
in your environment.
And that's what happens in
the traditional environment.
Most enterprises have
that hardware firewall,
perimeter firewall.
And when we go into the cloud,
it's no different, okay.
You need to have security groups.
That's the terms we
use, the security groups
that allows you to basically filter
what comes into your services,
the content into your cloud infrastructure
and what goes out.
And what we're seeing is number one,
they are improper attachment.
What does that look like?
Basically what I'm
referring to is the idea
that you have good intentions
and you create perhaps 10
different security groups, right?
You create 10 security groups
because you have possibly,
let's say 10 services, 10
different services, okay?
And you applied the
security to those groups.
What happens when let's say
you have an additional service
that's coming up, maybe it's
a file server that you need
to create an instance for, right?
If you go in there and just
go ahead and grab whatever
security groups is available there,
you can possibly improperly
attach the wrong filtering
to that file server, right?
It's kind of like, possibly
grabbing a web server
or web application security group
and applying it to a file server
that may contain your PIIs,
maybe even crown jewels.
It just doesn't make sense.
So what we're seeing a lot
is improper attachment.
So it's important to kind
of survey your environment,
find out are you improperly
attaching security groups
to the wrong services, okay?
We are also seeing some
default attachment.
So people just outright
saying, well, you know what?
I needed to get this up and running.
I created maybe two or
three security groups,
and then I'm gonna just
repeatedly use that
across all my infrastructure, okay?
That is a misconfiguration
and can open up a lot of
opportunities or increase
your attack surface, you know,
beyond just being a cloud consumer, okay?
Unrestricted ports and protocols.
So like I was talking to
you about the firewall
in a data center,
that firewall is the guy
that decides what goes out
and comes in
and in a traditional IT environment,
we have security engineers.
That is your sole job is to
make sure that what comes in
and out on a daily basis
is allowed and permitted.
They determine...
Okay, I want to allow a source
from wanda wanda wanda one
to come into my environment or not, right?
When you shift into the cloud,
that is still a requirement, okay?
Because if you go out there
and what you essentially do
is if you open all the ports
in your security groups,
because that was the simplest
and quickest thing to do,
when you open all the
protocols in your security,
because that's the easiest thing to do,
from all sources and to all destination,
that's another misconfiguration
that you are basically
putting in your environment.
So we're seeing a whole lot of that.
So it's important for
people or cloud consumers
to take their time to
evaluate their environment,
to see, you know, this security
group that I've created.
It's a web application.
Well, at the very least I know I need 180
and I also need 4403 and
perhaps you'd even need 80,
but you need to identify
those ports that you need
and only allow exactly what you need
to those services, okay?
All right, so for storage,
this is really, really interesting.
You have to think about,
are your storage publicly
assessable to the internet, right?
What we're finding is that a
lot of customers are not aware
if there storage is actually
publicly accessible, okay?
This could pose a huge risk, okay?
In terms of data breaches,
like I mentioned,
maybe you have a file server that has PIIs
or the crown jewels, right?
You wanna make sure that
they're not publicly available, right?
In fact, I wanna share
an example with you.
Sometimes when you're
configuring your in AWS,
if you go into your control settings,
you might see a button that
says authenticated users, okay?
If you see authenticated users
and you to an average person,
you may think, well, what this means
is that people that would have access
to the storage or authenticated
users for my enterprise.
And that's an error, okay?
But authentic unit users
in that particular feature
is indicating anyone,
any customers that can be authenticated
to Amazon Web Services, right?
So tenant A and now the
authenticated to tenant A
and because they are AWS customers,
they can now have access
to your environment.
That's a huge risk.
That's a huge risk because
when you operating in the cloud
and you've increased your attack surface,
that means that the attackers
are constantly scanning
the internet.
What they wanna find is
someone who's just out there
that has not put up the firewalls,
that have not put up the tools
to protect their environment.
And this is one way that
data is getting compromised.
Logging.
Yes, you'd be very surprised to also know
there's a lot of enterprises
that are not logging things
in their environment, right?
There's no object versioning.
How do you know what to roll back to
if you're not recording these things?
And if you're not
logging, how do you know,
how can you go back and review that data
and find some security gaps
you can now close, right?
It's very, very important
to do these things
and what we're seeing is that, you know,
people are just not doing these things.
So these are a few of the common
types of misconfigurations
that we're seeing in according to research
in cloud environment.
Now, what are the common
causes of these things?
Of these misconfigurations?
There are several of them
and here I have listed a few of them.
Number one is just that
shared responsibility model.
People just don't understand
where that line is, right?
They question it
and so they don't take the
time to understand which aspect
is their responsibility to
protect for the environment.
And like I said, for general rule,
what I always suggest
is that if a root user
has access to that service, okay?
Then it's your responsibility
to protect, okay?
And so that's what I always suggest,
but that's one of the common causes,
we don't understand where
that line is drawn at.
Default configuration.
A lot of people are using
the fall configuration.
Well, we knew that any
organization has access
to a lot of different
services to be able to deliver
what they in the market for.
So default configuration,
can not be enough for them
to protect the entire environment.
So that's one of the causes.
Quick spin ups.
Yes, this one is huge, right?
We have before the pandemic, right?
There were a lot of engineers
that will go to the office
and do their work, right?.
Now, post pandemic, a lot of
people are working from home
and in some environment it's
required for a developer
to file a ticket
and when they file that ticket,
they go ahead and wait for
someone to create that instance,
apply the correct security groups,
and then turn around and say,
hey, here's your instance.
You can go do whatever
you need to do, right?
Now, an engineer is saying,
well, I know how to
create an EC2 instance.
So I'm gonna go ahead and create that
and I'm gonna grab the
default configuration
for security groups and apply
it to my instance, right?
And what they forget is that
there are some security aspects
that they may be opening themselves to,
they may be some security issues
with that default attachment or something
that they need to protect
that they may not be aware of
and they mean well, right?
These developers or
engineers they mean well.
They want to be productive.
They don't want to be held
back by the process, okay?
And sometimes it's really
easy when they finish,
they forget about that.
They may have had intentions
to go back and protect
and put the proper security grip on there,
But it's really easy to forget that.
And so that's one of the common causes.
A lack of policies, lack of templates.
You should basically have
some pre-determined policies
that the template and build
for your users to consume.
All right, well we are
also noticing is that
there's a lot of lack of expertise, right?
In this day and age, a
lot of people are saying,
Oh, I know how to sing the song ABC.
And so what am I gonna do?
I'm gonna go to YouTube,
and I'm gonna become an expert.
I'm gonna sing the ABC song
because I'm an ABC expert, right?
And that's just maybe taken
a little bit out of context
but essentially there are a lot of people
that are creating YouTubes and blogs
and they don't really have the expertise
to be teaching people
on cloud infrastructure.
And if you don't train your users,
they're going to resort
to those free resources
that may not be accurate.
And so that's what we're seeing,
there is a lack of
expertise, a lack of time.
We have cloud admins that don't have
professional development time
to learn what they need
to learn to do their job
and obviously because of budget, right?
So this is some of the common
causes that we're seeing
that's leading to loosen misconfigurations
in the environment, right?
So now what can we do about it?
What can we do to go ahead and mitigate
from some of these
things that we're seeing.
Excuse me.
There are several things that we can do
to begin to mitigate from some
of these misconfiguration.
The first thing I wanna
bring to our attention
is security baseline.
Do you have a security
baseline or not right?
No matter what industry you are in, right?
We all have regulations that
we must adhere to, okay?
Perhaps you can use that as your baseline
for your environment
but don't stop there.
Define specific security templates
for your environment yourself
in addition to the compliance requirement,
the compliance control, okay?
This for the current
misconfigurations like I said,
Trend Micro said that
there's about on a given day,
there's an average of 213
million misconfiguration.
How many are in your environment, right?
Use tools to discover
those misconfigurations.
Be pro-active.
What are you doing in your
environment to make sure
that you have visibility into
these misconfigurations, okay?
At Cisco systems we like to
actually eat our own dog food.
So whatever we're putting out
there, we like to consume it.
And there's a tool that
we are actually using
that is a Cisco solution,
it's called the Cisco
Secure Analytics, okay?
Cisco Secure Analytics.
This guy enables us to know every entity
that is in the environment.
This guy enables us to know,
to see every conversation.
Are you able to see every
composition in your environment?
Are you able to understand what's normal?
Are you able to know
when something changed?
Do you get alerted when
something does change?
Are you able to respond to the
threat really quickly, right?
And remediate, right?
This is what Cisco
Cloud Security Analytics
allows you to do
and we actually use that
at Cisco cloud security.
So in essence,
this is the Cisco secure cloud analytics
allows us to have visibility
into your network,
allows you to get reporting
in your environment
and allows you to identify any threats.
And I'll ask you to identify
IoC's indicator of compromise, right?
And policy verification
and that's something that
I wanna share with you guys
there that you might be
able to take a look at
and see how that might help
you in your environment, okay?
Do you leverage the
principles of list privilege?
Do you leverage that in your environment?
There are several tools
that will allow you
to do that, right?
There are several tools that
will allow you to look through
your environment and say, you know what?
I give this person 10 permissions
and they actually need nine.
Let me take that 10 to
one (indistinct), right?
So you can use tools to do
that and automate, okay?
Automate your spin ups,
automate with your templates.
These are things that
can actually help you.
And so with that said,
I wanna end my conversation
with you is that we know
that cloud adoption will only continue
to grow significantly, okay?
Make sure that you take
the time to leverage,
to share the responsibility model,
figure out what your responsibilities are
to protect your environment
and then the cloud service
providers will also do
what they need to do to
protect your environment.
And that completes my
discussion for you today.
Thank you for joining us.
See you next time.
All right, guys.
Also feel free to hop over
to the networking lounge
and I'm gonna be over there
addressing your Q and A.
So feel free to meet me over there.
So let's have a discussion
and let's talk about it.