good morning
you're only just
arm welcome to stage be the top now is
by David Harvey it's on digital medical
imaging just a couple of things before
we start firstly if you've got some free
time today or even tomorrow to help with
her down
we would really really really appreciate
some volunteers so if you could spare a
couple of hours of your time to
volunteer at something anything on site
pretty much it would be greatly
appreciated and you might get a free
meal out of it
also we've had a wallet handed in it may
be picked up by now but I'm Robert
durham if you've lost a wallet
it's at the volunteer tense and if you
pick it go - there you should be able to
pick it up
other than that I'll hand you over to
Dave thank you
right I can hear me okay
this is yeah although i've been granted
the huge honor of a one hour slot
this is still going to be something of a
whistle top store one whistle stop
journey through a really large topic so
I'm going to need to keep going through
if it is desperately urgent stick stick
her hand it with a relatively small or
did so i can take odd questions but by
and large if you've got questions call
me afterwards and I'll sort out where
i'm going to be and where we're going to
be going
so here's what I'm going to be talking
about I'm talking about the overall
pattern of what happens from when one of
you goes along
let's say cgp he decides to order a scan
the most horrendously ambiguous term yet
used in medicine and he says that off to
the local radiology department is still
called despite the fact they do all
sorts of other things other than that
people with my energy electromagnetic
radiation and i'm going to use the
example here of an MRI you go in line
and not in a noisy tunnel and your
television pictures have been generated
week or so later you go back you see a
GP GP he's got a report probably hasn't
got the pictures because the NHS is
technology so bad they can't actually
get around the place and that's assuming
a GP could make sense of them but
there's lots and lots of things that
have gone on in the background
everything from how the images made how
it's stored poets
indexed retrieved viewed etc
i'm going to try to go through all those
various points along the chain to
explain what's going on to give people a
bit more insight
so yeah
why am I the person to be doing this
talk well I man or beast
I have a foot in both camps I'm actually
qualified doctor did medicine 82 to 87
so even though I took a year out in the
middle to go away and do a messy medical
computing did relatively normal jobs
then for nine years and everything from
being a Houseman working hundred thirty
hours a week with 80 our solid weekends
right way through to do my specialist
training as an x-ray specialist they
joke by interview that i was asked the
question dr. Harvey you have chosen
Radiology's our speciality is that just
because there are more computers the
square foot of the x-ray department than
anywhere else in the hospital my arms it
was only partially but I got the job
because of that all in spite of it I
don't know
anyway so including the end of that
after that nine years of training is
still called training even after you've
qualified in medicine
I then had a so-called Korea post for
six years as a consultant radiologist
actually specialist in swansea
I'm join which I developed my computer
interests further back
mucking around with the what was there a
relatively new standard for exchanging
digital x-rays will be talking about
more later became a hobby became a part
time job
just take a bit more and more of my time
and one day when like little difficult
in the department should we put it that
way this is being streamed i decided
that i was going to make a complete
change their last 14 years
I a non-practicing dr. running an IT
business we deal with the standards for
exchanging medical images which are we
talking about more later
I am officially a sponsor here and most
people we sponsor events come here to
actually try and sell
i'm not here to sell if anything I'm
here to buy in terms of buying time
if there are any of you who are hard
core programming geeks who find any of
this interesting and could possibly put
up with being anywhere near swansea come
and talk to me because that is what i'm
actually looking for but I mentioned
again at the end but I thought I just
put it in here at the start just to set
the scene
so what is actually happening we're in
and when this examination goes all the
way through
obviously the images have to be made
acquired call it what you will and that
i'm gonna be doing a lot of talk about
that in the next few minutes about all
the different types of imaging and how
different they are from each other
they then getting coded into a
standardized form called dicom digital
imaging and communication in medicine
hands up anybody here who's even heard
of that before today
Wow not more than i was expected
okay well you might find it but the
introduction to die , bit boring then
sent to the standardized system which is
a which is cross vendor with just about
every way every x-ray department every
hospitals got called picture archiving
and communication system where their
index that acts as the repository for
them they may be compressed and well
i'll talk about compression in a moment
which can save you about sixty percent
of storage space then get the tree back
to a viewing station and viewed and
their different ways of viewing them
either as they were originally or in
different planes and in different ways
are going to talk about that as well
and then finally of course somebody with
the same sort of letters after name is
may actually sits there and writes a
report saying
normal right
there's lots and lots of different
modalities as they're called different
types of imaging a in radiology
I'm not going to talk about them all but
there's five that i'm using to pick on
to it today because they're sufficiently
different from each other to give a good
cross sectional idea of the sort of
things we do we start off with good
old-fashioned plain films x-rays as
most people call and then of course
they're not really x-rays because the
x-ray is actually the beam of
high-energy well photons which actually
passes through the patient
what comes out the other end is
technically called a radiograph yeah
most people call them x rays or or or
plain films and until really 10-15 years
ago
most of those were still done with 19th
century technology
most of them were done literally with a
sheet of film of the appropriate size in
which the largest sizes 35 by forty
three centimeters with a plate on top of
it
you put your part you put your part of
the body by it
the x-rays go through they expose a
negative image and then that film
literally goes through a processor
exactly the same as you would do with
any with the size of photographic film
everything from a wet lab which they
were still using 25 years ago when i
started radiology through dry processing
to keep help keep health and safety
people happy and then through - of
course some versions where they will
rather more like a photocopier
but nowadays more and more of it is
actually done with direct digital
detectors such that they it's like the
same thing as you have a chip in your
camera in your phone or whatever it
actually detect the photons and actually
record them on a great but where is the
one on your camera is that size
these are still that size could it is
not really possible to focus x rays
what is interesting though is just how
similarities to what you have ccd
devices for cameras etc because you
don't actually record the x-ray photons
that's very very inefficient to try to
do that because it's not many things
which can actually record photons and
have enough heavy nuclei in them to be
able to stop them efficiently
so what you actually have is one of
which are drawn is this black line on
that on the diagram is a what's called a
phosphorescent plate and as each x ray
hits it it produces thousands of light
photons and if you work at the energy
relative energy of x-ray photons light
energy photons that works and it's then
the light which actually gets picked up
by the
detectives it was the same actually with
the later generations of conventional
film as well
the films are responsible to the green
light produced by the phosphorescent
screen rather than to the x-rays
themselves and then of course what you
end up with is a good old-fashioned
straightforward x-ray very
straightforward still actually one of
the mainstays of a level of a lot of
imaging the things that the chest is
brilliant is relatively low dose it's
quick it's easy and you got comparison
records going back for years
however taking that one step further
same basic method of distinguishing ie
how much x-ray photons get stopped by
the body you can take this one stage
forward further because if you think
about that previous image and so that's
a three dimensional structure collapsed
into a two-dimensional image you're
looking through one thing can be behind
another thing when things can be
difficult to see you don't know what the
depth is so in the late sixties and
early seventies and actually brilliant
guy by the name of God free hands filled
put together was effectively a skunk
works project acts am I
yes that is the same am i that produced
the Beatles records and worked out a way
of taking hundreds of images from
different directions around the patient
recording those digitally feeding them
all into a computer and when he first
did it in the late seven in the
mid-seventies you then waited about
three hours from the computer to crunch
the numbers could effectively what you
have is a massive set of simultaneous
equations if you've got
let's say in his early images 64 x 64
grid of points in the patient and you've
got
let's say 50 tie or 50 readings for each
position the gayatri and you rotated
that round 1 degree intervals
you've got a similar number of equations
you actually have to solve them
and these were solved initially
iteratively which is why it took hours
and hours on the computers that are
available then subsequently and in the
meantime
most of the work is actually being done
using for your methods which i won't go
into here i got enough
there's a there's enough for you to talk
to back you or later and come to the MRI
but interestingly in the last five years
or so people have gone back to doing his
iterative methods now that the computing
power is available to do it at a
reasonable time because they've actually
found you get a better signal to noise
ratio for the same dose or alternatively
and perhaps more appropriately
you can have the same signal to noise
ratio with a lower x-ray dose experts
more resistant to to quantum noise
so that's what he does not just to give
you an idea
I spent hours on PowerPoint making this
work so i hope it doesn't go as intended
yeah they're up ahead
thank you Michael
and so that's how that CT works and of
course when it's done it all by the way
the green blob in the middle of the
patient education and work out you end
up with a picture like that which is
actually picture of my father's brain
you and you'll be seeing more of that as
we go through
I i do keep this promotion family
related because i know i've got
permission to use those images right
ultrasound one of the non-invasive ones
this this one is not going to be
registering on the total population
radiation can't a show not only
dashboard at this event i'm not going to
go into a great deal of detail on
ultrasound
other than to say that it's basically
high frequency sonar you're running
signals in the few megahertz range and I
said that deliberately because in fact
the modern machines actually use swept
frequency ranges
because the higher frequencies give you
a better resolution close but don't go
very deep
the higher free with the the lower
frequencies don't give you is good
resolution but they go deeper so it is
it's quite complex modern ultrasound
machines but basically send out
it's just like sonar you sent out a
pulse you wait and see where it comes
back and where it comes back from and
you make a picture
I'm sure you've all seen ultrasound
pictures and antenatal ultrasound scans
interestingly from the point of view of
what I'm talking about today which is
how images get passed around the
captures the descrip the pictures you
actually take of ultrasound are almost
useless because you don't have a
standardized system for where the
probe's and recording it and it and so
on
the only person the pictures really make
sense to is the person holding the probe
who knows what they're looking at we
have to record them to keep the lawyers
happy
yeah medicolegal wouldn't be allowed to
say oh I've done it is my report and not
have something to go with it but
actually the images are very little use
said quite a few people now we're
actually recording video and if you want
to you can actually encoded up in MPEG
and i'll talk more about how that works
with daikon later
like almost every part of radiological
imaging the images you get back are
actually single child
there monochrome gray scale but that
doesn't stop people trying to combine
different sources of information into
the same picture if they want to
so what you can do with ultrasound
because as well as actually working out
what signal comes back from where you
can actually measure its frequency and
with a bit of work you can then use that
to actually work at the speed of what
you're looking at
apply the Doppler shift and that then
can get overlaid on the image as a color
signal which is incredibly useful when
you're looking at the heart because you
can be very difficult when you're
looking at a foul which they should be
that white and has been narrowed by ten
or twenty percent try to actually get
accurate measurements that is almost
impossible but because the flow through
it has to be fairly constant the person
wouldn't be alive even if you have
dropped the diameter by ten percent you
increase the flow speed through it by
twenty percent because of the square
looks and therefore you can really make
sure that accurately so this is the sort
of ultrasound image you get this is an
antenatal ultrasound
this is actually my own twins and if you
look hard at your left you'll see the
head of my daughter and on the right you
will see my son who's 18 the week today
and you can tell it's my son because if
you look very very carefully
if you get the bags up there that's one
lake
that's the other leg and there's these
balls
and he's sitting there looking
embarrassed right
yeah
so that shows how well these
technologies and then this was over
you know he's 18 next week and this is
over 18 years ago but that's actually
funnily enough the capturing these
ultrasounds which is very little use but
was using fast quantities of film which
was not only costing as 40,000 times a
year but incredibly eco unfriendly in
terms of all the silver etc was actually
the reason why I started playing around
with digital imaging in these days this
wasn't even direct digital this was
literally a video capture off the only
out for the ultrasound machine hat which
was it which was a video I put it into a
video card added the demographics and
store that as a magical image it saved
the hospital 40,000 pounds a year it
then cause them eventually to lose me
when I decided that was far more fun
than actually taking the pictures from
on the other hand he is this other
source you can get where you've got
ultrasound where we got damn doctor
sorry
and again it is only really to channel
information there is the there's the
reflectivity information the gray scale
and there is another independent
variable which is which is the flow but
traditionally if you want to show two
things you don't just use two colors you
use one is Grace game and the other as a
as a false color scale on top
so this is a nice picture showing the
heart with with measurable flow right
positron emission tomography how many of
you heard of positron emission
tomography
okay thanks to be sorry good
well it's actually it is a wonderfully
cool met imaging method
it was invented about 20-odd years ago
there's only one slight problem for the
first 10 years or so they had it they
knew it was cool
they knew it was wonderful then it was
technologically marvelous
nobody could think of a use for it
they just hadn't worked act what you
could do in terms of what substances you
could attach the radioactive tracer to
talk about how that's used in a minute
how what you could attach it to in a
means that would provide useful
information clinically they have got
there now they got babies markers which
they can use which careful going to your
radioactive tracer to tissues which are
particularly some cancerous tissues so
you've actually got a marvelous way of
localizing where the tumors are because
you've got some material which is guided
there
what's brilliant about positron emission
tomography is that where is everything
else we're doing here is working on
effectively emergent properties
stochastic effects
you're averaging act all these things
that are different happening it
what proportion of your photons get
through finding a quantum noise how many
going to get through how many arms and
so on
positron emission tomography you are
actually recording individual
radioactive events because what happens
is that if it's a positron emission be 2
plus DK what submitted obviously is a
positron and what happens when a
positron makes an electron but it
doesn't make morning more electrons they
turn into a pair of photons
now admittedly the majority of those
photons are going to be out of the plane
of the scammer and you'll never see them
and you'll never become up
but for those that are within the plane
of your scanner as we're showing here if
they both hit the detectors within a
very short time favourite time of each
other you know that the Commission must
be along that line
you also know the relative timing with
which you take those two detectives and
you know the speed of light
therefore you can actually place exactly
plus or minus it's a few millimeters or
centimeters is not one of the highest
resolution imaging formats we got
but you actually know from that single
event where in the body
it was obviously then collect a few tens
of thousands of these there are
practical challenges with pet largely
due to the fact that the material used a
half-life of only a few hours and you
going to make it in a cyclotron
I'm there for you and by the time you
taken into account all the extra time
after injecting in the patient for to
get around the patient etc that the
challenges of actually getting your
isotopes made
isolated produced the pharmaceutical
standards shipped around the country
injected into a patient and then the
patient imaged when you're half life is
I can't remember the date but no the
half-life of 1500 oxygen
it's a it's a few hours it's it's it's
very short and that does limit the
availability of pet two major centres
and but it's relatively low resolution
so what you actually tend to do it like
i was saying with the ultrasound with
the Doppler is that you actually
overlaid on top of other images and
typically pet and CT I used together so
the CT provides the high resolution
picture to show you exactly which bit of
the body you are and the pets then
provides the functional overlay to show
which bit of the witch bit of that
tissue is taking up the ice atonement
which according to what the isotope is
you can then tell about it now
MRI so sorry where I got a position yes
I should be positron correct thank you
very much
absolutely yes I i love nitpicking other
people so i can't complain what people
do to me
right we're now on to MRI which i'm
going to go into in some detail because
let's face it it is the only modality
that actually uses a strong
electromagnetic field so i have to talk
about that here reading and we are
talking very very strong magnetic fields
I mean and magnetic fields are measured
in Tesla's now I realize most people
when they talk about it if I DMF and the
talk about a Tesla will be thinking
something like this
I'm but no that's not what we're talking
about here
the Tesla is that is the unit of
magnetic field strength and to get some
ideas there's magnetic field fraction of
a micro tesla fridge magnets a few milli
Tesla's high power motors can sometimes
have a few Tesla magnets in them but
they're tightly
an MRI machine needs to be big enough to
take a whole patient in it it needs to
have a field that between x 1 and 5
Tesla and they need to be incredibly
homogeneous to within a few parts per
million
so that's how they actually built
I was going to try to show a real
picture i think the cutaway gives a much
better idea of just the scale of these
things and you realize why they cost you
a few million pounds each
because not only do you need to build
this have it is accurate
you also need to keep the whole thing
for a hold of its life pretty much at a
superconducting temperature so it's full
of liquid helium because you could not
make a resistive magnet that was this
that was this strong and this even so
they're all super conducting magnets
so what is nuclear magnetic resonance
which is what magnetic resonance imaging
depends on and i'll talk about the
distinction in a minute
whenever you've got a magnetic field any
nuclei with an old spin spin spin around
an axis power well to that field
now for those of you who have got
degrees in theoretical physics
please accept my apologies i'm doing a
wrote over simplification here
I'm not distinguishing between the spins
of individual nuclei and the overall
route resulting field
this is massively simplified but I hope
it's good enough at third for this talk
if anybody wants to shoot me down on my
physics later
please do so but you end up with it with
these nuclei and we're talking hydrogen
for imaging there either aligned with
the magnetic field we were imagine the
magnetic field going up and down on this
slide or they can be persuaded to flip
into the other field by a radio freq by
photon of exactly the right energy which
also happens to be by various quirks of
quantum mechanics
photon which has the same frequency as
the frequency at which it is processing
because it's like a spinning top
it's not it's not it's spinning itself
but then they
but then what we're talking about isn't
it spin speed is procession speed is the
speed with which it goes round red and
that speed and this is critical to the
whole of the rest of the imaging is
dependent on the magnetic field strength
it's about 47 maker hurts / Tesla
so which actually puts it but the other
two Tesla mad at you know two or three
tests the magnet mean you're talking
hundreds 250 acres you actually talking
roughly in the sort of standard radio
bat
I've seen bad and screened MRIs have all
sorts of artifacts which have turned out
to be due to local radio sources or the
local taxi company because that is the
sort of frequency band were talking
hastened right across non-ionizing there
for you yet you're not got the radio
you've not got the ionizing radiation
effects
so when the frequent when that energy is
applied it does this it flips
but thats its higher energy State like
most things in the world when they're in
a higher energy state what they like to
do is to flip back
so if you put a photon in to make it
flip what happens when it flips back
you get a photon back act and varieties
basically nuclear magnetic resonance
chemists do it for years any of you have
done a level chemistry in the last 10
years or so would have come across it
they do it in terms of parts per million
shifts
that's called magnetic resonance
spectroscopy
that is not what we are doing this map
is simple
NMR is great for a test tube full of
stuff you put it in there you blast it
you you get the signal out and that's
fine but he's not much use
knowing what the signal from a whole
person
please we need to actually know what the
signal is and how much material that is
and it but then again I'm not going to
go into details but whether it's fat or
water or whatever actually has an effect
as well on the different types of signal
so you're not just seeing how much there
is but let's assume for the moment that
we're just seeing how much there is a
particular type
we actually need to be able to resolve
it so you're not
that's the difference between my nuclear
magnetic resonance which is the overall
effect a magnetic resonance imaging
which is where you're actually resolving
it into a picture and in order to do
that of course you need to have
something which is different about the
different directions so as well
I mean it was on the diagram and I
didn't talk about it when you have your
MRI scanner as well as the main field
which is this incredibly powerful field
there are also three sets of what's
called gradient coils which can change
the field by about 1 percentage
it's typically a few tens of millions
testers from one end of the patient or
one side of the image or front and back
its its tricks that you can resolve into
three dimensions
i'm going to call them X Y Zed in fact
you can by using combinations of them
and this is when the great things about
mr i compared to CT
because you can use them in any
combination just with a simple vector
multiplication you can actually image in
any plane so as a CT you have to image
axiom the other girl named for the cat
scan computerized axial tomography
because that's the only way you can
image c NMR I you can image me this way
this way this way or obliquely if you
want to and that's very easy for the
time being we're just going to assume
we're talking XYZ is fixed dimensions
and of course these field coils producer
the field which is the same direction as
the main field but they're changing all
the time but they're producing a field
which is interacting with the big long
strong field can imagine how much force
there is on these on these coils you put
one magnet inside another and then
change it rapidly backwards and forwards
that's going to have some rattling on it
anybody's ever been an MRI scan has
probably been given earplugs
it's a very good reason
the actual vibration on these field
coils is very very strong and very
lagged but what when i'm not going to
talk about is how you actually do this
work
I like one of my colleagues down here
looking at the side was very proud to
protect me and said I'm am I going to
mention watching him and we have a
surprise to feel that I am because this
work was done in the early seventies in
Nottingham and that was actually another
UK Nobel price on top of the one that
term coffee ideals got for CT because of
the work i'm going to explain it to have
you actually resolve this signal into
three dimensions
lots more animated power points so
resolving in one-dimensional man call an
XY said but it really does matter just
called the 8th dimension another
dimension a dimension but let's stick
with exercise and for that is actually
quite easy because of the resonance
effect if you apply a gradient let them
and then you put in a a pulse of radio
frequency energy their natural
frequencies it is what I'm showing here
with the blue which is what they would
be right
this is what they would be processing at
a different because of the gradient
obviously exaggerating for effect on
here so if you have your external radio
frequency energy and you put it in there
is only the one slice of patient
where you going to have the residence so
only the only the protons only the
hydrogen nuclei in that slice are going
to be excited
the rest are going to be ignoring these
it's like you've got me three nice line
three
so they will absorb the energy they will
become excited
so every with me so far we've now got
one slight let's call it a slice around
my middle and call that the X so before
i go into the expert i'm afraid i need
to do a little bit of a tutorial because
it's important for the rest of it
i'm going to talk about Fourier
transforms anybody here not to know what
for your transform is
ok enough for you to make it worthwhile
if you look at your music system and
you've got a fancy music system
especially an old one from the seventies
or eighties
it may well have a spectrum analyzer
display on it so we actually shows you
all the different frequencies
ok it's actually very crude simple one
mostly they do it by operative you know
what have you got in the super bass down
in the 20 Hertz range
what have you got in the middle middle
range around a couple hundred Hertz what
if you got up in the high frequency high
hat but the principle of what you do the
Fourier transform is just the same
Amy signal can be broken down into a
series of sine ways and any serious and
those series of sine waves when put back
together with the correct phase actually
then can reconstruct exactly the
original signal something some bandwidth
of things but that will be no ever meant
the basic point is you can look at the
frequency way of looking at things all
the time waveform looking at things as
two different ways of looking at the
same data so just like you know if you
were to take a music sound and you can
you could either say here it is with
this shape repeating or you could say
our yes that's a signal of 14 Hertz a
signal of 32 Hertz the signal 53 hurts
in the following ratios and they're
there are different ways of looking at
the same
and what we're going to do with MRI it
depends fundamentally on this idea of
Fourier transform
so we're now going to take a read that
we've resolved the the X dimension
simply by what we have had excited so in
terms of wet what your screen
the X dimension is this way what's
behind the screen here didn't get
excited in the first place doesn't play
what's a long one row here doesn't get
inside them like what's in the planets
is the one that we've actually excited
by putting the be made have applied the
gradient during the time we have been
great we put the energy
so we've now got these 16 identical
pixels let's call them
ok the findings in the village but let's
that that's assuming things somehow we
have to make them more different
such that they're going to be solvable
because it's basically both and
simultaneous equations again
so it's actually quite easy to do one
the dimensions which were calling
worried because what you do is that you
actually change the Y gradient during
the time when you're getting the echo
so you apply one gradient coil you put
the energy in you've spun up just that
sequence
then why you're getting the echo back
act you apply grade in the other way
with changes the speed the spinning
so what you get act is a series of
frequencies and each frequency tells you
where in this case horizontally but
recording the y direction where the
signals coming from
so that's easy and it really didn't take
a great deal of maths and pick their own
work for people to work i have had to do
this is the difficult question though
you've used one of the gradients during
excitation you've used a second one of
your gradients during read out how do
you actually try to get resolution at
third dimension
how can you actually get a difference
between the differences along the said
axis and this is what the guys actually
got their Nobel Prize for and I think
they probably deserved it
so now what you use the actual I'm just
thought that you had my talks to use the
Exide ex-ranger excitation the white
gradient during retyped how can we use
that great it
the answer is that you use it in that
gap in between but what does that change
how can use that information
what changes is the things if you if you
speed something up for a little while if
you've got two people walking along the
same speed
one of them speeds up a little bit and
then they go back to walking the same
state
they're not next to each other again
because the one that sped up for a while
has moved ahead a bit and then things
that are spinning
that's called a phase changes . however
many degrees it it it in advance and
that's what you can do with the said and
what you then do our show this moment is
you've got more spinning you then
and you have to watch this carefully
because it's subtle you then applied the
third grade in change which does this
you will notice what happened
they sped up by different amounts just
for a short while such that if you look
at it as a 45 degree phase angle between
each wrote that when the top rows
vertical the road beneath it is pointing
at her past 10 beneath it is pointing at
three o'clock and they're open the fact
is pointing at us for so we shifted
faced by putting in this intermediate
then of course it redact I you apply
this is about changing speeds and what
we've now got is all 16 are doing
something different and that's a
fundamental thing you need in order to
be able to solve the maps
yes this was fun dedicated powerpoint
that fast far too long on this talk
so what you can't do is you don't have
enough information just from one set of
three types because you've only got that
one signal without one set to forward
with that one for you
so what you actually do is you have this
is why MRIs take a long time
maybe he's had one will know that you
having to sit there for several minutes
ago
twenty  and also the
wonderful noises that they make and I
try to make more you do it multiple
times with a different amount of the
phase encoding said every time and you
build up a complete and he would see we
have have a series of these lines
oh it's all right i just went backwards
so each one becomes a line you then
for as many rows or columns as you need
for your image you need to do that
number of what's called phase encoding
steps and read a pic ended up producing
a picture like this and this is a real
picture and then I'm afraid I have to
quit mr. been here
you do a two dimensional fourier
transform and as if by magic a picture
appears and that is literally what
happens at this stage
you've taken the data in a fourier
transforms which would you excuse you
from your transform of the image you do
the different phase encoding steps and
outcomes that picture and I think the
actual max behind that and the
simplicity of it when you actually look
at it in the end compared to what had to
be done with the CT
it's bit it has a marvelous symmetry
simplicity and as we pointed apt or
unwanted got the Nobel Prize utility as
well so that's how you get an MRI
picture
so where am I yeah for 40 meter
ok so you're made all the different
images you possibly got semen CT scan of
a GE MRI scanner
okie son ultrasound machine and a kodak
dr direct digital radiography
how are you going to look at all these
images right time to run around to look
at all these machines are going to talk
about for the next part of my talk which
is the standard that's used for actually
exchanging these images once you've made
them and effectively it's a bit similar
to what you have with JPEG you know
everybody's digital camera
whoever's digital camera tease will make
JPEGs ok there were people who tried to
do other things a few years ago they
pretty much died act so and it's
actually JPEGs and daikon was really
more closer to tiff but we know that for
the moment but the point is it's not
just the image is no good just having an
image if you don't know which patient is
which part of the body when it was taken
which contrast agents have been given
yadda yadda yadda
so basically what you have a dicom you
have the pixel data and you have a whole
load of other stuff that goes with it
it's even got its own network protocol
believe it or not because it was
invented about the same time
HTTP was being written those variations
HTTP now but at the time at the time
nothing else existed they wrote their
own and it isn't it's a very unusual
standard dicom because it encodes
everything from the semantics know in
terms of what I'm talking about X Y Zed
it actually defines impatient
coordinates which direction they shall
call X which is actually left to right
which shall be y which is front to back
in which he said which is head to tail
and they even define that for animals as
well which really gets fun
now I don't want bloody updates
right
I don't have any of you with the
previous talk but they they had the same
thing at the same problem right
so that's what the standard is it's
actually quite fun to be involved in i'm
one of the main terms of it and we had a
10 year birthday party for the standard
a few years ago
she's sad isn't it really I couldn't
find quite find the picture of birthday
cake but I got one somewhere anyway most
imaging standards have got metadata I
mean his I don't expect you to read all
the details but this is a picture taken
by my IT manager of the favor little
character he's got sat on top of his
monitor in our office and it's
interesting to see just how much jpg
data where there is you know the tin
foil hat pit brigades might find this
really interesting to me to be able to
see the the coordinates at cetera but
anyway that i can take this to a new
level
because here we have a CT against it my
father's you'll see in a moment because
the details are in there
his page 1 of the metadata page 2
including his name at the top
page 3 this is where you've actually got
some of the real fun details about the
low about the image itself like the
image matrix 512 by 512 the real image
size . for 37 millimeters per pixel 6 16
bits one thing is quite common about
medical imaging is that most of it is
done to more than eight bit
most is 10 12 or 16 bit not sure the
color most of that is still a bit but
most the ctsh was actually into a higher
bit depth and then a grayscale
transformation called windowing is
applied to the time but three others
I've interest I've marked which is
really really important we come to look
at the 3d which is 39 to line them is
we've got the image position which is
relative to an arbitrary coordinate
location but a defined coordinate
directions so that tells you where that
particular slice was taken and also its
orientation which you'll notice is not
actually one not not not one
which is what you would expect if it was
just along the x and y planes
it's actually slightly tipped which
makes it real fun when you come to put
these images together because they're
often taken not like a pack of cards but
like a pack of cards that you have
slightly slipped sideways so you don't
actually have a cuboid you've got a a
power level
gramma lead which really makes the 3d
reconstruction quite fun and then all
the rest of these attributes including
one interesting one at the bottom of the
pixel data because first icon is
concerned pixel data is just another
attribute has lots of attributes of
these images and one of them happens to
be the pixel data you can actually have
objects with a pixel data is getting
rather silly
so pretty much for the last 20 years
every manufacturer of digital image of
medical imaging equipment in the world
has complied with this DICOM standard
and they can all now send their images
into the hospital's picture archiving
and communication system which is a huge
great repository and they they they
typically you know hundreds of terabytes
some run into Peter bites which use the
defined archiving defined indexing
levels of a patient has a number of
studies study has a number of series a
series has a number of images and
they're pretty much modality independent
there are some dependencies in terms of
the low level data for instance you know
tube killer voltage which we saw there
on the previous at mct would make no
sense for ultrasound and so on but the
actual main bulk of it is pretty much
independent so the same packs can handle
CT MRI ultrasound and all the others
which is great and then it makes the
images back available back to work
stations for people to look at all right
I made a joke no talk to John T about
well you know if I'm going to talk about
this
I could really try to send people to
sleep with the talk about compression
and he said no don't
this is EMF you can't be too techy 3mf
so if you do find this bit too techy and
boring blame John T not me
um
so there are various ways of compressing
images do you all use the fact you're
jpegs are far smaller than the more
images medical images are so huge
there's a lot to be gained from
compressing them
not least of which of course it's an
emergency situation as i was doing for
home review if you want to be able to
get them down limited bandwidth lines
you get there a lot faster if they
compressed i won't go into the details
of lossy vs lossless here
there's actually a lot of work so you
can do lossless compression with no loss
of information whatsoever
all the techie people agree on that just
can't get the lawyers too
but certainly lossless compression the
medical equivalent or imaging equivalent
of zip is well worth while having i'm
just going to talk about that for a
moment because it's quite interesting
the fact that you know everybody here
knows if they know how it works i'm sure
you all know is looking for repeating
patterns which is why it works
marvelously on text and things here
where the letters th e going to keep on
appearing in English and keep on getting
replaced by smaller and smaller and
smaller tokens as the system goes
through
you can't really do that with imaging
because you don't have repeated patterns
are such the predictability of gotten
imaging is different
it's the fact that you most pixels in an
image aren't that different from the
pixels rang them so it's the differences
that you're looking at
not the absolute values and not the
absolute patterns so that's what's
normally use I'll talk about more in a
second so that said for the end for the
video and things when you wanting to the
ultrasound box standard mpegs got a lot
to be said for him and that can actually
be encoded within the icon the icon
allows the images to be uncompressed or
losslessly compressed with lossy
compressed or even for multi-frame
images it can be
MPEG I'm pretty impressed but still have
all the surrounding metadata to explain
what's going on
so here we are he's actually doing some
lossless compression
yes I know it's very very techy this but
what you do is you calculate what the
predicted value for a pixel would be
based on the pixels that have been
decoded so far adjacent to it
you then calculate the offset which in
most cases
is it going to be north of one most
pixels don't differ much from the pixels
around you then
Huffman code the number of length the
number of bits that are required to
store that data followed by then
providing the data itself
so in this particular case I've used an
example have been coding by the way is
arbitrary but it's typical ish so - 07 -
00 - 17 would become code is to needs
comes in the range plus or minus 2 to 3
so it has that is its have been coded
value needs followed by two bits which
00 in this case the zeros only need 10
bit
the minus one comes into the plus or
minus 1 so it has a firm encoding of
zero one in which case the value of zero
would mean plus 1 and 1 Willie - one
that's the one there and then you've got
the seven which is encourage further on
so you've taken what would have been if
it was 16-bit data 80 bits five values
each time 16 bits and have ended up
encoding the weapon haven't even counted
to be honest
aight i think I 17 bits
so you've got about 3 to 1 compression
there and that's about three or four to
one compression and that's about what
you typically get with this lossless
compression because the great thing is
you do actually get back to exactly the
images started with as ever it result
remain it likes it
it relies on having predictable these
images apply this to noise and it will
probably expand the image robins and
subtracted but that's you know that's
what you get
getting images to work stations the
daikon protocol can be used again
this dye column because it does
everything from specify the format of
the images through the network protocols
even specifies his own query language
it's like a version of SQL almost
because it sort of predates widespread
adoption of SQL this is 25 year old
standard but it doesn't mean you can
find all the images for particular
patients and and call back i'm going to
jump through this bit of it otherwise
we're gonna go on but you don't have to
look how are you going to review such a
large quantity of data
well believe it or not when I left
clinical medicine
15 years ago we were still taking
digital images and we were printing them
out on two sheets of 17 inch x 14 inch
film
Ellen fixed grayscale mappings and then
reviewing the magnet on the series of
monitors like this like this guy here
absolutely crazy but that's what we were
still doing 15 years ago
digital to analog to look at which they
lose all the flexibility you could have
then the next step was to go digital but
to try to replicate whatever you've been
doing any analog world
so is the stage where people had banks
of 21 inch CRT monitors which was not
much fun when combined with the NHS rule
they are not allowed to have air
conditioning in offices it
imagine these in a going back 15 years
in in a small office and it gets very
warm
yes yeah we could do is in here as well
because may then people move forward to
looking at them are in in real time for
smaller numbers of monitors
then they realize that in fact with a
modern computing power you could
actually look at these images in
different directions and I'll go show is
live in a moment but these these images
were obtained by taking slices this way
and then been reformatted into slices
other ways
uh and you can look through mathematical
maximum intensity projection and then
you can actually do
volume rendering if you really want to
produce fun fancy and fun looking images
have I say that carefully because they
are great fun to producing i'll show you
some now in a moment
the medical usefulness volume rendering
is great for showing patience is great
for impressing at sales conferences in
practice not many people actually do it
but the big thing nowadays it is you
want to go to talk about next in the
remaining 5 10 minutes and i got is that
of course you don't need the
supercomputers you used to have need to
be doing this
your average GPU like what I've got here
and I integrated graphics on my laptop
is actually good enough to be able to be
doing this live in real time with really
quite simplistic programming so if I
just quit out of this for the moment
well have had this is working when it
moves over
I see - oh yeah right
so there we are this is the sick this is
even just like it doesn't just know this
is actually my father's brain again
- images the green and red lines anybody
work out what they are
so no they're actually where each image
is on the other image
so if i move where that if i scroll that
one backwards and forwards you see you
see you see the line on the other if I
move this one which is moving side to
side it moves that one and you can do
all sorts of wonderful things that would
make you sick if you did this with your
real head you just spin them around and
so on
I get all of this this is actually a
single 3d texture held in the GPU which
I'm just not just re rendering that that
same texture again and again with with a
different matrix to say how to say how
to be applying it and that's yeah it's
relatively simple this is simple cut
plane so you only need to do one
operation for pixel is really quite
trivial
maybe this is a bit more fun maximum
intensity projection
this is fine see mr I didn't talk about
it earlier but things you can do with
MRI is you can actually do more fancy
things like you look where things are
moving
you can look whether whether they're
flowing and this is an angiogram this is
looking at the blood vessels in the neck
done with MRI without having to inject
contrast medium without having to go
putting a needle in somebody's growing
and inject all the stuff in the used to
have to do but the thing about this is
you can you can just do this
you can look around one little nice
oddity in view of what i was saying
about phasing coding earlier
can anybody work out what this bit here
is gone
No so now what
it is chin you have encoded in that
direction using faiths if you go too far
phase can only go from naught to 360
degrees
if you go too far in traps and what
we've actually ended up with because
they didn't quite get the positioning
right
is this his chin which should be here
has actually wrapped around the back of
his neck here and therefore I know
looking straight at the radio just
looking at this picture
I know which was in terms of what i was
talking about earlier which is the Y
direction which is the third direction
Zed direction phase encoding direction
is the front to back because that's the
only one that can wrap
so we've got the wrap on there but one
nice thing you can do with a special
want to look at things in detail again
if i go into a straightforward axial
view looking down
I've got the ability again because it's
all just in the GPU reasons - I can do a
cut and spin it round from there so you
can move stuff out the way that's
fucking then again
yeah this isn't this isn't a
supercomputer this is a bulk standard
business laptop with integrated graphics
going back to my father's head again
because it's been more fun this one
there's a prize for anybody who can work
out what was actually wrong with my
father and why it had to have this done
because this feels like clothes and the
top of the head
no no now though there were times I feel
like would actually be like to do that
myself but don't know bag art I have to
work out the prices
you're welcome to my company bucks
that's the prize i didn't i didn't
morning what the fuck was that you had
the cutting for here is really great fun
if you look at the base of the brain
which is great which is really young and
lovely fun structure
I can do that now if I spin you're
looking down inside inside the brain and
again just pointing out this is all on
that this is just using AG GPU is
technology which was
it's been invented an optimized for
games boys it wonderful for radiology
and I've got another image here
this is from the jaw it's a bit slower
because this is a higher
I think it is a faggot by a thousand by
500 or something says you know there's
basically a gigabyte of data here but we
will have attracted 64
it's a 16-bit data and again you see if
you want to look from behind
oh dear I got stuff in the way so if we
go back to say the axial view
I put a cut line all cut rectangle cut
around here
go back to rotate it's going to do it
this way so I can see where I'm going
around and now you can see the back of
the teeth
nice and clearly i don't know
none at none of this is rocket science
but it does give me an excuse to go back
into my last
slide which is just about right i got a
couple minutes left
which is to say that I actually know
what I should do is my business I'm
responses don't believe I'm like to talk
about my business for a few minutes but
unlike most sponsors I'm not actually
here to sell
I very much doubt with any of you guys
here who actually want to buy a dicom
toolkit
if you want to yes please come talk to
me but what we do is we don't do the
primary imaging we do all these sections
are labeled up here we we provide a
software tool kit which enables people
to convert raw data into die come to
handle it to do the network protocols
the query in the accessing and all that
3d rendering is actually our own
software as well so what I would like to
say obviously that's what we do we do .
com tool kits with hundreds of customers
throughout the world
we're supporting other developers we
don't have to deal with blips we don't
have to deal with the end users
we know we only deal with the developers
so it's a great fun job
and guess what we could do with an extra
person or two
so if any of you find this particularly
exciting
if you're hardcore programmer you love
the challenge of working in a totally in
structured environment with multiple
different languages
come talk to me for five min to be a
tent afterwards and I might have a job
for you . and finishing
yeah
thank you very much you've got about
three minutes left so if you like to
take like two more questions or so I'm
I'll take the two closest which of these
two here
thanks very much I just a quick question
about the MRI scanning that I might have
missed
and you get frequency domain back from
the receiver do you
and is it just a single frequency pulse
or do you actually vary the frequency of
the transmitter as well
you right you jet I was talking to terms
of putting a single frequency pulse in
what you actually do is you put multiple
frequency policies in and you actually
image several different slices at the
same time the ways of doing it with
minimal interference because when their
echoes are timed so the certainly the
generator can produce multiple different
frequencies and there are uses for doing
so but the simplistic version i was
giving here won't be the one slice would
be a single frequency in and then other
I a multiple frequency bandwidth limited
signal act
ok - small questions
first of all I recall that and radiology
usually you use black and white gray
scale monitors with a higher resolution
like 10 bit
is this still a thing or for current
this place catched up and I like you
also to say something about the amount
of gain you can get from jpg lossless
compression which I just found out today
that it exists
never heard of it how much data can
actually save using that right okay
first question second question first is
the easy one because it's updated
dependent lossless you the degree of
compression you get depends on the data
you put in and the at the engine bit
more precise the entropy content you
typically get about two-and-a-half to
three-and-a-half to 1 compression so
you're typically saving about sort of
sixty to seventy percent but it does
vary according to the noise level the
noise of the data the less compression
you get
it and it was actually defined in the
same standards define the original jpg
believe it or not that's a mighty
specification to find the one to find
the lost this is justice
it's rarely used as I dicom the monitors
there's a lot I Liberty stayed out of it
i mean you know I had a job to squeeze
everything into our so there are all
sorts of standards about how many bits
output you need to be displaying and
there's a consistency standard what more
the work is showing in fact is it
actually properly calibrated eight bits
will actually do you fine but what many
so what many people are now doing is
taking a bit with calibration in the
video card to produce the right
look up table in the card rather than
the previous approach which is
calibration software which then required
2-10 bit output card but what most
people completely forget if they do all
they're careful calibration to get it
absolutely right in a darkened room and
then they sit there actually trying to
use their carefully calibrated monitor
in a in a room with the windows open in
which case your calibration goes
completely to pot anyway you might as
well not have bothered and there's
actually more people actually getting
fda approval for viewing on ipads bit
dodgy to me but no imagine to get it
through the regulatory side
I'm afraid that's all we have time for
but thank you very much Dave