Heather
one thank you
coming I'm now going to hand over to
I'm just making sure I got that right
there just heading over to John is going
to talk to you about his self-made
eco-house so hands together for John
hi
so I'm gonna have a quick sort of
overview really i'm not going to go into
too much detail but i just thought if
you want to us and more questions
apart from that the end down but you can
come and find me around site somewhere
so I'm this is a the house I'd decided
to build myself Adam say well Adam when
maybe my for looking for a house we
decided we wanted to actually born with
a large garden maybe had a lot meant to
read wanted to so grown vegetables in
our garden and that sort of progressed a
little bit as we started looking we
decided to me might want to have some
animals and so it started looking around
for places that they have an acre and
I'm not a sort of snowboard a little bit
more
oh and yeah they even thought to make
this would be nice that we never thought
we could afford that and then I'm the
device being the chief decisions
decision-making by your house and we
came into this time
well i thought was an ideal opportunity
I'm set to arrive to look at it as we
had a 646 hold six months also at the
time and indeed breastfeeding so she
stayed in the car I had a look around
I decided that it's going to be a good
one so I went and bought this for that
had actually see again and i'm a little
bit of a mess but are their mind that
this was after a couple of guys who
spent a day's work try to clear the
stuff away
so you can actually see the house and
are issues that agreement because we
have always knew the other to get a
couple of acres and a nice house was
never going to happen so we were going
for ever building plot in some respect
so this had a house on it so we're going
to be able to rebuild a house there and
it was doing I am development boundary
of the village as well and so one of the
first priorities we ended up having to
do which was there an interesting one
with them
we have to build a garage first reach
this was actually gonna be our our
second polity we were going to build
this but we haven't we discovered we had
that's in the house so we had to build
them a nice college first for the
bathroom - I'm but this became very
useful because I could install lots and
lots of the house building stuff in it
and so on to the real subject has faced
I'm we were required so we can largely
minded say we did a bit of looking into
what we could do on the eco-friendly
house side of things and some of the
first things and when you do searching
on this sort of thing is that they're
the first golden already is 2 inch late
and to put lots more insulation on it
I need for even more information on if
you can because installation is really
actually quite cheap and it stops you
having any sort of heating bills to any
extent really later on
but after I mean after you've instigated
a lot you start finding that there to
half of your heat last thing becomes
because at the the house leaks air and
all the war where escaping the house and
and this is one of the interesting
things that build this don't quite
understand yet while they didn't five
years ago when we were building the
house debts
there's a lot of attention to detail and
a lot of things off I found out about
how to make it a house airtight heated
not losing all your warm air for no real
reason and and then we also looked at
him too low impact of materials and so
you'll see a thing called passive house
which is kind of make a and no ng house
and running but it's a problem I have
with the passive houses that has no idea
about how much concrete save use and how
much of it is logical impact that does
on the environment
building a house in the first place so
we wanted to do and bailed out would
mostly because that sort of is carbon
negative because you're storing would be
a CIT in the walls and got to have any
sort of really sort of trying to avoid a
Dominion is work that requires a huge
amount of energy to actually process the
other medium in the first place
I mean one of the other guy all the
girls was if we're going to go through
all this effort of building a house
we're never going to move the gate so we
tried to decide one that was going to
meet all our future needs to some extent
on today's is just making it a little
bigger than you really can't afford so
on the low impact side of things and I
want to do remove as much as possible in
dec 02 on the environment and in AC otey
use on constructions that's why we
avoided an ammonium and such
I know is there's also a time I don't
seem to think its submission and fast
these days there's this thing called
code for sustainable homes
that has a load of guidelines on how to
go about making a day returning a
zero-carbon house
the problem we have with a zero-carbon
houses to really go to that level you
need to generate energy on site somehow
and we have we have too many trees
shading are rules to be able to our
brief to be able to do and side side of
power of electricity which is what the
sort of thing wanted it to do
I know but when it comes to actually
build in the house is all sorts of
material so it's we went for it in the
frame house
- D word for the wooden walls ab we buy
used some eco-friendly paid so all the
glassware can order
normal mouse in the house is that are
impacted doesn't contain stuff like
titanium dioxide to make stuff white
because that's quite a bad thing
environment making stuff as well in the
first place and we where we try not to
use too much plastic if we could inside
the house
some of that was unavoidable but that's
how it goes
so yeah I mean you can watch all these
grand design programs and they give you
an impression that builders may know
about some of these new technologies but
if you talk to actually build it so if
you what grand designs or no and they're
all quite a bit and that field for them
so it's quite difficult to buy a fire
builder
so I mean the builders we talk to you I
mean Grand Designs the time had this
idea of co 2 negative concrete but none
of the builders knew anything about it
and so there's a lot of all battles and
that was one of the ones i sort of four
went on really
so I mean we decided not in the same
house and there's a once you've got him
the same that we got to insulate it
I'm so you got to fit in and fill the
timber frame somewhere
and some of the ones that i found most
interesting is a straw bale but the
straw bales actually a lot of labor to
actually put in
I'm and you have to go through a lot of
effort of finding a farmer who can build
your very tight straw bale in the first
place
and because i had a couple of a young
kid at the time I was working
I'm about an hour's drive away I we
tried to get at main building through it
do best a house for us and say that
wasn't even aware of this most
strawberryland him create as well as a
nice interesting technology but it is
out of time and still there's nothing
quite quite you and warm sell this one
I haven't had really heard of myself but
my architect
I'm mentioned it and that was actually
probably a good choice if we went with
warm cell is I'm the term recycled
newspaper but i think it's when they
have a load of printed newspaper that
they don't sell so it's still in good
condition they did not mention the app
makes over the bed blonde so it doesn't
get more do anything
and they've got this really sort of
fluffy tightly packed stuff that you
can't ban because there's no there's no
should I have inside it
I'm and the good thing is that it's
being unlocked for quite a while and so
some of the bells we talked to actually
build a house before using it and
there's other things you have after lots
of rest looking
you can win days one of the things that
also we chose and initial initial search
you will make you think that would
windows are premium product you have to
pay a lot more than a DP bc one day but
if you actually look around and find a
local timber in your local carpentry or
j chinese place they could make one days
they can actually do it for a similar
price two upvc and it
you can then use and linseed oil paint
which is a all traditional way to paint
you in days
not a not an eighties way to thank you
win days that they want to say if you if
you get to Papa join and you answered
all the page that those dishes glass
states like 60 years and the advantage
of witnesses said they were prepared for
that
upvc tends to get thrown away and also
on the structural insulated panels and
that's another building technique i
looked into and that's where they sort
of had these big panels that have gotten
plywood dog shit bored either side and
I've got a few PVR fame and stuck
between them
I'm that a the five minutes . between is
not really it doesn't really
eco-friendly enough for us
Adam and they can paint as i mentioned
i'm so when it comes to power in the
house
there's a few things I i was looking
into how about how to create energy and
how to him here at the house in the
winter months because although you can
build a passive house even the
Passivhaus standard which tries to have
a minimal footprint asst and then she
sighed as possible
I requires some space heating to some
extent and and I tend to have a a
ventilation system which has been
heating in it but my concern was with
kids really was and you get and the kids
leaving the doors open and calling the
house down too much
so in the only energy front of things we
looked at solar power that can be your
your normal pv which is you're actually
tangle set
most people accustomed to you can also
get there are more things so you get am
two types of some more panels which have
had more stuff which generally a tap the
water in that in the panel so you have a
flat plate 1 which I'm is the more
traditional one any of these new one
last but not like you anymore that these
new ones called evacuated tube ones
which is a bit like a thermos fast he
had this long tube with the heat pipe in
it
in a vacuum and there was one of the
technologies we want to because they
work better and the winter and in the
spring and autumn times where you get a
little bit more energy out and then the
flat panel and we couldn't we have trees
Irish a during our south facing grief
so we couldn't really use a soda side of
things sparkle to that I'm i also like
to win power and when power was it gets
quite expensive when you want a really
big wind turbine and probably start
annoying your neighbors and I was also
going to go to cause huge problems we
have bats
so there are bats weren't gonna go but
we'll probably going to get permission
for that and there's also a lot of you
go to love the South build type shows
i'll try and push on to these ideas to
the ground source heat pump more air
source heat pump and the problem i have
with those is they're quite expensive
and that you're really just using
electricity still to heat your house
so if you're somewhere where you don't
have names gas we could have got me and
asked if we wanted to
if there's somebody got mains gas is
probably more environmentally friendly
teasing - gasps and it is to install
your a source heat pump
well you guys the ground source heat
pumps the one where you have a big tube
into your garden and you take the heat
at the garden with electric type like
your French you like if how you frig
works and put that into your room and
the a source of the problem i have the a
source ones is the most efficient in the
summer when you don't need it and at
least efficient when it's really
freezing outside and it's cold and then
you actually need to eat some of the
other options we looked into a burning
wood and we also did look into - gasps
but decided not to connect up yet
because that's going to cost us
foreground and also there that you can
you can take your house with you i'm
just using a normal makes electricity
and so the side of tiles are as I said
that there's the PV is not suitable
workers as I understand it you get you
can have your south-facing roof love so
the panels
Beth a tree mask still just a small tent
to Center for those panels
that's it you're the efficiency drops
right off on your solar panels you don't
really make much electricity and I
believe now there are it held in vertice
can power so you can take the harvest a
powerful one thing out of time but at
the time i was looking into that that
that was a new technology that wasn't
quite released
I'm so the flat panels and I said that
sort of traditional bit like a black
girl aged 80 by the whole thing is just
got water in it and say that that is
affected more by the cold weather than
am evacuated tubes and yes so did you
pass on the actual heating is that the
Passivhaus world
you still need hot water people still
expect with hot water to be there
available every day of the year
so even if they even a passing you to
get your water somehow and for us and
especially living into it we we find the
space heating between november
february's when we start thinking about
whether we need to heat a house a bit or
not
outside these months it was just they
don't care they just don't think that
I'll whether we've got enough eat or
water 27 stone and we have a couple of
kids now so they they running at the
house and don't close the doors and
stuff so if we went for that whole pass
out house problem
I think we didn't have actually some
type of heating behind it
we made struggle so on are
Cena and so in the end i went with am I
thing called a step there more store so
I am thermistor is sort of best or out
as a large hot water tank been reverse
so instead of using the water in the
tank the water in the tank is what you
heat up and the actual color than the
tank is what you put your cold water
mains into any out the top it comes out
as hot water and domains pressure and
that's good for showers and stuff you
don't need any of their that shall come
to anything like that
we just showered the I am mains water
pressure
so we find that the am during their
spring summer autumn we get in a hot
water and really quite well and we just
find that when we have cloudy days we
just plan our showers or bars they were
out of the study days really
I'm out of work to do here house during
the winter we have am wood-burning stave
which is actually a German model and I
spent days i think on the internet
trying to find the best one and I think
I found it
so this one's got I am I think all the
water jacket
that's not just on the back of it comes
all the sides and the top as well that's
that's good because we've done a very
well insulated house and we find that
and the one kind of what it puts into
the room and then it is so it's a 10
kilowatt and boy last days
it's dave your normal sort of small
state of about five kilowatts
so this was twice as aight size of a
small one and the one kind of wanted
persons to him
where does really like but a large
kitchen diner and that's it still can
get that quite warm
efforts are careful I'm and all the
other day i can what goes into that big
thermal store that we can run there
enough
underfloor heating off I'm but we
that's don't store has a couple of Adam
imagine haters in it as well just in
case we need to use it and we're too
lazy at some point
not that we really come to that yet that
talks about working
uh-huh so the performance of our house
I think this was with one of the bigger
nose i was having when I was trying to
design and build the house but you can
get all these e value calculations all
these sad calculations but you still
don't know what that means in reality
i'm so we've got a better than what the
the sub Scouts we may actually an energy
rated beyond the SAP Scouts because we
don't have any actual electric
generation take care about and what we
find that when it's I'm freezing in the
in the middle of winter and we have the
house at 20 degrees c and he drops a
couple sees it too greasy every night
and that's where that big and you are
under floor heating on it or anything
I'm and that the self at tubes do do a
good job of providing a hot water doing
this
Marshall october and we have a slight
worry occasion in the summer when we got
a few hot days and that the the set of
hands pumping away in the tanks at 210
degrees and the time is getting 2 95 and
stuff that hasn't seemed to cause any
problems yet there's but when you get a
solid the austin saw that that high it
seems to drop lose quite a lot overnight
anyway i'm leaving the winter the am if
we put the underfloor heating on and
really cool down at the thermal store if
you get a nice sunny day in the winter
we still get a bit of energy out of it
which is useful I'm one of the things
that was on my real big richness to get
the builders install wizard the lane
water harvesting system but they're
going to charge me ten grand for it
I'm rate seems like a lot for just a
tank capacity attacking the ground
so about a year after Beltran
our company is after we moved in nothing
and I did it myself so that I got him to
put the sort Sol phrase all to the same
place
I don't spend about a thousand pounds on
high we can do you got to dig a trench
one of the things we really needed we
wanted water into a field anyway so I
love but why did Doug a big trench
I'm haha her hips slightly on the
civilian side of the way in hell i
bought 12 IBC's which are these big Adam
thousand need to contain us at the ship
liquid around the world are bad 10 days
into the ground covered in concrete perp
made it next to it and then put laps to
filled with the other and in the
trenches got everything you never think
of and that feeds back to the house and
that flashes our toilet window washing
machine so that sort of 1 i've actually
got after winning that sort of took two
thirds of our water bill and so some of
the other tack
I was just as i'm a geek i was i was
busy
it's in the early stages try to get on
towards the end of the project ended up
big I just want to get a house finished
so i put 1 y temperature sensors in all
the floors and staffing in the walls a
bit as a maybe I'll daughter at the
house and the heating system but in
reality that's for me over killed
because we find that one when we attend
the on the floor heating system a couple
of hours later they could take this
court to cold anyway into workable
without the fire began to have to put a
wood burning fire on to actually hit
house and the other problem is the that
because the house is so well insulated
it doesn't really need that fine control
so as for me a pipe dream know that we
are finished
but I also program can cut five
networking everywhere so every Power
Point and houses got a cat five bucks on
the next to it because I could i don't
know i am working on it not as am an
open source energy monitoring that is
i'm sort of setting up now sir to
control with stuff there's a lot of
things that I learned and this is just a
few of them
I'm one of the things I've in hindsight
I maybe could have done would be to put
windows in the house claim of the house
get mortgage
I then use that mortgage money to build
a house cuz ya without house their
mortgage
you can't get a mortgage and get
self-build mortgage for that a too
expensive and be very quite restricted i
had the problems like the death
110 notes of hot water tank went into
the attic and I didn't think it really
looks strong enough and the bad melon
meeting minutes from the builders that
they said it was strong enough then the
builders sort of went bankrupt me
and then so i went to the timber frame
company said did you make them very
strong enough to hold water tank and
they go now
we weren't told about that so I'm glad
that I i did keep an eye on anything but
I just worried that what would happen if
i wasn't really on the ball but you live
in that I mean it could watch what grand
designs and there's all sorts of went
weird of 14 building stuff on God
designs
thanks again talk to you normal did
builders nice and haven't heard of any
of them riches interesting time
one of the things had but one of things
i ended up doing with the plot i bought
was a notion riches and on the day that
you're there the or should we have to
pay over ten percent of the deposit
which issues you're not going to like
check out for ID and yeah that's when
you exchange contracts
Dave and you have to be ready I don't
have the video option is good exercise
for your heart i would recommend it
I'm stay one of the best I think things
i did do the same to be a load of times
to him
hire a proper professional
spray-painting machine the house we
built is a four-bedroom house with in
the attic space we actually use so i
made the pitch a bit bigger is if you
got a huge active actually that we have
a nicely done much with because we can't
afford it bad that four bedroom house
with a huge attic
I managed to Spain mystery because of
mystery case of paint
I'm painting walls different colors to
some extent and after weekend and got
there because you just mask off the
window so you put in
don't care about everything else really
I just go to town this paper machine you
can you can get a i'm sort of
rectangular piece of aluminium on the
boat on the stick so you can split a
white root your white ceiling and you
can hold it in the corner and going to
play your balls
you get two of you and one holding that
the stair couldn't you the other one
spray painting
yeah as I safe 8 rooms will say enough
and we came three coats and my last
bears
if you are building an airtight house is
you do need a second amv HR system
images of mechanical ventilation heat
recovery system
I'm one of the problems with them react
we when we first moved in we were quite
finished . it all sleeping in delivery
and we have serious concentration
problems for the first week until i
actually got my awesome together
did it got the m-th arts commission and
the conversation has disappeared
it wasn't an issue anymore and it also
removes the need to have trickle vents
on the windows which is another way you
lose heat it stops you needing any
extractor fans are the bathrooms or the
kitchen or anything like that it's just
I it's got heat exchange on it so it
why does it taste it and fresh air in
from the outside
and passes after in a change was all the
air is sucking out from the real and
moisture m0 kitchen your bathroom so so
worn out just kitchens bathrooms passes
student in heat exchanger and uses that
hate to hit warm up the hair coming in
I'm the SAPS calculation stuff that says
howard officially houses don't seem to
like it for some reason to consider that
Jesus small amount of electricity
positive thoughts constantly but it
removes to me to have any ventilation of
the way and it's a it's one you can
control
so I'm i believe this time for questions
if anybody has any me or you can always
email me and come find me later
and there's also i am one of the good
things is there in in bath
I'll i was living and rest of the time
in bar there's a self-build the group
set up where it's just like her father
I'm people had fighting challenges
building their own houses and is that I
found really good
I think we have time for a question if
it's answered quickly maybe two
I saw the gentleman here at the back
first I'm going to hand you the mic cool
thanks for the talk
um baba internet provision doing that
you seem to have picked a random piece
of one somewhere outside the village
so it may look like around the place
like it's actually a village it's got
about 300 houses and we we were actually
part of development boundaries the house
sold for the corner so that the house is
like on the beltline closest advantage
in the house was actually
and when we moved in yeah i was getting
about two-and-a-half Meg download speed
but now with the somerset and Evan
broadband initiative that actually can
put fiber to the cabinet in the village
so I've now got 70 make which I'm quite
amazing because all of the sort that was
never gonna happen
ok and it's now four o'clock so if you
have any more questions for John just
have them at the side of the stage or
outside and you'll be around all weekend
right fantastic cool let's put our hands
together for John thank you very much