alright so the next we've got
is
Theriot and it's how is the universe
like a light bulb so a big hand please
good afternoon everyone you're having a
good EMF camp
excellent so what I'm going to be doing
is kind of a bit of a cross between a
physics talk and a comedy show so who in
here enjoys watching comedy a excellent
excellent who and here enjoys watching
physics talks
hey you in here likes niver excellent
you all into my place
I'm know that this is a bit of an
experiment and as such i'm going to say
well I'm my aims of the experiment heart
out the front which is a good
experimental practice idea actually want
to be doing a double blind experiment to
see whether or not this was a good way
of transmitting physics
so I was going to try and put in a
second event which is going to have the
exact same title but be contemporary
dance but luckily that turned out to be
too much bass so you are excused on that
but what I'm going to be doing is I'm
going to be talking through some stuff
with and basically linking get through
the physics
so things like how is universe like a
light bulb all
how is you might you might know this one
already this is an old joke
how is duct tape like the boss and they
are answers joke is it has a light side
and a dark side and it holds the
universe together and no no it's all
comparison that you might make another
famous one is how is a raven like a
writing desk and there are a couple of
almost canonical answers to this one of
them is they're both in key and no one
is powe wrote on both but because i'm
coming at this from a physical
perspective I think the answer is both
bizarrely and made of exactly the same
constituent parts and obey the same
physical laws
despite being really very obviously
different and if you don't mean
obviously different then
yeah there's no hope I'm sorry you have
to leave it there but there's so many
things that are linked by the physics
underlying them and I was a bit
disappointed a while back I was reading
the garden Guardian education blog and
they had a letter
well an email i assume that had been
written in by someone who is choosing
her a-level subjects and she said I
don't want to do physics because I've
been doing physics and biology GCSE and
biology just seems so much more relevant
to my everyday life learning about
things like stem cells and I think if
we've got to the point where the subject
of physics which is literally about how
everything in the universe works is not
relevant to your everyday life
then we're doing something badly wrong
also if you're doing if your everyday
life requires stem cells when you're
doing your gcse's then it's possible you
might also be doing something wrong
so I wanted to put this together and
kind of bring all of the different
things together and also a lot of physic
talks they're all they're all about
astrophysics all about particle physics
and they're brilliant but there's such a
lot so much more to physics and I wanted
to kind of talk about some of the always
nitty-gritty they're often gets lost so
I i hope you'll appreciate all of that
so we're going to start with is how is
around about like a space station
1 answer that i have heard is a lot of
Americans haven't seen either of these
and don't honestly believe that they
exist but there is one that them as
anyone here driven through milton keynes
yeah did you enjoy driving through
milton keynes know now it are used to go
and there's a bus between cambridge and
oxford that I've been on called the x5
and it for some reason it did it goes
from Milton Keynes and all that you get
all the way through is getting shot to
one side and shoved back to the other as
you come out to the roundabouts and this
is this
don't understand this you've got to kind
of like we're going to use some actual
technical physical terms here because
most of the time in your life we talked
about how to speed
something is moving at but what we
really care a lot of time bout is its
velocity which is just a speed plus the
direction direction is really important
because if say i was wondering out
outside and then you said
which way is it to the toilets and I
said oh it's okay
there are only 300 meters away
and think of your direction I am giving
you not enough information is the same a
lot of time physics we need directions
as well and so technically the
definition of acceleration is a change
in velocity so it can be a change in
speed or it can be a change in the
direction and so in when we go around
the roundabout
because we're changing direction we are
accelerating and it seems to be this
weird link between acceleration and
being thrown about and feeling feeling
being pulled somewhere
so I'd like to do a bit of an experiment
with all of you
this is just a force experiment so it
doesn't require you to be from your
chairs and I just like you to imagine
that after this talk
you can wear out you had a fun rest of
the year and a half and then you went to
bed and then you woke up
bizarrely in what looks like a lift
you have no idea how you got there
perhaps you party too hard at the bar
tonight and you are just there stood on
the bottom of the lift and you think
that's usual
that's what normally happens I'm stood
on something I can feel the ground
pushing up against me
this is usual but since you don't know
how you got there something else might
be happening
you might be out in deep space where
you're so far away from all the other
stars and planets that the force of
gravity is negligible almost zero and
all that's happening instead is you
would be floating apart from the fact
that your rocket ship is constantly
accelerating in one direction so to you
it feels like there's gravity pushing
you away from that but then if you're in
the left something bad happens
the lift cable snaps the live starts
falling down and you start falling down
at the same rate as the left you at you
you lose contact the floor and just
floating floating there is a lift
plummets heading towards what seems
inevitable
at this point you're probably hoping
very much that you are actually in the
rocket ship and in fact all that's
happened is a rocket ship has stopped
accelerating leaving you free to float
around in zero g and it was this kind of
equivalence between acceleration and
gravity that caused eyes and using the
cause
albert einstein to actually come up with
his general theory of relativity which
is basically a theory of relativity
number two the first one was special
because it involved gravity
why that make something special is an
answer there is lost in the mists of
time so i think so
when Einstein did this he realized that
actually gravity did more than that
oops i mean it's just . slides on
he realized that gravity did more than
that because in theory of relativity
healing space and time and in the
general Philip very of relativity
he put gravity into the mix in that
warped space-time which is of course a
really poor naming system by I'm saying
is literally just taking space and time
and ramen together
I wonder whether or not Einstein was at
the time you thinking about this
getting slightly angry because and
perhaps even eaten a ham bread which I'm
sure is what you would have called a ham
sandwich
so he's got all that is put it all
together and oh one thing you might not
know the mathematics all relativity gets
very complicated and Einstein was the
master of the humble brag because he
said no matter what your problems are
with mathematics
do not worry for mine are far greater
i'm not i'm not struggling with that low
level mathematics
I'm struggling with the really epic
mathematics say than that and under you
eat food as he wrote some equations
which are basically the old einstein's
field equations and some of these
described kind of
how the universe changed over time and
Einstein actually joining this was an
awful awful scientists because the
results that came out of this
we're not what he wanted they basically
said I've a well they basically said all
of the matter and energy in the universe
will effectively be pulling back inwards
and so the universe will be up be
shrinking or if it was already going out
words that would at least be
decelerating come back in and Einstein
didn't like that so he put in what we
put call in physics in a very technical
term a fudge factor
he had literally no idea what this was
it was just because he wanted the
universe to be unchanged and eternal he
had no explanation for that
he later called it his greatest mistake
but we'll come back to that later as to
why it might not actually have been his
greatest mistake but the other thing
about this is that we've kind of got a
long way from our initial point which is
that acceleration and gravity are
completely linked in the last in
situations you cannot tell the
difference between them and these this
picture of space stations is actually
one that was kind of drawn for NASA as a
suggestion of what future space stations
might look like
as you can see there long cylinders are
pointing towards the Sun to always pick
up things and solar power but what you
can't see because it's still picture is
that these would be rotating and so you
have basically exactly the same
situation as a car going around the
roundabout you would feel yourself as
you know is going constantly around the
roundabout pushed out towards the side
and that is what you would feel inside
the space station
so this variable gravity doesn't just
link roundabouts and space stations but
also link some too
so they'll come back to later which is
just the fate of the entire universe
so the next one starting again little
close to home
how is a streetlamp the opposite a light
from a distant planet
now this is a very specific type of
street lamp who he recognizes this team
can tell me what element is using it
sodium yes this is a sodium streetlamp
firms to those you are watching earlier
cat was talking about sodium lights
being used in film special effects and
reason that they were used is because
they put out
technically a few but only one very very
close
colors of yellow light and the reason
they do this is down to quantum
mechanics and I realize I'm pushing a
bit in that i'm only about 15 minutes
into this and I've already gone through
relativity and quantum mechanics you can
like the big theories of the 20th
century but it's not as complicated as
sometimes it can be made a sound
you can have lots of people talking
about Schrodinger's cat and is it half
dead are half alive or is it both dead
and alive until you look at it and
there's lots of quantum weirdness like
that but the thing about quantum physics
is we've tested it really rather well
and we know that it's weird but
eventually we know how weird it is we
can quantify that witness and that means
we can use it and you can use it for
example to tell us what will happen when
you put has electricity into a sodium
light and what we've got there is what
I've got one equation followers which is
the Schrodinger equation which is kind
of the key equation of quantum mechanics
don't worry there are many equations
here but basically are on the right hand
side you've got
the energy of a state and on the left
hand side the far left bit you've got
basically some fundamental constants the
mass of whatever it is you're looking at
and a mathematical operator which some
of you may or may not recognize and
that's kind of that's kind of just a
quantum mechanical way of looking at
some things motion the v term on the
other hand is a little bit more
it basically says insert the rest of
physics here all of the rest of the
physics is basically combined into that
one B term there
this is actually a great frustration to
some people because obviously the rest
of physics includes gravity and we still
haven't worked out really how to
properly get that in there we can't get
relativity and quantum physics two play
nicely together but when we're looking
at that that's that's everything we're
looking at a solid
that's basically saying look at the
effects of all of the other surrounding
atoms electrons in that the electric
field we put up our cross things
basically not inside a particle inside
of an atom in a sin to its all of the
forces a strong and weak force which
involved inside the nucleus in various
cases but mostly it's going to be
electric and magnetic fields and that is
what's going to change things inside our
sodium light but no there's a funny
outcome of this equation which is
basically that we have very few specific
energy levels for things this is in fact
well I quantum mechanics gets its name
it comes from the word quanta which
effectively translates as a bit of stuff
and so in quantum mechanics we could
have only very specific sizes of stuff
in this case it's the energy of the
electrons inside the sodium light
they said in very specific energy levels
and when we jump up when we want to give
them some power by basically switching
to comment on what the electron will
jump up to a higher energy level and
will then fall back down again some
random time later
and when it does so it's got to give up
that energy somehow and how it does that
is by emitting a particle of light or a
photon and it turns out that the color
of the light that you see depends on the
energy of this photon and because we've
got just one size energy gap we get one
specific color of light coming out of
our lamb and so so why do we why do we
even use this in lamps and the answer is
because we're cheap at this like this
color lie is actually picked up really
well by our eyes and because it's doing
going this way
basically most of the energy that we put
in through these lights are coming out
as the light and it means that we can
use less energy in order light and our
streets at night and we can still see
really well but you might wonder what
does that got to do with light from
distant planets and it
this is the kind of the opposite and we
have to have to take a step back and
look at distant stars first
so in these distant stars we've got a
huge giant balls of plasma and light is
being produced in the center of the star
is kind of making his way out is being
absorbed its being we admitted loads and
loads of times
but eventually it's got to come out past
the router bits of the star and there
are some gases there as well and what we
have exactly the same situation we have
gases with specific energy levels but
different energy levels because they're
different chemicals the electrons inside
them are bound to the nucleus
differently so we get we can see when we
look at these distant stars we see a big
spectrum of light just as we see from
the Sun but there are some gaps because
basically what's happening there is
light is coming out of the Sun but it's
trying to get get through this gas is
coming out towards imagine you are now
representing earth a lot of pressure on
such a small group of people but their
way and i will be a distant star and now
is gas in front of me and the lesser
light goes into that gas
some of it gets absorbed it's a right
energy to actually make an electron jump
up an energy level it precisely matches
that gap but then when it gets we
admitted it can get we admitted in a
completely different direction to where
it was coming from originally is coming
at you but now it might instead be going
in that direction it might be going back
into the star
it might be going somewhere else and so
most of the light that was coming at you
of that specific allure color that is
being absorbed will never reach you
and so we see these gaps in the spectrum
these dark lines where we'd expect
normally to see a color but we can go
one further than that because we've been
detecting exoplanets recently
have any of you seen the news about all
the exoplanets that we think the Kepler
mission have been detecting yeah
one of the ways that has been done is
basically just a planet passing in front
of the star and blocking out a tiny tiny
bit of the light that's coming towards
us and we actually have sensors which
are fine enough we can actually detect
the dimming as the planet passes in
front of its star
but even more than that when a star
passes in front
ok when a planet passes in front of the
star so does apply its atmosphere and
that's made up of gases as well and so
some of the light will be absorbed by
the atmosphere and again scattered in
lots of different direction so it won't
come to us
so what we're seeing is not just dimming
of light due to the planet physically
blocking the light
we're also seeing some doing because the
light going into that planet's
atmosphere and then being sent off in a
different direction and the frequency
and hence color of that light
depends on what's inside that's planet's
atmosphere and so we can tell what's
there
ok I don't think excited enough we can
detect atmospheres and planets in other
solar systems by the light that is
blocking from a distant star forget jet
packs
we are living in the future now and
we're hoping that we are actually be
able soon to recognize some of the some
of the molecules or compounds that we
associate with life as well
all from just a slight dimming of that
light being captured from the light from
the star being captured by those
molecules and admitted in a completely
different direction
according to the rules of quantum
physics and I think this is a really
exciting there and it's all coming from
this key equation of quantum physics
so I mean that's pretty awesome and I'm
looking forward to seeing what comes out
later
no next
how is the sound of formula 1 like light
from distant stars and the sound of
formula 1
I don't mean the sort of sound which
involves that lots of rich people
sponsoring teams and money possibly
being used in dubious ways
well I mean is the sound that you hear
while stood next to the track and I want
to recreate that sound here
so what I'm going to do is I'm going to
. sweep across the entire audience and
what I'd like you to do is I'd like you
to make the sound of a formula 1 car
going past
on the count of three one two three
ok
and so what we've got there is the
Doppler effect
this is something which i'm sure most of
you will recognize and be able to talk
about but I am aware that for some
people in here some people might not
have actually got to this point in
school and for some people i know
GCSE or low level physics was a long
long time ago
so can I have a volunteer please come on
the stage
it's ok you know you're not going to do
anything complicated than that
please go to the stage big round of
applause for volunteer please
ok thank you so if you could just take
one end of this slinky and just take a
few steps back
so we've got it basically taught so i'm
sure most of you are aware that sound is
vibrations in the air and why I'm going
to be doing is I'm going to be using
this slinky to represent those you can
imagine can I each bring a slink a
slinky being a molecule inside the air
and when I'm talking and it's going on
the speaker's what's happening is we're
getting a vibration back and forth and
some in some places the slinky is
getting tighter than humans are getting
closer together and in other places
they're getting stretched out and that
those compressions and stretches are
traveling down the slinky also getting
reflected at the other end there there
which we know is a function of waves of
which sound is one but that's a fine if
I'm just standing still
if I start menacingly approaching Sarah
all of as I'm pushing this back and
forwards
you'll notice that the areas of with
other again
the as I'm getting closer the areas of
bits we just squished together are
getting closer to each other and the
areas of stretch are also getting closer
to each other
where is if i'm doing that while I'm
reversing
they're getting further apart
thank you very much a big round of
applause my phones in you and so we're
basically what we've got there is a
Doppler effect in action as I was moving
closer to the person who is hearing the
sound the sound waves were getting
squashed together we call the wavelength
which is about equivalent to the gap
between the squish together regions
where is getting smaller
the frequency of those getting too
obviously was getting higher and the
picture sound goes up which in the case
of the sound of formula 1 is the knee
whereas when they go past we get them
spread it the waves spreading out the
frequency going down and we get the
album to again
technical terms but one interesting
thing is that you get that weird
continuum between them
it doesn't go me Alma gosney I'll and
slides along the way one way I've heard
of explaining this is this only happens
because the f1 car doesn't hit you and
this is because when it's coming
almost every toward you its speed with
the way back to the directions being
important again all of its speed is in
toward you and so that gives you a
higher pitch but as it's getting closer
to you
less than a smaller and smaller
component of that speed is actually
coming to watch you it's going past
things going past you don't change the
frequency and so as it's going down
there getting close and close to you
the amount of which sound is Doppler
shifted get smaller and smaller and
smaller and then as it's going away from
you the opposite happens as it gets
further and further away the Doppler
effect gets bigger and bigger and bigger
and the frequency goes down even more
but this means that when you're watching
all the kindly old films and kind of
looking at World War two documentaries
the scary sound of the bomb falling is
not the one that you think it is
the scary sound of a bomb falling is not
the one the slides it's a one that is
just a whistle
which sounds exactly the same as you are
hearing in because that means it's
coming directly towards you and this
often happens happens for a lot of their
different waves including light
his light is an electromagnetic wave is
got oscillations in the electric field
in one direction and in the magnetic
field basically at 90 degrees in that
direction and it can have the Doppler
effect two things at the same way but
the reason you don't see it when our
projector screen is wobbling back and
forth is because light is very very fast
and basically what you need to get to an
appreciable fraction of it in order to
be able to see it
so what so we don't have anything really
hear that is going to be going fast
enough on this planet to be able to see
it but we can look at these distant
stars and we can look to see where the
light is Doppler shifted good but
compared to what
how are we going to tell the difference
between light being changing frequency
because a star is going towards us or
like that was just that color when the
star admitted there anyway and this is
where all of the spectra that we were
just talking about coming useful because
when we were talking about the sodium
lights
it wasn't quite just one yellow line it
was a few different types of yellow
which were very close together in
frequency and so
they have very specific gaps between
them and so we can help
look at the lights come from these
distant stars and look for those patents
in the light that has been absorbed by
the gases around them and so we can
therefore measure whether or not they're
moving towards or away from us and a guy
called edwin hubble in 1929 did this and
noticed that for basically every star in
the galaxy that was not our own
the light was being redshifted it was
moving towards a red and inspection
which is the same as going to a lower
frequency and so the objects were moving
away but more than that he discovered
that the further away
this galaxy was the faster it seem to be
moving there was a linear dependence
between these two things and we call
this
Hubble's law he was actually the first
one to notice this
actually there was a guy called george
lemaitre who actually published results
about this
two years earlier but he had something
of a disadvantage
he was French now that that wasn't this
advantage disadvantage was any published
his paper in obscure French journal
which meant that something French wasn't
really being read as much in scientific
journals by that time and so people just
in me that whereas Edwin Hubble's paper
on it got distributed and science is all
about not just getting your results but
sharing them with the wider scientific
community and so poor the measure not
only did he not have his paper read it
was later translated into English and
the translator left out
some of the key bits about this because
what we don't know but possibly because
they matched what Edwin Hubble had
already published in english and so even
then he didn't get the recognition of
actually discovering this first but
going back to the idea of Hubble's law
it does just luck
like all other galaxies just really hate
us and have been trying to get away of
us was basically you were if you want
i'm back
they've been trying to get away from us
all the way back until a point where it
looks like they were basically on top of
us and this was on the first evidence
for the theory of the Big Bang the idea
that the entire universe basically
started in one . and has been expanding
from there ever since
but there's still another few twist to
this tale which is that one inside this
we've looked at the acceleration and
we've been measuring it over time and we
expected based on Einstein's theory of
relativity that the acceleration
if they were going out the acceleration
must be decreasing because of all the
mass and energy pulling everything back
in words but when we look at the
measurements we don't see this
we see I'm not entirely up to date with
what we see as i believe was still a
small acceleration out the universe is
expanding faster than it should and so
Einstein is cosmological constant of
fudge factor that he put in these
equations
it turns out we needed that we needed a
bit bigger than he put it put it in
there and they're not so can be
competing theories as to what this
actually is and some people say it might
be the energy of the vacuum in quantum
physics your ground state has some
energy and it might be this which is
causing space to expand but there's a
slight problem with that
and that's formed particle physics
measurements
we've got quite a good idea of how big
this should be and if we compare that to
the size of how big it should be for
astronomical purposes
there's an error of 10 to the power 120
that's a one we have a hundred and
twenty 0 is activated which is really
rather embarrassing and we don't know
why we still don't know what this is
and then there are lots of theories
going around but fundamentally we just
don't know this is still an active bit
of research and so we've come a long way
from the same effect which gives us the
sound of f1 cars going past an ambulance
siren is it going past two boys now one
of the biggest mysteries of the universe
why is accelerating and that we still
don't know
ok how you all how you're doing you are
following a moment there
yeah it's good and what I like say we've
gone through some of the biggest bits of
science there but now for this next bit
i am actually going to get you all
involved because i have here a set of
elastic bands and i'm just going to
throw these out lately told you might
need some help getting to the at the
back and if you could all just grab one
of these passive and share them around
that would be brilliant
and yes you can just pass those all
around because what we're moving on to
next is how is an elastic band like a
fridge and for this I'm going to have to
be asking all of you to take an elastic
bands and make your own observation
so those of you who've got them widely
to do is I'd like you to take elastic
band into hands and hold it up so that
is just touching your face here like
some sort of natty mustache and like you
very quickly but we will be able to have
time in between them
stretch out really quickly and then
relaxing really quickly
stretch out relax it and just feel what
it does
what does it feel like on the top of
your lip
but when does it get warm when you guess
what when you stretch it what about when
you let me relax
was that
and when you relax it it gets cold and
bizarrely this effect is down to one
want one of the most fundamental rules
of the universe and time
so who here has heard of entropy before
yeah yeah a few people to people
entropy is a quantity we like to define
in physics which is always increasing
inside an isolated system and that's a
very important bit of the rule entropy
always increases inside an isolated
system an entry can be thought of as a
measure of disorder
mom I actually almost like the number of
ways that you can do something so
there's gonna be a lot of people like
most people say are the entropy means
that things just naturally get Messier
so for example I shouldn't need to clean
my room
he'll just get Messier any way to which
the fundamental flaw is your room is not
a closed system and so you can't use
that excuse them for exactly the same
reason
if you're creationist you can't say that
and she always increasing
it is it disproves evolution because it
evolution obviously things are getting
more order to come to the final time
audio coupe to the fine specimens we see
out here today and they say oh well
that's more they can't have happened
you've ignored half of the rule you
cannot ignore half of the rule that
would be like me saying the rule is you
can drive at 70 miles per hour on a
motorway and then proceeding to drive
through the center of town at 70 miles
per hour
it doesn't work and and yes some people
still trying to use this as a result but
going to the elastic bands and basically
the reason it heats up is because we
need entropy to always be increasing
so the first way that we've got entropy
inside elastic band is it's got lots of
long fiber chains inside it and these
are all giggling about in space in lots
of different directions and when the
elastic band is small there wiggling
around the normal lot and basically
there's lots and lots of ways they can
wiggle and the elastic band be small
which means that in this state they have
high entropy
but when you put taught all of those
bands line up nicely and then there are
only a few ways you can do that so that
physical position has low entropy
but there's more than just how to change
chains can wiggle
there's also how they can jiggle because
none of these chains a stationary
they're all moving all the time and if
things are moving faster then again they
got what they have got many more ways in
which they can achieve this and so the
moving faster means that you have a
higher entropy
so when you stretch your elastic band
you all the entropy based on how the
chains are aligned goes down but it gets
warmer all the entry based on how
they're moving goes up and basically
when you're letting go
exactly the opposite is happening is
still ended up with a net increase in
entropy
but you have to put energy in so he eat
up your get kind of getting a pull out
that collect elastic bands can pull
things they'd be giving the energy to
that and so they've got to lose energy
and cold cool down as well and so you've
got all of this going on but that
there's a blow it
no more there's also just how they're
losing heat to the outside world
this is my last equation so we can sure
you're glad
and this is a really simple equation for
change in entropy now on this left-hand
side we have D s as entropy and so TS is
a change in entropy and on the right
side are going to be on here
that's nonsense I equation that is
actually a nonsense equation i do
apologize that that d on the bottom has
snuck in and shouldn't be there the
bottom of that equation should just
safety so cause DQ is the amount of heat
flowing into a material that's positive
it's flowing out of material is negative
and tea which should be on its own on
the bottom and i'm going to have words
with that d later is the temperature of
that and so as you can see he goes in
the entropy increases he goes out the
entropy decreases but the amount by
which it does so is related to the
temperature of the body and this
basically explains why when you've got a
hot thing and a cold thing together
the hot thing gets cooler and the cool
thing gets hotter because
the heart of thing higher temperature
there measure of course in kelvin and
the the color thing has a lower
temperature so for the same amount of
heat moving
there'll be a greater change in entropy
for the cold object so the heat moves
the color object overall entropy
well increase there's a bigger change
for the color object to say my feet
lower temperature so that's great
and that explains kind of heat flowing
but the fridge doesn't really do that
it'd be kind of a rubbish fridge if it
did it in the fridge we've got a cold
area inside and he is removed from that
and dumped in the hotter area outside
so how we always getting an increase in
entropy and this equation shows that as
well because usually a fridge again is
not an isolated system
it's plugged in and so we can get
something so when transferring heat we
can create some extra heat basically by
using some of the electrical energy
we're getting flowing in
so the energy goes it goes leaves from
the inside the fridge and the energy
that comes out the back of the fridge as
heat is not the same amount more energy
is coming out so we can put a bigger DQ
and we can overcome the higher
temperature of the outside and still
keep entropy increasing and this in fact
all the way around inside the fridge
entry is always increasing you've got
you start off their inside afraid you
got cold fridge you got a cooler with
regimented now in the back
he flows from hot to cold increase in
entropy then you let that then you don't
you let that go through a that i can get
it
excuse me then when you've done that you
your heat your your-your-your now
slightly warmer fluid goes on the back
and is compressed is getting compressed
into a smaller space which means there
are fewer ways all the particles inside
it can be arranged
and so that would not only be a low
engine be put to counter that it heats
up higher entropy is now at the back of
the fridge is now in the little wavy
been to the back but now because it's
got hotter
it's hot on the outside it flows from
the hot to the cold
increase in entropy and finally it's
allowed to go through an expansion valve
and spread out it spread out more space
more ways of actually being able to have
the particles and arranged and higher
energy there and it cools down as it
does so and so all the way around
we've got this fundamental increase in
entropy and in as a physicist
that's really really weird is normally
in physics things people have any one
direction happen in your direction all
the laws of physics basically apartness
look the same depending on which way
round you look at the meantime this is
the only one that seems to have a
direction and this is Labor lot of
people start pondering on whether this
it gives you the meaning of time at the
only problem there is basically what
you've got is physicists talking
philosophy which is never a good plan
hello i am willing to do it with a few
points inside me if you see near the bar
later but when we've got one of these
weird lack of symmetry we should start
looking for more because they're
interesting places and one of the
perfect place we get them is in matter
and antimatter perhaps because inside
when we have energy of the vacuum i was
talking about earlier
sometimes that can spontaneously cause
some matter to be created and when you
get a particle and antiparticle at the
same time
normally these their meat and I late
done that's fine we not changed anything
but we expect the Big Bang equal amounts
of this matter and antimatter to have
been created but you look around and
we're all made up out of matter
you can tell because we not basically
exploded when we come into contact with
anything else
and so like we got this weird difference
between matter and antimatter and this
again is a current research project
partially at CERN we're just trying to
work out where it is
there's a difference between matter and
antimatter that actually allows anything
to exist at all
so we've gone through an awful lot of
physics
we picked up quantum physics we picked
up general relativity and we picked up
the contact concept of HP and these are
all kind of like always the fundamentals
of what we've got to work with and so
we're finally ready to go to a grand
finale
how is the universe like a light bulb
and I kind of jumped over a bit earlier
where I was talking about lights coming
from stars because I said you get a
whole different colors
loads of different colors of light and I
didn't really explain how that happened
how we had the entire spectrum before it
was absorbed by the gases surrounding it
and so the reason I didn't say that is
actually in some ways it's quite
complicated but it wasn't that way we
look at the light coming out from the
stars and we look at the ideas of
entropy and likelihood of various things
and with the entropy
we have said things go too high energy
things go to more disordered well as
more different ways of doing it and with
light as you get into the high-energy
light the high-frequency UV rays and so
on
then there should be more ways for that
we happen in caused by the jiggling
around of all of the plasma inside the
Sun but and so in that case we should
expect to see a lot more of it
we should expect basically to have the
entire planet irradiated by UV rays and
none of us existing at all
bizarrely it's the fact that this
doesn't happen that physicists have
called the ultraviolet catastrophe
yes yes I'm physicist again bit poor at
naming things often and basically we
didn't know why it was this didn't
happen until a max planck basically
looked at the shape of the emission this
is an example of the sort of shape that
we get from the the emission spectra of
stars and saying well and the
high-frequency why do we get this taylor
and he basically said let's go back to
quantum physics
it was a back to it basically was a new
thing around then he was kind of just
making it up and said well let's assume
that there's a possibility of getting
things which goes down as the energy
quanta involved gets bigger and more
people said to him why that why would
you do that
and he didn't know but it worked and
then allegedly they normally I teach
physics sometimes an end to my students
I'm always very keen that they write out
there working in their explanations
I wouldn't have accepted it just works
normally the only reason we were it was
really accepted by then is because it
gave us grass like this this is some
experimental data and basically the
error that the line that's going through
all of these points does it so well that
that the predicted line which is from
his theory goes with it so well that we
basically can't distinguish between the
two
and so this was brilliant and men that
we actually were getting somewhere
but still is kind of unsatisfactory
so it took a little while of quantum
physics actually coming in before this
was kind of accepted
we talk about all the different energy
levels and this kind of basically
eventually all worked but this data
isn't from a son
our star this data is in fact something
which is very similar to that which was
developed and discovered by arno penzias
and robert wilson in 1964
they built basically a radio telescope
and wanted to take lots of measurements
with it
they were good physicist say they cool
down the senses so that things weren't
talking about in there so much said it
had less noise inside it
but no matter what they did they got
some constant noise and they did
everything they could think of their
appointed the antenna all in different
places they still got this noise
they tried doing get join a day by doing
a night same noise
they tried doing get or different times
and unlike many experiments they had to
clean out what was referred to as
dielectric material which have been left
in the Horn of that their antennae
because some pigeons have been using
inside it and they clean it all out and
they still got some noise and they
couldn't work out where it was and then
this is where we see how the world of
real physics is very different from
school because basically what they did
is a phone . their colleagues nearby and
said we don't know we've got a signal
we need to get rid of it so we can do
our experiment do you know what it is
and then going contact with contact with
some physicists and nearby lab
who were very very disappointed in order
to get this phone call because their
reaction was I think we can we know
precisely what this is this is the
remains of the Big Bang
this is like that has been bouncing
around since basically shortly after the
Big Bang and as universe is cooled
it's shifted and basically this is a
spectrum for the University of a few
Kelvin a few degrees above absolute zero
and that is what this particular one is
it's exactly the same shape as you get
form stars and also from things like
eight filament light bulb but when they
were doing this
yes
so this was an amazing results and they
want a lens is on wilson won the nobel
prize for this which i think is
brilliant not only because it's an
amazing discovery
but what they won the nobel prize for is
basically being business who did
everything right
they try to remove all the sources of
error in the measurement
they went through it nice and
systematically and then they asked for
help and then they finally found
something
a very with someone else and come up
with independently which matched and so
I'm i think this is a wonderful place
was to be at but it's not the whole
story because this isn't actually their
original results
this is some later measurements taken by
NASA and in fact if you
oh one of those things like their color
ways of thinking about this but based on
the shape is the same for black bodies
but the position of the peak changes
depending on temperature so one way you
can think about this is is this
temperature because universe was
originally very very hot and has cooled
down since but another way of thinking
about it is going back to our formula 1
cars and our definitions from different
distant stars you can think of this as a
light originally basically being having
a lot
smaller wavelength and gradually being
stretched out as time has gone on and
moving towards left hand side of the
graph and so we're now a point where
we've seen the universe
you see how it's like a light bulb but
no matter how good with some results are
as soon as you start looking deeper
you're likely to find something else and
this is w map project
this is looking basically at the sky and
looking in all distant different
directions and these colors are
basically slight differences in the
temperature that we get from that nice
grab in different but when we look in
different directions
obviously red and yellow is hotter than
green and blue is colder and these are
all on the order of 1000 of a calvin
1000 of a degree temperature difference
which is quite a bit when you're looking
at just kind of 2.7 Calvin to start with
and this is where we are now and we're
wondering whether or not this is kind of
an imprint of fluctuations in the early
universe which basically meant there was
actually a way for things to start
coalescing rather than being forever a
diffuse equal throughout the entire
universe just set of matter things to
start coalescing and forming stars and
galaxies and planets and eventually all
of the processes that led to people and
the modern world today so I i hope you
enjoyed this
I hope you feel like we've come a long
way and we started from things that you
are used to
and I hope you enjoy the rest of EMF
camp one thing that I need to pop my
hand is all of the wonderful people who
made all of the figures and images i
used throughout this slide
attribution is very important especially
when you see science images on the
internet please make sure that
attributed to who made them but so just
two questions to evaluate do your thing
you've learned something
yes excellent and have you enjoy doing
so
as well thank you very much after we can
call this experiment and accept success
thank you very much and enjoy the best
your cam