and hi everybody my name is crazy i work
at the British Science Association i'm
going to hand over to have ready spring
a very very sick very soon after this
very short introduction and so I wake of
the British Science Association and
Bradley actually won one of our reward
lectures which he presented at the
British Science Festival last year and
and this is part of his his award letter
was giving this and talk on flexible
electronics and so if you're interested
in the British Science Vessel do you
find me afterwards this year is in
swansea in September
it's going to be great there's a beach
party and there's hundreds of events so
you do come along if you're from that
area or if you fancy a trip
the hour is beautiful so now I shall
introduce ready stay ready as priya is a
researcher at the University of sorry
and he research he is flexible
electronics and there are many
applications as they now can we
introduce him gets giving us giving a
welcome has given around
thanks very much thank you hello
everyone I am I can't see your faces I'm
just assuming that you're here
really i'm going to start straight on
because the time is quite sure for this
one
this is a talk about plastic electronics
this is a talk about electronics so I
thought we start in the time in place
which was absolutely essential for the
beginning of electronics which is of
course the capital of Romania Bucharest
where I come from so we're in 1998 in
about sep tember 11 saturday i was
coming from a film that I saw with my
girlfriend and i stopped at the bus stop
waiting for the bus and i bought my
first copy of this computer magazine and
I spent most of the evening reading it
and in there
the most fascinating thing possible was
this the pentium to 433 megahertz
processor this was an absolute behemoth
and I thought this is it this is the
future they seized the pinnacle of
semiconductor engineering so I was
completely enthralled by this but then I
got a bit sad
mainly because the film we went to see
was Titanic but it was more than that
you see I wanted to be part of this
thing I wanted to be part of the story
of electronics I wanted to create things
but it's unfortunately I was just a
child I was just going to school so I
wasn't able to do anything
and this was the future and it was
happening now and I'd missed it but was
it
let me remind you how the nineteen
nineties looked this is how computer
graphics looked in the nineties
this is how mobile communications looked
in the nineties and this is how web
design looked in the nineties
so was that the future well it was in
some sense but not quite
it was in fact a small cock a small part
of a chain that started with the
development of the first integrated
circuit in the fifties by a bunch of
guys that look like this one guy in the
picture
probably to your left is Gordon Moore
now go two more become famous for
Moore's law which is really an
observation is a lot of law at all
this guy at some point looked at the
amount of stuff that was going into an
integrated circuit
he said ok there were five or six or
seven components up to about 20 up to
about 30 by the mid sixties
so he just drew a dotted line and that
dotted line went on for 50 years to the
point that these days
computer chips have parts that are a
hundred of a millionth of a meter across
and there are many billions of them in a
single chip the size of a fingernail and
where of course concerned with digital
circuits where we only care about the
zeros and the ones we only care about
the extremes of of what the data can i
can represent analog is getting a bit
left behind I suppose in the public's
imagination in the digital world but i'm
going to tell you in a second that
analog is or rather plastic electronics
and the future of electronics is all
about analog so in analog we're really
concerned with all of the values that a
signal can take from its minimum to its
maximum and the plenty of Heroes for
animal for digital but there are a lot
of unknown heroes / analog as well who
is this
do you know who this is
what will our fantastic so this guy was
instrumental again in creating fantastic
electronic circuits amplifiers current
sources you name it
analog electronic circuits in the
sixties and seventies and eighties and
he was not quite the advocate of digital
as this picture shows right analog is
something that that I hold very DM and
in fact eventually to go back to this is
the story on my first slides
eventually I was able to work on some
fairly clever analog circuits still in
Bucharest and still something that I'm
quite proud of the thing though is that
all of these circuits analog and digital
usually are made of my new specs of
silicon
so the chips are quite small as you can
see but there are plenty of electronic
circuits which are large by definition
and we were talking about what what's
technically called large area
electronics but mostly display screens
right they're meant to be large because
that's that's their thing they need to
be large so the circuit has to go on a
fairly large substrate usually glass and
this is a genuine this genuine size of
the glass that people make TV screens
and and things on now of course glass
has a bit of a problem and i'll show you
what the problem is with this simple
video and i'll explain the UH the phone
there is just used for contrast is not
part of the circuit but i'm going to
make a very simple electronic circuit
that I'm gonna brother electric circuit
that I'm going to tie together through a
piece of metal eyes glass
so there's nothing very clever about it
is just a piece of glass with metal on
closes the circuit when that happens an
LED lights up but you'll see in a second
that glass has its problems
so that's just a simple circuit if we
use this glass slide with aluminium on
top
we just close the circuit and of course
the LED lights up right now the problem
is glass very frequently comes into
contact with fairly rigid stuff and we
all know if we had a mobile phone be
dropped on the pavement that happens
quite frequently and quite tragically so
you've seen the circuit dies the circuit
is broken so class has its problems but
what we do with our screens is we
protect them by encasing cell phones
into some sort of plastic cover and this
is exactly what i was doing when I was
making this video i was using some sort
of plastic protection for my eyes and we
do this all the time for electronics but
why not make them out of plastic to
start with
so here's a bit of plastic that I've
metallized only on one surface and we
still close the circuit the way we did
and long story short this can take a lot
of abuse as you might think
there you go
right so why don't we make all our
electronics on plastic rather than on
glass a large area electronics
well the problem is of course the
plastic doesn't really like high
temperatures and a lot of our processing
of the materials that gets into our
electronic circuits has to happen at 400
or 600 degrees Celsius a lot of the time
glass barely can stand that plastic
wouldn't stand a chance
right so we're
we need to change completely the system
of our fabrication we need to use other
materials other machines other processes
to create electronics on plastic
ideally that can we stand low
temperatures we talk about plastic
electronics but we can also call them
printed electronics a flexible or
solution process in the sense that the
materials that we putting down
I now put down at very low temperatures
in the form of things like inks sorry
pastes and gels by printing stamping or
even spraying so this is extremely low
cost fabrication at low temperatures for
future electronics and then of course
advantages things like costs and area
you can do this on a vast area without
having a large production machine you
can do it a bit like you print
newspapers and magazines and of course
you can print a lot of them
the point is that soon enough we should
be able to print electronics on flexible
plastic at the same speed as we print up
I know hello magazine however there are
downsides the biggest downside really is
the speed and by this i mean the speed
of our circuits so the problem here is
that the materials that we use the
semiconductors that we now use in the
place of silicon are now a thousand to a
million times less able to pass current
so the transistors that we're making in
the circus that we're making are going
to be slower by the same amount and
you've is a problem if you're using
these very fast production techniques
a lot of the time you're patterning is
going to be mediocre to say that the
least
and you you are going to end up with
either completely failed or circuits
with very very different specifications
to what you expected
now i work at the University of sorry
in the electronic engineering department
and the approach that we've taken to
solving these problems of yield and
speed and uniformity for plastic
electronics is to completely rethink the
design of the building block of the
transistor and we've come up with this
thing called the source skated
transistor and it's very very similar to
the conventional transistor that we
using display screens
except this time we're using the contact
between the metal and the semiconductor
and the barrier the energy barrier that
forms naturally there to restrict the
current and this gives us a lot of very
beneficial advantages I suppose so
for a start what we do to to look into
these devices is we create computer
models we simulate we fabricate and then
we measure we test these devices
so the way we do this is we use computer
software that will solve some fairly
complex equations in semiconductor
physics we discretize these so we told
the computer where precisely to solve
the equations of course you want better
accuracy in the places where you want
the data to be quite precise and then
you get something like this and this is
a bunch of electrical characteristics of
a transistor working in an analog
fashion
so as you sweep the voltage on the on
the egg scale you turn the current up
from virtually zero to something that he
could call Bob sizable I suppose
and then we make them we make them with
fairly conventional technologies like
this one with photo lithography the way
we've always made by Jerry electronics
but we make them with printing as well
and then we test them and then we get
fairly similar electrical
characteristics
so I mentioned printing and the idea
here with this device the cleverness of
it is that it can withstand significant
tolerance or process variations so here
what i'm showing which you can't really
see I suppose is the two curves for two
devices that are 10 times different one
is about 20 microns what about 200
microns long and we get exactly the same
characteristics which is not something
that you normally get from a
conventional transistor and this is
fairly important because what this means
is that when you're printing at very
high speed and the picture on the bottom
really shows a deliberately bad print of
two parallel lines when you're printing
at extremely high speed this transistor
will have exactly the same performance
regardless of the waviness of the of the
lines or the distance between them
so this means very robust electronics on
plastic on paper
you name it so this device is
particularly energy-efficient it gets to
the problem of uniformity and it is high
gain as in you can make very high
amplification devices out of it and
circuit
it has downsides as well of course one
is speed so because we are restricting
the current as it enters the device at
the metal contact
we're probably losing about ninety
percent of what this device could go at
and in terms of its switching speed and
because of the physics the current
passing through it is very
temperature-dependent that is probably a
major downside and it's different
probably his biggest problem is that is
different industry works on for six or
eight years time scales and if you come
up with a new idea
that's good for I don't know next year's
product
it's never going to be incorporated
because people have have thought of what
they're going to be doing for a number
of years so it's quite hard to actually
get this
into into industry we saw the
temperature problem with some some
fairly clever simulations and i'm a show
you if we have time and the speed is not
entirely problematic for the very simple
reason that we're not trying to create
processors and graphics card we're
trying to create very simple electronics
which will probably go at a few hundred
Hertz or a few tens of kilohertz at the
maximum so this isn't really a problem
in the real world
I'll show you really briefly how this
behaves in comparison with a
conventional transistor
so you can use the transistor as a
current source and ideally a current
source would look like this
irrespective of the supply voltage you
should get exactly the same amount of
current and you should start getting
that current from the moment you apply a
minut voltage across it
this is the ideal characteristic of a
transistor as a current source current
devices look a bit like this
so of course the flatter the
characteristics are the better the
source gate of transistor looks like
that
so what we're going to be doing and I'm
going to show you two videos of again
lighting up a simple led by passing by
passing current through this transistor
and in turn driving the LED with current
so what we're going to do is we're going
to sweep these characteristics
so we're going to go from large high
voltage all the way to zero and back
again
a number of times on the same curve
first on the TFG and then on the sgt
and what's going to happen is that the
TFT the conventional thin film
transistor is going to drive the LED
with increasingly lower and lower
current so the brightness going to drop
until eventually it goes down to zero
and then you're going to see this
happening a couple of times the second
film is about the source gate transistor
where as you might expect from the graph
the currents going to stay virtually the
same for the majority of the . so the
LED is going to have the same brightness
until very low supply voltages
so here is it
and see right at the bottom is the
supply voltage which is negative and
then you can see the tiny LED losing
brightness and being off for the
majority of this . and if we go to Sgt
driven sorry
here we go so it's the same period the
same time frame for this process but the
LED stays on for longer of the . and it
doesn't lose its brightness
this is with the same tech with the same
technology in fabrication but using this
trick of controlling the current at this
metal semiconductor contact
so as I said we can make these with
conventional technologies but also with
armed printing
let's stop type in jet printers stamping
spray coating that sort of thing
so this or gate transistor is a very
useful device for flexible and printed
electronics because its robust and its
light energy efficient and it has this
this property of uniformity
but it's only part of the story because
apart from very good electronic devices
you need to come up with feeds or ideas
that you couldn't realize before with
conventional technology i'm just going
to show you a couple of things that
people have been doing around the world
in the area of printed electronics
so this was last year a fully
functioning microprocessor made by
inkjet printing in Belgium
now the problem with this one is that
it's about the same performance as
something coming out of 1972 in silicon
technology but it's just the beginning
and it's very likely that we're going to
be able to do exactly the same thing
akin to moore's law with these types of
transistors in these types of
technologies in Japan
check out some AR is working on very
thin printed electronics
so this thing is an array of sensors
that will you put presumably on your
body to to monitor your hair
the interesting thing about it is there
is just one micron thick again when you
talk about nanotechnology that the
stereotypical comparison is the width of
a human hair 50 nanometers or 80
nanometers
so this is absolutely feather-light
electronics or feather for the weight
rather electronics
so this is how they imagine that this
might work you stick it on it would send
some data wirelessly would be powered
wirelessly and then when you don't need
it it would either peel off or even
absorb in the US and a banana champagne
John Rogers is working on transient
electronics
so these are things that can be
dissolved either if you're ingesting
them and they stay in the body for a
couple weeks and then they just simply
are dissolved or things that you put in
the environment and they are either
water soluble or with very let's say not
nasty chemicals so a a great deal of
effort is now looking into the ecology
of these things because this could be a
new beginning for the whole of the
industry of electronics right there new
materials there are new substrates to
put things on
why not do it in a in a an ecological
fashion and again in the US at Stanford
they're looking at Stampin this array of
electrodes onto some flakes of
semiconductor which are quite randomly
put around the the substrate but the
idea is that if you need something
extremely low cost
perhaps just sprinkling the
semiconductor on a substrate at random
and only working with the devices that
that work by by accident is probably a
good way of doing it
so this is this is general bow who's the
doing this sort of research and again my
friend children war after shanghai
jiaotong university who is a sarah
graduate i should say he's looking at a
lot of anti-counterfeiting biosensors
chemical sensors on the flexible in
printed electronics again extremely low
cost and things that eventually you
would be able to to print in your own
home
but speaking of printed transistors
this is the work of hunting searing
house when he was a post talk about 15
years ago and he developed the first
fully printed organic transistor and
just printed it with an inkjet printer i
gotta with the variety of materials
semiconductors conductors and insulators
fast for about 15 years and engineering
house is still one of the pioneers of
printed electronics
he's in cambridge and he started this
company called Plastic Logic and plastic
logic made this which is a fully
bendable display screen right
plastic display screens are you looking
at if you can even see it
it's a black and white image a bit like
a kindle display but this is the image
latched into this flat flexible plastic
display
now this is from a couple of years ago
they've let me show it to people you're
more than welcome to have a look at it
afterwards
these days they can do full color video
rate display screens in this size
so this is absolutely fantastic because
surely it means that this is the coming
of age of plastic electronics ride these
things are happening but the fact is we
can't really buy them
so is this really the future well it is
the future in some sense but if you
think about it if you were to compare
the the technology of communications to
the technology of printed electronics
we're not even at this stage in terms of
our development with more like at this
stage
so even though there are plenty of
companies and plenty of research groups
doing amazing stuff with new materials
and new techniques we hardly hear
so to get here
we need a lot more understanding of the
basic process is a lot more
understanding of the engineering but a
very good reason for doing things
because in this era of commoditization
of electronics is very easy to say okay
I'm going to build the same thing faster
or cheaper but eventually you're running
out of reasons to work to make things so
the key is enabling completely new
applications things that you couldn't do
with rigid or just conventional silicon
technology and part of this I think is a
doing or marrying old technologies with
brand new ones
i'm going to show you two demos which
have very very rough and ready of two
technologies where printed electronics
would work fairly well and would be
seamlessly integrated in everyday
products
so the first one is a photo book which
has ambient sound as you turn the pages
of the sound changes for a soundscape of
course you can do much more with it but
the the demo is about that
so that's it
the best vantage point to get some shots
of the annual pass lying
you can see here and the sound you can
hear is cockatoos two huge ones fighting
and Flying swing as such
so the book is effectively becomes the
trigger for digital events or it becomes
the remote control for interacting with
digital content the the other demo we've
made for for a little project last year
was a packaging box which tells you in
your own language instructions for
putting together a piece of fun eh SI
and the idea is that you can navigate by
gestures through the steps of of the
building process the point again is that
we've made this with off-the-shelf
components but the idea is that you
would be able to integrate absolutely
every bit of the electronic system into
the cardboard in a printing process so
it be dirty eventually
welcome to ikea drug and steps
it's recording together with the manual
supplied should make the process of
building your steps
easy you're missing God's here and
easily order them on the website that I
care
one begin by tapping the dolls and the
two-step panels and attaching them to
the side panel
to make sure
additional support is facing in the
corrector and so on paper and printed
electronics is a big deal these days
mostly to do with recycling and with
again the ecology side of things and in
fact the European Union minutes after
breaks it announced that there will be a
funding opportunity later this year for
paper-based electronics and we're trying
to capitalize on that
following on from these little demos
right so where do we go from him
my feeling is that the whole idea from
now on it will be from a sorry i should
say that in a different way
what needs to happen for new
applications for completely new ways of
using electronics for giving us a reason
to make these flexible electronics is to
marry the interaction with real-world
objects things like the Internet of
Things broadly speaking with distributed
data as in the cloud and big data and we
can easily do this
following the Digital side of things
with that immense computer and power
that we have and with the analog which
is coming from the printed sensors and
the printed electronics
so what's next well at this point
genuinely your guess is as good as mine
and for that reason I'm going to ask you
for your thoughts
perhaps by the large tree outside
thank you very much for listening
yeah