I
but for now
leave you with tim was going to
about the upcoming of apocalypse
so thanks for coming to the so now let's
get started
so imagine imagine this scene
it's the year twenty twenty-five you
open the wooden box and take the relic
out carefully hold it in your hands and
then you try to press the button and
flickers briefly but at any cost dark
again and the last iphone on earth has
died
forever so that's sort of like the mood
like I want to set for this talk and
there's three main points I want to make
effective
yeah
ok let's just do it like this there's
the three main points I want to make so
a our current civilization that we take
it for granted is much much more fragile
than it seems
the second point is if we think about
survival
we have have to think about long-term
survival not immediate survival and the
third point i want to make is well the
best time to start preparing and to
start experimenting is of course right
now
ok so first let's look at fragility
so there's a lot of things that could go
wrong right
maybe you say yeah but will it really
have that big of an impact
well I can give you a few examples what
could potentially happen it could be
something external it could for example
be something like a large asteroid
strike or large meat red strike right we
have craters
we have found craters
in the earth and the crust of the earth
and if something on this scale what
happened again then I'll ok it's obvious
that nothing can survive in the
immediate impact zone right so you're
saying okay maybe if it happens in
Australia it's not so bad over here
well it will be because basically
basically what happens is a lot of when
the impact happens a lot of um a lot of
stuff is stepped up into the atmosphere
and the whole earth will go dark and in
a very short time and when the earth
goes dark when the sunlight is blocked
all the plants will die
all the animals will die and we will
also die
so that's one possible scenario it could
also be something that is not external
but it could be something that because
ourselves right it's like nuclear war is
always an option
maybe even becoming more of an option at
the end of this year we don't know right
but it really is like 3,000 news on the
earth right now I think I'm and just not
even we don't even need 3,000 right just
a couple of them let's say like to add
10 20 would have the same effect
there's total any relation with a strike
but then in the aftermath
there's darkness and widespread chaos
well then there's other options if
you're still not convinced right that I
have other options for you
I could offer a deadly virus that breaks
out
this is also something that could
actually it could just be happening
right now we don't know right
just a virus that mutates in a way that
it has a long incubation period about is
at the same time quite badly are quite
dangerous
then it would immediately spread I mean
we have this is the nice thing like we
have everything is connected
normally it's a good thing but in this
case it's a very bad thing because it
would mean the virus would basically
reach everybody on the whole of except
maybe some disconnected tribes in the
Amazon or something right
so um why does this White why do I say
that civilization is more fragile than
it seems
well okay so that these things that
could potentially happen but then the
other thing we have to take into account
this that we are very much at the set
everything is interconnected for an hour
right
if you look at the immediate medieval a
medieval town medieval village
it is maybe not a hundred percent
self-sufficient but it is pretty
self-sufficient
whereas on the other hand we are
anything but right we need for example
to make the iphone right it
this is like it's if you really look at
all the thing that goes into an iphone
with all the raw materials that have to
be fetched from Africa
I'm smelted somewhere and transported
again turned into parts turn into
something assemblies turned into the
final assembly and it's it's it's
mind-boggling right
this is the whole earth is collaborating
to make just this one this one is one
magical object and I can hold it in my
hand
finally but this is not just for the
iphone right the same is also true for
at most kinds of foods most kinds of
machines that we use and so the problem
and that is if let's say I'm from
Germany right
I what I would i would say in the whole
of Germany 80 million people there is
there's not a hundred people that could
make an axe from scratch
probably maybe there's more but I don't
know right but we can make what we can
make is like specialized motors for cars
specialized parts for rockets everything
right but we can't do that
well we have a we want to have to do
that but be this is not like this is
this
we can only do because the parts are
coming from China the parts are coming
are being assembled and Vietnam
everything right
so everything is connected so even even
if it's not the total global catastrophe
even if it's just say a local
catastrophe local that takes out most of
Asia
we are still we still have a problem
with severe problem
ok so this is sam this is part number
one that why i think the civilization is
quite quite more fragile than it seems
second part if we are if we were serious
about survival
in such a case what we have to to do
what we have to look at and then there's
like that these people called Preppers
they they always get very excited when
the world is about to end like and year
two thousand right and then they come
out and make preparations day they go to
walmart and buy
I don't know 1,000 cans of beans right
and 22 tons of flour right and this is
all nice and good and it would actually
probably help in the first year but
after that when all the beans are eaten
right
what do you do then right so this is
short-term survival
this is and this is not so interesting
to me this is also very it's more like
you're concerned with yourself right - I
want to survive
whereas I think I am well at each other
in another talk he put it like this the
humanity
currently it's like the nervous system
of the planet and so we should not think
about how can I survive but how can we
how can we make sure that this nervous
system and in some in some form or other
can survive right so that's that's what
I mean with long-term thinking in
survival the short term of course and
first some some people have to survive
short term of course otherwise we can do
it but I'm more interested in what would
we have to do if we expect to do this
long term and I think we need three
kinds of things to make this work
long-term
the first one is seats the second one is
tools and the third one is knowledge so
seeds is pretty obvious because this is
something we cannot manufacture right
seeds
either we have them and we don't have
any done then we're fucked
but I he is saying okay so i will just
go to the next field and take some weed
and there are my seats right now I'm
done
why do we have to prepare for that well
the problem is the kind of wheat that's
growing in the fields this is not the
kind of seeds you want this hybrid seat
this will if you see it and grow at the
next year it will produce very different
plants from what you're seeing right now
in the field and it would take a several
like it will take like 10 years to grow
this into it even if you know how to do
it it would then take a longer time to
grow this into a viable seat again
so what we actually want is the kind of
like what's called heirloom seeds seeds
that are still in the original form and
not bred into a hybrid form and well
there is happily there is a large store
of these seats
it's the solid but small bird seed my
seat sucks well bird seed vault
if you have heard about it mmm it is in
small Bart
there is a man island and in its better
be in the middle between Iceland and
enter the North Pole sow the seeds are
very well protected there
that's good the good thing the bad thing
is we would have to go there and fetch
them if you want to use them right
so it's not really i mean this is of
course it is also meant as a backup as a
plan B but it meant right now it is
mainly a backup for seed banks that put
their stuff they're practically put a
backup copy there at to fetch it again
if their local collected them the
working copy is destroyed
but we could use it but even better we
should have em distributed seats seed
banks basically everywhere to maximize
the chance that wherever like whoever
people are able to survive then they
have seats readily available and that
yeah that is that is the first thing
seat
tools tools are in a way also something
like seats right because tools are what
allow us to make new things
so a an anvil and Hammer
this is quite a small thing still allows
me potentially to make hundreds and
thousands of other tools that i can use
them to bootstrap other parts of society
there so needing tools right
so I think it's more viable to
concentrate on the tools that are that
are compact tools that tools for making
other tools and then let's say we have
seeds we have tools now the most
important parts still missing is is know
how its knowledge is
I mean me with a hammer and anvil I
could start poking around and trying to
figure it out but it would be much
better if I had already done the
workshop that's happening this evening
for example right and then I had some
like a head start on on doing something
useful and the same is true for
everything else there's like the same is
true for agriculture
like if you have never had a garden and
you just read about it sounds or
everything sounds very nice and easy but
they have when you try it it's not that
easy as unforeseen complications and so
my feeling is it's better to work out
all the king's like right now then later
when we don't have the time right maybe
you just have this one harvest and it
has to work either
it works all your debt
so I in this case i would rather prefer
to have it done already a few times
before hand right
so in the third part i was good i wanted
to show a few examples of of things that
me and others have been trying
experimenting with and I call this
approach seat banking
so like I said we need seats
tools are also seeds in a way knowledge
is also a seat is that doesn't have to
be complete we can generate new
knowledge but we need to starting point
so together we need these seeds and we
have to start them in a way that they
are readily available in a distributed
fashion
so what I've been doing personally and
I've been working on
I haven't actually build it but i have
constructed a seat bank was just like a
readily as the stress of sandbox
literally just a sandbox
because it doesn't have to be
refrigerated right if you make it deep
enough let's say half a meter and put
the glasses the jars with seeds are on
the bottom then I think and maybe even
cover the whole thing with boards or
something
i will think this will hopefully this
will stay like a quite a uniform
temperature all over the year it would
be best if it was refrigerated like it
lets it would be best if Germany had
permafrost soils but it doesn't yet so
that's that's one thing i'm working on
then i'm working on growing potatoes
very and it sounds banal but it is
actually a cassette you read about it
it sounds simple you do it then oh and
uh huh
ok I didn't foresee that so I'm i will
i'm looking forward to harvest my first
crop this this fall
let's see you the only potato I've taken
out of the grounds of forest like this
yeah but the growing season isn't isn't
over yet right
what else
oh yeah there's this I was going to show
you a few screenshots status
there's a guy in Australia and he has a
youtube channel and it's called
primitive technology google it is then
watch it there because it's awesome and
so he's like he has this hobby
there's less of a is just like it I
think it's fun it's fun to go into the
woods with empty hands and start making
things so there's one video ways better
he is literally starting with empty
hands and he's making a house with a
tiled roof
ok so what does it do right it goes and
goes and grabs a stick and a suitable
stone and makes a stone axe and he
starts falling trees with a stone axe
then he's the erecting the the beams for
the house and I don't know with peace
just choosing stuff right that he finds
there and then he's making the tiles for
clay he built a little open to fire
tiles puts the tiles on the roof and
that in this video
basically it's like it's like he shows
everything but of course it's like the
videos 15 minutes it probably took him
like i would say a month of also to do
the whole thing right it's just a hobby
he has a full-time drop
he lives in a normal house it just does
this for fun and he has like tons of
other stuff and actually encourage you
to check that out
mmm
I can't remember ever to other examples
i was going to to bring up
oh yes oh yes in Germany we have a
children's to like now
once you have this mindset right once
you have this mindset and then end and
watching out for stuff that could be
useful
you see it everywhere like this and
German children's television there's a
very famous program called send on
Mickey Mouse
I'm and have like comic stuff and
they're always they have one topic each
each week but i'll show how something is
made so they go to factories
they've show how the biscuit is made or
whatever and then they had this like a
few weeks if you expect that had how our
ancestors made iron and just totally
blew my mind this is so awesome
like I learned that there is a form of
iron or did it just be that you can just
pick up from the field
it's called bak iron ore and it's
created by bacteria that my mind was
already blown at this point right I was
a heck
okay IRA or is something you find in the
in a deep in the mountain
no I just like it says she'll actually
there's like a plow going over the field
and then you can pick up some of like Oh
stolen CIA just the iron ore ok and then
they go
I'm and just on the lawn they make a
very primitive open to to smelt the iron
ore to put in the order to put in
charcoal to put in and this is so simple
right
but it is like it looks very simple in
the video maybe the practice a few times
I don't know
and this but it's also a lot of work
like this
the D open the kiln that the build was
like I think it was like two meters high
or two and a half meters from clay just
took several days and they had fire it
for I don't know a day or two and the
end they push it actually push it over
to get at the iron medicine on the
bottom and then they have to still have
to work out all the second
that as many of the impurities that I
can and in the end they have like I
don't know like maybe the size of the
iphone right that is the amount of iron
that produced in a week
so but still right still it's kind of
useful to know how to do it and I would
have to worry about would have liked I
was so envious that I was not there when
they did it right i would have left to
just be there and and watch instead of
having this video but the video is so
cool
so to sum it up
I'm i think civilization is more fragile
than we normally think
and so if we if we reflect on this fact
and think about it ended is even if i'm
not saying that something bad is
happening next year or the next ten
years and I'm not going to predict the
future right but just because there is I
think a nonzero possibility of something
like this happening
it's quite rational to reduce to do some
kind of preparation for this case and if
we think about it then the only black
I'm arguing the best thing we can do is
long-term preparation we can we can try
to make sure that seeds seeds are all
seats are basically distributed all over
the earth and in the app that's it is
just like maybe just Nicaragua's for
Nicaragua survives nothing else survives
right but even then they should have
seeds that they can use right
maybe that they would have something
anyway they would have something like
random stuff but I want it to be a
little bit more focused
yeah and well the final my final thought
is if you think yeah this is I don't buy
it right i don't buy the whole story
then still it's a nice framework it's a
nice
it's it's it's just a lot of fun playing
around with stuff right and this is what
i see when people are doing this all
over the place without this framework
so why not why not just have this in the
back of your mind while you tinker with
stuff and i set up a google group if
anyone is interested it's empty but it
has the slides so there's an incentive
you can you can go there and then you
can check out the slides and see what I
forgot to tell and it's tinyurl.com /c
banking
thank you
yeah
thank you I very impressive to do that
without slides or anything you wish to
have four minutes for questions if you
want to take questions
sure sure if you want to ask questions
please raise your hand and I will bring
the mic to you
hi you saying I'm that there were three
stages do you have to plan the seeding
the tools and the knowledge but what
about material with that come under the
knowledge of say you were saying
blacksmithing would you say the
knowledge of learning what steals you
could use in a apocalypse situation
would that be classed as knowledge or
would you put that in store like the
seed banking you stockpile a small
amount of material to steal for tools in
a future date
yes so for the knowledge I think it
ideally I envisioned something like
recipes a collection of recipes and I
mean we we should not assume that the
earth is in a state of two thousand
years ago we should assume the other the
current state so if I maybe i would not
start with black iron all right maybe I
would start with how do i melted them
post
what's the best way to to melt down the
lamp post because it will be given me a
lot of fire and quickly vs much more
slowly
right so stuff like that
practical so I have a question
I'm interested in what do you think that
the pros and cons of decentralized and
centralized prepping strategies
well as there's so much uncertainty what
can happen
I would argue it's pretty clear that
decentralized this is much superior
right because the latest father's seat -
see told it's it's it's it's awesome it
has 1.2 million different kinds of seat
but if it's taken out then it's gone
right so uh huh
this is sort of like they're at that is
always did the point against a
centralized approach
higher higher I'm just got a quite an
optimistic talk
I think the negatives talked about by
whole load of food and a crossbow
we wish to protect it and you look a lot
of that Apocalypse TV programs are
walking down the threat of them comes
from other people using there is a any
kind of value in preparing to defend
yourself against other people who are
coming for your seeds and blacksmithing
equipment so yes certainly i mean at I
think there's more more missing right
this is more like the technology side
then the whole pot like to hold
organizational side
this is also something i was thinking
about if just like what's even needed to
make a camp like this work right
you need yeah you did just it this is
not the stairs honor and it's not
spontaneous right there's this plan to
order in the camp and you would even we
don't need something like that in on an
even bigger scale of course to organize
the survivors and deal with ya
also deal with people who are playing
two other rules right yes
one last question No
hi have you thought about like keep
storing bacterial colonies for making
medicines or anything like that
like so Oh will be a yes but yeah that
kind of seating
well now that's that's that's a very
good point and no i haven't
that's a bit more tricky everything
that's living as much like i would also
like to to ensure that we have goats
around cows but how do we do that today
we can to freeze-dry a cult
we could we could
yeah I know I'm if you have good ideas
then
yeah let's talk
so we are out of time uh thank you I if
you have more questions I suppose you
might be available
oh yeah ah yes thank you