okay we're gonna make start now
so we have time with
to talk about blood sweat and tears and
electric some with solar cars so without
further ado I will hand over to him
thank you very much indeed a good
afternoon everyone thanks very much for
joining me and being here today it's a
lovely day and great to be here at two
what I to Glastonbury for geeks and
guilford fantastic festival have been
running around for most of the day and
look at some of the stands is and
workshops it's been great to be here so
I'm giving a talk actually its blood
sweat and carbon and not blood sweat and
tears
this was a phrase coined in australia by
the team and its really going to give
you this presentation is kind of give
you an overview of how we actually
designed we built and raced this so the
car is pretty incredible feat where all
students at Durham University including
myself are moving into my third year now
we've got a very exciting time ahead so
I'm going to give you a glimpse into our
past and a very exciting future ahead so
let's begin
so we are a student LED and student-run
team as I said and we're mixture of
undergrad and postgrad all doing this in
our free time so we're mixture of
anything from engineers normally to
business students marketers and it think
of any type of degree and we have one
and as a variety of degrees and its
entirety extracurricular so although
University you will think you're going
down the pub for a drink
no we are actually doing this in our
free time so we have a favorite of free
time at University and we and we like to
do this
what about the team history well we
actually are the longest running a team
to do this we are found in 2002 and we
built our first so the car in 2004
now a lot of you probably want to see me
so the car before met some of you may
have and i'll show you a picture 1 in
the second
it's a very unique design it's a
basically a table with solar panels on
as well people often say to us why is
there a table at a motor show why is
their table here today with solar panels
on
it's a very unique design and we built
our first one in 2004
so quite a while ago now we then took
this car and we raced it across America
now this is a race called Nazca North
American so the challenge
and we race this is two and a half
thousand miles so it's not like a test
track where you raise and she's got the
fastest time of star and the reason we
price over the car roll or something
what it is is a two and a half thousand
mile race all the way across America and
we actually won what's known as the best
rookie team award which we which we
liked in 2011
we took this car and enhanced a great
deal we put a lot of new refinements
into it and we raced across Australia
this time
so another big challenge this was 3,000
kilometers
so no mean feat 1,800 miles in in that
form and actually we were known as
durham university solar car now merged
with the formula soon team many of you
will perform in a student of course our
primary focus going forward is on
so the cars but we do it for me to shoot
attribute to the team as well so this is
the car itself in 2008 pretty unique
looking if there's any Americans won't
show anyone knows the jetsons that's
what we kind of like to think it looks
like very futuristic very different
indeed
and that's it driving along normal
highways everyday roads really really
cool and a big challenge for us so we're
driving at highway speeds
here's some more shots of it by asking
some testing before the race actually
began and we also have again and a shot
of us on the road so this car could do
about 50 miles an hour or so pretty fast
I had three wheels as you can see their
steel stop frame chassis with a carbon
fiber top
now here's the actual pic garage at the
event you can actually see us we are
next to that big white trailer we
haven't got a big white trailer at the
time but we had humble beginnings and
that was us there with a low loader in a
van so we still did very well
the best rookie team so they're a great
award for us to win
and still to 9,000 miles a big distance
now we took this car and we enhanced it
we made it longer
we made it lighter this is us with a 6
square meter array driving across
australia with infamous canopy bouncing
along
that's the ventilation i should point
out i obviously it clearly it is and
this is us on the just coming on the
shoot highway which is the main road
that runs from darwin in the north
all the way down to Adelaide so that's
1,800 miles it's a big distance and
that's actually finishing in a blade
so that's the car again similar design
to the one previously with a few
upgrades
now most you think what's happened here
is this car falling over know what we've
actually done is tilted on its side so
we raised from nine to five to eight to
five during the during the day and in
the morning and in the end the evening
we have an hour to charge up the
batteries and that's what we do he
pointed at the Sun and we managed to
collect the last bit of charge for our
batteries to drive the next day and
again there's another others they're
just going across the tropics and that's
in the pit lane and about 40 teams do
this so it's not like it's a small event
there's millions of dollars invested in
this and I'll go into that later on
now what's the point in all of this you
may be thinking what's the point in
designing building racing a car that
works in the sunshine but you think why
the developing in durham
I mean Durham's freezing cold and wet
that's a bit ironic isn't it
well we've got a very exciting future
ahead and we have three key arms to this
was showcasing the latest technology
it's all about proving to the public is
proving to ourselves that this
technology can work in any conditions
it's educating the public it's saying to
the public look what solar power can do
we can drive infinitely as long as the
sun shining
we are driving and it's also inspiring
the next generation because we do a lot
of outreach to schools will take this
schools across the UK when we go to
major events and say become engineers
think differently as to how to build
things and think differently about our
planet
now i'm going to walk you through our
brand new car
our new car well it's unlike anything
we've ever done before and had to move
to a four wheel design and we thought we
could just add a fourth wheel to the
existing one
that's fine actually now see me I've got
some lights brilliant home
we could have done that but we thought
we'll start from scratch so for three
years of design and development
we built this car this car has a four
wheel design six square meter array and
is unlike anything we've ever done
before
now this car itself we thought well
we're going to make it better obviously
because we're doing well we qualified in
the top 10 in 2011 had some technical
issues but we did well we can do better
though we can do better with a plucky
British spirit
so we can do forty percent faster top
speed than our existing car at 70 miles
an hour
70 miles an hour in a car that is 5
meters long and 2 meters wide and weighs
a third of the way to the previous car
as 200 kilograms
it's an unbelievable feat of engineering
and a true triumph for our team
so actually build on how to actually do
it
what does it take to walk you through
four key areas first one is aerodynamics
we've got to make a car that streamlined
to make sure it cuts through the air
that most in the most efficient manner
we're going to make a car that's very
sound structurally it's very light and
strong and that's why carbon fiber comes
in the electronics are key part we can
build a car that's very aerodynamic we
can build a car that has a very good
structure but we've got something that
goes as fast as a milk flow
we've gone backwards so we need the best
power output with the most efficiency
and that's where the electronics comes
in and finally we need the business side
of things
we are entirely student-run and led we
are financed through sponsors and
private donors and we have actually
pretty the one the lower budgets have
any of the teams out there as an example
our budget for this coming year is about
a hundred thousand Michigan have four
million dollars a team in the
netherlands i believe it is has 28
million dollars so we are the plucky
Brit doing this in a shared in our free
time but we do very well
so let's walk through this the first
things aerodynamics this is a CFD model
of our car as I said it spent three
years in the design and development
stage and it's a truly groundbreaking
design an asymmetric design
now when you add a fourth wheel that's
fine when we put the driver what we
could put them in the middle
makes sense but actually had aerodynamic
drag you add weight because we're going
to make the center of the car stronger
we have no God no longer go to throw
third wheel in line so we moved into the
left hand side in between the wheels
why is the left hand side on the
right-hand side when Australia drives on
that side
what is actually to cast the least
shadow on the solar panels
we're driving for hours in the morning
five hours in the afternoon
evening time and with that content with
those conditions we cast the shadow by
putting the canopy on the left hand side
as i said we sit between the front and
rear rules
we r rear wheels and we've also got some
innovative suspension double wishbone at
the front and a trading arm rear
suspension at the rear to make sure it's
incredibly light we're actually moving
to carbon fiber suspension as part of
the upgrades this year
so really exciting time for us the area
of the car that actually hits the the
air itself is less than the square meter
less than a square meter that is
unbelievable for a car of this size to
make it strong and light is very
difficult and now i'm coming onto the
kind of the structure of the car now
we've got a big team at Durham who are
now pretty much experts in the area as
to how to build a car from scratch out
of carbon fiber
this has never been done before by us to
build the entire car we've done bits and
pieces
you know I've meter squared let's say
we've never built a car that's 5 by 2
meters
how to actually do this well i should
also point out that we use five times
this power than the price when we're
cruising how to actually manage this
well let's go through and look at it the
first will create molds this is a cnc
router
cutting the mold out of model board in
order for us to make the complex shapes
needed to construct the car so we form
layers of these we build them up and
this is part of the process at southwest
durham just me around down the road from
us they gave us this machine said you
can have a machine
one problem is broken so you need to fix
it and then build the car so we actually
fix the Machine and build the car from
scratch one of the only teams to do this
most teams just say oh Ford you're now
down the road from us Michigan filled
the car for us thanks very much
so we built the car entirely from
scratch and this is what we ended up
with for the molds so we then created an
oven in order to heat the carbon fiber
up and get the epoxy to set when we put
the carbon fiber in but when you
obviously build carbon fiber you've got
to make sure it seals and and is
correctly formed and to do that you got
to create a vacuum and create a vacuum
need a bag this size
what about the length of this room big
lecture theatre we got there at the room
oh sorry it's a pretty big letters we
got a Durham and that cover all of it
so if there's one tear in the bag we've
had it we've got to make sure that the
seal is optimal across the entire range
and that's a key part of our layup and
building of the structure
it's a really interesting part of us
again we've never done this before and
yet we created a car that is very
lightweight and very strong
moreover when we move look at the
structural side we also think about
safety for the driver
the rules are excuse me the rules are
very specific and they say you gotta
survive a certain impact
so actually reinforce the side of the
car and the front of the car with kevlar
that means that we've got great shatter
resistant so when in god forbid if we
did have an accident the graph carbon
fiber doesn't shatter incredible
innovation there that we came about with
so that's the structural side that's the
mechanical side
what about the electric side about the
power tronix of the car again we need
this to go fast but on very little power
so
we've got a really innovative new motor
that we've designed and built from the
ground up
we're moving onto I think our fifth
generation motor the next time that we
go to Australia and it's an in wheel
motor
it's inside the hub of the most of the
wheel there's no separate gearbox
drivetrain chains anything inside the
motor itself and that means we got
incredible efficiency and we've got
incredible top speed as well as i said
we will have now got a second generation
of this particular form of in her motor
overall it's all our fifth one that
we're building and we designed this
ourselves and built it ourselves with
the only team in the world to go well
let's build our own motor rather than
going and getting one by one so we got
you built and designed from the ground
up and that's an able to stop demise it
to around ninety-four percent efficiency
we're actually looking at increasing
that was ninety-eight percent going
forward
so that's an incredible efficiency for
us and the total output is around about
five kilowatts we're looking at now
that's about what you run on a sort of
cattle or or similar
so we're not using that much power but
we're still doing 70 miles an hour
so by no means is going to set any World
Records for naught to 60 time but it's
only going to set world records in you
know the longest distance shall we say
you can travel
now what about the actual electronics
themselves well we have all did we
designed ourselves a patch management
system
we got maximum power point trackers MP
pts to ensure the solar panels are
operating at their best
we got the solar cells and Driver
management tools so we're going
completely designed from the ground up
ourselves and we've recently partnered
with Seth Conn just have the right in
Newcastle to assist us with with this as
well
we've also got really clever telemetry
so when we're driving across Australia
we have been or America or wherever it
is we have a lead and chase car and we
were able to feel it feat real-time data
to those cars via of high-powered Wi-Fi
to say well how the motors performing
how the batteries performing so we got
incredibly advanced data and that also
means we can actually control the car we
can set the speed of the cruise when we
are we going along so it's really
incredible feat there
and excuse me we also use standard can
bus in our abs and other electronic
components in the system now what about
these solar panels
there they are there's the the cliq they
are in question there's three engine
ninety one of them
so we're not see the count them up until
this winter 91 there about twenty four
percent efficient and their
silicon-based so these are the part of
the most advanced silicon solar cells
you can get in the world today that are
available there are the types gallium
arsenide for instance to go up to forty
percent efficiency
we've stopped with twenty percent the
actual weight of the whole solar array
you see there is five kilograms and it's
only a millimeter things there's no
glass or any extra weight holding us
back
it's just those raw panels and then
captivated by a company called
government in Germany using a process
that's unbelievable that increases the
efficiency for us we've also got a
lithium-ion battery pack on board we
recently have the way to that but
keeping the same energy density so now
actually what we did have 40 kilograms
we're now moving to 20 kilograms makes
this lighter makes us able to go faster
for longer
what about you know built a car would
actually do with it but we race it as I
said this is a cgi us bus by Ayers Rock
will have to go there this year
pretty cool and that's Australia driving
all the way down the stuart highway
highway from Darwin down to Adelaide
as I said it's 3,000 kilometers were
actually specifically 3022 and trust me
the 22 is the the hardest bit for us
darling to Adelaide as I said and it's
run every two years in the autumn in
Australia
next one's October next year 2017 we
race from eight till five
that's pretty long time to race
incredible heat to give an example we
saw temperatures of 50 degrees
centigrade inside the car and on the
panels
so our driver was the smallest person on
the team
her 13 of them are there to clinch
inside and not touch the carbon fiber
while sitting still that's how hot it
was it was be would burn you if you
touched it
we've got 45 other teams competing as I
said many of whom
most of them have six figure or more
budgets we've got one of the lower ones
but we do really well with it because
we've managed to design and build
everything ourselves and sees me
we've also got various different classes
of entry as an example we run in the
Challenger class
that's designed to go as fast as
possible for as long as possible but
there's also the cruiser class which is
a bit less table like a bit more
car-like shall we say I looked a bit
more you know the market car and that's
the actual distance were driving so
we're driving the equivalent of a kind
of Norway to Greece to give you an idea
to put it more Eurocentric so pretty
long way
now here's some of us are a picture of
us on the road with a land rover
discovery they're jagged and over one of
our sponsors
as I said we run entirely on solar power
we drive from eight to five
we can't where we stop now in 2011 we
kind of learned a lesson because we had
to stop and camp we decided to come next
for cattle grid which went well
imagine the noise throughout the night
as road trains thunder over it so the
person shows that campsite was not
popular
I think he was sacked the next day and
we entirely self-sufficient so we have
to collect how we have our water tanks
we have to have the ionized water for
the solar cells we have to have our in
food or in fuel everything we have to do
ourselves it's a it's a it's a challenge
for the car and it was a big challenge
for the team
let's have a look at some of the photos
from us there are of us there this is up
the pitch you can actually see some of
the cruiser class car as there are kind
of two in the center they look a bit
more car-like so we've got the the
challenge of class as well there
there's another shot of the cars going
down the pit lane as I said 45 other
teams do this so we're in the pits in
Darwin to qualify so there's a
qualifying round that we that we enter
and all the teams enter the various
dynamic scrutineering state stages and
Static scrutineering stages and that's
in the pit lane getting ready to to
qualify as a team and another shot there
and I show the rest of hidden valley
raceway in Darwin as a great test track
in a great availability for us to build
things and design things at the last
minute we should anything go wrong
that's our motor being slotted into the
car you can see the trading armor and
suspension on it and the role who just
behind that sits directly behind the
driver it on the left hand side
scrutineering comes along so the drivers
are wait there's a very interesting
technique which is basically we want
them to weigh as little you know we want
them to weighs close to the 80 kilograms
ballast there we have so we have to make
sure the driver is 80 kilograms
if they're less than that their balance
it up to it so we can see le there on
the right
she was basically force fed water to
increase their weight so we have various
tactics that we employ and other teams
employed to make sure that we get every
actually kilogram or less kilograms of
ballast to put in the car to a way to
the scrutineer as well
this is us in static scrutineering
inside a big hangar that they've got to
the other test track and all the other
teams to scrutinize on things like
you're braking distance when you're
doing dynamic scrutineering the design
of the car how many solar cells you've
got the safety systems in a fire
extinguisher city anything
god forbid happen everything is checked
and prove there is a very safe event
this is actually managed to qualify we
did encounter a technical issue with the
motor is 50 degrees out there so things
do and it's like humans are things to
short-circuit a bit easily shall we say
but undeterred we qualified a lot of
teams actually didn't qualify we are one
of the few to do so and this is ask
actually on the road
this is driving from Darwin to adelaide
land rover discovery is flanking us we
had two very kindly provided to us by
Jaguar Land Rover as i said this again
driving across that way in proper desert
conditions you can just about see how
sparse and barren it is a real challenge
for us
now this is an arc AR don't worry when I
first saw this picture when guys you
didn't tell me about this
when did that happen now this is one of
the Malaysian teams they as you guys are
saying about the battery chemistry
lithium ion and particularly sometimes
the lithium-ion batteries aren't
incredibly susceptible to thermal
runaway if they're damaged
this is what happened to the Malaysian
team we got a call over the radio saying
guys we got a major problem so we sped
up and you have to basically once a
lithium-ion battery start a fire starts
it's not going to stop very quickly so
we have to shovel sand onto it we had
fire extinguishers that we have to
deploy it was a pretty exciting moment
they might actually finish the race as
well they managed to rebuild their
batteries rebuild their systems all the
teams pull together to make sure they
could finish a real show camera Audrey
there but incredibly incredibly dramatic
site for us to see the driver
proving that you could get out in 15
seconds that was that was the limit so
it's a big challenge for us we mustn't
underestimate the challenge there and
the danger
this is us on the road fortunately not
on fire that we've stopped on the side
of the road just to get everything
sorted so we have various checkpoints we
have to meet
so as an example we have to be at a
certain place at a certain time to make
sure that we are performing correctly
and they check that are we haven't been
tweaking anything on underwear on ways
to the observers we have and this is
actually one of things we have to do
whilst there
so when we are on the road we have camp
for the evening we have to watch the
solar panels down they get a lot of dust
on them that degrades the efficiency so
i have to watch them off but not using
any water using deionized water to
ensure that make sure they're clean and
have the optimal optical quality that we
need to perform at twenty-four percent
efficiency
again these are so fragile if you touch
them it damages them so we have to be
very careful
we have to keep saying hands off array
so we have to make sure we didn't touch
it
very very fragile indeed this is camping
nice evening shot we had as we were
settling down for the night so not to
not to do similar to here as opposed
camping in the middle of nowhere
although a few more spiders and snakes
and other things as well to get your
sleeping back but an incredible up an
adventure for us and is a nice nice shot
of the car on one of the final evening
before we reached adelaide and this is
also the finish
we managed to finish the spiral
technical issues minutes to complete the
whole 3,000 kilometers from start to
finish
we did manage to do actually drive all
of it unfortunately we still finished
with big feet next year we're going back
and gonna be the first ever UK team we
hope to go from Darwin's adelaide
entirely without stopping without any
malfunctions so
we set a big goal because no team has
ever done that from the UK before
again this is a strike the finish line
is a big event well as I said every two
years he's been going since about the
nineteen eighties when a couple of drunk
Australian said let's go and have a bit
of fun with solar panels and see how
fast we can go because it's hot and
sunny
so it's been going for a number of years
this event but it's really great to be
the premier so the race
what about other things we do we do
other events we want to showcase our
technology to you guys now the car's not
here is these back in durham being fixed
and being worked on enhanced but we take
this two major events we get huge
publicity people go
what on earth is this thing why is there
a table with solar panels on it or why
is there
what was the other one they had a boat
people think it's a boat this is us
meeting Prince Michael of Kent and as a
nigel mansell at the london motor show
it was a big shock to me because i was
chatting to the stand next to me I
wasn't told that they were coming around
and managed to miss him on the first
attempt but then he came over and had a
very nice chat with us about the car
so very nice job and then if you
recognize this guy
your body more used to seeing him with a
white suit and helmet on
that was the stick Ben Collins he came
along and was very keen to see our car
and find out more about it again I
didn't recognize him into the actually
introduced himself as he was so was
pretty exciting to see him
that's myself talking to tiff needell
that's probably when I told him about
the malay that reaction he's got what I
want to talk about the Malaysian team
and the fire they had a guy like that
shot of him and I doing a Q&A they're
not too dissimilar to this kind of
environment actually that's coming back
next year as well so keep an eye out for
it will be back next year hopefully as
well
we were then really excited because we
were invited off the back of that to
come to probably the biggest motor event
in the world
goodwood festival of speed they're
leaving idea that had 68 million people
hear about it around the world that just
one event
hundreds of thousands came and source
that's the good that's the sculpture
there by BMW
we had a stand there that we managed to
get this is the car they're tracking a
great deal of interest is it really
really cool but the kids as we build a
new canopy for it as well and that's our
as i stand there representing durham
university and all our sponsors we see
huge reach and we see huge interest from
all ages and by all ages particular
reference as last week before last the
last week was last week
we're at the science museum we actually
exhibited for three days there's part of
the antenna live event and we were
featured on a number of programs in the
London area so we get really big
interest and kids going how on earth
does this thing work
its massive it's an incredible feat of
engineering and I know for example our
team principal saw during so the car
that jets and looking one in 2004 2008
time and his team principal and now it's
gone on to it so you've been hugely
inspired and just quickly recognize
these are the list of sponsors that we
have
so a variety of small and large
companies climb online as an example
recently signed a party might have heard
of a guy called Lord Sugar his
apprentice mark right the Australian
champion found a digital-marketing
agency
he's building a new website for us
that's incredible new sponsorship deal
signed with the jaguar land rover in a
series of others so and we continue to
look to expand this some of them like
connecting with our engineers and
offering them jobs others like inspiring
the next generation and others like
saying here's some technology going to
show how good it is
so as I said this car the 70 miles an
hour
it weighs 200 kilograms and uses five
times this power than a toy surprise but
what's next
that's the past what about the future
well I went into too much detail because
there's a lot of things which were
working on the economy mention but we've
got a very exciting future head
we've got all the events coming up
leading up to Australia 2017 going back
to Australia racing all the way across
the outback
we look forward to welcoming
a lot of people to see us at future
events and we're very excited for what's
to come
very very excited indeed and i hope you
can see that our new values that we've
come up with of showcase educate and
inspire are truly showing by myself and
others members of the team and indeed
the car that we've designed and built
from scratch
this was a toilet a labor of love that
we were up to a four-year most mornings
getting it ready
most of the guys didn't sleep while they
were in Australia the team principal
told me at the best flight back
so why is that he said well I slept for
the whole 13 hours
so pretty much from Malaysia to London
so I remember going to bed
the falling asleep just as the plane
took off and then next thing I know I
was in London so he had very little
sleep over the entire race is some
really grueling challenge but we are
very excited to be going back there next
year i think i've just finished on time
which is good
I went any Q&A on the stage i'll just be
down at the front if you want to come
and ask me any questions about the
technology we've done the events we have
attended what's coming up any questions
whatsoever i'm more than happy to answer
them and if I cannot to them then i'll
give you his contact details and you can
get in touch with them
so thank you very much indeed for
listening it's an honor to be a
privilege to be here
hope you enjoy the rest of the event and
thank you very much again