never close you guys probably saw it on
the on the team nationwide people that
never if it ever shut down it was it was
basically in a specific places but I
would say by state Sears I went out the
traffic was insane people eating going
into I went to a store actually was
bizarre there there were like glasses
everywhere like you can when you when
you want to buy something you there is
like a glass and then you kind of put
through the bra note they check you out
and then you have to they won't let you
in if you don't have a mask and then
you're like bombarded with all this
messages that you had to be six feet
away from it was like being a movie it
was weird and you saw if you meant to
know what we have that is actually in a
coffee shop and is open for business
though the reopening is happening not
sure how this but at least from what I
am right now see I mean how many people
saw out and how the the shelter in place
we should be like New York and we're not
I don't know if it's the heat or the
water but definitely definitely or we're
too lucky but is it
it seems like as soon as they say well I
said okay fine we're going on now so as
far as California goes we're gonna pan
any the medians online we have plenty of
new content coming and we're gonna have
the Cole CDF the polygon then have today
we're gonna had almost on top 10 API and
there's other wonderful
we're gonna continuously drone security
so touch with us join our our slack
channel if you email me at impact on or
I will like channel which is basically
where all of us are communicating if you
were affected by the the layoffs I've
been hearing there's been some layoffs
not sure how California is doing but in
Florida we have heard of some layoffs
already there are plenty of remote jobs
mostly if you're in security there's
this quite a bit of people looking for
for info sake and security engineers so
if you go to the hashtag job offers
channel in slack there's plenty plenty
and if you need a referral just ask us
most of us you know may not most of us i
noticed that sometimes people don't
publish your buffers because nobody's
responding cuz you know on before
covered pretty much everybody was
employing happy or it was easier so i'm
i'm assuming that so some of them will
be able to give you some some guidance
so there's the info if you send me an
email I will join you into the slack
channel we will advise when when we're
going back against the reopening had
just happened I'm not sure where
California it's gonna fall fruit but we
would definitely will be on top of this
and when it's safe to go out and go back
absolutely I will contact the library
and we will get the ball rolling a kind
reminder to please mute yourself and and
don't put her somehow because then we'll
hear the music that had to mute other
than that I'm gonna let the presenter
decide she wants to take questions
initially or at the end today we have a
wasp top-10 API
with that come here hi everybody how are
you doing
I hope you had okay yeah yes the if you
going Civic hackers you search you find
out a youtube channel every single
meeting that we're presenting is being
recorded like this one
was being recorded they will be uploaded
some time after he ends go ahead kuvira
can you confirm somebody can like unable
to see my screen now okay awesome okay
so today we are going to cover most top
10 API and a little bit background about
me
once again I'm trying to do this okay
so my background I'm a software engineer
I was a developer for a couple of years
before I stumbled upon the application
security area and then I kind of
discovered myself like I like to make
things smooth and the building so ever
since like 8 plus years have been in the
application security anything in Apps a
click from tech modeling SS DLC process
the tooling security testing tools like
SAS tests SCA the vulnerability
management analyzing and ship left
managing security champions program my
area is I like to work on the
application security so that's a little
background about me and having some
issues yeah so before I dive deep into
over Stockton API I just wanted to give
you an introduction
what is why do we need API security it
is is it different from the web
application security to understand this
a simple diagram like how the API
Gorem wall looking back in the days
traditional web application do you see
like a web app or calling an application
server or web server so the whole like
functionality is embedded like for each
HTTP call like the HTML you could be
returned to the client
so there is a tight coupling between the
client and the server and the state of
his main with the session ID or similar
cookies so it is just a plain
straightforward communication which no
extra layers on it and then it won't do
a single page application like I could
say early adoption I API in the Box it
is it is just for like abstract here the
web application you know like a static
content and a JavaScript with first like
a single a functionality API like the
whole data is returned for example like
one functionality want to add a user
like a Ritter a med user you call the
web server that functionality back of
the thing and return the whole response
back to the client so this is also a
little bit of client and the API up
tightly coupled so moving on to like you
see the single page application and
there are multiple API endpoints so this
is what I would say like like the
application authenticates a user with
some type of a cookie or a token for
making sense of the API calls like here
like that you are multiple in one
particular web page you might call
multiple API is for every functionality
for example if I wanted to see a user
like whatever the product that I bought
and ie reviews for the product it could
be like maybe multiple API calls on the
back but all these are like the results
are filtered through the client so
eventually it lead to many consumers and
many providers if you see this diagram
there are many types of application
single page applications as applications
mobile apps evolve and partner it via is
so then the API gateway came into the
picture so API gateway like that's kind
of an entry point that managers like be
back in all the API like one-way access
like it can call multiple API switch is
in house
also public facing API is and
third-party api's so as things get
complex you see this web application
attacks subsidies is not applicable for
the same API attack surface so they are
little with different although there are
can be some attacks are common but then
API security needs a special attention
especially when there is a mobile
applications and the user interactions
are more common these days so with
respect to web security the most of the
data processing you know they done on
the server side and the webpage is sent
to the client browser so baton for this
type of the application was played a
major role in blocking the malicious
traffic analyzing the malicious request
and blocking the IP is acceptable but
when acosta I think somebody is not on
mute you please don't meet you okay so
going back to API security so evolution
of mobile apps micro services and the
more and more richer user experiences
there is like more attack surface on ApS
that we are going to see in the session
today so bots and malicious actors
routing from attacking the web sites now
there are more targets on attacking the
public API is because API is are the
data like they can store more data and
they can handle such state between the
sessions so and there's new technology
like say how do you set your API keys
there is always manipulation around s
areas so exposes action access key
tokens etc so all these are leave a wide
range of attacks so I hope that you got
an idea about like the web and APA
security is different because one when
you develop a web application it's just
not enough these days to focus only
those web issues you have to pay special
attention on the API during the design
phase itself so now I'm going back
coming back to the top 10 API what is
top 10 API from wasp I'm sure everybody
is aware of us like it's a nonprofit
organization they have like a top 10
mobile top 10 where but it attacks
documented risk document them so this
was captain API or API is this document
or a piece written to 2019 it's pretty
recent so they kind of mapped all into
this 10 buckets we can go each and every
one in detail but at a high level you
can see these are the 10 so yeah first
the broken object level authorization so
what is it when you think of calling an
API in the screen you see a simple get
request get user detail ins for the user
ID 241 so from the like when you develop
this API like if you manipulate an ID in
the request because the server does not
fully track the client state instead
like whatever the functionality will
write on retrieving the user details it
relays on the parameter right like the
user 244 unlike so that parameter you go
hit the database get the details for
that particular user so now from the
attacker mind said what I would want you
to think is like what if if I can pass
to 42 will I be able to get the data so
what kind of mechanisms and controls we
need to have in place and what is the
issue here like you can clearly say if I
if my API
if I pass another 240 to another user
will I be able to get those response for
that user successfully let's dig into
another example it's similar to the
previous one I'm just doing a post here
product reviews so the application the
user blog daily and the user 140 is
supposed to update his review he had a
very bad experience he wanted to review
the product one point but is there a way
that the attacker can directly keep the
API manipulate it and then change his
reviews or some other users reviews like
again 141 make instead of the user
updating his mood really you can hear
paid into another user
so what is missing in here it's pretty
much the access control checks under
Singh and also if you see we are not
validating whether if the logged in user
has the same performed to same requested
action of the requested object to give
you a more detail on this if you see we
are not checking if you are not checking
in the API whether this logged in user
is the same user that is going to
perform the action on the particular
object so if that check is missing
authorization check is missing it's
going to return whatever the data for
the other user before I go into the
prevention I would like to give you a
real-world attack that happened on this
particular issue the broken object level
authorization it's this is the open a
chrome take over happened in 2019 so
step one I would like to go over that
act and to see if you can understand how
exactly happen at a high level if you
see this request this is the API request
one of the API any phone number that you
give and the response gave you an
additional correlation for that
particular just by giving the phone
number it gave it mapped a UUID
user so with this API the UUID gots the
eight that is a first step
using the UUID there was another API
marketplace RPC whatever that if you see
on the left left side the user ID
whatever you returned with the earlier
step request and send the API malicious
request whatever you're not supposed to
it then you got their successful API
response back with the PII data for that
particular user so pretty much what
happened here you're able to get all the
PAA data for any other user with just
passing the so how do you prevent it so
one thing to prevent it it's pretty easy
you see like use gyd instead of UID you
know it's not you gy d is not guessable
whether we're a see why he is always
guessable also you have to include the
proper authorization mechanism that
relates on the user policies and
hierarchy but you have to check in your
api whether the user that is logged in
is the same user that is retrieving
their user data here it is not the case
in the first example we saw so
authorization check has to be in every
function just not one but whatever the
function that you do you have to make
sure just not the authentication is
satisfied you whether the user has
authorized to do some action on the
object so one other thing you can do
developers can write test cases early in
the development
so the second
the top two is who can user
authentication the first one is like
object level so the second one talks
about authentication so when you talk
about the authentication API endpoints
for authentication are treated
differently from the regular endpoints
like there are multiple API influence
obviously login and user so many API
endpoints but what I'm mentioning here
is there are few API endpoints that
require special attention just not
locked
maybe there are other API is like not
forgot password and reset password it's
special attention to and should be
protected same as login we are going to
just see a use case why it is important
because it allows the credentials like
with the credential stuffing mechanical
say you want to reset a password so the
API request and response accepts request
username password so what if if an
attacker can perform a credential
stuffing on that particular API by
sending in multiple passwords username
and password combinations in the API
request so how does your API is going to
be good for that particular use case you
have to think about it so even when you
are implementing the JWT totals they are
all possible that in the developer when
they are implementing it they think it's
safe but then there is a way one of them
is like if you say the algorithm is null
that means it's pretty much like it's um
you're not like signing up properly so
these are some of the flops and I have
seen auth tokens and FAQs what is being
passed in the URL and also weak
encryption keys
the keys are not good enough the length
whatever it is we caches and in this
case no account lockout so what if like
I keep trying multiple times to I
I mean do i implement the proper account
like maybe depending on your application
whether ten times eight times six times
whatever it is so these are the good
points to think about when you consider
the Authenticator part I would like to
go over this example see I am doing a
post API call like a very figure on the
reset password lick this is the API that
would send me a verification code to my
mobile SMS code is like six digit if
there is no rate limiting the API
this is suspected to brute-forcing
because you can set you can attempt
again with the help of script try x
times with the various six digit code
eventually that will lead to the reset
password again we talked about the rate
limiting without rate limiting it this
this would break so what is the
prevention for this issue implement
multi-factor whenever it is possible
that is just not enough but that's a
good starting point just do a
multi-factor and also definitely for an
anti root root first mechanism
you got a rate limit your API you go to
know your API so just it I mean rate
limiting is used to control the amount
of incoming and outgoing traffic from
and to relate to work say if you say
you're letting your API allowing like
eight requests per minute then anything
more than that it would it would be an
error so you can have some kind of
protection over here and we talked about
the account lockout and there is another
capture to consider and also don't mean
when the wheel use the standards for
authentication token generation of
password storage so now moving on to the
third top ten on in top ten who was VPN
save data exposure so what is excessive
data exposure so this happens when you
sniff just knit the APA traffic looking
for the sensitive data
what is impaired just by sniffing if
your API returns some responses more
than it is supposed to return consider
in there I have seen this a lot like
when you develop or design an API so we
just like okay this functionality this
is the request and this is the API
response but there are a lot of cases we
send wood because just because we create
from database we don't if you don't
consider what the client is expecting
and sell the whole bunch of rest
response back to the client and expect
the client to filter it for the display
then it is a problem because C cannot
trust the client to display somebody can
hit your API and can read your data data
so by looking at the example it's very
simple example I just wanted to read my
user reviews get API user reviews so
here the response if you see the
response you are supposed to give just
this is the user and this is the list of
reviews that here total like say 5
videos but just because the way it is
developed I would talk about why it is
coming so the whole user object is
present as a part of the response and
this is not very earlier this is pretty
common people used to do that because
the ORM framework like bar when you bind
it it just until you filter it filter it
out it just sends the whole object back
to the client and and if you just do it
like the object dot to JSON it displays
the entire data which including the PII
data available on the user object so so
that's why
what you have to do is be conservative
in exposing the data so always use the
principle of least privilege expose only
the Recker I'd call for the APA call in
the previous case the ideal would be
just to display the user ID the request
like we need the reviews just the
response should be like user ID and the
review will say five reviews that that -
should be the response rather than not
giving the whole user object back to the
client and the client filtering the
reviews and so that's not the ideal way
to do this also prevents accidental
exposure and also some disclosure of
personal information and sometimes you
can even like figure out by correlating
the data from different data sets so
it's always like that good to follow
their principle of least privilege
another real-world example the Twitter
app work was used to match 17 million
phone numbers to user accounts so this
is like December 2019 and design flowing
Twitter and draw API a high level the
API the Twitter API one of the API you
could upload and stops bunch of phone
numbers
somebody is such a found this money it
could accept a public number of phone
numbers and account match the API so
there are some validations there were
some validations in place basically if
you gave like consecutive numbers if you
threw errors but there was one
validation bypass and he was able to
upload a bunch of four numbers millions
of phone numbers and it matched to the
user account user information so upload
the entire list of generated phone
numbers through Twitter contacts upload
feature and fetches they use the data in
return so I really shouldn't have
returned the response the whole bunch of
user data it
just an upload functionality I don't
know much in detail but then looking at
this is it's like excessive data
exposure problem so how do you prevent
it pretty simple never rely on the
client to filter the data always you
just return whatever it's needed for
that particular use case and the best
thing is like no truly good figure this
out but best methodology or what you
want to do is just review your API is
what you are selling and what you are
getting back some peer review that would
help and the developer should ask this
question who is consumer of the data
who is the consuming this data like
instead of just okay I'm going to turn
it this one asks these questions who is
consumer and what is it what data is
required ask these like questions and
avoid using those two J to string and to
JSON eventually end up in the log files
which would be an internal thread so and
as we talked about return only specific
properties and always use the data
classification if possible depending on
the use case and moving on to number
four its lack of resources and late rate
limiting so so this issue happens when
your multiple concurrent requests
it doesn't require any authorization or
anything it is just like DDoS attack
right like like exploding your resources
so sending multiple concurrent requests
by using a like a cloud resource or a
real computer and see and observe how
the API is wants us respond back this is
a clearly a denial of service attack so
because multiple clients compete for the
resources
at a given time now look at this example
the requesters I just wanted to see the
list of users in a page and the this is
the request and I am limiting it to the
size 100 so this is my functionality for
example when you want to develop
something like this there will a per
should ask question so what if the
attacker changes from the size like
hundred to a big number
how does my API respond back it would be
unresponsive
maybe buffer overflow errors can happen
the nail of service can happen but how
do you protect it so this is where the
rate-limiting comes into picture it is a
best way often to limit how often the
client can call the API within the
defined time frame that I told you like
your H API is very different and you can
set a PA rate limiting Maya this is the
API we used frequently the other ApS are
not that frequently so you can define
the API is like I need to serve my API
is like yeah like hundred requests per
minute or whatever and the other one
server-side validation on control
parameters in the earlier example we saw
the size hundred make sure you check
because it is a user parameter it can be
manipulated so check for the parameter
and also check for the maximum what do
you allow if anything more than that
message now moving on to dopamine
function level authorization so this is
a little different this is a functional
level authorization issue that good
example would be so there are lot of API
endpoints and there are few endpoints
that you will have you never intended to
expose to the public
so the attackers selling the legitimate
APA calls to the API endpoint they
should not this happens a lot too
because the way in which CI CDE now it's
pretty quick the way in which the
functionalities are turned out there are
a lot of old API endpoints are there are
there are api is without documentation
so on there are few higher level
permissions API which are not exposed or
exposed there's so many ways it could
happen just because it is the way the
API is are structured if you look at
REST API is I can tell you like you know
API users 100 it is a gate API right but
you are not supposed to do a delete on
that particular the delete request but
then if you don't disable the HTTP
delete then you are allowed to do a
delete so these kind of little
information or configurations might be
missing that the attackers can take use
effec in this simple example that I'm do
I am supposed to do
only the get but since delete is not
disabled I am NOT occur or anybody can
able to perform a delete operation on
that particular user so this is read
standard it's easy to guess
so that opener attack range and also
yeah simple example would be the URL
string if there is anything that changes
from user 100 what if I change to admit
what it is what does it return so all
these questions like when you develop an
API you should ask yourself so can
regular user access the admin endpoint
and the user can perform sensitive
actions where suppose not to say from
get to delete so this open up this
function level authorization I can
explain with another example
in the ride-sharing app there are
different API is available driver API
right away Pia admin API but you are not
supposed to expose your admin API but
somehow that I got hold of the admin
appeal can he the use user can perform a
delete user and attacker can perform it
any user - it's the function level
authorization checks are missing how do
we prevent it so deny all access by
default requiring explicit grants to
specific roles for every function again
it is something to do with the
authorization like policies and roles
because it's getting complicated in this
example you see the same functionality
but different roles like driver and
rider and ID so getting a little
complicated so you need to have like the
access permissions and rules defined
properly in your code and also implement
that the solution would be like
implement the solution in the who would
check your configurations an API gateway
disable the unused HTTP methods I see
that a lot lot of sensitive methods are
not disabled and then the fact of
getting use of those and have
authorization checks in place now moving
on to boss assignment math assignment is
a problem where you bind the client data
to the data models the ORM II with the
use of ORM models
whatever the data forget collected from
the user and then it mapped to an object
automatically that was a lot Vantage for
developers when you are working on it or
yeah that was a feature and that is
getting exploited I would say it is by
blindly
laying on over them so this this is
because the framework encourages the
developers to use automatically bind
from the input to the object that is
going to be saved in a database of a
tribe
either guessing object properties or
exploring other apan wines or reading
the documentation input and figure out
how your API is working and what are the
properties available so can I manipulate
this that's the source of the attack by
not preventing the client from changing
the values like it should be only
readable
literally but then you somehow make it
right so an example I can show you the
next one say there is a forum user a
password and email you collect it from
the user info and and this is the user
object it is been buying - username
password email and there is another real
value is admin - or false it's being
there in the user object right so when
you do an edit user you bind the form
running to the user automatically
instead of instead of manually setting
it that is the issue here
that is the master class assignment
issue here so we need to a post call a
PA call what does it do like anywhere I
can I the original request will be the
username is something password and email
but now just flipping through it I am
figuring it out hey there is another
variable inside the user that I can
leverage and it says is admin so I have
what if I try with eggman true and that
is the whole issue right like you were
able to edit a user as an admin so
that's the mask assignment issue so one
of the real world
that happened in some Harbor which is on
2019 a cloud registry service this is a
popular open source system for
registering the container base images
again it internally used o RM for
writing the objects to their database as
we discussed in a lot of places so this
list just found that the user objects I
have an admin role flag on them that
directly matched to the field so
basically they got hold of the admin
variable and they were able to track
what the base images used in the company
so so that's the mass assignment problem
what could be the prevention mechanism
do not bind automatically the client
input to the objects just whitelist only
the properties updated by the client
so in our example we saw previously we
would just manually set only those three
properties and not binding the whole
object so how is everybody doing
is it your able to follow through just
just making sure okay nice ok now the
security Miss configuration so this is a
pretty standard same as wasp issue 2 in
the web application nothing strange and
it is applicable to API also any
unpatched flaws common in points
unprotected files like that you can
directly used to gain unauthorized
access give to the Miss computation that
is happening that can expose only the
sensitive data compromising server sort
of configuration issues that we are
pretty much aware oh so this happens due
to the lack of secured headers and we
talked about HTTP method not able to
whew and we are exposing more and in
case of web application again polls
policy is misconfigured that you are not
supposed to access but the course
policies are like you can define a
course policy but it is like
misconfigured like what aps can access
if you give a star on it so that
configuration can be Miskin is a problem
here and again cloud configurations i
would see a breach here like Equifax
everybody is aware of the lack of
security headers untouched Apache struts
again the HTTP header content type that
was being manipulated with a malicious
payload so in the alerting system also
failed due to a security certificate
that has been expired for 19 months so
in then 148 million customers got
infected so there's a lot of
misconfigurations issue here including
not maintaining your certificates
properly
what's a prevention it's hardening there
might be some automate there must be a
way to automate your configuration to
find the configuration plot flaws you
can think about it and disable the
unused HTTP methods we saw that earlier
make sure our certs are in place so and
also review your s3 button
configurations API stack across the API
stack the configuration orchestration
files everything comes under this
particular configuration topic to
injection this is also kind of the same
attack surface as in the OWASP top 10
and the web application so
this happens because a client data that
is coming is not validated or filtered
or sanitized by the API again the same
issue is when you have an input that is
not being properly sanitized and your
API is accepting that input without that
sanitization and the input is being
passed on to a query which can mean
concatenating a query and then it cannot
try more than what it is supposed to a
simple example would be if you see a
delete API bookings like you're supposed
to pass daily the particular 678 but the
attacker was able to intercept this
request and change the booking ID in the
query string parameter so just by
manipulating in in the query string
parameter he was able to manipulate and
delete another person poking so again
sanitization of the input would have
helped here don't trust any user inputs
that is the number o number one and
sanitize is all the inputs that is
coming into the API that would be the
preventer prevention and care in input
properly decode properly special
character should be escaped and you
prefer a safe API that provides the
parametrized interface use prepared
statements in in the backend to retry
from the tables
so the next one is of improper asset
management so this term this is again a
very common issue in the development
management of is APA assets in the in
this fast c ICD pipeline
we gotta update so many versions very
quicker so we don't be commissioned the
old version properly and any new fixer
security fixes goes into the new version
but the old versions are left behind and
still there are some requests active
requests going on that input is being
serviced so that is a core problem in
this issue and also then like so many
api is like um and if you not in the api
gateway there are how do you discover
them and having not documented API
endpoints whole team working on some API
is long back having download
documentation so the API discovery is
the problem here the old API is that our
government and abandoned but still are
in active servicing so and also the same
security standards is not being in
production and not production
environments for example I put just in
this picture just cb1 get users and I
have some other new functionality I
released a v3 those two are active so in
the real world now experimentation you
wanted to in you wanted to introduce a
new functionality so you created a new
III get users that might be the new
latest API does some like get more
details or whatever the functionality
that they've already develop so there
are some users like with the
experimentation like 80% is using v1 and
20% users are getting the v3 request so
both of them are active and consider
this case there is a security issue
popped up and you fixed only on
three and you did not fix on wheel one
what would happen still some other
attacker can get hold of v1 and
manipulate it and exploit that issue so
it is always the best idea that whatever
the fixes that you put in it has to be
getting to all those API versions and
also there is a third one it's pretty
old API it's not discoverable that
nobody moves what it does but it is
serving some traffic with no
documentation it's up in the world for
exploitation as well this is pretty
common link to a Google that for a
particular like you will be able to find
out all the old API versions etc it's
out in the world another example would
be unknown API host for example DevOps
they can tail table something for them
but nobody knows it so there could be
some again it's a discovery issue the
real-world example would be a company
called Just Dial it's a local search
service in India so it got reached on
2009 19 just because again would
unprotected API I was left in the world
that leaked the data on their users so
basically their latest version did not
have any issues but the old version had
some issues and the attackers were able
to exploit it and get the user
information this one is pretty
challenging and time-consuming for
developers like just to make sure
whatever the active API is are serving
the same and how do you play
again it's required some work you need
to have the inventory rod staging what
are the APA host host generate API
documentation using open standards these
days it's left a lot of open standards
are available just do the APA
documentation and make them available
and then protection measures that we
talked about not only for fraud just do
the same thing for the other
environments and move to new API secure
version decommission the old one
whenever you can and the last one
insufficient log and monitoring this is
pretty standard you leave a lot of
information in your log and also you
don't wanna tear it up those two
problems so video sharing platform
dailymotion hit by the credential
stuffing attack again the same problem
is like there were no alerts what
occurred there was no monitoring
happening after the customer complains
then the team started looking into it
and they found this packet oh okay then
they reached up with the customers and -
for the person password reset etcetera
so yeah like you got a monitor and logs
you gotta make sure there is no PII
information or anything sensitive
information is being logged as well and
the prevention log in the failed
attempts prepared some alert use like
sim tool to collect and aggregate the
logs monitor create alerts dashboard
anything that helps on this particular
issue and these are the references I
included thank you that's was an API I
am open for any questions if you have
any questions I think somebody was
asking how often this is updated yeah so
um this 2019 like couple of last year
and then they I know the team is
actively working on and updating the
standards and also they are working on
to release a vulnerable API that that
everybody can just use to learn like how
web code was used to learn the web
application attack um so yeah this team
is pretty active and working on the
initiatives and there is a group working
on the JIRA issues as well yeah I have a
question what tools and techniques do
you use to evaluate the API endpoints
and it would be nice if we have example
to illustrate yeah so I think this like
issues that I've talked about like
except for the business logic flaws any
- tools we're able to figure out a lot
of issues - I'm not mentioning any one
in particular but and and for business
logic flaws
unfortunately there is not any tool that
will figure it out it is all about the
pen testing so I would say lot of issues
in the API so far have discovered
interesting from the basic ones like
HTTP headers and there are some rules
around that like you can figure it out
with these - tools but for the API
security I feel there's a lot going on
in the business logic side like you've
got to validate there is nothing like
one to will figure out your
authorization flaws or anything
that so it is a lot of manual review and
pen testing there's another question
here any best practice recommendations
you have for authenticating all modes
and it'll be the question yes any best
practice recommendations for
authenticating mobile apps yeah use the
what like the standard framework what
2.0 integrate that and then you protect
your access tokens and that's my answer
like use a pop like whatever the
framework that is instead of like
reinventing yourself use a popular
framework like I have used what 2.0
framework the question how is rate
limiting done in practice doesn't that
consume significant computer sources can
you elaborate on this question um this
was Shan Hsiung can you speak up ok
let's move on
comes back it was mentioned in an
excessive data spa sure about sniffing
API traffic how is that possible if you
I mean get hold of the API like I mean
I'm just thinking like something like
you bypass it then get hold of the API
and then get that sensitive information
so I have not done much on the pen
testing side but yeah there's another
yes I think that's the last question I
think Shawn is having issues with his my
I have a question if that's okay
yeah so you mentioned earlier about the
C CI and C D that continuous integration
and development
I was wondering how how would you like
if you share with us like what - like
the tools or the framework that have
been used during your experience that in
and how it does change the the API is
like performing security maybe check or
gate checks I'm just really curious know
I'm just mentioning about the CI CD
pipeline is like I mean now the
continuous integration people are
releasing more more features faster and
how the old version is like yet
abandoned so with that perspective I was
mentioning the CI CD and like you to
move fast so there are a lot of like old
API is getting abandoned undocumented
version but is this your question
like regarding what dose is being used
or is it anything in particular
yeah thank you I would be interested as
to that that it you know you explain the
the previous slide that's nice but I'm
just out of curiosity what would be like
there's so many frameworks but from your
experience as a security engineer what
would you like see the like a pipeline a
framework that it's that that did work
for you especially with that implements
like security gate checks okay I'm so
not in particular with API security so
in general the gate checks anything with
this like I mean any sassed checks also
automated like a SAP tool I have
integrated that was pretty cool I mean
I'm just not talking about API security
but in general the pipeline when you
come with the code or before you come
with the code the SAS kicks in and you
can the developer and before even
committing there is an IDE plug-in well
if it is available you can validate your
code for the security flaws because
assists all about the rules and there
are also you can do in your pipeline in
like when your module for what it is all
how you want to integrate it many before
you merge a for somebody I mean the
sastra scan can determine and give you a
report of whatever the security issues
and the next is the - if you wanted the
live request malicious request like how
the responses are and like the lot of
issues that I've spoke about like
headers and headers and we methods are
not enabled those are can be caught by
the - or can be like a wasp
you owe us consents Abdul you can try
that true it does both active and
passive scans the third is the ACA
software compositional analysis so any
code that you push in you want to make
sure that you're not introducing any
using any vulnerable libraries in your
corn yes like so yeah just a quick
question here for rate limiting can you
use API gave weights that offers this
yes so I have not worked in detail on
that but I know that yes you can use APA
gateways and rate limiting questions
there's a question we're getting Nets
Parker how good would that be for ABI da
da SD security yes it's just the there
in nets Parker which is a tool for for
testing web web services ABS how good
would that be for a API DASD security
dynamic dynamic yeah I have not I have
not used it to so I cannot comment on
that but whatever I may experience like
the rules like apart from the business
logic flaws I mean business logic like
the object we talked about the object
level authorization function level
authorization like all those are like
the - tools would not be able to fight
it or any other tool like I have tried
was not able to find it those are all
manual review interesting you got to
work with the development teams like
security person or the developers
to be aware of it checks are like
business logic sold but other than what
I when I talked about like the security
headers missing or any HTTP method its
disabled all those like dust was able to
find it with respect to this API and and
some sensitive information also they
were able to figure it out here's
another question how would you
differentiate de ASD from threat
modeling in terms of web app security
okay
Tech modelling is completely like the
only is like it when you do an
architecture review for your web
application say set morning is just
another term right then we think from a
different perspective when we are
architecting we draw some diagrams but
then that model is available you have
like you draw or like you discuss about
what are your applications what are you
inside the application and what are your
trust boundaries so it is a design way
of thinking that what could go wrong and
there are so many principles that you
can apply close try which is from the
Microsoft atom show start like so I
follow this tri principle like bringing
information is your sure so apply that
model to figure out the threads early in
the development phase before I even
start writing code we used two figures I
put a diagram how the process flows from
your application and output and then has
boundaries and and you do the stripe and
suppose whether spoofing can happen what
could go wrong so so that is totally
different from write logic model is like
I haven't seen I mean I use like this is
manual fit model
I know there are tools available but I
heard like they are also like not up to
the
like finding all the vulnerabilities so
it's the best way to manually sit and
threat model and record all the threats
and the mitigation - to something it's
very different from that model you
configure the URL the test and basically
the rules kick in and it sends the
malicious request flex crawl through the
pages and finds out the actual
vulnerabilities and we give you a tour
of how this flaw could be avoided and
what is the request URL and what is the
response that you got it
any other questions I just wanted to
yeah in the talk like so any automated
testing API I haven't explored that much
but then I would emphasize this like a
lot of issues that have we talked about
it is like just a manual review or
asking the right questions like so like
working with the team like hey this is
the request and this is the response and
sitting and talking what the client what
is the functionality and what is the
flow and who wants this data and seeing
the actual response and asking questions
like hey is this a pure data if you see
something fishy just drill down the API
response and talk to the team's like is
it needed like if you see anything
sensitive like hey why is neither
question that and and that and then
authorization how are we authorization
how are you limiting the access like
it's more like manual review that helped
a lot yeah that's one thing that ever
share my experiences with the API a lot
of thing like during the development
before we develop like you ask questions
and you figure it out a lot thank you
very much
thank you very much everybody brother if
you ask if you send me an email you info
be hacked of the org I would invite you
to slack we have amazing an exciting
coming up I'm gonna have the Koval CTF
the panel goichi we're gonna have a
container security drone security and
many others stay tuned check meet Colin
for / specific hackers again hacker
specific in Twitter or FAQ meet up and
we'll stay in touch and I'll thank you
very much for attending thank you for
this opportunity as well thank you hey
Rob hmm are we still using the P hack
channel on the slack
absolutely okay cuz I didn't see
anything for today you guys don't talk
if you guys don't die assume that you
guys are not nothing that you're not
active if you guys post off for sure
we'll get it going but you know you see
the general the thread in tow that right
now and the current disaster but yeah
you get this is your channel so please
use it didn't thank you alright guys
thanks so much