okay well thank you very much for
staying it's been a long day and I am
the last one usually not a very easy
spot to fill so today I'm going to speak
about attacking and defending drones
there's been there's several plenty of
presentations in the internet on the
internet about defending or attacking
drums I get a particular point of view
and I have two demos for you today hats
on videos obviously have to have to do
this record it right because one of the
basically the demos one is an indoor
drone that I was able to compromise use
an exploit during this pulley framework
and then the other one is it's an
outside drone that I was able to
basically I created what I call a
postman drawn fence and um we're gonna
look at this proof of concept we're
gonna talk about what the implications
for this things are for our environment
for our companies for our society
there's a lot going on with drones and I
believe there will be part of our lives
even more in the near future so let's
get started most of you know who I am
you talk to me in slack or you talk to
me in Pacific a curse or whatever I'm
very out in the community on brought
sorrow and I I'm a researcher with hack
Miami and Pacific hackers I worked at
Burrell x'q cos PETA which was a AI you
be a startup and now I work a Splunk and
I also worked at Akamai Technologies
kamae technologies a company that sees
around 30 percent or plus on the
Internet
so I have quite a bit of a experience on
security operation centers penetration
testing I still do penetration testing
and and Brett Demian
per time and I don't also quite a bit
above Trento and I also do a lot of
investigations in my spare time I won
the black hat catching flack in 2012 you
can google that it will see the picture
or my tweet and I could found it hack
Miami uh and Pacific hackers and usually
me and Marco and Kevin or Tyler we're
we're trying to move this on and in the
California and California and hopefully
we will have good news for you and new
things
soon in the future so let's talk a
little bit about drones or they're
called sometimes UAB or UAS so UAB is
uncrewed a aerial vehicle and UAS is a
unmanned aircraft system so the acronyms
are used differently depending on the
context but we can all agree is usually
an aircraft without a human pilot and
it's a an aircraft that sometimes have
different autonomy the autonomy can be
isolated autonomy or connect autonomy
for the most part is connected and
usually based on ground based
controllers the system communications so
the communication goes back and forth
and we are gonna look at it and how the
grace of autonomy can be more dangerous
and increase the amount of risk that we
look at on this devices a little brief
history there's plenty of history up
there
these are Nick Nick picks that I did for
my presentation on 1800s is the earliest
recorded use of a UAV for war fighting
and basically was balloon carriers that
were used in the eighteen hundreds and
and
offensive manner in the 1900s in World
War two
and I put this in the tone during the
Vietnam War they were use for recon and
attack it's important it's important to
understand some of the dry the drivers
behind the the drones like the USA only
lost around 5,000 Airmen during the
Vietnam War that itself is a big driver
right it also came along with a
miniaturized components right the
development of how we shrunk electronic
components were able to put them
together and the development of RC
controllers in the fifties sixties and
seventies is also the commercial spread
like in hobby RC planes and stuff like
that then in the 1990s obviously we had
the US and Israel collaboration and we
got Gulf War One the late 1990s 2000 who
started seeing the weaponization use and
enhance the command and control
capabilities and obviously you know
since the war on terror which is posed
9/11 the drone said then a fundamental
piece of a weapon against other serves
the 2010s
we saw increased autonomy we saw the the
first aircraft carrier takeoff and
landing the application of stealth
technology can increase the moisture
availability and during the 2020s
which is right now where we are there's
a lot of the testing and deployment in
the commercial sector so things such as
delivery transportation surveillance
media and home use the leave it or not
there are there are right now in data
drums that will patrol your house will
patrol your house call the cops or send
you pictures of your outside this is
part of the future they're about to see
and there is definitely a a component of
of pervasiveness because components
usually like any industry components get
get cheaper the products get cheaper and
that's a growth the product is cheaper
and easier use then you become
widespread and with a weather widespread
this products then then a lot of new
applications come on so here's some UAS
milestones right 1917 first Ron Rustin
Proctor area target 1950 advances in C
technology
flying systems November 5th 2002 was
according to to some historians it was
the first American lethal drone attack I
didn't get into these specific of discs
the links are there for you I will be
shared a lot so you can click on it and
more in 2060 FAA issues the first
commercial drone permits you have to for
specific drone you have to register with
the FAA there are some restrictions we
look at it a little bit in 2010 friends
company name parrot releases the first
commercial Wi-Fi controlled drone parrot
is a very popular brand they actually
have some sort of an open-source drone
that many people are working on it and
we're gonna look at it today so this has
definitely helped the the adoption of
this type of assistance in February 2012
better 2012 we hacked Miami did a
created a prototype of a drum and I put
the link there you can actually see it
this was February 2012 we're trying to
actually submit for the dark back dot
back talent we actually submitted a
proposal for that for challenge and I
will tell you more about it later in
this presentation
in 2013 first aircraft carrier take off
in the u.s.
2016 first Amazon Prime
by a drone I don't know why this is not
happening right now this is one of the
things that actually I discovered as I
was doing this research
20:18 first air kill and by developed by
the United States and in 2020 we have
things such as the development or the
delivery of drones of carbon 19 kids in
Ghana for example and many others um
many other situations by the way I
actually research on that famous couple
that supposedly was in a cruise in Japan
and they got wine by a drunk apparently
that was a prank that was not true uh so
so yeah so that was not true so they the
drunk did not get to the to the cruise
and they're not deliver one so here's
some of the general components of the
UAVs obviously you have to have a body
the body obviously has to be aerodynamic
you need a power supply in a platform
you need a computer unit which is most
of the processing and the the actual
coordination of the things the sensors
actuators and obviously with the
software resides you can see that
diagram that I took that diagram for
Wikipedia it this is an overview here
are some of the general components of a
drone they may vary depending on the
brand
depending on the size depending of the
usage so most of them have some sort of
a rotor it's no more than a fixed-wing
some of them have flight controllers
some of them have GPS some of them have
satellite communications some more than
are controlled by a Wi-Fi or are see
some more than half what is called fpv
first-person different which is it's
some sort of a goggles allow you to do
pilot and a maneuver the the drones so
there's there's plenty of differences in
components but in general you have a
structure some sort of a rudder or
propulsion system so sort of our dynamic
they're based on weight and materials
and some sort of a unit that will
control the rotors and
and the sensors to keep this thing
moving and going against something that
controls it that's that's pretty much it
here the some of the used examples
mostly divided military and civilian in
the military we have things that recon
logistics combat surveillance that we're
very familiar with military and
disability we have in this show which we
had the drones that are surveying for
example of power lines or utilities or
construction like for example I know of
some companies that for example if they
do your roof inspection you will
probably be done by drawing you will not
see this guy like climbing on whatever
they're nowadays they they bring a drone
and the drum goes up and and and you
know how to pilot it in fact our last
video at Miami conference that we did in
Miami Beach parts of it was filmed by
drone the the actual photographer was a
drone pilot and this is again this is
again the adaptation of new tech and to
new up into businesses so expect more of
these we also have delivery inspections
and photography just like a name it
photography also is becoming sort of
popular there are some available
commercial courses would you get
certified as a pilot and then you can
you know if you know you can offer the
to the pilot for events and some news
channels actually have higher drone
pilots and of course you have home for
security entertainment which is
obviously everybody wants to have fun
with these things or photography
personal photography all right so of
course there are risks about it and now
we did not come here to just hear about
the knives and and the Rosie thinks
about these devices where we're trying
to look at this on the from the
perspective of risk from the perspective
being weaponized in using malicious
manners
so so basically in if we're looking at
risk here's some of the the general
known risks associated with with drum
usage right so one of them is civilian
misuse so in Sevilla misuse you have
things that have for example drones that
had hit airplanes you have things that
invasion of privacy we have a lot of
people that have used drones to play
Devon for example on nudist beaches
there's actually you throw for people
throwing sandals at it there's some some
person that actually basically flu and
he drawn into a if a nudist beach and we
do have things such as smuggling by
criminal gangs this has happen in jails
far away it has become survey a more
prevalent and used NGOs because they
they procure forms that procure food
that procure drugs
so so this things are able to bypass
defenses and in at times even civilians
from this from jails and they're able to
do it and one of the things they're
doing is actually doing it about the
across the border there they're sending
drugs as well this is just happening
everywhere bow and only here it's it's
it's becoming a unfortunately in the
usage of this type of devices we do have
a recent case of alerts done by the
Department of interior's were which been
Chinese made drums and DGI
which is say a Chinese company has been
has been pointed out by some agencies
including some security agencies as
possibly send in telemetry data that may
indicate
sensitive information to a foreign
intelligence sir
so this this they uses this of this
devices had been actually forbidden and
there was some a company that was
actually donating this devices so the
problem with this and we're about to see
that in the tread surface is that we
many times these things can connect back
call back home but we don't know and
that is a definite effect and of course
we have the weaponization on the
terrorists using drones and I put a
picture there as you can see you can
actually even by a flamethrower when you
have time you go in and watch the bee is
pretty funny this thing is like throwing
flames at everything and and you know
you you put the tag the humans are gonna
find a way to make it crazy so here's
some recent drone instance the one in
2019 which is the attack against Saudi
your uncle I and I do have a take on
this of what happened and and I'll leave
this for the end obviously we saw this I
think everybody looked at it which is
what happen in Chile during the the
protests which is as you can see in the
picture there's a number of people
directing lasers this lasers borrow it
can be bought in Amazon you can you can
get the slicers III did research on this
and if you see the video you you should
take the time see the video as well you
can see how it overwhelms this drawing
the drone eventually crash so that was
kind of cool to see but it tells you
that there are ways to counteract these
things and and just like there used the
there is a number of ideas and people
using things to counteract the use of
this machines and of course we would
with the unfortunate pandemic we're
going through the Chinese where the
first ones to use drones to talk to
people and encourage them rotation mark
to go back home the Chinese led with
this we're leading with this because
there was repeating in the u.s. it was
forbidden in Italy it was repeated
everywhere so it is there the
Republicans are using drones across the
world to enforce quarantines and enforce
security obviously so here's a another
servant notorious but also an example
that these things can be used for very
nefarious purposes though the one to the
left is a drone basically carrying a gas
grenades in Afghanistan and the right
one is the the recent incident happened
in Venezuela where apparently there were
some drones that were targeting the
president the countermeasures worked by
the way if you actually look at the
video you can see how the drones to
start moving crazy
those are countermeasures and you can
see how exploded
II still still caused quite a bit of a
of a rumble when this was used but this
tells you that these things can be used
and it was also discovered that most of
these drones for commercial and that's
what about to get into it
here's a category of drones I know you
had the Nano
which is something that is this is
something less than that 200 grams there
in the places metric sorry for for you
can do your compressions to Imperial but
the operating altitude is usually less
than 90 meters the range is less the 100
meters the payload is obviously less
than 200 grams then you have the micro
the mini the small in the tactical right
here we're gonna talk about the the the
small what what I found a major caused
this mall
a unmanned aircraft vehicles right so
this category is less than 55 pounds
Chito quarter you can buy this in Best
Buy you can buy this in anywhere fries
i'ma tone any better already and easy to
fly many of them have pre-programmed
flying functions do a 360 return to
launch takeoff from my hand stay static
some of them even have GPS we're gonna
see one today which is the one that I
used the demo for the demo
they are commercially available no
restrictions
nobody there's you had to register but
the registration is almost like an honor
system
I mean if we have somebody that takes an
identity or uses or impersonate somebody
I'm not sure how accurate that is once
the person acquires the system some of
them can carry a few pounds to pay looks
like you could see in the last picture I
this mall the very small ones like the
Nano or the micro so the main they may
not have much of the payload bunch of a
payload there's still Mike Harrison but
the the bigger ones
I definitely able to do so they can
evade most of the current come to
Mistress there is no way to detect these
things they fly too low the fingerprint
is also very small and they're easy to
conceal deploy and actually that's what
happened and apparently in the plot in
South America where these things were
shipped they were that were assembled
there were carry in different places
different different operators stupid
assemble them together and put together
the operation that's a danger that's one
of the dangers of distance and they can
be used in multiple numbers with no
infrastructure you can actually manage
this with Wi-Fi or RC controllers and
you can actually get a phone with the
app and that's it you're ready to go and
we're about to see the implications of
the of this I guess items I just spoke
about but remember we're trying to look
at this from the wrist perspective
obviously you look at this from the
market perspective and you're a person
you're a law-abiding citizen you
obviously this things are pretty Austin
you can fly then I purchase several of
them and I had a lot of fun and my kids
love them and it teaches in technology
but unfortunately there's another use of
this so here is something that I've
found from Michael miker basically has
an aspect of the unmanned aerial systems
so this spectrum goes from the operators
in can't the technical complexity the
the standardization the flight controls
the number of aircraft the command and
control links and the cyber productions
so so basically you can have a person
that is on inform and basically flies
the drum close to the air for the
airport clay gets closed
that is something unintended that's me
shoes you can buy a parrot like a like a
Matic for example or a any other in the
same category and they will fly up to
over a thousand feet so you could if
you're close to an airport you can cause
a lot of issues here including flying
aircraft as well so the the the
technical complexity he goes from toys
to highly sophisticated so we have
consumer great things that you can buy
things that are commercial graded for
example the drone there are photographer
years it's a little more expensive
usually those drones cost above the
thousand dollar mark and we had things
that
flight control for example that some of
the additional navigation you can use
the the the Goebbels
you can use GPS waypoints and some of
them you have automatic return to launch
we're gonna see that today and one of
the demos and remote controller and also
we have a number of aircrafts the
concept of swarms which is sending a
bunch of drones in a coordinated manner
or a coordinated manner the pencil
number of operators you missed you pull
it off it can definitely cause a lot of
trouble and depending on will not drawn
you're using and what type of balaam you
can you can you can carry that's
something you have to consider and then
of course cyber protections if you have
anything that is Wi-Fi connected
obviously Wi-Fi is an attack vector if
you if you disconnects by an RF RF is
the attack vector if you have satellite
and satellites attack sector so so we're
gonna see this in a minute of how on the
tech surface this is sort of extensive
but it's interesting how these
researchers divided this then basically
we in between the CI a confidentiality
integrity and availability so as you can
see here there is a number of attack
vectors that target network staff target
kinetic stuff target humans target
communication links and the tread
surface can definitely be quite
extensive bending on the number of
either components sensors and features
of the machine that we're looking at the
ones that we're looking at here are
pretty simple mostly controlled by Wi-Fi
the outdoor we're gonna look today at
GPS and that those type of drums
according to what I research are not
really
major tread can they can be useful
option like for something was wrong case
that somebody flew a drone and there was
a president speaking in Europe and they
had to stop the summit because obviously
they don't know that this drum has
something in it or whatever but think
about it a commercial something that you
can order from Hamas on disrupted a
president's meeting so that is actually
one of the problems with this things
because they're small and they're easy
to conceal and about to show you not
easy to detect they can represent a
serious threat mostly I would say in in
the when we're talking about small small
drones they can they can be used for
something to disable things like
turbines and that things are there the
have brothers or things that have
engines with the what the the drone can
get in and and and damage it or even for
assassination depends are clever and and
how sophisticated the plot can get so
here's some of the examples right how
will attack control obviously we we need
to look at sensors and the sensors we
have video audio navigation you can
blind the drone with lasers you can one
of the theories that are read about what
happened in Chile was that the heat from
so many laser pointers eventually
overloaded the sensors same thing as the
cameras and you will see actually doing
and doing my first demo you will see
that the drum actually wants you to say
hey I can't see very well the the vision
of the disability is not very well so
I'm not sure if I should there might be
a malfunction satisfying you see that I
found that very interesting so that
tells me that if I pointed something
doesn't have to be a laser
but-but-but-but a visual stimuli that is
strong enough that overwhelms the camera
I might be able to in fact disrupt the
flight of this for this
air pack the physical labor kinetic
write kinetic you can shoot you can
shoot you can throw a net you can always
do it I so there's been cases people are
actually being charged because a shot at
a drone with a shotgun the link layer
basically what we want is telemetry in
the lemon tree we want to destroy things
like things such as line of sight or we
want to overwhelm in like jamming or
DDoS it which is distributed and ILO
service may be sent several points of
stimuli that basically confuse the
sensors and then if there is not enough
of a countermeasures but what we're
sending the drum might be able to keep
this strap or basically we'll decide to
do an idea which is referred to to
launch on encases or crash network layer
we have basically we have to target
either the RF component the Wi-Fi
component satellite or even mobile which
is some of the things that are being
implemented with the attainment of or of
the the beginning of bringing cellular
either cellular networks and things like
fine key so so those are definitely
things that we have to consider if we're
going to attack this in on the network
layer in this case what you're gonna see
basically when a compromised Wi-Fi over
if it was an if' based controller you
can overwhelm it or you can use a jammer
or there are certain problems where I
will go in in a minute
and then of course there's a traffic
controller the traffic control you had
this thing's the things like the GNSS
GPS or a DSP so then you can jam or
support GBS you can create objects would
ideally for example that will trigger
collision avoiding collision mechanisms
or if they're using radar it will force
the
the the actual aircraft to to divert so
that's these are some of the vectors
that we'll be looking at so let's look
at how we will defend the consistence
number one is usually its embedded in
some of the commercial drones to deal
fans your friends is basically embedded
geofencing software meaning there is a
number of coordinates where one's the
the the aircraft the tech stars nearby
on the only flying system it will not go
in it or it will retreat from it because
it's basically marked as no flights on
and this is being used or in the airport
and it's being used for many other
events where they do not want obviously
drawn intrusions of course there's again
the manufacturers have done some effort
and that this into their products
however as we saw recently on Heathrow
heater was paralyzed for I believe a
couple of days because somebody was just
flying a drum around the texture of
Raiders which are specifically designed
for you a beat UAVs are usually smaller
and very hard to detect by traditional
Raiders so there is a new generation of
Raider assistance are being adapted or
created for the sole purpose of
detecting UAVs all the detection systems
that I was every she's rustic basically
detecting the sound of the rotors this
things cannot stop fixed-wing or free
fall rotors or or sound that can be poof
and replayed to actually confuse the the
detection systems so this is some sad
sort of weakness and it cannot be
deployed as a single as a single measure
radiofrequency most of the
look at that were commercially available
we're using sort of about RS
command-and-control Inc and this can be
detected by different means and they can
be attacked we would see that this can
also be evaded by going radio silent and
using some sort of a inertial navigation
system which is I won't get into this
yet and it's also electro-optical
electro-optical is basically optical and
thermal sensors that may detect sort of
a heat signature what happens
unfortunately with the system since
today they may confuse and do false
positives with actual birds because of
the heat that they produce so here's a
defense of some of the tools for defense
and we had things here such as the
jamming the c2 you can jam the c2 by
using a some sort of icon this this is
actually available you can look at it
and in it and usually the frequencies
that some of these drones fly is
actually two point four or five point
nine gigahertz so basically what you
have is some sort of a a device and that
looks almost like a yagi antenna
attached to some pump stock that's
basically targeting a drone and and and
attend to to basically an excitement lit
like I said before depending of the
system that you're targeting this may
work or not also like I said before you
can attempt to tamper with a global
navigation system jamming the problem
with doing this is there might be
collateral damage like people are
driving around will be affected
airplanes are they rely on this might be
affected a lot of this stuff by the way
that I'm saying is borderline can get
you legal trouble so I
personally wouldn't do these things
unless there is a rules of engagement
and illegal in a legal context that
allows to do this so always considered
that in mind I get our sometimes calls
from from friends and colleagues they
tell me hey I had this problem at one
time somebody caught me asked me we got
this person that's constantly flying
their drama Bob close to our building we
think he's trying to crack Wi-Fi or some
of our products when you do this type of
things you always have to consider the
legal framework because the one I get in
trouble obviously and if you use a
condom measure that is overwhelming
they're my vehicle aural damage they've
met and the collateral damage may bring
legal consequence so be careful with
this also you have the ABS B which
basically I think somebody spoke today
about this doing the SDR talk at hack
Miami you can generate fake aircraft via
SDR there are several as they are
available I will show you picture some
of them two over one vertebrae there
trigger collision avoidance systems we
had a presentation hack Miami 2017 by
wills neck
there's the youtube link so you can see
it and it's something that you that you
should definitely review course the
kinetic defense and you can you can't
shoot the drone point cutter you get
that looks very silly but hey you still
do it there is you can throw like a net
on it and then you know who knows maybe
there's an extra concept when you go to
pick it up so I'm not sure about these
things but they still record you can see
using here's something that I wanted to
talk to you about and that is you have
to be careful on the counter
countermeasures
so the count accomplishments are things
that can be used to bypass many of these
defenses that we looked at you can put
on those defenses
together but there's still there's still
encountered countermeasures that may
allow malicious actors to go through and
do success for their attack I put a
picture there or what you see there is
supposed to be a movie
kamikaze drawn now as you can see there
is fixed win right so when you have
things like fixed-wing inertial
navigation system is embedded autonomous
navigation multi-layer sensor um
bod that mesh like resilience we
actually proposed this in DARPA
challenge in 2012 in 2012 we made a
proposal the body of drones that we're
gonna use basically we're gonna
emulating what sues the Sioux smog were
did that Sue's p2p which basically as
one of the sea toots balls then the
other one takes over and then if you
have a mesh network you can always
bounce around the situ in a way that the
botnet continues to be operated that it
this is a bonnet type of countermeasure
technique which is not new and we
propose do this in doing the DARPA
challenge we're gonna make a bunch of
drones off the shelf and and develop the
software based on some of the fondants
that we were looking at we were not
effective so unfortunately never so
fruition of this but that's definitely
something that will if you're using for
example a group of drums or what I call
the swarm if you use something like a
mesh like C to peer-to-peer command and
control where you can actually extend
the range of it even if one of them K
gets taken down or the the C to blink to
controller gets taken down
that's that definitely increases the
chances that attack will be successful
same thing with fixed-wing fixed wing
systems can for example glide even if
you turn off the
entire system it would still fly and he
was still go through which is what I
think happened in the incident in Saudi
Aramco I believe that these individuals
use drones that were fixed-wing that had
embedded navigation systems they had
they had to have some sort of a recon a
target and then once they got close to
it they must have turn off every kind of
signature what are the signatures he
repulsion noise and they bypassed a
number of confirmations including a
Patrick a patriot defense system so this
is to tell you that these things can
succeed and can bypass defenses of
against or content measures against
alone so this is a clear and present
threat that can see that can be used for
malicious actors and we had pay
attention to this the head I'm sure
there will be a market develop around
these things there is already but right
now several of this devices can be
successful if if we have a clever and
sophisticated
Adolphe adversary to perform an attack
and the the Houthi Kamikaze promise a
proof of that then you couldn't get you
can get more more defenses that the
saudi aramco have right so all right so
here's some of the tools I told you I
was gonna give you some pictures the
available stuff in the in the market so
obviously hack RF is one of them I have
one it's a nice research tool I don't
think is that powerful to create for
example a drone fans or or to emulate
out a gun shooting put like a yeah
Guiana and
drum my my research did not produce a
let's say successful results using this
as a contour measure there are yeah
jammers you can you can use jammers as
well again the jammers be careful with
jamming jamming can get you in trouble
so if you're gonna use this or you're in
a place there's a security context and
legal context that allow you to do this
things like that this has to be in a
context what is lawful so you just can
get and say I don't want people to fly
above my house it's just gonna put a
jammer that you can't do that by the way
doing it might capture the flag games I
seen people Jam the actual spectrum like
I could impose the Twitter that people
do not actually do research either Wi-Fi
and I had warned people this is illegal
you can't do that so I don't all the
know you might be in one country with
this is legal but in the United States
this is not legal be careful again I
cannot emphasize this enough so so these
are some of the toys I guess I call some
of the toys because they're not really
production don't rely on this you wanna
do some research and you are like for
example a law enforcement organization
or you're in a big organization you you
wanna use commercial grade stuff and you
want to test it if you want a researcher
and you you you want to test these
things against certain things then yeah
there's a value put but I my experience
is that these things even though they're
available they are not how can I say
this they're not equal to the tray the
were facing and there's a presentation
from Henry's a coffee in hack Miami that
I that I suggest you to watch where he
goes more than that of some of the the
things that are available for contouring
drones so here's some of the interesting
tools one of them I'm gonna use today
and one of them is drones flooring which
targets in attack wrong
mostly nano if you remember the category
that we have we're gonna be targeting
nano drones
there's also drone Jack and there's also
sky Jack some of these target obviously
manufacturers and these are things that
you can look at we may give you some
ideas for attack vectors and it may give
you some educational knowledge about how
some of the things that we have this
cost about targeting this systems so
here's let's go on the demo so here's my
first demo my first demo is a DJI tell
which is a Endor
it's an indoor drawn nano as a video
resolution is 720p can fly up to 100
meters it weights around 80 grams it can
fly it around 10 minutes not 30 around
10 minutes then go up to 29 km/h that I
haven't tested and you can you can fly
up to 100 meters that I did not test
either but it depends mainly on Wi-Fi so
here's the screenshot so you understand
the video well what you see in the top
left this me you've seen Callie on the
top prize is drums ploy you know the
bottom right is the the actual video
from the drama so let's watch it see if
I can just go straight into it see my
screen
just yes we can see it okay all right
cool so here's a video let me so here we
go there's no audio so I think I can go
and talked about it so what you see it
below is basically the operator new
operator which was my girlfriend Angie
very not super to help me basically
connects to the drone the drone is on
top of the tables you can see now we
have connection we can see the video it
gives you a warning it's just you the
ambient light is too weak and now I ask
you to take off Ron takes off and as
soon as the drone takes off
I run the the attacking framework with
the attacking framework basically what
I'm doing is trying to find the link
between the cellphone and the drum right
sir this is a Wi-Fi attack basically the
most of this off the shell in door and
someone out there drones have passwords
that are too easy that's one two three
four five six seven eight so you can use
things such as Wi-Fi the word or you can
use aircraft and G and basically you can
be authenticated or you can even guess
the password and with a framework like
what you see him there you can take over
the drone and as you can see the drone
is flying and I am basically changing
commands and changing my my neck in
order to be able to connect to the drum
I connect to the drum as you will see in
just a second and then eventually I
issue a command to to do an emergency
landing and once that happened you see
the dr. drum drop and then you see how
the video goes away so this should
happen soon you notice that there's a
warning about interference right that is
basically the network I'm you can use
this with a network card that you can
enjoy a package
or basically a non-fun would some of
those TV links are actually pretty good
and we should be able to see the drop
the drop of the drone in just a second
watch how the the video goes away and
the drop falls and there's the commander
this is available and github you can
download and run it and um Callie
obviously this was done within my home
this is a proof of concept again and as
you can see it wasn't that easy it took
several attempts but eventually I was
able to connect and then execute the
command so you see the drone drops you
can also connect and turn it back on so
why did this happen this happened for
two reasons the authentication was weak
even you can actually perform all their
Wi-Fi attacks and you can still be
successful in two they rely only in
Wi-Fi so that is my my first proof of
concept let me go back to here's the
link it will be available tonight here's
my second demo so in my second demo I
wanted to use an outdoor drone I don't
have enough budget to buy myself like a
big big drawn and mostly use RF and I
really didn't want to get into the RF
business for now I wanted to I wanted to
target the Wi-Fi first and then I want
to look at the RF I know the PRF needs
to be done in a much more controlled
environment so I was able to find this
drone which is pretty cool by the way
this drone is called the semi drone
unfortunately that company went out of
business but it has GPS and Wi-Fi and
then we're gonna see here this wrong was
producing 2017 and I don't actually I
don't take I gone out and talked some
nice taking some nice
shots and it is it's actually pretty
nice drawn but relies on Wi-Fi right so
although it relies for Wi-Fi and also
relies on GPS so there's two what that
vectors are you can address their I like
I said again I we looked at the GPS
a-gps
did not work and I believe because if
our nice a lot of what the phone is
sending and I believe the the hakka
reference is simply not it's not there I
mean like you actually poem and look at
some of the the stuff that you can do
with GPS with the hacker a few basic
they had to put the target right on top
of it so so there's no much like I said
before be careful when you're using to
think so as is it's not really what
sometimes advertise for so in this case
we I car gated a a outdoor GPS Wi-Fi see
me drawn I put the the actual links so
you can I eat yourself do you want to
experiment and play what it is it's like
strong actually does the nine 360 you
can take pictures it would allow you
actually do to connect to phones to wear
one of them can navigate it the other
one can look at the camera so this is
cool stuff so with this let's look at
the second one so the second one once
again some packs at stuff here so in
this case on the top left camera
we put this we did this outside and we
put a ride into a close to a a pound
conserve a little late so in case if my
crazy went to the water we didn't want
to affect anybody or hit anything
so then you see on the top left the the
camera the camera of the drawn and then
you would see that eventually the drum
hits the top high I execute the attack
which is basically a disabled one
by you will see how to walk fighters
disabled and then the drawn per dozen
RTL which basically goes back and Lance
again you see this is outdoor mode drone
goes up that's me and that is the
antenna that I use I use at out an
outdoor Wi-Fi and I think I overwhelming
to be honest and there's a drum landing
again and that's where called push
mayhem drum fence so this thing can go
actually way higher but again you know I
only have one drone not much of a budget
so we sort of did this we wanted to
research what's gonna happen but I also
couldn't afford to start buying drums
it's expensive so so that's my second
drone this will be published and there's
the the the link and with that I will
open it for questions you know thank you
very much this was worth your time
no questions I think some of them you
already cover like first one I see here
is why the multiple green lasers caused
a drone to crash in South America thank
you
your I can answer that one is basically
overwhelmed there there are several
theories one of them is that the
operator could not see the the other one
is the other one is the the sensors to
heat up and that was kind of crazy
because if you actually look at the
video there's so many of them that it
must have gotten very hot and that may
have taken the actual drone down talk
about the last one from Lennon is there
a restoration to transport drones from
the airport like in your carrier no no
there's no no that I know no actually I
do have two drones as well but they were
actually expensive trunks and I'll tell
you a funny story there there used to be
a balloon race where I used to live and
recently I'm talking about like - 2014
2013 I recently bought one of the B he
gave DJI drone to me whatever and I was
so smart to take it to the balloon race
and did a flyover and serve you know
basically recording 4k all the balloon
races until suddenly I got from the
speaker
you know we noticed a drone you please
take it down and I did but they actually
they did push it like he came back to me
and I at that point I didn't have
control of it
that my drum stopped working and I
couldn't make it fly anymore
so I took it to be a I support they have
to change the whole motherboard until
now I still don't know what exactly
happened what they did to it I mean I
can't understand they they there was a
jammer other than that I I don't know
what exactly they did to actually kill
the motherboard because after that the
the drone was not useful you know I
can't use it and then going back to the
question I mean I I I traveled with that
drone to two different countries like
Mexico for example I did some video
shooting over there and and two
different states in the US I never had
any issues I mean they're always
obviously they always questioning what
it was and I'm back in the day it was
kind of like a new new thing on drones
so they always you know was talking
about you know ask me what it was and
stuff like that but um that's basically
it no no major issues right the same
thing with the batteries or berries or
consider it's almost like when when I
travel a for most of us travel Def Con
you know if there are things there that
much more dangerous dead drums okay all
kinds of electronic equipment badges and
stuff but they usually treat that like
TSA would check it but if there is then
we check it for explosive and stuff like
that but other than that there's really
no restrictions there's just really not
restrictions the airspace above you I
think there is a limitation and and
that's how the paparazzi's get around it
just so you know there is a limitation
of how high is your space I don't have
it with me I can look I can look it up
but I did look up that I noticed that
some of the the paparazzo were actually
playing with that limit in order to fly
above some celebrities so back when da I
started gaining like
you know being noticeable about their
drones
you know people surveying them so I
remember that's also about the time the
FAA started asking people who were
buying drones to basically raising them
otherwise you couldn't fly them also
back in the day there was a case where
someone a guy and this is this guy was
actually filming these teenager you know
swimming in the pool so the dad went out
and shoot the drone well the the the the
guy who actually chatted the drone
filming for purposes that for his own he
he did not get in trouble but the dad
did because he shot drone so there's
always a gray area between what you're
filming I mean actually if you go to the
FAA now there's actually more
explanation of what you can do where
you're not working you're flat at work
and you not also you mentioned the
geofencing so now all the software that
comes with the you know you know they
have like the GPS coordinates like you
mentioned but about you cannot shoot the
drone however you can put a jammers like
to basically not to to go to that area
basically but again it's almost like the
same thing if you ask me uh it's in the
gray area so that's how you steal a lot
there you go let's click on that
yeah so here's a so rather to use a
drone to capture photographs or video of
a person that violates their privacy
such as final celebrities that's yeah
obviously that one that's because you
know Hollywood right so that was pretty
much like the first one
arrested somebody during the Super Bowl
by way Miami Beach that was flying a
drum because they were trying to get all
this footage is a lot of money
exactly and that was that the other
thing too I mean then first the first
time when they come up with their the
laws they said it was because so you
know you can cause harm like physical
harm not really about copyright or
anything like that but as you know the
last progress and as you know people
with money and Sarah you know I'm saying
all these things now you became like a
copy dry and we came like something
along the line and yeah I can imagine so
posting that also a Alec T there that it
says the low past in 2016 makes it a
misdemeanor to interfere with any
emergency services well if you guys so
my my action my first slide is it's
about a an ad from California that
basically says if you fly we can't which
is this one and it's because during the
fires
doing the wildfires there was a lot of
amateur people filming and flying drones
and then there was a problem for in the
helicopters so that's that's important
and thank you for bringing that up
any other questions
I don't see any other questions unless
like me something so if there's no more
questions my my slice will be posted
tonight around 8:00 p.m. Pacific and
I'll thank you very much for staying
this late I know it's been a very long
day today this it's been quite a bit of
a date I hope everybody enjoy it thanks
to lending and thank you thank you thank
you you are the guys and make this
possible
join the slack join us we some of us are
jumping from now to that CTF channel and
we're gonna keep pounding that hack
aside and see if we can get somewhere
and again thank you very much for
attending and we'll see you soon we're
gonna I'm not sure the person that
supposed to speak on our next meeting is
here it was about Nessus but if not we
will find a presentation soon yeah I'll
I'll commit now I'll do the PDW RT which
is a continuation of Phil Morgan's on
Wi-Fi I you know that there was a for
the people who attended that meeting you
know some people were asking things you
can do with your current Wi-Fi web
access point and you know there was a
discussion on he did all your tea and
and some people didn't know about it and
so that's when I said well basically I
did all your T's turning your you know
hundred and hundred dollar web access
point to a thousand dollar web access
point you know because now it will give
you more capabilities so it looks like
people where you know we're asking about
it so I'll do a presentation on that now
I look how they take it but that's next
either you will be on six
or the weekend after that I don't know
yet
like we we did a lot of precipitation
due today so we have June July where
we're supposed to have the pre DEFCON
meeting and obviously there's not gonna
be DEFCON but there will be there will
be villages so maybe we can come up with
from that so so stay tuned and hope you
guys joined the discord send me an email
for the slack and again thank you for
your time this is all about you and this
that we are gonna we will have surprises
hopefully for you and better things to
come once things are normalized thank
you thank you guys thank you Alex for a
great presentation and see you guys next
time
thank you guys bye bye thank you