have to switch modes here this talk
actually has a title even though I tried
to explain it to the organisers few
times but they kept ignoring its so it's
called the surprise stalker stalker
whatever but of course it's about the
web because that's what I do and I like
to talk about and it actually has a
title the way the cookie crumbles and
it's about cookies are really starting
about first of course the biography and
I don't have a lot of time so I tried to
contest this down to a single picture of
my life and I hope you recognize the guy
to be president of the united states
soon I really hope he wins awesome guy
but that's not what I'm going to talk
about I'm going to talk about another
type of scenario it's a classic scenario
you have a sim serving on the internet
server you have your a smoking hot red
server there that's well full of Chris
if you have a laptop that for the sake
of argument going to assume that it's
free from our own abilities apart of
course from having a web browser which
can be considered member of course but
we need to protect the somehow so we
have a nice corporate firewall or
authentication mechanisms for whatever
just serviced separated but still these
needs to be able to talk to the
computers on the Internet as well as the
ones on the awkward ones on the internet
from this guy of course that server and
declined computer is controlled by this
guy so now how do we prevent this troll
the internet from affecting this
internal server so that you know that
dying down the forest this guy's browser
to tax the internal server while
emerging policy here represented by Adam
poses the most important principle of
web browsers as this is the one that
prevents your great sacrifice them from
accessing your online banking jobs are
important but let's go a bit off topic
rural or at least it will seem so you
have some nice internal system are
considered to be just the system
actually I have access here of course is
that these applications so we can assume
that it's vulnerable to process
crippling or for worse so the strongest
do some simple like 123456
separately analysts equal interest which
is fine so of course we start by devin
is trying to select username from users
may be ok that works we construct some
user information you're still what I was
doing that this is an internal and
protected application for Messrs crime
and have this database returned from
JavaScript as well or some other users
in the database and put them together in
a and then just add some houses tomorrow
as well yeah ok so now we have the user
database scrolling by in an interpolated
in the tag of course more details are
not really super interesting here it
would be a lot more nice if we could
have a script type of course you can
just get the script but I'm not gonna
standing right thats myself rebuilt
that's filled script this actually just
create a simple script and it looks like
this is creates an HTML file the request
and then it takes all the date but that
it just extracted from the database and
posters to reserve part of location is
that location for this is the hackers
servers
without actually can sit and watch they
use this afternoon that the attacker has
no access to the server could still take
this URL that maybe even mix it up a
little bit so that it doesn't look as
crazy and then send it to the victim
represented by this brother of course
the victim is some object to visit the
euro is that in the background is in
some way or the other doctors looking at
his
preserver of the victim to the victim
leaves the data even though the same
origin policy as opposed to separate the
servers are things that I can now run
the script on their version of
bipartisan resembles a fairly easily
made a nice I also really loved the
usual here with a javascript
history of its own I jumping in the
source of the page
there but this of course is pretty lame
an obvious the attacker is able to run
scripts on the servers so you can bypass
the same origin policy that's the way
things work let's talk about something
slightly more interesting we have
another application and this also serves
suffers from some from some service i'd
injection vulnerability in this case
it's not very obvious takes this
parameter value it's some sort of action
and doesn't matter what you put in there
is just something
but let's try and put in a sleek
director me be 42 seconds so apparently
we have the blinds a connection problem
here which you can exploit by just
measuring the loading time of the
picture and this is interesting because
let's take that that your real and dry
and embedded into my friend so so
now we have two friends they're fun of
themselves to sleep for trying tho them
and we can see that the loading times
are different so now the vulnerable
service actually leaked information
through the browser to this frame that's
on separate domain though actually
bypasses the same origin policy without
script because you can measure how long
it takes for this page to load though
some friends in these frames will if we
look at the famed that took some longer
time to load it actually says if the
magic secret key starts with the letter
Z you should sleep on second and that
the other friends as if it starts with
an age 40 seconds so I hope to see where
I'm going up apparently we now know from
loading these two things that the secret
key starts with the letter from iran
it's fairly simple to build a little
script that systematically goes through
this tough bind the connections to
retract one that read the time just like
she does for those who don't care to
properly use when you read it yourself
and you doin JavaScript so I did thats
this trip to address do this and the
last minute values and actually working
fairly good I can
actually managing to expect passwords
from the stable and some extra points if
you recognize whether passwords are from
the middle of one of the more than the
last one is actually the Super Admin
password for Facebook to look into any
accounts at one point in time to do
something different accounts it was
pretty awesome does it is also missing
one letter in that because I didn't
brute force for this particular letter
in my ultimate
upside that someone you want to get all
the letters now this is very interesting
from an attractor
to do this but right now we're talking
about the prospective with the attacker
doesn't actually have access to this
valuable application so what this also
does one this managed to extract some
data from the vulnerable service it also
post the state up to third party here so
I have the passwords posted now at this
point let's look at how to actually do
this property will you have to go and
pick this victim into visiting some
strange page and page extracted a bill
to pay for that as well I
that you won't get my son of actors so
looking for the this is the hackers
server where he is receiving the date up
the victim this page three
well I'm surprised the passwords are
coming in here so the
operating system
so you can agree now with me that it's
possible to bypass the same origin
policy and have fun and have this server
out on the internets leading the
declines browser even though we have
simmered in trying to predict it was
just the basic time
so what to do to protect this
well first of all as we saw Superman
doesn't care about timing
protect you and what we need to do is of
course to introduce some magic box for
the sake of argument of course we're
assuming that the guys that built this
crazy vulnerable service required for
building such as shit the service so you
know we're watching it so instead would
find to introduce a magic box 22 stop an
increasing attacks against this but
what's supposed to happen in this magic
box
well first of all let's us to filter out
the actual strings of that off topic so
I'm not going to talk about that because
buildings
think that this extreme options which
would prevent the vulnerable position
from being loaded in the ninth frame or
in a dream at all that doesn't work
actually because even if you have that
the service until these pages actually
loaded or unloaded events trigger will
still trigger but they still could shift
the HTTP referer head there you know the
weather that the server which page that
cost the request to be some will surely
do that
out this magic attack from a gem of 5
which will prevent any refer others from
being central and then you have nothing
but of course if you shake the referral
had their only if it exists and if it
doesn't exist they just stopped a
request that might work
and also of course you have different
other crises range features that you use
constant security policy and what have
you
this not sure they may work they may not
work depending on what kind of strange
feature you want to use but I mean this
fact that I used to load stuff and my
friends I've been replaced by its
XMLHttpRequest sister and they have the
same sort of thing coming months so it's
not as easy to do with actually easier
to do it with a request I am posts in
the idea of a global cross-site request
forgery protection for this sort of
thing and what out of the global order
of protection work you out the magic
tokens to the requests
there was some together with Curtis and
the server sixth to make sure that these
tokens are correct
otherwise the request is rejected
wouldn't want to have this for services
start altered they do you know if you
want to change your email address that
problem something that you wouldn't want
to be able to do through client browser
if you say that to all your services not
only the ones that are supposed to alter
date on the server that would mean that
the attacker would need access to the
application itself to do the action
which is actually a big help as a bonus
having a global cost reduction for all
your else would actually also mitigate
most reflected process proposing tax
which is not because you won't be able
to get the exact year olds that you need
to
but of course it will also kill some
features you won't be able to click the
link and then the application anymore
because that will be rejected but it's
really easy to enable if you have a
proper Web Application Firewall load
balancer
switch so I guess you did that's already
everyone know you forgot to press the
magic secured about the Nano you made
some new card sad you always have to
press the magic secured about them to
secure application so what happens when
you press the Magic Mountain well look
at mister NetScaler states that's when
they see an HTML form through their load
balancer they will have the magic store
in the forum and then when the form is
posted they will check the token to see
its ok so this of course means that it
only applies to forum posts that really
helped us and of course you could
possibly suspect that there might be
other services in this application that
actually all Thursday down the server
without receiving an HTML post you know
breaking par of 72 research and they
don't get requests and then of course
you soon as well so you better beef up
its well looking at their instruction
page and how to protect against
cross-site request forgery of this nice
picture that says these just this option
recruit refer out there if it accepts
only if its presence you'll validated
and if you remember what a few minutes
ago it's fairly easy to just disabled
request something of richard is just
adding in this simple math so using this
option for another if present is
obviously completely useless there is
another option to do always enforce it
this is the one that they circle for
some reason so there are other ways of
doing this will if you look at what the
FI beloved answer does the insert some
javascript into the pages and that if
you have a fight with a look at the
JavaScript because it's really funny of
the solution is really crappy but it's
also really funny really easy to dig up
the state and they do really strange
things but it's fairly certain it's
actually something that something to
play wrong with but this magic
JavaScript it inserts tokens into your
health you consider to insert and 20 you
ralph is of course may result in your
bringing your application completely but
it might also prevent cross-site Request
for directly but looking at the sexual
talk and so that we sometimes have
problems with the request what would
stop her from retrieving month from self
and then used up her in the cross eyed
requests that is forcing the victim to
some could just take us on to create the
form like this some of the victim posted
obviously not completely worthless the
tokens are tied to its so the server and
then you need to talk to that is somehow
tied to that of course always
automatically submitted and originality
the group you can't just because
companies extracted from fans and the
story
good I'm still from time so let's look
above us and so is it really that hard
to set up your clients let's assume that
we were in a factor and we found the
courage to try and say hey cutie use
this when you when you send requested
this crappy broken service and then off
not to tell the victim yet no son this
requests with you and the client's
browser is short and goes to the magical
machine the magic machine takes a look
and say what the heck out so the server
is this really possible course it is
possible in flown since at least 13
years when such a fixation was first
described this information is basically
about something onto a victim's browser
and then have the victim authenticate
them with it and then you know the value
of the organization so now the tackling
the victim are sharing the same session
this is alan simpson that information
that I quirks doesn't specifically say
how deceitful so that's what I'm gonna
do this by the way is fairly easy to to
resolve this issue because it's just a
matter of victim submitters password
but then lets out how we can actually go
about the people's browsers
apparently are obviously the server
there could not say that would be sent
to another server everything crazy but
of course you consider trip to you that
sounded for larger domain so if you have
your own garden variety of the unit and
articles for the entire ordeal the
domain that means it's also getting sent
to battle tomorrow of course is for even
more general bombings because that
wouldn't also major things really crazy
emina full-year example.com for you
that's valid from carid.com bombing the
new resume be flooded with the coaches
from everywhere there's also some other
lists or methods for preventing certain
there's a public service list and at
least the number of domains on which you
can't put cookies because these domains
sharing sub domains where the users are
completely unrelated to each other so if
you have a domain and have some things
that different than you should submit
your domain to this list to prevent
users from seventy percent each other's
service this is the modern and same way
of doing it the old way of doing it this
way that explored us it's still so they
take the domain and divided into two and
then they start second stuff down on
second down jackets the top-level
Dominus TV
just under yeltsin sort of Christmas
trees especially stuff going on then
they said if this one of these domains
if so well then we do this it's pretty
sore Poland and do something different
than if the length of listen through
them
expect this to blow up so in adjusting
the actually moved to the public sector
to do with like saying that but assuming
that the application of our vulnerable
its application is free of crisis
rippling vulnerability and if there was
no other Greece available functions that
we used to set cookies were primarily
have two different ways of setting up
his victims browsers from the fact of
prospective first of all the obvious one
if you want to attack targets we go
around and look for other servers on the
same domain will find 11 that's called
vulnerable to which contains a
cross-site scripting vulnerability
some words mobility but something that
we can use to set them on their entire
victims remain in our cookie will get
sent to the server and of course is a
sound doesn't work for me because I do
see GDP only so you know scripts can't
really thats my cookies and that's of
course good to use as you should know
that the only does not prevent
alteration of it prevents the scripts
from reading cookies but you can still
over right and HW with javascript and
you will be overwritten with an honours
degree so read only attribute
and of course you would think that if
you set the group's on another domain
dunn's deal that would be less specific
done the genuine courteous service
should be the service reduce the general
and we'll get into that in a little
while
talk to you about option to which is to
intercept the traffic to the victim and
that the minds of Americans are
basically someone sits on this open
network team tries to intercept the
response from the rewrite its to become
a redirect and redirected through the
year
vulnerable or the server that I want to
tax over HTTP of course and then when
the browser tries to follow this
redirect in disaster response again and
reply with each other that's fairly and
then you would say well sure but I mean
of course we used to secure attribute
for the saudis are never simple plain
text and that's of course great but it
will not help this either because if you
have a security it will be overwritten
by anon security over a non-story
channel and this is something that is
really think about because security
situation people think that the Sept the
Sakura tribute to cookie that means that
it is secure and it will only go to grip
the connections and its troops will only
be sent to ruin Creek the connections
but it will still be able to be managed
manipulated by the store writing
and of course you could say that Joshua
but no one can manipulate traffic on my
network because it's it's secured and
that's good dude your users ever leave
your home networks just a Juniper do
they ever go out on an unsecured network
may be so that you can like the money
could be here and then when they go back
to work though still have my cookie and
go in there and be vulnerable with that
of course you could say that gesture but
they are fairly short lived in this
group is so it will be raised by the
time that it just works
sure but I mean that we should set the
cookie with an indefinite lifespan that
will live for next thousand years and
live on Monday and then we'll at the
same time on the server to keep it from
changing so that's why possible problem
apparently can overwrite computer that's
interesting but if we now have multiple
copies for the same name
what happens
well the browser will some old excuse
that it has a request so long as it
matches the domain the path and expiry
time on this of course is to be under
security so that means that if the
browser has undertaken in session that's
it for this path and then another
session that from other polls done the
browser will send both of them and the
browser will not tell the server which
is rich and the names so this is what
the service it's the same name different
values the normal behavior of servers is
suffused the first one and then you
forget about jerusalem but that means
that order is important so that comes in
first if the one that will be used so if
you want to attack someone and forced
them on murder a horrible Curtis
you better make sure that somehow you're
the one that comes first in the list so
how is this done well there's some sort
of order food somewhere i think thats
list that cookies are supposed to be
some in a specific order if they have
the same name if they have the same name
that should be sorted by how long the
process that has been created so with
the same path will be something
but there will be something based on
vacation time so that means that if you
have some stupid page to tell if someone
from that page it will default to that
spot but if you were on any other things
are you can actually get the more
specific path so this is very easy to
rest of wind if you can if you have some
page and then you can set a more
specific goals done the default path so
getting your degree first industries
it's fairly easy but it's also fun facts
cookie domain is not considered here
when you when you decide the winner
that means that even if you have this
super generic domain at the example to
come you can still have your trip to be
some before the quickest to respond on
like specific server on the specific
path and you're still be some first that
means that this actually works on the
droid I is happy because that means that
it's actually quite durable 22 attacks
finds his way but I know I'll just be
happy with you doing still across the
border
assuming that we have the possibility of
setting two dozen times they're not even
more funny things we could do have you
ever tried an application where you have
one could do that identifies your person
and then another cue that actually
identifies your application session of
utah snow protection I can tell you for
sure that probably even today if you are
browsing the net today and this is
because people like expensive applying
for the sake of families would say its
large corporations and banks and stuff
you have an application server and that
we should practice session using an
application settings and then you have
an authentication server which has its
own authentication and i have a web
application firewall relative that might
set their own cookies to prevent you
from photographers for himself
so what happens if we mix this up if
we've raised bands would take our
application session cookie
application session and force this to a
client authenticates so that we are at
the actual valid session and then the
victim prized or something but you still
have hours session cookie that means
that we now even though we have our
separate identities we still share the
same session on the application server
so interesting
Coast the session if you use that the
store sensitive than the attack would
actually get hold of this data even
though the attackers not identified as
the victim was killed when a victim of
implicates you might stores things like
the credit card number in the session
temporarily that means that the attacker
would have access to shop with a
critical something and this is actually
true because I've done so is this not
just saying things such information and
it sort of is but it's affecting more
like this service session rather than
authentication which is what decisions
decisions about originally and also you
know when people buy these very
expensive products to to reform
multiplication these sort of thunder
soon that would prevent them from from
being vulnerable to third in Europe
vulnerabilities so how does this
actually a reason you know make sure
that these different cookies are always
tied together have a one-to-one
correspondence if you have it needs to
be tied to a specific application
specific value and make sure that if one
thing just done just throw them away in
general
if you don't do scheduled indication
like bicycle through when they go or no
nvm then tried to tie your application
logic to that implication mechanism
instead because I haven't that separate
the means that you're vulnerable to this
type of attacks again so you have a
separate session from your vision that's
actually solution and I think that's so
I'm already running out of time