thank you for reading The Sing Off word
of other stocks employees but were used
Stuxnet as a benchmark for the ordinary
abt it remembers the report sucks it was
discovered around 2010 2011 and was back
then the most sophisticated cyber weapon
ever seen since then you might have
noticed that were several reports about
more sophisticated weapons and and the
more most sophisticated weapons and and
insanely complex and so on so forth so a
bit but that's still in the hands of the
people are system most dangerous piece
of filter every person I've never never
looked into the box of the hold on to
the images that some of the most
physical thing ever seen
Janeiro work on mower working for a
California company called so far and
their production technologies sort of
her so i think im war we're the good
guys are hunting goes things pretty much
black and white and let me tell you this
is actually a month so the times of
cyberwarfare where the hunters were
after the the bed criminals are pretty
much older brother having a jungle out
there were
people are in the way more horse riding
which number where does it come from
who wanted to actually target which
victim what was that other victims
machines lists actually victims were
talking about her is that targets or is
it just another entity on the internet
anymore he was targeting home and after
all it's not even a child there but it's
wild wild west religion because actually
nowadays the good guys are hunting goes
under the guise of selling stuff to the
good guys for hunting goes again she had
other comparable with harvest was
interesting there's no have so many
actors being active in our West using
their tools as well cause cyber weapons
and there's little fuss about this other
weapons and interesting for me is that
several weapons or not by the
sophistication of the moderates half but
Miley who was the actor behind it and
was targeted you can't really measure
the complexity of a binary based on the
victim was affected by it to do with
this presentation has come up with a
with a measuring skills how to measure
the complexity of mother and by doing so
eight different points that I feel as a
reason to make my life harder or other
in hunting after his mother
these points as trying to tell you how
to make more whether you might grab some
interesting bits of information if
you're showing the complexities kill I
picked case studies of different case
studies of motor in the fields of mass
murder as a call the school Melbourne
which doesn't care about which computer
just after banking credentials of the
second category B abt
targeted member being slaughtered
commercial goals but knowing which
victim has in fact government number
which is not after commercial goals but
after political information
the case that is the first one I just
heard about susan was probably the most
notorious bank interest has been out
since 2007 and the two simple success
story of one piece of software really
changed almost two decades and still
being very successful next to think it's
doing things from machines and more
importantly supply company
construction work overtime of added
functionality and emerging technologies
and other stuff this muslim poorly
because
open source back in 2010 someone like
the source code of susan has since then
things went wild so several different
versions of news of you often and Sons
of susan's grandsons of Susan and others
headlines news has been around forever
and I'm sorry it hasn't shared lots of
money is not the most complex piece of
malware ever seen but it's very
successful one which makes it very good
over compared to others liked the sally
is more fun factor affecting machine by
placing its malicious payload is
malicious paled into existing binaries
pending its 22 the company have an
existing binary my friend of binary the
way to start up the executable the
decorative stuff in the beginning
look at the entry point will decrypt the
payload injected into nuclear threat and
then start off the original binary will
spread out throughout all of the system
in fact several wineries and make sure
it's always been run on the infected
machine was also very hard to remove
from she never saw these appears to be
about that so she decided to join but
that does not
one command controls over but actually
being controlled by solid infected
machines themselves we have master note
taking over control and slave nodes
being the usual
components very resilient
which is hard to take them because
they've done to target the control
components which is very hard after all
decentralized also so these are very
invasive as we mentioned it in fact
several weeks ago that was on the
machine and other countries of security
software actually order of saudi king
with a driver component of a watchdog
the background and scan for security
products that were installed and try to
deactivate them and try to hide her
their operation is more forever first
version of study have been detected in
2003 which together makes a lifetime of
also over a decade which were over
family itself is very long time
bypass this is one of the apt example
that shows just like ross is approaching
these symbols of what causes one of the
most employers have reversed but pasa
two-component mower with a plan
component and the sort of like this so
you know the Target Corporation we have
cash machines reporting to a central
server target is a retail company which
have been infected with the client
component of blackboard scraping the RAM
and just parsing rubbery find
information in the room
collect all information together and
really push it to share on central
server the server component will collect
all the other than just push it over the
network has worked through to russia has
a very simple ways to conserve as much
as protocol is creeping around pushing
to the share taking their from the share
of pushing out of the network itself was
written by the models look like written
by a doctor was written by high school
kids I was a russian teenager post a
surplus of was like a stalemate should
load of money
we have a very simple softer making
money again next
was not successfully been used by the
program called
bear bear I think there's are really
russian
targeting ICS systems trying to gather
information about industrial control
systems service networks the Windows PC
interface were when those gathered
information about this information after
having a lot more component but the
spiciest criven component was the run
during the most public attention because
it was something that Ellis hadn't seen
before and you would imagine house price
rose engineers work on welfare or if you
see something that they haven't seen
before the first example of Nations
tomorrow talking about evil bunny bunny
is part of the Animal Farm apt
by Kaspersky there were other entities
giving it a different name his name but
got by the Canadian intelligence service
who operated by the French government so
we have reasons to show that money was
incredible but it came with an
integrated product just download
scripts to script its own car body is
work so far away that the Lua scripts
can call back into the sequences that
are compiled binary off a funny and
modify its behavior at one time talked
about was director of animal farm or
snow globe bar bars in the Spanish
Russian to lock key strokes and steel
screenshots emotional running
applications do their homework about
like still virtually everything that's
happening on the machine on its way to
implement the implementation of the bar
rising because it was surprisingly
simple for being a lot of course the
physical part of our look surprisingly
similar like being chronicled project
how many of you have seen gold project
website
grade I don't know how people read the
articles on there but I would be
surprised how much of the code being
published in copper to find again Miller
was kind of stuff trying to hide its
presence in five goals in the process
and system process including backup
instances in tomorrow welcome instance
would do is be on our way to tell them
instant ice house process then take over
the execution we have a very stuffy
last piece of nations that number
want to talk about was just shocked at
how many people you have heard about
Cheshire Cat ok talk about the summer or
in mind for the first time so you
haven't heard about this very very
interesting group of our been around for
almost ten years since 2002 until 2011
apt is a very long time this is over and
I'll exercise attribute yourself do you
think
which nation is behind this kind of
stuff around forever
the boundaries are targeting very old
Windows platforms
talking about
but Morris tries to infect your system
when the 24 and even older Windows 95 98
the main targets aftershock of mother
was network monitoring seeing richard is
going in and out of the machine
monitoring a terminal server solutions
and information from the infected
machines and the most important thing is
the temp files but start with the tilt
and the other for it
about other member of the operator been
agencies which are to the right of the
complex II complexity we find them over
because I was fined us as a resolution
here i think is charging I came up with
the Stoxx little meter to measure the
complexity of a given piece of lumber
and compare it to another piece of more
serious for targeting all reports and
all the news the other about the next
most nations did our targeting the plant
looks like this
we have a lot of complexity done here
health and less than stocks of here on
top of the clothing consider the most
complex piece of paper boxes are
benchmark and wanna compared to the
ordinary apt to the case but how we do
this how can we came up with eight
points that I find challenging
analyzing his lawyer tell you how does
that actually wrong so percent how
gets it wrong and how better as it's not
unique as soon as you want to infect
more than 35 machines with your mother
you might want to go to the binaries
place in his machines are unique or
different from the ones I'm not kidding
we actually Animal Farm set of models
that are in our service parts of butare
building a botanist you might consider
that should because there have been
large
you want to infect machines desires of
the game without any in a unionist
without some of the Feingold can without
any image including but not with the
same binary how long does it take for
the company's actually pick up the
binary let me tell you I worked in the
insurance company takes them from two
hours to two days
signatures for a new winery let's say
fifty thousand of the machines and with
one thing signature find these machines
want to be represented by the other
backers are a pattern that can be
managed by and versatile is also looking
to a very simple
BIOS is using comparative thinks just
the tip of the things you can do some
hundreds of different BIOS from one and
the same copies of the pieces that give
me a hard time our API a resolution to
API is causing by are usually tell you
what the binaries about it doesn't
bother you want to hide them something
with strings you don't show any critics
strings binaries and there are certainly
thought to actually hold these are
interesting in the case is the usual
sort of asked Asian and South modifying
code does have a closer look at how very
easy way to highlight a few calls are
some time was this really very easy to
implement already gives the travel to
reverse engineer because they're using a
temp table is an indirect cause within
the binary which don't show the actually
be a name so at least as well as the
jump before there's a lot of other
missiles to make this harder than just
you know you have to hide
API calls with the strength of critics
strings and shown here is a very simple
to hide your strength from the binary
and also
for the memory of longtime strength of
character to character at runtime you
can hide them from themselves from
security solutions which can build
affection these concerns a lot more
complex methods to heartstrings of
frustration for many dedicated christian
beadles which will get a string right
ones near the office kid again to hide
it from other memory or results to
strengthen however get this straight
seasons actually the only mothers are
found huge managed to obfuscate the
payload America you should keep in mind
that usually Morris built-in in layers
usually you have your payload which is
wrapped in a Parker was wrapped in a
production here unless you make your way
through the Packer you make your way for
the protection there with the payload
realized I don't think there is a clear
payload so as long as you're on the cold
you can just read actually 6 KO's really
cause you're perfectly fine so this is
not this is not rocket science office
killing called this is actually pretty
simple but most mower doesn't get to the
stage for the payloads itself is
obviously that
kind of application others are very
simple example I picked her up we have
this instruction which when debugging
for the piece of code changes its layout
looks like this turns into an increment
instruction the following review helpful
obstruction of here on shelf has six
fights so many December will give the
jump instruction 6 bytes of length is
that the job description
chance that the fifth 265 in his own
section to section this is the address
of destruction self exam here plus fight
so
chance here and as it does so creates a
new construction right there just turned
into our income and as lovers have
example of self modifying code were from
you know December and the world will get
this right because they just cant answer
not built to disassemble instructions in
itself
these kind of bets in your binary code
you can merge to office case which was
just awful skidded in my very hard to
analyze 130 Morris got the first rate
this well was it is a polymorphic
richter every time the defects in your
file charges to modify its own culture
look different
very infected infected piece of
executable has a different version of
the in there and I think it also you can
find out because for the company's
caught up with options for somebody just
happened that's always ago as crews
researcher was very excited about
finding her
solely through active in the DPRK of the
guy was more surprised you still think
so each other or actually north Korea
has public appearance by there is room
for other chances are when you were in
fact that the machinery machine is the
infections gonna be discovered
eventually there's always the smart user
so she's in fact the longer she doesn't
like the chances are that your
boundaries are going to be like that
college based options security companies
either tried to find evidence
which are like pieces of defining the
boundaries or they cut my hours before
her she's so once one of your BIOS is
known to be detected forever and
everywhere so you might want to have
updated every once in a while
irregular intervals and you want to
reroute traffic that's 216 fetch the
area from Russia and South East Asia but
from a local proxy very good again as
soon as you can see the updates traces
officers infection who watched Love
Machine vs would be updating its final
season as homogeneous copley within the
distance of a few days and this
effectively evading flash-based
deductions are engine
when you read the piece of motor usually
have a binary but artifacts in the
machine that you need for persistence
that is restoring the need for
communication so here's a list of
proposed for defects you might want to
be repetitive we track actors mostly
there have to reuse their remote service
so email services the link from his
mother to the actual active behind and
to the actual network that is important
but also filings dropped onto the sample
the tiller temples but keep popping up
being user names are registered to
legitimate seconds
changed over time to leave a positive
cases on my favorite reporter for
defects was was this one was like not
not a final dropping this message
embedded in my memory as was the bar
the first time this type of message
popped up in several different families
and our apt group of animal farm so this
is an error message stuff think whoever
told through several different buy these
securities in our seniors first thing I
did was create a signature for like this
beautiful type on the street level find
all the batteries contain the same piece
of code number 6-2 they're not sensitive
to their environment especially if you
want to right around that your
mother-in-law was supposed to run the
thermal grease Martin Luth to not run
any other machines such as sin taxes are
Emily there's this is very simple
techniques and boxes is extremely simple
detecting virtual machines is simple as
well and doable and detecting Ellis
machines as well
boxes can be detected by 3% books
because of a loss of behavior of the
machine itself of the user data that
should be on the machine original sin
taxes never their interaction with the
machine of this tells you that you're
running it is
boxes being used by human but more
importantly especially if you're right
part of the lower the target's you're
after
usually home watching us you know you
want to target the specific entities
with the company for example the company
uses specific software used one specific
security products they have specific
network settings you find the right
moment the kids try and make it
impossible to ever LA's these pieces of
my principle which I found smilar only
starting to use this but actually
inspecting 16th 17th and 18th of this is
a very simple very effective means of
two hundred and boxes and housing it so
she plans to target specific company you
can such a simple method were just check
for the teacher mother just execute in
the time frame where you expect your
instructions have been sent another
meeting after its not controlled is able
to actually follow this logic and I
promise you
which this is kind of things he was just
our cat and weighs just sheen's a
beautiful match for this was just a
couple still because it's run as show
extension as I can have a means for this
assistance with a Cheshire cat was
loaded with an icon for specific file
type of temples and only run there in
the context of the program manager the
program manager is the windows show the
predecessor of explorers and explorer
and when the show them the Explorer
program was introduced before that
sometime around when those three points
11 and if not detect this and it
wouldn't executed on the system
on the lookout for security tools for
execution so even a drum time when is
already infected or the running it was
still have really contracts if there was
not referring if there was any other two
running behind her execution detect them
over if detective security products
which does not show specific part of
functionality we would not stop running
but it was also not show it was actually
supposed to do
versions of the product
think about it yet occurs gathering
security settings from Kaspersky
products which means the new before the
referendum over that target of Kaspersky
products installed at a call for a very
often find checks for any other security
product so far as we know what kind of
systems they were dealing with
Mr Cameron 5 singer persistence which
two things create a registry key for
being loaded adult start or through the
service which effectively is another
registry key which looks similar to the
two mrs. Lucy or over again and I've
never seen actually coming with more
than two different positions me that's
what your membership eros want to be
persistent memberships the system very
fucked hard to do this if you look at
selling
affecting several different executor
wasn't worth all this trouble system
even better would be to keep up with all
possible that there are and combine them
to not depend on one single person but
that's a roll back of my thoughts
sure the kids running on the system is
responsible for this was back up another
point of self over which would create a
watchdog which would watch the infection
with infection too damaged in fact the
machine will go on and inject a credit
check code into which did nothing else
watching the inspection work the
following recent backup within the
kiddos running through your texts at the
same time it was dropped and cracked
version of itself on the disc and could
imagine what stocks would run the
context of nothing else than watching
this coupled with the musical still up
if the music's was gone which means that
infection of the curve was removed the
threat rather go on this decrepit Andrea
infected machine infection was up again
this is a very simple very simple method
to assure the infection is not removed
any security number six thinking in
layers before usually when I try to
always be slower I have the protection
for their have the impression that the
Packer McMurray through another payloads
delegate the payload does this is
something that I can always doesn't work
tomorrow and usually this is very clear
x86 this is because most others are not
experience riding mower but they're
expensive writing software then use
third-party software to encrypt the
railroad and to protect the mother was
not what he should do the simple middle
/ right here on the actual office
caterpillar triggers there's another
problem if you use a third-party
contractor likely being detected friend
of our software just for using drugs can
identify Capello's so you have a binary
and you kept it with a customer service
which create 10,000 copies of your
similar with doctor as soon as I
restarted the people the memory still
looks the same like a binary as
accusatory is able to
detect them or their problem so I'm
staying consistent evasion is the key to
success would be fully undetectable
after I spent a lot of time on as well
as a contractor go on and give the User
Options to like just check boxes of anti
tricks that runs in the binary and rub
the binary in Visual Basic Editor is a
basic visual basic supports pic code
which is it's a disease is a pain in
years
peak of america's decision of botnets
before it came out its my code which is
interpreted by the Visual Basic virtual
machine will be interpreted by the
vision machine and their visit to see
the bike old which you can tell lies
because there's a documentation for it
doesn't accommodations for pickup
however the script her kids these days
because primaries but other than that
it's a transit scripter
execute our stuff afterwards for the
does is it creates
new process or Chris remote threat to
run for this point in time when the
process is clear that you can be sure of
the payload is actually the group that
there's always the case descriptons work
this week so she can manage to get
executions of the points by process
instrumentation you can just go there
and pick up a child from me at that
point I'm when it's gonna be 13 simple
to pass by
because I told you confiscation is very
difficult to analyze it is cold for
static analysis is closed impossible
because you have to go once and
disassembled the code yourself is your
disassembles feeling you have to go
through the code which instruction is
actually real and which instruction
this is under control during application
how's your strength at the time code to
the winery is nothing worse than having
a five-match series four point nine
megabytes are just look like for doctor
but actually doing nothing effective in
the boundaries of event to trigger
division of Univision later you don't
have a particular version of throughout
your primary abusing structures there or
either like object-oriented code is
difficult to analyze a lot of structures
to binary that you have to go through to
actually find the productive code inside
the binary and this is another packed
with this is like the C++ and implement
inheritance of dependencies of your
classes then you automatically create
lot of cult of structure called the
binary but the reverse engineer has to
make its way through
write again very very strange Cheshire
Cat Cat again
constantly monitors for security
products doesn't have a layer which but
it has the basic functionality built in
built into the payload it will have nine
different soon cease contact but in
large doses of times they would be like
this time between contact the census of
its cause no noise on the perimeter of
the network the internet settings of the
machine and all about these and other
settings to not only while contacting
its didn't support the options that are
collections you still have the dial-up
connection you're going to see very well
considerate and all layers of operation
how to be evasive least common in
beauties communication to the interval
be done in this approach process so such
a cut would start an invisible instance
after default browser and inject its
since the communication come into this
browser instance to have the web browser
talk to a remote and I'll catch any
attention of security number
we're almost there monolithic design
build a stand-alone binary to infect the
system should should have its framework
911 call jobs but have different viruses
different components different plugins
do the dedicated work this hard easier
to our place it piece by piece and it's
more flexible and more evasive to have
different components invading the
computer to a certain extent in invasion
chance because there are several
different instances of itself the system
and has multiple instances of itself
running almost all the time which
communicate with each other and as much
older versions have a driver component
which would do the protection of the
watchdog functionality of the mower
fostering development seen as soon as
his ass people after missing off Samoa
which is going to go up their own
protection for example for this new pink
is gonna come with with the bar and
their functioning Trojans with a
framework component which was already
first they were being installed to
target systems and then decide which
plugin which plugin for the next you can
see the very sophisticated plug-in
installation just pluck new
functionality into
framework installed the system didn't
didn't actually get the Droid with them
with a string of the station however you
can see there's a lot of equities and
Muslim nation state power which doesn't
come as stand-alone binary but as a
platform and then just choosing picking
the functionality that the puck from
once to add
fears over that's more than all but does
the same things over the region
companies have become smarter overtime
and have been trying to detect these
things things are happening over and the
region so dealing with stupid skinny
engines and twenty years ago actually
have smart security to build smart
security presence not only in the cold
but also behavior and it just does the
same things over and over again at some
point even if we're gonna have a
presence detect the behavior that's
repetitive behavior so this way we can
decide which is moving announce fears
are known as few as remembered a run
something advanced biofuels and moved to
tears
execution at a like Words With Music
speakers virtual machine execution use
of pain from the reverse engineer
because you have to go through the
vision machine actually find out what
Europe so the codes is trying to do you
have to manually allies washing machine
code and put the pieces together that
should be doing based on both coasts
from from where E is still a flirt
region engineers are you won't find many
analysts
security solutions which are able to
analyze the spindle kids running kernel
even if the colon chrome is not that
smart as you will see looking for some
things running kernel are but the safer
side than the usual and book isn't and
never dare to actually touch biased
because I don't know any security
company nowadays which can actually
watch our biases secure any other
component then was running on your on
your hydration something that was smart
but that's a particular office PC
Rebecca under try to fire on industrial
control systems were basically built as
cervical and architecture so you have
your clients which are you human machine
interface will talk to an OPC server so
the the basic Windows application
windows Server PC server which would
translate the input Fri July two actual
system now I have no idea of industrial
systems and tell you straight up an idea
of ICs are good and when those reasons
she found out when going through heroics
is that her PC thing is still only
Windows API so you're able to read the
documentation when you will have no
trouble at all
analyzing have expanded its component
what is ICS coupon did though was caused
a lot of media attention of people cause
havoc slick very sophisticated I think
it's not because you just went through
their Android API calls and
another engine of my mother was measured
before but he would come with a lower
interpreter which would parse and
execute Lua scripts which is installed
on the system and download the scripts
which told what to do the following
where you have scripts that are being
done all the money plain text format
usually embedded into HTML so any
security solution will just see website
being down those from and not an actual
buying these were being put into the
likud threats which would then the
scripts to the lower engine engine with
interpret the scripts scripts invoke
functionality that was embedded in the
loo and present the scripts with
corruption do was injected behavior into
the into the body under this regime
change my behavior agenda but just going
back into the study compiled code after
interpreter just picking whichever
function they wanted to have this way
but he could be doing is owned by the
changes flavor
at runtime free stuff free because
scripts are in this case it would not
catch a lot of attention right this
weather makes people making that
shouldn't be so let's reconsider points
if you want to write good number of your
brain areas are you want to see that you
don't have several machines in fact that
he's pushing out of your building but
that's hard to live your regular updates
that you update your brain research and
conservation but nothing like once an
hour or once a day but maybe once a
month or maybe not a specific time
frames at all engines don't believe the
facts don't want to fall same name all
over again for signals be detected by
security solutions you want to be
sensitive to the environment around you
might want to think before you write who
is actually the target we want to 221 in
fact i just want to see how you can
prevent
resistance to consider democracies and
machine even if security software
inspector by area or the persistence you
might want to see
onto the machine vision and ideas of
what makes my life harder
and another thing about from
architecture lot of 13 but the set of
images by which helped each other out
and all secure about their positions on
the machine and you might want to touch
on those fears because this is what we
saw the reverse engineer the most
obvious together let's see the hairs are
putting this again the 700 families you
see a lot of the the Chancellor is
really empty the blue squares indicate
that was performing these such as the
music and you can see that for example
like the story and didn't have anything
physical have a target that had some
interesting bits but and are highly
priced French Spanish mother wasn't that
the physical either leading the pack are
evil bunny showed her how to put up the
most too and I wasn't redirection
interesting though the side just told
the empty
amount of 56 million for the course you
don't have to be the most sophisticated
the most successful closing of us get
back to stocks and whether they're put
all of the presented my families and
give them writing is absolutely faces
complexity than we have susan have a bar
which are somewhat interesting and we
have said so it's been a really good
person or from my point of view the most
sophisticated 10 bunny and write the
stock centimeter I hope you get
information about how to how to make
your mobile better future and give me a
hard time in Dallas actually I
appreciate complex more actually is more
fun which complex thing so I thank you
for your attention if any questions I
think there's time left
let me sorry we have microphones walk
around
so the amide my first true my first
reaction is a person that I don't know
that this is more like to thank you for
the cookbook you shouldn't do this you
shouldn't do that you actually want
people to make their you want your job
to be more challenging yet this is my
secret desire to have over as you get a
noise they are gone I could you fix this
before I have to sit here with a
personal contact to actually playing
so yeah because that's the select the
second part of his life was there
something that should have been on here
that you you still used to detect things
that you didn't want to tell us because
you don't have something about pocket
rocket sure a lot of stuff to talk about
but there was one there was one column
that no now we're all implemented number
three was completely
reported adverse effect on stocks that
did that thing as well like everyone has
to leave some artifacts and system
specially for persistence you can't have
assistance with other she leaving
something on the disc to some degree but
maybe it's possible to expand this by
having you know they did it to this
degree yeah I mean that's not a
scientific approach scientific paper
there's a lot more points than he's 80
to give me a hard time that there's more
to the complexity of his more than than
usual here just about the approach of
how do you can evaluate binary not as
sophisticated as the next big blog post
on the most complex forever
is adding there's probably a lot of
people that would like to maybe help out
with this makes this even more useful is
a really nice start I'm sure there are
people who maybe you can make this into
an open source project or something our
project idea of making a little stunned
that over not sure if you would like to
learn how to build better Miller now
there were questions in the audience
yeah so if you are an experienced
programmer and maybe you have your
source code kind of in a bad way and
don't have really weird kind of
dependencies is that gonna show
program so I wonder how much how many
programs so that the thing I like about
my job working on a specific piece of
malware you kind of get to know the
other personal things going on there
because you see what he did ride with it
wrong sometimes you you see what he
thought would implement specific bit and
you think I would have done the better I
mean sometimes it's unclear what's this
next video did this actually makes sense
especially when it comes to garbage code
when you find one for the code in the
binary dunno
thanks for imprisoned station I'm
impressed I think most guys I guess like
to find their ways behind the shortcuts
behind whatever protection you got some
protections self indicating well I mean
someone dies on me
trials or shakes that that could be
effective to actually
mitigate the effects actually trying to
accept all these predictions that fire
protection of the machine
protection against infection the machine
and the user's state of course of course
countering the controversial sort of
possible to detect millroy actually by
the fact that it trust you what's being
done just that the funny thing is that
this is not pursuing legal thing to do
is just the same as antivirus the text
runs on Packers run some focus on jobs
are not malicious so actually is not per
se in the killing Miller in other cases
it doesn't like 98% of the cases but
then the 2% cases our group is off with
your security solution because you're
detecting their product there is sort of
one another using random Packers and
using virtual machine detection using
all sorts of stuff and they want their
their legitimacy of the products to run
machine in lawsuits threats of lawsuits
against security companies because they
detect this obviously delicious thing
that wasn't malicious after all because
it came with a license agreement
thank you
that cold sure I wasn't quite sure of
the author was serious with what he was
doing or not because it is easy to embed
code unproductive code within the
product of cold it looks as if it were
productive if you just have like blood
for branch which branches which are
always true
is like perfect occasions for replacing
coal in there which is never executed
because the branch always go to specific
way in there the other one they have
analysts like going study for the
Cardinal checking the branches breaking
the code and he plays like interesting
stuff in there you know it's there
forever and analyze all the garbage and
out of us find out that this was like
last time they are garbage colorful off
curves but it was a mother after I would
love curves obviously
examples of monolithic design and no
leverage wondered whether the two
mistakes and no lingering they seem like
they would be at odds
so the layers are speaking about the
Miller that the binary 31 binary with
different layers of the monolithic
design the young have won by three
different countries the most action I
could imagine wineries one caring about
the persistence one caring about the key
logging when caring about the
screenshots dealing and the expiration
on caring about the communications sites
we have different priorities with
different objectives themselves are not
like heavily pregnant triplets did they
don't have this layer of protection
telling you don't have a specific number
traced but look like shit in the
software with a lot of evasion is built
into the binary this usually takes big
teams of developers and a lot of money
that's being put in there which is
usually not brought up with other
criminals but fire national institutions
any specific
talk was very interesting I would just
like to ask you mentioned that sand
boxes are usually I would just like to
hear from you because I guess you spent
a lot of time analyzing kojak Sri detect
and not executed sandboxes how would you
suggest go back to signing a sandbox now
would be actually better extracting the
malware in to execute a friend there
there would be very rich boxes they have
their use as a most members not aware of
the emotions running until I work for a
company which has their own sandbox and
they're pretty successful 44 bitter
moment detection with the combination of
books of behavior and studies teacher
sent box design study analysis and pick
the of the binary and have some big
famous reputation and pick different
information sources about your P's
mother and try to come to a conclusion
with a sandbox loan your last longer on
Wednesday to improve sandboxes like as
you saw your did your mother to just run
a specific date or to search for user
profile with Blake Facebook daughter
which goes back in time for at least a
year like something human something that
the samples can't make up and then the
sin taxes actually and I haven't seen
any study like there is Eliza's which
represent the binary
in the different different level and
managed to follow the execution managed
to find specific bits which could
indicate he's kind of vision techniques
but I haven't seen any of this in two
predecessors smart enough to actually
find click the real things that refined
in the mower
just added just out of curiosity my
perception and a lot of this in terms of
looking at it is that commercially
written spyware would probably be a lot
of times more complex than what I B
correct her on the bed that the
complexity and the economical successes
never really connected by posting the
thing is if you want to survive in the
Masai Mara market for a long time you
need a lot of Asian refineries are being
attacked and your own business week
which have been around forever they have
a lot of development time so there is no
husband continues the developed over
time and still others in fact like
random jeans and deal with random
security solutions also equities after a
specific company with specific machine
specific installations they could be
like sloppy version because the near
there was nothing to be sorry for her
the target so explain where the
complexity is likely a different one
example of a BTU tax I have the
impression that the ruling by someone
who knew how to write divisions knew how
to implement application and he sees
after which was like beautifully
structured and multi-threaded and Lake
very good exception handling in regard
to the future
I'm you see that there was a software
developer there another script so this
may explain why once more complex than
so let's start by giving
thank you very much