all right as you can tell there are two
names on the slides and there's only one
person up here unless you want to be
Sergey Broadus for the afternoon yeah
all right you can do this all right
perfect
so and if you may have guessed my name
is Jakob Torre and I'll be talking about
going from theory to practice and back
again with memes and gifts along the way
and inducting you all into the cult of
lang sec so thank you all very much for
coming as theorists and academics we get
to be snide and kind of condescending
from our ivory tower so exploits will be
patched but lang SEC is forever real
quick who are we or Who am I I live in
Denver Colorado
I like cat pictures and I usually do
low-level security research so
hypervisor EFI BIOS type security Sergey
is a professor at Dartmouth College and
we're both co-conspirators in this cult
of Lang SEC we have an outline so
problem so because there's a lack of
objective and comprehensive metrics and
security and software development
practices ad hoc or cult-like
development practices have occurred so
there's development based on tradition
like this is how the person when I
started at a company told me how to do
it or this is how my professor told me
how to do it and there's a very little
way for us to kind of question that and
figure out objectively is this way
better than another way that someone
else has told us and you know you can
kind of get into these little cult Wars
if someone says VI is better than Emacs
I think you guys all know that
objectively Emacs is better but the VI
people are just kind of slow to get that
right and so that's what we need is we
need metrics to be able to understand
that I think some of the current issues
of today I have issue of highlighted
especially as of yesterday when
basically the u.s. decided it didn't
want to do Twitter or github or the news
basically the status quo is not doing
too great more software is being written
than ever before by a more diverse group
and secure composition of all these
components and libraries is very hard so
I'm sure in the future you know we have
pwned by cloud-enabled light bulb now
it's a cloud enabled computer video
camera so that's kind of where we're at
right now
so keno last year at troopers by Sergei
talks about the theoretical
underpinnings of cyber insecurity it's a
great talk it's on YouTube check it out
it's called my favorite things the field
of Lang SEC basically uses computational
complexity theory to argue about the
root causes of vulnerabilities and why
exploits exist so exploits are basically
these weird machines where data is the
code that the program is the interpreter
for so exploits are proofs of insecurity
and they are just basically Rika siding
how the program should run outside of
the intention of the developer so we
also need a software development life
cycle SDLC in order to take Lang SEC and
put it into practice and that's what
we're gonna try to talk about today so
hopefully after this talk I'm people
will understand what Lang stack is how
it has a crucial impact to building
secure software have a framework to
transition that into practice and into
their development practice for those of
you in the room who are developers who
are developers or write software raise
your hand all right
like three people great so for those of
you you'll be able to recognize
dangerous constructs and avoid some of
these defect prone semantics and I'm
assuming that everyone else is a program
manager right everyone else is a manager
no technical skills perfect you're gonna
get to audit these five people upfront
who are developers and so you can then
use this to sell the the underpinnings
and the theory to increase your
corporate buy-in and get a bigger budget
to go travel to conferences around the
world so all in all this should be a
great talk for everyone so I think as
we've seen for the last 15 years bugs
will happen how you structure your SDLC
basically dictates where in the process
that will that finding process will
happen right the sooner you find the
bugs the happer you are because the cost
goes down and the impact to your bottom
line
we've also seen I think I have 10%
battery life someone whose staff or
excuse me
staff I have 10% battery life so I can
go really quick I have another like 70
slides oh yeah
fantastic so a lot of organizations have
kind of arrived at these theoretical
underpinnings kind of by happenstance
and so we want to make sure they don't
just happen to move away from them
somewhere else so talking about finding
bugs right see how happy all these
people are they found a bug during a
meeting and they're also in a stock
photo so that's why they're being paid
to be happy right but they all found
this bug at the design and architecture
review so they haven't even written a
single line of code and they've already
fixed a bug right this guy I mean look
at him he is thrilled because his
compiler told him he made a mistake and
he was able to fix it now rather than
having to get a bug report and a QA guy
calling him at 2:00 in the morning
because production is down and at Google
they're losing a million dollars a
minute because their ad system is down I
think that's well I have a friend that
worked at Google and he said you're not
a real Googler until you've cost the
company at least a million dollars so
this guy is happy because he's not a
Googler right this guy's in dynamic
testing and QA Quality Assurance and you
know he's hoping that the QA guys are
good and that you know his dynamic
testing is going to get to some of those
code paths that are a little sketchy but
he's not so bad this is not as good
right when Liam Nilsson calls you and
says I have a bug and I'm going to find
it and basically pown you that's not
your ideal situation and certainly you
know bug bounties are good in that sense
that now they're going to least tell you
but you still need to get that early
phone call and have to deal with it
figure it out and scramble resources and
then there's the last case so this is I
don't know for you guys who don't know
recently in the u.s. the OPM which
basically handles everyone's clearances
they got massively owned and this was
the director getting hauled in front of
Congress trying to explain why even
after the Attorney General told her to
shut everything down because it was
insecure she ignored the Attorney
General and just kept doing it so she's
not the happiest person in the room
right now you also don't want to be
hauled in front of the US Congress
probably all right so now that we have
kind of the overall frame of how we want
to do this let's take a very concrete
example so dnp3
is a protocol used
a lot of in like industrial systems and
power control systems and so my
co-presenter right here worked with a
few other folks he had an academic he
had an industry guy and then kind of
like government folk to be able to see
what we could look at if we design a
dnp3 parser from the ground up with the
Lang SEC processes so what is Lang SEC
so Lang SEC posits the security issues
stem from a lack of recognition of the
language and so an exploit is basically
allowing bad input to come in and take
over that process and so the question is
is what do you accept what is expected
in what is valid so our a great example
of this is return oriented programming
basically you're allowing the attacker
to give you an assembly language or
return addresses that then is
reorganizing the execution flow through
your binary and so technically you've
allowed them to do that because you've
created a weird machine or a almost like
an ad hoc virtual machine that is now
running that return on to programing
exploit so we see a lot of this stuff a
lot of fails and then if you look at
some of the things like heartbleed which
we'll talk about a little bit later you
know if you look at the complexities of
some of this code that's getting owned
there's basically it's getting way out
of whack in terms of how complex it
needs to be and we'll see with dnp3 some
really concrete examples of that some of
which we're gonna call poison so anytime
you have a nested length field fields
that have to agree that might have
happened out of order etc you get into
some weird situations where you're
trying to figure out if this input is
valid or you should reject it because
it's possibly some form of exploit fun
facts of the PDF spec you can actually
have the length of an object point to
another length and then that one can
point back so you could basically make a
circle and you can make the Adobe Reader
go in a circle for a long long long long
time so that's kind of an example of
maybe some syntactical poison so a
couple cool quotes right data format is
codes destiny and then the other one is
basically the complex specifications
that managers are creating and then
forcing software developers to use
are complicated enough that they should
be verified using formal methods or some
other form of automated techniques but
basically because they're so complicated
the algorithms needed to verify them or
undecidable which means they'll either
say yes this software has a bug in it or
I don't know and I'll take until the
heat death of the universe for me to
tell you so that's what we're trying to
address so here we go we're gonna start
with a grammar so this is basically what
we want DNP to be able to communicate
and the format for that if we don't know
what that is to start with how on earth
are we going to expect that anyone can
write software for a protocol we don't
even know yeah so then also if the
protocol comes without a grammar you're
in big trouble
and then once you have that grammar then
you can basically start from the very
bottom of these kind of you know little
pieces of it and build it up in kind of
a very iterative way that you can test
in each increment that way you don't
have to have the whole testing
everything when it's done you can test
each part so what do we do to do that
parser combinators so basically we can
start with a really small unit of data
and then we can build them up to make
bigger units imagine like a structure
I'll talk a little bit later about a way
you can do this so you can handle very
complex data structures and I'll talk a
little bit about hammer so Meredith
Patterson was supposed to come and
present but she couldn't the last minute
she was gonna present her work which is
is actually hammer and I'll have a
couple slides in there so for those of
you who really interested I'll you can
at least tell you what it is and then
you can reach out to her so back to dnp3
it does have issues if you want to count
CVEs there are some of them they tested
about dozens of implantation and very
very few had no problems they also had a
set up a special buzzer for these
implementations and they're able to find
more crashes those that had the fewest
defects basically chose a subset of dnp3
so what happens when you have a bad
specification so OpenSSL if you looked
at their parsing it's as Sergei says
pointer salad basically you're trying to
figure out what it was doing and you
have no idea and so in the next slide
I'll show you the heartbleed bug
and then the fix for it and then
basically for those of you three
developers or five developers raise your
hand when you understand what the
underlying issue was and then you can
come up on stage and describe it to
everyone all right
another issue is for asn.1 parsers which
are used in a whole bunch of encryptions
already developers go
so it's something in that one plus two
plus payload plus 16 is greater than ask
to s3 to rrx so clearly that's defined
in some RFC 65 20 section four so I mean
well that's pretty obvious so these are
will be called shotgun parsers basically
it's like someone took a gun with loaded
with a bullet or I guess a shell with
parsers and they screwed it all over
their code so it's like spaghetti but
it's not just tasty and it's full of
lead and will kill you so another thing
complexity is not grown uniformly they
have something known as the Chomsky
hierarchy which describes how different
languages get more and more complicated
and they can handle more and more
powerful inputs like regular expression
is a lot less powerful than like a
Python interpreter fortunately once you
hit a certain level on that as a Turing
completeness you've fallen off the
verification cliff and you can no longer
make kind of very complicated reasonings
about software in any kind of useful
amount of time so basically you've hit
this cliff and now you've fallen off and
now you're very sad let's take a look at
dnp3 so it has multiple layers just like
you know all of our favorite protocols
is it complex so you have you have some
fragments in there and some objects so
far we're looking pretty good this seems
like most everything we've seen and then
what wait a second what what is going on
here and now it's it's getting very
complicated and that's just even parsing
the syntax now let's look in the
semantics I don't know if you can read
this but basically there's like a time
thing that you can add another object
after that this says oh that previous
object that I wanted to read into is
actually a right so now it will change
your behavior of that in the past so
that's not so great
another one is is the date you could
have a time object or I guess a time of
occurrence which is usually the
absolute time but then later on you
could get an object that says oh by the
way that object you received previously
that was a relative time to another
object which you may already have or may
not be we have to look back and find it
so basically you're just kind of
constantly trying to figure out
something and it's a really kind of
awful situation so when we tried to
develop this dnp3 we wanted to try to
make the control flow graph as close to
as possible as what the specification
says we wanted to obviously avoid
duplication and abstract and we wanted
the code for parsing the data only in
the parser none of that shotgunning so
also when we did this we could capture
the true syntax of DMV three because if
you read the specification there's a lot
of very vague words this way we can
actually understand and by going through
this process it can actually force us as
developers to understand what the
specification should say or does say and
be able to ask those questions before
we're hold in front of Congress so a
parser Combinator's this is an example
using hammer so basically you can get a
sequence number and a bit so you have
some number of bits set out there you
have choices or many or many plus or at
least one or more and you can define
your own combinations thereof so here if
you have you know a fragment header with
all the flags in it you can pretty
easily kind of build them up with some
sequences higher and higher and then
combine them all together another
example is this crop object and you can
see the kind of code related to that no
more of that so one of the interesting
things actually the only kind of crash
in our with parser was when you had a
stream that had no objects and we got to
the point where we were trying to think
should this be many or many plus one or
whatever and we kind of made that
assumption but we had to actually ask
that question and so we were able to
kind of come up with that and figure
that out during development time so we
were like that kid yay rather than the
sadder person so anyway so this all was
really great in the sense that we were
able to have this discipline roadmap to
develop it
we wanted to continue testing it just
like we usually do but it's a lot easier
to test as well because we can test each
kind of individual chunk and then build
them all up on top of that so then what
do we do then we had basically two
devices that were communicating over
dnp3 and we were able to kind of you
know break them out and parse them and
then we would fuzz them and basically
observe only mode and kind of see what
would happen and then we were also using
AFL which you guys if you have our turn
of fuzz stuff and you don't know a
fella's you should grab it it's really
nice so basically we were able to fuzz
both with a model-based fuzz or for dnp3
as well as more of a generic kind of
coverage guided fuzzer so our parser
only had that one bug for the most part
as far as we can tell we were able to
get really high test coverage and by
doing it from a specification first
rather than this ad-hoc parser where we
kind of think about what we think the
attacker is going to do and that's the
only state we can encapsulate we're able
to do it in a much more kind of focused
way that helps us ask these questions as
we go along so dnp3 was well-intentioned
and it wanted to be simple but then he
got really complicated when you had like
objects in the future that can change
the objects in the past so that's a
problem but it could be there so
verification basically as I said before
developers are not available not
perfectly we really shouldn't expect
them to be so there's a I think
originally a Russian saying trust but
verify so you can use static analysis to
look for the bugs which we just had a
whole talk about looking for using
static they also look for malware
samples but unfortunately certain
runtime semantics are lost like if you
have kind of dynamic function pointers
or whatever those usually kind of get
lost dynamic analysis runs the program
as is looking through it but you have a
challenge of coverage and also it takes
a lot longer so we had an interesting
challenge in the program verification
automatic exploit generation area so
there was a bug that marked out found I
think in like 2003 2005 in send mail
base it was called the crack at her bug
it was a while loop that was expanding
email addresses and then matched to
making sure that it was matched
in terms of braces and parentheses and
the semantics were very abstracted it's
still saying my battery is now down to
seven okay basically that they found out
is that
I'll just go fast I only went down 3%
and I only have half more slides so I
think I should be good so dynamic
analysis then requires an np-complete
problem to be solved so unfortunately as
the software code base grows it becomes
very challenging so crack at her
basically it was proposed as a hard
problem for verification could you
either develop software that could find
this bug and automatically exploit it or
find this bug and automatically tell a
developer to fix it it was very very
challenging and only recently has
someone been able to actually find it
but they kind of had to know what they
were looking for and it's very very hard
in practice and in general just give it
all of sendmail and say find that book
kind of already talked about parsing
basically where you know you want to
make sure that there's a boundary
between the program input and then the
ones it's actually finished parsing then
you can start executing on it and that's
comes from all sorts of things reading
user input RPC etc etc you want to start
with the specification and then if it's
not compliant you want to actually
reject it like see how happy she is that
she was rejected because it was an
invalid parser like she's trying to kiss
the cat and know right why do you want
to do this because there's a lot of
issues with parsers as they get more and
more complicated so there's a term
called parser differential where
basically once your parsers get really
complicated it's almost impossibly to
figure out if the two parsers that
should parse things the same are doing
that or not so one example is a Bitcoin
was using the asn.1 spec and actually
you could generate a specific
transaction that 32-bit systems would
agree and say yes that's a valid
transaction and 64-bit systems would not
and you could actually fork the Bitcoin
pool after this so they had to fix it
and then wait over a year before they
were allowed to release it because
otherwise they could basically break the
blockchain another really good one is
SSL certificate parsing on Firefox when
you go and you register and you get an
SSL certificate for a website the
certificate uses Pascal strings which
has the length of the string and then
the string and so I could go and
register paypal.com
know
terminator attacker site.com and as long
as that was correct there would be no
problems in the sense that I was
actually asking for a certificate for a
sub domain of attacker comm and most
browsers would detect that that was not
valid for actually PayPal com so if
you're trying to man in the middle
someone that would work
however in Mozilla Firefox they would
assume that that certificate was using C
strings and so it would read the name of
the site and it would stop at that null
terminator and then it would say yes
this is a valid certificate that chains
all the way back up to Verisign or some
other roots authority for PayPal com you
can enter your login and made a pastor
so again we're sitting in our house and
it's on fire and it's all great so
there's a lot of conventions out there
trying to make software more safe so
Misra C is like industry and safety for
cars and they know that there's a lot of
safety critical stuff in cars and so
they actually have built a whole bunch
of tools and code examples for how you
should validate your code bases to make
them safe and if you want to go even
further you can go to space right hey
something happened yeah okay
who'd have thought plugging it in huh so
NASA's Jet Propulsion Laboratory they
have to write code that runs in space
and it's very very challenging to really
go up there and push the restart button
once it's crashed I actually have a
friend that had to disclose a
vulnerability on the Mars rover and that
was quite the coordinated disclosure
because you're talking like 40-minute
round-trip time for radio signals to go
back and forth so they really want to
make sure their code is as safe as
possible
before they ship it out thousands of
miles away and so they developed a
basically a top ten list for safety
critical code and their goals were you
know reduce the defects make
verification easier because again they
trust their developers are good but
they're not a hundred percent and
failable and really when we looked at
these it just kind of happened that they
map very nicely the Lange psych
principles so the stuff that was
developed to run in very weird
environments in space mapped very nicely
and so we're gonna talk about some of
those so some of the top ten so reduce
the control flow complexity as much as
possible
don't use go to like remember maybe
Apple had the go-to fail bug long jumps
and recursion because that makes your
control flow graph in two cycles which
is much harder to verify if you get rid
of recursion you might have an acyclic
graph which you can analyze and then
also it makes their programmers think a
little bit harder about what they're
trying to get done and that might mean
that they put more intent into the
software specifically number rule number
two all loops should have upper bounds
and iterations basically you want the
analyzer to be able to determine
termination obviously some loops are non
terminating it would be really silly if
they made a scheduling loop for the Mars
rover that only had a thousand
iterations before it just quit that
would be kind of a waste
so those loops that you should prove why
they need to be non terminating another
good one rule three basically do all of
your memory allocation and memory
changes before your business logic that
way you can analyze the memory map much
easier and also you can guarantee that
your business logic is not going to
start until all of your allocations have
succeeded and you're not getting into a
weird situation where you've kind of
already allocated half of some structure
and
you realize you have no more memory and
now what do you do do you start
deallocating and you've already sent an
acknowledgment package so they're gonna
start sending the next one so what do
you do also it's really nice if you can
you can use LD preload or valgrind and
basically create malloc this fails
randomly to see how your program can
handle it again for those 95% of you
that are managers if you're looking for
a devious trick that might be something
fun to put in your continuous
integration suite rule seven so this is
a really interesting one you want to
check all the parameters in each
function much like the network has been
designed where you have a nice soft
gooey interior and then a soft gooey
exterior I mean very hard and defended
exterior you want to make sure that a
parser bug doesn't propagate through
where you have something that some
function that's in your input and then
after that it's just deemed trusted
because what's gonna happen is is down
the road you're gonna leave your company
someone else is gonna start and they're
like oh you already wrote a function for
this great I'm just gonna put it out as
a Web API and everything's gonna be
perfect
and so that's kind of a challenge and
one way you can do that is by fuzz
testing and doing unit tests with
fuzzers in your QA step and that way is
you can make sure that your internal
fuzzy or your internal functions are a
little bit more resistant another one is
is listing your use of pointers you
don't want that pointer Sal like we
talked about earlier so they basically
shift problems from compile time to run
time which makes static analysis less
powerful and then forces you to do more
dynamic analysis and I already talked
about the PDF specification where you
can have recursive pointers so not so
good either so really like hammer the
gabble on this strict parsing input data
you should scrutinize it as much as a
compiler looks at the code when it's
trying to compile your code and as those
of you who are the programmers appear
you know that if you forget a semicolon
the compiler doesn't be like yeah that's
ok you probably meant to put a semicolon
there and I'll talk about a more
specific example a little bit later
invalid input must be rejected and never
rewrite that input trying to guess with
their intent is because that means the
attacker can try to trick you into
thinking what their intent is so that
guy right there is the guy who made an
son and basically he had this mandate
and I don't think you can probably read
it unless you're in the front row oh
geez okay
he made this mandate so apparently he's
like known for micromanaging and he just
sent this email out to everyone
basically saying all your data and
functionality must be a service teams
must communicate only through these
interfaces no direct linking reading of
other teams data store everything has to
be a service it doesn't matter if you're
using HTTP core bro whatever these
things doesn't matter and then basically
all of these in services should be
designed to be public facing anyone who
doesn't do this will be fired thank you
and have a nice day
Mme I guess the Amazon employee who
posted this said haha those who worked
at Amazon folks would of course realize
that number seven was a joke because
besos most definitely does not give a
about your day but there's actually
very interesting things here because by
doing this he was able to get Amazon to
the point where he can become a services
company and now you see how empower 'fl
their web services platform is because
he got all of his developers basically
gone threat of being fired to focus on
making everything a public service and
had to think about their data format and
basically put it out there for other
people to attack that's what I like to
call a verification oriented paradigm
you heard of functional programming
you've heard of you know object-oriented
paradigm now you have another one it's
basically a meta development paradigm
how can you make your developers or if
you are a developer how can you expose
as much of intent about what you're
trying to do to the compiler and
verification tools so they can help you
do your job so a quick example if you're
looping aim for the induction variable
basically the variables that change to
be really easily identifiable then the
compiler can do a loop unrolling because
you can actually figure that out and you
can make your code faster you don't want
to overload types because again that
means there's more ambiguity about
certain things
so some certain benefits kind of got all
this stuff here's a graph from some
software engineering book basically if
you are fixing a bug really early on
it's really cheap if you're fixing a bug
in production or operation it's really
expensive you want to be doing it sooner
because it's a better business thing so
all of you program managers you
a good example so for those of you
programmers who maybe want an example
like a little bit more concrete this is
a really simple development trick that
allows you to push a what could be a
runtime bug into compile time so this is
C code not really but basically if you
have a variable and you're checking
against a constant the first one and the
second one are slightly different but
semantically equivalent right you're
there checking if the variable a is
equal to 10 or if you're checking if 10
is equal to a no big problem so as long
as you implement them correctly you're
all good if you fat-finger and forget
about that second equal sign the first
one will compile and now basically
you're doing if a is assigned to 10 and
that means it's going to be a runtime
error or some semantic ambiguity the
second one will fail to compile which
means you're like oh I forgot that
extra equal sign no problem so that's a
really small example I think actually I
from the keynote today another one is
just if you do if and then a variable
you're basically assigning anything
that's not 0 to B ok and as we saw
before that means someone that can
corrupt even encrypted data can then set
it to not zero so reducing complexity we
try to implement the least privileged
principle in the network you don't give
everyone root if any one of you guys
connect to IRC and your username is root
at whatever means you're logged in as
root
you'll get laughed out of pretty much
any security channel so don't do that
but I like to argue that computational
power in and of itself is another form
of privilege and we're pretty much
running everything as root so AV usually
relies on having more privilege thank
you
then malware and it doesn't work if
we're all running in the same level of
computational power so here's an HR that
shows you that basically there's the
Chomsky hierarchy on the bottom and then
your more traditional privilege of user
and admin and then ring 0 in the kernel
and hypervisors and you look at a whole
bunch of different data points and
almost everything is running in the more
powerful side more complex problems lead
to more complex bugs more chances of
error less chance of detection and then
getting hauled in front of Congress so
the rule to limit looping will restrict
your growth and it improves
verifications I have an I Triple E paper
where I wrote a compiler that is
provably sub Turing so you can't
right a non terminating program in it
and we found that a very few
computations actually need that or if
you design your application properly so
you have a PDF reader the actual parsing
of a PDF file should never take an
indeterminant long amount of time it
should be some polynomial function over
the size of the file and then your UI
loop that can go forever because you
have no idea if the users walked away to
get a coffee or is dead right so very
few computations need that if you
isolate things out and then we also
showed like pretty good verification and
security benefits from that and that was
also done manually on the SCL 4 which is
the you I think the only formally
verified microkernel in existence out
there it's open source it's pretty cool
but they did that by segregating bounded
and unbounded code manually and then
doing a lot of verification work so
tools for enforcement it's really nice
to know all this stuff but if you're
like me and you're lazy
you're not gonna do them unless someone
is telling you or beating you at the
stick right you know morale will improve
or the beatings will continue until
morale improves right so how do you do
this how do you encode this into your
development process SDLC so code reviews
function testing QA etc etc obviously
you want to scale for effort right it's
just like technical debt you want to
figure out where you're comfortable and
where your organization should sit you
know you want to spend the most amount
of time and figuring out where you're
gonna be in your specification because
again data's format is codes destiny so
if you can figure that out you're gonna
save yourself a big headache down the
road and then doing a little bit of
dynamic analysis fuzzing unit tests and
then you don't want to get on the front
page there's some tools out there cool
crema I talked about it's open source if
you're curious is basically it's
embeddable domain-specific language that
you can use for parsing it's got a
familiar syntax you can use form of
partial generators but a hammer and Nam
are ones that Meredith is going to talk
about they're designed for complex data
parsing and so basically you can plan
your specification and you can implement
that one example of fail on that is the
IP version 6 fragmentation you can
actually scramble the packets up so long
that it takes a laugh or some kind of
firewall so long to recompile it that it
just has to pass the packet through in
order to deal with the quality of
service guidelines and then
can pass things through so there was a
talk by some Iran W guys a couple years
ago where they would just send a simple
SQL injection that should have been
caught by the laughs and they just
reordered the packets and then the thing
went and right through nail was
something built on top of hammer that
basically allows you to write a data
structure and then it will automatically
generate parsers and generators for that
while rejecting anything invalid so here
we have a really simple example I'm
going very quickly because we're on the
clock
basically you have an employee database
which has an employee name and etc you
basically create this little structure
right here of a person that a database
is basically comma separated many people
and that will automatically generate a
parse person and a parse database and
then a generate person of generate
database and all the structures you need
and looking at this code makes a lot
more sense than looking at something
like that open SSL code another cool
tool is Cle which is a symbolic
execution engine you can gain really
high coverage of code and you can find
crash cases or verify semantic
differences in between certain areas
like let's checking for partial
differentials so what is symbolic
execution basically when you're running
your software whenever you reach a
branch you execute both paths of them
and you maintain the constraints on how
you would have gotten there so you start
off with you know x equals x and you go
down there and then basically there's an
a conditional statement and used to
assume okay the constraints on the
program is that X is less than Y for the
left and X is greater than or equal to Y
for that and say if that false case
crashes you can then solve the
constraints on that and get a real input
that will crash your program so there's
a quick tool I'm going to show you about
that and then I'll get out of here and I
think it's break time so the Pope came
to the US and it's pretty cool he
performed a miracle I'm not sure if you
guys heard about this it's really neat
and I just threw this in there because I
thought it was a funny gift Wow
all right so I made a quick open-source
little toolkit that I'm building right
now to do this some of this so you could
add this if you're masochistic or
sadistic program manager you could add
this into your continuous integration
stuff basically there's some memory
management failures you can cause random
fail
of your memory allocation you could have
a header file that can poison certain
bad things like get s or some of those
ones that are known to cause problems
and then the one I'm going to talk
mostly about is automatic symbolic
testing for parameter variation every
function so basically automatic unit
test generation using symbolic execution
this one pretty easy that one's pretty
easy
alright so clue unit is the name for
that little 90s I know so CLE when you
give it a whole program it takes rarely
will it find every single bug and it
requires a lot of computation we did
this on some programs and you end up
running into an np-complete problem for
solving those constraints and those take
longer and longer and longer like on the
order of you know hours and hours and
hours to solve a whole program and that
can find really interesting bugs where
if you have some state and program over
here that interacts in a weird way with
program over here and that's something
that's going to only be found through
like functional testing or really kind
of guided fuzzing what I was thinking
about doing is I hate writing unit tests
and they're so silly for a small
function is there a way that I could
speed that up and so basically what I
wrote is is a C parser that for each
function in your program it generates
symbolic values that are passed to that
function they execute every branch in
that little function so you're not going
to find in secure composition you're
gonna find just little kind of flaws I
have a demo that I can show you guys
later offline as I'm running low on time
but basically I wrote a program that has
a slight / 0 error in some cases and I'm
able to automatically find it and point
out to where I need to fix it without
having to write a single unit test so
that's something cool it's available on
github and it still needs to some work
but I'm kind of nice
so in conclusion as we're down to our
few minutes all right yeah these slides
will all be posted online I don't know
why everyone takes take pictures of
slides but they're all come out crap I
don't know I was at sissy and there was
like 15 Chinese people with big SLR
cameras taking a picture of every slide
and I told them the slides were gonna be
posted online
anyway so the perimeter grows weaker
Network defenses must shift to more
hardened applications so Alex Thomas has
a great talk at on YouTube called app
sec is eating security one of the most
pivotal lines in it is the time that a
firewall has to make a determination
about whether or not a packet is
malicious or not and whether to drop it
or not it's the same amount of time as a
photon does when it bounces off my
toenail and into my eye and as we move
towards you know forty and hundred
gigabit systems that's gonna get even
even shorter so I'm you know in the
average height but now imagine a much
smaller person that gets incrementally
more difficult and so we have to harden
our applications so my prediction
Nostradamus Jakob says lang SEC is
eating AB sec I think Google's beyond
Corp initiative showed that the
perimeter leads to that false sense of
security thinking that oh I get so K to
do something really silly because I'm
inside my network and that is an issue
that also comes up with an application
security a quote I made up to err is
human to be caught at compile time
divine secondly you're trying to do your
tooling and your organization trying to
add some of this stuff into your SDLC
will hopefully improve the semantic
quality of your applications and the
verification of that allow you to trust
but verify and also for those of you
program managers out there it's not just
for security it's less expensive because
now you're spending less time in QA and
less time dealing with bug reports
because you're reducing bugs in the long
term and then also you can sometimes get
some faster code because the semantics
are more easily understandable by
compilers and currently I would say the
state of software's quality highlights
the need for us to adjust strategy so
with that I'll open up for some
questions Wow okay
and my god
you write some code in Python and
everything's great and then like three
days later it crashes okay if you want
to take some more pictures I have more
links if you want to take a picture that
youtube link and then type in manually
that that hash I have some more -
they're even longer all right well
there's no more questions I think it's
break time and thank you all very much
and enjoy your coffee and free alcohol
[Applause]