now you can listen to me I so well
the my name yeah it's a fiscal
people knows me ask to make at this
person that I
it's a mock they know him as per month
Empire
and that's a look a he is no nasa
Lucille
and a we have some of the members of the
AU that team
I mean we had up
adequately six or seven people now NEA
8 sorry and the
well most of tank with a calm because
most of them are based on the use
so that sucks so
what are we going to that now it's a
what we need way with the lead and a
yaso St Pete
ourselves not you so
a up
so a first thing with make to
make clear is that the okay
so air first thing we want to say it's
what the you there is not
and the first thing we want to make let
it's not I hate based for
and a Wii in by tatler not case the
and connect to come here for a reason I
have something up
hap
no not a fork either thank you for
giving us
cause a this talk
red
in it's our way of paid to say you
thoughts and we don't hate you really I
mean we have nothing to thank you
we make make but jokes but
if that's a its use but jokes so
what this haven't we well we are not an
asset
an attempt to make a him to use s is
sweet
again if they're prolly knows how about
that as much as we
a again to lose usually able to raise
will have to think I'll let you splash
which means
you can ensues what's your packets with
people with me
and their a Sat
us at we understand perfectly that
justice may want to use
with that being said the few that and
they must be able to the soul
and we like them being able to do so
who put everybody so
not lot of basic auditing
well it is a2 but not anymore and they
now we had
doing create quite a extensive cook
leave you spying when we are working on
it
in order to prevent things that channel
flax and stuff like that
and a you sonya comic has to be a review
it
by at least one all that you that the
middle but and a
if it's not quite important to me is
necessary at least 2 reviews
before it's accepted so in that aspect
we I think our best
make well good coat at least is not
contest the cold
we try our best it tickled with you
before we
a.m. policy I because we note that the
ball
include ep can be a serious problem
because
I mean are you said cannot boot the
system for example
that could be something really bad it's
not the into only thing
if there is any other at least it wasn't
a lot but I don't hear that wants to
join us
he can do so you want to use this on
your list was in a sauna tonight if to
their you cancel
and if you honey backs that are related
to you that
on anything not into placed in them will
try to fix them
Philly and there yet it's not a close
play at the need
a if anybody wants the UN is welcome to
do so
so this is just the
you the people that have committed to
maintaining
you does and just making it work
on we have Luca at their
0 I tried to get
Anthony best deal Louis to come here
that he's teaching right now
unfortunately he's been doing
a lot of the work on the build system
you we factored
make file support that
we have for Francisco chronic
already on excess I don't believe
think he made it as well on Matthew
now hi on Tony Forlan
he unfortunately cannot make it either
and
Richard is actually with Anthony as his
student
so in
the way these things work without you
what is not which is the general
direction
meaning okay we do this call we
to read the part put it back together
what we are going to do with that
his well
the usual stuff more or less we want
something that is
simple p.m. and possibly whether it's so
you can read your eyes lead we try to
stick to the Sounders
meaning that we try to get rid of
everything that is
not exactly see GDP expansion on or
something that is quite ACP's specific
bad you can do without
so you that can be a with like seal and
on YouTube its UTC or something like
this:
some people is that we provide that
well most of the people involved are
sort of interesting
this kind of provide alternative so
unalterably Lipsy should Lord
with our project
yes or even muscle more or less
than a the other direction we try to
keep everything a separate this possible
so
if you want to make some match you can
we tried will provide yes
a support for all kernels Sabah for
alway to breakthroughs when it's
possible we do
so if you have something that is a
legacy system
you cannot well update the kernel or
is a quite and also to update all the
rules them
we provide to you way to survive pretty
much death
generic idea
well so short term
it said nothing the there are loss of
gypsies Pacific called we try to removed
them
replace it sometimes CZ sometimes is
while or for we are trying
comp compare not sick okay
we still need c99 compiler that means
that
about you have not that many
opportunities
the mainline are supported yes
okay a can architecture agnostic means
that
the okay we got new goodies
with the new kernel up we know people
that are struck with
then the branch that are not updated so
try to support them for system
nothing okay we got lots of people that
have
large deployment you some kinda
range weird the out we try to support
them
a is not just using you that with
magically solve all your problems
if something is not broken before
our session one warned you all
to stop issued
we tried to yes
so the question was what are we doing
different in that regard
I do remember which session a
more or less track some user like a a
ton there because
a they've force you to
do something actually you won't be able
to complete the boat
because you need some specific feature
yes
up
I mean you US that I did slush you there
was something you want support but we
supported
know what that's about you're saying
because upstream you have to support
such as fine
and it has forever and I think change
their
a single branch
I yes okay when I'm going to tell you
what we have a
to the with about was anther what will
happen to them
the first thing we I'll with it was a
making a pakrats that would work well
gentle that was not your fault
that question to spark a two-fold now
you there
works well in with about you sir and
that's because say
the things we have learnt was the you
the app
hustle be useful what they do that
developers
but in the future we take to improve a
little bit on that aspect
I mean we want to for example a
be able to mark whose as mean particle
at mount points
listen to the government to wait until
the amount so we can wait
and the there before wept like that
tools
at the Fairmont points that are you
there
the
up
awk
up okay YouTube it was him so you once
want to run you to and slash user is not
mounted
and the air and then you have for you to
rules which one to startle to Lynn's
this user but it is not yet mounted what
do you do
well 102 tPSA
the week that also we can apply it onset
by the use at this moment
is keep a key of the rules we cannot
apply yet
because the that he say staff that they
need that is not there
and then apply them a
we X we will execute them are at on on
state but you said his mom
yes %uh attorney you can
X a yes 02 other well
attorney will be in or their
with already aerostat meet but you said
but not with but not with their toast
need bad on
so
we also have wanted up and he meet at
the at most the queue depth that goes
back to the use that stuff
I see you wanna meet and imitate the
to mount you about you said it separated
stuff like that yeah hopefully it's not
not only through i mean their problem
there Benin
on it at the it's not that you that the
style you that problem
but if there is no unit that the and
there is an estate sale like at separate
but you said and we need to play our
best in order to fix it
yeah it's about getting easier maybe
but s put up
the majority of these are but issue with
the gem
dove packard was not with the source
code
this project no working so
you're gonna pics Midori abuse in your
you build up
have a chocolate up
so honestly the
separate user issue really just confuses
the point it just
its a minor right it's a minor separate
thing there are many reasons why we did
this
other than pool superuser reasoning
so
was the rate yeah so
them was a major reason for the forking
it sent it's another slights
attorney prolly the best threesome with
her for the Fort
it's learning no no no I said
leading not let up I I
I think this is like a bizarre with that
though air we have paid to it's a 11
model detail that
and with AP particular I mean
we have lent Lord just by forget the
staff doing
Casey comets and monitor staff that was
so that happy most because was a moving
piece suco it's not working because of
that
so the the clear the issue that I have
with you if it's
really not that you guys for UK everyone
have a scanner
they do point out the things as system
he would support
about system is a likes it seems like
you that supports a pretty useless to
relief I'm
it supports Rd non-stick stuff just fine
and all this kind of stuff
like it's it's like at flight doesn't
make much sense
it's like an hour its for I'd
about upstream well
play a complete their at non all their
apps objectives
I'm getting or
those
short time is for us probably they are
shipped about
is working okay so those are
our short term objectives is not why we
did the fork
the so that that's more or less
okay we are trying our best to get to
this point
if it's a problem of packaging is the
problem of adding that the fork onto
your
biting you are not depending on what you
want
farther later a well those are our
objective if your question is what the
hell you did
for that is far more or less that
okay we can yes we do yes
we want to learn that we will to figure
out exactly what the hell is about
you that that is so strange or so let's
Eric still
just three people here knows that good
we try and that's it the problems that
too many people got this kind of strange
expectation
that we will defeat the EB overlord
right here no we are just learning
and this is ass a pet project that
some people the side that lost huge
important and whatever
is just our pet project we are doing
our best to do to achieve some
objectives
we are trying to actually well the first
point is learning
so we do learn we will probably
break some system if somebody is so
foolish to use it
min
is somebody decide to use whatever
software that is not exactly
ready for the prime time from that
primetime just looking for it
so up we had not say
from start and hate for core we have
some kind of
interesting idea about conquering the
world it is not yet
a we aren't just a
experimenting stuff the easy for you
that could be experimental
a am we are trying our best we are
trying to
be as coordinator in the as
well regular about what we are doing we
try to use the bedspread x2
not me a mess i Justi
the code itself is complex so
we happen to cure it all just because we
want something simple to see
and then maybe put back it together once
we
understand exactly what the cause is
doing not doing
pretty much it is so those are our short
term 'cause
maybe some is does a matter of packaging
some others well a bit more encompassing
says
supporting its Texas them or not
under System is usually fun
you see learn about it and said so
our short everything as simple as
possible
quite stupid we know
and a somebody wants to use it
maybe there is to break or maybe they
are fine with it because
say simpler
said try it contributed
with us said
light
okay death probably the other question
about
okay so ago and
slide on so
one in the things that people we found
worried about when we 40 you to to you'd
have
was a that we would
diverge from you dad and make
incompatible changes
and make it so that
all the stuff that supports you don't we
would split
that we would and just making
incompatible
its but I'll we are aiming to keep
API compatibility with you'd have as
much as possible that
as much as long as it does not interfere
with sum up our
longer-term goals in
its simple
so the when we initially 4q dove
we did it could be factor
because the combine kobe's to insist
Indian you do
was something that we did not
we don't we do not like it being
combined as it was
on we wanted it to be simpler smaller
more agile
on
funny up is
so we've me made the build system than
we found that the
bill system for system to you to was
not area
will all isn't is something silly that
was fast it was
I believe wanted the initial complaints
was that be
had to build system D in order to build
you def
ap decide if the shirt causes system the
laws sugar-coat but since the namespaces
Cindy
well able to call it system the so yes
units
to be a system the at least part of it
at least login stuff
these whatever that is in the shared
directory
we are placed so the question was the
do we build the stuff in the shower
directory assistance you'd
I Wiese I believe what happened is we
dis respected code and its
not shared directory more since just
you'd me restrict
no no no no we don't rename the trick
well we have a slight on that
and yes min
River buildings the same hope
you you turned the the thing on make
filing top directory into a recursive
bill system which basically means
everything directory now used to be
built
and then one step and then you build the
next one rather than everything in
parallel
this was just
up
pack
in and another public so
this is just the perhaps so
I'm trying to get through all the slides
and hopefully most at the slides will
answer some of the questions well
believe you have money questions but the
food system the police will test will
miss
because he is the one that did most of
the work at that aspect
so made a common this image that is you
speak louanne s
on fernald and he will be able to us but
then it was as if up
prolly that and I'll of us together okay
so
for the reason that we 42 others to
support legacy systems
on an we can do that with just beer
configure flag is
its just more mixed up on
legacy I'll the old-style
the you liberals help
so one of the things that we're working
on is
to monitor after and
and monitor mounts so that
when rules depend on stuff that are
within those mounts
we me trigger and I guess we
nationalized
you know rules are whatever or whatever
I am so
and
system up
but we don't
124 system to you to be on
package you want to support things like
a winner CE
upstart other think other in its systems
on
so we so we pulled
Ruth pulling a couple if teachers outta
system D that are useful they're good
that
a hunter on it
I'll
asylum it some time at all his blog we
have someone to call us on me
at the cuff been spread I don't you that
a eat like to note that
Wednesday you there a started
we even got any requests for an
interview
from the media Akali we only got one
party that had not thanked was what it
left them because we were madly sort
that line will stay in the courts in so
a dennis Howlett the pooled
and meets that have been a split old
both able to their
about you that and that at least for the
website with like to play at
021 symbolic you there and they would
have done with like a fairly long it
takes the stand and face the clerk at
once a bombing killed it
that we might have a spat yeah really do
it
that you think and so and
and one month when men and women i sat
on their sites that we are
database for work I think quite obvious
may note that not thats is we have
nothing
a article that I system the on it with
it
we have thinking but the colonized
leonard gays
their network and the
because this is working well up
whether
up
method yeah call so
at they we need quickly it used to
collect some necessities that we had
back then
they were not related to with AP self
some of them were related to call with
packets at the
but the for example a
we want a to her to be let that what you
said
be able to used the last this feat using
the ip was using whole cat memes
okay alt that the pain all for some for
something like two point six pointed to
two with just at the
if they want acknowledge that the one
but the
the two you fight about but at least the
last night they met getting that
would have been a while you know what
this so
would like people to be able to use most
of the universe to
he felt better if they can a well
thats likely ally
it shouldn't be a state like that i with
you that the sensible so
at the interest layouts a police say
our alt way of political that the
principles that they system layouts
and their yeah
half let the their issues as with their
let the blame if the penny on that one
the we want them to be able to you
to use the best patient
at that day you there remove on people
rules
yeah because mostly they're left just
after with it
I mean things like for some but they all
naming or network interface s
and list similar stuff that we
like at least two I don't for some time
it may not work but
we have a plane how I were there and the
then there is the fact that they their
peace matter consistently
and the was there is no longer super on
a stand-alone you there
the we red
that comment on that saying back then
muscle if he if he you will stand by you
now saying in the future everything
be system the and no think there's and
the
with that won't be a separate play it
that that was one of the reasons why
with that the full
therefore but then and their
well will have a lot of useless that
happy with openness
the so we'd like them to be able to keep
you see
then I mean if they using open as the
then there is the copyright yes well
a i think is that and place will miss
them it was me it was my fault
a the SI staff was basically a
really big news from the stir
misunderstand the allows
and stuff like that I say say
we were talking to their I plan it
though on bury some copyright
either I so the that the benetton pee
and poo
when they see him because into the lot
better world calls their
and there when I had ponied up there two
or three
over really have any frequency and
eights while another
detect a copyright here which by the way
you could respond that I
who help lot a because there were
different for months the format
depending on
it's fine and the so
well a finale what they call me really
be call me
a was a pic to my personal brand and
with a one-sided affair
I want to sleep there was people
monitoring how r
any the we were going to
break lows that what people not
returning my branch
which only hope that got me and the yes
and I thought
we never method that met at that the
bathroom
and their networking to maintain them
animated what also the fat than
we've got I lot many I'm on me and I
love affair complaint
up so place I accept my apology from
that aspect
well i think is if you think some belief
that s on their
I'm sorry that a
then
will have to take all the while yes you
know you they're pissed at that
Sally quillian and a everybody knows
that the best way to NOLA Computerworld
the
and the moment this is something you see
it won't work anymore so
the we play it to a similar thing that
that moving pieces of you have the
company that mean
thank you with other morning people who
have and the
we at something that last us close to
the corner
their past week will we play at that
level that because as we could
you know that law holding what and one
the a funny we want to put by
evident that there would be more with
most of the staff that will remove it
and slowly on sweetheart love how it
works
please take into account that you that
be separate without the law
history I breaking the law the fee to
use
and the we have me mean
it's hard for hasta la everything on a
single so we want to go
step-by-step another complaint is that
the level ever
in spfld yell we've taken that I mean
that's not me. we have an experience
that when it comes to that
we have my little to you that before
yeah
when who but any a few things we
probably would have to apply it we
already have some experience developing
further
and a we r it on what we call me would
like to
present-day you pick the stuff like the
one week one week
and really I mean we developer
added
on me I'm 10 p.m.
me our way not the best one always
on 11 but good
little you'll
who would
I worst-case everything got gets
meditate back into
reenact at the bank or if nothing gets
mad at their workplaces
there and nothing has happened analytic
s or vice versa
the other player takes over l1 get a
place to met with their
be you know one and we're a happy and we
pay to be
together that's not a problem and what
that will at that time he felt that I
really hate
a they state that you there is yet to no
I mean hormone first at the scene we
still
a keep commenting using with a hip is
that the view that begin to
in order to make happy Saints like
removing with their permanent the wee
wee
we could meet the super the course in
and that's not going to happen
a do that we need is to get to the same
as the
you that was the intent same as the ps2
Cup
use used to refresh button yeah we had a
lot but so what
I mean that's like the alexei that
everything that I face
its aight by C span the no he set up
itself
personal opinions that may not be the
same deploy it
unfair in general well
yet we are into you to project which
means that we used at the festival
we are into the pillow pet but we are
not be in
so I yeah well I really like that one
yet that definitive solution who are you
said
about it but the same yeah no we had
I mean and that I think that maybe if
they be broken
any after happen battened
what we are going to play is to make it
little problematic for the USACE
as we come from our it may work well my
what a bath with the
by your face I ASA yeah I think it's not
at all
well in some cases
we are going to play our method I'm not
we think it and saying we are going to
play you make
a no
I'm not blow me think that we are going
to fix it please note it down
I don't put we don't premies all we are
going to fix I'll
the case is about you said whatever most
of them I companies is that we are going
to try
and with the hopefully we the worst case
well we get a wall
with about what I but
all so I think
column 12
it is
are yes well I don't quite have
questions but I A would have
something to it this project the UDA
was made the I believe so
that was made for
every this rule to not
listen to Leno it's cold am i right no
okay listen I mean by listen
into a use it so
the everybody thinks Leonard scored
is awful everybody thinks that that
don't know laureates
just it's just that seeing a
some or at least
as the at least some of them well the
thing is
the thing is a there are
many anything as you want to see a local
call
both my workday cafe both from where but
because of the value
any wifi oval opened
okok okay perfect a.m. the ideas
there are some developers out there
in all other distros that are still
interest into
all standards the Hooda and I'm sure
love it
some other than Kyle are usually coming
gandu the
to ask well I need to all our
a a you are package from March
for for you that day I need that that
backagain RPM package well the question
is why not having an alternative
to system the thats
my question we happily
it with of course I mean you are gay
there is a lot of things that are not
the end but that Afghan is them worded
okay
it and they have not done anything to me
modest up but there were you sleeping
pad
the with them yeah
the idea the idea is to have a valid
you have you their system I mean to have
a working
you their system and to be to be almost
I to be honest
as are as i've seen the EU the was was
not quite
well integrated in %um am i right
well I mean the 3
you death no sorry the user
feature slash users feature was not
is not currently working you know that
and I write grant
Japan still being well 'em
good
okay used up okay it works %uh who is
doing the
all the main kal the project with a
moment
first up is the slashers are
I stuff is just a small little feature
that requires the more packaging
coordination than
just a tension some need to call
here and there an a say
is not just saying OK from
tomorrow we will support it because
haven't a number of issue
and the number of issue the non issue is
you're having that you have a server
that is completely set a
okay you can even do without you that
from stops
ok some people need some be at the few
that for
whatever reason than you have to make
sure that that be it
doesn't require lectures are and
it is a simple as that how to do that
you have another
a of late but is not X sock-b_
depending on justice bit is something
that is more ok
all local passing it over yet Anderson
lot of people are still testing us about
it so
okay we will have a look about it
because there are people that are
interested
you know open source 11h
discretion so we got people that are
quite focus on that because that
larger valued at the use whichever
strange architecture
sold they will try to contribute to this
project you want to contribute to this
project Europe we are quite happy to
have you tried
are you interested in cooperation with
other distros
obviously yes the want to be is that
this project is a gym to project meaning
that just into that stuff
no is a gym to project just because so
it's really it's mainly
for other dearest this shows to also
cooperate on
you there if they're interest in make
the if they're interested in making the
alternative with if using alternative
EU death right yes hopefully we'll have
books
involving actually looks that we aren't
able to solve and the for example when I
see that there is a person with you went
to the settlement there
if you also want to have you there and
you have problems welcome to open box
we are going to play our best I'm fixin
and if you want to join the project you
can ask that wanna kiss question
a one last word if you are trying to
call
to seek cooperation other distros how
will you re presented
I believe that's how
d report bugs aka so
we so the origin to project the
source code and most about tracking is
taking place
and get home just about going to have
you don't what
out so initially when we first for the
project
levy try to focus on just getting the
code base
same and working still
we focus mainly on Jan two sons were
mostly gentle developers
we are as we grow and as we get
everything more stable we
hope to work with other distributions to
have you dove working with them as well
okay
new Christian I'm he said you're hoping
for people to contribute to your project
and like you expect that to be or become
a community project and you want to
learn because based am
and you consider working the right way
to you
to work within existing community
project I actually thought about
by well one thing is a question them
which is thought about approaching this
by just
cloning the existing you do making a
Bronx
has your features on it IQ regular
distribution brahms
and then trying to submit those back to
the yeltsin project to space and emerge
requests
and that by also you working together
with with the existing you have
maintainers
and you you actually learn from their
experience before you have to make a
lotta carcasses ever learn
the slowing height weight so up again
respond to this initially at least a so
for the reason that we factored the code
is to
in just make it simpler
I know how to explain a freelance I am
that in
0 yes there are a few patches a
for instance a won the reasons that we
Fort is because
someday except for stuff was not
accepted upstream
as so up
force have well except for stuff my
maybe it's to just fix the Lipsy in
question rather than walking around in
and you said 20 I mean it's just a
question
a ship
other one probe probe project whether
bug actually is usually what
what you mean it such as I mean keep
architectures and in the kitchen where
where basically
the in sync with the current board
them so well their other in its open
source
convicted everywhere sure now earlier
about
yet for if you will a have the problem
of integrating the whole thing
sometimes you have people that are stock
with something that is not
that optimal saw you have to be a
well really sick and yes obviously you
would live to fix the problem
where it is but workarounds are what
make
stuff working up
well the final
group like them
at real-world so
is the same as that water did you some
branches forming every decision I there
has patches to
upstream packages and you know that's
very common way of working weird
distribution different Cesar
handled in the circumstances if there is
a problem with
with packet right on your budget you
know in your lips Ian
in the right place in this region or
whatever or if you need a workaround
you need to put into to you for users
need just because there's
on a crazy situation attorney
we would we like to think of you there
as a pet
that's an awful them I mean that was
compared to change the code buyers
ethical debates and now it's almost
impossible to talk to stop
you there to their a much better
about their weeee work thinking of it as
our own personal for their with the Pats
wanted to see their
so it's not that the fan know what to
say a funny
well came to visit the way because by
by approaching the project in that way
your your you're almost
consciously and deliberately creating
some kind division
rather than working home decisions
always worked for many years which is
to carry these these parties please
upstream the ones that can carry the
ones that they can
in their attention packages am by serb
announcing it
is public project in taking that route
rather than going down
the more traditional its is almost
growing division by
by its very nature well actually
we don't think that working debates
these him
I mean and booking will only pay to be
seen if there is no communication
between two sites
to that have forget that are you now
playing
we are happily train koala bears put the
most that the reason
from our project and we're playing our
best world
to communicate with between us and the
people on you there
at their data it one of the reasons why
I personally
sent an invite to special yet to come
because we want to so that we don't hate
them
but we want to communicate with him did
he just say that
through the re factoring that it it's
almost impossible to
twosome port something from one project
with the other
and idk the ugly KS only happens with
words but also with code
and if you may need treatment is like
making it
incompatible I mean I don't see them
much latest
the biggest changes that it has gotten
more is incompatible with the
initial upstream one thing is that our
project it's a
not directly on but the compatible with
lip as in this sense of fairness that
will happen made
most battering you cannot support about
to collect
was at the bill that another different
areas that they
yes we r play of this is that swept away
and abuse at the you there
because the bases is because same
a broadly is fighting in some parts and
you think a slightly different ones
you can get it done at some lip
yeah but I think you should be very
careful about
if you think of the future your project
should
try to not an edge more division
for very little reason let's put it this
way
well polyurethane I wanna booooo our
best not think based
that debate we are dedicated and think
that their
despite our project being home at the
Munsell something like that
three months old the it's not that that
some sort of
revelation thing out there anyway but no
sanitary the politic knows that there
were no sense
Sat are probably the best thing in the
world
it the worst thing in the world because
basically a that evolution use
they too getting he said fast badly
and but stuff that you saw them Pats and
in bed
you end up with things that are hot to
maintain or cut that the whole thing
or think that about but the I what aim
is that at least when we get to a stable
grant and without
as little changed from you that as
possible history from
with ep as possible okay
hi my name's Michael I'm looking for
them project
for some alteration I mean name you to
probably wasn't the best choice of
for your pro two I'm opposite I'm if
you're talking about your project or the
odd
original project just an observation I'm
so that's fine one is system the
the other issue that year but to just
sayin I mean it wasn't
it was exactly clear when you were
talking about what so
specific get the topic about seles user
or separates less user
I mean I'm coming from baby and there's
also assaults of talk about
how we have to support that and I know
the difficulties that bring so that
entails and
I mean you also talk about kiss and I
think
if you if you look about the idea to
just use the unit
Rd 22 mounts this user and you get you
solve all the
those problems for free but this just so
compelling
or in i mean the the easiest way
obviously is to not
use a separate such user but if you you
just take those two sets
and see which uses are there which don't
want to eat happen
Rd or which don't want to have us less
user I mean there aren't that many
and having to complicate things that
much for such some
II dunno I mean maybe you you have a
magic idea how you solve this
your YouTube rules I mean how excited
you want to do that
do you take the binary look if that
since less user intended for the rules
or
mean height how do you know if a binary
which even isn't slash been
a.m. butts needs resources from other
parts of the system is less user
how is this supposed to work I can't
imagine how
so the Atlanta a couple of questions
there I
won the
I think the batteries back um 12 the
one of the reasons that weeee for is
to support so
at a hundred percent this is another we
want to support as many of them as
possible
I am just france is pulling a number out
of a hat
Cindy you'd have supports ninety-five
percent just
a number um we aim to support
ninety-eight percent
re just trying to get those few users
for trying to support them as best as we
can
on some users are not able to use
and it Ortiz
at mall howard's embedded systems a lot
of the time
from do you really think embedded
systems have complicated layout with
separates less user for example yeah I
don't think so for such as what I'm
talking about
that the set of user no for example will
have a lot of a
you says that absorbs with really costly
not separated but both but the Sims
those people who caught up in the hype
bank getting money that the that will
take like 10 20 megabytes
that they cannot using it sees them
I mean haven't there in bolivia example
that this is the using a bit into
up so what
okay
got some
up a is not a matter
of God you're wasting time or
whatever is just somebody that as this
problem
once a solution
I don't know if his if the guy wants to
work on that
so be it
the the res 1 I think of it this way
so many people has the problem it's 81
and you pose the next person but a makes
a lot of trouble for that one use that
you think that when you said is going to
say good things I will too
you said you know you said you are
having problems with food
you said you're having problems with
hard whether you think they happen
I mean and if you do it by putting
something you are
doing you said about user experience
he is not only going to you not they not
to not to use you pull your
his ass along too sate the worst thing
stonewalled
on your project and if somebody say
something but to him in any
it's not true he's going to be a big hug
before using that
so if at their forty takes to make that
you said
not on the it's not that much this to it
why not less let's make an
another item ally karnal
2.6 point 30 to
yes there are many system that are using
data and our stock
with that should we support them or not
down stories yes
by if we can play not
up
so want one simple question a.m. one is
for the system developers and the other
one is for the UDA
you there developers so the question is
same
and why did you decide to drop support
for older kernels
and why did you decide to put the
super for the current us back in the
wants to go first
so we decide have a tough one
we decided to split
we decided to support the older kernels
because I friend that needs support for
the older girls
thats for the reason
they will have to use as we saw them be
say it that and only used
2.6 points 52
which
arm when you're up root system you
upgrade everything
you cannot always keep backward
compatibility for everything
arm someone who changes occur in all the
time
we break or use both ways digital no
because your crew other packages
you can through you just your
maintainability
things over time is good to drop things
and put away
they wanted to well
Terry that is one example that is
somewhere you could want to
a great you that I left school a few
years but
that West is nice based on this an issue
we can do that
that there could be exploited the other
to get through access by some states
steamy stuff I'm not sure if it was you
that we're def
or different but it was one of those two
packets just at the scene
and the
and the then just for fun okay I know
can I would see you cannot to create
because they
have to stop at King Soopers whatever
and there you have that personal view
that
would you like to be able to
okay so
we have to live so we will discuss
probably side
up the shower nation for that okay
people was some software that uses new
the view that
the trick lies in you you'd have and
they are stocked with that colonel and
the system is like
set the box multimedia staffing you
really want the new version of the
software so what you do
you try to be put up and thinks
all the user submited so everything is
sort of okay and thank you do again for
the other
stop or you Ripple Down and if you
thought
done if you can touch the kerner you try
to toss
the stuff that is the closest into chain
you actually would like to upgrade
soccer analyst and
you that maybe not because by simple
to say one last thing it's underneath
form with
and CyanogenMod 11 it's the florida
point 2.1 percent
and it uses 2.6 points 59 kennel
because their developers of DNA on don't
want to
dated I'm
no it doesn't pass UTEP in there but the
point in trying to say is that they re
that uses that this the needle that can
this because limited it a month after is
a stupid enough not to lose
up
with %uh the one thing like there is a
quite why we don't support that
it's like it's not that we only support
the most recent we support like a couple
of that like back
wanna years or so but I'm the thing is
truck simple clean code that that is
reliable and we always wanna pick
the the problems where they are so in
order to keep symbols
know who you know you have to keep
always the convertibility forever they
like it that makes it
Cody me to deal with if there's a need
to be was always bugs missing is also
it's about the big question about the
test matrics basically
like if you wanna support all the
possible combinations of law for any
worse never
the new explode your test metrics and
you actually need to to to make sure
that all works together
at the same week on reddit do I don't
know it it it's a question of keeping
code simple not like
liked am we tend to not want to have
that many if steps for example in our
stuff
and we're pretty good at that and Ben
for example for the except for stuff
that they were raising
-ism yeah we don't we think that the
acts up for stuff is something you much
better fixin
Lipsy once and it works for every am
tool then I'm vixen every to like work
around in every tool in halves if
doesn't have to configure checks and
have the
the implementation except for its system
the way to work and now you can say of
course
yeah and i know it it's it's basically
we like our coats simple and
maintainable
and clean and then you can read it and
that there's no if Steph there's no side
effect that you can see
there's no non your stuff that we
contest
I want to be sure that when I compile
system deep that that actually
I'll test I'm that is in the system the
tree
but I can't do that if they're the if
deaths and tons of
optional coat that is this is used in
some systems but not on mine
so it's it's a question about about them
and in a way with this to me we are
relatively fast in developing things
and the way we do this is by making sure
that that weekend test
the stuff as we go and and be reliable
in that
if you have all these obstruction code
like it that the same questions about
portability to other operating systems
if you have all the obstruction code in
there and you always need to make sure
that also works on the other parading
system everything so it's a question
about
yeah