right
thank you everyone so arm are we talking
about
Tracy come ulcer give you an
introduction to with the project is why
we did it
from up search began for use cases then
I'll go to the background how's work
present some features some went from
fish deals and future work in a real
sometime I'll present some more
work already done didn't use your work
alright so the main motivation is though
we
you want to tree system calls on
different architectures and different
platform so that would mean Linux
be used the et cetera et cetera as well
as some
into architectures a remark pictures et
cetera business kinda hard I mean
there's a
been
alright so from that we'd better
thank you alright so there is this from
system coco peat race and some
it's implemented in B is the in Lenexa
must be unique systems
but thats not very cross-platform in the
sense that the FBI divers on all
platforms
an architect is which is kinda to be
expected I guess be alright so we
provide system call tracing
and you can begin to system calls and
signals but you can also modify system
calls
which is a very useful feature and you
can even inject system calls
from use goes for it it's you this could
be
jailing processes so you can touch to
reach from process with Pete race
trestle system cause it's doing and
modify them sorry one picks a certain
files right certain files et cetera
arm you can do to spend on if I O which
we
implemented and we can promise you this
later arm
you can still be bugging replaying I or
whatever
you can do some fault injection by
modifying return codes at the system
calls to
savory rush out of memory in Yukon
allocate more memory
and you can too I love being alright so
we went a bit over the top
they're just now with just using the
term system call arm
out briefly explain a system called to
serve fundamental interface between the
application the kernel
and the hard road to reach the current
status through so
the way you can use you can through
contract with the hardware using your a
program
I am examples will be Rome very typical
examples
open right support for work we so
arm we didn't use the beatrice system Co
in Tracy
which is go pretty much the only way to
do it
efficient be from but we provide them
after cleared the woodwork from
other platforms and characters as well
um
songs at work basically with betrays you
I durst start a process and the process
as well please
trace one around during or you can
attach to an existing process
arm and then you can I do to help you
chose to
trap on every instruction sorry
instruction executed by the program will
stand your signal members will be
stopped and then you can do whatever you
want resume
or you can tell it's on the truck bomb
to some girls and signals
which is what we're doing because you're
is very slow in murder me to do it
um it's not worth your Petrosyan
actually POSIX
blue might think that abuse reported
both sexes action no
and well as I said it's no uniformity I
arm
so like a third arm obviously you are
lotteries event-based
so you consume luggage world I'm
tell me something when say that it is
using call this function and then you
can text me whenever you on that
function
the same goes for signals from
well business ample for me into the root
system call
and I'm calling this function you can
check system calls
when process suspended all talk about
this implementation later
and you can pretty reader writes memory
more quickly
most time depending on what your
commitments arm we have support for
both the Antarctic tourism and your
pictures and a room
and we have some bindings for piping
although we were everything in CC
as you can see I'm still alright so how
do we implement
a single injection this is kinda main
cora for work
site from just well you know tracing
system goes
easy arms or reduces when the program
from susan Collins stopped
and then we can do whatever we want we
can change the registers recanting see
instruction pointer Rican singer
stack pointer whenever from points on
and from so what we do is we holders
SystemC arguments are on the
in the register so we can change them
from region system call number:
and on the differences in growth
extradition arguments and 12 system goes
down
we recently instruction pointer to the
previous inspection
which was again system Co and restore
order resistors to what they were before
soldier on actually modify the program
aside from whatever fixins
on wheels to distinguish between
synchronous and asynchronous injections
are you can I just say I want to inject
a system call when we come to it
completes
or you can say he didn't exist in
Callington call this function when
you're done
which is my certain issue everything
from based
program
sorter different ways accessing the
memory when you're treating process
you can do this using a putrid system
Colbert for every word you have to call
that Beatrice it simple which is very
expensive
arm re you can use the special member
I'll
in the profile system which is
relatively fast and witches were using
but you knew some reason kernel for this
to actually write when small
and was very reason grounders also these
two system calls which
allow you to the same thing
okay so from what does what we did so
far we did some more workers with the
basic thing I wanted to
talk about arm so what we want to work
on his memory showing between the trace
unit racer
salute races to program your trees in
your three sir arm
uses for disorder if you say wanna you
wanna chill process
and the processes executing an open call
with some path
and you want to check the participants
found it done another threat in the
process is not anxious minutes with my
change a string assume you said well
there's no clue stream go ahead and and
open the file
so what you should do is computer string
to some save memory location which is
indicated in the process
otherwise it can reduce France's call
emblem
make sure that most it's great to have
been defensiveness cutie opens com
from another big issue is missiles were
read in sport view the
but we're planning to what we can do dat
is though from when a process works in
the next you can set some special
of like which were immediately make
mixed-race your purse
but prices well but it doesn't work
amused D so we've made a solution for
this so we tested an expert but %um you
see
but it should work technically arm
spins a problem especially when you're
in a system calls arm
handling once a single requires for
complex which is
was was quite people have to Mike to the
process which which showed dual do
something
and I'm you can read conversion process
them UAL
be in charge again once a simple
completes its
kinda painful I'm can become restore
especially when you're chasing something
like Firefox
arm and an open research questions how
crossbar from we can actually just
because next was not a funky things
like using different system calls for
basic stuff like networking
on 32 bit that's the from them
64-bit through yeah
that's kind of a problem we can talk a
home in five left broke something
I guess few minutes alright so I guess I
covered
this
is just solution to verifying so the
argument
open and make sure the didn't change
much from thread
alright so this is more interesting arm
when you're running us like that before
system call neutrons created the news &
trailers military abuse team
so you need to execute before to some
colour clone or whatever system
whole creates a process in a safe
environments for which is kinda escapes
so you can attest to the process I'm
most recent
so we did is we checked some somebody in
the
prosper tracing and I am change in
fortune pointer to run into somebody and
you some you're basically
askew 24 call us and the new PID
so you can touch the process and unjust
do nothing and so you with a surprise to
new process and just
modified instruction pointer to move
away from this and the strip
finally like a ser despues an issue at
times and I wrote a small kernel patch
we would allow you to stow
or make good perpetrates not for you on
the absurd and system calls or
when simple doesn't match from Services
Inc also wants a black vest
and that really improve speed if you
just one say only choice you're right
arm it's not biggest employer and I did
in about three days but a
those works
so that's it arm is me and who to assume
fitted with the University of Amsterdam
I'm thank you for attention if you have
any questions and
shoe
why did he cry from his
help how is this different from P tracer
other tools that came before all right
sir peter is a tool we use
arm but Pete Rose's architecture
dependent so
like reading them his different on
architects whose I'm use the
you can read memory fast as you can
trace processes mom
system call numbers are different
architectures and usually when you look
at
programs and do like use betrays means a
report from sarajevo separate platform
file for
like first step is rest of secure more
specific
mission
on a questions
sorry the microphones coming
so it would be virtually a question your
I
I was so wondering whether you will
upstream to buy cheese for Derby trace
this does is call
selection no be interesting to me
personally right arm
world there some rule main problems were
and that is
them this has been tried before this
kind of partisan was
rejects because was incomplete an order
something I think it's called sir
secure computing succumb in the kernel
which does something similar but doesn't
allow you to
unser which symbols you wanna trees
which is kinda
paying I mean for Joan would work but in
general it's not complete yet
so this was more to prove concert was
around the time
I might look at see if I can give it to
me my bottom purple would be very hard
with me like 30 seconds ago from the
show demo well
mine works you know if time for a quick
ago
okay what I will show you is a program
we made which will trace
all be suffered calls and rewrote I'll
like he will connect to a proxy server
other than the actual server
a sub up the socks I for protocol and
unjust
some the room a bite so you can
transparently road all network traffic
on the to secure this moment over
program I'm in a very small
video so I hope its visible but we'll
see
right to adjust from program twice once
with our like
home for switches on cruel which will
return on some IP and then we'll run
with our transparent networking
and you can see the appeal to different
it's a very simple concept but it works
on Firefox and
programs function