K well thank you for coming the stock
was not announced
to in this is why we don't have many
people
a so I came to the 22
since the last time a giver I give this
talk
it is about understanding no internals
to administrate this top didion machines
who
come it can apply to this supply next
machines
in the general case so
why the stalk am
we know that and began is quite
widespread when
you have environment with a lot of
machines
and there are good reasons for that we
have
automated deployment tools easy
customization
administration tools and reliable system
to
to give to to use a
and workstations are getting more and
more
good use case over Linux is to
minor player on the desktop side a
is getting ready interesting to
administrate
Linux latest stop machines
so the easy way I'm what many people do
with that
okay to give you to give you machines
with administrative permissions
and these anyway these Linux users new
targets to begin
began you with a any problem this
themselves
a when you have a lot of users of course
it doesn't scale and you come have any
kind of peace and supports
so a
logical way and a secure way to deploy
workstations to be
really stand on workstations with no
specific permission is given to use or
so
it means you need to add to do the
restriction for them
and a there there is a
saying about a gnome that
it is not easy to administrate I will
show you that it is wrong
and our on the contrary a lot of tools
to make it easier for the industry to
who work
to delegates permissions configurations
and whether so this to be useful for
people who want to ministry their own
machine as well because the mechanisms
are the same but was is a
easier the I will not give
a complete course a over that because it
would take several hours
but I will you entry points where
you feel you need to look at when you
have a problem
when you need to configure something and
then
by digging you will find where is your
problem
so first will deal with the base
plumbing
beef this term with call
going but so long ago but three popular
and
the user settings how to set default
settings military settings
login management password management
networking very important and
run them other stuff that you might want
setup so
I am this these are the focuses of my
talk
a doing 2.0t in squeeze gnome 3.4 in
wheezy
and the the classic known 2.4
also in wheezy the be tough
the to get specific stuff in that but
should apply to
all these longer shins as well so
first plumbing the most basic looming
the one is used by the basically
everyone every
single application know now is divers
what is the birth but the best
a at the base
it is messaging system a typed misting
system
to you send a message to recipients
a and you can pass different
better values with types is very
important
because it is done at a cost up speed so
you should not use the bus
for worth spews critical butts a
your data is safe because it would not
be accepted
on the other side if the type look much
Inc no
it is not use of course that the
messaging system a
percy it is used as the or PC system
remote procedure call so what happens
a.m. is
you your yeah
three you have to buses
who these buses because the the bus is a
place that some tries this communication
so messages will go away to the birth so
you have other system both he started at
Boots a second bus
which he started right before you log in
and/or the
exception and you can start up
system services all session services
which will
reduced our name to simply a
you have two ways for example that we're
gonna go
is a demo which starts at Boots and
release doesn't name
and it is accessible to the name all
got free to stop that network whenever
but
it is also possible to ultimately
start-up
a service so to demonstrate here and it
will be started
you note who I'm so to requests
and be sold for both system the rooms on
for sister session DeMint's so
these are the fis a would be fine what
binary to spoon if you want to access
the service
divers implements basic permissions
management
depending on the to call you want to
make the
you can see these about group is
authorized to make that cool
the but it's not way way be used because
we have something much better his police
ticket
for consultant police ik its
a are the offer basis for the plumbing
consul kate is a demo and which keeps
trucks of users
it knows really you it knows
which user is logged on from where on
what total to me know
I'm work processes it is using
will be spot doesn't work very well a.m.
so the city early sessions comment will
give you
released of running sessions and you
will see that one of them is active
I'm the active cistern has more
permissions and other ones and mmm
for example the the active system will
automatically
get a specific permissions for a lot of
devices
for example some devices were
automatically get
required permission for the user of
the active session and these %uh change
dynamically you switch BT
permissions these appear so
so he's got a.m.
in case he would replace Council kits by
a system the look in the service
a because a lot of problems sconce ok
it's
especially it with no or processes
another just the session concert it's
only knows the process
that started the system while system the
by using C group can though the the
whole session ernie can say
this process belongs to be secure and so
I can give
to these process permissions for the
system
police acute a its this one is not
really
at their own it's a it's a mechanism
where there is a demand but
its its more the mechanism to add
commissions
to the bus it arose for much more
flexible permissions
so it we're up deeper schools so it is
not visible from the application itself
the application uses the birth and
in incentive the system serviced talks
to the police
rubble and the
the throttle a will well as the name say
it will apply policy for the policy can
be fine either by the system
by the administrator or so to
to you the political policy is
in these directories and it can also
look at
were with her the application calling is
ineffective session
so in in this case you will have more
permissions
and it will also be able to ask for a
password for example you want to do
from Peter quick Wales root privileges
in no way with police acute you will
have a root process running on your
exception with
is generally Reese recip for security
disaster
so it was only asked for the root
password in the
in the use the system uses using the use
of police acute agents
so euro the good no matter of getting
agent old name for itself
can act as the police ticket agents to
the
so that the the title books he's
in looks better in them
so police ticket a Los
very easy to tune the policy these are a
few selected examples
for example so
by default you are low to to
shut down the session on should on the
machine on if you are the only user
and this is good for this stuff machines
but maybe
you have machines with multiple users
benefits
who is to say and you don't want that so
you gotta know the active user views or
log on the machine to always being able
to shut it down regardless
%uh with other people are using it to 69
a or you can eugen
delegate one unique group permissions to
manipulate the CPU frequency for example
a you don't want you want to win
benchmarks so you don't want the CPU
frequency to
Kane and the user this way can look for
the CPU frequency using
abandon affect all you can do the gates
permissions
with APT mm and delegate package
installation
to one user so you can do group
user group or a active inactive
selection in to see it
will be much more complicated a well not
everyone agreed with this change
including myself but the advantage the
is that's a in addition to pick a really
fights it will support JavaScript
retreats in replacement but I don't
think we can do without
Calif knife a so
JavaScript a will allow you to set
permissions not only
according to the to the actions
you're requesting butts a
also true the to the permit to us up his
action
so for a good example hero you will you
wouldn't know maybe
to this is the city because he select or
you would be able to say this user can
said if we can see two that that user to
another for
quincy of course issues that's but I
mean you can't dig
much deeper a into permissions
the management and also you can make it
today at Miss
if you move to write too many kinda
sweet fights
in bloom 2.0t and Steve for
replications a user settings I'll be
fine through the well-known kickoff
the d kickoff
works a Ryan
not such a complicated way there is a
library
a there is a Devon would respond by D
Bus
a it used to be spill make about but
seen squeeze
this poem by the bus and the demo axis
is
to the stores of settings
with garth which are the excimer trees
nothing more nothing less and the truth
the store the stacked
through the reason on ordering and you
can have reading the store
over that read/write store and so you
can have a
defaults you look at things and you
can't have another reason the store
on top of that which would be mother
teresa things you cannot
override the settings for
pieces only use now by you flip a few
applications
a I don't think a in wheezy you
you will need a lot of bugle tuning for
2013 machines
at least you can find any 15 we want to
to
to change now a this
is really did you have specific a the
famous are installed in a specific
directory and
the default settings are generated from
the famous
in a specific directory the
you must are the
the description a which settings you are
low Sep this is the command to change
a sitting as a user this is a completely
visiting as a group for all users
should work on all systems and
with again you can change the settings
in a bucket so
a package concert settings for another
package
with priorities who is very flexible if
you want to do
a local packages for your site so for
the the rigidity distribution and this
is a common
the kick off to work minus are
will least you also things the two
concerts
and there is a the will only go for the
tour which
she's a well known for resembling the
the Windows registry way being much much
easier
to use regardless starting with Gnome
to point to teach you settings will make
with to key settings
the it was not finished in to put fifty
two cute because one of the reasons for
not using it for
squeeze in room three D's completes
a three sittings works entirely
differently
a you have the so the the city's I
managed directly by
the you I would like to read which
we'll manage in itself the schemas
am overwrites so it
it doesn't have to you don't have the
but
basically you can already see the
default settings without
them and you can
but you can plug it by default displayed
to the peak of them you can plug it with
cement which stores
the settings but you can also even a
as legacy is legal for example some
people prefer other ex the
excimer store and apparently it works
wouldn't recommend that there are some
cases
where you might want that and Eagle
a this one only has
a by the restores and so there is the
the system by the restore user 1 it is
the specific formats
the which is good BBBB a
it should be should showing promise that
cute appear in the giau
interface soon and the reason for
inventing a former
yet and other formats: which looks a bit
like the
to cabinet or or libraries like that's
East to have type database
exactly like the versace tights so you
can Matt
a any kind of a messaging
including streams arrays
arrays of complex data structures in
peace by the restore
which other former 2.0 the
and the reason for also for binary that
have a sister
instead of XML is that because affects
medical was very slow
so for example let's say you want to
change a
the somoza be simplified because a
will when it is only read only the
library directly access
by the restore with his much faster of
course
uni only need dement right
so you can change the setting using
using the GV settings
cover which is what I with them to users
user
a you have decal for the talk a min
the don't come complain if it crashes
it will crash sometimes but he can be
useful to
look in the tree for a given better
just like with would you go if you can't
you mean the the settings in a packet
so you can you can she put these things
are right fight in that again directory
depart but we do the rest for you I'm
the same holds as with the pic of you
can
you can have stacks settings with
different priorities
a
a.m. a few selected examples so hoping
the different backgrounds
the and the aids you can also set
a.m. nice transition backgrounds which
would print different picture depending
on the time of day
the you can bring back for the
beacons the the desktop directory on the
desktop
from liking squeeze you you
you would have some random trust you can
put on the desktop
you can play the team the
we've big a drawback which is the key to
key theme
has to be has to exist for you to teach
you want it to be three
because unfortunately both versions use
the same
exiting to read a theme so unfortunately
there are maybe two or three teams
that would actually work for gnome 3.4
because you still have a pair of
you to get you a pic asians that we look
really
bad if you don't you the theme that
works for both
a.m. for example what we use
in the cell to to set the default the
the default extensions
the default applications for example we
we enable the the alternates
the user status menu so that you can
shutdown the machine directly from them
said
with Oprah senior hidden key amusing de
Golf
it is a bit more complicated than with
legal to set monetary settings
a but you can you can basically
by thing a system BB
for you creates another system database
and Indies at a base user defaults
just like you would otherwise
but it's the key things defaulted decal
defaults a so absurd the
by former to look exactly the same but
it looks very similar
and these defaults
will b-max to locks
a sorry you set the default
and use it locks together and
when sitting file locks the least
the the settings missed it here we not
beam
modifiable anyway gooey
it gives the same results the than what
you have with you go
but it's a bit located and forget the
call for dates
whenever change the system database so
we're done we use the 13th
a vending
in both from really important piece have
the desktop is the login min ago because
this is where
everything starts arm sometimes
everything and see if it doesn't work
so how does it work
it is a as you can see it you from call
its
the plate of spaghetti because they are
not
of small pieces that talk to each other
and that's
%um scenes version 2.0 twenty-eighth it
it works really the same in you give
people in four for you have them
that's thats unknown def
software an the dement with its poem
slaves eat one slave for each displayed
when many
so at startup it starts one slave and
it's not one slave a the slave into
thief slave process starts x-over
them useful and at noon session mind me
mine will no session
run as a big and medium user why
white a full session on that list a few
selected processes
you ask me because a
what you need is the same as in a full
session you need accessibility
you need to read said to read default
settings
well universe emblems basically so you
start to my
my name also from with many many
processes blacklisted anyway
and one instead of setting up an alarm
window when it really starts one process
the greeter
the greeter or will contain the actual
user interaction
it talks with the slave and the slave
talks
to Pam a new gonna love you
and once you login everything like that
sq
ever love that is cute and you get your
new
X over on the computer and you can talk
from your system too badly jim DeMint
through but the bus
interface which can spawn another slave
on another display
because everything is dynamic who when
you close the display
you would be switched to another one
consul kits is used everywhere into the
inside that's
because a it is the Demoman which knows
were the the slaves and the displays our
own
who is logged on where sodium doesn't
have to be just ordered information
it is go directly from console kits
which is more reliable
for that
so the useful things to do with PDMS
configuring it
so as you can as you could see
there with the demonym so there are
things you need to configure for the
demonym
the they are not lot apps of things
but you will annable yup automatic login
because in this case you don't even want
to run the first
a look in session the
the little to no configuration you can
enable debugging you can enable
like the MCP although it is very
slippery so
don't do that miss really know what
we're doing
don't do that on the interested networks
really
re never a.m.
but the reconfiguration is for stuff
that these run inside the
them minimal session a the supposed
differs between them to win three
because when to use is legal so use it
legal defaults
that the united with you could you can
set them in a package this is how we set
the
to be four bedroom for example the
in them three you said you said
key settings before in the
into the settings from its and you can
also set the
other defaults in a package user
defaults
the which I i mean language social
and the user i kum the the I can you get
from your
near you and your name the use to peace
to be stored in your home directory but
the they were be so this there were some
problems with the
for example all too much mounting
or bankrupted home directories so now it
is thought
in the in the system directory which is
managed by the account service the
service I did talk about account service
which is
another demand tedium users but it's
really a it's both
the internals a PDF almost used to be
part
%um actually so once you've logged on
a UK you have to manage the user
passwords
the this is what the gloom curing does
the book the
what these software does is storing
secrets
the use all secrets because it is run
with the use a session
ES included fights the
will be spies are called hearings a.m.
hearing comes with its own password
the there is a demand which alexis is
the key rings
and it also does the nifty things like
replacing the
new PV SSH asians with the gnome like
probs and there is the
nice special case which is the login
keyring love the look in curing is the
specific ewing
which is uses login password so when you
log in
you automatically unlock the key ring
but it is on you looked in memory
on these use to have safe passwords
so how this works it is the pan with you
a which is cool by GDM at the time a
plugin
with you startup a good hearing but
process the it is very the
a treatise something like a a 28 from
from
main mean from from would just keep the
bus within memory
and when you look into the room session
starts
the demo and it would just get back the
the password early can unlock looking
cuming
when it has to look other hearings if
you set it up
if you set them up you will set them up
by home by default with in using the
login keyring
into a new look at another hearing you
would be asked to prompt
user applications can use the
these them through the either the
lignum hearing library or with a
altered disturbed at Secrets the bus
interface
this interface is supposed to be
compatible between PE
and no all who by had we have
noticed be the strange things a you
when running the reputations about he by
the other way around seems to work
there is also a user interface name
seahorse
too many you're too many your documents
the it just presents you with
information it's useful
when you UT I think it's too
the password for something that was like
that
and it will also manage your just new PC
Keith
its very light sweet into peaceful
Yuki's
and the same time a jury school when you
change a password so it is important for
that
you change your passwords on the on the
machine
using Pam because this will update the
look in curing
a this may look like nothing but when
you have
be network it is often the reef reflex
to say okay password management will be
on the server
and users will have to use the web
interface or whatever to clean the
passwords
you come do that if you want to use the
curing
okay next is networking a
a bit complicated to but extremely
useful
gloom entirely relies on this week when
a girl
the so at boot time
the network with a demonstrated
early talks to directly to the terminal
using the looking into faced
setup connections a
the network whatever them on reads the
you to store of conditions in this
directory
these are text by simple picks fights
which is quite connections to start
the default behavior or when he doesn't
find anything is to start up
the any interface that is not many by
the something you're for example you
have
eth0 confer European if saddam to been
not to be taken over but otherwise the
default is who thought you to be under
but you can change everything is going
to you able
then when the user loads on
it was starts a NetworkManager agents
ever either nm up let's Ingram 2.3 on
classic
or directly notional acts as an agent
be safe and is responsible for
the main user interface with his
demeanor you click and you see connect
to these network
an also personal problems in the same
way as the key ring
for example the network when I got them
a mighty
I need secrets for that connection
prompt the user for the
will be secrets
system connections are always thought
you
user connections used to be stored in
kickoff and now they are also stored at
the same place
Asus as system connections but there was
a permission
a minimal missions management system
that up a little so the
the commission is marked as owned by
User
true instead of being for everyone
and only DRO can right condition for use
with Drew
what you need root permissions to right
conditions for everyone
and the important thing is also that the
agent talks to the key ring them
to stall the secrets securely
so this is the Commission's I started at
boot time an
you can't control them only to have
appropriate
policy get permissions when you can
pre-configured them
which is extremely useful for into
prices
set-ups user connections
well you can give or not the the ability
for the user to start connections a the
default
East who will that anti-sway secrets our
store
for use a connection stick with us
during the curing
but a of course the the the connection
between
becomes attacked to the use or so if you
switch
to another user the connection we
automatically dropped
some people see these are the future a
some people see these are the bag
and it was a it was solved the
very recently in the beyond by the
making the the behavior depends on your
permissions
so if you are a member of those who do
group
or the network
net for but def group
you have permissions to edit system
connections without password
and the agent detects thats and we try
to create system connections by default
which will be shared between all users
but if you don't have this permission
instead if we create use our connection
would be
which would not be shared
a.m. there are some complicated set ups
like system connections but
with the user secrets a NBC's most
useful for the peons
and for the the a to chew doing
one X a
with a vacation mutant repeated the
route wpa2 enterprise or authenticated
if in its
so configuration can look like that
let's say you have a very very stupid
problem
a on only very very bad
company could have such a problem say
let's say your DHCP server returns
a information that is on ebuddy for
Windows machines
butts you want to play Linux machines
and
so all no problem I will override that
used to be settings
yes that's you will also need to connect
these machines
on outside networks where
well the DHCP server we would term
information you need so you can set up
to system connections and external
connections
with his some kind of a default a
so you define an Ethernet connection a
which use you to be me for is 02
an you have to specify the mac address
is to
say that we don't fight the device of
course is
peace you can get caught when you enable
ipv6 but use use
set up another comment from with the
same mac Address
and this one is a
you overwrite everything from that used
to be subtle so you return a difference
DNS different the research suffixes
and the user will be film a with the two
you you're so beautiful ipv6 because
usually when you have such a bad set up
it won't work at the user will be
presented with both
corrections arm will be able to switch
from one
to another in one click it is a of
course to see
a simple example for very bad case
but israel unfortunately the
or the use cases you can present for
your pre-shared key for the wifi without
the user knowing the the key
just not very useful anyway but the
it is more useful than giving the shift
key to the user's
is we didn't have to remember it a but
you can also do a 2-2 that when X
a either with with the machine
certificates so
this will you deploy to certificates on
the machine but the user doesn't
use it Kate but you can also give the
user certificates
in which case you can for your a a 2.1 X
and the user can select the connection
it is because your
but he would be asked for his personal
credentials
all love that's wasting Halloween users
to create all the connections like wifi
to roaming et cetera so it's
very flexible and if you
eat some love you were at the this
morning's talk about it with whatever
there I think a lot of features a like
the bonding support InfiniBand which
will
make all about very revoked also on
service
yeah yeah
permission for important
a.m.
related to networking is the VFS layer
a from so with his name
DVFS no the
this one works with also with the key I
Ribery
he spotted you live and the key I all
over the excesses
the PDF is their mom youth spoon when
needed so let's say
a you are accessing only five a
you are both so not no need to look to
them an attorney you ask for something
else
well the the TV offers them on would do
a lot of things
possible it will the Spohn
on explicit request this is a huge
difference with
e summer you knew order from the
into mounting is explicit so
you ask for example amounts for these
SMB server and it was dark specific
process
to talk to the server you going to you
can start as many
PDF is the process as you need got
started
and as upon request and the same them in
talks to
the leap you film this cutie to the
library
which talks to you the sperm
a new disc is the system them on
responsible for mounting
system devices to let's say you played
a USB device is a a very a
a period you useful keys to see
you def notices the device says to you
these
other you have a device the beast
notifies
league did you a.m. one of the
applications using its
is the new rochelle on them sitting
dement
which has a policy of mounting USB
devices
when there are blood so 0 mount its
police a guitar do you have the right
amount this
yes you have the rights mount and after
being mounted of course you get a signal
that
that's been mounted a.m.
to other interesting things a you have a
fuse interface
for applications that don't understand
the but don't you sleep
giao so it appears in the in
the got his GFS with but leave the
office
directory and notice
knows how to how to tell apart
applications with do
which do know how to exit are those who
don't
for example a benefice doesn't have the
you support so notice was started in
the by giving it the path to the file in
this directory
and it is it would still transparently
access the
the remote fights Libra piece anyway the
used Kia you now so it is
not we don't anymore an example term
with the forgets yes how to how to mount
command
from the command line all love that can
be done from the command line
and
the last part is the palimpsest a
user interface which expose all the
internal
functions so this is for example what
happens when you have a
when you look at the the partitions and
you can control
a almost everything a on these
corporations going to them
your to mounting from a team encryption
whatever
a tons features an
last but not least a missing the noose
stuff that's you might want to know if
you have trouble to begin your
system or deleting permissions or
whatever
so applications for you
used the XTP mmm mine system
use of applications on the user
counterparts this includes
positions that appear in the menus and
applications
that can be associated with the mime
type: this is how you at
a assume a submenu in your you main menu
where you can say beef application
categories will go there
cups
a for printing you have a a
up little legal stuff which is the
cups because keep helper which
complements cups
the because as you know cups is a bit
rough the
to use directly because you have to go
to web interface the biggest hit helper
lost control cups through the bus he
doesn't do all the operations you can do
on the web interface
but it does already a lot you because
you can confer European tourists or
start them stop them print whatever
so
a on it is accessed through the
configuration interface
which season squeeze persistent conflict
printer or in wheezy
the no cultural center and from
the the notification the applets
that will tell you something is printing
be bringing messages or 2.0
as little no more people there is a poor
management interface
you power which is excess directly by
the city's them
the to play the policy the
Council room disposal you'll a which we
intentionally excluded from squeeze
because we felt it was not
ready given the state of some rivals but
which is here by default in wheezy
so bad if a
by default or mixing interfaces so this
includes
what happens when you press the
this that maybe those that is
this interface a is now done through
a both with you only so if you want to
these herbal both with you
a you you have to
so you're you also have to remind that
mixing will not work regardless
it's not of a problem who if you do that
but people who is now ready are required
for mixing
the an interesting setting can be too
if you have really %um multiple use a
machine you can
good for you prosecute to mute the sound
whenever switching users
so with
the is what when you switch users on
doesn't play anymore and you come back
it plays is it resumes be okay
a mmm finals finer things I'm almost
finished
the scripting the home a
which is also something you want to do
when you are when you have a lot of
users who was who often have
a spent by specific stuff it is very
easy to integrate
your stuffing gnome you can scripting by
phone
you can skip no script a
free why would you want to do that we're
them you we have
the real example here a.m.
enterprise proxy which only works with
Internet Explorer
the a bite from cold that bypasses its
and requires the use of a password the
bus were is stored in a computer in
through these on the ice
month so this is where you would want to
interface with them curing
and with GTK in with two starting
a.m. you you might have
the you might want fear better with
Windows servers
so you want your to store
a to look for the the
correct path in the Active Directory and
ask the user for his password
for research and you the same password
for kissing
the the fights petite to try to
so or look at them hearing is the thing
we interface with the
the most on our setups
because the it makes it really easy to
manage
all the passwords you have the you know
in a complex
by sitting
but all love that's is nothing compare
to the work you have to do for
a be infrastructural
the configuring one this top you put all
these all the fittings are told you
you're missing works fine now you want
to have a thousand
15th this is different you needed
infrastructure
who this is just a checklists because it
always depends on the
much you have what you won't the
there was a very nice talk by the way
yesterday about free IP a
the used good example of what's an
infrastructure can look like
so you might want
a demure or from the custom repository
to have specific packages a custom
installation CD
using one of the two available solutions
medium FBI or
begins tomorrow Union Station
printing printing is re doesn't look
like should still be a problem printing
is what would cause you the most trouble
if you want
to to enable its from Linux machines
a.m.
why is that a.m.
you can have you have a cup server
with hundreds of Pringles even 1000 the
printers now
and if you if you do that
the user interface will present you or
other printers and you you you don't
have easy ways to feel to them out
the work through
there is no easy solutions that some
people puts
a lot of principles so you have one
principle for
eat building but it's expensive so you
you put them into two machines but you
have in terms of the two machines with
on the 10 printers a
if the investor who used to work for us
find a good solution but the each week
with berksten cups
baking cups well you can but you will
never
have you back accepted by the upstream
because upstream supple
Apple requires copyright the sitting
room so
thank you up for keeping cups
non-working a.m.
every time you use the network
never forgets a this was stressed by
many other speakers never forget about
time synchronization time
synchronization
the out of sync machines will behave
erratically and many many ways network
by systems
authentication the even printing
the everything with fayed you'll have
been to be a.m.
and you win the most of the time because
none of the solution is complete she
will name a need a solution to
to confer your stuff directly arm new
machines
so that means pets because Pictu or
other imaging solution night salts a
it's very very very vibrant community a
currently
you will need that's traveler machines
and
to to think that I'm not not humble
at all but any who I've looked at root
password generation
because you you don't want to put the
same with possible machines right
and information systems don't deal with
that oh yes yes
you can set up a root password by
default
and heavy transmitted the in clear over
the network
it up so you know have any solution for
with better management
and the same holds for encryption keys
if you decide to
use a a DM creeps to
to encrypt your partitions on laptops
the same holds you don't have
an easy way to generate a key and then
make the user and threat the password
for the ski
et cetera
and that is all thank you for listening
any questions
yes
yeah yes certainly a
be there already uploaded a I will
looking to
the place I
I think they should today I
actual you the an address where you will
find them
starting from today from tomorrow
okay
a
this this address this is my personal
sites
and it is the same for the committee in
Paris so this later would be here by the
way
other questions
well
%uh sorry I love
that no
yeah
have to to talk right okay
okay thank you again