so
lol my name is much and I want to do a
quick shower and demo of
small utility that I have
just open source towards us Justin
tenderly very because I put their
0.1 version today it is called vendors
educator and I don't know if you are
familiar with the discussions
named vendor everything it is point of
view that
if you have a project you should keep
all your dependencies
together in the same repository to be
independent of charge no authority
pulling the source of lying to be
independent of
Robbie James breaking to be independent
of
pipe I being offline which happens
way too often and so on and two may
agree or disagree
are agree partially about to it's worth
moving the discussion and vendors
secretaries have told that to
works with git to make possible to not
on the Inc Lord
the vendor or upstream sources but also
make it possible to keep track of
it keep track of what pieces do you have
where they came from
the in which versions and
what are the local changes because they
are always local changes
it works only with gate it is written in
Ruby so it is available as a ruby gem
it works by creating pristine
orphan Browns for all the upstream
modulus
which means that every module has its
branch
which is on the then merged into master
or whatever branch work on
which also means you always have a whole
list of modules you always have
de France between wat was or should I
download
and what you work with and so on and if
you
ever go through or and a startup
acquisition are any
license compliance audit their auditors
will thank you for that
so
to get started at installed
undereducated RAM
in it gets repository and
the main configuration listen the
so-called vendor file
or if you don't want to clutter or
directory just invent context lash
and RB Antron endorsing
to synchronize to download the now the
Quique de Moor position how it's looks
that Coke works
it's an example vendor file
it gets pop culture Google Books I don't
want
all the dependencies sir just some I
want to download virtual and for Python
on
sample books and something forget
this bit customized it is not a simplest
example bob
it shows that it rocks were third
various kind of upstream modules that it
is
extensive boy just how capable and let's
see what can we do with that
when we try to look at the state us
we see that there are some new modules
and that
met today to offer cool of travel books
cannot be read so it cannot figure out
the dependences
let's try to SEnuke
that the and a right now
this is not a live demo because right
now the vendor educator award download
a lot of stuff and it takes a while but
downloads all the specified modules and
their dependencies
and after that we can see the state owes
that
everything is up-to-date in clouding the
dependences including the call box that
the ones that we specified
depend on we can see that for every
module for every don't know that piece
of software
a separate branch has been created a
separate
tagged in it has been created for every
version or download
and we can see that
the branches are orphan they don't
inherit from muster they include only
the pristine pure upstream source which
also makes it easy to emerge from their
pristine brown trust
different branches of your a project
without
running the risk accidentally emerging
in Psalm changes of
your own called
and we can see that inventor
subdirectory
all kinds of stuff has been downloaded
and
I don't like the the the trial and
beats I want to edit it I want to
have only some of the files not all of
them not all supports groups and so on
does the documentation and a the main
python script
their arses clatter so I changed the
vendor file
I can always add a block call the block
to edit
whatever was no no doubt
I also upgrade the version at
the Schwan or whatever to let under a
ticket or no
that it has been changed
and in the stages our sports the
we can see it is this one is outdated
when we think the outdated model is now
know that it is
always even difficult to and download
something unjust
always download it from scratch into an
empty directory:
no incremental downloads no s you mean
that everything is the same
to be sure that what was don't know that
is
clean original ups themselves
has been downloaded unpacked tagged
as previously and we can see that
carl s files i'd didn't
folder taxing screenshot but a new
attack also has been
crater there
and a in the log we can see that
in the pristine the change walls
introduce into the pristine branch
with a new tag and merged again into
master
so all the changes in models all the
upgrades all the updates
work on the same person branch which
means if you
operate and dependency goal from
virtual and one point age to 1.91 is
when it is released you also have a
clear difference
of Wat happened between the previous
version used
and the current version and issue
introduced any local changers
bullying a new version is nothing more
than a
get March the if you have conflicts you
will have to resolve it box
in I don't think it gets any easier
and the evander educator also supports
keeping track of local changes
for a test I have for changed introduced
a single line change a single command
and I can Ron vendor def
the and it shows me a gift DF again de
France
the for all the branches that are
that half any changers between current
works three and the pristine branch
I can see wat exactly I have changed how
exactly I have diverged from
upstream I can view the same as a
get a log of changes that are on my
branch but are not
on the pristine branch and this is also
good
tool review and keep track of your local
updates after a local purchase of
for wat can be
and enoch work with open source some of
the changes you may
wont sometimes to Porsche to the Arjan
authority
talking about open source if you work on
a single branch
you want keep track of it it will be
hard to untangle
display you keep all the change issue or
and you also stay accountable to whoever
reviews if you're
okay without a license on the model or
not
so that would be it
now is def five minutes for questions I
suppose and a
other and then
the question was how it works with John
file actually
to be honest I don't use it with Japan's
for this if I want to vendor are you
lose a bundle cash from gym
for John file and I don't think it
could be integrated at on the other hand
if you will
who wants to have some a really cost all
murder i'm for example you copy it from
deter from an under these branch and
then at on top of it at your own
modifications
you can just added to vendor file have
it in directory
and point to Jeff I to that directory
this will
this will also work
okay
I guess that's it than thank you