right so I I'm here to talk about
hacking gently so what I did there lamb
before we get into any about I'm Anna
children born an American raised
blacksmith my specialize in traditional
methods it's nine I did a nail I got
completely addicted started classes at
twelve apprenticed at the Hancock Shaker
Village for four years and then ran that
Forge and then I started my own business
in 2017 so why am I here I'm gonna be
talking about the history of steel so
what it actually is on a chemical level
how this is happening because while it
seems a little weird is the parts of a
knife and language surrounding that
everybody knows what I'm talking about
if I say things like education trigger
cancer whatever how those things
translate into real life different uses
for its geometry different temper colors
and their purpose and why you should or
should not change thank you because
that's an option so let's start at the
beginning with history at some point
some guys saw a rock like that
and decided to crush it and put it
through a sieve until he had that then
heated up with coal or charcoal and they
ended up with that weird sponge
okay so that is iron in its most basic
form
in this iron there's an almost no carbon
and that makes it incredibly soft
there's I'm gonna be getting this into
this in a bit
there's a trade-off for spring softness
and for tension and overall performance
and you sort of have to pick which
aligns naturally you're doing at that
moment so here's the that chart ever
attention mainly at this point
commercially available not you made out
of stainless steel and that's great they
don't rust they're easier to make but
they're soft and they have chromium so
adding different things to iron it
changes the effect if you add carbon you
get harder metal in the end if you had a
silicate you get a resistant metal to
things like cracking yeah it's all about
just sort of finding a balance so in
other words but handle tang bolster heel
spine edge tipping point I'm mainly
going to be focusing on talking about
the edge tip today because most
universally useful parts yeah I kind of
doubt realistically that many of you
were going to go
make knives based on this talk but but
you could do is take that one kitchen
knife that you had that's garbage and
turn it into something good temporary
and temporary colors these are the first
thing you looking at if you hold the
knife at an angle you can see different
colors inside the steel lose those
Pink's that ground is everything as you
increase the temperature the color
changes and that's how we engage
temperature because it's fast things
that are up here at the Bluebird ends of
the spectrum are very soft they won't
hold an edge very well but if you need
something that's flexible like a fencing
sword it's perfect Dampier at the 350
400 440 mark that's most chefs knives
they're made to be not quite brittle but
one step below it Japanese knives it's
different because
HG entrence those are the things that
actually make nice
western knives have edge geometries that
are wider they're more similar to access
like this one so that once that's flat
the other side is entangled that lets
you take something that's round and turn
it square
but if you're left-handed you can't use
this axe because of the direction of
that though all the wages are what we're
gonna find on straight razors not really
look like maybe this chisel edge
Japanese knives convex edges and the
edges are the most common in western
knives so how wide we change energy on
tree if your knife that is garbage in
the kitchen is cutting and vegetables at
odd angles or not straight or not even
coming at all
you need to start looking at what the
energy on the tree is traditional
methods rocks basically and
hours and hours and hours with these
things exactly the lower the grip the
more metal you take off in each swipe so
that was 220 and then this one is 8,000
yeah I didn't know they got that fine oh
they go higher do they're really yeah
the Japanese sword smiths have yeah
everything from like 50 to contemporary
methods rely on engine powered
rhinestones
it's the same concept but with an engine
attachment instead of pushing with your
foot or just your hands my problem with
these is that you can heat up the blade
bring it quickly on them and turn the
tip or a part of the H blue do you do
that you have effectively read tempered
the blade in that section
[Music]
yeah Jenny is geometry is as simple as
looking at what existing edge is how it
works and changing it to suit your
purposes if you're cutting through
softer things specially Tomatoes fish
that kind of stuff you want very thin
knife and you want an edge geometry of
around seven degrees your earth yeah
European knives have more of a convex
edge geometry because they're designed
to cut through the bone and flesh as
opposed to soft more delicate things
fish um yeah so sharp inacol sharpening
knives isn't as hard as many people seem
to think it is it don't get me wrong
it's not easy there are a lot of
different methods you can use a lot of
we make it really easy some of them are
a little more complex like these you
need to first match the angle that is
existing if you're just trying to show
them with a lower Crittenden
you're trying to polish the very very
edge of the knife to be as smooth and
shiny as you can because if you do that
you know that you have a very fine
surface requires less pressure to select
or the same
these guys recommend putting coins
underneath the spine if you're nice that
we slide them back and forth it can't
move up or down my only problem with
that is that it fills the pores and
Stemmons we come over neck and that
would adversely affect you as you keep
going up through the grits
it takes practice but you would stop
feeling an improvement in the swampy so
changing the edge geometry and this is
the part where it's actually getting it
to happen you're taking
a knife that has a existing purpose and
breaking you're saying okay I don't want
that anymore I'm butchering more fish
these days so I'm going to take this
young tree make it slick
so first figure out what your actual
angle is not just adjusting in some
direction figure out what you're trying
to cut with it what angle you use and
the action of that modifying it
so the takeaways from this the steel
matters they're kind of steel that
you're nice it's made out of it's going
to really affect how long you can shake
it if you get something that's too hard
and you drop it once you go crack steel
is when you harden it and temper it
there are a lot of internal stresses in
the steel millions of micro fractures so
if you take a piece of steel that's only
been hardened and table that's when you
temper it so raise the temperature up a
couple hundred degrees you relieve all
those stresses the edge matters
check your edge geometry before you
start changing things figure out what is
wrong with the knife through using
it the changes in the knife will sneak
up on you
so they'll think you're sitting that for
six hours not making any progress also
she's totally different and you messed
it up the edge can be hacked you can
take a cleaver and turn it into a
skeleton that's an option you just need
to change the angle at which the knife
is actually terminating knives can be
sharpened there are lots of tools and
ways to sharpen as I said I like
traditional Japanese or Chinese
Whetstone's
I know a lot of people like things like
wicked edge it's a little vice that has
arms connected to it that's very
specific angles like pieces down plate
that works it's fine it's kind of
expensive but you don't need to practice
yeah the trick really is to commit to
learning to sharpen well if you want to
do traditional methods it's gonna take
longer
you build at the end have a more custom
edge than you would if you used one of
those machines and you know for a fact
that not gonna overheat them which is
very great advice
basically what you'll do spend you know
3,000 dollars on his beautiful
that's been handed in Japan underground
or once in us we do it
sharpening well is easier than it seems
it's all about matching the geometry you
can do with your eyes you don't even you
don't need high power tools you don't
need a lecture chromatic graphs to
figure out the exact density of this
stuff you just need to look at it most
of the time and if you know what you're
looking for these things are pretty
trivial to solve I'm going to be doing a
demo on sharpening and I'll be adjusting
the edge geometry on one of the sides of
this knife I sharpen this this morning
just sort of practice but I don't like
the way that the edge on the left is
more convex geometry meaning that it's
harder to make fine cuts and because
that thing's so lightweight you don't
you can do it it's check YouTube check
all these things you don't need to
invest in these kinds of stones you can
start with sandpaper if you take low
grit sandpaper and just put it on a
table and rub it at the right angle can
totally work it's not quite as romantic
as sitting there with wet stones for a
couple of hours but it gets the job done
every paper is what you're looking for
standard aluminum oxide sandpaper breaks
reading
quickly we started running it on sale do
you let the paper at all or oil the
paper paper you can do wet or dry those
stem amines you have to soak it for
around 10 minutes more usually they're
incredibly for us these things are
basically sponges when you look at all
the bubbles thank you for now accessory
once those pores are filled you are you
can be sure that there's enough water on
the surface of the stone to serve as a
lubricant for the steel and also in
traits that you aren't filling all the
little pockets with because that will
ruin your so yeah that's basically my
talk about any questions so when you're
sharpening with the paper yes what is
the best start does it depend on what
we always start at a low grade lower the
grade the more metal in you're gonna be
taking off so unless you have chips
taking out the edge of a knife don't go
below 500 just it's not worth it it'll
take forever if you have chips in an
edge like this or steak or something you
need to go down to like 50 all the metal
up until the lowest point for those
chips basically yeah start to finish
this knife took around 20 hours when I
got it was coil-spring French yeah
well a lot of my knives are made out of
sort of reclaimed materials I take a lot
of garage door opener Springs and use
those carbon content yeah unless I need
to know exactly what how the knife is
going to perform I'm like it's just
yeah
so that one knife in your kitchen that
is absolutely garbage still haven't run
out it's sitting there every time you
see it and think about grabbing it
within your wall all its are that's
because I've had to convex and edge
geometry sheet knives they send the
blanks so the knife that's doesn't have
a handle yet not polished they send
those on a conveyor belt to angle
grinders and they're set to a 45-degree
angle and the knife goes through once
and that's sharpie for that I don't do
that I sit there for six hours you're
looking perfect you can't change it and
that's really sort of a point I'm trying
to get across you don't need to spend
$900 on the knife to get something good
you can go to a thrift store pick up a
$2.00 knife just change it
yeah
and there are if you guys google night
sharpening there's going to be a million
different methods the stuff I'm talking
about today that's not all of it not
even close but what I'm trying to get
across with that changing metal isn't as
hard as people seem to think it's not a
constant material that's always true
to want to change into your purse
where do you get the Emery cloth from is
that just like a poser
yeah even in today's um this I think a
dollar a she it's it's more expensive
than regular sandpaper it lasts longer
for them they go up that her I should
say that fight of a grit like at a
typical hardware store at a Sippel
hardware store you can get at least up
to 1500 grit okay
and that's funny sharp for any
applications unless you're trying to
perform surgery with these knives you
usually don't have to yeah never way I
can tell the stones I have down oh
absolutely
so if you want to figure out what great
it is that's a little bit more
complicated basically just sit there
with an assortment of sandpaper above
the sandpaper rubbish going figure out
what's the same okay if the stone has
waves in it and that's called a special
opening one spot over and over again
where else don't get this Bose that's a
serious issue and stuff and that's an
optional you have to take a cinderblock
hmm yeah knife maintenance keep the
blades try if they're carbon steel if
not don't worry about it
please please please please do not soak
the handles of your knives ever doesn't
matter what they're made out of however
they're connected like the handle
materials connect it to the steel
there's something there that really does
getting wet keep knives striking from
sharp we don't have a good time yeah
don't be this super expensive knife to
cover the food you don't need really
expensive my first to be sharpie you
just need to know some of the ideas
behind it
yeah
so when you say don't soak the handles
for kitchen knives and that kind of
stuff
keep them on with the dishwasher never
put sharp knives in the dishwasher just
don't do it it will ruin the edge
completely like that you can take a
scalpel put in the dishwasher take it
out with this butter knife yes just
buying knives every time in fact buy
them from me being a banker you where do
we find you go online or burn for that
kind of thing I am at Latino Forge I
also have business cards oh oh
absolutely
so for every day knocking hi
yes Carrie do you have a specific angle
that you tend to like more than another
or it really depends on what you're
doing the edge geometry is not defined
by the shape of the blade right
completely separate if you're cutting
cardboard boxes open and you just need
something that will slash through stuff
get a convex edge even if it goes down
you can still cut things with it or with
a super slim edge geometry the whole
edge just gets rounded and you won't
have a good time cutting anything I like
personally slimmer edge geometries for
everything I just had find it easier to
cut through things Wisthoff does
something like a 45 no 35 degree angle
on their knives I do seven so yeah a
little bit of it a little bit of a
difference yeah and again that's why I
don't really prefer the wicked sharp
models they don't get me wrong they're
great they will put a fantastic edge on
any of your knives as long as they are
commercially available in western if
they are Japanese don't even think about
it it's too expensive and
there are too many little pieces you
need to add on where you could just
spend 50 bucks again one of those sounds
yeah the arm to it yes yeah that's all
the knife and yeah that's what I do with
mine I got mine set it right at about 20
25 and it works pretty good but I find
that it does go dull relatively fast
okay and the other the other portions to
consider are the type of Steel that's
being used and how the template was the
temper will determine the lifespan of an
image more than anything
aside from maybe the type of Steel
you're using there are now contemporary
air hardening alloys where you make the
knife take it out you sharpen it as it
gets more exposure to oxygen as harder
and stronger eventually you won't even
be able to scratch it with sandpaper
it just won't happen you will not lose
that edge that's crazy
yeah now the drawbacks to these are that
yep it's a radiator super high toughness
super high edge retention completely
garbage ease of sharpening and corrosion
resistance will probably be pretty high
but at what cost
like right how practical is gonna be to
have a knife that you can never shove it
I have found that the easiest knives to
shove a are ones like these this is not
one piece of steel that three that I
welcome together in the fort there is a
sliver of high carbon steel
and my uh seal on the edges the Maya the
steel takes the majority of the impact
from work well the high carbon steel is
only used to actually get that beginning
cut this is as a result easier to
sharpen and hold much longer
so how do you clean your knives yeah I
used on and this bone you should just
plate
I don't usually clean the handle all
that much okay
unless it's you know you might want wash
it but yeah just by my handles off they
can work they can crack bad things can
happen
yeah oh if you're buying an antique
knife and it is a carbon steel like a
Sabatier or an opening out if you leave
them wet for I'm not kidding thirty
seconds you can watch it rust yeah that
black stuff on the outside of that knife
is actually also type of rust it only
forms at very high temperatures it's
harder than steel itself and its really
annoying to get off
how do you have to get that all well Pat
stone right there rustling yeah yeah
this this green stone is a really low
crit so for that one my high school will
actually have a program where we had to
do some sort of project a service
project to finish graduate I went all
trip and you see them and they this man
like everyone else is doing like you
know aquatic research and climbing the
Himalayas stuff like that and I was just
like yeah classical knives that are made
out of carbon steel and they will hold
an edge longer
oil for the handles it really doesn't
need to do that complex
I used to use olive oil to fix my
handles I think that was I have now
swapped to tung oil which you can get on
Amazon for like six bucks a bottle and
you can refinish forty or fifty knives
of all its greats no no yeah it's mostly
used for finishing pine boards it's like
its food safe it's all natural it's just
it makes the know that my knifes right
there I sand it up to 2,000 for it and
then finished it with that tomahawk
mm-hm and the result is just sort of a
silky feeling it's almost got a little
bit of a tap to that to where you can
feel like it wants to yeah it's easy to
hold on to where you think when when you
say I put oil on something you think
it's gonna be yes yeah now the oil tung
oil takes a couple of hours or days to
dry
depending on how many years you do I
unit like one or two that's good I'm
just trying to
a crane and the handle and it just makes
a whole lot prettier
cleavers you can use them just make sure
they're sharp yeah not absent like
sharpening it's a lot of fun takes
practice my hands are so messed up at
this point I can't use finger print
readers I have a past work I got the
passport before my fingers got so messed
up and I'm lucky but if I try to unlock
my computer just I've never met this
person in my life little bit more goes
in thank you yes that's already here if
you want to do less work don't put it in
the dishwasher
I remember this guy somebody used his
knife to cooking he wasn't
the dishwasher and ek1 it was very
rustic it was so rusty and was swimming
man he was great today's to take their
eyes yeah and he puts no do not for the
dishwasher yeah if you were to take you
don't want these knives and put them in
the dishwasher they would be completely
and you end up having to sit there
yes yeah with a little tiny piece of
sandpaper your fingers from black their
clothes are all black steel gets damaged
yeah that that rust is a later coming
off exactly so you're taking off the top
layer where everything is shiny and
great beautiful and turning into garbage
I sell the knives
I bought these stones from a website
called Koren
ko Rin it's fantastic these are by far
the best ones I've ever used they
reasonably priced you're not going to be
breaking your wallet getting a couple of
these and they will last forever if you
take care of them properly so let them
air dry before you put them back in the
box
yeah so before you use them the Huayra
grits don't soak them in water before
like when you get up to 6,000 7,000
8,000 the stones to war
so water over the top yeah if we could
get stung how many different ones can
you say would be a good number to start
with
for most people I would say one or two
it's funny okay I'm doing stuff that
most people who don't ever have to do
I'm making the edges so need something
you're like little like this if you get
a thousand grip stung you should be set
for catching mice yes yeah okay yeah
it's a mid-range zone
it won't be too expensive it should be
50 bucks yeah
[Music]
what time are you doing the sharpening
different oh I'm gonna be going out
there like now this will hovering around
them oh yeah I've just been doing that
way okay cool