Solutions and mobility non-singing
sub-second one of us all right I usually
like to start off with a really lame
joke so you compare not to life who made
markers table rotting sir cumference so
today we're going to talk about chip
second-level s so we're going to talk a
little bit about what each of those are
going to provide demonstration was
opposing life but I had this dream and
so the first question is why do we need
something like sugars the chip second
and level s well obviously having a
low-level hardware level breach is
nearly impossible to detect and it will
allow the attackers
basically gain irrevocable persistence
to the machine it could obviously cause
the device to become useless
and there's devices everywhere now and
it just continues to expand
thanks to they promoted things and last
but not least it's a lot of fun to be
honest death
so first we'll talk about second place
so trip SEC is basically a a Python and
C based tool that was developed by Intel
[Music]
and so what it does is checks low level
settings the chip level and different
flash memory settings it can be used
there's multiple ways that you can use
chipset chip ii think they can be either
installed on Windows or Linux it is
available and can be put onto a Mac but
there's a lot of additional risk
and they can just also be used as a
sting you can just build the Python
library as a standalone Python
executable and probably the best option
is the executable UEFI shell version
where it's basically in a pre boot
environment and it prevents the
possibility of damaging your lifetime
system but we'll talk more about that so
the basic structure of chip second is
that there are there are two primary
excuse one has the chips at main and
then the others the chipset utilities so
each of those have specific functions
that can be used there's whenever you do
make the compiled of the the chipset
program you have to build out the the
drivers for the OS helper and and that
is something that has to be done
specifically
for Windows and Linux or Mac as well and
it's important to note that when doing
that it will fail if you try to if you
try to run it within Windows initially
it will fail because it will not pass it
the signature check for that drive link
so if you want to test on a system on a
live system without doing the USB you
need to set the configurations do not do
the integrity checking and and then
there's one other setting in there that
you have to say so that way it will
allow you to run unsigned drivers on
there and then there's the specific test
modules so you can see you appeared at
the i/o PCI SPI CMOS there's also three
EFI the BIOS secure boot all of those
are different modules on there
we'll see that during the demonstration
so the chipset main module is obviously
the the primary test used to to run and
and so what the main module does is it
basically will run through every single
one of the tests that comes with chipset
it is a pretty comprehensive test suite
it runs very quickly but it does also
provide you the capability to run a
module by itself if you're not wanting
to test everything or say you have
multiple failures that you come across
and you want to be able to investigate
those further you can then run that for
mostly against those single modules to
get a little bit more information and it
does allow for multiple output formats
specifically the two that it comes
native as Jason and then Matt XML and
and the JSON format can be just the
basic pass/fail information or you can
also record the chipset session and
it'll dump basically the entire test
into the adjacent file and that's that
way you can run that test again to see
if you have
changes to platform
so it does provide a lot of valuable
information about any possible chip
level or abilities like I said Jason and
XML and the probably the most common
thing that you'll see with the any
misconfigurations and the board level
memories so it checks for like if you're
if you have the ability to write to like
the ethernet area or if the flash hasn't
been properly overwritten and leaves up
in the memory space so right here is
just a real quick example by us keith
warren buffett test so you can see here
that it's empty all zeros basically that
demonstrates that there's nothing left
but there are so my demonstration system
which I am unable were plugged up it had
some stuff in the buffer and so if you
take the time and dig in and you can
obviously export that can see what was
in the buffer and and so this would be
important obviously if you're trying to
discover like the bios password or
something all those lines to be able to
execute attack or they also holds like
the secure boot passwords where if you
have if you're using password
authentication for a bit longer stuff
like that so this was just a real quick
from a demo system the s3 boot script
basically the resume from sleep and it
shows there that the memory is
unprotected and so it's also out there
what their body feels and that's
valuable whenever you want to go and
take an additional step into the testing
and discover if you
actually modify the memory at that
location and in this case we'll get a
movement further into it there's a
utility script that you can run and
prove that you are able to write to it
and so that's that's important because
you could then modify something during
the resume where you could again capture
credentials or additional information so
this was the kind of explanation of what
happens whenever he Revathy the
modification test group so you can see
that it moved the termini code to
different memory locations just as a
demonstration that you were able to move
stuff around the memory and and write to
the memory to show that it actually was
not protected and you do that obviously
because in the case of that test it
showing that failed initially but it is
possible that it detects a failure and
when you go to test it further it will
not be able to prove
because just a different different set
up in the system so next is the chipset
utility the chip size utility is a lot
of fun you can do a lot of really neat
things with it but it is very dangerous
primarily because it gives you direct
access to the hardware not just read
access so you can go in and modify
things and obviously you don't want to
go and modify things that you're not
100% sure what they do or you may end up
with a really big paperweight so you can
do things specifically like dumping the
memory into binary files or log files
and you can also dump the variables for
like the UEFI settings and and similarly
you can dump the the key for the secure
good stuff and get your primary key your
CAC
some additional information
so one of the commands of the PCI
command and the PCI command it will
allow you to basically have direct
access to the PCI configuration
registers and through that you can
obviously gain additional information
and and you can modify memory if it's
not properly written the TPM command
will allow you to make various TPM
variables and you can dump that
obviously as well and you use it use
that additional forensic analysis given
some of the recent Hardware attacks it
it is valuable because it can provide
you with the microcode ID for that cpu
and if it's been updated stuff like
that's that way you know if certain
possibilities may apply to it
all right chipset fiddle see if it
starts
all right so I put some delays in there
so I'm basically dumping everything that
Jason Klaus
so that's how fast it actually it runs
crazy fasting you can't see anything
here but it failed the specter v2
that's one
sorry
all right so so when I ran the common
dot CP you got spectrum V 2 module by
itself then I was able to get more
information specifically it provided the
information that Nicorette very
interesting speculation
it's not a capability that was on that
processor and then it also tested at the
OS level asleep server to any
medications in place which they did not
have any I can't really see them read so
it does you know it does say that there
that there may be additional solutions
available but it doesn't give you any
initiative to help with that
and so this was that SP I have a flash
memory access so you can see here that
it says that you know access to the
image and so you can see a thinner that
it does show that was having the reading
access but it also shows it was having
the right access and so so something
like that is kind of important to pay
attention to because you know it is
possible then that arbitrary code could
be loaded into that area of the flash
and executed and you'd be able to gain
some very low-level persistence
sorry five seconds timing was enough to
talk through it
[Music]
so this is the that Sakura booth
variables access controls one of the
test systems that I had did not have
that configured correctly specifically
it was a variable and and so it's the
biggest thing is it's checking to make
sure that some sort of authentication is
required before you can write anything
to a secure but variables and that's
important for obvious reasons and in
this case it has the time based
authentication and so whenever you dig
into that module it basically will allow
a trivial warning if it's not time-based
authentication but it still basically
says say you're ok but the best is the
time based authentication for the right
access
or is it in its source of time is a real
time clock battery dies a ruin
for are you talking about time based
authentication so that would be yeah I'd
be at the source of time so I'm you know
I honestly don't know the answer to my
question that's very good question that
had not been easy so again this is just
showing that the keyboard buffer was was
empty and does not necessarily mean that
it is but it definitely indicates there
that it was more likely
the resume
so I write here with UEFI variables
it basically is looking at the efi
specification and it has basically the
date ways of what that should look like
stored and then it's testing each of the
variables to make sure that access
controls are convenient correctly so the
enemy is non-volatile the vs is moved
time access and then RT is runtime
access and then time based
authentication and then just
authenticated right so so each of those
tests each of us to make sure that they
are configured in accordance with the
efi specification so that way you know
that someone doesn't have access to
certain variables
that the ability to modify those
variables and for obvious reasons you
want to make sure that they are set
correctly otherwise someone could
definitely do some damage to the system
all right and then this next so that
what what's possible right is the firm
our test suite and I just have that in
there because we're going to be talking
about a little bit later so I'll go
ahead and run through that little
segment but then well expound on that
one for later as far as what it does and
so the the firm our test suite you can't
see it but the technique come in
episodes of batch so it's running in the
preset bunch of tests and this is also a
similar to chip SEC but it does Ted do
some additional testing and it will you
know check things like fans and and all
of that different stuff and the firmer
test suite was developed by canonical
Ubuntu and they they have it also has a
standalone live operating system but
we'll talk a little bit later that it's
also included in the planning to do if I
validation on this so you can see here
it does take quite a while to run
and specifically when it gets to things
like checking your computer
wake up scripts and stuff like that the
only thing and when you're doing it on
all the machines you definitely think
that it's reasons because it takes quite
a while is
and you can similarly with this one he
didn't have it dump out the output to a
log file so that way you can take it
offline so just as a quick recap for the
chipset side of it it does have a wide
range of pre-configured vulnerability
checks one thing to note is that you can
make your own configuration files and
develop your own scripts to check if if
you have that understanding that's
something that you want to do like
whenever you know through the main
of the chipset it does show some
additional modules that they don't
include but it was modules basically to
prove out some of the vulnerabilities
and it was showing how you could steal
passwords and different things like that
so so they have written their own
modules kind of and for their own
demonstration purposes I have not taken
the time to do that yet
so I guess more with back legs and
windows as we talked about but obviously
the in my opinion the best is doing the
custom EFI shop because it reduces the
overall complexity and the risk to the
system because you're able to yep so
there's that the short answer is there's
is no however the so I had to make this
for someone and they had the restriction
that it had to be able to be both you
know legacy a me if I boo and it had to
be compatible with their current Windows
system so I just took a Windows PE and
then loaded it in there which doing it
that way is kind of a pain in the butt
but it worked
and
was something that's easier for like if
you're doing this in large-scale right
if you're trying to do this on a network
of devices and you just set it up pixie
with all of them you know it can run all
of those you can make your script it'll
run all of those and then if you wanted
to set up to have how to push back to a
shed or something like that in the case
of I why I did that that's what I had to
do it so it would just run the script
collect everything and then pull it back
off and dump it onto they does one
central computer so that way the goal
was to check all of these identical
pieces of hardware that all came from
the same manufacturer to make sure that
that there that what they were saying
was actually true regarding the memory
configuration yeah how compatible is
this what Intel SGX
so you mentioned yes
so it does it does check for the
presence of SGS so I know it works with
it I haven't done much with the SGS side
of the house but but I know it does do
the detection and and there are some
additional utility scripts that that you
can do some additional
and last it is very powerful you
definitely want to use in this car
specifically the chipset utility so next
is the
Linux unified validation list so kind of
similar to chipset it is also an open
source project it's backed by Intel
it is a live operating system and it
really is kind of what I would consider
a Swiss Army knife of doing the
low-level testing and one of the big
benefits is that it does provide a nice
package full foot as opposed to ship set
where you know it just dumps like an XML
or JSON file whatever whenever you run
this it makes it creates a HTML and has
a direct review of all the results so
it's just easy to navigate
through the results
so level s has several more tools that a
BIOS implementation test suite so that
one is kind of the structure of level s
is and that one is also defined only
it'll run bits first when it's loading
and then it'll has the script in that
bits UEFI or that bits get my file and
at once to the level s if I file to
continue that's how they eat up for more
tests week we talked about it also has
the NACDL so that tool by itself is also
a very powerful tool for managing memory
for the kernel subsystem and and so by
itself you can recur do things like
erase create memory space so it's
something that you want to be very
careful with I've never been brave
enough to try to do anything with it as
far as doing any creating or destroying
of the space because I don't have a big
enough budget to be able
or braking megameters and then there's
the the colonel yet I want so that
Colonel EFI warnings is basically a
shell script that that that looks at
Intel made and it will check your
message bus to see if there's anything
that any kernel messages that might
provide indication of compromised or
vulnerabilities within the unified water
system and then the peace tour test
that's specific obviously the Linux and
it's just designed to record so it is
developed as our end of it basically
leverages the project there are the
three basic configurations and it does
support both 32 and 64-bit the USB boot
is the easiest that boot is very nice
for the situation of if you wanting to
do a you know network based pixie
testing the challenge I will tell you
with with met who is you have to do some
customizations to the OS itself and they
provide you with instructions and saying
that I have not been able to
get their instructions to work as they
have suggested so it's it's there
I'm sure it's due I just haven't been
able to dedicate the time to figure out
what I'm doing wrong and and so
basically the netboot is nice obviously
for that pixie and it'll basically write
results if you have a web server you
could just create this little upload
page profile and it points to that and
pulls everything down that's that's the
idea behind so talking through the tools
a little bit the bits and louse we're
checking of micro code that does support
Python scripting if you want to add
additional testing and level s uses
scarcity of executable test and you can
run it from grub as well so you're not
just limited to
less and it uses Python towards that
exclusion so this is just a screen
capture or picture on the screen rather
showing bits in execution and this is
what it would look like if you ran it
initially whenever you were moving out
less it would give this screen you spit
out all the information about the tests
and then it would carry on to the finish
moving level bus firm our test suite you
know we had run that during the video
there and this is this is an example of
the firmer test viable s by itself and
that level when he run for more to test
me by itself
you can select individual tests to run
or run all of them one of the one of the
challenges especially with one modern
analysis and
depending on how you know the system you
bigger is it wants to do a reboot test
if you tell it to run all tests so it
takes a very long time and if you
obviously don't have the error system
said to the order that that you want if
you just do it one time override then
it's not going to be able to continue on
the test it will twist it or remove it
if you don't catch it I'll just carry on
loading the OS so it's so there are a
bunch of tests that you can't on with
the foot board test week and honestly
how eat you also within the SS that you
decided to build it yourself you can it
uses bitbake since it is Yocto and and
you can go in and modify the recipes for
lamar test suite that he wanted to have
it run different tests and that just
would require you to then compile
everything yourself and it does support
or a it does identify bios PDF i
the errors there's over 50 different
tests and it can execute either with
analytics the libel s by itself or and
and there are some integers of Avoyelles
with chipset which from the verification
standpoint is very nice because instead
of relying just on your chip SEC or just
on just on for more tests week that you
are able to then you know do that
comparison and it's that all you don't
even have to a Warner ability or just
one that popped up as a false positive
so the kernel efi warnings like I said
it's a shell script I just analyzes the
message buffer and it will look for
kernel messages that may indicate
so any CTL I couldn't talk about you you
can create destroying namespace and do
other reconfiguration obviously it is a
very powerful tool if you run it by
yourself or by itself
aim and start to turn around with that
stuff but the the level s basically is
just using it they have scripts built-in
that that check the security
configuration of the non-volatile dim
and so that's like I said I've not been
brave enough to try to do any and
creating and destroying the namespaces
myself but it definitely it seems like
it's a great tool to check configuration
okay so this is just basically the
screen that pops up when it's executing
and just gives you a very basic screen
and it tells you what test is running
and then when it's finished it'll tell
you basically how many tests rain so in
this case it reckons seven
tests of which 97 past 28054 worst gift
and there were also 11 mornings and so
so in this case this was from the from
the USB boot and so whenever you write
the level s it will have the level s
partition on us being that then it'll
also write a persistent partition to
write every all the information yes yes
yep yep and and that's one thing that I
didn't mention about the net boot you
can set it up so that way you can
basically do a net camp when it's
running and get the outputs that way as
well again it's something that is
possible I have not been fortunate
enough to do so
all right so I went a little bit faster
than I should have like this
kind of wrapping things up there's
obviously we we have computer ships and
everything even though even though this
set of tests is really specific to
intelligent there's obviously importance
in testing firmware famine and testing
that low level memory of devices since
it's not being incorrectly gained a
great deal ship second we first talked
cloud was very very very powerful tool
you can break your advice and and you
can leverage those utilities groups to
dig deeper if
if I would've known I had a little extra
time I would have gone through some of
those utility scripts to show how you
can dump that information and just gain
a little bit more information about
systems and then level s it does provide
a great deal of tools to test your
system at the hardware level and can't
be used to fix loop which is very nice
if you're doing it obviously on like a
production line or something like that
or you're just trying to do the testing
at a more efficient manner so that way
you don't have to draw to plug a USB
stick to every computer that you're
testing and it does provide a very nice
report of the findings
any questions going once
thank you guys
[Applause]