welcome to detection as code the
engineering future of detection and
response I'm Jackie Beau
and I will be your panel moderator today
I'm really excited to get to talk to you
all I'm really excited to be back at
b-sides my favorite conference don't
tell the other ones don't tell them
all right so what are we going to talk
about today
we're going to talk about how applying
engineering focused Concepts and like a
software engineering mentality to kind
of the classic world that is pretty
Manual of detection and response
actually unlocks so many possibilities
reduces manual toil and just makes
everyone's lives better
so in particular what I'm talking about
in applying these kinds of Concepts is
and how it makes us better is it helps
us detect actual serious threats to our
environments rather than what tools or
things that we have no control over tell
us is a threat
it helps us automate a lot of the noise
out of our day-to-day
it helps us get faster turnaround time
from detection to actual response so you
can do the work that you need to do to
keep your companies and organization
safe
and also it just means you get to focus
on the things that matter and the
interesting parts
I have strong feelings about this topic
I started my career as a malware Analyst
at a government cyber security
operations center or we'll refer to them
as socks doing manual cue based work and
since then I have done detection and
response at companies as big as Facebook
and as small as 100 person startups
what I've always found is that the way
that we approach threat detection and
response we're Treading Water we have so
many alerts so little of them are High
Fidelity the things that are actually
incidents aren't usually coming through
our tooling we separate out analysts and
engineers and we expect them to operate
on outputs of tools that they haven't
written and they don't have any
ownership over
uh and so I want to share one of my
favorite quotes which is by Cliff Stoll
if you don't know about him I highly
recommend reading the Cuckoo's egg he's
pretty much the OG blue teamer and he
has a quote that goes
the first time I do something I'm a
scientist the second time I do something
I'm an engineer and the third time I do
something I'm a technician I want to be
a scientist so that's kind of the
mindset that we are applying to to this
uh this space
so the good news about all of this
manual toil and work that we do is
there's a shift that's been happening
and I've witnessed it over the 12 or so
years I've been in this field to apply
engineering focused Concepts
and that's what we're going to talk
about today and so for those of you who
don't know me I currently am at Asana
and we have started up our detection and
response program which if you couldn't
guess is engineering focused and so we
focus on a lot of the concepts that
we're going to talk about today things
like detection as code infrastructure as
code automation having really high
quality data Pipelines
and yeah so obviously I love talking
about this area but I decided what would
be better is to get people who are also
doing this work to talk about it with me
and share their perspectives so without
further Ado I'm going to turn it over to
our panelists so they can introduce
themselves tell you a little bit about
their backgrounds and why they're
excited about this topic so first I'll
go to you Louie yeah hey how's it going
folks I'm Louis Barrett for the past 10
years or so I've been working in both
detection response as well as instant
response these days I work in the AI
space in product security as well as
Cloud security I'm basically trying to
marry the two disciplines such that we
get better at building detections using
Ai and get better at security securing
AI using the detection work I've done in
the past really excited to talk to you
today
where are you currently I'm currently a
scale AI leading both product security
and Cloud security
and we're hiring
yes awesome Jessica
oh I gotta get closer to the mic I'm
being told
usually everyone tells me I'm too loud
um yes uh Jessica rezine I currently
work at Brax as a security operations
manager which includes the security
detection response function as well as
corporate security
um and I find my I found my way to the
wonderful world of security and scenario
spawns I started in tech support and
then I moved into a knock kind of a
junior sres type tile style role and I
just loved incidents like I'm that crazy
person I love a good crisis the world's
on fire and I'm having fun finding out
like where the burning pile of garbage
is but that pivot and I realized like my
favorite incidents were the security
incidents and that's how I came to the
detection response space it's like
hopping one crisis to another
um and I'm particularly excited about
this because I've been really fortunate
in my career that when I started out at
in a knock I got to witness the
transition to being less of a knock and
trying to be more engineering focused
and then in my security roles I've been
at smaller companies and had the
opportunity to help build a program
program which like lets me do more
engineering focused stuff so I'm like
super passionate like I have experienced
the benefit of detection engineering
like engineering first rather than the
sock model so that's why I was really
stoked to talk about that here today
awesome thank you Julie yeah I'm Julie
Sparks I'm a security engineer at Brooks
I currently work with Jess and you can
tell we align on a lot of things but
I've been in security for about seven
years started in GRC and then
transitioned over to detection and
response what really interests me is the
fact that you can apply these things
that we like learn about from other
Engineers software Engineers SRE and we
can take that and we can use those tools
to make detection and response more
efficient and give us more time to work
on threat detection and work on security
incidents some of the things that I'm
passionate about something else I really
love is that these engineering first
detection response teams we tend to help
each other we love to open source things
we love talking to each other about
these engineering problems and how we
can work together to solve them so that
maybe we all have the same size team but
the end of the day we're able to work on
more exciting problems and really
optimize what we're doing and that's
just been a Love of Mine
love it thank you all right let's get
into the nitty-gritty what are we
talking about when we're talking about
engineering first detection and response
so first we're going to start with
detection as code which I'm sure many of
you are familiar with this is a switch
to really owning your detection
signatures writing them into a code
repository using classic CI CD pipelines
and the the benefit here is that you
don't have to deal with signatures that
you have no idea who wrote them was it a
tool was it an analyst was it someone
who left your company six years ago and
put six random IPS into a deduction
signature we've all been there
um so there's a record
um and so Louis I'm wondering if you
could talk a little bit more about like
detection as code and why it has been
revolutionary
yeah so we lost that segment we had a
pretty small team and we had to be
detect um engineering first otherwise it
really wouldn't scale so for us we've
really benefited from having our
detections in Version Control allow the
engineers to comment on detections learn
from what people are building and have
more visibility across the team and what
was actually being done while we're
trying to detect it also let us know at
a point in time what were we able to
detect so you could actually go back and
say hey we would have caught x-ray
wouldn't have caught X based on
the detections we'd actually submit the
source control and you know even with
that being in place we could say like
hey if we have an incident come up we
know that we had a gap and we know how
to fill that Gap because we can
literally see you know what that Gap was
written into Source control additionally
it kind of like helps to deal with
crunch as well a lot of teams are under
this kind of crunch work style when you
have small teams but if you're able to
kind of push things through CI and test
whether that your detections actually
work you're less likely to rent an issue
in production where you're then having
to say okay this detection is failing
and we don't know it's failing yeah
alerts that were just generated exactly
why like knowing why is crucial to
detection so like we should definitely
be better at that when we're building
alerts yeah another point I think is
really important is when you are making
pull requests for your detections and
you're storing everything as code you
get the collaboration aspect that other
software Engineers benefit from we're
able to provide feedback work together
become a better detection engineer
because everyone on the team is looking
at it or at least a subset and you guys
are working together on what makes a
good detection and then all of that is
like historical like saved in the code
like the repo request and can be
referenced by people who are onboarding
or who want to learn more about what
you're doing
yeah and I think like the big thing
about detection is code is it offers
consistency repeatability collaboration
and things are just better when you have
that like you you know exactly what's in
your environment it's like just the next
step to being more mature in the space
is like you're not you're not expected
to write something sit look at all of
the data in the future be like oh what
would fire and in a traditional model
that's like kind of what you do you
don't have the tools to test what it's
going to do in sort of your seem prod
and still until you do it
um and it's just like a massive step
forward in maturity to be able to store
detections in a repository anywhere and
not just in whatever logging system is
running them for you totally and
speaking about maturity I think I would
be remiss to not talk about
infrastructure as code kind of this
concept where we're actually building
all of our Cloud infrastructure our data
pipelines our product in code so we have
again this like source of truth of what
infrastructure is set up what is it
going configurations and I mean one of
the big benefits of that is disaster
recovery right like things get blown
away you can send them back up but I
also think for us as Defenders it gives
us so many steps forward in
um like our processes because if we know
what infrastructure should look like
when it's drifted and also like we can
accurately threat models so much better
and so just yeah this is this is
something that's also like a little near
and dear to my heart is like
infrastructure is code it's just what
you do now and if you as a team are not
doing it you're behind your team's not
technically mature you're not really
sitting to play at the table with the
big dogs if you're talking to another
team that does infrastructure as code
and you don't it's like this is just a
core table Stakes for an engineering
team to do and like of course a
detection Response Team should be doing
it
yeah but there's and there's so many
ways you can do it
depends on what works best for you but
you need to be doing it be an adult put
on your big boy pants yeah it also comes
out like getting the respect of the
engineering teams you're going to ask to
make meaningful change if you're not
kind of like you know being toe-to-toe
with them and their capabilities let's
be frank like they're not going to
respect you as fellow engineers and we
can't really call ourselves Engineers
within security unless we're building
something contributing the way a
software engineer or infrastructure
engineer would
right yeah I think there's also like the
ability to scale up and down
um depending on like your pipelines
whatever alert
alert payload your handling
um there's a lot of these benefits that
come with having infrastructures code
and being able to add and subtract
resources as needed yeah it makes makes
your life is an engineer easy too
because you don't you you have an idea
of what's going on in your environment
you have those yeah absolutely I
remember one Friday evening of course
because you should make breaking changes
on Friday evenings always I blew away
all of our IM configurations in AWS but
thankfully terraform
so it's really a savior
oh yeah I mean I don't work for Hershey
court but
um so when you mentioned pipelines and
so something that we have to talk about
when we talk about detection and any
kind of threat detection is we're
operating on so much data so many
different logs from different places and
so there's this concept too that Julie
we were talking about about data
engineering and having like a really
clear process on how you're processing
all this information and storing it and
how you use it I wonder if you can yeah
so maybe this is my hot take but I think
that detection and response should have
more data engineering skills whether
that's having a data engineer on your
team or just having detection response
people that are familiar with data and
can work on these pipelines but at the
end of the day you're not going to have
good quality detections if you don't
have the data to write those detections
on so data quality where you're able to
ingest logs from understanding what
those logs are and for a lot of teams
that also means understanding the load
of data you're going to be bringing in
and whether it's cost efficient for what
you're going to need in an incident or
whether you're going to need for a
detection further on so I think focusing
on data engineering as a problem and
something that can really up uplift your
detection work and making that like a
foundational piece is really important
at Brooks we we open source substation
which is a way to deploy serverless data
pipelines to collect logs we are able to
collect logs store them pre-process and
post-process after they're enriched and
so that gives us the benefit of being
able to store the data have it raw but
also be able to perform any
Transformations we want on the data so
maybe we want to add certain role
enrichments we want to like make custom
hashes based on certain patterns and
then we can utilize those in our
detections but all of that can only
exist because we have control over our
logging pipelines and what happens to
our data and does anyone have a story to
share of like what it would have looked
like trying to do that if you had a
scene instead of like controlling your
own data pipelines it wouldn't have
happened
because you just don't have access to
like some vendor has sort of given you
this box and they go here you go it does
all your logs it does all your
detections but they don't give you that
control to get in and actually see how
well they're handling your data and they
might not be doing it very well and you
could just be stuck with whatever their
slos slis are yeah and I feel I feel
like we've talked a bit about kind of
this like build versus buy
um mentality and I personally feel like
there is a balance between sometimes you
do want to buy vendor Solutions but you
should have a framework or a way that
you're thinking about what you're what
you're building versus what you're
buying and so I'm wondering for any of
you have like stories about where you
made that trade-off how you think about
it
yeah I think there's this underlying
concept that
you have way more flexibility to build
if you have teams who have also
engineering like like skills otherwise
if you're just if you have a team of
analysts and they're working within a
tool you're kind of just going to buy a
new tool for them to work on but if you
also have Engineers on your team who are
building the tools that you use to do
the detections like that's kind of where
the magic happens and build isn't even
possible in a situation where you're not
focusing on engineering first no 100
true I think we also need to like
kind of nudge vendors to build tools
that support the ability to extend and
integrate because without that
capability we're never going to be able
to build anything that's hybrid and
we'll always be in this situation where
we're you know at the mercy of these
vendors to give us you know data fields
like strings where they should be IPS
and everything we know that should be
right and they're just not doing this
for us so they need to kind of move in
the direction of detection engineering
and you can just fix it yourself if you
have yeah not a string should be but
yeah let's do it I'm going to give like
a big plus one to that extensibility the
ability to work with a product and have
it be able to be molded to your
environment and have control over like
what's going in and coming out is just
revolutionary rather than I mean I'm not
going to name any names but just like
buying you know your classic big name
Sims and you have to learn their
proprietary you know query language and
you have to do everything in this very
specific way that probably doesn't
really have anything to do with your
environment and additionally like those
skills don't transfer right like exactly
you get this like lock-in or where you
as a professional now can't grow because
you've only used vendor X and vendor X's
skills are not transferable to vendor
why critical think we're starting a
revolution I think we're like looking at
fictional response engineering teams are
going to take back the power from
vendors because if they're not giving us
what we want we can build hybrid
solutions that take over that and take
note vendors in the room yeah get scared
or work with us or open up your
platforms so we can really yeah really
customize them yeah I think that's one
of the successes I've seen a lot with
like our open source like toolkit is it
doesn't do what we want let's change it
like oh we have a cool new idea like we
have uh checks like you can't ship a bad
config for this environment anymore but
we could only do that because we built
it ourselves not because a vendor would
have allowed us to do that yeah I did
want to go back to your comment about
how sometimes we have kind of this
ceiling that we put on when we have
analysts come in and they're only
working on these proprietary tools and
they become experts in one you know
query I'm really trying hard not to say
a vendor name right now
but as a hiring manager and I know we
have like other like people involved in
this when I see a resume and your
experience is nine years working with
one proprietary scripting like query
language that just has to do with this
one tool
I can't see how I can slot you in to the
like the current kind of like
engineering focused approach and I would
say that is not dunking on the analyst
that's dunking on the companies that
don't give the opportunities for you to
have extensible skills
[Laughter]
word all right I want to talk a bit
about the noise and prioritization and
so we know that working and threat
detection response where our scope is so
uh it's so large and I mean Jessica you
talked about you own corpsec as well so
it's not just incident response it's not
just threat detection it's also
corporate security and asset control and
the the issue too is right we're not
working on systems that are static or
not changing we're not working with
threat actors who aren't changing what
they're doing every day and so there's
so much that we could focus on and
there's so many things that we could
focus on we have vendors we have
organizations like miter telling us what
we should be focused on we have
Frameworks that were written 10 15 years
ago that tell us we need to be focused
on certain things how do you
operationally know what to focus on when
you're building out your detections and
I'm gonna throw it to you Louie so I
think it really comes down to threat
modeling your environment and using
Frameworks internally that makes sense
um one that I really like is kind of
this High exposure versus low risk to
low exposure high-risk type of map and
what that basically looks like is if you
have uh say an external system that's
customer facing right you have a lot of
control of that system typically because
you designed it you can put security
controls in place but it shouldn't
really be something that's high risk
versus the other side of the spectrum
there where you have your cloud system
is that might have very very low
exposure no one really sees this except
injuries with admin access but the risk
is very high of something were to go
wrong so focusing on either side of that
actual diagram tends to be really
impactful because you get the swath of
people who are trying to attack you
while also focusing on the systems that
are most critical in terms of things
actually going wrong in your environment
so with that in mind like I've always
worked on very small security teams and
we've had to prioritize because we can't
bring it we can't log everything I never
believe we should log everything else
it's expensive it's so expensive an
insane Paradigm that only your vendor
wants you to do for more money right
vendors I see you in the room
um yeah so like basically focusing on
the things that you believe as your
organization have the highest risk put
your logs there right and then really
you get to know those logs and learn
them yeah so rather than like that
breadth first let's do everything let's
log everything let's actually look at
what the threats are to our organization
and like every company every team is
going to have different threat models
like there are different attackers
there's different threat vectors and
trying to apply a one-size-fits all it's
just gonna
it's going to give you too many alerts
it's just it's not going to be a good
time this is something I would love
Julie to comment on because she because
she actually
did something which has been really an
incredible prioritization tool for the
team that I reference constantly
yeah hoping to actually probably open
source us but it's a way of thinking
about log prioritization so went back to
this whole thing like my hot take is the
data engineering
um but what logs you ingest how you
store them and what is in those logs um
should all be prioritized basically for
incidents for detections you need these
logs but you only have a team of three
people so how do you choose which logs
to ingest and what data to keep and how
long you keep it for and for us we have
like
more frequent storage where we can like
access it immediately in frequent where
it's a more expensive to query and so we
have to make decisions
um based on our budget and how much data
we're bringing in where do we put each
and when do we spend time ingesting
those logs and I think having that
conversation internally looking at
um there's a couple different ways you
can look at it from like the risk of the
the logs the platform itself or the logs
are coming from you can look at like how
is that platform secured how often are
you having incidents with that and use
all these different factors to determine
what is the priority of ingesting those
logs how do we store them and then
making sure those are available and like
planning your quarters around that so
that you keep getting logs in you're
making sure that you're moving towards
the progress of having everything you
need to do those incident response
actions those threat detection actions
yeah and so so what we have as a team
now is we have Internal Documentation
the log prioritization framework it's
there it's documented logs come out to
high medium low risk depending on like
the context of our environment the
framework is very specific to like what
we are where our customer data is and
because of this we have a prioritized
backlog of high medium low log sources
and we're like cool what are we doing
next we just pick them up off the top of
the pile and then those conversations
for me as a manager become a lot easier
because I have conversations about how
much our tools cost and I get to write
documents that justify the cost of our
tools and when we have a frame where
it's like look we think about this in a
really mature way it also makes all of
those managery like conversations like
talking about budgeting and like what
the real value is because we've been
prioritizing like so consistently over
time like Finance is like okay you're
actually doing a pretty good job and how
how do you leverage these to talk about
the things that you're not prioritizing
because I know as security teams I joke
with my team that a lot of what we do is
emotional triage because people come to
us and they're like I'm scared there's a
there's something weird that is
happening and you have to talk to them
in a reasonable way about what you're
prioritizing why you're prioritizing it
and so I'm wondering how you Leverage
kind of these systems are these like
processes to do that yeah it's I think
what happens most commonly is someone
who has a little bit of knowledge about
the space makes a suggestion that at the
surface level sounds incredibly
reasonable so like as part of these
conversations talking about where we
want to log this Source not this Source
we think this is more important a
regular one that comes up is like oh
what about Network things what about VPC
flow logs and I was like do you know the
volume
um but it becomes like out of a place of
a lack of knowledge from them and
because we have just like this is how we
think about it this is how we prioritize
it's much much easier to have a
conversation about a framework in place
to do this rather than like no you're
dumb or like like pushing someone off
and making them feel bad you get to read
them into how you do it rather than them
feeling like you ignore them or blow
them off because you didn't listen to
them and it becomes like self-service
too like Louie I'm wondering yeah yeah I
find that super helpful in the past
because like just pointing people to the
document station you have as to how you
think about logging tends to alleviate
their fears and usually have
compensating logs they weren't aware of
like we think about VPC flow logs and
VPC Vlogs will have DNS logs are useless
so like is there a better way of getting
that context there often is right and as
long as people can see that they're less
focused or hyper focused on the thing
they think is scary like an additional
kind I want to make on this was around
like documentation in general and kind
of back to our original infrastructures
code detection is code questions here
these things are self-documenting once
you actually put them in place so it
becomes a lot easier to have these
discussions after the fact because
you're codifying these things so people
can go back and reference them
that's a really good call out because
the documentation also makes it easier
for you to onboard people to your teams
as well as stakeholders and compliance
efforts
our jrc team loves us like working with
us like you're on top of it and we're
like oh it's because we just we write
down how we do the thing and that's like
a huge amount of like what compliance
and grp yeah infras code infras code
makes um the GRC audits like very happy
times yeah it doesn't have to be very
hard to make GRC happy it's actually
like
can be quite simple when you focus on
the things that matter yeah and I'll
give like a little shout out to someone
on our GRC team Alan you're amazing um
but he'll he'll he will look at
something or be pulling evidence from a
ticket and he'll go find the ticket from
last year where it's a specific place in
a GitHub repo that I linked that shows
like yes this is this is the connection
of the logging for this thing and then
he just goes and he's like wait this is
what you showed me last year is this the
same page like am I right and I was like
yes you're right just show to the
auditor again and the consistency of
having it documented in the code repo
which is also like self updating
essentially is massively helpful for
like my peace of mind when it comes like
audit season I try to keep the team out
of it and I can usually because they've
documented the work awesome I want to
talk a little bit about Automation and
especially like automating manual
processes and I think here I I think a
lot about how we saw this revolution
when it started to adopt engineering
practices and devops so I'm wondering
and I'm going to say it are we in like a
sec Dev detection Ops Revolution is that
what we're fighting for here yeah okay I
hate acronyms too but yes it pains me a
little bit to say yes to that and I
mentioned earlier like I started out my
career in a knock in a knock that moved
from like into a more devops approach so
I feel super super passionately about
this
um yes devops is the future and I think
all this comes down to a very Central
like human behavioral idea of ownership
if you own a system you own it
um which means you have the skills to
maintain it you have the ability to say
no when other people want to touch your
system and you can like make changes
when you need it and if you feel the
pain when that system breaks you're
going to build an excellent system and
if you have any of those things split to
other teams you can't control your own
destiny things are going to get worse
but when Engineering Systems break if
you can fix them and you feel the acute
terrible 3 A.M this is the worst pain
when they break you better believe
you're going to fix that the next day
but if it's an analyst that feels that
pain and some engineer over there hears
about it like theoretically they're not
going to make any effort like really
emotionally to fix that thing you just
have misaligned incentives so in my mind
like devops helps bring the right
incentive structure and sense of
ownership like to work and I don't do
you can really have an excellent like
system if those incentives aren't
aligned correctly
and directly the reason vendors aren't
really here to help you right they're
not living your life they're not feeling
the pain points that you're feeling and
until they are we won't really get
better products so we do have to be the
ones pushing them to make these things
extensible to give us some more of that
control back yeah and I think when we
talk about automation something that I
hear often when I talk to people like
especially people who are in analyst
roles now or have spent a lot of time in
like classically more analyst type roles
they are like well you can never
automate out the people from threat
section response like and it's something
that I think
is very like
uh gets spicy quickly and I want to say
I don't think any of us are thinking
that we can automate subject matter
experts out of this process but what I'm
talking about instead is instead of
having someone on the factory line
dealing with things that are coming out
of a black box giving them the ability
to actually modify the factory and
change what's coming out like Jessica
said it's the ability to control your
own destiny and the ability to apply
your specific knowledge and threat
detection and threat actors and how to
protect companies and actually be able
to do
the cool work of like hunting and red
teaming without having to be stuck under
well I have 5 000 alerts to look at
today so um and I have no idea what this
IP address is yeah I think it's like
time allocation if you think about it
you only have so many hours in the day
detection Response Team handle a lot of
things if they're engineering first
they're engineering building new systems
they might be building incident response
automation they're going to be writing
detections they're doing threat research
you might be doing threat hunting like
you're doing a lot of different things
and you really want to free up time so
that people can be doing those
interesting things and they're not
burning themselves out looking at alerts
or handling the same thing over and over
again and so like I really like this
like way of viewing automation as just a
tool to make your team better not a tool
to remove people
yeah I think a pretty key example there
is kind of in just the alert and
enrichment type pipelines if it looks
building out and you know these things
should serve to make every one of our
analysts a bit faster and also kind of
spread the knowledge of our senior
analysts more widely saying here's a
process I would follow this process is
now codified as a script or an
enrichment Runner such that anyone who's
more Junior picking this up can
immediately benefit from the experience
of others
yeah and when when you're like looking
at a thing in front of you and you need
to do it faster if you can control the
system that's emitting the alert you can
control the system that's providing you
with the enrichment like yeah I'm gonna
take that extra five ten minutes out of
my day so that I'm one minute quicker
every other time just like crops up in
the future yeah potential gains yeah
yeah and I think like the alert
management system that uh you and Josh
built for the team is like a really good
example of trying to take all that stuff
and put it all in one place all in
one spot that gives someone the ability
to do all the information they need like
just go like why stop yeah I think a key
part is also like looking at how alerts
are coming in like the point where
you're making the detection to where
like an analyst or an engineer is
responding to it how can you make that
process like faster and easier for
people whether that's like incident
response automation for us it was also
like looking at the context of every
alert before it gets to the um end on
call so that we can suppress and
de-duplicate alerts more efficiently so
we're not getting if the system spikes
we're not getting a thousand alerts
because something that it did download a
script on every endpoint and we want
like an alert from every single one of
those like it's going to see that it's
the same script that's running and we're
going to get one alert to triage
um and looking at ways to do that so
that you're spending less time doing
this like repetitive work where you're
doing these like investigations that are
probably benign but you still need to do
them and you're able to like free up
that time to like hey there's like a new
threat research article that came out
and I want to write a detection and so
just like giving the power back to the
individual yeah so it's like once you
see something and when you see it for
the first time you want the context
there to not have to go to a bunch of
other systems or like and have like you
know 40 tabs open as you're trying to
figure out where this came from and what
it means and also once you see something
getting all the contacts there great but
then do you need to see it again ever
like if I'm triaging an alert and it's
not relevant or it needs to be tuned or
something I never want to have to
process it again
um so yeah yeah I think you touch a
little bit like on burnout incident
response roles detection response
humerals are really burnout prone
because you have the high pressure
you're doing an incident response like
any given you could just have a terrible
week
um and yeah like it's like death by a
Thousand Cuts I would see it in your
like your day-to-day life that alert's
really annoying and you like sling it
away like oh it's fine um but the
automation really gives people the
opportunity to make their life better
yeah I sleep in hand since they have a
place basically with automation yeah as
possible it makes your life better but
it also speeds up if you're in a real
incident
where there's that like pressure like
there's like a million bricks on your
shoulders and you're like struggling to
breathe and you're like I have a million
things to do right now well like you can
automate some of that away whether
that's like the incident like process
handling writing the documentation
whether that's isolating laptops all of
these things make it easier so that like
it's not as much pressure on a small
tune
that's really well said
um I have one last question for each of
you which is about what you're excited
about for the future or kind of things
that are on your mind and then I want to
open it up to any of you who want to ask
us questions and kind of pick the brains
of the panelists here so I'll start with
you Louie what are you excited about
yeah so I'm definitely most excited
about like the using AI to make our jobs
easier security Engineers I think
there's an opportunity in basically
every part of security to do this if
you're an application security you can
use language models to essentially look
over a block of code and see if this is
risky or includes any like known
vulnerabilities on the instant response
side you can use the summarize instant
Communications basically removing the
need for instant Commander
but like really being able to summarize
this especially when you're dropped into
it like as a newcomer it can be like
really you know challenging to scroll
back up through that instant and figure
out what's going on it's really nice if
you can just say hey AI summarize the
last comms what items are open what
items are still in progress who are
things assigned to so there's a lot of
opportunity in this space and we as
security people need to like actually
look at what's possible for these
technology and like feed this back into
our work sorry do you work for an AI
company
[Music]
all right Jessica how about you
um I so I've like recently actually got
a really
excited about
like what ways we can take detection or
response like skill sets and move them
like elsewhere in the organization and
like very specifically for me I right
now am fascinated with the financial
fraud space
um so at brex we have we have like a
fraud compliance like org that is
separate from us but we collaborate um
when we do have like incident level
stuff when like fraud has stuff and I'm
so fascinated like the work is so
analogous but using different tools
you're detecting slightly different
things but also there's the security
aspect too so I'm increasingly excited
about like how can we take the cool
stuff detections response does and like
apply it to other places within the
company because I think that we also
like our team specifically has a lot of
data engineering like chops and skills
that we can also share too so it's like
that's the part I'm also excited about
like I love textual response and being
able to like take what we do to other
spaces that are really adjacent is like
that's my my new my new thing I'm on
right now it really is applicable across
domains I think sometimes we Silo
ourselves and we're like we do this very
specific thing but what we're actually
doing like the meat of it is so
applicable to others one thing that also
keeps me too is um like alert management
and cue management like a support cue
like we kind of do that like we actually
have a lot of ability to tell people
like why are you doing that just turn
that off there's no value and other
people don't think to do that in some
ways yeah so I think we have a lot to
share
all right Julie yeah so one thing I've
been thinking a lot about is how we're
writing detections and how they exist in
the system and I think that the
traditional way is like you write like a
query and proprietary language of some
sort and then you store it and it's
looking for a specific behavior and then
you match on it but it doesn't have this
versatility to it um I think like a more
modular approach where you're maybe
writing logic that's behaviors and then
you chain those behaviors together to
represent a technique or an attack that
you've seen and then that way
um when you're as a detection you only
tune a small part or you're able to add
all these parts together that you've
already built into a new detection and I
think that versatility and modularity is
going to be really important and
actually like showcasing showcasing the
skills of the deduction engineers and
actually modeling the attacker's
behaviors in a more sustainable way so
you're not constantly editing or writing
new detections when one little aspect of
their technique has changed
what if you told us what
what AI
you're getting kicked off the panel
sorry excuse me
I want to say quickly what I'm excited
about is just people sharing what
they're working on I want to just give a
shout out to Brax like part of why I was
excited to have y'all on the panel is
you're both creating new systems but
you're writing about it and you're
sharing what you're doing and I think a
lot of us don't realize how interesting
what we're doing is and how interesting
it is for other people so like please
you know do talks write blogs it really
helps other people and open source your
stuff
and AI
and Ai and AI yeah yeah all right do we
have questions yeah before we open up
the questions I just want everybody to
give a round of applause for these oh
thank you
[Applause]
[Music]
all right so um
they have a lot of enduring fans it's
just me so if if anybody has a question
just raise your hand and I'll try to
pass you to Mike because they can't hear
you from up there especially I also
really can't see you yeah they can't see
you either the lights are bright so if
you could come down a little
foreign
I'm an old man
uh I think it was Louis you said but
this is a question for any of y'all I'm
curious what you think but curious how
you feel detection as code has enabled
you or not to validate whether now your
detection is actually catching what
you're looking for I think Louis you
mentioned like looking back and saying
oh we should have caught that or not is
that something that detectionist code
has enabled you to kind of program in
events plant flags that you're looking
for or uh yeah what's the deal there
yeah so we actually along with the
Texans code actually have the
adversaries as code as a part of our
testing pipeline such that when we write
the detection we also have an
adversarial test that should trigger
that event right so if we're not
essentially testing our detections we're
not really doing the the full job of
knowing that this works we're just
throwing something over the fence and
hoping it will actually detect something
so definitely big enough like codifying
attacker behavior and making that the
testing mechanism for actual detections
no
next question
raise your hand
though I think someone's just walking
around we can
yeah we can we can talk more about
um kind of others question
cool
what are some of the hardest parts about
making this revolution dream a reality
for each of you hiring yep
okay tell me more about that what is it
about hiring that makes it
I I feel really fortunate that
um the I
was hired in to be a manager of a team
that already had like an engineering
Focus to it and I got like lucky there
are people who are already there and and
hired before I arrived
um so yeah but hiring like was a
challenge like trying to find another
person finding someone who has a mix of
the software development like skill sets
and then also the operational ability to
do an actual like incident response and
run the incident is like a really
challenging overlap to find because you
you're typically finding people who have
more of an analyst background like they
don't they haven't been giving an
opportunity to do both those things yeah
hiring is very hard yeah I think another
thing is like leadership buy-in so if
you're at a company where you have
security leadership that are behind this
idea of having like hiring predominantly
engineer people with engineering skill
sets and doing this like detection and
response um engineering first style then
you have a lot of support and that's
great but there's a lot of companies
that are maybe a little bit older school
that see security response as having to
be a sock and so being able to push
change for that I think is going to be
really really difficult like I think
that's why you see a lot of detection
and response teams at newer tech
companies newer startups because they
were able to start the team from scratch
with engineering first principles rather
than having to go back and change
everyone's perceptions and get buy-in
yeah absolutely we have another question
here okay
okay
non-hiring challenge
I mean the only thing I've seen was like
try and break folks off that uh reactive
mindset into a proactive one because
like you could have the like a brand new
engineering program we're like yes we
won't be engineering first but then you
have analysts who are only used to being
reactive yeah and kind of like breaking
them out of that mindset of hey I have
to react right and I'm like no yes spend
two hours build a good detection and it
will save you time later it's getting
people like into that bought into that
idea basically for sure I call it the
reactive wheel of hell where you are so
stuck in operational work that
everything is coming in at the same
volume and severity and you're just
running around with your hands on fire
setting everything else on fire
um no one relates to that
[Laughter]
hi
um this is kind of a question for a
comment that both Jess and Louis made so
you mentioned kind of seeing the gap
between how financial fraud detection
Works versus sort of like security
incident in response do you see some
patterns potentially like going towards
the security side so for instance things
like synthetic data sets and using those
or is this something that people already
do in industry
I think it depends a lot on like what
your fraud team looks like
um but typically from my perspective
like from what I'm seeing the fraud team
operates a lot like a sock
um there's uh there's like levels within
it like there's Specialists for
escalation some people who do more of
the the data the actual data modeling
for fraud and detection rules is backed
by a data like an actual like team of
Engineers but then the analysts who are
actually operating on the work
um you know they have good knowledge
about what they're doing but they don't
have that engineering level knowledge so
that that's what I see the in the
parallels the most is from what I the
way I watch this the fraud teams operate
it's a lot more analogous to a sock cert
than it is to like an engineering team
so that's what like makes me really
excited but it'd be really hard to push
that model like that would be a really
challenging one I think that's why I'm
also like fascinated by looking at the
fraud space yeah I think for me what
I've seen is like
the kyc type of type of motion in both
spaces is really important and if you
just have take away that singular piece
and focus on it both sides can really
benefit right because when it comes to
like identity in your applications or
within your environment if you have a
really strong signal for that you can
solve for fraud and you can solve for
most security issues yeah 100 plus one
here
hi so you basically talk about how you
want to use AI to do a lot of proactive
security response and I think actually
that's pretty ingenious coming from an
SRE background because firefighting
[ __ ] sucks because that's my language
um but I wanted to know for the AI side
are you actually building custom llms or
are you using like chat gpt's
professional license as an exposed API
and then using some of those agents that
they have to build those models and
those tools so this might be a bit of a
hot take maybe some folks in the room
from some of these companies but I'm so
ready I don't believe we should really
be leaning too heavily on third-party
llms it's not actually really
complicated to have an in-house llm
that's a lot smaller to serve our
specific use cases and that's basically
what we're doing right using these
smaller more fine-tuned models instead
of relying on sending our you know
really confidential data out to a third
party wait you mean sending all of your
logs and customer information to a third
party that doesn't have strong privacy
or security policies is not a good idea
oh no
no who hurt you
all right we have uh last question
there you go
you're someone's really oh so
um so great talk thanks for the panel so
so uh for the vendors in the room
[Laughter]
you just outed yourself
so uh I understand having having worked
for both open and closed Source uh
tooling but when it comes to
detectionist code how would you like us
to when it when it comes to say we're
different customer bases different user
bases want to make different changes at
the same time how would you like us to
manage that would you like to say
maintain a fork and we offer you changes
and you decide to accept them or not or
have you thought about how that might
work yes yes
yeah that's exactly what we do right now
it's like yeah let us work but also we
want to benefit from what the community
and what the company because you all
have in-house subject matter experts and
if you don't please get people who do
security working in your company yeah
like the the model of like this is our
official stuff we offer you this is what
you do and here's the community stuff
you might find helpful those are kind of
the three buckets I think of the
detections falling into
and remember sponsors paid for Visa so
that's why we didn't trash them directly
no we said no did I say any names no no
no no all right all right thank you guys
we'll be around thank you everybody
thank you
[Applause]