my name is David I'm an engineer on the
security engineering team at chime and
I've been here for almost three years
today I want to talk to you about
monocle which is an internal rails app
that we've built at chime which helps us
get everybody to do the right thing for
security specifically engineers
so we're going to look at some of the
scaling challenges we've had at chime
First for security specifically how we
approach those in terms of gamification
education and appreciation of people
doing hard work
or work that's typically not appreciated
and
some of the results we got from leaders
among engineers
and how you could get started at home or
at work I should say
in an easier way than what you're seeing
here like you know I spent
as you heard a few years here at Chimes
so this is definitely not something you
finish in a weekend
so
in terms of our challenges at chime we
recently tripled our engineering team
so that's a lot of people to learn
things
we've created a lot of new services and
with every new service there's different
Baseline security
configurations that you need to set up
so we've filled those
and we've also completed a number of
audits of PCI socks things like that and
as you can imagine those were somewhat
stressful at times raise your hand if
you've ever had a painful audit
okay wow that's like 95 of the audience
so we want our teams to focus on
security
I think we can all agree on that
but how do the teams actually learn
security best practices
you can't just rely on them you know
reading things online and teaching
themselves
so also how do we get everybody to
secure their services without burning
ourselves out with all of the jira
tickets that we create
and Bernard TPMS out uh technical
program managers out with all of the
pinging that they have to do to get
people to address the tickets
um and then also how do we even know
whether our services are secure in the
first place uh you know
there's a lot of security tools that
we're all using and it's hard to figure
out uh you need something to fuse all
that information together
so I want to give you a little
illustration of what it's like without
monocle or a tool like it
um so hi this is David I'm from the
security team can you please resolve
these 23 vulnerabilities in your service
so raise your hand if you've sent a
message like that
okay nice
um yeah and you can imagine that this
kind of uh message
might make the engineer receiving it
feel sad
um some of the things going through
their head are like I didn't know I was
supposed to resolve these
vulnerabilities like why didn't somebody
tell me about this before I got in
trouble so
so to try and address that one thing we
do is we send a message to their team
Channel
and we say hey your score dipped below a
b because we're giving everybody grades
but or not the people but they're
repositories a grade between an A and an
f and we want everybody to be above a
beat if they're a production service
so we send them a message
looks like that's big enough on the
screen and we tell them hey do this and
this to improve your grade
they can click through and learn more
about it
when they
when they're on their GitHub repository
itself we are showing their grade on the
readme and the reason we're doing that
is because people spend a lot of time on
GitHub and looking at their own readme's
they'll notice oh my score is not good I
should make that go up
um and so the majority of our teams are
really proactive about this which we
love and we don't even have to ask them
to um follow the rules
so
here is what it looks like once you
click through the badge you can see a
number of the different rules score
factors that we are grading people on
and each one has some points associated
with it this is recalculated every night
based on API calls to different places
and you can click to expand an item and
learn what you specifically need to do
to fix that item and
uh some of the key items that reduce our
audit workload
are approved base images these are
getting rebuilt every week or so to make
sure that the vulnerabilities that are
patched are the patches are pulled in we
make sure that everybody has at least
one pull request approval you know
making sure you don't have like a single
uh actor threat type thing but also
making sure there's no bugs and things
we want people to resolve the
vulnerabilities that we find so if
you've got higher criticals we're
telling you hey please fix those
and we want to make sure that everybody
has tests and passes those tests before
they merge uh
it seems like a basic thing
um but you know some repos don't have
that
so we show a good amount of information
to leaders as well about how their how
our security posture is so this is a
screenshot of the home page of the app
and you can see a breakdown of how we're
doing in terms of who how many people
are above a b and this screenshot
roughly this is a fake one but gets
presented at our monthly engineering
review meetings
if you don't have one of those at your
company you should maybe tell people
have one and then you can join it and
present security stuff basically the
attendees of that are like all the
engineering managers and Engineering
leaders up to the CTO
so on the right
we've got a breakdown of which score
factors are passing or not and that's
really helpful because sometimes you've
got a new initiative you want to make
sure for example that code climate is
enabled for everybody or let's say that
we've got no security vulnerabilities
for GitHub security alerts
then you can easily
click on whichever bar and find all the
repos that are not doing that thing and
then just go track those people down
um
that's pretty helpful
so we've also built this thing called
risk advisor which
uh
evaluates every pull request to make
sure people are following our like four
most important rules
some of those are I already mentioned
but the the important one that's not
mentioned is dependency confusion
uh that's when you accidentally
downloaded a dependency from the
internet instead of your private version
of a gem
or dependency
so the way this looks is on your pull
requests you see a status
it's kind of small sorry but basically
it's showing you yes you're good to
merge and if you click through you can
see the rules that were evaluated and
see that your
ready to merge but let's say you're
failing some rules then this is what you
might see as an engineer on the page you
know a little red X on your pull request
and let's say they didn't notice that
and they clicked merge anyway
we're not blocking the pull requests
because we want people to
still be able to get their work done
um
so that means that they might merge
without passing the rule and if they do
the monocle will detect that
and automatically create a jira ticket
to track it so it'll also send a message
to their team channel so that the whole
team can just be aware of something that
happened that wasn't supposed to and
help resolve it
um
we found this really helpful
um you know with jira you can query all
of the past
forever's worth of Juror tickets and
then
very easily satisfy your auditing
requirements
um so we realized that even though
arkadi here who's giving a talk later
today gives a really interesting
onboarding session sometimes employees
Engineers will forget that monocle even
exists
and so we wanted to create more
awareness for monocle and so one of the
ways we did that is we came up with the
idea of sending scorecards and we send
these scorecards to slack channels and
it shares some basic information about
the repo and how they're doing
and we noticed that teams celebrate that
they have good scores and that's really
nice because
a lot of us probably have co-workers who
are doing important work like keeping
all the packages up to date but they're
not really appreciated because it's kind
of really annoying work and it's not you
know as cool as building a new feature
let's say
um
a quick note about these uh slack
channels that we've got we've found it
extremely helpful to create a
convention-based slack Channel naming
scheme so hashtag GH repo name
and uh when we
we have it set up so that monocle will
create the channels for us and add the
top contributors but that's not really
necessary you can just do this manually
um
and you know all of your tooling can
just send messages to those channels
without having to figure out the name
you don't need an ownership directory or
a spreadsheet or anything
so
uh it would be very bad if our members
lost trust in us and we lost the
financial data that they've trusted with
us
um so
does gamification work does it work for
us to give grades to all these repos and
I would say yes it really helps us get a
view of how is engineering doing how is
security doing and are people following
best practices and culture guidelines
um
so
we've seen that leaders can see what our
security posture is
Engineers are not overwhelmed by having
to check five different security tools
probably we don't even give them access
to all of those tools in the first place
um
and we're saving about 2 000 Engineers 2
000 engineering hours a year on auditing
um that's time that they would have been
spending trying to use github's
improving but maybe not perfect search
capabilities
um and clicking through just manually to
check stuff
so this is a graph the blue is how many
score factors we've been tracking and
that's been going up over time and the
green is how many repos have above a
beat and both of those have been going
up and to the right which is perfect so
we're safeguarding member data people
are improving security and leaders can
see the numbers going up
we've also found that it's much easier
to roll out new security initiatives so
every time we've got a security
initiative the all the structure for
notifying people and
delivering the words to people so that
the instructions all of that is already
there with monocle so we just need to
focus on what are the instructions and
then following up on the few teams that
don't already
uh follow our instructions on their own
um and uh just briefly on that our TP
GM's technical program managers are just
very happy with this as well they have a
lot less spreadsheets that they have to
track and they don't have to Ping all of
these engineers
and Engineering managers
um
so if you are thinking about where to
start for yourself think about where
where does security intersect with
engineering and
uh
start simple it could just be a Cron job
and it gets some basic information out
of the GitHub API and then it sends
slack notifications to teams and maybe
you have another Channel where it sends
reports
There's Something Beautiful about
sending slack messages which is that you
have a chance of
critical hit or whatever you want to
call it basically an engineer might have
five minutes free a junior engineer or
just anybody and then they see the
message and they fix it
and it's done you didn't have to make a
jira ticket and track it and all of that
tracking can be more expensive than
actually fixing the item for in some
cases
um I would also recommend checking out
ossf's All-Star and more generally
backstage as uh terms of solutions that
you could try setting up at your company
um here's a little photo of the
architecture so everybody is visiting
the rails app the rails as excuse me the
scores recalculate every night as they
talk to our different data sources like
GitHub stack rocks jira Circle CI and
then that gets stored into postgres
this is roughly how risk advisor Works
where subscribed to webhook events from
GitHub and we validate that they came
from GitHub and then we forward
information on to open policy agent
which runs these Rigo rules and tell us
whether or not the person is passing the
the rules that we've written
and you know based on if they pass them
or not we create a ticket notify people
and update the GitHub UI
we are authoring those rules inside of
the monocle repo which you know makes it
simple as well
um
talking a little bit more of the
philosophy of where you start
um it's a good idea to find Engineers
where they already are so ideally that
might be in their editor because it's
the cheapest place for someone to fix
something we haven't really gotten to
that yet
um next would be GitHub they're readmes
and pull request statuses that's what
Engineers are looking at all the time
and in slack because at least for our
company that's where everyone is hanging
out all the time they're not looking at
email so much or at least me
um and you want to give them
instructions that don't include security
jargon so ideally small items that they
can follow
and
if you can help them celebrate their
investment in security with their team
that's what the scorecard is about and
these messages to the team channels help
with that as well
so if a tree falls and no one hears it
did it make a sound
uh yes your security is definitely
better after these things have happened
and so showing everybody that they did
happen is a really nice thing
um so yeah uh we can move on to
questions in a second but if you have
something you want to ask us you can
send us an email or mention me on
Mastodon and probably someone's going to
ask this but yes we do want to open
source monocle but we just haven't found
the time yet hopefully this year we'll
see
um and chime is looking for an engineer
to work on data security so consider
reaching out this is definitely my
favorite favorite job ever
thanks
[Applause]
foreign