all right hello hello good afternoon uh
we have a wonderful presentation uh
we're going to talk we're going to have
Terry o'daniels talking about going far
together and how to build your squad
I'll hand it on over and let's give a
quick Round of Applause
hey everyone if I can just fight through
this crowd for a second to see you all
oh there you are okay good
um welcome to the approaching the end of
b-sides thank you all for showing up and
I hope we have a little fun
so my name is Terry O'Daniel and today
I'm going to be talking about building
your squad
picture this
you're defending your company's critical
infrastructure from a Cyber attack
you're feeling overwhelmed and alone
the clock is ticking the stakes are high
and the pressure is immense
you're working tirelessly
but you feel like you're in this battle
alone
and you're starting to feel despair
sound familiar
or how about this
you're trying to get to the next level
in your career
or maybe you're dealing with an
unexpected setback like a layoff
you've been updating your resume and
you've been watching Interview videos on
LinkedIn and YouTube
but you can't seem to make it past the
first round of interviews at any job you
apply
hmm
well what if I told you there's a
powerful tool to help you overcome these
kinds of obstacles
it's not a fancy technology or a secret
hack
but rather it's just the power of other
people
just like in any great adventure having
a team of trusted peers by your side can
make the difference
So today we're going to explore how to
build your squad and why it can be a
game changer in your journey
so let's start with the preface of this
entire talk
if you want to go fast go alone if you
want to go far go together
so let's start with talking about the
power of peers
here's a quick overview of the four
areas we're going to discuss today
okay
let's dive into the first aspect of
building your squad finding common cause
just like in any Mission a strong sense
of shared purpose helps bring a squad
together
it binds its members to a common purpose
and in the cyber security field that
means finding peers who shame share
similar goals who appreciate the same
challenges or even who have common
interests
it could be a group of like-minded
Professionals in the company you work at
now
it could be a local cyber security
Meetup or it can be an online community
or even a gathering of cyber Security
Professionals in one place like b-sides
find those people
join forces with them and support each
other in having common goals
let's talk about the power of
transparency
in cyber security knowledge is power and
that includes knowledge about pay and
promotions
did you know that the gender pay Gap in
the cyber security industry is a
well-documented issue I sure did
according to a study by the center for
cyber safety and education
women in cyber security on average earn
17 percent less than men
it's time to change that
by being transparent about your pay and
the promotion process you're going
through within your squad
you can advocate for fair and Equitable
treatments around compensation and
promotion and you can promote diversity
and inclusion within the field
so let's talk about the importance of
mentoring and sponsorship within your
squad mentoring is a powerful tool for
professional growth and sponsorship can
open doors to new opportunities
in fact research shows that employees
who have mentors are more likely to be
promoted earn higher salaries and have
greater job satisfaction
to seek out mentors and find sponsors
within your squad but also be willing to
mentor and sponsor others
let's lift each other up and help each
other thrive in our careers
last we'll talk a little bit about
resilience
cyber security is a dynamic field with
its fair share of challenges and it has
setbacks and even failures
but it's how we bounce back that matters
and your squad can be a source of
strength during tough times
lean on each other for support
share your Lessons Learned and celebrate
your successes together
by building a resilient Squad you can
weather the storms of cyber security and
your career and you can come out
stronger on the other side
so let's start
by talking about the importance of
collaboration and knowledge sharing
within your squad
staying up to date on the latest threats
challenges and Technologies is a key
part of our field but we can't do it
alone
your squad can be a valuable source of
collective intelligence
share your knowledge experience as an
Insight with your peers and learn from
them
collaboration not only strengthens your
skills but also also Fosters Innovation
and creativity leading to better
outcomes in your cyber security efforts
in fact research shows
that those who are collaborating are
five times more likely to perform at
higher levels
let's discuss the power of networking
and building those meaningful
relationships within your squad
cyber security is obviously a very
rapidly evolving field and it's not just
about what you know but who you know
building a professional network of
trusted peers can provide you with
opportunities for career advancement
it can give you industry insights and it
can even give you job referrals for your
next role
so attend those industry events join
professional organizations and actively
engage but bring your squad along
network with intention and build
meaningful connections that can help you
succeed in your cyber security career
so let's talk about diversity inclusion
in your squad
cyber security I firmly believe is a
field that benefits greatly from diverse
perspectives backgrounds and experiences
think about the last time you did a risk
analysis
look around the room
if everyone looked like you during that
analysis do you really have the right
perspectives
Studies have shown that diverse teams
are more Innovative resilient and
effective at problem solving so Embrace
diversity within your squad and actively
seek out diverse voices and participants
for your squad
find those New Perspectives and Foster
an inclusive environment where everyone
feels welcome
if you build an environment of respect
and you make sure that everyone has a
voice and can be heard within your squad
you're building an inclusive environment
and you promote fairness inequality
within your squad but you're also
promoting the overall performance and
success of the team
finally let's talk about the importance
of continuous Learning and Development
cyber security is a field that always
requires us to learn and grow and build
those skills due to its Dynamic nature
so I encourage you to stay curious seek
out learning opportunities and encourage
your squad members to do the same
whether it's attending a training
program obtaining a certification or
participating in Industry conferences
invest in your professional growth and
Inspire your squad to do the same
by sharing that continuous learning with
your squad you can stay ahead even in a
fast based security field like cyber
security
so 72 percent
of employees surveyed
believe that their peers are the best
source for Learning and diversity or
excuse me for Learning and Development
and yet so frequently we go to our
managers for Learning and Development
opportunities
let's talk about transparency in the
cyber security industry and especially
when it comes to pay and promotion
transparency is a key component of
building Trust
and fostering a healthy environment
in cyber security it's crucial to have
open and honest communication
but about not just technical elements
but also around pay promotions and
career opportunities
discussing salaries openly sharing
information about the promotion process
and advocating for fair compensation can
help break down inequalities and promote
fairness
transparency also promotes
accountability
and encourages organizations to
prioritize diversity equity and
inclusion
so let's work together to create that
culture of transparency within our Squad
and then take those Lessons Learned back
to our place of business
and how the squad can help with that
in cyber security it's important to
stand up for yourself
and for your peers
it's important to take defensible
positions and Advocate and argue for a
position you strongly believe in
don't be afraid to negotiate in the same
way for fair pay promotions that are
Equitable and other career opportunities
advocate for yourself and for others in
your squad who may be facing challenges
workshop with them how you approach that
situation maybe they can learn from it
by collectively advocating for fair
treatment and helping others see how you
do that we can all create a more
inclusive and Equitable environment in
this industry
remember you're not alone on this
journey but by supporting each other we
can go far together
and in fact supporting each other
through challenges is one of the key
benefits of this squad
there's a vast importance to mentorship
and sponsorship in building your career
but you can find those opportunities
within your squad as well
mentorship can pay a pivotal role in
professional developments by providing
guidance insights and opportunities for
growth
but seek out mentors within your squad
who can provide that same advice and
support and create opportunities
mentorship mentorship and sponsorship
can help level the playing field and
create a more inclusive industry in
cyber security where everyone has equal
access to growth and advancement but it
starts by working on that muscle with
your squad
finally let's talk about resilience and
supporting each other through
challenging times
the cyber security field can be
demanding and it can be stressful
so it's essential to create a supportive
environment within your squad
be there for your peers
during challenging times
offer them a helping hand and provide
them emotional support
building a resilient and supportive
Squad can help you overcome obstacles
navigate through setbacks in your career
and thrive in your career overall
remember we're all in this together but
by supporting each other we can build a
strong and resilient cyber security
community
studies show that
groups that have a peer support group to
fall back on feel 40 percent less
stress and likelihood of burnout
that's huge
so let's talk about what you can do
with some of the tips I've given you
here
in this final section of the talk
we're going to talk about actions you
can take to build that Squad and ways
you can bring those learnings back to
the larger industry
it's time to empower yourself
by creating a network of like-minded
professionals who can support each other
by collaborating and leveraging the
power of collective effort
we can achieve remarkable things
so let's dive into some practical steps
for how to build your squad and go far
together
the first step in building your squad is
to identify common goals and interests
why is this group of people coll
collecting together
so look for those peers who share
similar Passions
similar mindset career aspers
aspirations ways of working different
ways of working or core values
you can connect through professional
organizations
online forums industry events
conferences and even within your current
company
so collaborate on projects together
share knowledge and expertise and
support each other's growth
together we're stronger so by aligning
with those like-minded professionals you
amplify your impact in the industry and
you're amplifying your ability to find
success within your career
the second step is to create that
culture of inclusivity and collaboration
within your squad no one's going to
create it for you so the onus is on each
member of the squad to create this
actively
Foster an environment where everyone's
voice is heard and respected regardless
of their experience level or background
find ways to ensure that everyone's
voice everyone has an opportunity to
speak not everyone is an extrovert
sometimes you'll have to create
structures to make time for people to be
heard
you can encourage open discussion
feedback one-on-one sessions and
brainstorming sessions
but by diversity by embracing that
diversity of thought and promoting those
inclusive practices actively
you create an environment where everyone
feels that their career is valued
equally
and everyone has an increased chance of
success in those careers
the third step
is to support each other's professional
growth and development directly
so share those resources that have
helped you recommend relevant training
and certification programs that work
steer people away from the ones that are
bad provide each other with feedback
provide each other with guidance
celebrate each other's successes provide
constructive feedback on how to improve
create those opportunities for
mentorship either directly within your
squad or indirectly
find sponsors and align them with your
squad mates and ultimately collaborate
and support each other's growth in an
active way
we can collectively Elevate our
profession and we can collectively make
a positive impact on the industry
through these small steps
so let's review
building your squad in cyber security is
not just nice to have it's a must-have
for success in this challenging field
as we've discussed creating small cadres
of peers who support each other can help
you navigate your career increase
transparency and overcome challenging
times
so I encourage each and every one of you
to take this action today reach out to
your colleagues form your squad and
embark on this journey
well folks that's a wrap we've covered a
lot of ground today from the importance
of building your squad to strategies for
success now let's recap what we've
learned in hopefully a fun and memorable
way
first of all we're all in this together
it's like being in the Avengers except
we have firewalls instead of capes
by building your own Squad of
like-minded professionals you can
collaborate support each other and make
a real difference in the industry
your squad is not just about saving the
world from cyber threats it's also about
having a support system that understands
your cyber security jokes and shares
your love for Star Wars references
plus having a crew to commiserate with
when that late night patching goes awry
is invaluable
so here's the bottom line don't go solo
in cyber security
find your squad Foster a culture of
collaboration and inclusivity and
support each other's growth
together we can raise the bar in our
industry and make our Mark as cyber
security superheroes
I challenge each of you to take action
today
connect with your peers start building
your squad and take some of these
concrete steps let's make this industry
better and stronger
we can do it together
thanks for coming with me on this
journey and remember with the right
Squad by your side you can conquer any
challenge that comes in your way
thank you so much
[Applause]
amazing thank you Terry do we have any
questions
we have some time
do you have any uh anecdotal Lessons
Learned or just you know stories from in
the trenches thanks for asking
um
I don't remember if we're under Chatham
House Rules here or not so I'll slightly
anonymize them I think one of the
biggest challenges I've had is there's a
there's a real
motion currently within the cyber
community towards sharing the mic and I
am incredibly supportive to bring to
share the mic with those who are have
been underserved who haven't had a voice
within the cyber community but I'd also
like to see people get paid
and one of the things that I've actively
involved with is making sure that people
who are more Junior in our industry have
the exposure to those of us who've been
around a little longer around what they
should be asking for how they should be
negotiating and and what are the
sometimes the differences from industry
to Industry how do you negotiate in this
industry maybe we talk about total comp
and then this industry base and bonus
are more important I think that is
absolutely Far and Away something I
would love for all of us to really lean
in find the most Junior person you can
invoke the cone of silence and tell them
about your own Journey so that they can
understand what they should be expecting
in their own career
I guess uh when I saw your talks
abstract I thought it was more about
like assembling a team for a purpose and
it seemed to be related to like MIT card
counting at least the uh you know
illusion in the in the title but in
terms of assembling a squad for a
purpose
uh how do you know you have the right
members how do you know you need to
recruit more and where to recruit
I think this is for a purpose right I do
think we you know it's a bit like
collective bargaining right you're
putting together effort for a common
goal even though your own you're only
trying to help yourself you understand
the value of bringing those people
together for that that Collective action
so I think
I call out two things briefly one is
there is a
um there's a high likelihood that you
will start your squad in a least diverse
way
right because you're most likely to
start with people that you're most
familiar with and studies show that
people were most familiar with have the
highest degree of commonality with us we
went to the same University we grew up
together we probably morphologically
look the same so I think it's okay to
start there but if you continue down
that path you're not doing yourself any
favors so I think you have to build in
active growth checks whereby you might
say okay the three of us that's good
enough but you know what if we add a
fourth person it can't be another white
guy
right so I think that's that's one way
to approach it and to have uh growth
checks I think another way is by
bringing in people to share their
perspective because you never know in
the course of those conversations you
may find an ally and they may become a
member of your squad whether it's for a
common purpose at an organization or for
a common purpose like this
uh yeah I also don't mean to sound
argumentative but my question was also
regarding Dei you mentioned uh that you
possibly don't want to hire people who
might you know look like you in order to
get a diversity of ideas right
um how important is it to really test
people not just on that
um inherent trait of appearance or race
or you know sexual orientation Etc but
on their ideas within the interview
process
yeah that's a great question and I to be
clear I don't think I said that we
shouldn't hire people to look like us I
I suggested that when you're building
your squad at a certain point you need
to make sure that you're looking outside
the closeness Circle that you're used to
and you're comfortable with
to that point though I do think there's
a huge
um there's a diversity of thought
um
I I am a disabled neurodiverse single
dad
there are several elements of diversity
there uh I do think however there are
morphological elements that if I look
around a room and everyone's a man I
think there's a problem because 50 of
our world is women so I do think there
are some morphological elements that we
we should look at and we should ask
ourselves hey that's an awfully white
room or gosh why is it all men in that
room and I think those are perfectly
okay ways to start because visually we
get a read on a group based on some of
those morphological traits so it comes
down to say life experience that's de
facto coupled to who you are right is
what you're saying yeah I would say it
doesn't I would say there's a strong
correlation but it doesn't have to be
causation is someone who was raised in
an inner city environment necessarily
also from a economically disadvantaged
home not necessarily but there's a
correlation
appreciate it thank you
I guess one more follow-up is well okay
let's pretend we're doing a startup if I
if I just hire engineers and I can have
a diverse sense of Engineers but if
we're not reaching beyond the
engineering mindset where like we we
have to have sales we have to have uh
you know marketing folks we could have
to get out of that comfort zone as well
so you get a diversity of perspectives
from other disciplines as well right so
um this is sort of like
back to the crack team thing I'm
thinking like do we need a guy who can
do safes do we need a new guy who can
like do uh hacking blah blah but I think
Purity I think there's there's enough
diversity of approach uh for example
I have used uh the the rigor with which
GRC people approach a problem space I
have sometimes asked them to come help
out our vulnerability Management program
right because GRC does a great job of
sort of taking a huge unexplainable
problem and turning it into a framework
and then we've got a list of 20 things
we're going to do right whereas as we
know vulnerability can be something that
we just we feel like it just grinds on
never ends so I do think there's it's
important I don't know that we need to
bring in sales people and marketing
people yet but I do think even within
cyber security there are difference in
approaches and differences in values
even right do we care about speed or
quality more depends on who you ask
it will be our last one
yeah to that point I guess you know
maybe I was expecting something a little
bit different but you know what I think
about my squad at least within my
organization it's my head of legal my
head of quality and compliance it's
folks outside of security who are
natural allies in the challenges that we
have to address
um
what's been your experience you know
bringing in people from outside the
industry into that Squad that's a good
question actually I
um I've worked with this this is from
personal experience I've used this a few
times and I do have squads where uh some
folks most people tend to have a general
background in technology and they
understand how like the modern tech
stack Works they may not be Hands-On but
we can have a conversation right like if
I say Docker they know what I'm talking
about right that's that tends to be my
self-selection criteria but within that
certainly we've had people who have
worked more in the VC space and they can
help us understand
how the money people are going to react
to the things we're talking about or the
things we're building I've worked with
people who have gone from working in the
cyber security
profession as an operator to becoming a
a product person within a cyber security
uh tools vendor and yeah so I I do think
those are related
areas that we're talking about but with
different perspectives
advice that I had earlier on in my
career was essentially you know as
you're you're socializing and you're
building these networks within your
organization you want to try to reach a
level higher rather than at the peer
level
um Can the same thing be applied to
squads
that is a really good and really tough
question and we may not have time to
answer it I would say
um squads tend to have a natural life
cycle
but you probably want to push them to
end sooner
and we talked a little earlier about
having to be intentional about like what
are we going to do over the next two
months four months three years Etc you
may want to Define
um like what is the life of this fund
what is the life of this squad and that
way it there's there's less of a sense
that this is just something that is
going to persist forever but rather it
is a temporary thing that we're all
using for value and I think it builds a
little more commitment because people
realize that I can only take advantage
of this for so long
wonderful thank you that was me another
round of applause please thank you