all right hello everyone thank you for
coming out for b-sides this is our first
year of villages talks uh of hopefully
many more I'm presenting today abhinav
who will be talking about all of the
logistics and uh techniques and his
trial and error of making the astronauts
badge
um abhinav is the founder of hackerware
this is his second year with us as a
hardware Village in badge Village
representative I will now go ahead and
hand it over to abhinav thank you for
kicking it off for us
yeah thank you Aaron and good morning to
all of you uh so I'm here my name is
abhinav I'm here to tell a story about
how we made the astronaut badge if you
guys haven't seen it we have it in the
bash Village
uh so little bit about me I combine
electronic art with Hardware hacking and
I make badges uh for conferences around
the world so we have been
um present across not 12. I really lost
account I think it's 12 countries so far
and lots of big conferences in like
Defcon and HTTP and code blue root con
and uh all sorts of events
um after this conference I will also be
at the RSA we have made the RSA badge as
well so if you guys are on maybe you
want to say hi there uh so there's a lot
of people ask me how I just got into
this thing uh so when I was in college I
really didn't like the the way college
did things like I I found it like
creativity and all so I got frustrated
and then one day I just went like I'm
gonna drop out of college and that's
what I did and back then one of the
Indian conference they wanted to make
badges but they absolutely uh didn't
have any uh way or means to make it
happen because it's just so complicated
to do things and manufacturers not want
to talk to you they're gonna throw lots
of stuff at you and they'll bring up
funded issues with you know why they
design they can't do the design or if
they can do the design they have certain
issues and all so that's how I got
started we made I made badges for an
Indian conference first and then
eventually uh I made badges for Defcon
China there was a village in Defcon
China and that's how it started rolling
and I began expanding to more and more
countries and more and more conferences
so this is my second year at besides SF
I'm really thankful to the crew for
having me back and last year we had a
phenomenal rubber ducky Village you know
we made this inspired by the California
and uh I forgot the trees name yeah so
so it was in like a tree design rubber
ducky badge last year uh
so when I started thinking about making
the badges for this year the the natural
instinct is what's the theme and the
theme was putting cyber in the space and
I was really glad because I was I am a
space Enthusiast myself so I was super
excited uh that they would choose this
name and
um again we didn't want to do just a
blinky batch because uh it's just a
blinky batch and we wanted to bring
something more to it um maybe put some
CTF in it and have some learning done
through it and
um the idea was we'll put some space
facts and space trivia and all in the
city also if you play the CTF you will
come across uh challenges like James
Webb and it will make you go through
some of the NASA resources and things
like that so it's it's fun for even for
people who are not good at Hardware
hacking it's still fun to do this of
nonetheless
and this was sort of an initial design
um with lot of just a black PCB and a
Cosmic Landscape with you know white
silk screen and we had a bunch of uh I
wanted to do a bunch of reverse mod LEDs
uh to Glow the planets and all and of
course the USB port of on it uh but what
happened is essentially uh so we have
done Fair number of the PCB badges
before like uh if I were to go to my
website it has lot of the previous uh
badges that we did and a lot of times we
manage this if you see this batch we
managed uh the shades by basically we
print the white shade and then we print
the red and then we print the black and
then we print the red so you get a
lighter red and then you get a darker
red and stuff like that
um
and that's what how we try to maximize
the design in that way
um by just layering the color the ink
layers on top of one another and the
thing was because over the six years of
time we built our in-house lab so we
have our own machines to do everything
now so we had the freedom and
um uh we had the freedom and time to do
all sorts of these things and pay lot of
attention to detail but yeah it still
was lot of tedious
process to go through each design is
customized then each design is you have
to work through it and all
and so I started wondering uh what do I
do if I want to go beyond it I just I
just don't wanna uh just do the shades
like you know darker or red and
um
and then so one of my friend he was in a
trade show and he overheard that uh he
was seeing a machine like a Euro
printing machine and he overheard it can
print on any surface and then it kind of
ignited the bulb I'm not here it was
like okay if it can print on any surface
can it print on the pcbs and so we
started doing the test uh so I already
had the artwork uh we made this t-shirt
sign hoodies uh before like the one I'm
wearing right now um
in a moon and mass version you know it
just hacked the planet theme and I I
really like the artwork so uh so we made
like a a customized version of it and
which shows this thing so we just uh put
some elements on it for the CTF so we
have the rockets and ISS and then
Supernova colonized planet and all and
the whole idea was Will you will write a
CTF that essentially gives you a feeling
of us or running a space mission so
solving the first challenge glows the
rocket and then the second one it will
put you on the ISS and there it has
challenges to do with James Webb and you
know all sort of stuff uh so this was
the design and
um the astronaut and the Mars kind of
theme and both the CTF and the design
had to go hand in hand with this theme
um so he started doing some early
testing
um
we always been focused on making PCB
single-sided that the reason was I
really like just having a clean PCB look
on the front side
um
and then the components and everything
on the back side so uh this was like one
of the early stage testing we did with
the colors and all and it was having
this matte finish by default and in in
the UV printing there's a technique
called lacquer coating and if you
do the lacquer coating it has the glossy
finish on it
um
and this was the first prototype we
built and it had quite a few issues with
it uh mainly the issue was uh there was
very inconsistent white print uh in UV
Printing and of course one of the issue
that I later on got to know was the most
common with u printing on PCB was that
it turns yellowish so one of the process
in assembly what you do is you for the
soldering you put the board through a
very high intensity kind of a thing
and the UV printing reacts to it in a in
a way that it turns the color yellowish
and so on and that was one of the key
issue we were trying to solve and again
there was this inconsistent print area
it was shifting a lot from what we
wanted uh and these were just bunch of
early issues we had with it uh and the
way
we solve it is first and foremost we
um we we bought out the techniques from
both the old PCB making and then also
the new ones that we were doing and
essentially what we did is we masked the
PCB so on the back side we had the
black masking and in the front side we
had the white masking and on top of the
white masking we would go on to print
the UV printing on it so as a result
what happens is we
fixed that white tissue which was the
inconsistent white print that's how we
could fix it
um
and then the second one was we we could
put a reference point when we were
assembling so let's also face the shift
issue which is like the artwork not
matching the PCB size and then finally
uh for the LEDs we just put it open on
both the masking so as a result we have
the LED is glowing from the back side uh
if you can check it here the LED is
broken from the back side but then the
glow also comes out on the front side
um and yeah that that fixed uh half the
issues and those with especially with
the color correction and all uh and then
the second one the the yellow strain
tissue which is extremely common with
people trying to do sort of this stuff
uh and most
um
people I talk to they really couldn't
fix it uh but we were able to fix it and
the the way we were able to do it is so
in the in the Reflow oven which is the
process for soldering the components
um
and the Machine you can do this profile
and it's basically how much is the
conveyors paid how much is the wind
speed and the temperature and everything
uh uh we did so many experiments and
then had so many fails
um so the the problem is if you put the
temperature too high the boat turns
yellow is for sure and then if the
temperature is too low then it's not
gonna solo properly
so we just kept experimenting and
experimenting and then trying to find
this sweet spot where the components are
soldered but at the same time there's no
allotted issues happening and eventually
we are able to uh find that sweet spot
and we were like yeah we found the
profile and then we made like two copies
of it just to be on safe side
um and noted it down you know history
books and so on uh so
and once we did that so uh we UV printed
the artwork so we black masked on back
side and then white mask on the front
side and then UV print the entire Auto
conference side and then you put it
through the Reflow one and solder it and
oops Yeah and I'm going to go ahead and
focus do not disturb yeah
and so yeah so the take on the PCB now
which is uh we have
uh
moved away from so some of the previous
data badges they featured achieved from
a company called a both
we have moved away from them now
um and we have started using note on
part of the reason is we wanted to have
some
proper support from those companies and
note on was the one they were like we'll
send you engineer to your site and he
will install a software and he'll be
there what do you need it from us and
you know just use our chips and you're
like okay fine I will give you a chance
and yeah it turns out I'm glad it turned
out very well
um they have good support and
[Music]
um
architecture and
we put the micro USB for a very quick
interfacing so even if you don't solve
the challenges here you can just go home
and you just need a micro USB cable and
you should be able to connect your
system and then you should be able to
play the CTF there are pads for uh
reprogramming if you want to dive into
that rabbit hole
um
and then data and maybe your Hardware
hacking pleasure and then we have a
customer server header as well uh
we did it again because I didn't want to
drill any holes on the board
so we it's a very custom SEO design it's
not the conventional one you will see in
batch life and of course all of it is
powered by the coin sale because that's
easiest thing and most suitable
um
so yeah this was pretty much the tech
and
there's a switch for you to turn it off
before connecting the badge and yeah
that's pretty much it so we soldered the
LEDs upside down once again these are
just the standard LEDs
um
so and this was the final form when
everything was done so
this is how it looks when all the
challenges are solved
um it doesn't show the essay although
but you can get this if you solve the
challenges here and just show the badge
that you have sold all changes will give
you the SEO it's like an alien abduction
yourself
um and this is how it looks when all of
it is done and ready
so now designing the SEO so which is uh
again as I said you didn't want to drill
the holes on the board so they it had to
be an like SMD mounted
and we did Fair number of
experimentation with it we tried to
try to see how we can mount it without
going the conventional way and it's just
it's just a single LED that's glowing
this abduction effect uh if you call if
you want to call it
um
and the initial one yeah and that was
the idea but uh so if you use the pth
LED it's going to not mourn properly it
was mounting like uh diagonal sort of
almost and then
we tried with the SMD LED but it wasn't
having the full glow it was just like a
pinpoint glow and but that fixed like
just the same uh so how do you fix it we
basically extended the leads and then
um
put a really nice urge ability on it so
it has this really cool alien abduction
effect
um so yeah but you know stuff like this
uh we always try to
see what new things we can do or not
what Innovative things we can do a lot
of time it's you can argue it's tacky
and I would agree it is a little tacky
but
um the whole point is how we can push
the boundaries of patch life and
try to do unique things and try to try
to experiment with what works and what
doesn't work and thankfully everything
works in this batch
so hopefully next one also was just the
same
uh uh so yeah so the best city of Seoul
um
is built on the
serial monitor setup that we have always
used so you can
use any serial monitor you like you can
use the terminal you need to know the
right tools to connect the batch but if
you don't you just want to get started
with it as a newbie you can download
Arduino which is the open source ID
to code these chips and
in the Arduino you can just select the
right port and that gets you started
it's it's like it takes like two minutes
to get started and that's what we
essentially want you're gonna make more
and more people to participate and more
and more make it accessible for majority
of people to get into it if not everyone
to get into it you just need to have
interest to do things
um
so the city of uh again it's uh
it's not too technical on purpose it's
just
um how to explain it it's more like a
puzzle uh
so you just need to think bit creative
so it's it has crypto puzzles then it
has ocean time it has techno puzzles on
it uh again nothing too difficult to
solve if you just if you know how to
Google things it should be fairly simple
uh again turn off the badge before you
connect the USB because you don't want
to risk it uh and again it won't work
the CTF by Design so you need to you
know turn off the batch before
connection so uh yeah and as usual we
have the three star thing you open the
serial monitors in three stars and the
badge goes into this CTF mode and on the
CTF mode uh it prints out this so we
build lot of ASCII art as well in it so
uh maybe any fans of you know 80s
terminal era uh you guys really gonna
appreciate the asciard
so it's built in that and there's a lot
of um
design and like rockets and ISS done in
SKR for each challenge has asked uh
so uh yeah and if you solve as I said if
you saw all the challenges you get the
SEO the alien abduction SEO and uh and
the fun part is to reset the badge you
have to send the command black hole
that's it so you just type the black
hole and send it and that resets it and
you just connect the batch again
and of course it's me from the last
having my lunch because I didn't get
time uh but yeah so we have the badge
Village to uh encourage the CTF and the
programming aspect of it uh try to get
people into some of the crypto
challenges and you know taking the
challenges in it uh we have plenty of
laptops to for you to try on then we of
course we want to hand out the seos you
will also get the badge there we have I
think 250 Something badges to hand out
without any cost so just only have to
have interest and that should be done
and yeah let's celebrate the bash life
and put cyber in space uh so if you need
any CTF or support or anything you it's
right on this link uh and then there is
a slack challenge if you just slack
channel on the research SF and there's
this bad CTF channel so you can just go
ahead and ask us queries there we'll be
here for entire two days so if you have
any issues for two days I'll be here and
if not you can text me on I don't know
Twitter or any any way you want you can
text and that should be fine and this is
the website so on the website as well
there is a contact form and email and
everything so uh yeah that should be it
I think
thanks a lot for coming to the talk it's
my first talk in U.S and I hope you
liked it so if you have any questions
we'll take questions for
five minutes if not then I will be just
around the badge Village
yeah anyway anybody okay
I was just wondering what is what was
the cost of the badge run about how much
is it per unit
uh cost of the bedroom yeah
um cost per unit and kind of total just
curious
um yeah I think we probably had some run
25 or something with the badger and yeah
and that's again because this was the
first time one of the thing is as I said
uh when I first time when I saw the uh
the UV printing uh samples I was so sold
out we went ahead and purchased the UA
printing machine so we imported it and
that was I don't know fifteen thousand
dollars for the machine but I was very
glad because we could now do the full
color pcbs and the the rest of the
badges we are doing this year all of
them are probably going to be full color
as well uh so yeah there you go yeah
that should be any other question
yeah I think we are yeah I think we are
done here uh thanks a lot and I hope I
will see you in the badge Village uh
yeah have a great day everyone