all right everyone hope you guys are
here to
visit Brienne and see what she has to
talk about today Brienne take it away
all right
hey good afternoon I'm so glad you're
all here
uh for the next 25-ish minutes we are
going to talk about threat modeling
um and we're going to make it cute as
you can see
as an introduction my name is Brianne
Boland I work in product security at
Gusto I really like threat modeling in
part because it puts structured thinking
and a salary on top of my natural
paranoia and Imagination and that makes
me very happy I also write a lot of
fiction which I think uses a lot of the
same skills of just kind of looking
around corners and at a human element I
am currently taking a stained glass
class it is a blast although um
soldering stained glass and soldering
circuit boards very different motions
and artists will laugh at you a little
bit when you adapt
this is me after visiting the Canadian
embassy at the Toronto Airport last
month
we're going to talk about we are going
to look into the past of our fictional
product look at the advice we've
previously given our engineering team
because we are all now the product
security team together by the way it's
you're deputized it's happening today
and then we're going to look forward at
a very new and different feature that
they are proposing which requires us to
stop the gentle complacency that can
creep in if you get used to things and
look at things a little differently
and then at the end we're going to talk
about how to relate this stuff usefully
to the people that need to hear it
a useful note philosophically
there is security that sometimes has to
demand this is security that is more
about suggesting we are advising not
dictating we are here to make friends
and keep them ideally so we want to
suggest rather than just telling people
what their business is it also happens
to be the philosophy of security at the
company I work at which is part of why I
took the job
so we want to point out risk and offer
mitigations and we pop in in a
consultative way rather than being
consistently embedded or making a bunch
of Demands of people all the time
so let's talk our product
we work for a wildly popular snack
loyalty app called snack tracker and the
new product they're looking to debut is
called snack Adder because I guess
there's a Rowan Atkinson fan and product
which we love to see
so snack tracker offers snack tracking
and a rewards website but they want to
go bigger we've had a popular app for a
long time both mobile and web and we
want to partner with fine snack shops
across our test region to have in-person
check-ins and bonuses adding an extra
Dimension to the experience that just
wasn't there before
what we want to do is have tablets of
some kind specifics not determined yet
where users can go and they can logs
next to their wish lists they can check
into specific locations they can get big
rewards at special events something that
hasn't been possible till now
we have previously expanded existing
features but it's been a while since
we've had something completely new and
both product and security teams can be
used to things and it's time for us to
break out
to give you a sense of context of where
we're coming from
up until now there have been two kinds
of users there are shop owners and there
are snack fiends
shop owners need to see customer details
snack Trends and reviews and cash out
loyalty points snack fiends however need
to see their account details and point
balances learn about events enter and
update their snack preferences and
adjust communication details yeah pretty
normal stuff
both types of users logged into the same
mobile and web apps any differences came
from authorization after they were
logged in
so our challenge is that all previous
threat modeling and security guidelines
were done in the context of this
specific use
you could depend on things like users
entered their username and they're
definitely long random used only once
passwords because our users are the best
people in the world because this is my
story and it can be that way foreign
and that meant that only one maybe two
users would use a single device ever
which made things like convincing people
to do MFA easy those snack points are
popular and we also bribed people with
bonus points for setting it up
the way we approached it before sessions
for snack fiends if they checked they
were on a private device lasted up to a
month and this was easy because it was
only on their own device no sharing
shop owners it was a little less we did
kind of more of a like Bank credit card
model because there's transactions going
on there so we logged them out after a
minute or two of an activity
and it's useful to remember snack fiends
are not used to needing to log out after
app use and that's something we're going
to have to account for
looking forward though
the in-person team is super psyched they
want a simpler way for users to check in
at this in-person shared device that
doesn't involve those long complex
beautiful passwords in the MFA we've
previously previously pushed them into
instead the user is only going to
interact with the tablet for like a
minute maybe less so enter snack adder
the users the snack fiends went to log
snacks and get rewards the shop owners
want to allow the customers to log
snacks and also not have more work or a
new vulnerability to worry about
so our goal is to offer actionable
security advice to a product team that
is excited to move fast we want to
protect our users and their data and we
also want the product team to want to
talk to us after this is all over
let's look at the advice we've given
them before
and then aside if you haven't bumped
into threat modeling it's a good day
because you're about to learn something
really cool
and it's core it's just an organized way
of examining something you know feature
product system situation and looking at
where risk might occur we look for
opportunities where vulnerabilities
could be exploited we want to quantify
what we find so that it's understandable
and actionable and then we want to offer
assessments and guidance to those
responsible for what's being evaluated
so they can make things better for our
users
there are lots of good threat modeling
Frameworks out there and lots of
opinions about them if you haven't dug
into it before look up stride pasta
miter attack if you want to get a sense
of how big the world is and what you
don't know yet
for us though we're going to do a little
more informally and just kind of look
piece by piece of what we're dealing
with
tales of the past what have we told them
about web and mobile app stuff and past
context matters when you're working with
the same Engineers across time because
you get the chance to either give them
deeper knowledge when you're bringing up
something familiar again or point out
that there's something completely new
coming up
um so if you get to build those
relationships a little bit of depth gets
to emergency do that
so in our case some of the engineers
there are familiar with our people we've
worked with they've brought some new
folks in for this new initiative too
so this is something that we would ask
them to review anyway
so like encryption we give the usual
advice you know encrypt things in trans
and arrest use a good like current
industry standard encryption Cipher and
for this because we're a good
full-service security team we point to
our robust library of available
knowledge and we say hey check this out
we keep this up to date for you we
updated every six months or as necessary
whichever comes first
and it lets people stay on top of things
authentication similar uh as it happens
at snack tracker we have an
authentication team because we are
blessed and we're able to say hey just
talk to them about what we have been
doing lately just do that there are
great things to innovate on we recommend
for this just going with it because we
trust our team
authorization
you know along with just having certain
actions attached to the user we also
want to make sure that in code you know
connected to uh
you know different functions they might
access that they're allowed to do that
um
sessions as I said not too short not too
long varying depending on the function
that's actually going on there
uh for user info things like please use
uuids rather than anything sequential
that you can enumerate or possibly Brute
Force
um you know scope usually either
permissions appropriately for both
regular users and admins
going to secure libraries you know going
back to that robust Library
recommendations we say please if you can
go and pick something off the menu there
if not we'll dig into it for you
and we also of course mandate
user-dependabot because uh we like
ourselves
privacy concerns
um
so we have a really wonderful tight
relationship with the legal team I like
them because they are word-based
organisms which I also am
but we also have a lot in common so it
makes more sense if we work really
tightly together and as a result we're a
security team that can give some
guidance around the laws of various
states and countries things around data
retention what you should do
you know deeper questions we're like you
should go talk to a lawyer about that
but for this we also push a very
specific philosophy of data which is
please do not ask for it please do not
store it if we do not actually need it
does it pertain to snacks no don't ask
so in this case do we care about
someone's gender if they just want to
snack I certainly hope not so if we
don't need it don't request it and we
don't have to worry about it
but let's look to the Future
going back to that last question so how
little data can we collect with this
particular feature
and in ways this is better and easier
because the scope of it is going to be
so much less there are going to be a
really limited number of actions that a
user can take within what they're
proposing
and it does give one interesting
opportunity so because we have a very
healthy respect for our snack fiends we
have never collected location data
before we just didn't want to get it off
their mobile Device just because it
makes us feel funny and we don't like
that however if someone opts into using
a device that's tied to location that's
very different so we have the
opportunity to collect geographical
information when people do check-ins
other than that though because this is
so pared down there are much less
concerns
next up and this is one of the big
interesting questions here
how is authentication going to work if
they don't want to use something that is
so similar to you know everything else
everything that this company has ever
done
and we like encouraging developer teams
to do new things we like Innovation it's
great but we want to make sure they're
imagining in the good way and not going
toward things that we just don't want to
invite in the house
so in this case what kind of credential
or login method is appropriate for
one-time use without a user session that
persists we're not expecting people to
type in their long unique passwords on
an unfamiliar device when a line of
frantic snack fiends is developing
behind you as some of you might relate
to with what you just experienced in the
hallway because conferences
so what are we going to do instead
so one option that's proposed by our
team who are wonderful enough to come up
with ideas and bring them to us what
about a pin
what if it's only used for this specific
thing you couldn't enter it as a
password you can just enter a pin and
you know people have a context for it
with phones with ATMs they'll go right
with it
and we say yeah it's thank you for
suggesting that's a very interesting
idea
ultimately we decide like we'll keep it
in mind we want to stay open
but security feels a little queasy about
making an equivalence between a even six
or eight digit PIN in a proper password
so we're like yeah you know thank you
for thinking of that uh what else do you
have
and the next idea they bring also
interesting uh meaning that in a good
way
I've seen this call I haven't I haven't
seen a really specific consistent term
for it so I'm going to call it second
screen authentication if you know a term
that everyone knows for it I want you to
come and tell me because I've had
fruitless Googling around this this is
the kind of authentication where
on one device you have you know an
existing authenticated session and you
want to log in on say your TV on a
streaming service and you don't want to
put your password in using a remote
control because we only have so many
hours in the day
so instead what you do is give it your
user ID it gives you a short code six
letters is what I've usually seen you
enter into an authenticated session and
hey it's Hulu wonderful
and we're like yeah that's that's
interesting people have the context for
that people are getting used to that
it's definitely shorter
and that establishes like a different
kind of session that's happening there's
a paradigm for this cool cool right
so we consider that like that is a
decent suggestion
but our product team loves us and they
have another option
and they say
what about a QR code
and they explain that what they're
picturing is a
you know and they they can predict some
of our our arguments they're like it'll
be dynamically generated it won't be
static all the time not easy to share
it'll be unique to a person and they
generate it on their device and just go
Boop and they're in
and so we think about that and
considering the level of uh State change
happening here the data involved this
could be a good thing so officially we
say we'll go off and think about that
but what we're really going to do is go
and further refine our existing guidance
around things like sanitizing input just
to educate our team about the weird
sneaky stuff that can be stuck in QR
codes
foreign
then there's the question of
authorization and that's really key here
because the whole thing revolves around
a scope down set of operations
and this gets interesting to you because
roles and permissions are often really
foundational in a product you know
they're innate to an MVP like literally
what can people do here
but the ownership of it and sometimes
the fragility of code can mean that
later on it gets really weird to change
stuff and there are a couple ways this
can exist one is that um
either people are very protective
reasonably or otherwise it's not easy to
make changes and so it becomes kind of
calcified and people have to work around
it in weird ways not ideal
the other version is that it is too easy
to change things and that means you end
up with this big like chaos Katamari
ball of things that the original role
designers did not intend and did not
foresee
and across time you can have really
weird side effects like you know hitting
up a certain API endpoint and going I
did not ask for this and who is this
person's medical information
so the recommended approach that we end
up coming up with in part because we
don't want to just do unnecessary edits
to the existing permissions is to think
of it
like
third-party integration
where you give an API key you know think
like a GitHub personal access token your
account might have all these permissions
but the token might have this one and so
that's what we're doing here that's what
we encourage the team to do and we're
talking to them fairly early no code has
been written yet so we can be kind of
high level about this and be like yeah
come back and tell me exactly how you
implement that I would love to see it
so in this case it would allow admin
functions just saying like you are
authorized to say I belong to this place
people can log into the store within
this session
and then it will do one-off operations
for users who connect to the store
through that device
there's also the question then of how to
invalidate it
the snack shop owner situation gets
interesting because like a lot of small
businesses the owner is not necessarily
there every day and they definitely
don't necessarily want to give an admin
level password to someone who maybe
works there 10 hours a week
so the compromise that we reach is we
say hey yeah this session can be two
weeks and if you find that's not long
enough and people still need more than
that come back and we'll talk and we'll
look at your user research and see what
we can reasonably recommend
but it flips though with the snack
fiends that instead we say we want this
to be limited to a single operation they
Boop and then they log one snack they
Boop and they check in once and that's
it
and also we recommend uh by the way we
need to have it possible to revoke this
tablet session in case that tablet grows
legs
so then there's the question of asking
them to drill down more into what the
state changes can be things like
for the snack fiend password changes
redemptions and points because that
requires a cashier stuff like that
totally off limits
it's only just here's my account I want
to do a check-in or an activity that
gets me points I want this new very
exotic flavor of Hot Cheetos that's what
we're gonna do
and then there's the physical context
which historically we mostly haven't had
to worry about
because unlike the current shop owner
use instead of the uh the admin level
device being right in front of them it
might be across the store behind a giant
display of cookies it might be out of
sight because it doesn't require
attending
so then what are our expectations for
putting it in place for initial setup
the shop owners aren't necessarily there
every day and we really can't in the way
of small businesses expect a dedicated
technical staff I suspect a lot of
people in this room have been the go-to
dedicated technical contact for some of
your friends and relatives that's the
best we can expect is someone like us
just being drawn in
so we need to keep it pretty simple and
it becomes more and more in our interest
to offer some security guidance because
the folks that are involved in doing
this stuff probably aren't familiar with
a lot of that
then there's the question of what this
thing's actually going to be
in the way of product folks who've been
talking to marketing our team comes to
us with really big Ideas they say words
like custom form factor
which feels bad to hear they say what if
we got into device manufacturing what if
there was branding it could be immersive
yeah it's a whole experience and they
start using
um nice big lofty high level words and
that's when we start going the mean
that's a very I'm writing this down it's
a very interesting idea but we want to
be encouraging
so what we do is listen to what they
want to do and then Scurry off and Talk
Amongst ourselves
and in this case we decide pretty
quickly
we do not want to be in the business of
device manufacturing we are in the
business of uh recording details about
chips that's a very different thing and
we're not we don't think we're ready yet
however this is the kind of
recommendation I would escalate pretty
pretty highly before I actually said
anything like that because maybe who
knows in some two years ahead of us plan
there is something that says like you
know what we need to do is like custom
tablets for the chip people
so what I would do is go talk to my
manager and probably also go say hello
to RC so just to say hey I heard this
I'm not married to a feeling either way
yet but like tell me what you think
about this
and in the case of our story I get a
nice wide-eyed long couple seconds of
Silence before getting confirmation that
no we don't want to do that because
manufacturing devices is a completely
different kettle of fish that is not a
snack that our snack fiends are eager
for
and it also would require hiring for
skills we've never had to hire for in
order to do this even vaguely
effectively
so this becomes in the way of ranking
recommendations kind of
I'm afraid I must insist on this uh
we'll call it a do-level recommendation
compared to try and consider
um so fortunately we've all agreed over
insecurity we don't want to get into the
business of specialized device
manufacturer
we as a security team go off and have a
sigh of relief and maybe just go have a
nice fizzy beverage to commemorate that
our lives aren't getting that much worse
today
say is hey what we could do we could
offer security guidance to shop owners
for choosing the device for equipping it
definitely for keeping it up to date
um
providing them security advisories that
they might not encounter in the weight
of their regular business
especially because we can definitely
expect some secondhand device use in the
mix in the way of people being
resourceful
all right so we've got some initial
recommendations for what our product
team is proposing
how do we explain it effectively
there are a few ways one of the ones I
really like to be good on is uh having
very very clear and as concise as
possible recommendations in a written
form this is worth spending some time on
and doing a few drafts if you are not
thrilled about this work which is valid
give it a shot and then reach out to
someone maybe on your team even better
someone who's kind of like the sort of
people you're trying to reach with this
stuff to get them to look it over and
say Hey you hit it or just like yeah
this paragraph I read it and I don't
actually know what you want me to do I
just think you're kind of mad at me
so get that second opinion just keep
refining and just remember like it's a
skill like anything else it takes time
to really nail it
it's also useful just whenever you can
to ground things in really specific
security principles this gives us
consistency across time which is super
useful but also when you work with teams
a lot they will start to be able to get
a sense of what you're going to say
before you say it and do preventative
work to answer your questions before you
raise them and this is the best thing
and to cultivate that it is useful to
offer some knowledge to people it
doesn't have to be exhaustive it can
just be a link at the end going hey man
if you want to know more about this you
might really enjoy this blog post from a
couple of years ago that explains it
well
this is a favorite of mine because it is
a big part of how I became a security
engineer
um getting to read more stuff that
connected somewhat to the work I was
doing but added new depth and explained
what the you know co-workers I really
liked her out to Super useful and uh
also really good for the relationship
building
beyond that
I am afraid I'm here to tell you that
sometimes you need to go to more
meetings
but some of them are good actually and
some of them are necessary meetings are
good when relaying your recommendations
if it's a team you're not familiar with
and you don't know yet how they're going
to react it's really good to be there to
see the the misconceptions come into
place and get ahead of them just kind of
like throw yourself in front of it
it also keeps you from relaying on
third-party versions of what you sent
over people like to read and interpret
and it ends up in a game of tech
telephone and that is very painful and
we can avoid it in part
by showing up you don't have to do it
all the time but just especially when
initiating relationships it's a really
good idea just to have it be a
conversation
but of course make sure your
recommendations stand on their own too
because they are going to persist so
much longer
it is also useful to maintain a
philosophy of offering help that we are
here to assist and not to prohibit we
are there to enable people to do their
jobs and not have sad times
um we're trying to make their lives
better and their products and we
actually are allies even if sometimes
people don't feel like it or they've had
days at other jobs where that actually
wasn't the case we can do some good by
healing things over a little bit
and finally ask
for feedback a lot ask for it in
different forms here is my survey link
here is where you should DM me here is
the official feedback form here is uh
what I want to know about in particular
I tried this thing can you tell me if it
worked for you if not you have any ideas
about what would work better the more
you ask for it the more people will
believe that you actually mean it and
across time you will get a steady flow
of more information
so keep soliciting it it's how we get
better it can feel funny but it's great
actually
finally
is for you
push against complacency it is a lot
easier to do it if you're doing it
regularly instead of just when you see
something completely new and go like oh
yeah I need to shift my brain into
something different
the more you can try to cultivate
beginner's mind you know treat every new
feature like you're first Falling in
Love
it's useful and it's better to cultivate
it as a habit rather than having to
massively course correct after you've
really become entrenched in something
try to
you know just try creative things to
explain things well you know that can be
that really good concise description of
what you need I like metaphors that's
not everyone's strength but it's useful
to be able to cycle through a couple
comparisons of things and then see
someone's eyes light up as you see them
get it super gratifying and it works
really well
when you're relaying stuff
try to cut the noise reduce things as
much as you can so that it's
straightforward reads easy and there's
no question about what you're asking
people to do
and make it clear when you're talking to
people that you actually are here to
encourage their cool ambitious technical
work rather than be an obstacle we're
not just here to penalize things with
heavier overhead we're just here to make
sure that they can actually do the
things they want and not have it cause a
terrible week six months in the future
and finally
ask the people you serve how you can do
better over and over and mean it every
time
thank you very much
thank you
[Applause]
folks we have a little bit of wiggle
room if you have questions for bran we
have maybe one or two questions
and some test tickets am I going to the
wrong direction or like recommendation
properties you know
okay the question was about once you've
formulated your recommendations
and correct me if I'm wrong if they're
just being put into jira tickets is that
the wrong direction for actually getting
them adopted that did that
no it's part of the right direction for
sure
um things do need to be tracked if you
just put something in like a Google doc
or a Confluence page it's a great way to
never see it again so I like the
combination of like I've written
something for you and it is connected to
these tickets so that they actually
offer some kind of accountability and
usually a deadline and you can assign it
to someone so no they're actually
incredibly useful if you're a tiny
company you can probably get away with
just like I have crafted for you this
finest report it will definitely do
everything that I want but if you're
more than about five people like yeah
you went somewhere Central to track all
that stuff and just do a lot of linking
back and forth
yeah thanks
any other questions feel free to raise
your hand I'll walk up with a mic if you
can speak louder
okay
uh yeah how can you make sure that
you're one of the things that you're
talking about is when you're going to
meetings to explain the recommendations
that you're making how can you make sure
that you're included on those meetings
rather those are happening without
it okay yeah the question was those
meetings to follow up on things how do
you make sure you're actually included
in them instead of them happening when
you don't know
um part of it is uh being a ruthless
stalker of calendars it's not my
favorite method but it is one way just
if you know certain people that are
going to be involved in it yeah be a
giant Google Calendar creep it is useful
um it's not the softest method but it
will get your answers
beyond that just like having those
regular conversations and checking in
saying like I actually do care about
this hey please involve me generally you
can ask too many times and be ignored
without the other person looking kind of
awful so neither of these things is 100
but together they end up covering a lot
of it
you know the other thing is that a lot
of this you know you in my experience
I've had conversations with the folks
involved across time it's how I knew
they had anything to review
so we just stay conversational and you
know I put extra effort into like making
it a bubbly candy colored experience
sometimes people respond well to it and
it lets you get actual security work
done too
thanks thanks
yet again oh one more question over here
thank you
I appreciate it second screen
authentication is called device
authentication flow
now the talk is officially worth it
thank you it's really bothered me
yeah now we all learned
cool
once again let's give Brianna theater
15.