hello everybody and welcome to B-side
San Francisco 2023.
so my name is Reed Loden and I am the
president lead organizer for B-side San
Francisco
um we're so very excited to have
everybody here again in person uh once
again
um we hope you've grabbed some uh
breakfast and are ready for a full day
of events our thing this year is
security putting the Cyber in space we
chose this theme to commemorate the new
James Webb Space Telescope and as an
homage to cyberspace
our 100 volunteer team has worked
tirelessly to make this event possible
um it's uh you know it's it's put on
foreign by the community it's uh you
know our goal is basically to expand the
spectrum of conversations uh it again
but you know again 100 volunteer managed
uh it's about 19 different leads helping
throughout the year plus an additional
attendant or so staffers supporting
various departments several special
teams including our call for papers
review team our Capture the Flag team
and almost 200 volunteers helping us out
this weekend to actually run the event
so there are no attendees at a b-sides
event everybody is a participant uh we
want everybody to add something of value
to the conversation
so we have three floors uh this year
that ahala have different things going
on we've changed up the layout uh a bit
so make sure to walk around and explore
there's a lot of things on the schedule
this year
so the the we have uh right there we're
on AMC this is where all the talks will
be except for the village talks will be
on the fourth floor mezzanine is where
you registered and then on the fourth
floor in City View will be everything
else it'll be all the villages where
food and drink where our party will be
um and everything else you get the CTF
and everything else you can think of
so lots of opportunities for
conversation uh this year uh so make
sure to check out your full schedule on
sched and in your program as well again
our goal this for this year's event is
to maximize the space for uh
collaboration and communication so again
we've rearranged the space so everything
on the fourth floor is now part of our
participant Hall we added three new
Villages this year we have the bug bunny
Village the cloud Village and our
reimagined career Village
what okay
technology is hard
let's try this again
and now that my notes are not here
give me one second sorry folks
I love Chromebooks but sometimes they
can be really annoying
uh but I want to
nope that's not right either
fine we'll do it the old-fashioned way
where are my notes there we go
that's fine we'll wing it
um cool so uh let's see
there we go cool uh participant Hall
upstairs we have the uh the capture flag
is in Twin Peaks uh the career village
is all the way down the hall in
Embarcadero and then again something new
this year we're actually having free
headshots for everybody
um so you uh it's gonna be a long line
all day so just uh you know if you want
a headshot again you know we understand
that there's a lot of turmoil in the
economy lots of folks are getting laid
out and such and so we wanted to offer
something new this year uh to folks to
be able to update your LinkedIn profiles
and such so please make sure to take
advantage of that we also have Village
talks this year are also all the way
down at the end where the uh for those
folks that were here last year the CTF
used to be or uh will be the village
talks and then make sure to enjoy the
lounge out on the patio
um
so there's a lot of cool stuff going on
the lounge is sponsored by uh by slack
this year so very happy for that we have
lunch from 12 to 1 30 in Embarcadero
coffee and espresso are from now until 5
PM we have the bar until 5 30 in the bar
in chill out space sponsored by conveyor
happy hour is sponsored by Ori and they
are from 5 30 to 6 30 in the bar in
Charlotte space and the Saturday night
party brought to you by lacework is from
6 30 to 9 30 in Embarcadero and on the
patio we have some really cool things
for the party so make sure to stay after
the happy hour and enjoy yourself
[Music]
let's see so additional Services we have
a mother zoom in prayer room if you need
to access that just go to the info desk
and they can help you out something that
we had last year and we brought back for
this year is our emotional support via
Dr Sarah so if you want to talk to a
counselor about anything going on in
your life we have that available just go
to the info desk for more information
there
so using slido again for Q a if you just
go to slido.com or slide At Doe on your
device enter in besides SF 2023 and pick
the appropriate track for the talk and
you can just go and ask questions for
each of the uh the talks there
uh we want to hear if we've made a if
we've created an atmosphere for
conversation we want you to give us
feedback we you know this is it takes us
year round to do this event and again
all of us have day jobs as well and
stuff and so we really need your
feedback to know what we're doing right
what we're doing wrong what we need to
change
um so please provide us feedback we go
through every single piece of feedback
that you give us so you can provide
feedback at besides sf.org feedback or
if you have a particular feedback about
a session or something go on on scad and
there's an option at the bottom to
actually provide feedback on that talk
um so we could use your help again 100
volunteer run a lot of us have been
doing this for a while
um and so could always use more help
here so again all of us have separate
day jobs uh that actually pay the bills
because again none of us are paid to do
this for all volunteers so we knew new
faces uh we have to you know keep
besides going uh in the future and that
takes means bringing on new folks so if
you're interested in taking on an active
Hands-On role year-round it does take
about a year to put on this event
um please sign up at besides sf.org jobs
so I want to talk about a little bit
about code of conduct
um it's it's pretty simple it's show
respect and tolerance for each other's
uniqueness be kind and practice the
Golden Rule simply put do not be an ass
or we'll kick your ass out that's really
what it boils down to so absolutely no
tolerance for physical verbal or sexual
harassment intimidation or
marginalization of any human robots are
okay though
um if
you have an issue or witness any
Behavior not consistent with our code of
conduct report it to any radioed staff
member we're in the very bright pink
shirts this year are any of the safety
officers in the orange shirts again if
you want a full copy of the code of
conduct there's some signs everywhere
and then also check the printed program
as well
video photo policies uh you know we're a
bit different of a conference um you
know most conferences nowadays don't
have any kind of policies like this but
one thing that we like to have is um is
that we respect people's privacy and so
uh before you take any photos or videos
uh we just ask that you get permission
of everybody in the frame
um we actively discourage crowd shots uh
you know and that uh and if you have
mistakenly taken a photo or video of
somebody
um and if they uh you know delete it and
if they if you're asked by somebody to
delete or blur a photo you did please
respect that now there's one exception
to this we do have an official besides
photographer
um so she is right around that she may
be in here there she is right there
awesome so she is allowed to take
pictures and such because but she is
more than happy if if she's taking a
picture and you're like I don't want to
be in that just let her know she will
make sure that you're not in it or blur
it appropriately so thank you
um so every year I would like to do some
t-shirt Charities uh take this
opportunity to give back we've actually
sold out of almost all of our t-shirts
via pre-sales which is amazing that like
never happens
um so there are a few shirts remaining
so please go to code check uh to get
those it's really cool shirts this year
they're actually glow in the dark
um so really cool and and uh we have
three different charities we're
supporting this year we have uh noise
Bridge eff and tectonica and so the the
net sales proceeds are going to be
benefiting these Charities so when you
pick up your shirt if you're already pre
bought one or if you're buying one Anew
you had the opportunity to actually
decide which charity you'll be
supporting
so again thanks to all of our sponsors
there's no way that we could do it
without them so let's take a second and
just give a round of applause to all of
our sponsors
I want to especially call out our four
leading sponsors this year we have Adobe
appiro code red partners and Google
um again it's we while we're they uh
we're actually the third biggest b-sides
in the world
um but we are by far the most expensive
besides to put on just because it's San
Francisco and everything is crazy
expensive here
um and so we could not do it without the
sponsors uh you know and so it's uh it's
very important
um to please go up and uh say hi to all
the sponsors so in your registration
bags is a our sponsor passport
um and so if you go to each one of the
booths own that passport and get their
stamp you have the ability to
participate in our sponsor raffle the
sponsor raffle will be at 12 30 today
and tomorrow near the b-sides booth in
the participant Hall we have some really
awesome raffle prizes I was looking
through them earlier really cool stuff
so make sure you do that just uh get
your passport out of your bag get it
stamped and get it turned in at the
b-sides booth in time for uh 12 30 today
and then the ones that are in there
we'll roll over to tomorrow as well so
we have some really awesome stuff too so
again I want to do a major shout out to
all of our sponsors again we could not
do it without you so thank you once
again