uh I'm gonna start some timers up here
because this is going to be condensed my
first time given this talk it's one that
I wanted to do for a very long time uh
it's about seven years of physical
penetration testing kind of my career
Journey from coming from absolutely
nothing not knowing anything about the
industry to seven years later
um performing dozens of heists you know
break into critical infrastructure even
getting arrested once along the way so
it's going to be a good talk hopefully a
lot of good stories here and then the
pictures are chef's kiss whatever makes
it work so who am I first of all I'm a
director of the red team at Coal Fire so
I lead a team of Associates we go out
and Consulting break into all the things
a lot of the engagements that we do are
virtual so probably a lot of stuff that
you're familiar with obviously this talk
is going to be focused on physical
security there's some social engineering
components anything past that that I'm
interested in is ethical hacking SDR
lock picking Etc a list of my
certifications below and then some
non-certification stuff but courses that
I've taken from Red Team Alliance
include covert methods of Entry alarm
bypass Access Control safe manipulation
and all that sexy good stuff like I
mentioned on the first hopefully last
wrongfully arrested Red Team or along
with my partner in crime so to speak
Gary di Mercurio I've done a couple
talks before
um b-sides I think was the first talk I
ever gave down in Tampa that's where I'm
from Florida man so good to see you all
over here on your Coast
um keynote at secure world uh did a dark
net Diaries episode and that's still
probably one of my favorite things that
I've done we did black hat as well on
b-sides is always going to have a
special place in my heart since the
first security conference that I ever
went to and then thought Con coming up
so if no one's going there I will see
you there
all right so the talk
um we're gonna go back round again like
I said how I got into the industry some
of the first engagements the highlight
reels that show some of the pictures or
some of the best parts
um career details kind of like what I
see uh physical security uh being what
it's going to develop into and on our
industry Outlook going forward so I
think it's very important the first
question that we ask ourselves why phys
SEC right why physical security
um for me personally there's nothing
better to rob banks and break into the
critical infrastructure so that's why I
do it from the information security
standpoint it's absolutely invaluable as
and don't roast me for this but I think
externally virtually things may be
getting a little bit more secure over
time or at least out of the box things
seem to be happening a little bit better
so as organizations mature and we're
testing things properly sometimes the
external infrastructure does get locked
down past that people I see breaching
nowadays uh primarily stems from social
engineering attacks and going down the
road as that gets more hardened defense
the one thing that we're not looking at
is physical security so if you can walk
into a building or if you have your
employees in there you have Insider
threats that can walk around and
circumvent all the virtual controls that
you've put in place what happens then
what happens if somebody walks right
into the security operations center
right
so uh along with that I see even in the
infosec community we see a lot of people
come to conferences like this and they
say well what's what's the lock picking
Village what's going on there this is a
hacking conference right
not wrong not wrong but that's our first
tangible exploit that we have in our
hands where we can see a lock pop open
right in front of our eyes and that
feedback just you can see it in
everyone's eyes the first time they Pop
A Lock and it's so important and it
drives you know a whole different type
of security that I think if we're not
looking at and not educating our
customers on we're doing them a
disservice so
I've been going around for a little
while building this talk out like I said
it's my first time giving it so super
excited for this
um but you know I solicit advice from
people that I meet out at the bar or
what have you first question like
invariably I wanted a couple plants in
here so we do live
um but the first question I get is how
did you break in the industry how do you
do this like that's a crazy job never
heard of that very fair question right
so I came out of college I was working
in a grocery store I was a marketing
degree I had no idea what I was going to
do right so things got pretty real after
I had to like face the real world and
start making my own money
um what was I going to do for work you
know I was technically inclined I had a
couple passions
um there were breadcrumbs along the way
where I should have been in this
industry a lot earlier you know I had
backtrack installed on the family
computer back in whatever 19 something
but then once the Anarchy's cookbook got
found on that parents kind of kicked me
off the computer for a number of years
so that's to me that for sure
um so I'm sitting there and I'm
wondering you know what I'm what am I
passionate about what do I love love
doing and then there's a lot of things
that can be fun you know if you're an
artist or something like that but I
didn't want to be a starving artist how
do I intersect that with profitability
how do I marry my passions with
profitability and that to me the answer
was simple Urban exploration I loved
breaking into abandoned construction
sites abandoned military bases what have
you many of the photos that we see here
about half of these are from a Nike
missile site in Florida if you don't
know back in the Cold War we installed a
lot of missile sites around the country
specifically in South Florida to
intercept ballistic missiles coming from
countries like Cuba right so before they
could reach their targets these missiles
would intercept obviously all
decommissioned now but a lot of this
still exists and it's amazing to go and
explore that kind of stuff around Denver
I loved exploring a Titan II missile
silo which is essentially an underground
city and you can just walk around
there's like you know a rocket ship
that's stored underground it's not there
anymore all decommissioned as well but
see like our history and what that all
meant it was incredible and then the
rest of these photos are just from Urban
exploration around Denver once I got the
job so that was very clear I started
researching urbex and then found out
that that could be a job there's
something where you can break into
buildings and then help them secure it
by exposing how that was done the first
taste I got from that was watching
deviants talks right so probably a lot
of people know him he's on YouTube all
over the place so he had a wonderful
playlist and just every day you know I'd
be working 12 to 16 hours for two months
at a time without a break opening up
this grocery store and at night I was
just hooked I knew this is what I wanted
to do I had the vision I didn't really
know how I was going to get there but I
knew that's what I wanted to do so every
night I would come home I'd watch his
videos while I'm cooking I have a couple
of slides here about other other things
that I was researching to help me get
into this industry
um one of the first things I did with
that was I realized okay this is
information security that's kind of
where this is housed
um you know a military government does
some things differently there's other
routes there but I wanted to be an
infosec I realized hacking is where all
the money flows through in this industry
gonna have to Buck Up gonna have to
learn computers so that's the first
computer I ever built which was in a
milk crate from the grocery store they
kindly donated it to me without their
knowledge and I still contend this is
like the absolute Pinnacle of form
factor I mean it's portable it's
stackable it has all the ports you can
plug everything in if you're not doing
it in a milk crate you're doing it wrong
so then I started learning about barcode
hacking so I was learning everything I
could I mean it was all the secret
knowledge coming from the dark web and I
just couldn't get enough anything that
was forbidden fruit I had to have it had
to have a taste so I was on tour all the
time and I saw a barcode hacking I'm
like what is this so this is back in
2013 2014 essentially it's a client side
um verification vulnerability so you can
print up a barcode that says for this
product it's going to be 50 or 100
discounted applied to the product and
then it never sends to the back server
to verify and check that this was a huge
vulnerability rampant like people were
sweeping the nation with this uh Purple
Lotus was one of the people that I was
buying barcodes from never using but
like just fascinated with it learning
how it all worked and it really got me
hooked on that but again I'm working in
a grocery store how do I make this work
right how do I learn on the job so we
had a huge issue for this new grocery
store that we opened up none of the
barcodes printed from the deli for
whatever your chicken salad would scan
at the register there was a mismatch in
formats or the checksum what have you so
that's where I got to apply all the
knowledge I learned from barcode hacking
on the job and then we ended up making
all the barcodes work had to reprogram
everything we got things jamming so it
was super cool any other opportunity I
had to practice physical security I
absolutely had to execute on it so I was
on the hunt everyone knew to come to me
for it so somebody got locked out of
their locker one day and they needed
their tea for lunch so I made a little
shim out of a Pepsi can shimmed up with
the padlock got them out their tea and
then the look on that face when I
delivered their teeth they're like how
did you do that man that's the coolest
thing
um so same deal one day somebody locked
their keys in their car probably like a
1995 Honda Civic and this still like
kind of blew my mind for a long time
until I realized what had happened here
anybody know what the keys on the bottom
there are says Club Car anybody you can
shout it out
golf cart keys right so this is another
huge vulnerability that we see there's
key to like systems so this one key
operates all golf carts not gonna die
two feet into that but what I did was I
took this key used it as a Jiggler just
on the front door of the car and that
popped it open and if you notice there's
a little bit smaller than a real car key
I had to ask Stevie and years later I'm
like hey man like this happened how did
that work he's like oh it's a valet key
so for the valet for the Pat or for the
driver's side of the door they only used
half the key space about that front half
of the key and this was just the right
length to touch all those uh pins and
scrub it open so any chance I took try
to apply it on the job one of the things
that really stuck with me throughout
this I had a Comcast tech that came by
the house one time he's like man I've
been in the industry doing Comcast stuff
whatever it is that they do for 10 years
and I really want to get an infosex
sorry for all everyone that works at
Comcast here uh he's like I really want
to get into infosec you know and one one
day I'm gonna do it I'm like man that
guy's been in there for 10 years it was
daunting to me I'm working at a grocery
store and this is the first thing I want
to do but I vowed that I wasn't going to
let that happen to me don't let your
dreams be dreams I was going to go out
there pursue it and get it
so the path to get there again pretty
nebulous I didn't know how it was going
to go but I knew certs were a big thing
right that's kind of a big thing in our
industry so I started from scratch again
I had to learn how to build a computer
how to troubleshoot it and unfortunately
that was the a plus certification which
I'm actually not gonna dog on it I love
that cert I love these books and for 22.
the 1300 pages of information that
provided I read every single page and
this Lata Foundation unlike anything
else that's still today and especially
with the network plus a lot of other
Security Professionals have gaps you
know we're all kind of siled we have
overlapping knowledge but not always the
same that really helps pull things
together for me so I did the same thing
passed that certification went on to
network plus paid 46 bucks read all 800
pages of that and after that I was about
ready to quit because nobody wants to
learn about ipv4 and 6 and UDP and TCP
for that long but we went through it we
got it we passed the cert and I bought
the security plus book I didn't read a
single page of that
um turns out I was able to get a job
before I had to go through all that so I
was very very fortunate I got an early
Break
um still an amazing sir I'm sure you'll
have to tell me
um so after work studies I knew VMS were
going to be an important tool as well
right so we can practice technical
skills in this it left out a lot of the
methodology it's almost kind of like Jiu
Jitsu like once you're practicing in arm
bar it's like I saw that for the first
time like why are you practicing there
you gotta like start fighting right and
that's kind of like what VMS are to me
it's very technical you're trying to do
a privilege escalation attack on a Linux
box and unfortunately I'll say I don't
think Linux exploitation has been almost
relevant at all on the job which is
going to speak to them you know the
types of clients that I deal with and
the work that I do but typically we
always work in Windows environments A.D
occasionally Mac and there has been
Linux exploitation for sure but this is
where things got uncertain I didn't know
what I was grasping at if this was going
to be relevant powered through I did a
lot of OAS testing a lot of web
application stuff that turned out to be
highly relevant so we're going to go
past this and I'll show you some lessons
learned and things I would have done
different
but this is an oddball one so SDR
anybody heard of this heck yeah my man
software defined radio has got to be the
coolest out there so I was really
big in a Tesla at the time the
electromagnetic spectrum like physics
nerd all about that and then to know
that you can buy a TV tuner for twenty
dollars and see meteors falling out of
the sky or like watching pager signals
tracking cell phones the things that SDR
can do is absolutely mind-blowing so I
got really big into this and whenever I
needed a break from hacking or reading
that Network plus book I studied on SDR
and that was kind of my break and relief
from things and it turned out this is
what landed me the job because I wanted
that interview obviously so green and
they didn't know whether to hire me or
not but it was the passion behind SDR
that got it to me they're like hey he's
hacking he's trying he's not really
focusing on the right stuff but like you
know he's he's got the spirit you know
all right so after work studies as well
YouTube university has got to be
probably still one of the best
on-the-job resources for me so I think
with about 30 minutes worth of education
on YouTube you can go into
um go go there and break into probably
30 50 of buildings across the United
States so the wealth of the knowledge
there seeing the Defcon talks and
learning about what has become our
industry today was just fascinating this
hacker lore and culture I was smitten I
couldn't get enough so all the resources
there highly recommend if you've never
seen elevator hacking from pit to
Penthouse
um you know the not so civil engineer
UDT guide absolutely phenomenal I was
also reading a lot a lot of Industry
literature out there from people that
have done it um
I'll focus on the middle one here is
lock safe and security this is an
encyclopedia about pretty much
everything physical security and it
starts off pretty dry too a lot of this
is metallurgy you know Pig metal how are
safes form things like that and then it
gets into latches and safe dials and
everything else and that book's probably
2 000 pages long still working on it um
and it really is it's just to me I love
that kind of stuff so any of these were
great resources looking back to breaking
in the industry
and all throughout this time I'm trying
I'm putting out feelers I know I'm
massively underqualified and this is
actually a letter of rejection from the
company that I work at today Coal Fire
so perseverance right it'll get you
there eventually right I mean fail fail
fail until you get it that was
absolutely it so I scrapped enough money
together for Defcon 23.
um and then to lower the cost of that I
hit up the forums and then one guy
reached out to me his name was cause and
it was the luckiest break I ever could
have had this man hooked it up he had
been coming to Defcon since Defcon 2 and
he took me through all the behind the
scenes the most mind-blowing tour that
no Noob and passerby tourists coming
into the industry has any right to
experience and he was just such such a
kind person to me
um so after that that fueled my fire and
passion after Defcon like it does every
year for me or attending these
conferences I think it's so important
for us to reignite that passion it kind
of energizes us to go forward I kept
putting out The Feelers until finally
Coal Fire responded and they said wow
thank you for your enthusiastic summary
let's see if we can get you on a call
with somebody and ultimately
I went out on site because I knew I was
going to be able to do this better in
person than I could remotely remotely I
have no credentials I had nothing A Plus
or a network Plus or I think we can all
agree probably not enough to somebody
come in an infosec in practice and start
exploiting things right
um so I had to go in person and show
them guys like I'm not just like some
wannabe like trying to walk through here
I don't know anything I am very willing
to learn it please give me a chance and
once I met them in person in the offices
and coal fire flew out there for that uh
this is the uh offer letter I received
for them and this was huge to me so this
is my first job out of college you know
going from low hourly rate wage I think
my first job was like 7.25 an hour to
making 65k I hit the big leagues baby
and then I moved to Colorado paying
downtown Denver rent I was like oh we're
gonna need a raise here pretty soon
um so that's I don't know piece of
history there but I want to share that
just you know um talk to a couple other
people once I got in the job and they're
like man did you be honest with me it's
okay did you cry a little bit when you
got the letter I'm like yeah I cried man
I had a tear roll down my face when I
got that for sure so after work studies
if I had to do it over A Plus network
plus all the CompTIA stuff super
relevant for me I think probably
everyone in this room is well past that
if you do have gaps in your foundation
would still recommend it uh SDR was an
oddball and I'm not saying you need that
for infosec um but be passionate about
something that's the core takeaway there
and it was super technical it is
fascinating please get into it and then
we can nerd out over that and then
ideally having an infosec related cert
so whether that was Security Plus oscp
in my mind would be the one to go with
like practical Hands-On I know I had a
hack they've changed the lab since I've
gone through and I think it's now a
little bit more 80 focused and it wasn't
when I was there so anything that you
can get Hands-On active directory
experience or testing external networks
internal networks and applications if
you know anything about compliance
drivers like PCI or HIPAA you're going
to get a job that way one way or another
so you got to think about where the
money flows through and then it is it is
a leap you got to listen to somebody who
knows what they're doing to say hey we
do test almost exclusively web apps
don't waste your time doing mobile
application testing which is which is
huge our company doesn't focus on a lot
so go where a breadth of the um
the work is right so College also not
required so many people are just
self-taught and so much better than
college would ever do so I got the job
first week I almost checked out I'm
going in there I'm sitting next to these
Geniuses these great beards that have
been in the industry for 20 years I
couldn't wait to get out of there be
like guys I have no idea what I'm doing
I'm sorry for wasting your time everyone
had these black little screens up all
over their computer running Linux as
their host OS it was horrifying it was
terrible but the people were amazing and
this is the thread of the hacker
Community these people raised me and I
would not be anywhere where I am I
wouldn't even be in this industry if it
wasn't for them still so I remember
somebody that worked in it they're like
oh yeah man you got to get access to a
lot of the internal resources here go
ahead and set up your ldap account I'm
like dude what is ldat man so I'm going
through and learning what that is and
thus Scotch Saturday was boring so I
invited all the guys out every Saturday
to my place bought a nice bottle of
Scotch and they just grinded me into the
dirt teaching me everything they could
as fast as they could and I'm forever
grateful for them that's my hacker
family and then later we're gonna have
some stories about how the overall
hacker Community rallied to me so just
there's a takeaway it's I'm incredibly
grateful
um and then I I think I owe a lot of
people in this industry so happy to pay
it back
so let's say you're already in the
industry you probably are and maybe you
want to get on a physical pen test how
do you transition how do you get in
there if your company's not doing them
it's going to be pretty difficult I'm
not saying it's impossible but you're
going to have to drive some initiatives
to make that happen I know a lot of this
work does flow through fedramp um it's
not I've never done a fedramp engagement
but
um for like their physical component
there is an on-site requirement to go
through check the camera layouts check
the doors and from what I've seen like
those those teams that I know in our
company that do it not as knowledgeable
as the Consultants like doing this from
an offensive perspective however
compliance drivers money flowing right
common theme it is definitely a viable
Avenue so whiteless walkthroughs I'm
going to talk about this but you can
take away the offensive element of this
and go from a blue team approach you fly
on site and then walk through the
facility with their team in hand and
this alleviates so many issues I have a
different slide on that so we'll get
into it but regardless it's not going to
hurt yourself it's not going to hurt
your chances to start doing this type of
work if you start researching how to
lock pick how to bypass how these
engagements are conducted so red team
Alliance is a great opportunity if you
have the money of some of their courses
around three grand so it's pricey it's
not as bad as Sans but if your company
can pay for that Bingo if not resort to
YouTube pick up the books buy yourself a
lockpick kit carry it with you
everywhere
all right so the number two question
that I get if number one is how did you
get in the industry number two is are
you wearing camouflaged you repel down
from the roofs I love it because it's
like 100 of people it's how did you get
the job are you repelling from roofs
um and the answer is obviously not you
know we have to blend in their
environment so typically it's dress
clothes right so we're working in a
corporate setting we can go in like that
sometimes we'll dress as the janitor
sometimes you know it's blue collar
employee we're there to check on the
roof it's leaking right in the data
center how about that we got to go in
there and check you know all the systems
and things are uh looking okay and that
the roof is you know secure
um so going down I'm just in the middle
here that's a prox mark that's an RFID
reader um taped to my buddy's forearm
long sleeve sock for business clothes
but man if you're going to do it hide an
RFID reader under there it's a good use
of it
um just to the right on your perspective
um that's us breaking into a law firm or
we had to hike up like 23 floors through
the stairwell to get to like just the
juiciest store that had an inch Gap so
we could under the door tool pop it open
that way and immediately it's uh that's
my buddy Jimmy two times he's a goon at
Defcon just wonderful person
um he's like all right man what what
next I think it's their first time
working I want to say he did engagements
before
um but I go right into the hallway pull
out a full like cupboard of files and we
go right into the handicap stall and
we're just like ripping through this
um so no typically we're not wearing
camouflage we're not repelling from the
roofs
except for this one glorious time and
this was the greatest engagement I have
ever been on this was a water treatment
facility and an undisclosed part of the
country
um and let me tell you a little bit
about this so five-day engagement five
water treatment facilities at the end we
had to do social engineering component
so this is my first ever engagement this
is about I think four months after I
joined the company and I have been doing
a lot of virtual work this is going to
be the first real one right like getting
paid to do this this isn't robex there's
going to be people here there's security
guards so I go out with a more senior
consultant
and I defer to him and he says you know
what man let's take the woods let's
state that red line let's go through
there it's going to be sneaky covert I'm
like I hear you man I hear you but the
yellow path we can just walk right up
you know there's not going to be like a
lookout station like looking for like a
half a mile to like see us coming so why
don't we just do that and it'll be a lot
easier and quicker he's like no no we
can't do it it's too wide open they're
gonna see us so I'm all right you know I
defer so we go through the red path that
is swampland
it is water the entire way it takes us
three hours to go let's say a mile and
we're checking in on the fence once in a
while and there's like a security guard
there checking the locks and everything
which like never happens by the way if
you really get into this like
everything's wide open
um but uh we're having a slosh through
if you're on the land you know we're
hitting any twig or along the way and
that's not the way to go so we started
going through the water we're in ways
high water waiting over there in this
part of the country there's a military
base nearby so there's Jets ripping
overhead and any time that was our
Saving Grace uh we heard the of the jet
flying overhead and that was our break
to start sprinting and then we could go
100 feet so three hours later we get all
the way down to the bottom part of the
facility where the red and the yellow
meet
and the gates wide open so overall it
worked out right I will say this is
another slide kind of shows
pre-construction of that facility
um we came back two days so the yellow
is one and the red is another or the
orange
we had gone through we hit every single
building in here there's people all over
the place we're dressed in full camo
it's not the thing to do if you're going
to be confronted by somebody you get
caught wearing that like I don't know
what your what your excuse is gonna be I
was unprepared for it
um so we get all the way to kind of the
top part of the picture and that's the
admin building we're kind of like
following along a golf cart that have
been moving around here and we stopped
by some dumpsters I'm like damn listen
man this is my first engagement we've
been doing great people talk about how
they've never been caught in this
industry why don't we not follow the
golf cart into the last remaining
building where we know there's going to
be a ton of people he's like no no we
got to do it and by the way not getting
caught in this industry is not a good
thing you're not doing yourself a
service and you're not doing your
clients the service unless you're
getting apprehended unless you're
identifying where your client can detect
you and I'll add there is no greater
stress inoculation or bulletproof vest
that you can wear than having a get out
of jail free card and knowing you can
and talk your way through this
and at the end they're not buying it
here's our card we're good to go why not
use that if you have that privilege you
don't get that anywhere else in life so
super cool thing so I'll show you a
couple other pictures from that
engagement which again still probably
one of the greatest of My Life
um but maybe not the most uh insightful
right wearing camo the entire way
through but it really is you know I've
seen these facilities at night you know
places that you've always driven by and
then you know have incredible importance
to our national security it was a
privilege it was a gift to get to see
these kind of things
so here are some other funny ones this
is Dan hopping a fence after we're like
two miles out from the facility so I
take a photo with flash for posterity
and he's freaking out you can't do that
man they're gonna see us I'm like no
they're not Dan
um I vote we have a petition we gotta
like Nix all the cliche photos of
hackers wearing hoodies hackers being
dressed in full camo behind a terminal
that's the way forward that's what we
gotta shift things towards super cool so
I'll add to there's something of a
religious experience here I heard
somebody say in the industry once that
there are things known in this life and
there are things unknown and between
them lies a locked door what does
physical security do for you it teaches
you how to get through those doors it
teaches you how to see this other side
of life whether it's CEO financials or
intellectual property lights it just
pulls down the veil and that Pursuit and
this freedom of all this esoteric occult
knowledge that all of us are seeking
it's here it's in our industry and it's
a beautiful thing it's super cool to be
a part of
so one last highlight from the end of
this story
go ahead and read that I'm not sure how
I didn't get fired from this job just
like solely based on the way I wrote
reports my first hacker nickname was Nat
Geo National Geographic because I'd say
things like oh this exploit not commonly
seen in the wild you know we came across
it while potentially a suspect
occupation and uniform to some the only
confrontation Coal Fire received was
when an employee directed The Coal Fire
team member to put the hat back on after
he had taken it off if you can't see it
there he is dressed up as a Krispy Kreme
delivery man which does not exist not a
real job but we had broken into
everything we've done some social
engineering at this point and we get to
the point where it's like man we just
got to get egregious we gotta like have
somebody detect us so we can give the
client that win and tell them hey to us
here everything else below that we need
to work on so Krispy Kreme delivery man
we tried and we were still successful
so it had been a week on site again
water treatment facilities a lot of
bacteria floating around I am sick as a
dog I'm in the car for half an hour
while he's in there doing his thing
getting all this done and I'll just you
know people are passing me and I'm just
like trying to slink down as low as I
can in there so I'm not like caught and
detecting blow the engagement and
finally he texted me back he's like hey
man coast is clear come on in I'm like
all right cooling gives me the
directions he's like yeah nobody's
watching the door you can just walk
right in I'm in the bathroom go ahead
and bring me the other laptop bag
and so I go in there and gives me
directions walk right in on unchallenged
and so I'm walking in and there's an
employee walking out of the bathroom nod
and then I just see there's one pair of
legs sitting in one of the Stalls so I
take the stall next to them it is Dan I
know you could think that's where the
story's going
um but instead of doing your typical
drug deal where you pass the the drugs
underneath the bathroom stall of the
laptop I was going to be cheeky because
man we're having the time of our life
and nothing will bond you together like
a red team engagement I stand on top of
the toilet seat reach on over and I look
down at him just to freak him out his
pants are still down now I'm freaked out
he had been in there half an hour I
thought everything was wrapped up we're
good to go so I'm in horror I look up to
make eye contact with the employee who
had been walking out and he's washing
his hands
and still didn't get caught he never
reported that so I don't know what they
have going on there but that's that's
what it was so we got some other
pictures here these are just random
engagements um let's see far left for
you so safe fault right in a bank that's
just wide open
um and then there were like you know
more secure compartments inside and
those are the easy ones once they're
past the outer layer
um defense in depth does not exist with
physical security
um again things are in disarray we need
you guys in here this is part of this
talk we got to get more people into the
side of the industry
um and again same point so the next
picture over in the fire safe room just
that door that could be loaded um you
know the latch for that door just popped
open and then from there all the keys
which are medical Keys like a really
nice high security key are sitting on
top of the safes right all the file
volts so you can pull those open
um the one with car we got to steal a
car that was a dream come true for my
for my career below that we have so many
pictures just in data centers idfs mdfs
what have you
um Diamond doesn't but that's my buddy
Gary's I had to throw him in there
um
I don't know just the infrastructure I
see a microcontroller switches factories
to me I have a mechanical mind so like
understanding how a product works is one
thing and then you think about like man
for them to put together this product
and to build the factory a whole nother
thing so getting a break into factories
and see that it just always always
tickles me nice so I like that in the
middle again this is you know getting
egregious with engagements um we just
carry out every one of us had like two
bags of shredded documents and we're
yelling out to employees in the office
hey guys we're uh taking the stuff we
probably shouldn't be if anyone wants to
stop us
silence so we just walk away with it and
this this happens all the time we've
been in like the middle of cafeterias
for factories on like third shift and be
like I've had my boss stand up on a desk
he's like ladies and gentlemen I need
your attention for just a minute please
my boy here just hacked into your
network stole all the things we have
domain admin if you don't know what that
is it's very bad this is a security Risk
please go to a manager and report this
incident to maybe about 50 employees we
went in for our debrief the next day not
a single one who reported it
and a lot of that's culture it's not on
the employees right that's things we
need to incentivize you need to have
your secret shopper of somebody trying
to break into a facility where their
challenge where it's incentivized for
the employee get a 50 gift card if you
can detect who that is and then it's man
that story spreads like wildfire
throughout the break room and then
everyone's on the lookout for that so
developing the security culture there it
doesn't apply just to Virtual systems
right
bottom right there that's us getting
into a cash safe literally the money
shot
um we may have a pretty cool opportunity
to do a Netflix documentary here
um as a result of some of the things in
our our career so again very blessed um
but the way that it works they film it
first and they pitch it so we'll see you
know and I asked the guy I'm like man
giving a talk soon I don't I don't want
to say hey we have a Netflix stalker and
coming up what are the odds that's going
to happen he's like man Netflix 50 50.
if not it's going to be on Hulu it's
going to be on peacock like one of the
major networks
um at the worst will be on your local
news network that free over the air
stuff but it'll be somewhere so I feel
more confident being able to say that so
engagement highlights a bank heist right
no physical talk would be complete
without one
um nothing too crazy man just stealing
some money from a bank was a lot easier
than you'd think so we go in through the
back door uh it was an emergency like
egress door that wasn't alarmed there's
no handle on the outside so if you ever
see like what they pull up server tile
not server tiles but the floor tiles in
a server room
um it's like it looks like a headset
right with suction cups and you can
attach that make your own handle on the
outside of a door we use plastic Lloyds
like thin cutting boards to go over and
then slip that latch door pulls right
open no alarm we go through the office
space and there's every violation that
you'd like to see for physic for
reporting purposes so violations of
clean dust policy passwords what have
you we hop behind the teller's desk in
the in this main bank branch and we
install key loggers on the back of the
system come back the next day no alarms
no indication that we were there that
they were compromised come back the next
day pull off the teller information we
had the teller log on for the system and
boom easy to deposit 100 dollars cash
deposit thereafter hours the system
locked you out after that you can't
deposit more than a hundred thousand
unless you have the override credentials
which were also captured so we could
deposit any amount of money so we report
this fine into the client they say no
well we would have caught that well when
did you do that Saturday oh man we
wouldn't have caught that until Monday
or Tuesday
and there's a couple laughs is there
that we help them identify
so engagement methodology
CIA like Ops that's a quote from some
Iowa senator
uh that was remarking on some of the
work that we've done before and this is
my personal approach to engagements I
like to go in covertly everything
depends on the rules engagement so
you're always working within the scope
all that every engagement's different
personally if we have the flexibility
too I want to go in get the lay of the
land understand everything that I'm
working with at night undetected without
confronting people and then once we go
in for social engineering we can do
things tightly a little bit more
sophisticated and again we keep dropping
that guys down until they catch on to us
and we can rotate different people out
if you go the other way and you just do
the Krispy Kreme delivery man right off
the bat and they catch you engagement's
over a client has no value so working
your other way up is my preferred uh
approach so sometimes you know that can
be authorized entry during business
hours like you can walk into any
building that's open during the day and
use the bathroom what have you AKA
casing the joint and then that helps us
get the lay of the land and break in the
later that night so again every
engagement's different it's going to
depend on what the client's looking for
what that flag is so can we connect to
the network can we to gain access to
sensitive rooms client data donor
information network access things of
that nature and sometimes there can be
purple team components of this where
we're training the employees and just
leaving things out of sorts seeing that
gets reported if that's detected then
once we have that upper hand then we can
return back and do our hardcore SE and
again lowering the threshold
all right so timelines is something I
hugely disagree with with the way my
company does things and the way many
other companies does this but it's
dictated by budget right we have
Consultants there on site it's expensive
you can't stay there for a month at a
time and do Recon and surveillance and
all that if you can that'd be amazing
that's how if you do this in real life
like CIA engagements there's plenty of
times different teams different skill
sets we hit the ground running so in the
case of Iowa but anybody heard of that
Iowa engagement with courthouses
yeah that was a good one we'll get to
that
um that one was five government
buildings in five days six days right so
we hit the ground running make our first
entry right off we had gotten uh off the
plane later that night on Sunday so
typically we arrive on site we've done
Osan Google Maps is pretty much that you
know you can look around company history
everything like that but there's no time
for heavy surveillance we can't do sigan
we can't do signals intelligence listen
to employee comms
um seeing when people come in and out of
the facility what they're wearing then
you know get different badges made what
have you that doesn't really exist in
these time frames that we're working
with so maybe we have a day for light
attacks but again I try to make three
entries two covert After Hours the
second one typically to retrieve tools
uh or maybe you know cover cover your
basis for something you missed and then
your social engineering
so after a while I got the idea to be
super cool if we start doing whiteless
walkthroughs instead of the offensive
approach let's work more closely with
our clients this might be more
considered like a purple team approach I
suppose but instead of doing an
offensive engagement we're taking a path
of least resistance low hanging fruit we
show them a single attack path let's go
in meet with the client walk through the
whole facility this is a wonderful
training experience for myself and then
for the junior associate we try to bring
along with us too so they can train and
get learned up the first time this also
allows us to do more configuration
reviews see their software assess their
rules then train and work with that team
so they can scale that out so this is a
much big bigger value prop for that team
if they have multiple facilities and
they can't afford to assess everything
let's train your team up then they can
go around and see what they can see and
then once you guys get those first bases
covered then we can come on do the red
team and then see where the gaps exist
so we're gonna switch gears here a
little bit
um I'm gonna try to leave time for QA
everything's condensed I think I'm
already running out of time but we'll
get through this alarm Hardware so this
is typically what I'll see on site you
have your interface this little keypad
um they'll come in a million different
formats and it really doesn't matter
it's a front end for in the top right
that circuit board that Vista 20p
everything Aggregates to your alarm
controller so in your
bottom left that's a PIR motion sensor
passive infrared
pretty dumb sensors they can be
fine-tuned they make higher grade ones
rarely will you ever see anything fancy
like physical security always gets
cheaped out on so bad which is why it's
kind of so easy I'm not good at my job
it's just terrible security like it's
really easy to do
um so that one you know if you're
underneath you know the detection
threshold especially in residences
you'll see this you know they
accommodate for pets like your dog's not
going to trip the motion sensor
um in the middle here we have read
switches so these are magnetic based
detection uh that if a door opens you
know the the magnetic field separates
and then that sends an alarm condition
to the panel and then in the bottom
right you may not recognize that one
that's a glass break sensor this really
doesn't come into play for any of the
work that I do but it's highly valuable
to the clients because let's be honest
if physical compromise happens more
often than not for most clients it's
going to be a smash and grab and your
glass break sensor is going to help
detect an alert on that right so we have
detect deter and respond maybe deter
detect respond but you're not going to
keep somebody out physically
indefinitely right even the government
rated stuff GSA saves they rate it a
number of time and number of hours it
would take to compromise that
surreptitiously covertly and maybe it's
like six hours but that buys you time to
detect and respond to that incident
right
so that's a pretty key principle of
physical security
so going forward with alarm Hardware I
rarely see these on site these are
mechanical switches so this will also
alert if the door is open these are much
harder to bypass I'm going to show you
some bypasses that we have for some of
the Alarm Systems this one you have to
be able to depress that on the far side
of the door the only one that's
different here is all the way on the
left
Gary used his Coal Fire lanyard to
retract that because it's on the outside
of the door so obviously anytime you
have a sensor on the outside easily
bypassed they're on the inside properly
installed these are a little bit more
pain in the butt you can see like the
electrical conduit coming into them
they're not as easy to work with for the
installers that's why you don't see
these so hopefully a little bit more
work down that side of the industry and
we'll start seeing those a lot more
so here's a goofy one for an alarm
bypass that we did once you've done it
all in this industry you're just looking
to have fun with it I mean still provide
all the class all the value in the world
of the client but come up with new
different ways to do things learn more
about the systems that you're trying to
defeat
you got a video there that'll play
tactical that's our portable hula hoop
like extended on like barbecue skewers
10 minutes less seriously all right
let's speed it up
um all right go going for it so it
didn't work and eventually we just ended
up putting like the um uh space blanket
over the sensor so it can read out
um we have a MAG switch in the middle so
this will emanate its own magnetic field
and that can keep that circuit closed
from the outside and then at the bottom
right we have a pole switch so we can
identify where those sensors are from
the outside again something you can do
with a magnetic sensors not the physical
ones so here's kind of an exotic one
that should never really happen but it
came up once and it's super cool an
electric strike bypass readers in my
mind so we always see them on the
outside and there's vulnerabilities with
that you can take it apart and if you
can access the wires you're hosed um
depending on the protocol but typically
it's clear text behind there so you can
install an implant in the reader read
everything coming through and then just
replay those credentials there are some
other protections against that but
typically it's it's not the standard yet
but anytime you have something Exposed
on the outside that you can interact
with you're asking for trouble and
especially the case in this one where
you had both the reader and the strike
uh wires going through so the electric
strike there we just bypassed the um the
power for that and then hook that up
into like what was powering the reader
that powered the strike to open up and
then gain access that way for an
otherwise very secure door
and they just flickered on enough wrong
wire
so then once he gets the right wires for
the strike just Bridges those into the
power cable
click open you guys are so cool
uh we'll skip this video anytime you can
see the alarm panel from the outside of
the building I consider that a bit of a
vulnerability I don't want that alarm
status displayed to anybody from the
outside that should be internally facing
there could be other reasons for that
and everything's going to be a trade-off
rate but personally that lets me get a
good layout maybe I can see that the
alarm's just off that night
that's a video but we're going to skip
it other career highlights everybody go
to black hat
yeah two people that work for big
corporations that can afford it it's
purely corporate you're not really
missing too much but it's been really
fun for us every year cool fire runs a
lock picking booth there and this is
also one of the most rewarding parts of
the career is teaching thousands of
people to get their first opens while
they come through and then we have all
the prizes associated with it so super
cool super cool
um career highlights for me personally
like what this has led to is dark net
Diaries wired articles we were
interviewed by the same guy that
interviewed Snowden Glenn Greenwald
uh keynoting crabs
um black hat um and then cool artwork
and stuff so let's talk real quick about
the reason a lot of that came up was
Iowa so many of our uh us had heard of
that we got totally smeared by the media
and all the statements put out by the
sheriff in the state were if not
erroneous completely false knowingly and
we never got the chance really to set
this story straight so again I know
we're running out of time but in a
nutshell the state of Iowa hired us to
come on site assess their courthouses
and judicial branch and show them the
vulnerabilities standard pretty much
covert penetration test right so we do
that and we're fully successful and then
you know one night we break into our
point of contacts desk and I leave my
business card and then that's the image
there you say hey sorry about the state
of my office uh well done I'll be
interested to see how easy it was and
then our not even the last time it was
night like two or three we'd assessed
everything broken and everything we go
to our last Courthouse break in set the
alarm off
um deputies arrived bonded to it
verified us called the state they said
hey they're working for us we were all
good to go deputies let us go then the
sheriff arrived and police start turning
off their body cameras you know the
sheriff is visibly upset you know at
some point causes and says this is
the state can't do this you
guys are going to go to jail and then he
pressed charges against us came up with
extended height and bails I think it was
a hundred grand to bail us out and then
was pressing charges for seven years of
prison time for us for doing our job on
behalf of the state because the sheriff
said that's his courthouse and the state
doesn't own it so a little bit of a big
ego in a small town and that's that's
kind of what it boils down to to me so
nowadays we're doing our counter lawsuit
um we're going ahead with that and then
looking forward to giving you guys an
update on how that went
so I have a couple top exploit tools
that we use one is latch bypass this is
what we use to break into the bank that
I mentioned earlier it's a flexible
cutting board Lloyds and things like
that
can slip over the latch from the outside
and that's what the purpose of the notch
is instead of just pushing straight into
the latch you know which way the latch
is going to face there's a beveled Edge
when the door closes automatically it
hits that curve the door can close so we
have to get around that and pull that
latch that'll open the door that way
there's other tools for this and there's
a way to remediate this this really
shouldn't be happening it's pretty easy
to prevent it if the auxiliary dead
latch is working properly that little
component in red it's tough because it's
like kind of a rubber Belling pad at
your head what keeps the door closed is
the primary latch that extends into the
strike cavity that's where if you go and
pull in the door what's jamming it up is
the latch extended in there and that's
not going to retract
the auxiliary dead latch needs to be
depressed right so you have one that's
inserting the cavity the other one needs
to hit the wall needs to hit the uh the
door jam the door frame and stay
depressed and that dead ends the primary
latch so you can't just come in there
and scrape that primary latch aside if
you're able to push that door in and get
that auxiliary pin to extend as well
it's disengaged then you can bypass and
that happens all the time what I prefer
to see instead of seeing the ones that
are in line like this get the ones that
are vertical and then you only have your
strike cavity that sits just in line
with the latch and then it's just the
entire rest of the door is where the
auxiliary latch hits and that's a easy
way to prevent that so
I don't think I have an example maybe
like kind of like where the screw holes
are and the other mechanism there that's
where your strike latch should be hit
and just something lower like away from
the cavity and then it's so hard with
building settling or maintenance over
time for that to go wrong
um
the other exploit tool that I'm going to
use invariably is going to be the under
the door tool
um the common theme Here is tool
insertion anytime we're able to insert a
tool onto the other side of the door we
can manipulate mechanisms
um like ADA compliance States you got to
be able to egress quickly from a
facility because in most facilities
preservation of life is far more
important than the security and then
with that you can't have a fire where
people are scrambling have to find the
key to unlock the door you can pull from
that authenticated trusted side and
bypass it that way and third top
favorite tool would be RFID I consider
this one to be the only tool that I
cannot Source abroad or in the field so
wherever I am drop there without any
tools you can find everything in your
house Home Depot what have you RFID is
the only one where you need specialized
circuitry to make this happen that's
used for cloning there's other tools you
can use that embed into the reader like
we talked about
uh and that's that so 3D printing I made
a couple tools here for the industry one
is a linear Access Control uh key to
light key it's the a126 there's other
tools that can hold your shims some
bypass tools and picks shims are crazy
because man you just like try to keep
those in your pocket anytime you reach
for anything they're just exploded so
staying maintained and tight on an
operation
um it's it's ideal so I made a tool that
helps with that everyday carry I
encourage if you guys are interested
carry lock picks they're not illegal I
think like one state like Tennessee has
some restrictions but their TSA approved
I carry the sear pick wallet in the
bottom left I don't think they make
those anymore so I'd opt for the top
right just a little sleeve that you can
insert in your wallet purse what have
you top left is the cover instruments
covert companion and that has a ton of
little bypass Tools in it really I get
by with picks in the hall pass there in
the middle and beyond that the only
thing I long for would be your flexible
shim that your metal can't go straight
around you know you need something
flexible to reach around the curve of
the door some sometimes into UDT the
under the door tool outside of that lock
picks in that Hall Pass are all I need
you can also use flexible shims like
this and just keep two minutes guys wrap
it up
uh just a flexible shim like this sheet
of metal that you can fold up and then
you can keep that in your wallet to
bypass uh padlocks as well
resources that we use for our black hat
tool or for training each other or
learning yourself go to tool.us read
everything but tool.us resources they
have the best animated gifs gifs two
appease everyone in the industry and
it's super cool that'll help you learn
otherwise
find somebody from Tool they're great
people they'd love to help you where to
purchase I'll leave this slide for
posterity so go through the list and
that's where you can Source everything
coming up next I want to steal a plane
it's like the only thing I haven't done
yet
um disappointed noting the cia's contact
of me my Handler made me put that in
there super grateful for everything I'm
looking forward to giving it back so if
I can help you guys this is how you
reach me contact me hit me up and let's
do this thing let's get you guys
breaking the banks and securing physical
security huh thank you
all right we only have 30 seconds if
someone has a question
do we follow up with the engagements
after 12 months typically only if we're
doing another red team we have a renewal
with that client otherwise I try to work
with my clients they have a question how
something worked but then they have
their contractors in so we say hey the
store had this vulnerability find
yourself a locksmith that can remediate
that and hopefully you're good to go
um yeah there should be more I mean just
like compliance stuff just like virtual
penetration testing we should be
following up more but it typically comes
you know monetary standpoint gotta do
another engagement with them