welcome to the state of blockchain
security
in case we have not met my name is Peter
and I stumbled upon this field of
blockchain security accidentally about
five years ago and I'm very excited to
share with you like what it is what are
the threats what is this why is this so
near and dear to me
um
in case you're not familiar it's a brand
new security field with a mission of
securing and defending the
cryptocurrency ecosystem and you know we
can think of cryptocurrency ecosystem
where you read about the news you know
people buying dogs and jpegs and all
sorts of fun stuff but to me it's about
the Ukrainian and Russian refugees
escaping War zones and you know being
able to preserve their livelihoods even
when they're going through you know
border control that takes everything
away by just memorizing 12 words that's
that's all it takes that's not something
that my family was able to do that's why
to me if I spend my time making the
system safe and sound and it saves at
least one family out there to preserve
their livelihoods it's worthwhile and I
invite you to join me
I have a whole lot of content for you so
talk fast there'll be hopefully some
time to ask questions but I really want
to give you a map for this brand new
industry explain what are the unique
threats what are the unique
opportunities for you to build on and
let's see maybe you'll find it fun
enough to explore more
so that first let's talk about what is
the difference between cryptocurrency
ecosystem and the uh and the traditional
security ecosystem
the best way to look at it is just look
through the economics of it
so when we talk about exploitation with
traditional security there are about
thousand or so incidents that happened
in last year on the blockchain side
there were about 294. so it's obviously
a much smaller industry so there are
less hacks where it gets interesting is
the dollar amounts involved in those
compromises
so the 4.6 billion dollar value that I
calculated it's pretty hard to find
because you can't go to some report of
it from Verizon or maindient or anyone
else out there that says you're like
this is how much money was actually
stolen would they concern themselves
more is like this is how many emails
were compromised so Social Security
numbers there's no actual dollar value
they can assign there so I extrapolated
based on the report from IBM which
counts about four million dollars per
incident things are different on the
blockchain side where because of the
nature of it because it's an open Ledger
you know exactly how much was in the
treasury of a company that was
compromised and suddenly it's not there
so from that I could see 3.7 billion
dollars that was in treasuries of
cryptocurrency businesses and now it's
gone
so what that means is that per incident
for businesses a single incident is
worth not just four million dollars in
traditional security but 12 million
dollars this is basically it's a
life-changing event for a company like
if it loses 12 million dollars a large
chunk of them shut down after the fact
so it is critical for businesses to
shore up the security
let's look at the attacker perspective
why are they so interested in hacking
crypto assets
same thing on traditional site thousand
incidents
the way that you can calculate attacker
profits that's really hard too the most
profitable like Cash Cow of traditional
compromises ransomware so ransomware 450
million dollars were stolen according to
cheat analysis if you're stealing uh you
know emails and all that stuff we saw in
a phishing talk yesterday you're selling
millions of records for pennies per
thousand or a million records so I would
say like I'm giving it like a big chunk
like big variance here about two million
dollars per Incident That's the attacker
profit
on the blockchain side it still is 12
million because the exact amount that
left the company's treasury now ends up
in the attacker's pocket
so naturally a lot of Bad actors a lot
of traditional Bad actors nation states
they did the same math and they said
well we can spend all this time trying
to go out our way steal steal identity
and try to go on the black market try to
sell that or we can just steal the
actual cash so it makes sense for them
to really Target this this field
so that's the math breakdown
let's talk about before we dive into
specific threats let's talk about on a
very high level what constitutes a
cryptocurrency ecosystem
uh from the defender in the attacker
side uh so of course there's the
blockchain like that's the underlying
technology this is the consensus
mechanism that allows you to do
transactions in a decentralized fashion
with no one being able to say no to you
those uh blockchains communicate with
notes which are specialized servers
which enforce the consensus so that
making sure that whatever The Ledger
state that appears on one side is the
same on the other
wallet software is the client software
which communicates with those notes so
that's what you and I would install in
our machines
smart contracts so those are tiny little
programs that run on all the nodes and
allow you to implement things like
Banking and I guess decentralized
Banking and loans and all of that good
stuff without any central control
there are C5 businesses that's
centralized Finance so think of
exchanges
and D5 that's the most exciting part a
decentralized finance that's you you're
building up whole Banks and whole
ecosystems Financial ecosystems without
any single entity exerting control on
you
and of course there are users which
interact with all of that
with that let's look at what's happening
with this model so the slide shows you
how much was lost just this quarter in
the last three months
so on the user uh C5 and blockchain site
that's around 200 to uh sorry 20 to 30
million dollars lost
the real losses are in the D5 390
million dollars stolen in the last few
months and we can give to you this
number with Precision because we can
observe the act the projects actually
getting compromised and losing that
exact amount
and this is where we we're going to
focus for most of the talk this is where
attackers are most likely going to focus
because they're transitioning from
exchanges and other compromises to defy
and so we as Security Professionals
should focus on defending as well if we
want to contribute to this ecosystem
so let's begin with the user and wallet
Security First
so just on a very high level we have our
users who communicate to the client
software which is usually a browser
extension or mobile app the wall is
communicate to depths if you're not
familiar it's a just a website within
that website there's some embedded code
which can talk to those extensions you
can talk to your wallet software and
then wallets take commands from the DAP
like hey I want to swap some Eve and I
want to send it over to the blockchain
to visualize it imagine a wallet
software I'm biased here coinbase wallet
here
uh you navigate to adapt so this is
uniswap you're trying to switch you can
try to swap one eth for some usdc you
can't do it's no longer two thousand it
dropped in the last couple days
um you say go for it your wallet accepts
a command you approve that command to
perform the Swap and then it shows up on
the ledger so that's a blockchain
Explorer where you can see all the
transactions
and that gets us to the first and one of
the worst uh user threat vectors out
there it's called approval phishing you
can imagine that if you navigate to a
malicious website and oftentimes they
entice you with some kind of with some
kind of airdrop it's a it's a free
tokens that you can claim because you
are you and just for you will give you
some free stuff well little do you know
that when you navigate there and you
click on hey let's retrieve those tokens
you'll be presented with an approval
screen but that approval screen doesn't
authorize you receiving those tokens
because of how limited the ux is
oftentimes you approve things which end
up sending all your money on The Ledger
to the bad guys and then you end up with
an empty wallet and a sad face
and you say well couldn't users be
better well not really like Kevin Rose
has won recent hack and if you're
familiar Kevin rolls the Dig Fame he's
been he's been in the crypto ecosystem
for a while so he's an experienced user
OG we call them
and he was still tricked into losing a
million dollars worth of nfts for the
squiggly Alliance yes it's worth a
million dollars
um but the idea is like what are the
limitations of wallet software out there
that still tricks uh even more
experienced users uh by the way you'll
see QR codes I know we are at the
security conference and you're not
supposed to click on QR codes but you
know who I am and you know where to find
me this is just a way for you to get
more information
and more research on this particular
subject so it really sounds interesting
check it out
let's talk about zero transfer fishing
so that's another attack Vector the best
way to understand it imagine that you
called your bank
and then you want to call your bank
again and the best way to do this is you
look at the phone phone call history
right who do you call you remember like
the phone number started with 555
something and I'm gonna call this number
again well imagine that if attackers
could inject a number into your call
history which also start with 555 what
are the chances of you accidentally
dialing the bad number as opposed to the
original one and that is exactly what
attackers figured out how to do they
inject a a transaction with an address
which looks closely like your original
one but just slightly different
uh you approve a transaction a transfer
there and now your money is gone so this
is an example of a of a zero transfer
fish transaction you'll see the first
three characters five EC are the same
but then the rest is different so these
are called vanity addresses you can
Brute Force until you can calculate an
address which is similar enough
but it it surprisingly it's successful
enough that on ethereum blockchain uh
almost 20 million dollars were lost to
this to this hack in the past few months
okay so to summarize the state of user
and wallet security wallet ux needs
Improvement
um it's a new field people are barely
trying to get this going and
unfortunately bad guys are also taking
advantage of that
malicious transaction and address
detection is a huge growth opportunity
think of it like uh like a firewall or
anti-virus product but for
cryptocurrency users that tells them
like don't go there you know this chrome
big red screen that you get when you go
to a phishing site we need that if you
are Builder you're you want to create
something new this is an amazing
opportunity the other part is
investigations if someone compromises
your wallet who are you going to call
there are no maintenance or crowd
strikes or anyone else that you can call
it's volunteers volunteers right now sit
down and spend hours and hours of their
personal time to investigate and shut
down these hacks so again there are
opportunities for more Professional
Services there
no talk about blockchain Security will
be complete without exchanges so let's
talk about exchange security again I'm
not going to focus on more traditional
hacks like you know your server gets
compromised or someone somewhere
downloaded malware we'll talk about
blockchain specific threats and for that
just think of users communicating with
some kind of exchange backend over API
the key element and then the exchange
will forward on whatever it needs to to
the actual blockchain so they're
intermediary
the key thing to keep in mind are the
kind of uh asset storage that is
embedded inside we distinguish them
between hot storage hot wallets and cold
storage
hot wallets think of them as live data
that is accessible for users to
immediately quickly retrieve Swap and so
on and then you have cold storage Cold
Storage was introduced because exchanges
get hacked so if you do get hacked you
probably don't want to lose everything
you probably want to keep the majority
of your assets
somewhere offline which is very
difficult to retrieve requires all sorts
of steps that that is the common
practice at least for most exchanges
this gives you just some idea of how
exchange compromises go over time and
2022 would have been amazing if that's
for this one exchange which I'll cover
in detail shortly you can probably guess
who it was
but first the attack vectors on
exchanges hot wall compromise is by far
500 500 million dollars stolen in the
last uh year and year and a quarter
other things like server compromise
credentials theft credential theft is
more like API key theft that was popular
last year where One exchange like Ira
Financial was relying at API Keys stolen
from it from they were used to access
Gemini for Cold Storage server
compromise is more related like
incidents with uh Bitcoin ATM machines
like their whole info got hacked private
key stolen application logic
misconfiguration there are smaller
attack vectors they're more concerned
with like incorrectly said exchange
rates that attackers took advantage of
to Arbitrage
okay let's talk about FTX
um
if certain someone was not thinking
about
re-hypothetication they would have at
least implemented cold storage and as we
found out from the bankruptcy docs those
432 million dollars that were stolen
would maybe some portion of them would
have stayed
uh from chapter 11 bankruptcy docs no
security staff not using Cold Storage
Keys private Keys stored in clear text
multi-sig multi-sick wallets stored in
the same text file in clear text so like
really wild like I I can't believe this
was happening stolen assets were
extracted went through chip mixer North
Korea favorite not sure who it was but
one of the indicators and it's gone so
this is an extreme example of an actor
who was
extremely careless
uh let's talk about North Korea threat
actor apt-38
North Korean Lazarus group was
attributed to stealing 1.7 billion
dollars
so far in the last I guess five years or
so that they did the math that I showed
you early and said like wow we should
really start stealing crypto
um
their techniques that they use are more
traditional like they they don't create
like all day vulnerabilities and do all
sorts of like crazy stunts same old
malware spear fishing supply chain
attacks their latest invention is that
they apply for jobs at uh crypto
companies saying like hey hire me I'm an
American developer uh malicious Insider
you wanna anyways people have like all
sorts of weird YouTube recordings of the
conversations I invite you to research
that
ah so overall the state of exchange
security
hundreds of millions are lost that said
those hundreds of millions are still 14
of total losses in the crypto ecosystem
so you you definitely should if you're
interested as a career within the space
exchange security is great what I'm
going to talk about next is where the
real losses occur though supply chain
attacks spearfishing traditional attack
vectors are very much applicable and
whatever security profession you're
going to talk to like who is their
Boogie person that they wake up in the
middle of night sweating it's North
Korea they're thinking of Uncle Kim so
uh the state of protocol security
protocol security uh here we're talking
about blockchains the actual blockchain
protocols
um again on a high level you have a
bunch of notes
they all communicate the current state
to each other they uh like this is this
transaction occurred everyone should be
notified they get rid of bad states by
implementing variety of consensus
mechanisms from proof of work proof of
State I invite you to learn more about
that but the key element for the for our
purposes are the layers there's the
execution and consensus layer the
consensus layer concerns with making
sure that the larger state that they
obtain is legitimate and valid across
the ecosystem
this is agreeing on what transactions
are present and then we have the
execution State and I mentioned smart
contracts previously this is the layer
that makes sure that you execute those
tiny little programs in a secure fashion
and no funny business occurs because it
does if we look back in history let's go
back to 2021 the majority of attacks
were on the consensus layer so raise of
hand saw many are familiar with 51
percent reorg attacks quite a few okay
for those you're not sure about it's
basically the ability to trick the
system make a deposit to an exchange is
swap it out for something else and then
cheat and somehow that deposit like as
if never happened
no vulnerabilities back then were only
five million dollars it was just
starting out I was afraid it's going to
happen but it did the vast majority of
compromises today are as a result of
node exploitation so 700 million dollars
and then the on the consensus side
there's still consensus level exploits
but they changed they evolved into
something called Mev vulnerabilities
I'll talk about it in a second
so let's let's talk about first uh
attack Vector on the on the protocol
side Mev boost block leakage exploit
what is Mev mmev stands for maximally
extracted value it was previously called
minor extractable value but it's not as
politically correct so we don't we don't
say that anymore
think of it this way forget about crypto
let's talk about General Finance you're
familiar with Flash Boys the book where
people were buying data servers close to
exchanges to make sure they can
front-run legitimate Traders
same story Advanced traders in the
cryptocurrency they figure hey if I'm
going to pay this little bribe to a node
operator and I'm going to ask them to
include my transaction just before
another transaction or right after or
around this go to sandwich attack
I'm going to make some profit and the
whole industry was immediately born
where professional Traders would bribe
their way to include a transaction a
strategic place
now when it was disorganized in the
beginning you can imagine that node
operators could also front run the front
runner Traders like if they see a
profitable trade why not include your
own or why not drop that suggested trade
and keep all the money for yourself
so it was a mess and to address that a
more democratic system was introduced
where there's a proposer node which is
completely blind to those highly
profitable blocks that are proposed by
builders
and proposers their only job is to see
hey what's the biggest bribe from this
particular block I will choose that one
and forward onto a relayer a relayer now
can unwrap that block and forward onto a
note to actually mine
and all this works great proposers
cannot produce malicious blocks based on
what input they get as long as they're
not aware of what are the transactions
in that obfuscated block except for
April 3rd on April 3rd someone found a
vulnerability in this package that
facilitates this called Mev boost where
they figured out if they transmit a
broken block the relayer will take it
fail but it will still expose all the
transactions so what this one malicious
proposer did effectively they leaked the
contents of the block they included
their own transactions in there
rearrange the transactions and stole 25
million dollars from these Advanced
Traders meds and by the way we're not
talking about people manually putting
together blocks these are actual machine
code fully automated Bots that generate
those every few seconds
on the Node execution side so node
exploitation BSC token Hub is is a
perfect example the way that it works is
that you can imagine like you don't want
to implement everything as a as a
virtual machine you want to probably
embed some highly optimized code like to
calculate hashes Merkle tree
verification or other things deep inside
the node itself so it's running in go
code not in some kind of virtualized
machine so you can run it fast
was the case with the binance smart
chain where they decided to implement
iavl Merkle tree verification
key element this is used to produce like
a claim ticket to the uh to the node say
hey someone is asking me for 100 million
dollars and they're offering this
verification receipt is this thing legit
and the note is supposed to say yeah it
is legit go ahead give it give it the uh
give them the money well someone was
able to find an exploit and if you look
carefully at the source code here
this if else statement this is a case
where both sides of a tree are defined
they were expecting only one side
effectively I'll give you some more time
to look at it but effectively you can
sneak in an extra proof in next door to
the legitimate one that's exactly what
the attackers did they were able to
steal 586 million dollars half a billion
dollars this is a down Market this if we
were it happened a year ago that would
have been the first billion dollar hack
um
from from the binance uh smart chain
token Hub they effectively created a
ticket a claim ticket that said hey you
owe me 2 trillion binance tokens and the
smart contract here obliged because the
node was uh the no proof verification
was vulnerable
so to zoom out state of protocol
security no one does 51 of reorg attacks
anymore that's in the past
I really was wondering if governance and
staking uh proof of stake attacks would
take over but that didn't really happen
the real game here our virtual machine
and node exploitation so if you want to
spend time researching for
vulnerabilities
um that's where you're going to find the
most deadly bugs
and that gets us to the state of defy
security this is by far the largest
field so let's spend more time on this
so just to give you a mental picture uh
D5 protocols we have users they're
interacting with dapps so these are
these web applications where you can
talk to let's say a lending protocol
uh daps talk to wallets so that's your
interface to the blockchain and then you
have blockchains that communicate with
smart contracts this is where this is
the Divide where the D5 ecosystem begins
those smart contracts can Implement all
sorts of things from uh Landing
borrowing protocols swaps you can
leverage your Investments and Flash
loans all sorts of fascinating things I
invite you to explore
contracts do not exist in vacuum in fact
it's a feature that they all stack and
interact with each other it's called
composability
one particular type of smart contracts
that I want to talk about are called
oracles they provide the ability for
blockchains to receive external data or
they provide information like what is
the current exchange rate like you know
if you're trying to swap eth for usdc or
what's the current price
and of course we have to talk about
admins so if you compromise
administrative Keys which happen
that control Smart contracts you can
empty whatever treasuries are inside
those smart contracts or do all sorts of
interesting things
so this is kind of a limited model I
just included just enough to talk about
a couple of use cases that I'm going to
discuss
so let's talk about Chain Bridge hacks
and the reason why these particular
hacks are so relevant is that there's
just a few of them but they're so costly
you saw that binance smart chain uh
compromise that was a bridge compromise
and it was immediately half a billion
dollars poof gone
the reason why Bridges exist is that we
no longer live in a world where there's
a Bitcoin Network an ethereum Network
and that's about it maybe a couple more
there are hundreds of chains out there
so if you're a user and you purchase
some token on let's say ethereum but you
want to do transactions on another chain
maybe they offer cheaper transaction
fees or different security
characteristics or different speed of
transactions whatever the reason you
want to transfer your tokens from one
chain into another you do this using
Bridges
the way the bridges work imagine that
you have some usdc on the ethereum
network
you will use bridges on both sides of
the network in this case it's polygon to
transfer that asset the way that it
works you send the usdc to the bridge
the bridge takes in your usdc holds on
to it in the liquidity pool and then
from there it mints a new usdc token on
the other side which is sent to you now
you'll immediately see wow those bridges
they hold on to all that usdc and other
tokens that they receive from users
you can see why attackers are interested
in this because they hold on to a lot of
it that's where the huge liquidity pools
holding on to all the user tokens there
and that gets us to the first exploit
the Wormhole compromise and this one is
just so fascinating from so many
directions
similar to the binance smart chain hack
that we discussed earlier there was an
issue with the proof verification
someone was able to craft an account
with a specific characteristic check out
the QR code for more details effectively
they were able to cheat and claim more
assets from the bridge that they were
allowed to in this case 325 million
dollars worth
they stole it on the Solana Network
transferred over to ethereum
but this is where it gets really
interesting
so on the Wormhole a year later
normally when you see what attackers do
after those compromises they use tornado
cash or they find some exchange without
a kyc requirement and they start
swapping it laundering and so on not
this one this guy was really really
wanted to extract maximum value so what
they did as a true DJ and DJ like just
people who are like doing crazy things
on on these uh on these networks is a
true d-gen they decided to take 120 000
eth and put it up as collateral on Oasis
Network
they took that as a collateral and then
they borrowed whole bunch of
our eth and staked eth and if you're not
familiar these are just ethereum tokens
but they're interest-bearing ethereum
tokens so not only did they steal 120
000 eth now they're earning interest on
what they stole so they're like really
cashing in here
except because they did this lending
thing there's always a risk of your loan
going underwater and we'll cover lending
protocols shortly
if your loan goes underwater you may get
liquidated that means you may lose all
of your collateral
and to prevent that there exists
specialized Bots they're called stop
loss Bots which you delegate access to
your token so if your loan is just about
to go underwater these Bots will step in
liquidate your loan before you lose
anything
the one thing the attackers did not
figure for is that the stop loss Bots
were also controlled by the Oasis
Network in the Oasis Network had admin
keys for that bot that means they could
potentially change it in such a way that
they could reclaim those funds and
that's exactly what happened they
upgraded a white a bunch of white hats
figured out that hey these guys are
going full DJ and they just deposited
and they delegated access to their
tokens to this new contract which you
have admin keys for could you maybe hack
your contract and you know steal those
back
sure
upgrade went through they stole those
assets from the attacker who was
probably sitting there what the hell
just happened I got hacked
they restored the loan took back the
original Eve plus actual 17 000 extra e
that they earned in interest and gave it
back to the Wormhole protocol
this type of stuff only happens in D5
this is the this is the wild west guys
this is just one example of white hat
attacks again there are a lot of
volunteers that sit there and they
constantly Monitor and watch for attacks
on it's a public ledger so you can see
the attack live happening in front of
your eyes so a lot of white hats what
they started doing is that they actually
the second they see the first
transaction of a hack they will swoop in
and start hacking the protocol
themselves and then they'll give
whatever money that they recovered back
to the protocol
um so there's there's a whole
interesting and the best part is that
once again you can see all this
happening live in front of your eyes
transaction after transaction
pretty fascinating
okay
um let's talk about lending protocols uh
so lending protocol I guess why do
lending protocols even exist first like
imagine you have one million dollars
worth of Eve and you want to buy a house
not in San Francisco far away
um
so your one option is you take your 1
million each and then you sell it you
pay 30 40 in taxes now you have around
like maybe 600k so you got your down
payment you got a mortgage cool the
other way you can do this is you can
take your million dollars worth of wheat
eat and uh
well
uh
and you can put it up as collateral and
you put out as a collateral and withdraw
one million dollars worth of usdc so now
instead of paying your interest rates to
some mortgage company Fannie Mae or
whatever you can actually pay to this
lending protocol which is probably a few
percent it's decentralized they're not
going to confiscate your your mortgage
if they're pissed at you or something
like that
um and that's great you just got a house
million dollars that's cool uh lending
protocols when they give you this uh
loan internally they keep your
collateral and they also keep track to
make sure that the the ratio between the
uh the collateral and how much usdc they
gave you remains at least a one to one
ratio
the reason they need to do this is
because this is all permissionless they
don't have your kyc there's neural
mechanisms that they can go and find you
like hey give me back my loan or
Institute a legal action that's not the
whole point of D5
but imagine a scenario that within this
ratio what if eth drops like it did in a
couple days
and now your loan is underwater while
lending protocols they implemented a
mechanism where they get rid of bad
loans
once they go underwater and the way that
the smart contracts cannot call
themselves so the what they invented is
they created a liquidation Market where
they incentivized Bots the smart
contracts or individuals
to come in
with some of their own usdc pay off the
um the collateral uh pay off the loan
for for uh for that user and then
reclaim the uh the collateral so a
liquidator comes in gives some usdc take
over all of the users collateral
and now we are solid
you may ask what's the incentive the
incentive here is that they obtain the
initial collateral at a discount
so instead of putting up million dollars
worth of usdc to purchase that million
dollars worth of if they put in maybe 99
or 98 and that's their profit
now the more underwater is the loan the
more incentives The Lending protocol
must give in order for someone to swoop
in and give up that loan
and that's where that's something like
you can imagine like normally this this
whole action occurs
just the second the loan even approaches
a um a liquidation point
um and then that discount is basically
compensated but whatever fees are
involved when you first originate the
loan so the lending protocol is made
whole Liquidator makes some money user
uh keeps their initial like borrowed
assets everyone is happy
but imagine there is a Black Swan event
and it really drops under
now the Liquidator comes in gets a huge
let's say up to 20 discount on some
protocols that we'll discuss shortly
gets that huge discount but what happens
with 20 percent discount on the lending
protocol side they have to hold on to it
because no one's going to buy it and
it's called Bat debt lending protocols
hate accumulating bad debt
so with that knowledge in mind uh let's
talk about Euler protocol compromise on
March 13th Euler Finance
a landing protocol lost 197 million
dollars and the reason they were able
they lost all of that is that they
introduced a function and Method called
donate to reserves the method allows you
to take your collateral and effectively
burn it and burn arbitrary amounts of it
so they created this feature because as
you do borrowing and Landing you slowly
start accumulating all sorts of uh junk
and you want to get rid of it just it
was a cleanup function what they didn't
realize and account for
what happens to the to the loan if you
start burning the collateral
and arbitrary amounts of collateral you
can force your loan to go severely
underwater so you have this million to
million loan and you just burned half a
million off collateral now your loan is
underwater Oh what are you going to do
with that well you're going to say well
Liquidators are going to come in they're
going to take a cut but what's the
benefit what's the profit to the
attacker there is none they just burn
some of their collateral and they lost
lost all of it now
except the Euler protocol introduced
another feature which is called minting
or leveraging you can take your initial
million dollars
and you can leverage it up to 20 times
so now you have 20 million dollars of
debt and collateral which you need to
pay off but you can do this for all
sorts of things you can enable Short
Selling mechanisms and so on
so now you have a 20 million in
collateral
and the protocol and he forced it to go
underwater and the protocol can give you
up to 20 discount so you can you can
make uh 20 of 20 Millions around four
million dollars so uh sorry 200 up to
four hundred thousand so you can you can
slowly accumulate the profits beyond
what you initially uh sorry it is sorry
20 million dollars twenty percent four
million dollars four million dollars
from the initial million dollar
collateral so you put in one million and
you just forexed it pretty profitable so
the attackers were able to use that and
abuse this feature to effectively go
token by token that it was offered by
this protocol and empty it 200 million
dollars
but again there's a reason why I'm
talking about this protocol because it's
not so much the hack it's what happens
next
so let's talk about me V bot so briefly
mentioned that
briefly mentioned that there are these
machines that are sitting watching all
the transactions on chain for anything
profitable and you know it's a really
profitable transaction an exploit you
run this thing and you generate a whole
bunch of profit and such was the case
here so the attacker uh on March 13th 8
50 a.m in 23 seconds deployed an exploit
contract
four minutes later they perform the
actual exploit why do they wait so long
what happened in those four minutes well
the second they deployed the exploit
contract and bought
detected at a deployment understood that
it's profitable and decided to redeploy
it so at 8 50 35 seconds that's exactly
12 seconds after the initial deployment
some machine fit simulated the whole
thing figured out it's an exploit
redeployed the contract and then a few
seconds later actually ran the exploit
and Fran ran the attacker
and all they had to do they
automatically went into the byte code
just the sophistication of those things
they went into the contract there was
some access controls built in they
automatically replaced the bike cult to
make sure that they can run this code
themselves
and try to extract The Profit they were
not successful in this case
unfortunately because the attacker built
in all sorts of hard-coded addresses so
in the end in this particular case the
Mev bot ended up sending money back to
the attacker for which they put out
Unchained message apologizing profusely
but the point is not even attackers are
safe from those things they constantly
sit on chain and they they attack
everyone if it's profitable exploit or
not they will Target you
but the story does not end there
there is a happy end
uh
the normal operating procedure after a
D5 hack occurs
is is that people start communicating
with attackers a lot of them are begging
like oh this was my entire life savings
could you pretty please give me my money
back and so on and on so the way that a
sample transaction looks like is you can
put arbitrary data including ASCII codes
in a transaction you can transfer like
maybe 0.001 eth to get attention from
the attackers
in this case it was an ASCII code from
Euler deployer so this is the Euler
people themselves and they put in
message again standard operating
procedure hey you hacked us haha good
job uh you know if you keep 90 of the
profits sorry if you give us 90 of the
profits and keep 10 for yourself you
know we promise not to pursue further
legal action
um and in this case I again invite you
to visit this link we just put out a
blog post part one which dives into this
thing
fascinating story involving somehow
North Korea and you know backstabbing
this is this is defy land this is pretty
wild the way there culminates is the
attacker
put out a message Jacob here I'm sorry
I'm not sure what I did I'm sorry for
messing people's money and ended up
returning all of it
um and that's that brings up another
interesting point is that this bounty
thing works uh again there are a bunch
of volunteers that sit on chain look for
those hacks and then they dox the hell
out of the attackers if by some mistake
an attacker interacted with a
centralized exchange where they can
extract kyc or in fact if the attackers
used metamask so metamask is a common
wallet but if you recall back to when I
was introducing the model you don't just
send messages directly to the blockchain
you go through centralized servers and
what do centralized service have access
to your IP addresses and your addresses
and they do collect them
so there are a lot of opportunities for
the good guys to catch the bad guys
um
and worst case there are rewards that
are that are put up there so in the case
of the Wormhole they were able to
reclaim it a year later and in this case
they were able to effectively Force the
attacker to return all the assets this
happens more often than not that the
same scenario played out a couple times
since March incident
okay I'm not gonna have time to talk
about all the different exploit vectors
what I do want to point out this is
think of as like o wasp top 10 style
list uh what I do want to point out is
stolen private Keys the North Korean
style hack where they go in and get all
the keys and extract them from your
contract that's probably by far the most
painful methods that said the most
frequently occurring method is probably
price Oracle manipulation so remember
that price Oracle node that gives you
price data where people figure out all
sorts of ways to manipulate the price
data to make sure that they can do
interesting uh creative Arbitrage
so I invite you to learn more about
these attack vectors
so overall the state of D5 security
we lost 3.7 billion dollars in 2022 I do
see the same attack vectors being used
again and again so there's definitely a
gap in security staff security
development processes and tooling when
targets when when D5 project gets hacked
there's also a lack in incident response
and monitoring processes oftentimes
these projects recognize that they were
hacked because someone tweeted them like
hey project XYZ you may want to look at
this transaction
um that that's your incident response
that's obviously lacking but there
there's there's good future in that in
building those response capabilities
um and then the other concern is just
overloaded audit companies there are
specialized audit firms that exist they
can look for those bugs but there's so
few of them the professionals are it's
just so hard to bring someone into this
field that most of them are booked for
months and maybe a year ahead so in the
case of the Euler Finance debug that was
introduced that resulted in the exploit
they added this feature after the audits
were done and quite simply because it
takes months to get something audited so
they just added it
okay let's talk quickly about the state
of block SEC ecosystem or if you if this
sounds interesting to you what what you
could build on
uh so I already mentioned audit
companies there are hundreds of them I'm
only listing just a few most of them
popped up in the last year or two so if
you want to learn and pick up the skill
there's just such lack of them that
individual Auditors are making like
pretty good living like you can I've
seen people pick up this field maybe a
few months ago and they're already
full-time booked
uh tooling could be built there are bug
Bounty programs now like immunify code
for arena all exist in the last couple
years it's a brand new field
um
in terms of monitoring there again last
year so we've seen some solutions which
use machine learning they use uh just
the ability to detect that transaction
is malicious
decode a transaction the risk algorithms
that tell you that hey this lending
protocol thing that you're building is
you probably want to look at again
insurance companies deal with inevitable
hacks so you can insure yourself in case
there's a compromise and so on
wallet security exploded seemingly in
the last few months and that's basically
dealing with how many people are getting
fished so they're creating these
crypto firewalls if you will to alert
user that something is amiss
forensics companies and incident
response are still they're just a few
that are fairly old but not not too many
new players
let's talk about security Community
security Community is amazing their
Capture the Flag competition they're a
dedicated conferences just for D5 and
blockchain security their newsletters
Shameless plug this one that I'm running
block thread.io wrecked and others that
go in details over exactly what's
happening who was compromised how would
they compromised what's the latest
research people in the community are
warm they share knowledge they welcome
new folks joining us
foreign
that said if any of that sounds
interesting to you and you're kind of
sick with the same old security stuff
that you do like no more exercises okay
yet another exercise that's cool you
want to do something completely wild
Hunt down people live on chain
join explore this ecosystem as a smart
contract auditor on chain investigator
to figure out who the bad guys are uh
security Engineers incident responders
are probably much needed
and with that I'll give you some time
for questions
yes
what does that mean but the question is
modular blockchain security what does
that mean
sure uh Layer Two blockchains
effectively ethereum evolved as a
primary blockchain
but everyone is using it so the fees
start going up so people start
introducing additional layers where you
can offload some of the capacity to
those layer 2 blockchains that way you
reduce the fees increase the speed
there's some trade-offs with security
sometimes but
um
it depends on the protocol some
Implement zero knowledge proof switchers
very secure but kind of slow some
Implement centralized nodes centralized
sequences and architecture and that's
very fast but very centralized so less
secure so all sorts of trade-offs uh
there's a resource I'll remember I'll
tell you in a bit that measures and
Compares them
yeah that's that's the future that's
where a lot of stuff is happening right
now any other questions
all right
there's one coming up
uh there's one coming up in France it's
called D5 security Summit
I would recommend that one that said
every um there are like eth ethereum
conferences which happening there's one
in San Francisco coming up I think in
like later in the year and they always
have security track talks so I would
just go to General crypto conference and
just there's always someone talking
about different threats in attacks
all right thank you folks