hello everyone welcome to normalized
logs and Beyond with our speakers Brian
Maloney and Dave Levitsky or David
Levitsky
hey everyone good afternoon
um thanks for sticking with us for one
of the last talks of the day my name is
Brian Maloney and this is David Levitsky
and we work together to build a cloud
native threat detection Pipeline and
platform for benchling now what is
benchling you might ask benchlings the
software service platform that powers
some of the world's most cutting-edge
biotechnology research
with customers ranging from two
scientists and a molecule startups to
some of the largest biotech companies
around
these will say benchling protects some
extremely sensitive data on behalf of
their customers and needed a scalable
and reliable solution for detecting
threats to that data while retaining
maximum flexibility for an unknown
future our work resulted in a platform
built on replaceable components using
combination of AWS Technologies and
off-the-shelf Hardware software which is
the subject of this talk and just one
last note about mentioning we are hiring
so if you're interested maybe we can
come talk to me
um but first let's just briefly go over
the steps of threat detection for those
of you who might be primarily offensive
practitioners or if you're just new to
the field this you can think of this
kind of as just a brief blue team 101.
so this is kind of the the overview of
the steps um from collection to
normalization enrichment detections
running on that security alerts going
into investigations and then response
actions
so what about collection right we start
on the left with collection we we need
the data to do our work
um collection I think of it is like the
hard part
um any modern organization of any
significant size is going to have a
ridiculous number of security data
sources from your Enterprise identity
and your HR applications things that you
use to run your business to your
productivity software that you use to to
drive to communicate with your customers
to the product itself we're a software
as a service company so obviously our
software generates a ton of data
um
and these sources they're they're not
uniform you know they're they're going
to come in in many formats raw text logs
delimited formats CSV and space to
limited Json could be some binary
formats even
um and those come in Via different
protocols uh you know some of you may
not have to deal with syslog today but a
lot of people still do
um buckets are a common way of
delivering logs as well
um and you need a way to get that data
into your platform easily HTTP apis via
either pull or push are another common
method and then Cloud event buses are
kind of an up and comer in this space
so then once you've got that data into
your system you want to normalize it
um why do you normalize because you need
to be able to do efficient queries on
that data
but in order to do that you're going to
have to pick some kind of a schema
you're going to want to make sure that
you have the essential pieces of data
that you need
and you're going to need to
um track those things like time stamps
and log sources and then of course
you're going to have to think about what
goes into your normalization as well
um so for example if you do have those
raw text logs that may involve regex's
regular Expressions which there's some
operational risks there which we'll
cover maybe in depth a little later CSV
logs also if it's a perfectly
standardized CSV you're probably not
going to run in any trouble but
sometimes you have quotes in the wrong
places that then break your parsing so
normalizations engines just need to be
limited so that they don't run over and
they need to be able to handle erroneous
data
once you have that normalized data
you're going to want to enrich that
enriching it provides the insights that
you need to detect threats to your uh
your platforms
this enrichment could data could come
from internal sources like your
Enterprise Data Systems
um you know HR systems things like that
who's doing what how do we attribute
things it could be metadata about your
production resources
and it could also be indicators of
compromise for your detective controls
so you may have specific indicators of
compromise that are specific to your
platform
this may also come from external sources
so those indicators of compromise could
come from public databases they're like
things on GitHub that you can grab or
there are vendors that can also provide
these kinds of uh threat data that you
can use uh with your normalized logs
finally once you have been enriched data
enrich normalized data you can run
detections on those to find the actual
Bad actors in your systems
this may be predefined indicators of
compromise it could be anomaly detection
using statistical methods or
unsupervised ml models or maybe you know
everybody's favorite topic large
language models might be part of this in
the future
but it's important uh to do to be able
to run iterative development of those
detections because they do change over
time and you want to be able to tune the
performance as things change in your
environment
and you also want to be able to reduce
false positives because there's a human
cost to this in the next step
finally those alerts go to the response
team they need the details about what
happened and how they can investigate it
so you do need to have some kind of a
system for alert delivery
moving on to the last step and then
we'll get into the architecture you want
to be able to
investigate what happened so you're
going to need the same data for that
right
um One One log Source might indicate
something's wrong and then you need
additional context from other sources
from there that step you can move to
confirming whether it's a malicious
actor or benign most the time it's going
to be benign but you still have to check
every time you get one of these events
fire
in the case that it is malicious again
just wrapping up kind of our blue team
101 you're going to want to contain that
intrusion close the vulnerabilities that
may have allowed somebody to get in in
the first place
um prepare and execute your recovery
plan and then as always whenever there's
some kind of an incident be it an
operational incident or security
incident you're going to want to conduct
a Lessons Learned section session
afterwards
so this is what we want to do now how
did we actually do it so we're going to
jump in now to the architecture
so I'm going to go over kind of two
parts of the architecture the inputs and
then the detection side and then I'll
show you just a slide briefly where we
put the two together
so you can see on the left hand side of
the screen
we support multiple different sources
types
those could be HTTP API syslog buckets
Etc
and those go into a series of lambdas so
we are an AWS shop so this will be an
AWS specific architecture but this could
be applicable to many other clouds
so those we use lambdas for inputs
except in the case of syslog which
obviously it's not really easy to tie
syslog to a Lambda
um
so for that you'd want to have a
traditional more traditional kind of
compute platform with a load balancer
from those Lambda inputs we then add the
origin metadata and run it through
Kinesis fire hose which allows us to
aggregate huge amounts of data into a
semi-structured data bucket and that's
kind of our golden storage bucket where
we do all of our work from
once we get the data in
you can see that the same bucket is kind
of down on the bottom left of this
diagram
we can use both aws's analytics tools
and third-party analytics tools with
which we connect to the same bucket and
this allows us to use the right tool for
the job which is one of the most
important things that we try to
accomplish with this architecture
so putting these two sides together
this is what the entire thing looks like
and it's a little you know it's a little
big it's a little complex but it's all
managed by infrastructure as code
doesn't require very much uh you know
care and feeding at all
so now we'll get into kind of deep Dives
on the different parts of this
architecture
so to begin with we're going to start
with the data collection which is one on
the left hand side of that diagram that
we were just looking at
so this takes the raw data and brings it
into our platform
now as we covered previously in the
overview the data sources are extremely
diverse we have a preference for pull
and the reason you want to prefer pull
for data collection is because
there aren't as many reliability
concerns with the pull data source so a
pull data source caching is inherent you
grab the data when you're ready to
receive it
and generally that's very very
straightforward and allows data buffer
On the Origin side with a push data
source
like syslog or an HTTP receiver
that increases the reliability
requirements on that input
and the reason for that is that if your
input goes down for you know hours days
uh then that data will be buffered on
the source maybe uh and it will
eventually be lost it may be lost right
away so that's why we have a strong
preference for pull inputs even though
we support both in our architecture
now the scale can be very large so we
needed an architecture that is you know
elastically scalable Cloud native
and we want that scaling to grow and to
shrink as the input changes over time so
we want it to handle bursts you know the
the old slash dot effect right uh and
also just general seasonality of data
where you know nobody uses the platform
on a weekend so we don't really you know
need to be running a full capacity
cluster at that time
another goal is to have the cost growth
be no more than linear with volume so
ideally we can get some economies of
scale as the volume goes up the costs
may not grow as quickly as the volume
does but at the very least you don't
want to be paying any more as you get
more and more data because that limits
your long-term scalability
we wanted a system that was limited
required limited coding so a lot of
these inputs we wanted collaborators to
be able to help with this
um you know anybody should be able to
get data to us so we developed a system
with a significant wrapper functions
that allowed you to write many types of
inputs in just a few lines of python and
we wanted to be resilient to failure and
have health monitoring which will cover
the specifics of in a few in a few
slides most importantly
stay Cloud native otherwise you're going
to be just paying extra and you're not
going to be efficient on the cloud that
you're running on
so for pull sources
the architecture for both sources is
kind of similar for all pull sources one
way or another in our architecture the
notification notification of data will
arrive on an eventbridge bus and that
will route to an sqsq which is in front
of an input Lambda the reason we use
sqsqs instead of going directly from
eventbridge to Lambda is because sqsqs
allow your Landers to run synchronously
and give you some
um
retry benefits it's more able to redrive
data if uh if things don't go so well in
your Lambda which can sometimes happen
so after the it arrives in that sqsq the
function is triggered and the data is
collected and written to that Central
Kinesis fire hose uh which then goes
into our bucket
now what about when it's an API that
we're pulling from and it's not an S3
bucket S3 buckets are pretty much the
trivial case but when it's an API you
may not get a web hook notification I
haven't really even seen that
eventbridge has a scheduler built in
which is an AWS service but that
scheduler does have some limitations it
doesn't have any ability to catch up if
it gets behind it'll just keep
monotonically generating cron type
events uh and um it doesn't have a sub
minute granularity if you need that so
we do have a tiny event generator for
our poll sources and that runs in
fargate and it just generates events
into our eventbridge bus that triggers
those inputs
so this is kind of the visual of what
that looks like so as you can see on the
left hand side we have log buckets which
generate bucket notifications into the
event Bridge bus and we have our job
generator which stores booksmarks and
dynamodb but otherwise also generates
into the same eventbridge bus those
trigger those sqs cues which trigger the
lambdas in turn Which pull data from
either those buckets or public log apis
and the logs of course are written to
the event the Kinesis fire hose and then
onto our bucket
now what about those push sources
um as I said uh there's syslog still
exists in the world uh you might need an
HTTP receiver
AWS is pretty much completely optimized
for building high volume https services
so similarly we want to use a similar
type of architecture Lambda is a very
good tool for this because it doesn't
need to process things for long
typically
so you can very simply meet this need by
building a receiver Lambda behind an API
Gateway
now you'll need to make your own
decisions if you're going to build
something like this about how resilient
you want it to be do you want to be in
you know just multiple era availability
zones within one region do you want to
be in multiple regions uh and resilient
across that
but in general again you know you can
reuse the code from the pull inputs and
use the same formatting and filtering
that you would use in your push inputs
designed for uh for high volume of
course so you do want to allow for
batched uploads
um if you do an HTTP request for every
single log message you'll quickly
overwhelm even aws's scalability
and finally since this is a security
talk you do need to threat model an
https input and decide what the risks
are that you're willing to accept
um you know in some cases I don't think
that it's particularly risky to have
this on the internet as long as it's you
know right only right only being the
important thing
um but you know your mileage may vary
um be sure to you know threat model this
for your own organization
now once you have that reliable log
endpoint
um you can then use collectors to
collect things that don't speak HTTP so
you know there are many tools for this
um they're open source tools they're
easily easy to get easy to install and
from there you can make a centralized
syslog collector and have that forwarded
to http or you can pick up files from
machines or you can collect metrics and
that all goes into the same pipeline as
everything else so once again we're all
centralized everything you know is is
hunky-dory so far
so
what if something goes wrong right so
obviously these things do uh you do
sometimes get malformed logs you do
sometimes get uh you know a format
changing how do you detect that
so again once again we're using an AWS
native architecture
so we use cloud watch alerts to detect
messages and dead letter cues from our
sqs cues too many messages too few
messages
Lambda failures and the runtime of
lambdas because there is a hard limit of
lambdas you can set a limit on each
Lambda but the longest you can set is 15
minutes so as you start to approach that
you do need to tune
um
typically we only see failures in
response to somebody making a change
again you can see format changes
Downstream but again that's usually due
to a human likewise other failures with
like run time exceeded or things like
that are usually due to some human as
well so we have not seen a lot of uh
We've not needed a lot of care and
feeding and it's usually untraceable to
something in our gitups process
so now we've collected the data and
we've put it all in a centralized S3
bucket
um or actually as part of putting it
into an S3 bucket we're going to take
this normalization step
we developed a companion system uh
notice this is the normalization and
enrichment step we developed a companion
system for managing enrichment data
which David will cover a little later on
but right now we'll just talk briefly
about normalization
so we talked about normalization earlier
just the why again structured logs are
more performant and easier to analyze
and you also have an opportunity when
you normalize to standardize your field
names so there are some common things
like username and IP address
that can make your analysis code much
easier to write if you use a
standardized format
we also have some instrumentation inside
our normalization engine which allows us
to verify if something starts performing
poorly if we get less data than we
expect it's just another point of
instrumentation in addition to our Cloud
watch
one important choice when you do build
your own normalization is whether you
want to keep the raw message or not so
the whole point of normalization is to
reorganize the message into something
that's easy to use do you keep the
original for us the costs are low enough
that we have chosen to keep the raw
message that allows us to reprocess in
the future if our schema does change
now I mentioned log schemas
if you're building from scratch like we
did you have an important uh you know
very important choice to make in what
schema you use there are some very high
capability schemas that have a whole lot
of uh you know data types in them
um
they require a more advanced normalizer
and a more advanced normalizer requires
more care and feeding the more regular
Expressions you use the more likely that
something could go wrong
um but some popular choices as far as
those more advanced schemas would be the
elastic common schema or the open cyber
security schema framework both of those
have support by you know fairly large
chunks of the industry
but what did we do
so
we decided to go with a very lightweight
wrapper schema as I said that we are
retaining the original message so we
have a fairly large uh a fairly good
ability to
take actions further Downstream on that
uh that original message or slightly
restructured message
so we just have a simple wrapper that
includes where it came from
um what the metadata about how it got
there was when we saw it first a
deduplication ID and you know the
message itself and a few other uh less
important fields
now again since this is an architecture
deep dive
we're just going to briefly talk about
how we actually accomplish that
normalization and that's what I consider
like to be a Cooperative design the
inputs give the basic format uh they
ensure they verify that the format
matches what's expected and structure it
so that it's already
in you know in a structured data format
so it can be embedded into Json without
needing to then pull out the data later
on
um from there it goes to fire hose and
fire hose has the ability to run
arbitrary functions on uh the messages
that go by in firehose so there's an
additional normalization Lambda there
where we can do centralized processing
for example we can add enrichment data
into the message if there's something
that's going to be transient that we
might need in the future
and we can also do
um some metrics on the data as it goes
by
in the normalizer so
that should wrap up the normalization
phase and will then move on into the
detection phase which David's going to
take over for
oh thanks Brian
so
going back to our original architecture
diagram uh thank you Brian for covering
the left half which is the very complex
phase of you know getting a lot of
different heterogeneous data sources and
placing them into a single bucket where
you have a nice source of Truth and
right now we're going to focus on the
right side of the equation which is what
do we do with this data from a detection
response function when it's actually
flowing into our kind of data Lake
so taking kind of one quick step back uh
you know what is the detection blue team
101 really we're looking at some sort of
data source and trying to identify
whether malicious events are happening
that somebody needs to either respond
respond to either automatically or
manually and for us we kind of have
broken it up into two different
classifications we have streaming style
detections where you're looking at
events as they come in one by one a good
example of this is you know you're
looking at Network traffic you have a
host which has reached out to uh some IP
or some domain that you know is
associated with a malicious actor that
event in and of itself that Json payload
is enough to tell you that hey something
is wrong you can look at those events
kind of one by one they have
self-encapsulated context a bit more
complicated is the batch detection where
you're actually looking for additional
context and addition additional
information of the same kind of events
over time a really good example is the
MFA fatigue attacks that have been
happening uh pretty frequently and we're
in securing you a couple months ago but
essentially if you think about detecting
for an attack like that where you're
consistently having or you're having a
user who's consistently getting MFA auth
requests if somebody fails an MFA auth
request one time that could be normal
right you hit the wrong button on your
phone your face ID doesn't work
something happens but if you see
activity where you're having a user
consistently failing it three four five
times in a span of a few minutes that
might indicate a little bit more that
something bad is actually happening so
um we have kind of these two different
categorizations for detections that we
look at
uh really want to talk about how we
manage detections as well uh there was
actually a panel right before this which
uh seemed great I highly recommend
checking that out that kind of covered
this topic in more detail uh we just
wanted to touch it really quickly so
taking components from software
engineering principles Brian and I are
software Engineers by Nature we're
Builders at heart spent a lot of time
kind of in those kinds of workflows and
for us it was really really important to
kind of take those principles and align
them to our detections as well so if you
think about detections not as a
detection but as some sort of software
service and you shift your mental model
a little bit there's a lot of parallels
that will happen so you want to be able
to write repeatable detections you want
to have a centralized source of Truth
for them you want to be able to test
them upgrade them roll them back in case
of a bug and you also want to be able to
promote them across different Dev and
prod environments so by the time with
detection or your software service gets
to a production environment you should
have full confidence and its ability to
do the job that you wanted to testing
both in unit tests and integration
testing is something that we really
wanted to have as well to ensure really
high Bar for our again software services
in this case detections
so wanted to walk you through kind of
the detection workflow that we've kind
of come up with that has that we've
built out has been working pretty well
for us so I'm kind of skipping the
initial phases of the detection life
cycle where you would gather your
requirements you'd come up with a
hypothesis this is more when you've kind
of have a little proof of concept and
you want to start working on a tangible
detection
uh so we start off in a Dev environment
we purposefully have a delineation
between our Dev environment and our
production environment again just going
back to that testing story you can make
changes you can try new things out
without risking any Downstream systems
we have two similar data flows in both
our Dev environment and our private
environment to keep costs down we do
data sampling in our Dev environment but
you still have a very real stream of
data that's coming in uh you know with
certain contextual requirements if the
data is okay to be in Dev and then that
gives you a really nice environment to
test things out uh prototype things and
again without having the risk of
impacting something in production
so you do your local development you
write some code next thing that happens
is as with the software service you're
going to write some sort of unit tests
unit tests get committed to a GitHub
repository that kicks off a deployment
uh and once the deployment happens we
also have an additional step of
continuous validation so if you think of
uh you know a web service or or a
website it's pretty easy to know when
issues are happening the website won't
load uh latency is super super high
maybe there's error rates that are
happening on the back end uh but for
detection you don't really necessarily
know how often it's going to or not
going to fire in fact for some of your
very high fidelity detections ideally
depending on the environment you're in
they shouldn't really ever fire at all
so we really wanted to have some sort of
continuous validation system to ensure
that the detections that were written
you know one two three years ago maybe
by someone who's not even on the team
anymore are still doing the exact job
that they were designed to do from day
one
so if all of these steps pass and the
noise level is acceptable continuous
validation is good we will simply do a
promotion process and deploy it in our
production environment or we still get
the continuous validation consistently
so I've talked about this continuous
validation step a couple of times and I
want to dive into it a little bit deeper
um one thing I also want to call out is
that when Brian and I were building the
system we were kind of faced with a fair
amount of work to do to go from you know
from scratch to something functional and
for the detection engine we kind of
needed to figure out if it was something
we wanted to build or something we
wanted to buy for a variety of different
reasons based on engineering constraints
and a couple of other factors it was
also really important for us to be able
to immediately deliver value to the
business so as the business is investing
in a detection response function we
needed to be able to kind of show value
pretty quickly and so we chose to kind
of buy a detection engine so that we can
build workflows on top of that gave us a
nice Foundation to get started and let
us invest in some really really neat
efforts to guarantee a high level of
service for instance continuous
validation
so on the detection Health System I
think I got a little bit ahead of myself
here uh but essentially your deductions
can only help protect the business if
they're actually functioning and if
they're actually working uh unit tests
are great when people talk about
detections as code there's a lot of talk
about unit tests which is fantastic but
they're not necessarily enough to go
from a raw log to a response action all
the steps in between there's a ton of
different interconnected components you
can have bugs you can have bad
deployments you know something can be
failing along the lines that you know
you might not have monitoring for you
might not have thought to build
monitoring for so we really needed some
sort of fully functional end-to-end
integration test
one other thing for us is we want to
keep in mind that writing detections is
part writing complex detection
detections is hard you go from the
requirements phase you go through your
prototype you build it you test the
noise level you tune in the last thing
we wanted to do was come up with some
sort of process which would you know
upset detection response engineers and
want them to bypass the testing process
so we wanted to build something which
was low friction easy and would make our
DNR Engineers want to write tests
because it would give them a benefit
versus something that you know they
would just have to do because we put a
check box and then they kind of stopped
doing it after some time
so our detection health system has uh
two different components um the first is
generating Canary alerts so what we do
is we built a system that takes
synthetic data uh fires in into our
detection Pipeline and then that flows
Downstream there's a couple of different
components here you'll notice uh very
similarly we have a event Bridge rule
which kicks off a Lambda on a Cron job
Lambda has monitoring with Cloud watch
alarms all the built-in native
Integrations again taking a cloud native
approach has been extremely helpful for
us
we put Canary data in an S3 bucket that
the Lambda will read from and then it
will fire into our detection pipeline
which Kinesis fire hose it will take the
data it will send it into our
centralized source of Truth
um S3 bucket what we do with the canary
data is we mark it in some way to
determine that it is actually Canary
event if so in our Downstream automation
Downstream processing typically this
will be a soar platform we short circuit
so we make a note of that event but we
don't generate anything that a human
would need to interact with we don't
cause additional alert for you know an
analyst or a DNR engineer there's no
extra work that's generated from this so
it only really raises noise of canary
events stop firing if it's not a canary
event if it's a real thing of course we
don't want to get in the way of any
alerting there so it just proceeds with
the regular flow uh one other thing I
want to call out is the reason why we
chose to start with synthetic data
rather than building a bunch of
different environments to kind of write
scripts to generate real data is due to
the heterogeneous environment that we
operate in uh Brian alluded to it with
all the different data sources SAS
companies so lots of different
environments and Integrations rather
than spending the time to kind of build
out and mimic every single environment
every single offering that we wanted to
keep track of we felt that we would be
able to provide value more immediately
and faster in achieving our goal of kind
of maintaining a high bar of detections
by using choosing to use Canary events
down the road the intention is to kind
of take the most common environments and
swap out the canary events for real
events that's some future work that will
be done at some point
the second component is actually
sounding the alarm or being the canary
in case a detection stops firing so
every single time a detection fires it
gets written to a detection table which
is actually also used for our batch
detections so there's a record of all of
that a Lambda will query this table with
a cloud watch rule consistently on a
cron it will take these metrics and
report them as cloudwatch metrics
cloudwatch metrics will have alarms tied
to them so if for some period of time
hours days you know whatever your
threshold is there will be an alert that
fires if there's no Canary event that
has run through
uh so what we did was we took kind of
all these two components and we
abstracted it away in a terraform module
very similar to how Brian talked about
having a terraform module to allow for
easy repeatability for onboarding new
data we really wanted to maintain kind
of a similar approach for these uh for
the detection Health System again just
being mindful of the fact that we don't
want to get in anyone's way we want to
empower people to take advantage of this
kind of free testing so all it takes is
instantiating a terraform module it's
like four lines of code and uploading a
file to S3 so very very low friction you
get free monitoring for your detection
knowing something's wrong
the next section is called alerting but
it's actually a trick it's not
necessarily alerting yet so just because
you have a detection that's fired
doesn't necessarily mean that you're
ready to generate an alert and the
reason for that is how much context does
your detection have that's already fired
uh context is key because if you just
have detections alerting humans or
sending stuff into a queue very quickly
you're going to hit alert fatigue you're
going to have a huge backlog and it's
not even going to be helpful you're just
going to have too much stuff that's
firing a lot of it is probably not even
important or is benign so you need
context to be able to filter things out
and suppress them accordingly
I want to walk you through a basic
enrichment example of how a detection
can fire but by enriching it and getting
additional information you can triage it
a lot faster and have much better
understanding when someone begins an
investigation on the screen is a sample
guard Duty alert so this is not a real
alert if you use the service you can
like click a button it will generate
some fake alerts you can see the ec2
instance ID is not real but in this case
it's simulating a real guard Duty
detection firing also guard duty is
Amazon's threat native threat detection
service so you can see that you know
there's an ec2 communicating outbound
with a known C2 server I blocked out the
account but there's an account number in
there and you kind of have a description
of what's going on there so when this
alert fires if you see it and you send
it to someone to take a look at you know
something is wrong right you have some
sort of host it's communicating with
things that shouldn't be communicating
with what's going on but the immediate
questions you're going to ask are what
is the cc2 doing
um whose ec2 is is it important is it a
build server is it like a one-off kind
of research thing is it a production
server we're taking down the server will
impact a production workload and you
have to take a completely different set
of response steps there's a lot of
context that kind of gets built in who
owns the cc2 who's the service team what
kind of stakeholder are you going to be
working with
you have very similar questions around
the account portion who owns this
account again who are you going to talk
to how important is this account is this
a Legacy account that's been forgotten
about is there extremely sensitive data
in here to the business or from
compliance perspectives where all of a
sudden you know this is P0 hands on deck
uh lastly this one is a little bit more
of a stretch goal I guess but if you
have thread until feeds that you
subscribe to or maybe more mature thread
Intel capabilities you can maybe track
the IP or the domain and say hey is this
a so is this associated with the threat
actor that we're tracking have we
already been hit by this you know threat
actor during a different campaign what
do we already know about this so that
can be helpful as well
uh Brian touched on it earlier but the
way that we do this is with our
enrichment architecture so again to add
context into detections when they fire
uh prior to an alert just being created
there's a couple of different a couple
of different steps here but the main
building blocks are the same ones that
we've been demonstrating throughout this
entire application so we have an
enrichment data source again it can be
external it can be internal you got data
that can be useful somewhere and we
query it with a Lambda on a Cron job in
which in AWS is an eventbridge scheduler
so the Lambda will take this data it
will write it to an enrichment table
which in our case is dynamodb the reason
why we chose it is because it's great
for unstructured data it's easy to use
scales has really easy Integrations with
things like soar platforms Etc just
gives you a nice little hook to query
the data Brian actually wrote some
really neat code to do some
deduplication between data that comes
into that enrichment table so making
sure we're not just consistently writing
the same data over and over again we're
only doing updates when there's a change
in whatever enrichment data that we're
recording and some neat sequencing for
different point in time interactions as
well
the rest of the steps are kind of to
convert the data so in our streaming
alert and SQL Search tool to integrate
this kind of enrichment capabilities it
expects the data in a CSV format so we
have some functionality to take it from
this kind of source of truth dynamodb
table convert it into a CSV and feed it
into our streaming alert and SQL Search
tool so that we can take advantage of
this data as well
so now we're at the investigation phase
so we had a detection that fired we
enriched it with some context uh we
decided to generate an alert we're not
going to suppress it and then now we're
at the investigation phase so continuing
with our guard Duty example we still
have some questions for how we're going
to do this investigation so we got some
more context
but we still have a list of questions
that we need to answer and this is more
of hey if you have an investigation
that's going to happen most of the time
depending on the maturity of your
program what your environments look like
there could be a lot of uh maybe basic
things that can be a lot harder than you
think for instance do you have access to
this AWS account to come in and take a
look at this ec2 host fired an alert can
you even get access to the ec2 do you
have SSH keys do you have SSM do you
have some other way of interacting with
the Box do you even have an IM role that
you can use to take a snapshot of the
EBS instance if you want to do forensics
on the machine in AWS it's not as
straightforward there's a couple of
different steps along the way and when
you kind of want to take a snapshot of
it you want to also boot it in some sort
of isolated environment so if there's
malware running on a host you know we
just want to take in start running it in
vpcs inside of your network you probably
want to create some sort of isolated
environment maybe you have some
pre-installed tooling on a workstation
you can do forensics on uh you know
pcaps and all that
so a way that we kind of think about
this is if we fail to prepare for these
kinds of Investigations uh we're not
really going to be supporting our DNR
Engineers or responders when
investigations come in so at the
investigation phase again when a human
starts to look in alert this is
typically where you're going to have a
lot of bottlenecks because it requires
manual effort again you know you're
going to have some Automation in place
but eventually you're going to have
alerts that are going to come in that
physically require a human to come in
and take a look at so what you want the
responder to be able to do is to answer
the questions and finish the
investigation instead of getting bogged
down and things like how do I get to the
cc2 how do I get to this account so the
way that we do it is we try to have a
mentality of ruthlessly automating
everything that we possibly can if it
takes more than a couple minutes or if
it's something that's painful or hard we
build out some processes to save time
and more importantly minimize mistakes
so really make this kind of conscious
investment in setting our responders up
for success
one way that we do this is uh by
building a forensic workstation so what
we do is we Leverage The Amazon's ec2
image Builder service and we kind of
create this workstation that any analyst
or any person on the security team has
access to in a security forensics
account so we create this ec2 we boot it
we create an Ami we load up all the
software that's necessary to do these
kinds of forensic workflows then we
publish it we tag it make it available
to whatever work streams needed or if
someone just wants to boot it attach an
EBS volume and then go to work
this diagram turned out much better on a
big screen than I thought so pretty
stoked about that uh so the other thing
that we do is we actually decided to
automate forensic extraction so going
back to this guard Duty example where we
have an ec2 that fired you know we want
to do some sort of research on it answer
some questions
um there's a lot of steps in AWS if you
have an arbitrary account and this alert
Fires for an arbitrary region you need
to have a role that can take snapshots
of these EVS volumes you need to copy
them to the right region you need to
encrypt them you need to have the
appropriate KMS access keys so that your
security forensics account can decrypt
the EBS snapshot and then mount it onto
an ec2 again you want that forensics
environment so that you can comfortably
boot up the ec2 and there's just a lot
of things involved that can take
honestly a couple hours if you're going
through it for the first time and you're
not super familiar with the environment
so we wrote some tooling around this we
wrote some scripts to take a process
down from a couple of hours to a couple
of minutes where the bottleneck is not
access to your AWS resources knowledge
of AWS
or anything else the bottleneck is just
how long does it take AWS API calls to
execute you get a forensic workstation
booted up with these volumes attached
you can begin your investigation without
having to worry about anything else
uh if you've made it this far uh to the
response portion uh congrats uh through
the day through this talk and also
through your detection response function
so now actually is where the real work
begins right so you have to fix whatever
is wrong you have to assess uh whatever
issues have come up you have to deal
with the ramifications of it
um you have to do the fire drill of
getting the right stakeholders in place
following your run books etc etc but
there's one other really component a
really important component of the
response piece that I want to call out
which is remembering to evaluate your
detections
uh this is a detection life cycle uh
this image is not mine I took it from
the snowflake blog they have a really
great article about this which I really
really liked and so there's a component
in here which is called monitoring your
detections so we've already talked about
the continuous validation phase where we
have some sort of integrated testing to
monitor our detections make sure they're
working and this isn't monitoring in the
sense of hey I want to see how
performant my code is running what the
latency is this monitoring is from the
context of how effective is this
detection how noisy is it are there
additional signals that we could have
inserted into the original detection
that could have saved a responder time
later in the investigation so even after
the response phase kind of finishes
Brian alluded to it earlier at the start
of the talk in the overview but you
really want to make sure that you kind
of go back and maintain these detections
as you would maintain a software service
over time as it's running
so Brian and I spend a lot of time on
this uh and we're pretty proud of what
we built uh but we also had some
learning some things that went well some
things that didn't go well that we kind
of wanted to share uh some things that
have been really successful for us are
automating onboarding of new data
sources so just making things as fast as
possible so folks who aren't necessarily
as comfortable with terraform maybe as
comfortable with python just don't have
time to do it we don't want to be
blockers for them to onboard new data
into the pipeline for their own use
cases scale has been great again taking
a cloud native approach lets us scale
really well very cost effectively uh
notably with the Lambda and the sqs
following the detections is code
Paradigm and taking software engineering
and applying it to our DNR function has
resulted in pretty well tested and high
quality detections where we have very
high confidence by the timeline
detection ends up in production that
it's going to run something is
continuously checking looking after it
um and yeah overall just building a lot
of confidence and enrichment system is
something that's been great for us just
adding that content next helping us get
through investigations faster and able
to prioritize things that come into the
queue
some things that uh we definitely want
to improve on over time is empowering
folks again I outlined this as a
positive but it's also still a work of
improvement or area of improvement that
we can work on is uh onboarding new data
can still be sometimes depending on the
data source a high touch process so we
want to make this as self-service as
possible so there's some continuous
improvements we can do to make
onboarding data even easier I want to
continuously improve our CI CD story and
this is mostly for me uh but uh have hit
some parsing struggles I wrote a regex
which wasn't great some time back and so
just making sure that when we do those
things and we Wrangle a log sources that
are a little bit Messier we take the
time to kind of do it and flush it out
as much as we can before deploying it
anywhere
since we've built this system and have
the opportunity to kind of present this
there's been a couple of other
alternative approaches that have come
out or some other systems that have come
out we haven't used any of them they all
seem really cool this is not a vote of
confidence for any of them just
something that we would look at if we
were to rebuild the system from scratch
again AWS has an offering it's called
AWS security Lake its goal is to
centralize a bunch of data marketing is
really really good what they do is they
leverage ocsf one of these security
schemas that Brian called out at the
start of the talk opened cyber security
schema framework to help out with the
log normalization purpose uh per log
normalization aspect of it so you have
this nice kind of centralized data Lake
if you want to use that term where you
have a schema in place uh matano not
sure if I'm pronouncing that right this
is open source version of it and also a
detection engine on top of that so it's
really really neat if you look at the
GitHub they have architecture diagrams
which look similar to what we've built
so that was really nice validation for
us in terms of the approach that we kind
of pursued and they leveraged the
elastic schema elastic common schema for
their log normalization and they do
something really cool they leverage a
vector remap language to normalize logs
so kind of taking that compute portion
and the normalization it's a really neat
way to do it so highly recommend
checking that out if you're early on in
your journey lastly this is more on the
detection validation side but datadog
released a tool called threat test it
also integrates really nicely with their
like attack stimulation platform where
we can fire up uh detection that's
mapped to miter you can execute it and
then you can use this thread test
framework to make sure that alerts fired
on this specific workflow that you
kicked off seems really really neat
so to tie it all together we started off
with a need to go from a raw log to
making a security decision and it sounds
pretty simple and it is at lower scales
but as you get more data sources more
scale it can start to get a little bit
more complicated so we walked you
through kind of the six different
phrases you have the raw data
normalization detections alerts
investigations response there's a lot of
different work streams that you can take
along the way to kind of make this
process as high quality and as useful as
possible for the detection response side
and for the business as well so we
definitely didn't cover everything but
hopefully this can be a helpful
blueprint for building out a scalable
and cost effective threat detection
platform with a high bar for quality and
reliability
and with that I'd like to thank you all
for your time for coming here and would
like to open up the floor to any
questions
[Applause]
not a question yeah
uh the question was what detection
engine did we use
um
we we purposefully left that out because
we didn't want to endorse or turn this
into a vendor talk I would be happy to
answer that literally uh right right
after this
uh next question yeah
so
um right now we are kind of peaking in
the tens of thousands of events per
second which is not that big but we do
have every expectation that this could
grow to you know millions of events per
second if we needed to
question
the question was any plans to open
source any part of it
um
I have to ask the boss I think on that
one uh at this time not that I know of
so
um there's not any open source yet but
there is I did publish a blog post on
thebenchling.engineering site which is
our blog
um which does cover a very tiny piece of
what we used which is a jwks exporter
for KMS asymmetric keys so again just
just as kind of like a breadcrumb of
we're not entirely opposed to it but
we're just kind of Dipping our toe
yeah I have another question
uh don't see any other questions uh but
Brian and I will stick around right
after so thank you very much again for
coming to our talk I hope everyone has a
great weekend great conference thank you
thanks everyone