all right everyone let's make some noise
and then be quiet for our speaker leaf
I'm Leaf I'm currently taking some time
off in between jobs but most recently I
was uh
senior engineering manager at twilio
segment for the security features team
um currently the co-host of the hit
podcast uh 404 security not found which
has been described as friends at a
conference talking about security stuff
I'm not sure if that was a dig or a
compliment I took it as a compliment but
if that sounds like something you want
to use to catch up on some news we we do
one a month
and I'm also a startup advisor and
investor so if you you know have a early
stage startup I'd love to hear about
what you're working on
you might be asking what's next I'm
joining sem grep in about a month so if
you uh use sem grep and want to give me
some some feedback on the product happy
to take that if you don't use it go buy
some sem grep make my my options worth
something so
um
uh
the agenda for today I'm going to give a
little bit of context about what our
team's up to I think that's helpful just
so that you know the types of things
we're creating metrics about
I'm gonna try to sell you on why you
should be doing metrics at your company
although based on your attendance I'm
gonna hope that you're at least kind of
bought into that already
um gonna kind of walk through a project
that we did to really upgrade uh our our
own use of metrics and then wrap things
up and maybe have time for questions
although when I was running through the
presentation it was right about time so
you might have to harass me in person
afterwards
um so most of what our team builds is
stuff in the authentication realm so uh
the whole like login logout flow is all
stuff that we work on we also work on an
internal application called access
service which is something that you can
use to get time based peer-reviewed
access to things there's some commercial
tools out there that do this now if
you're familiar with OCTA IGA Crosswire
opal and I think it's worth keeping in
mind that segment is a business that
sells to other businesses which I think
makes security a lot easier if your
customers get mad when you do a bad job
at something the business tends to try
to do a good job at that thing and so I
think that investing in this stuff is is
a little bit easier when you work at a
B2B company
so uh yeah based on your attendance I'm
going to assume that you're at least
kind of bought into metrics but I think
that these are really important because
a lot of security teams really struggle
to quantify and demonstrate the value
that they bring to their org and I think
a lot of that boils down to
other parts of the business not knowing
enough about your team which you can fix
through internal sales to an extent and
then also security just not
understanding enough about the folks
that they're supposed to be working with
I think that everybody here has probably
heard about a security team that's not
giving practical recommendations or
stuff that Engineers just like know
won't work and you really want to
minimize that because anytime you do
that people are less likely to work with
work with you in the future
um so the right metrics Empower teams to
communicate cross-functionally it helps
educate other departments about how
things are going what things are
important what things aren't important
and even if you're not a customer facing
team the way that we are or like a
directly customer facing team I'd
encourage you to get creative about how
you can tie things to customer value I
think one thing that I thought was very
clever that our GRC team did is they
started making our sales team enter in
the contract value before they'd give
them a sock 2 report and this wasn't
meant to be like a hurdler or any
anything like there wasn't I don't know
that there's really a minimum bar but
it's just at the end of the quarter you
can say hey we helped out with x million
dollars worth of deals
um because they wanted this this sock 2
report that we had
um so I'm going to talk a little bit
about access service again this is an
internal app that that we built a couple
years ago and I think the metrics can
also help you justify spending time on
internal stuff or help you rationalize
to other teams why it isn't a good use
of time right now
um
without metrics you might make a
statement like this at the end of the
quarter or the end of the month or
whatever however long you spend on this
like hey this thing felt slow We sped it
up and now it's fast
um but if you have metrics on how slow
something actually is you can make this
a lot more impactful by you know doing a
little bit of research
saying okay hey uh the web standards
recommend a page load in one second
before people start feeling slowed down
it's an internal app so maybe like two
to three seconds is okay but like five
is is definitely too long
um and then you can do a calculation you
know I use calculation very Loosely but
really what I'm what you're doing is
trying to figure out like the effort to
value and so if you think hey it's going
to take us two weeks to speed this thing
up
um and we can get a 50 reduction in in
loading times like maybe that's good
maybe maybe it's not but you at least
have something that you can go back to
other teams internally and say hey this
is how long it's going to take us to do
this thing this is a good use or a bad
use of our time right now
um so creating a a solid metrics program
is pretty time consuming this was a
pretty solid investment in our team our
by our team this this past year it was
something that two Engineers spent
um like close to a quarter working on uh
obviously Engineers work on plenty of
other things it's not just three months
of straight work on something but
um this is a pretty big investment and
like any meaningful size project you
should be asking is this the right thing
to do right now
um your company or your team probably
has no shortage of of good ideas and
it's really about figuring out if it
makes sense but this was something we we
said we wanted to do at the beginning of
the year so we had already kind of like
put a
um you know some time allocated for it
but we ran into a few issues that I
think we probably could have avoided if
we had had done this work a little bit
earlier we had an internal app that
crashed during a big migration and there
wasn't really any warning we just looked
at the logs afterwards and we're like oh
hit 100 utilize 100 utilization and
crashed maybe a warning at like 80 that
something bad was going to happen would
have been would have been helpful
um so I break things down into two
different groups of metrics Health
metrics and product metrics
um Health metrics are things that help
you answer is what we maintain
dependable and will we know when
something goes wrong
um I think security engineering teams
should really try to be as similar to
their end counterparts as possible and
so you should just don't reinvent this
wheel like just go to your Edge team and
figure out what they're doing they're
probably better at running reliable
Services than you anyway just steal
their homework
um
and so some things that I think like
broadly fit into this category and like
there's probably others too is error
handling uh this is pretty pretty
self-explanatory I think but just to
give you some context on like what we
actually fixed we had some things that
would send errors to Sentry but then
those were inconsistently sent to slack
we had some services that would just
send stuff to slack without going
through Sentry and then you lose out on
all the benefits of Sentry we also had
stuff going to a bunch of different
channels which is annoying because then
people have like more things to look at
it's nice just say hey it you know if
it's important it just goes to this one
channel
um
Sentry also has scheduled task
monitoring so we have a lot of jobs that
just run like once or twice a day and
you're just going to assume that those
are going to keep working until they
don't and so Sentry's great because they
have the ability to tell you like hey
this thing didn't run because a lot of
times if this stuff doesn't run and it
doesn't even start to run you won't get
any errors so you won't know that it
didn't run we used to use datadog for
this but we actually found Sentry to be
more reliable for monitoring when our
stuff was unreliable
um SLI is this this is like a really
broad category but you can think of like
latency to an external service is
something that might fall into slis
um application performance monitoring
this is something that allowed us to
figure out like what
um
what was actually happening in uh in
Access service like why it was so slow
I also these slides are on sketch so
feel free to keep taking pictures but
they're also up there if you want to
just use the stuff that's up there
um
service best practices these aren't
really metrics at all this is just kind
of like in the same broad theme this is
having readme's that are easy to get
someone up and running it's links to
dashboards it's claiming the service in
backstage which is what we use to track
like who owns what I think of this as
just the things that you do to be a good
citizen in your uh in your organization
so some examples of what we might track
for something like off-board Service uh
off-board service is a pretty simple
service it runs once a day it boots
everyone out of the segment application
once they've been deactivated in Octa
and it prevents ex-employees from
accessing their accounts so
for the health metrics
does Sentry think this thing ran were
there any errors if so what were they
how long did it take to run how many
calls did it make to the OCTA API and is
this service something that you know if
somebody needed to make some changes
they're not going to get bogged down and
like fixing a bunch of unrelated
nonsense and just like have a really
hard time getting the service up and
running
switching over to product metrics I
think this is the fun part you get to
put on your product manager hat and
think about why the stuff that you're
building is valuable I think there's
also a lot more art on the the product
metric side than the health metric side
those are much more science is your
thing working or not
um but I think everything that your team
builds should have at least one product
metric if you can't come up with one
reason why the thing that you're
building is important it's probably not
a good thing to build and if you've
already built it you should maybe retire
it
um I learned a lot about this from a
former product manager Rachel who I gave
a presentation with last year
um this I would say this presentation is
like complementary it's it's not a
rehash of last time but if you want to
check this one out uh this one's on
YouTube on the uh the b-sides page
yeah it's actually the same brand and I
have matching shorts for both of these
but I didn't know if people wanted that
so I I wore pants
all right I'm I'm keeping that uh next
time I'll wear the matching tops and
bottoms
um so product product metrics
um without any metrics you could
probably say something like this at the
end of the you know however long it
takes you to build this we built
off-board service it remove X employees
simple
um but if you throw even like a little
bit of data in it it sounds a lot better
um and so you can say hey not only does
this help retain customer trust it helps
maintain our compliance with our
internal policies it helps with our sock
too and in the first 30 days it
off-boarded 60x employees 48 of which
were missed by previous manual reviews
so you can draw some comparisons to the
before State once you have this kind of
information
um for product metrics there's plenty of
other things that could be a product
metric these are just some things that I
think are worth at least considering
um if you can tie something to customer
Revenue uh that's always a good one
um if that's a little bit more difficult
just having some data on like how many
customers are using this either just raw
numbers or percentage for internal tools
it's good to try to capture
um how many people are actually using
something in a given week or how many
times a tool completes something that
could be a bad thing avoided or a good
thing encouraged you can also always try
to tie things to team goals or or goals
or company goals those are good because
I would say generally those are things
that other people should at least be
kind of familiar with and so if you can
say hey we did this thing that supports
this other thing that the company said
is important
that is kind of your job so that's a
good thing to to try to do for your
metrics as well
um some product metrics from SSO let's
just say you work at a company that has
100 Mil in ARR you might be able to
track that 30 of your customers have SSO
enabled
um and you might find it somewhat
surprising that so much more revenue is
tied to something rather than the
percentage of users but for something
like SSO that actually makes a lot of
sense because your bigger customers are
the ones that are more likely to pay the
SSO tax and so they are naturally going
to shift this and then it gets even more
uh
the comparison grows when you talk about
something like scam because typically
you have to have SSO enabled anyway
um
if you haven't heard of scim and you
work at a B2B Company please convince
somebody to build it it makes corpse and
it's jobs a lot easier it basically
allows you to do provisioning and
deprovisioning and group mapping and a
bunch of stuff
so uh getting started uh hopefully you
have a list of what your team owns if
not that's okay but that's definitely
Step Zero is figure out what you want to
start tracking things about and then
figure out what the current state of
these are like maybe you have some
metrics maybe you don't that's fine too
and then you should have some idea of
where you're trying to go you're
obviously going to figure stuff out
along the way which is great but just
have have some path that you can plot
from A to B
this is an oversimplified version of
something that we made pretty early it's
just a list of what we own and then like
what the state things are in
um more tiles and datadog or you know
whatever you're using isn't always
better I would say that it can be
overwhelming when you have a bunch of
useless data and so more or less is more
here I think that you want to have the
right stuff tracked rather than just
like a bunch of stuff
so for our implementation
we have all of our services send stuff
to Center your datadog and then we send
stuff to Slack
we also have an internal logging system
that you know is used just kind of like
for debugging stuff so that's kind of
unrelated to this but also part of the
same project on the metric side we're
very fortunate to work at a company that
has very smart uh data engineers and
analytics folks that have set up a bunch
of this foundation for us and so we
didn't have to figure out how to tie
something to a customer account in
Salesforce and get the ARR like there
was already patterns in place where we
could say hey this workspace
is related to this amount of money
um but I think that getting good with
business intelligence software is pretty
valuable for for engineers whether
that's a security engineer or software
engineer or whatever because it allows
you to answer a lot of interesting
questions about your business
you can also use bi tools to augment
internal product functionality so we do
this for for Access service which
um as I mentioned earlier it's something
where you can say hey I need access to
this thing for a certain amount of time
like a day or a week somebody else
approves you and then you get access and
then it expires
but we often get asked questions that we
don't want to build something in the
product to answer this question we can
just refer to somebody to a dashboard so
somebody might ask like what are all the
tiles that this person is an approver
for they're going on Parental leave and
we want to make sure that we have
coverage for them and you know if we're
a commercial product we would have to
write some database queries add some new
routes put some stuff in the UI write
tests but you can just skip all that and
just write some queries and create a
dashboard in Snowflake and you know it's
fine if you make an internal person go
somewhere else
um so some product metrics that you
might or that we thought about for
Access service just to give some more
examples of what an internal app like
this might care about
tiles with less than three approvers so
if this is an OCTA app or a group that
only has one approver and that person
leaves that can be annoying to people
that need access to that thing
um more generally if you have an
internal tool trying to figure out how
many people are using this um if
someone's like hey why are we spending
so much time on this and you can say hey
a third of our company uses this every
week that's a lot easier to justify
spending time on that
um something like median approval time
allows us to do a contrast between the
before and after it used to take hours
or maybe a day to get access to
something with access service it's maybe
like three or four minutes in most cases
and then the most active users are a
great pool of people to get feedback
from so if you want to build something
new or you want to change something like
hit those people up because they're the
people that probably care the most about
what your app does
um so let's assume you you love these
ideas you want to do this at your own
company you should take stock of like
where your metrics are at before maybe
these are all zeros which is totally
fine that's gonna make you look really
good at the end of the project
um but you should have some metrics
about your metrics so you can say Hey
you know just like any other project
this was a lot of work we spent a lot of
time on it
um you know this is kind of the the
before and after and this does get like
a little bit meta of like hey we you
know we put metrics on your metrics but
this is just a you can just think of
this as a project
and your projects probably want to have
metrics this one just happens to also be
about metrics
um
pause for photos
so once you once you do this you should
share your work there's probably a lot
of other teams that want something like
this at your company and some of the
things that we did to make this easier
every single snow site dashboard Sal can
attest to this he built a lot of them
has comments and so anybody else from
security or wherever they can go in and
they can see oh this is why they did
that crazy join that I don't understand
let me just copy that because I want the
same thing
um you should have links to all this
stuff in your readme's make it easy for
people to find this stuff and then
present it internally nobody's going to
know that you did this stuff if you
don't tell them that you did it and this
is a good way to you know to practice a
lot of things but it's also a good way
just to make people aware of what's
available to them and say like hey go go
steal our queries they're also a great
thing to put in promo packets I think
that a lot of managers get caught off
guard when people start asking them
questions about impact and stuff like
that and it's a lot easier if you can
just say like hey we made this thing 25
better 25 faster whatever if you have
the data at least that's been my
experience during promo and like
calibration time is I feel like the the
managers that have metrics usually do
better
um this is also something that you
should start thinking about during
project planning so we actually have a
section in our template that's like what
are you going to track about this thing
and you don't even necessarily have to
have a goal like you don't have to say
like Hey we're going to make this thing
10 better whatever I think it's good if
you do but just having the raw data so
that at some point in the future when
you want to make improvements you don't
have to spend a month collecting data
you just have the data about like the
usage and things like that
you need to include time for this in
your project plan if you don't
somebody's just going to say hey the
thing's built move on to the next thing
unfortunately this stuff has to happen
at the end because otherwise there's no
data to build the dashboards and so
it can be put into an awkward spot but I
think if you put this as part of your
project plan it makes it easier to
defend the time that it takes to do this
um one last example this was something
that um we had an intern two summers ago
uh she did a fantastic job on this this
project the goal was to get more people
using MFA
um more more customers specifically
using MFA and the way that we targeted
them is we went after the workspace
owners and got the workspace owners to
force MFA for their workspace because
then that just gets everybody
um and without any metrics this still
would have been pretty good especially
for an intern like hey successfully
completed this project got a lot of
people to enroll but because we had
metrics of how many people were using
MFA before
we could do something like this where
it's like hey we actually saw a 25
increase these are the total number of
impacted users for all those workspaces
we had originally guessed we'd maybe see
like a 10 increase so I don't know if
we're just bad at guessing or just
sandbagging but
um yeah this looked really good during
her final uh presentation
some closing thoughts uh metrics make
your team stand out during quarterly
progress reports and help you
supercharge performance reviews and they
also make it easy to communicate
cross-functionally
um and it allows your organization to
see how things are getting hopefully
better maybe worse over time but just
having the data makes that a lot easier
so if you want to try this for yourself
I highly recommend using whatever your
company already has set up and paying
and is paying for
um this stuff does mention like segment
and Snowflake and whatever but all those
are things that could be swapped out for
like Tableau or like whatever else
you're using
um this will be recorded as part of
b-sides uh the I wrote a Blog about this
in December so if you want to go back
and not listen to me again and just read
through it uh pretty much everything in
the in here is in there and if you don't
have this stuff set up and you want to
play around with stuff on your own
twilio and or segment and snowflake both
have free tutorials you can you can mess
around with stuff but yeah definitely
use what your company is paying for
and then lastly we got some other talks
to walk watch my girlfriend's on a panel
um with some other great people uh that
are some of them are in the front row I
don't see Louis but uh wow
uh
there's some okay people on the panel
and then uh tomorrow uh we have some
some current and and past twilio folks
so we've got Kelly Robinson we've got
Sal who I mentioned earlier he's talking
about some uh cool API security stuff
we're doing and then Colleen
right there our former CSO is on a panel
as well so check these out the slides
are are already up as I mentioned and
then the blogs there uh
questions or do I get kicked off
one minute
all right let's do it
yeah
the audience is counting on you yeah we
have one question we have one minute to
stop so if you guys something has a hot
take for leaf raise your hands and sing
it out loud
are you talking about that tomorrow or
later today or no
so my team doesn't really do incident
response stuff unless it's helping out
with something that that we own I
imagine that there's probably a
a place for metrics on any security team
but I'm not a good person to ask about
that yeah go to the panel they claim
they'll talk about it
hey
uh
right way too much
so Snow's site is the bi tool that
either snowflake comes with or or we pay
extra for
um and it can help you create like
graphs and charts and like it it's
basically like
all the stuff that maybe you used in
PowerPoint at some point growing up uh
based off of the Excel data so once you
have the data in there it's it's pretty
easy and if your company has you know
data engineering or Analytics
just make them help you until you get
good
all right folks that's been great Leaf
will be out in the hall