this is to talk about rolling out
webuthen newbie keys to everybody at
Discord for corporate authentication
um but first a little bit about me
hi I'm Alex I work on platform security
at Discord a lot of infrastructure a lot
of I.T stuff before that Healthcare
technology uh platform is a service
company called Alto with an app Sarah
did electrical engineering back end full
stack and that brought me to security
over the last decade or so and
I want to talk a little about Discord
security
we have a pretty uh awesome security
team nowadays our real intention is to
make a secure way the easy way we want
to come meet our users where they work
means we want developers people who are
Engineers to come talk to us about the
tools that they're using we know how to
work on those tools we make PRS the same
way they do
we always want the right solution we
don't just want the easy one and that's
kind of hard in security right like it's
really easy for us to come up with rules
it's hard for us to come up with things
that actually make people's lives better
and move the security needle forward
was it mean to actually enable
developers enabling our users supporting
BYOD I think if you're a security
professional you probably have had
challenges around BYOD within your org
if you haven't had that you're either
very fortunate or you just don't know
about it yet with 400 plus people like
we have an engine product we absolutely
have that as a challenge we have
desktops we have MacBooks and many more
in many many countries
makes it challenging to do something
like say ship UB keys to all of them
so if you want something that's better
security and better user experience what
do we want security feature we want more
MFA props we want more multi-factor
authentication prompts
things like if you're accessing a
production uh piece of infrastructure
you know accessing a Production Service
uh you're accessing a sensitive
application like your hris system or
doing the role escalations I want to
have some sort of check be like hey are
you actually who you say you are a
presence check in there and you know if
we just start saying more MFA props all
the time the misery index creeps up so
how do we do that while sustaining the
misery index where it's at or ideally
Bringing Down the misery index
so emergency to web authen but first
we're going to talk about MFA and kind
of the state of MFA and why web authent
is what we chose
so why MFA at all starting from the
beginning password reuse is incredibly
incredibly uncommon um you've probably
seen people successfully or successfully
do credential stuffing attacks you know
having breaches from things like have it
been pounds and try to use that on
multiple websites some and within your
org
beyond that phishing attacks are
incredibly prevalent uh we all have
people who have been fished we've all
been fished anyone in this room can be
fished whether you think you can or
cannot you absolutely can be and the
goal of MFA is to raise the cost to
attackers it's not going to make it
impossible but it's making it harder for
somebody to take your credentials and
log into a different website
nobody really uses MFA the stock is
really focused on corporate users and
this is for users of Twitter Circa I
think July 2021 is when this report last
was pulled but for all types of MFA
across Twitter 2.6 of accounts had any
type of MFA at all the changeover from a
July to December of that period was plus
6.3 percent so really not growing a
whole lot and I think this is pretty
similar but we see at other places
really single digit percentages of MFA
obviously you have more levers you can
push with corporate MFA but it's
something that users are telling us that
they don't really like using because
it's very high friction
so there's a whole Spectrum right you
have a lot of options of MFA you have
um no MFA right we have one factor we
just have passwords we have SMS and
email we have totp probably the one that
a lot of us are pushing out in orgs and
tftp or push notifications something
that we probably have in a lot of places
we have web authen which I promised we
would come back to and then perfect
security is you live on a Mountaintop
you uh three computer out the window and
you never log on the internet again but
you can't get away with that while
running a business so we go to the next
best option
so what do we do
web authentic the primer on a better MFA
so what is this what about that is a web
authentication API so the auth n stands
for it's an open standard leveraging
public key cartography so you in general
have a public key that you advertise out
and a private key you keep on your
device talk through the registration
flow in a minute why is this thing so
good like why are people talking about
this why am I talking about this why did
I spend too long working on this uh it's
because it's really strong right
leveraging public key cartography is
something that we've used for a lot of
problems in the past let's bring it to
this domain it's scoped you have it
scoped to a certain website you know you
do it for for instance discordapp.com
you don't have to do it to Discord weird
a that looks like an idpu.com let's go
up to a certain domain and to test it
you're tested from the Hardware security
module on your device so these are kind
of put on the principles let's talk
through what this registration flow
looks like
so you have a device in this case it's a
cell phone but there's a wide plethora
of devices all of them valid you
register by saying I want to create a
new account with the site the site says
sure generate me a public key you donate
the private key as well so the key pair
is generated we send the public key off
to The Ether and the private key is only
ever kept on the device and you've
registered a website and just as a shout
out webauthen.guide is a great website
it's where all these graphs are pulled
from
so you have registration now you have
the handshake when you're actually
trying to authenticate you have a device
come and say hey I want to sign in so
the device says please or sorry the
service says please sign this data
because payload so I know that it's
really you so I can do that at a station
we're talking about
so on the device you come back you say
cool here's a Blog I want to sign up my
private key and then you pass that back
up saying here's a signature it shows
like no one can be tempered in transit
and the website says let's take that
public key let's verify the signature
and great it checks out you can sign in
so how do we use web authent I talked a
little about logistics it's going to be
the second half of this talk but
um the spoilers you probably already
have things that could act as a web
weapon authenticator you may already be
using it under the hood even if you
don't know that it's kind of two big
categories there's external and roaming
authenticators Yuba Keys Titan security
Keys other things like that and then
there are internal or platform
authenticators you know MacBook Touch ID
face ID on iPhones Android fingerprint
unlock Windows hello things that are
inherent to the platform whereas the
roaming key is something that you plug
in walk around with it can roam with you
you don't need to be tied to your laptop
for that one to work
so it's a little bit of a breakdown of
ATL account takeover prevention rates by
type this is from Google security blog
which is excellent comparing on device
prompts so push notification SMS code
security key and then a few other types
of MFA and you can see that the efficacy
of security Keys is really really good
which is awesome this is even for
targeted attacks which are the yellow
bars I'm colorblind I hope they're
yellow the bottom and you can see that
they have 100 for all the cases that
they've been auditing which is really
great so by the way Google research has
made it really easy to make this case
internally I'll quote that more later
but just shout out thank you for making
it easy to make this sell
so more Google research here we've had
no reported or confirmed account
takeover since inline security keys at
Google and that is Google I imagine
people are trying to hack Google people
who work there and they said they
haven't seen anybody get compromised in
this way it's really cool to be able to
take one of these threats off the table
because we have enough keeping all of us
up at night
so then what about that at Discord I
work at Discord this is how I make the
case for better corporate MFA for
Discord and hopefully can help all you
make the case if you're not already
using web but then internally
so security is not an island we've hired
a lot of talks about this this weekend
people need to come to terms with us and
US agree to them like how important a
thing is and how much is it worth
disrupting workflows ideally like I said
we can move the security bar up without
blowing up people's workloads without
increasing that misery index ideally
stakeholders go up at misery index
either stays flat or goes down
so we had a lot of stakeholders to work
with I.T Engineers CX people who were
both ftes within the company as well as
people who work outside of the company
all of whom work together to make
Discord great so the mission here was
that we had to show that this was safer
than the status quo it's in better MFA
more effective I want to show that it
was easier too this wouldn't just be
incurring that misery index on there we
also want to show that it was cost
effective you know you're talking about
buying new Hardware in a lot of these
cases so it's going to cost some money
it's going to cause some disruption how
do you show that's worthwhile to do this
so safer again shout out to Google he
made my job here really easy we've had
no confirmed uh no reported or confirmed
account takeover since employing
security keys at Google
that's big right so really easy to make
that case saying this is the de facto
standard people have been moving toward
and it's not just Google there's also
great research coinbase security blog
also has some great uh talking about
rolling out this internally as well
easier to use so you can all see here
it's kind of a jumbled mess of all the
different Topp authenticators and I'm
not knocking to be on authentication
whatsoever I use it all the time
but you know you're getting your phone
out of your pocket you're logging in I
use authy and I have to use my
fingerprint ID twice to log into that
people feel the urgency as well of the
time-based nature of this too and
something that just adds friction every
time you add this prompt if I want to
say do this every time you're pushing a
commit or every time you're logging into
a server it's going to make people get
their phone in and out of their pocket
unless you have a cell phone holster and
if you do it's still going to increase
the misery index quite a bit
so I think it's easier to use web out
then and we're hearing that from our you
know users at the end of the day as well
the most common experience at discordant
is 80 of people are working on MacBook
Pros and they register the Touch ID on
the device and you just tap it when you
get the prompt for other devices we have
Windows hello you also have ubiques of a
wide variety I'll talk more about what
we lean toward later on but you don't
have to fish uh phones in your pocket
and if you're fishing resistant with web
authen MFA as well the friction is
really low and which means you can say
we can start playing with MFA prompts
and adding them all over the place
without increasing that misery index
is it cost effective that's the next big
one right uh two factors per user is
about you know 30 to 75 per person
depending upon the kind of prompt that
you're doing the kind of uh you know
keys that you're rolling out you also
have to worry about an increased burden
on it distribute and service like we
have to talk about shipping this to
every new hire everybody who comes in
Discord works from everywhere so we have
an office most people never come into it
so how do we enable that how do we
enable people in countries all around
the world without you know ruining it's
life because they are great it really
helped me roll this project and they
would not be as happy about it if I you
know took up all their time servicing
lockout requests for instance if you're
comparing this not to an action right
you're comparing this to the cost of an
action the cost of an action on average
from 2022 report from IBM a successful
phishing attack at a company is about
five million dollars 4.9 million dollars
I think we can all think through like
whoever gets fish depending upon who
that person is and what kind of standing
access they have it can probably go a
lot higher than that too
so again shout out to research from
Google this is talking about the support
incident so the burden to I.T you can
see here that the support incidence of
lockouts precipitously dropped as people
adopt Hardware security Keys which is
awesome to see so you can see over time
the support rate from OTP drops and for
Hardware security Keys it's flies they
rolled it out throughout the org
for the deployment we found the
increased user productivity and the
decreased support costs were worth the
increased Hardware cost so that's big it
really helped make the case this way not
only are you decreasing the burden in
I.T but you're also saying the decree
increases your productivity from being
locked out less often less support
requests means that people are getting
far fewer lockouts than they were before
so it's not just that cost in I.T it's
the cost amortized across your whole
organization it's big cost savings
everyone gets Yuba Keys some people get
you two UB keys somebody gets a Mac like
a touch ID keyboard something like that
we have a wide spectrum of devices that
we support here but it's cost effective
and we can make exceptions like that
because really savings are worth at the
end of the day
so we sell people but what's the plan we
sold them on
step one get everyone asterisks and to
OCTA and get every asterisk app into
octave anybody here who's been early on
Security Programs knows that time is a
flat circle you see a lot of the same
themes you get people behind MFA or
behind SSO rather it's the first thing
that you do for us we did that with OCTA
something we started the ball rolling on
prior to starting this project
step two get two plus authenticators to
everybody a platform in a roaming is
what we decided upon but it could really
be any of those some groups we wanted to
go with uh three for redundancy so execs
or people who are super admins in Octa G
Suite super admins people have high
privileged accounts that are hard to
service if they get locked out or have a
lot of risk we got multiple
authenticators for those because again
you're talking a cost of like thirty
dollars for an authenticator fifty
dollars for an authenticator much lower
than the uh the risk of compromise or
the risk of lockout in these cases
step three uh we've heard this a few
times this weekend in other talks but
it's important to start testing on us so
when we laid out the strategy if we
wanted to start rolling this out too
gradually the first step is security if
this is a bad experience we want to feel
that pain first and when we come to
other users we want to say hey we've
been dealing with this for a month and
it's actually better than it was before
it builds trust with your users if
you're going through this sort of stuff
and not just imposing it upon them and
saying we'll get to it later so we did
security infrastructure it execs
engineering all ftes and then everybody
again Discord has people all over the
world in all different capacities
working for us that all help make
Discord great we want to make sure we
encompassed all of them reduce the risk
across the board
from there we had an exception group in
octave so this is kind of octa-specific
whatever your SSO provider is probably
has similar functionality but for us we
had an authentication policy that said
everybody needs to get password and web
authent prompt to log in or webathon
prompts on these certain cases except
for people in this exception group so
it's allow us to say okay we can opt in
the whole category but if this one
person infrastructure is on paternity
leave or whatever else we can opt them
out so which is awesome to have you can
say like these long tail cases you know
someone's ubiki got lost in the mail it
was stolen whatever that's fine add them
to the exception group but follow up on
them judiciously and then over time you
see you shrink the number of people in
the exception group but you keep it
around in case there are lockouts or
loss authenticators there's always cases
like this where somebody gets stuck in
some sort of exception case so it gives
you that flexibility we had a lot of
moving pieces here but we had enough uh
you know kind of back doors if we needed
to to get people into a working
condition while we roll This Out
so we had some tools to work with here
right I talked earlier about platform
versus roaming authenticators the first
most common thing was that people had
MacBooks already they had Touch ID on
there so this is something people
already knew how to use people are often
using this to log into their devices
it's a really familiar interface which
is nice
but past that you can also have Windows
hello other devices like that you can
also have web compatible keyboards you
know some people keep their laptops in
docked mode we're pretty lacks about
like you can use any Factor as long as a
web authen factor and we will probably
support you we want to meet your users
where they are because we're asking for
a change of behavior so it's important
to come to them
has that we want a roaming authenticator
so it's important to have two plus
factors to decrease that lockout we
talked about earlier so we chose to use
the UB key security key C NFC uh it's
kind of a mouthful it's this blue key
about 30 bucks a pop and one of the
really cool things about it is you can
bootstrap a new phone using NFC so if
you have a phone you want to use it as
an OCTA authenticator itself with Web
Bot then you can tap on the back with
NFC and use it that way one of the other
things sort of like a ux philosophy here
you don't want both your factors to
often travel together you know you can
have the low profile 5c Nanos that live
inside the laptops but if the Key C and
A C is Big it's probably not going to
travel with laptops because it sticks
out like this and so we want them to
live in separate locations that was my
theory of the case
so it is 2fa for us it's 2fa you can use
these for uh your single factor for pass
keys I'm not going to touch on that too
much today but very exciting highly
recommend reading more so we have a plan
sounds pretty easy right
let's talk about what actually happens
so we have a plan timeline all good
projects should have a plan timeline and
they should all be as optimistic as I
was
so we started this off in May 2022. um
June we had it all rolled out to or we
wanted to have it all rolled out
security it infront execs so on and so
forth basically one month after another
we're like cool four weeks is long
enough to get some address and ship out
Keys no problem it's like basically
Amazon right what could go wrong
uh it went pretty well um but everybody
was a long tail after that you can see
it pushing off the page there so we went
into this year
people who were ftes we were able to get
to them pretty quickly but that long
tail case is a very very long tail
because you're talking International
Logistics at this point and if you take
away one thing this talk is that when
you go through this figure out your
International Logistics Way in advance
so if I come into a distributed Global
team is really really hard and I don't
work for importers but just pay for
importers for these countries that are
really difficult for something I wish
that we did uh coming back to we got
stuck in a few cases and having somebody
who knew how to do customs in a country
like Columbia or the Philippines would
have saved us weeks if not months
another key learning as I mentioned this
earlier is test on yourself so I think
why we were able to roll so quickly
through everybody within the companies
that we knew what would work like for
the most complicated cases people who
were accessing infrastructure so by
testing on ourselves we heard our
concerns we were able to understand what
this flow would be like and we knew what
the most complicated cases would
interact like
shipping shipping Logistics really the
biggest part of this we used uh the
ubico Enterprise delivery portal it
works really well all we did was take
from our his system export basically a
dump of everybody's addresses ship them
a key or two and then send it out and
you can do a bulk CSV upload using
ubercon Enterprise delivery super simple
highly recommended
for nonefts it's harder remote work and
agencies make this hard again I'm going
to keep repeating this work with local
importers if you're working with like a
business partner outsourcer firm or BPO
work with them figure out the best way
to distribute it to them and figure
these out far far in advance
Imports the biggest delays for us were
in Philippines and Colombia and that's
really coming down to like I've never
done anything like this before we hired
somebody with procurement experience
like halfway through this project which
is a godsend but by that point we
already had things out the door that
were just waiting in customs so again
highly recommend getting importers would
have saved us less than 10 grand and
probably four or five months in some
cases by just getting importers
somebody in leadership so shout out to
Discord leadership and you should all be
happy enough to work at a place that has
leadership willing to theoretically
bring a duffel bag full of UB keys to
the Philippines didn't come down to that
but we had people who were willing to
hop on a plane with say 600 700 UV keys
so this is pretty awesome we're hiring
so okay uh we touched Logistics I've
touched enough on importers um
uh for enforcement we have OCTA as our
wedge right so OCTA is um we're going to
have a long tail of apps and users
people who need to be moved into OCTA
apps when you want to put behind OCTA
it's okay to have a long tail you know
some apps just never support SSO
unfortunately so you want to focus on
the things that are the most impactful
that people will be using on a regular
basis you want to get through the
rollout and then work on exemptions
you're always gonna have somebody who's
fish ether you be key there's always
weird cases that you will never
anticipate because International
Logistics because of male theft or
people move especially during remote
work it's hard just have exemption group
and follow up on it make sure you're
working with your users and saying like
Okay it's like 48 Hours 72 hours
whatever reasonable like how quickly can
we get this key to you in a way that's
not going to make your life really hard
so I want to finish the call to action
this is worth doing this is a painful
Learning lesson for me on the pains and
joys of international Logistics but
hopefully my tips can help make this
easier for all of you doing this
phishing attacks successful ones at that
are incredibly incredibly pervasive and
again I want to reinforce that anyone in
here myself everybody in here all
Security Professionals anybody seeing
this in the future can get fished what
about then is phishing resistance it's
not fish proof but it's something that
is really really hard to fish you have
the interactions the MFA prompt which is
something that is really really strong
okay what about that in you what can you
do to prepare for this first advice is
to know where everyone when the works in
the world far in advance which sounds
really obvious right and it is but I'll
say that like remote work makes that
really complicated and people move uh we
had missed deliveries because of that
so get a good wedge next to prioritize
for SSO for us that was OCTA and then
zendesk so a lot of our BPO again
business partner outsourcer agencies are
working in zendesk day in and day out so
that's something we could get an app
that like half of our entire user
population used on a daily basis and
identifying that is the right thing to
put behind SSO first made it so that we
could move groups in and know that they
would have it in force on a regular
Cadence
next up identify countries not supported
by your shipping partner early you
become Enterprise delivery was really
helpful shout out they did a great job
with the portal but they don't have full
coverage because International Logistics
are hard so there are some countries
where they really can't help you so
figure that out far in advance and then
figure out what your alternative means
are and I'm happy to help with this like
I wish that uh we had something like
this to say like hey the Philippines
you're going to want to work on that in
June
okay and the rest of the call to action
what about that in you please support it
Apache browser and device support is one
of the biggest hurdles we have to
adoption we have an open standard here
and you can sort of see up on the screen
some of the patchwork support it's a
little fuzzy up there this comes from
webathon.me a lot of great compatibility
about like can I actually use this with
my browser with my device we have an
open standard here and really to
everybody out there working at different
companies to help improve this support
it extend it so we can make this the
standard so it's not sort of an
exceptional thing that we all are doing
this as a baseline because the more
support that we have the more
multiplicative this effort becomes and
becomes more worthwhile doing
so with that I want to leave some time
for Q a what questions people have
yeah we're here
actual personal devices and save mobile
access to
yeah so questions about BYOD which I
mentioned kind of in passing how do you
handle access to uh services from
personal devices with doing a rollout of
Web Bot then so
um I think one thing that we were
flexible on early on that I haven't
heard everybody be flexible on is that
you can use your personal cell phone as
an authenticator if you want to set up
your iPhone or your Android phone not a
work phone as an authenticator we're
okay with that so you can access OCTA
apps on your phone otherwise we would
disrupt some people's workflows we use
people that you know they play a game
and they would review PR's on their
phone in between rounds of that game we
wanted to keep enabling that because
they want to do that and we don't want
to just shut that off so we're flexible
on that we're also flexible on the type
of Yuba Cube so we really wanted to
focus on the security key cnfc as the
standard but then if someone asks a
question like hey you know I have um we
have a game Studio at Discord actually
and they all use desktops and so they're
like it's not going to work for us using
this USBC thing I was like cool I've
been getting some USB a devices so
that's supporting their use case one
that I didn't even realize that we had
you want to set a standard so you can
kind of converge around what docs and
support there are and know what the
standard onboarding package is that'd be
really flexible after that someone's
like hey got a problem here you figure
out cool what's the thing I can get you
that'll make you successful
does that answer the question cool
over there
yeah so the question is about usability
feedback from non-engineering users
um
honestly most of it was not getting much
feedback at all which sometimes is the
best feedback to get I did talk to
people and kind of do sampling polls of
people working in different roles across
the company in general people do not
miss to tpmfa for OCTA we didn't allow
octopush verify or octave verify push at
the time we started doing this so it was
comparing that to tftp
um yeah people who are working in the
mode case really like touch ID something
people are already used to using and
then being flexible on the interactions
with uh you know different other ebqs
people really enjoyed that too
Yeah question right there
so the question is about comparing the
efficacy at scale of security key cnfc
to the USB 5c Nano is that the one
you're talking about
5cnfc um I don't use the 5cmsc directly
comparing it directly to the 5c Nano
which is the one that we were looking at
primarily because the NFC thing was like
it was sort of a nice to have we didn't
need to have that for bootstrapping
authenticators but I was about choosing
for byd purposes to allow people to use
personal devices
there's a few things that you need to
consider when you're looking at what key
to support and that's a lot of like what
are the authentication protocols
supported by this key security key NFC
is actually pretty restrictive and that
supports like u2f mode and that's all we
wanted so actually some things that you
may want to turn off if you have the
five scene Nano like um I think we've
all seen at orgs when you touch the UB
key and you get like an OTP code spanned
in the chat it's fun you would sneeze
but you don't necessarily want that and
so the key to NFC having the limitation
of not having OTP mode it's actually
kind of a user benefit because you don't
have to worry about turning that off and
you can do customization with ubico but
it requires paying extra and shutting
down the assembly line so it's kind of a
headache to deal with
yeah a question right next to the last
question
yeah um the question is about uh
different compatibility and support
issues with embedded browsers one of the
big ones and I think the still problem
is with hris workday logging in
specifically on mobile that's one of the
big ones that we saw and uh the way you
work around it is by allowing people in
temporary exception groups for setting
up those apps because the sessions are
pretty long-lived it's not the best
experience but again because the
supports kind of Patchwork on different
browsers especially like um you know
mobile browsers that are embedded like
it's a great call out for now that's the
best thing we can come up with is like
when you want to log in that way we set
the session that way and it'll have some
sort of refresh I have no idea what the
refresh mechanism is with workday
specifically but something when we want
to allow people to use that from their
phone that's how we did that I think
setting up Google Calendar was also a
pain point if I remember correctly with
that and so same sort of uh same sort of
issue same sort of Remedy there
exception group set it up take them out
of the exception group so you just
exempt them from one of them one
important call out the exception group
that I probably should have mentioned is
uh we didn't say like okay you just have
no MFA now people have backup tootp
already set up or if they don't when
they go into sign in with OCTA again
they set up totp MFA so they fall back
to that so we never have people logging
in without MFA there's always a backup
authentication mechanism standard so
people are still using trtp when they're
logging in with a new OCTA session this
is about you're trying to create a
session to log into an existing app we
can exception group you for now and
things will be okay
Yeah question right up front
yeah uh it's uh two questions there I'm
gonna go to the next slide too so in
case I have any other questions you can
find me afterwards but um two questions
there first one is we use any other
features of the UB key like storing um
OTP codes on the UB key itself and
generating OTP codes from that answer
that one um we haven't used that we've
been still using OTP like uh apps like
authy or Google Authenticator again we
like intentionally chose a pretty
restrictive um key the key cnfc is the
standard that we came down to the second
question is about Windows hello
specifically setting a pin yeah that was
a pain point that we felt fortunately we
have limited users of Windows and so
what we did is for those users we had it
go through and disable the pin mode
using YK man which is command line tool
so you can turn it off that way but it
is unfortunate that we have to do some
manual operations this is again one of
the goals here was to not put too much
burden onto it just want to give a shout
out it team and Discord you're awesome
thank you for helping with this and
thank you everybody else in security and
thank you for all of you coming and
seeing my talk today I really appreciate
it
[Applause]