we're really super glad to see you guys
on our next generation cyber Wi-Fi talk
and today we are going to discuss about
our approach how to teaching security
operation team on how to detect
cyberattacks how to mitigate cyber
attacks and how to configure
cybersecurity tools for many different
infrastructure types ok let's go
my friend Tilly I and I where
researchers in information security
field and we are conduct penetration
tests on daily basis and constantly
faced with defense and Blue team during
our projects and very often but also
we'll stay undetected so we decided make
brief research on why this has happened
and today our talk will be as follow
we're talking about actual problems in
security operation team we then we will
discuss about existing methods to solve
management problems discuss about
drawbacks and benefits of teaching
security operation came through traffic
replay CTF like attack defense and quiz
gaming after we do try imagine ideal
solution for teaching security operation
team and requirements for this after all
we demonstrate you how we realize these
requirements in our teaching solution
which called Empire also we're talking
about technical issues technical
problems which we faced why we realize
this solution and of course we show you
what benefits you could get if you use
this approach let's start begin with a
sock operation problem due to ABM data
brief support in this year incident
detection and reaction time is a two
hundred and seventy nine days two
hundred and seventy nine days this is
much more longer than was the area and
this concludes there are several
important issues related with use of
cyber security to skills of
configuration skills of detection and
mitigation cyber attack consequences
and also maybe due to intercommunication
between blue team and security operation
team monitoring team and respond to him
and what is the main problem think about
it
modern security operation center
includes at least minimum three key
roles incident responders security
operation analysts and treat hunter yeah
based on their own names
this is dream team which can save world
from any cyber attack here but why not
highly skilled hacker compromised his
system why we have several crews and
problem number one you can see
screenshot from emerging print website
containing open rules for snore database
and we can see this rule alert security
operation team if they were white and
user agent in the request okay surely
normal user not use Python for self
internet or maybe open Internet pages
such as FBI dot-com yeah but what if you
a hacker is it really hard to bypass of
course no after googling how I change
how I can change my user agent in button
request you give an answer and for any
security operation team your normal user
let's look another example when your
fruits are built as follow if count of
and connection time if current attempts
connect to host organ attached great to
when five per minute then security
operation teamwork his IP address and
mark he's a hacker but religion is that
many years it's a list of most popular
password
look like this yeah and when information
security tools aim to check a many one
password for many hosts for several
costs for example click map exact allows
not only to replace rashes but to check
one password to on several hosts and for
security team we are again a normal user
and trouble number three due to
checkpoint there are around 33 millions
attacks per day including dangerous want
and but mostly there are BOTS and script
kiddies here as you know if you imagine
of this events in ideas dashboard it's
really hard to highlight important
attack vectors that could compromise
your system and if you should pay
attention to all his you wouldn't have
time to react
this is why average incident responder
time is at 279 days and after defining
all some all problems in the security
operation team we are talking about
existing methods for solve this problem
and first up one is code of business
games lectures quiz game you may know
about such events when information
security specialist I divided in groups
and trainer ask a questions and trainer
give a right answer for these questions
for different situations that may arise
during creel cyber attack yes this
interesting approach but this approach
have benefits and drawbacks benefits is
organizational cost and only one
restrictions for teaching this is room
size but drawbacks this is only
theoretical knowledge and only simple
attack reactors method number two
actually it was created to test ATS
rules in the defy false-positive in
ideas rose network traffic replay which
approach could be used to demonstrate my
new vulnerability and not me to have
professional training attacks and not
have any professional trainer drawbacks
for this method always identical
behavior and two simple text vectors and
Method number free CTF
CTF is a great approach yes but
unfortunately even this also matters
there are drawbacks complexity of
infrastructure maintains and
and ability to repeat specific attacks
because every attacks where team in CTF
and also there are only one
infrastructure and if you want to teach
one team on the office network and you
want to teach to another team on the
bank office what to do so we decided to
try answer all mention questions and
create our solution what is the cyber
training cyber training is an event
where information security professionals
we have different level of training to
teach on how to detect and mitigate
cyber attack consequences so cyber
polygon is a platform where cyber
training can be conducted so firstly you
need to elaborate list of requirements
and create cyber polygon core which you
include maturity of previously benefits
and have the possibility to adapt as per
user request now let's move on
requirements first of all personal Isis
simultaneous trainings the platform
needs to have possibility to Train
security operation team to detect
analyze and mitigate cyber attacks
different attack reactors for every
infrastructure we should have
personalised attack scenarios next one
possibility to use different reaction
tools as per security operation team and
this is needed because different teams
use their own tools our mission is to
provide the survey polygon with Verity
of open source and proprietary solution
to simulate a real-world infrastructure
like cisco ii on open source Palo Alto
and Check Point and another important
requirement to our platform is
availability availability for training
trainer who select infrastructure and
conduct cyber training possibility to
select iveco attack reactor for selected
infrastructure and shock student who has
access to reaction tools
interface and every host infrastructure
and interface to interact with trainer
and with other students for
communication and also possibility to
conduct
no trainings on different infrastructure
if you wanna teach one group on the
network templates and another group on
the bank office in the premier every
training you have only necessary action
tools which I use in typical
infrastructure and let's collect our
requirements and once while these
automated attacks much put simultaneous
trainings and personalized trainings and
of course infrastructure is customizable
and easy for use for training for
students and repeatable attack scenarios
and fully autonomous finally all these
requirements was implemented in our
teaching platform Empire now I want to
talk about key features of this platform
let's start let's start with many
networked employees we have a two-man
team plays as such as bridge office and
enterprise surface during summer
training our platform uses and Rises
real infrastructure consisting of
virtual machine at any moments you don't
have possibility to interact if n is
this cost and templates have Network
segmentation and traffic emulation Rayo
users one of many a check and our
platform name is HTTP fully autonomous
attackers start in map scanning found
HTTP host with Drupal 8 use Drupal get
on and after provide internal scanning
service found a SSH and provide the
cessation boot force use post
exploitation techniques and after G be
compromised this platform is a for
teacher have friendly interface and easy
for student and now students are divided
into two groups who detect events and
who check these detects and fix
vulnerability in this platform
the second group using information from
first group and knowledge about will
shown for
tries to fix vulnerabilities such as SQL
injection reverse engineering tasks and
walk and containing configuration
through admin panel and of course we
have this amazing vegetable like CDF for
feedback between trainers and students
and now I show you okay platform I'll
show you how to interact with the
platform we have record video we wanted
to make like live demo but due to issues
which we will show you a video if you
want we will show you after the
presentation the live one so as Sergey
mentioned the system have different
roles for the teacher for the students
they are divided into two groups the
reaction team and mitigation team let's
login as teacher we have a dashboard
with all the trainings that this teacher
have been created previously with
incident created by the students with in
the top part you can see it has seven
users created three templates available
three trainings you can see them on the
left part and one student created by the
user the users tab has all students it
ever created and the groups he has a
sign of them too so he can create the
users I assigned them to groups to know
which users can passed or assign them to
specific training groups let's create a
new group and assign users to this group
so you feel like login first name last
name email and assign users to specific
click create a new group so after the
group is created we can create the
training so you can see the list of
trainings completed they are finished
and the progress status for instance the
second change is failed on 72%
so you know it's not been finished so
create a new trend they've come 2019
click continue select the template every
template has the attack script connected
to this template on the image you can
see the list of boxes and P addresses
this information also available for the
student during the infrastructure
investigation so we select an office
template select best scenario it has one
scenario DePaul get on the another
another template has the name of the
company it is much bigger than the
previous ones
many subnets and also with different
scenarios connected to invest select the
attack on database and continue we
select the group Sauk students continue
and we should select the detection team
all the another students automatically
pass to mitigation team their training
case appears on screen he still not
started so to start them you should use
another screen with which contains all
information about this training let's go
to dashboard that's the main dashboard
you previously saw so select the
training they've come 2019 you can see
the left side the main lunar abilities
that should be mitigated to successfully
complete the training by the students
the monitoring team the defense team and
we in right side the incidents created
by the monitoring team the locks from
the script are available below the three
main boxes and you click a start button
and script starts to
in trade via network so he still
produces the 3% locks are appearing on
the screen and now we will again as
monitoring students to see what is
available for him a little paused to
admire the beauty of this screen one
second
so another the main dashboard in
incident taps contains the only
previously created incident and when the
users are start start to create the new
ones
they appear on this screen yes we login
with another account the students is in
a group of monitoring team so he has
information about trainings completed
and still in progress so he likes the
Deaf camp the incidents are empty so he
uses linked to the sensor or sixel
security tool he uses to detect the
animal it is in traffic he walks him and
he uses the Avensis like you can use any
ideas or you a solution you like so he
investigates the events that are now
appeared so he sees the map scream T
tangent is detected on the user agent
you can investigate the packet he sees
the destination that source address of
attack the new events are appearing
constantly and this is how he may assume
that something happened on the network
it's a simple example but of course you
can use another tools or more complex
more it depends on what you want to
teach the students so after detection of
an incident he sees the emerging threat
exploit PHP rule fired up so he may
investigate the rule and find that
[Music]
yeah he finds information that it was
created by executed at Drupal sites web
page contains Drupal so he knows the
source and destination addresses and he
now may create an incident to monitor to
reaction team to solve this or try to
investigate what happened in the network
so he creates incident gives us a name
also fills the source address the
affected host the indicators that might
contain information how he received this
information about this incident maybe he
used the ideas maybe he used another
tool so he feels all the fields and the
date also they said no time and he might
upload the file contains packet capture
- if monitoring his reaction team is
unsure he can check also the file and
may make some conclusions
the description about the incident - for
the reaction team it will be much more
easier to investigate if he was
information of about what happened and
why the reaction team thought that it
it's real innocent in incident in rent
accommodation he pulls the check this
host or blog this host or investigate if
it's another attack and investigated so
he created an incident it has a score
the trainer can also see this incident
and rated from 0 to 5
also there I chat window like if the
monitoring Direction team or the trainer
and doesn't understand something he can
write a comment and and find out another
clue or something so it was the trainer
he just marked the vulnerability or the
incident card with the five stars so now
I can begin as a reaction team member
also the same screen the trainings the
incidents created by the PHP report what
he investigated is the affected host and
using where he has linked to his working
computer can LDP to it and he now in he
now in the network it's in a training
network itself like using his computer
inside the right information security
officer computer inside the vulnerable
network so he any tools can be
pre-installed is there to solve the
issues he checks the webpage of the
affected host while it's loading he/she
can use the SSH to connect to this host
and investigate the operating system or
logs so he says that the browser load
the web page to the triple-eight he
finally she managed to login and he uses
the net stat to find out that the
session is established from the attacker
host to this host to mitigate the Drupal
Kadam vulnerability she may update the
Drupal or she may disable the user
registration functionality through which
the payload was delivered so he uses his
credentials and disables the user
registration functionality all he
attacks are checked with scripts if they
were mitigated so when she fixes the
information about the that the issue is
mitigated will automatically be shown on
the trainers and the students and the
main screen I'll show you later the main
screen that contains all information for
this particular training - available to
the users who are watching the training
so we see that Drupal given to was
mitigated and what if if student decides
just to shut down the host the scripts
also checked this and if the host is
shut down the the status of new
abilities you will encounter so you that
the issue is not mitigated and the
service is unavailable for you this main
dashboard contains also key owner
abilities the time left for restraining
the status of incidents created
mitigated and the statistics so this can
be shown for any users because the
information about the vulnerabilities
without the names so he shuts down the
host and one second
and after the host shut down and passes
same amount of time the in without
responding the mobility will change its
color to blue and this is how the
trainer or another students now that the
vulnerability is not fixed so this was
the quick demonstration of the platform
and integration between trainers and the
users so when we develop the platform
faced with several technical issues I
want to share you with you
so for instance we know sometimes when
you do a penetration test you use the
matter perjure so once we developed one
of our scripts we notice that sometimes
the SSH connection with the host doesn't
work so we stray we try to investigate
what happens and we not just when you
use the pivoting in amateur perjure not
this the default meet after not the
Python not PHP the standard meterpreter
the SSH packets are reversed we get in
reversed order sometimes so we googled
and we found that this vulnerability
exists for two or three years and nobody
fixed this so be aware if you use this
and were unable to find the password for
when brute-forcing so it might be the
case also one of the technical issues
about the instance isolation because you
have several you may have several Perl
trainings and for the students the
template one and template to need to be
completely isolated from each other so
we created a different network with a
static addressing
and with dynamic and racing the network
with the dynamic addressing is above the
network of the static address if the
static addressing network is the
vulnerable enterprise and the stat in
the dynamic addressing contains their
hosts needed for the services that sends
the statistics to dashboard energy to
interaction with the trainers and the
users so another problem you might face
if you develop something similar is you
need a spam port of course and the spam
port should be different for each of the
networks because you cannot send this
the information about the network
traffic to another training so to solve
this you can write a custom
configuration to the virtual switch as
if you use VMware it contains the vetos
fish also the open source solutions also
has the open milto switch so you can
configure them what can be done with
this platform you can of course train
the soap teams you can also train put
replace the automatic attacker with the
real attacker and also complete
differents we passed one or two
trainings and the fig with what was
really positive even from the people who
are in this field and not only the
students who just learn to in in cyber
security field so also you can use this
platform to write some tools because you
have the infrastructure you can test
your tools on this platform you can of
course teach students and teach students
to communicate because during one of our
ones we saw that even the students the
monitor
team and reaction team were near each
other they didn't in communicate because
they were asking us why we can find in
one step how the checker penetrated from
this segment to another and the another
team said in front of them they knew the
answer but they did not cooperate with
them so also you can use such platforms
to test the hardware for instance
compare ideas solutions firewalls and
other tools needed to detect the attacks
what's for the future we plan to like
it's like a concept not like really
major product we want to create the
attack and network scenario network
builders to give the possibility to
trainer to create the new
infrastructures and the attacks from
some primitives that they have
pre-programmed also you can like create
some certifications based on such
platforms thank you for this for reading
that's all may be questions
so since we are providing trainings I
believe that this will be our it
question would you be so kind to go back
to the slide six five six yes so here
you have description of thread hunter
being a guy who is performing an
automatic stance to determinate if there
are some vulnerabilities in the network
this is clearly outside of the scope for
threat hunting deer hunting is based
assumption that network is already
compromised and trade hunter is working
in order to prove or disprove the
hypothesis like for example X filtration
filtration of the data using DNS
requests so you may want to correct that
okay thank you for this thank you
I'm just curious if you have a public
trial version for for us to try this out
we can we can discuss so if you're
interested we can yes show you something
but now it's an available publicity to
the full Internet all right so yeah you
just select customers right no we don't
sell yet it's like it's like say you're
a proof-of-work or something
I see thank you there are scoreboard for
students or something or in what in
which way the teams are created for it's
not only for students it's also to
improve the skills of existing teams but
of course firstly there need to be
implemented the real scenarios in more
complexity edit to network itself and
the field with the solutions you want to
be in this you have to be a teacher to
create teams or get access to various
platform the teachers are not to be
highly qualified because they can use
the platform and the attacks are
automated so the purpose of teacher is
to create the group or also create some
tasks for knowledge now it creates on
the group and selects from predefined
pre created tasks and fires the training
okay so if he's he has skills he yes he
can access the platform and modify the
script but from the interface now it's
unavailable
how long does it take you to build a new
network schematic or a new now it's not
really hard because like it depends it
depends on the size but like we have for
the components it's not really long but
like and you're probably having the
machines pre-scripted before and you
just raise them up so the original
question that I wanted to ask is do you
actually change the passwords for the
accounts to improve reusability of
scenarios or the passwords the passwords
for the accounts I mean you create an
entire infrastructure there change the
credentials for the users in the
directory course even you can't you can
build the boxes from the vagrant or son
yeah
from the beginning or no but now you can
use like I know yes now it's nervous
it's not really long like but depends on
complexity also
okay you have a mic hello thank you for
the presentation really interesting but
I was wondering where we can find some
updates because you said the is not the
own Internet you are working on this
project and when we're going to be
finish it we plan in half a year to
finish all what we want so you can
contact us if you're interested it's
only for companies maybe the project
will gonna be like hack the box maybe
for all the students we wanted to build
a cloud version but it's we need to
raise an infrastructure it's like a
costume of money so it's it depends on
what the future of the project will be
so the solution is to for the companies
to buy infrastructures and also the
software from you now yes now okay thank
you so you can take one more yes yeah so
we have here regarding the
infrastructure you're using classical
VMs or toker technology Williams
classical classical have you thought
about using docker yes we can but the
problem is the the real boxes are more
like more real and for the training the
stock seems that works with real
infrastructure I suppose that more
convenient to use VMware but if you like
need to use FreeBSD how you can raise it
on docker for instance so
yeah thank you yes the last one
how can you Emily to the layer 2 network
attacks such as a roofing etc I'm asking
[Music]
because which all switches works not
like which they don't have we can
implement also the switches as virtual
boxes for instance if you like to
emulate these kind of attacks and
develop scenarios containing the
spoofing we can use the real toll not
will not with all switches but the
images of real switches like this thanks
thank you right thank you again guys