the topic is the penetration testing of
the vehicle components like ECU and the
deplete management systems so I'm Aaron
Manny I'm the founder and director of
the Amina siq labs LLP that particular
focused on the the component the
services like hardware testing
industrial control systems vehicle and
telco products as well so my interest
lies in those those field and I'm the
speaker and trainer of different
conferences like Def Con and death camp
has let's start the presentation so so
this this is the definition for those
people who don't know the car actually
so it's it's for more than more than
three our other cancer more than two
wheels they call it as a car and they
transport one people to another one
location to another location and that
you can find on Wikipedia so if you talk
about the modern car so you will find a
lot of components over here like the
Bluetooth Wi-Fi telematic telematic
devices even key folks key entry you can
say with the key folks or keyless entry
in that case we have obd2 TPMS tire
pressure monitoring systems and body
controller module or rather you can say
engine control unit electronic control
units those those those components you
can see in the modern car so what
exactly the can-can is nothing but the
controller area network so it's modern
the communication protocol for used used
for use in vehicles rather you can say
their transportation so it's a two wire
protocol so can high and low and its
uses differential signaling so 1987 they
the boss was the company who
reduce the can canvas protocol and it
has a two type of protocols like you can
- 1.0 and 2.0 and again 2.0 has the two
parts a a and B so it's difference
between the a and B is like identifier
bit
it's a 11 bit and in 29 Peters so what
we are targeting over here is we talked
about the physical physical testing of
the car or rather you can say the the
ECU so sorry about that so OB - it's a
onboard diagnostic port you can say here
if I talk about the Oh buddy - it's it's
it's like in u.s. is mandated in 2004
the every car sorry in 2009 1999 they
they every car should have the Oh buddy
port so first they introduced obviously
the orbital one then they come up with
Aubrey - if I talk about the European
standards they call it as a EO pd o
buddy so that specifies the architecture
of the not exactly the pin pen
description of the Oh buddy - and here
you can see six and 14 are used for the
can low and can high and you can see
over here like five and four of the
signal ground and the chassis ground so
whenever we talk about the campus or
rather Albany - it always works on 12
volt edges so where you can find obd2
port like if I talk about the car so
there are different places you can find
the obd2 ports like it's nearby the
driver seat may be on the rear seat as
well backside also so mine car is a like
electric car in India so I have obd2
port on backside at the at the backside
and the one over T 2 port is on the the
rave seat of the driver so there are
different cases you will find those
structures in white sometimes in the
black so sometimes you come up with
the the female obd2 or mailed over
Tidrow depending on the manufacturers
sometimes you'll see those kind of over
t2 as well so in that case you need to
have some sort of the converter so in
that case if we talk about the usb are
rather db9 cable so you need to have the
veenai to obd2 converter or in that case
you will have it this specifically I
believe it's it's from the Mercedes so
if you open any ECU rather engine so you
might find those kind of the structure
other port where you can you need to
find out the USB db9 to this this kind
of pin numbers so that particular pin
numbers are described like four and
fives like ground another 14 and six is
four can hand can blow so how the ECU
looks like so it's a kind of embedded
systems so they use the microcontroller
instead of the microprocessor so microf
assessor I can give you the example of
Raspberry Pi it's a microprocessor right
so we can install Linux rather raspbian
OS right but in an ECU it won't be
possible it it's pure microcontroller
and if you if you compare the entire
coding the skeleton or rather the number
of lines number of lines of codes with
respect to the Facebook and other social
network it's a huge if I compare with a
modern modern car so it's very huge it's
a billions lines of codes in the car
modern car so if you compare with the
Facebook
it's very less the core lines of course
of Facebook is very less than the modern
car so in that case the all structures
are other course it's it's in C language
and it supports a lot of
microcontrollers which which take which
flash the entire code inside so if you
see there are a lot of capacitors some
crystals over here so it's pure embedded
systems so we'll come to the hardware
part as well how these things are
vulnerable for
harder attacks as well so this is how
when when when you see the internal
parts of modern cars so every every
every every devices has rather features
has some sort of the ECU we call as a in
control electronic control unit so
nothing but this thing so very small
it's different on the sides it's they
depend on the the size of the what
exactly the device inside the car so in
the modern car you'll see more than its
minimum like more than 200 ECU's in the
car so if you snip the entire
communication in the car itself will get
lot of communication on the while you're
sniffing the entire communication so the
these are the some features features for
the modern car like every seat controls
infotainment systems then emergency
brake systems and ventilations HVAC
everything has some sort of embedded
system be called as ECU so every issue
has some sort of the functions or rather
you can say event to perform so again
the control unit as I said so what about
the fork protocol different kind of
protocols you will see so if I if I
distinguish this protocol as per the
requirement as per the data rate so it's
a Lin protocol it's a one wire protocol
so where the data rate is very slow and
if you see the requirement is very low
actually if I compare with the canvas
canvas has a huge demand in the and in
the market as well so the data rate
would be the hi-hats if I see sorry if I
if I talk about the Flex take the same
now the flexor is getting outdated but
the speed of the flexor is very higher
than the canvas but the requirement also
it's get increased so as I say
the canvas is the two-wire communication
can Hank and lo and it uses differential
signaling so if you see the differential
signal over here can hack and lo but it
has some sort of you know the packet
frames so arbitration ID here is so
important in that case when you when you
trying to do you know pen testing or
rather you can say some sort of attacks
on the ECU or other in the car itself
physically so it's a DLC and pin data
and then CRC and end up the frame so if
I see the can network so in on the
single bus not we cannot save the single
/ sexually so in the main bus you will
see lot of components are attached like
ECU lamps head ECU headlight headlamp
they sees you then lights ECU these are
the different kind of issues connected
with each others so what's what's the
how it communicates it will only
broadcast the message so if it is
broadcasting the message so what exactly
how they identify a rather you can say
if if they broadcast at the same time
which would be which one will be the
higher highest priority message
so it's depend on the arbitration ID so
the if the arbitration ID is low then
the message would be the would have the
highest priority on the can message so
let's say the break break has a the
arbitration ID very low because it's
emergency at the emergency you push the
brake and that's the execute
mechanically with the help of ECU right
so in that case the arbitration ID of
the break would be always be less than
other other messages because it
dominates that arbitration ID to other
can messages so here in that case if if
you want to do some sort of reverse
engineering of particular event like a
brake headlamp or rather you can decide
indicator a lot of things or other you
can say rpm so we need to find out what
kind of the the arbitration ID in that
case so in a can transmission if I say
the ECU a1 and ec2 and ECU 3 so these
are the messages let's say 3 & 3 so it
would be 1 second 52nd and 250 seconds
so it's a the time difference between
two consecutive messages so it's very
important we need to find out the
message the time difference between the
two messages for particular thing so
it's depend on the what kind of message
it I say if it is break so so time tram
travel or other time difference between
the two consecutive message would be a
very less because it's fast faster than
the other messages so what are the
extended protocols for the canvas these
are the protocol like iso TP protocol
can open GM lang s s EEG so one at five
zero PWM see these are the different
kind of protocols which is based on the
canvas and which can be the extended so
depending on the if I talk about the GM
Lam is the gentle motor land so it's
internet-based protocol as well so and
if we compare the entire protocol with
with the with the obd2 ports so here see
as I say the 6 and 14 numbers for the
pin numbers for the canvas scan high
infant and low and key k WP l link and
the other PWM and M scan these are the
these are the pin numbers for the
different messages so what are the tools
you can see in the while doing some sort
of the testing so there are some
commercial tools are available here I
listed a few of them commercial tools
not few and only single so value can
three is one of the good tool you can
say in the market so there are some
tools like vectors canopy there are some
optimizer from the Germany this
duels in very expensive this tool is
cost around the 390 or $400 and the and
the software cost around maybe from 150
to 400 $4,000
100 to 4,000 1000 to $4,000
so if I talk about the software is
really costlier than the hardware itself
so there is open-source tool called as
us between so here we are doing the car
hacking village over here so you can see
this this kind of tool in car hacking
village and you can see the live demo of
the how we can do some sort of the
canvas testing and the the how we can
crack the seed keys or the ECU as well
so can us between is supports only
canvas message not the lint protocol and
this is the same thing inside the they
use a microchip even they can us between
uses microchip chipset even in this Tula
so they use microchip and this can used
or with the hell with the help of can
socket that can scan utility of one of
the library and you can find it on Linux
so if you install can can you Till's you
definitely attached with these things it
has a see TTL to USB converter so you
can connect with the Linux and you can
start sniffing those communications as
well so this is one of the cool tool is
called a scan badger so these guys are
the creator of the can badger is one is
Ferdie and he's the xavier right soon so
this car is very genius i follow them
actually personally so they're good
researcher and they they they make this
scan batcher it has two dp9 cables and
the third net as well so they made
declined software the it seemed like a
bob suit so you can intercept the
communication you can change the
communication and send it to the issue
or other car so it's like you can you
can see the talks
in hardware i/o 2016 they call it as a
car hacking like a bub suit so if you
see these things really amazing then you
can same Judas packets
I study P packets and ton of things you
can do and if you search for the can
badger on the github you'll see the bomb
so within 100 125 dollar you can make
those devices and and now they are
coming with a pro version I believe
within 5 months they're going to release
that can badger pro its but it's really
cool can tools is one of the software so
even the u.s. between and the other
software can work with this the scan
tools is from the Russian guy for linen
for lane as of now we we can see this
the microchip Lynn as analyzer so
microchip gives the windows-based the
software from there it can analyze the
lint protocol and you can send it and
receive it those kind of protocols as
well but there are some protocols like
there are some tools commercial tools
available in the market like optimizer
or other you can say the vector as well
so what kind of attacks you can perform
on the canvas we can we can we can
perform the toss attack it's nothing but
if I do if I like here in Oh buddy - if
I short this thing with Canon camera it
becomes DOS again it's it's like a
physical but what we can do with on the
or the packet is itself so in the or the
packet it's like if you saying the zero
zero zero the message on particular ID
and that that can cause the denial of
service a denial of service attack on
the particular de canvas fire rose again
so as I said in the firehouse
so this speed is very critical right so
let's say we have 500 milliseconds 1 e
c.o transmits those message
with the 500 millisecond so what
happened if you same same thing that
message with the 500 millisecond so it
would be same right so there is no
effect on the the the one particular
issue so we need to reduce these things
we can reduce one millisecond 10
millisecond so what message goes first
on the particular issue and you can see
the effect on this called as fire roars
attack
Spyros that means it's related to our
the the transaction so packet payload
modification so he can modify the
payload so you can inject some sort of
other packets as well which can it may
be you Dias it may be anything like if
you know the ID and if you know the idea
is responsible for reset ECU or other
you can you can talk to ECU to dump
entire the information about the
firmware other you can dump the firmware
over the ID so that that thing you can
do with the packet payloads modification
packet replay so again it's the same you
can you can record the entire session
and you can replay it there will be
possibility that that that can be a
replay attack right after right before
it's kind of the attack where if you
have the malicious packet first and then
you are sending in legitimate packets
there is a possibility that's FIFO and
LIFO is it's it's happening on the
microcontroller that that triggers a
buffer overflow attack on the ECU itself
the same thing if you send the
legitimate packets first then the
malicious packet after that there is
again there a possibility you can
trigger the buffer overflow attack on
the particular particular issue so for
that purpose you can you can come to our
the car hacking village and we'll see
the live demo that how we can do sit-ski
or rather silky cracking or rather you
can say the other dos attack and fire
hose attack on the speedometer itself so
now it's a FMS it's a fleet management
systems
so if we see over here the management
systems over here it's connected with a
lot of communications it supports the
GPS locations and the its it supports
GPRS and gsm 3g 4g depending on the what
kind of the fleet management uses the
communication and that's connect to the
the tracking server is nothing but the
manufacturer
are there any vendor which sub which
gives the service of fleet management
system and from the client PC or other
mobile you can track the entire
communication the what exactly the USB
over here the location so location is a
main critical area because you have to
understand rather we have to see where
where exactly my the vehicle is going in
which direction so for that purpose they
use fleet management systems so what are
different kind of attacks you can
perform so fleet management systems like
a obd2 dongle are there any kind of PC
you they call it as a transmission
control unit or rather telematic control
unit that's that resides in the the
car Network and from there they connect
with the GPS and from the GPS to GS
sorry GSM to the cloud and cloud to your
PC or other mobile and that supports GPS
as well so when I was when we are doing
some sort of hardware testing so we
found some the the WP ROM that SPF flash
so we could not find any protocol or the
GPS though I can do some sort of you
know the GSM GSM the GSM jamming or
rather you can say they can I can make
the fake GPS fake BTS and that that yeah
that fleet management system can connect
with my fake BTS and I can intercept and
I can try to inject some SMS if it is
supports SMS or rather any any can
message on the on the D BTS through the
yes itself so what we found the the the
SPI chipset and we have the programmer
that is cs3 for one a programmer and we
connect with the DSP a chipset and we
extracted and we found this information
from the these things we found here is
the IP address here is the some
companies link and the company link and
here's some IP addresses which is
hard-coded inside the SPI ROM and these
are different some phone numbers these
are the phone numbers when they use the
fleet management system and they
registers the mobile number
so you'll find those mobile numbers here
so this is again one kind of
vulnerability you can say and this is
the serial numbers so when we scan this
IP address so with the help of n map we
found the this FTP server it's running
on particular thing and we found all the
bin files that is firmwares right so
these are the former's which is used for
the fleet management systems and what
happened when when we extracted those
firmwares and weed and reverse
engineering so we found some sort of
passwords over here so username password
for a particular link so I cannot show
that links actually but this is how we
found a very juicy part and we try to
control that particular devices and we
can easily locate the where exactly the
the other devices other devices are
registered devices on the in the fleet
management systems so then we do done
some GPS spoofing so we have the hack RF
and we have GSM antenna the rather GPS
antenna so initially this is this this
this addresses from the Pune India
actually so we are driving the car with
a fleet management system so initially
we were here then we move further so so
we spotted over here then our car is
here and you can see we are moving
around and when we start gsm spoofing
this is the one of the very good tool
gps SDR sim is one of the Japanese guy
who created this software very nice you
can you can use the software but but but
it's depend on you actually so how can
use that and how we can use for
malicious things so what we do we
mention our coordinates with the the GP
SIM bin so that that particular bin file
has a as the coordinates and with the
help of hack RF and the the GSM antenna
we executed this data
geum's gps sim data and what found our
car is in New York right so we were in
India after spoofing the coordinates our
car is in is in New York USA and we are
driving the car and you can see the the
car is moving from one location to
another location so this is another kind
of one ability with with the GPS still
we are figuring out the what this
solution it is like if it is GSN
spoofing if you want to avoid the GSM
spoofing and even the the device is very
small so there are some techniques to do
that but if someone has a solution you
can talk we can discuss after the talk
actually so how we can mitigate this GSM
spoofing so so how this is it's very
critical because it's a it's a USB for
the those people who makes the fleet
management fleet management systems what
happened your car is get stolen and and
your yours try to see where where
exactly your car and someone is from the
very genius robber rather we can say the
thief he can do some GPS GG GPS spoofing
and you can your cars can put instead of
romanette can put in India or somewhere
else and
you cannot look at the exactly the car
verities so this is the this this was
the one apparatus we found in Africa
management systems and everything so any
questions
hello Aaron thank you very much for the
nice presentation I have a question do
you know when the can has started to be
encrypted the year the can can message
can yeah when they started to implement
encryption on the camp when when they
started encryption encryption which year
they start the carmaker's encryption so
I don't believe actually so so there is
no encryption but there are some things
you can implement the gateways they call
it is a gateway like like an IT sector
we use firewall right so in that case
they can use the gateways it's acts as a
firewall they can you switch between the
issue and the your sensors as well so
it's it's depend on the how the big how
your the architecture of your car and
based on the architecture and based
based on the the safety security
standards and the cyber security and
ERDs when you implement some sort of
cyber security solution you have to take
care of the safety standard as well
sometimes what happened there there
would be a delay in the message in the
in the in the or the ECU so that can
hamper the safety security as well so
according to we we call it as a tera and
they call it a sahara
so tar and Jara we need to match those
things the threats and we need to come
in a particular state where we can our
be able to use any critical solutions
like a gateways or a firewall in that
case and on on which protocol on which
device or rather you can say which
feature that that's that's the thing
that ok think your own I have another
question here you can start the engine
of unlock the car if I have connected
the
obd2 dongle yes so in this in this
example that that that only reads the
message not writing any message on the
ovary - so if it is reading message like
you need to check first whether your FMS
like fleet management system is able to
start your engine or not if it is if
that fleet management system has those
kind of features yes definitely
so if you can hack rather you have
access on the cloud and you know the
particular FMS the device we can send
those message to that MMS and from the
FMS that can message sent to that
particular or the obd2 that can be
possible a rather rather if you do some
sort of reverse engineering first of the
car what the message is responsible for
to start engine off engine opening door
and that particular message you can
inject through the MMS or the G GPS of
certain GSM or the 3G or 4G so you only
you need to make some sort of the fake
inor if I talk about the 4G if it is 2g
you need to you know create a fake BTS
in that case thank you we'll take one
more question yes okay hi very great
presentation but my question is was a
simple driver I I can protect myself
from some attacker or something like
that so I don't know some all this kind
of stuff that's that's really
interesting question actually it's the
user standpoint of view actually so
there are a lot of possibilities that
nowadays a lot of the technologies
talking about the ADSI anomaly detection
systems so that thing can be possible
and if it is there would be possibility
there's some people some research
researchers are working on the
prevention system as well as some
incident occurs they can kill
the canvas message but it's no it's not
exactly the word I cannot use that
particular word but the in layman
language yeah it can kill the the canvas
message so there would be in future that
a lot of possibility that that thing's
the ideas or the the prevention system
can implement in the ECU and that issues
itself sufficient like it detects
automatically and it it killed that
particular message so still we are also
on this pace of research actually we
made a TS but we are in - in the face of
the prevention system as well yes for
reversing you want to do the kites lock
and you don't have physical access to
the obd2 connector you can hack the car
yes yeah so so there is a different ways
to open the car actually so you can you
can do some sort of replay attack on the
key folks or the relay attack on the
wireless key that that would be a
possible
I know but forget about the key and it
won't be possible but yes anyhow if you
open the bonnet there there is a
possibility they can connect directly to
the ECU and that that yes but this this
this thing is the penetration testing
point of view that talk is it is so it's
not like but if you have access you
don't need to obd2 as well you can just
do some sort of the short circuit
there's some wires and you can start the
car and go away that you can because yes
there's nothing like the movies
yes okay thank you so much
[Applause]