so as we take our seats so this is a
very interesting incident that I managed
and negotiated and found a resolution
for and give you a bit of a background
about me because many of you might not
know much about me I actually started
out very young younger than B ahir I was
actually in computers starting from
around the age of five and unfortunately
at the age of ten I was busted for
breaking into the Department of Justice
and the Federal Bureau of Investigation
so after I was 18 and I was allowed to
use a computer again the US Air Force so
kindly recruited me and started using my
specific talents for them in the various
ways I also was a military aviator and
worked for Space Command and my previous
role I headed digital security for IT
IOT and ICS systems for the Saudi Aramco
family across amia and Latin America so
where it was located for the Aramco
family my office was in The Hague the
Netherlands and one day I was eating
lunch which was pretty rare because I
did a lot of things for Ramco including
heading the joint international
intelligence team the Security
Operations Center and the network
operation center so I almost never got a
chance to eat lunch but this day it was
a special day I know it's coun into some
spinach salad and I was having a great
time until a very large man and a very
nice tailored suit stepped up to me and
he says mister Becca there's a problem
and I go uh what kind of problem is this
and he goes come with me
so I had been summoned by this gentleman
who took me into our empties office and
said we need to get you to the Saudi
Arabian embassy immediately they've been
hacked Saudi Arabian embassy wasn't too
far away from my office so I'm like okay
let me see what I can do let me take my
forensics person with me
and when we got there it was very
interesting because it started out with
an email hack and grew all the way to
the point where a terrorist group tried
to extort the city it was so bad that
the Embassy of Saudi Arabia and several
other embassies in The Hague actually
put a disclaimer on their website to
warn them that there was something going
on in The Hague with their embassies and
it also included the Dutch national
terrorism police and it spread to every
embassy with a business email on the
backend so one of the reasons why I was
chosen was because I'd already been
doing a whole bunch for the Saudi Aramco
family and it was myself and my team
that actually reconnected business
operations in 2013 after they were the
victim of the world's worst cyber
warfare attack when the Iranians hit
them with a piece of malware called
Shamoon and that piece of malware was a
wiper piece of malware and it knocked
out 85% of their windows-based computer
systems it also took out to oil
production facilities at the time and it
basically stopped their business
operations completely they were back to
typewriters they could not load petrol
trucks or fuel trucks as you might call
them here the country of Saudi Arabia
was running out of gasoline so if you
went up to the pump you could not get
any if you called an ambulance the
ambulance had no fuel so I was a trusted
individual with the Saudi Arabian
government and the Saudi Aramco family I
also have law-enforcement experience not
just getting busted by law enforcement
mind you but also dealing with various
cyber crimes and being the interface in
those particular investigations and I'm
very good at communicating so I
regularly talk to heads of states and
ministers and so forth later this month
I'll be doing two workshops with the
United Nations one on IOT and one on
protecting journalists with reporters
without borders now during this time
frame we have a right-wing individual in
the Netherlands called Kurt
and he had made a video at the time
where it looked like he was ripping up
the Quran and this angered a lot of the
rest of the world so they also insisted
after I brought my forensics person who
was Dutch that he had to leave but I
could stay because I'm a US citizen
the Saudi Arabian government also
cancelled bill over a billion euro worth
of contracts of Dutch companies and
kicked a lot of Dutch citizens out of
Saudi Arabia during this timeframe so it
ended up only myself handled the case
after I arrived now it's another thing
to remember with an Embassy's an embassy
is a piece of a country and that means
that local law enforcement does not
apply local laws do not apply the police
are non existent now in the diplomatic
world there is something called the
diplomatic core but they cannot say
openly arrest somebody without causing
an international incident if they have a
diplomatic passport I really miss the
days I traveled on my diplomatic
passport and made things a lot easier
and another thing to consider is the
fact that the Ambassador is the leader
of that embassy and is in essence the
king or queen of that embassy for that
country so what we found initially
because we were allowed to do a packet
capture on the network with the
forensics guy before if he was kicked
out was we found a commercial
off-the-shelf piece of malware now
what's interesting about this was we
were able to trace the transaction of
the purchase of the malware when I
solved the case to someone who was
affiliated with the Iranian government
now the way that cyber espionage works
is a nation-state can spend millions on
some fancy-schmancy apt or if they want
plausible deniability then they will use
commercial off-the-shelf so they it
doesn't look like they immediately did
it and this happened to be the case
unfortunately this also involved an
insider
working or thought he was working
completely for Isis now at the same time
we also had another type of an incident
I like to say you never forget the first
time you were droned this was my office
and blue and in the red was the embassy
of Yemen now Yemen all of a sudden they
decided to purchase the building next to
my office Aramco headquarters of Europe
what's unusual is it was not in the
embassy section at all it was a very
expensive building they were cash poor
at the time supposedly the government
but they bought it for cash straight up
cash and shortly after they moved in we
started having some problems with the
embassy our good old neighbors we caught
them in our back yard of our property
digging in to try to get to our
fiber-optic cable to bend and surveil we
caught several of their employees
pretending to be our employees inside
our building in the cafeteria because we
did not have a proper wall for the
outdoor eating area which we built
shortly afterwards then one day I was
talking to my boss and we happened to be
on the top floor of the building and I
looked behind him facing outside in the
windows and there is a very nice
commercial grade drone well it turns out
the Yemeni embassy decided that they
were going to try to surveil us by using
drones and flying one two three drones
around our building now because local
laws don't apply we couldn't just call
the police
but we had to have the diplomatic corps
step in and also the Dutch government
explained they could fly the drone over
their own property but it was illegal to
fly it over anyone else's property and
they also had to register the drones as
well if they were to do so because we
actually have very strict drone laws in
the Netherlands so you can't just do
that so finally they stopped but there
were a few other incidents involving the
amending embassy as well in some of my
direct personnel so when I got there
there was a young man he had just
started that week
he was a bit nervous obviously because
here's this big incident and he's saying
well what can I do what can I help you
with I go well listen what happened goes
well there were some suspicious emails
and I think that the email account has
been hacked and I go ok all right so
let's get to the bottom of this what is
the password for the email account for
your embassy one two three four five six
all right how many people think that
that's a great password for an embassy
right great password for no-one and what
had pique their suspicions was there was
only one person allowed to handle the
embassy emails and that was the
ambassador's secretary it was also the
only computer that was supposed to be
set up for this system and when a Saudi
Arabian national had asked the embassy
hey can you help me out with procuring a
visa and this person did not know that
the Saudi Arabian embassy stopped doing
visas they were sent back an email
saying hey I can expedite that visa for
you if you just give me some money and
so this was the email and what it said
was sure man we can get that visa for
you if you send me two hundred dollars
right over to money grant in the name of
the Saudi Arabian ambassador to the
United Kingdom who happens to be a
prince so this kind of looks suspicious
right so from this point it involved
several email events going back and
forth where the perpetrator had been
able to get into the email account doing
a man-in-the-middle sending messages
back and forth and it was very
unfortunate because it started to get a
bit personal during this time frame and
the perpetrator attempted to also make
believe that the Saudi Arabian
ambassador to the UK was actually having
an affair with the person who had sent
in the visa request and the person who
sent it in she's a rather controversial
figure
she used to run a lot of Islamic schools
in the United Kingdom that were funded
by the Saudi Arabian government and they
were shut down by the UK government
because of extremist literature that
they were giving to children so they
were trying to start a scandal and a
place where there had not been a scandal
so we locked down the email account
because I'm not a Saudi Arabian citizen
I can only do so much and made a whole
bunch of recommendations and then two
weeks later I'm eating lunch and finally
lunch again and then here comes the same
guy very large man in a very nice suit
and says mr. kubecka we have an issue
can you please come with me and I was
like all right you've already done the
embassy thing he doesn't act like a
family member died hopefully they didn't
find out I was mining Bitcoin on
supercomputers but instead it turns out
that the perpetrator still had access
somehow to that email account and
instead of it being $200 for a visa
suddenly it went up to $25,000 signed
Isis and this email was sent from the
Saudi Arabian embassies official
back-channel email account to the rest
of the GCC countries in the Middle East
and to Turkey which included Oman which
if you know it much about current
geopolitics Saudi Arabia and Oman are
not friends excuse me
Qatar and Saudi Arabia are not friends
so second email comes it says hey I'm a
friend
you can save many lives by just sending
me twenty five thousand dollars signed
Isis I standardized a little bit of it
but it was from Saudi embassy signed
Isis so it's always nice to know who you
working working with right so you know
exactly what you might be dealing with
now unfortunately the diplomatic corps
we're trying to be proactive however
they had no permission whatsoever to
send out any email
regarding this incident this was
supposed to be involving only the Saudi
Arabian embassy and we were using
diplomatic means with the other
embassies including I was already
collecting and evidence from those other
embassies who were giving it to me
freely except for Turkey they did not
and now we all know that they're also
not friends and the diplomatic corps
decided to send a warning email out to
every single embassy in The Hague on
their official back-office channel to
say hey if you get any of these
suspicious emails trying to extort you
for money go ahead and send it to us and
we'll see if we can help you out well
that sounds really cool
except they used CC instead of BCC and
the perpetrator was still on the backend
so now instead they responded back and
also to every single embassy in The
Hague that was included on that CC then
they started taunting the diplomatic
corps and saying I'm so glad we have
your attention now the amounts going up
so then it started getting very very
personal now in this case the
perpetrator while I was still trying to
figure out things because I only had
limited access broke into the
ambassador's Secretary's personal gmail
account and then sent an extortion
demand for 35 million dollars now of
course is freaked out the secretary so
she filed a local police report
unfortunately we had to ask that local
police station to make it disappear
which they accommodated for us then it
got even worse now this happens to be a
place called the ker house and it's a
national landmark and the Netherlands
this is where all the rich and famous
people would stay at before they headed
out on their luxurious cruise ships
before we had KLM airlines in the
Netherlands
and we were about to host something
called Saudi national day which a lot of
different countries they will have a
national day wherever they might be and
they invite in our case the Dutch royal
family the ambassador to the US the
ambassador to Romania the ambassador to
the UK Japan and so on and so forth so
when I say vvv IPS they were definitely
vvvvvv VIPs and instead the perpetrator
change tactics and said if you don't
give us 50 million dollars we are going
to blow up the ker house and everyone in
it so it was at this point that the
Dutch national terrorism police came
into view and tried to start helping us
out but because of the geopolitical
nature of things that were going on the
Ambassador wanted nothing to do with
them so privately the embassy section of
The Hague went on lockdown
we had plain clothes but armed forces
around that entire area bodyguards were
hired embassies were very very rattled
about this because their ambassadors and
their staff were targeted in this case
and to make matters worse I was I was
finally able to take a piece of
equipment home with me because I was at
this point so well trusted and I was
doing all the liaison work between the
Ambassador himself and any law
enforcement and all the rest of the
embassies that I was able to figure out
that the perpetrator had set up a
forwarder on the back end of the email
account and that's how they could see
the traffic going back and forth the
email and suddenly the Ambassador
himself said I think I know who it is so
one evening after everyone had left
except for his clothes protection
bodyguards I was left behind with him in
the building and he started getting down
on his hands and knees helping me look
for post-it notes for credentials for
the
suspect because we did not want the
person to know that we were on to him
because that could have made matters
much much worse and because of the
suspect the suspect had diplomatic
immunity so especially in this case law
enforcement did not apply whatsoever I
was able to then get the perpetrator out
of the email account then the
perpetrators started sending emails from
other accounts in also repeating the
various threats also listing specific
ambassadors names that they were going
to kill mentioning the Dutch royal
family and so forth but the perpetrator
screwed up did not mask where he was
coming from so I was able to geo locate
us several of the emails to the exact
neighborhood that he lived in in the
hague
so that was between the personal nature
of the attacks the way he acted when I
interviewed him on several occasions and
the geolocation information the
Ambassador was very very certain it was
this particular individual now in the
mix while we're dealing with all of this
around the corner from both the embassy
and where I live because I lived in the
embassy section of The Hague I used to
frequent this lovely pub called
Sherlock's pub which is all Sherlock
themed and it's fantastic at one the
best British pub in the Netherlands
award because I didn't even know that
that was a competition right so you know
when when you're stressed or when you'd
like a beer I could walk right over it
was a block from my house and one
evening I go in and the owner is there
and it goes uh these three guys have
been waiting for you for two hours now
I'll give this disclaimer in case
there's anybody from the Turkish
government or associated with them
because I met one in at Luxembourg last
week who was not happy with this talk
I'm sorry their intelligence agents were
so dumb so they've been sitting there
for almost three hours at a pub sipping
tea waiting specifically for me
so I walk over and I go hello I've heard
that you were waiting for me three
people I had never met in my life so
they give me their cards they happen to
work for the Turkish embassy all three
of them our cultural attache and they
have been waiting there so that I could
give them English lessons and they spoke
perfect English right does anyone think
that this is suspicious right not at all
so for two and a half weeks I dealt with
these individuals gave them English
lessons they would wait for me patiently
at the pub sipping tea until I could
arrive and I of course reported this to
the security services and they verified
indeed yes they were working for the
Turkish embassy that they were cultural
attache x' that they also had diplomatic
immunity great stuff right and then at
the same time I was also notified that
they found a list and on that list it
was a list from Isis and I was number
two out of ten people up for a
high-value target so things started
getting even more interesting because it
wasn't just an incident involving the
dumb dumber and dumbest Intel agents I
had ever run into in my life but now I
was at real physical risk so I'm not a
person who likes close protection
bodyguards so I made agreements for them
to just watch me at all times and
towards the end of the two and a half
week time period that I was dealing with
these Turkish intelligence agents one of
them gave me an unusual gift I am NOT
Muslim I do wear in Arabic necklace but
I'm not Muslim gave me prayer beads
which of course I promptly handed over
to security services to make sure that
they didn't have a bug in them right so
after the two and a half week time
period they just disappeared and when I
asked security services they verified
that all three of them had left in a bit
of a hurry out of the Netherlands
never to be seen again right so towards
the end because the incident lasted
almost three months and it was a
stressful three months because most
incidents do not last that long I'm
lucky I still have hair and we did not
pay any extortion we ensured that all
the embassies were safe we did a lot of
talking myself and the Ambassador with
various other countries using diplomatic
means to basically apologize for what
happened to work with them and also I
made a lot of recommendations for the
Saudi Arabian embassy because the way it
had been set up was very very bad they
did not have antivirus they had Windows
Defender right and they had a business
network and like many embassies in the
world an intelligence network luckily
they were completely separated because
that would have been even worse right
but they used a home grade router for
example that also had one two three four
five six right there networking rack was
in an area where all you had to do was
if you walked into the embassy you
didn't even have to register the way it
was laid out it was in a dark corner
there were no cameras you could just tap
right in or like Jason would pop pop pop
right so that had to be changed but the
matter with the person who was a suspect
now I do not condone extrajudicial
punishment however he was from a very
high-ranking family very good family
from Saudi Arabia and the likelihood
that he would have been prosecuted when
he was sent back to Saudi Arabia was
very very very very low so he was
promptly reassigned to a physically
dangerous location and shortly after he
arrived after his bodyguards got out of
the car he was the only person blown up
in a car bomb
so I like to say modern problems require
modern solutions so I got some rewards
because it was very stressful and one of
the things I got to do was there's very
famous painting in the Netherlands
it's actually listed in an addendum of
the Constitution which states that only
a Dutch citizen can ever own this
painting it's by Rembrandt and it's
called the night watchman and it's
actually bigger than this screen it's
not like the Mona Lisa
tiny tiny right no no no so when the
ambassador was leaving the Netherlands
he had a farewell dinner in front of the
right in the Rijksmuseum in front of
this famous painting and gave me a gift
in an award which I also tested I don't
trust anything from foreign government
that's where I roll and I got to enjoy
the evening unfortunately I was sick
that night so I couldn't partake of all
the fancy-schmancy wine so I could just
smell it
that's okay and I learned a lot of
lessons that sometimes when you're
involved in an incident that might be as
simple as somebody leaving a password of
one two three four five six depending on
the situation that could be rather low
risk or it could get people killed or
almost killed so thinking about how
certain things can actually cause real
human consequences is very very
important now imagine if you were
dealing with the nuclear event imagine
if you were dealing with the aviation
industry or the space industry or
something of that nature I happen there
was my fifth nuclear incident I've got
lots of stories like Jason actually
involved a nuclear crane luckily it was
not carrying the rod when it collapsed
and the vendor had not told the nuclear
facility that they had installed a 3g
modem in it with a public IP address
yeah cuz that's a great idea so you
never know with these different types of
things obviously never trust gifts from
a foreign agent or you know anyone kind
of suspicious and also prepare so if
you're ever involved in one of these
types of incidents one of the mistakes
that I did that made make was I had a
partner at the time and I thought hey he
doesn't need to know about any of this I
don't want to scare him but
unfortunately the person closest to you
or the people closest to you can
actually be used against you in these
particular types of incidents well we
would call your next or closest hop and
another thing that I learned was try
your best not to panic in these
particular situations and also pause
before you speak as much as possible
there there's two benefits to that you
think deeply about what you're going to
say especially when you're dealing with
the minister or you're dealing with an
ambassador of another country another
thing is you kind of look smarter when
you do that long little pause right so
try your best to just take a deep breath
and I did leave some time for questions
so we should have about 15 minutes to do
questions and I hear that if you ask a
question you can get a hat and who
doesn't like hats so thank you very much
and I'm open for questions
[Applause]
Chris that was absolutely fantastic my
mind is blown I have a lot of questions
but first we're gonna take some from the
audience so if you have questions raise
your hand and let's get this party
started
yes your what are the front okay hi
first of all great story just wanted to
ask let's say did eight year old no ten
year old I think you after hacking the
DOJ did it ever cross your mind in that
eight year old period from being ten to
being 18 and being able to use a
computer again basically did you ever
think you would actually be in charge of
handling such a massive event I guess
absolutely not I was so happy just to
use a computer again because I had made
so many dumb mistakes as a ten year old
me that I didn't think that I would be
involved in something like that I knew
at the time both when I was pen and when
I was 18 that I wanted to get into
computer science and I hated the fact
that during that eight year time period
I was not even allowed to use a gaming
console so I could only watch friends
and cousins who would always point it
out because they were little bastards
but I never thought that I wouldn't be
involved in something like this and
let's say having known that that would
have happened how would that had would
it have swayed you away from doing stuff
like this or would that just empower you
even more I would have been empowered
even more and I would have learned
French a lot better to deal with
diplomats which is one of my challenges
that I'm facing right now I need to
speak French more thankful
thanks thank you next question somewhere
there in the middle yes we see your
enthusiasm right right in front of you
nothing to keep your hands up yes
well get to everyone I promise hi I just
loved your presentation I'm not really
sure how you can go through all that and
still be so funny and so humorous
so congrats on that but you seem so
confident that I have to ask a question
were you at all at any time afraid for
your life and my second question would
be if you mentioned at some point that
they might use your partner for was your
partner used against you in in some way
and how so because my military
background I have to think that very
much for handling these particular
situations and I was trained for various
things like if I was kidnapped and held
hostage and things of that nature and at
one time in my life I actually was
kidnapped and held hostage for two and a
half week time period so this was a lot
simpler in many ways you know because I
wasn't you know being you know tied up
and gagged that that that sucked but I
also have the belief that I could be hit
by a bus
I could be hit by a car I could you know
not wake up tomorrow because I don't
know I might have some undiagnosed
medical issue so not not very much now
my partner was not targeted in this
particular case but because of this
incident on a later case a more recent
case actually he was placed under
surveillance by a foreign government but
he was prepared at the time whoa Thanks
okay next question here up front the mic
is coming to you then we're going to go
there in the middle well first of all
thank you very much for your
presentation and I'm just doing this for
the Hat no just so you mentioned there
are three Turkish intelligence that you
met in the bar and you taught them
English and so I'm curious how was the
interaction with them because you had to
actually give lessons right and you had
to do as if you didn't suspect anything
or how was that well I didn't have like
a lesson plan but we did conversational
English and they asked me a lot of very
interesting questions about things
especially dealing with the Saudi Aramco
infrastructure which I danced around
because these were very strange people
and they were trying to I think feel me
out also to distract me during this time
period which didn't work because you
know I knew everything that was going on
but it was just conversations long
conversations over tea at a pub which
was very strange but kind of
entertaining at the end now I can
definitely laugh about it thank you
we had a question there in the middle
yes please keep your hand raised so we
can get the mic to you
hello how would be your life without a
computer very boring
okay how did you fight with your demons
while not being able to use a computer
well I kind of turned it around so at
the time I had to take type writing
lessons of all things so I context like
a teenager so that's pretty cool I tried
to do other things but still keeping
track of what was going on in the
burgeoning computer industry at the time
so the day after I turned 18 I bought a
computer for myself well okay thanks
okay on to the next question the paint
guy he's been like raising his hand the
whole time
hey I was very curious about your
digital fingerprinting and how do you I
don't know how much you work on not
having so much mr. fingerprinting well
over the last seven years I was more
permitted and allowed to come out in the
world at a previous job so although I
don't have an actual Facebook account
I've got various fake ones and so forth
I I just try to know my surroundings
because I know that I am now a bit more
of a public person than I was before
seven years ago there was only one
picture ever of me on the Internet and
that was a LinkedIn picture so I just
watched myself I don't if I think that I
might be in a dangerous situation or I
might suspect certain things then I try
to divert where it might be and tried to
use precautions including checking out
the hotels that I stay at speaking with
their physical security staff as well so
I try to keep myself safe in that manner
and I have no I Oh t devices
and a commercial firewall at my house I
[Laughter]
do have yes yes this is my hobby up to
the next one
there's a question there so congrats
about the presentation so I'm a nervous
flier and I wanted to ask you about
something I read you uncovered some con
abilities in the bank network so I
wanted to ask about that what you can
you tell us about it
yes I can tell you a little bit about it
a couple of the things that I found on
bone were quite disturbing nowadays
aircraft are flying computers they're
driven by software they have autopilot
they also sensors and I was able to
because of egregious coding errors able
to bypass authentication to get into
both the live and test aviation ID
systems and that system for Boeing is
how you log in and you get flight
control software for classified
unclassified planes and also satellite
systems and that was part of what I
found I also found a way using
open-source intelligence to find all of
Boeing's fleets in the cockpit cabin
view monitoring system as well so
there's a few other things and I'll be
getting a lot of pressure from Boeing so
I'll be nice and leave it at that yeah
ok we have time for questions yes hi
thank you for the presentation and nice
to meet you I'm a journalist and you
mentioned that you are going to work
with reporters without borders on the
project to better protect journalists
can you tell us more about that and do
you from your experience have you seen
journalists being targeted do you think
it's increasing how do you think
journalists should because it's not
about only journalists about their
sources as well and how can journalists
if they don't know how to protect
themselves how can the
they're sources to protect themselves
thank you sure so the workshop is for
cybersecurity for journalists
specifically to discuss protecting
themselves and also their sources not
now not every journalist works for the
Guardian or the BBC or what have you and
gets security awareness training so a
lot of journalists especially
independent journalists are not so
cybersecurity savvy and when they get
documents and data from a source they
can actually get unfortunately targeted
and then that source gets found out
we've just heard if you've been
listening to the United States news that
Donald Trump's son outed the CIA analyst
who was the whistleblower which is as
far as I'm aware illegal but I'm not a
lawyer and it's imperative that we have
freedom of the press and I'm a big
believer of that so one of the things
that I do on the side is I work with
journalists and set up various trainings
for them to try to keep them safe
because I've been a source myself and I
would like to be kept safe in these
particular circumstances it's something
that I do pro bono so one last question
if anyone has them cuz with this I'm
going way back there all the way in the
back row wait for the mic keep your
hands up we're getting there
all those here thank you I enjoyed your
your speech oh stop so we can see you
okay okay thank you sorry I enjoyed your
speech very very much and I actually
like those kind of stories which which
imply diplomats and such things but my
question is do you believe that at the
moment of speaking there are other
diplomats or vvv IPS that still has such
a weak security and how people like you
try to prevent issues like the one in
your speech to happen again again uh yes
quite a few embassies from various
countries do have very weak security in
many cases the people hired at these
embassies are not a computer expert but
somebody who is from a high-ranking
family there's nepotism and so forth and
favors that are given not every country
does this luckily but some do and
absolutely I was speaking with a
minister from Luxembourg the week before
last about this particular topic which I
agreed to help on a few things
and this is not the only type of
incident that's happened within
diplomatic circles there are actually
much much worse incidents that have
occurred from cyber security issues of
food security which have actually cost
lives
thank you so much Chris once again this
was absolutely amazing
thank you thank you
[Applause]