I will start the presentation by just
providing you like the mandatory about
Me section after that I will talk about
the exploits change what are they then a
bit of even causation and process
monitoring so as you told me I'm a
research fellow at NTNU I'm also doing
my PhD from there I am like I receive
like an innovation innovation metal from
Interpol for developing future smart
cities concepts I am also a member of
their verdicts per group on smart city
placing I also involved in strategic
level policymaking in Norway and I also
really recently led their joint
civil-military team on cyber strategy in
a recent 912 challenge I am also
involved in the training of selection of
the national team for European cyber
security challenge
and in term of my serve game I have like
18 plus certification I think this is
which include LP d OS CPC so many I
don't remember how many but there are
many so what is their exploitation so an
exploit chain is a group of expert that
exhibited synchronously in order to
achieve the system exploitation like
high respond abilities they have system
exploitation using only one eyes
equation step and exploitation takes
advantage of multiple vulnerabilities
low and medium low risk on the abilities
to get the system level privilege or to
compromise it so when we see like a
single vulnerability exploitation we see
like they have like a very simple graph
so you just start identify visibility
like a major vulnerability like in an
assembly like it or not exploit it and
you will have like the priority of the
whole system so these are some of the
examples of like high risk of abilities
that can be exploited like within one
execution step but in exploit a change
you see like you find out when the
ability you exploit it but after you
exploit it you get a lot of data that
you use that data to identify other
explore other vulnerabilities and
explore them so like yesterday there was
like a micro zero day initiative was
going on so like the flow set
do you like again exploited
as perform like an explosion from
integer overflow in a JavaScript
retrieval of like an image from a
samsung phone through NFC communication
so we know these things like exploits
chains and what are they and how they
are being exploited in the wild but is
there a way to detect them because if
you detect like a single vulnerability
you know like this is like the
low-hanging fruit you can patch them but
in terms of explosions you have like
multiple low-hanging fruits that are
very hard to detect okay so even if you
patch like one vulnerability they can
find another so there was actually like
a very good work that was going on in
Japan shot so they released like a very
major report so this research is based
upon their report so if I have seen
further it is by standing on the
shoulders of this so they were actually
the Giants so I am giving them full
credit so they released this report in
like early 2017 about detecting lateral
movement within a network so this is a
very important report if you don't know
it like as a blue guy or as a forensics
guy then not doing it right
so in this report they talked about the
exploitation tools that are used by
different hackers like mimikatz
meterpreter and Metasploit and the type
of logs which they generate so they
created a very long list of logs windows
logs that are generated by the usage of
those tools the only problem with this
report is that they have like the
information about the logs that are
generated by free tools like Metasploit
and other but if you go for like bail to
like vaults like you can't get the
information of the logs that were
generated by them so if we think about
our priorities in terms of security
there is a lot of buzz about machine
learning and blockchain but I will show
you like the most important things are
the even logs as suggested by this me
this is the only memory in the whole
presentation so I am actually focusing
on the event log that is process
creation event so this is the
eventid force excited it did you can see
a lot of information was there in this
image log but how we can use this
informations so it have like new process
ID process name process ID command-line
arguments those were the main important
point of interests and from the same
report we got the information what type
of processes a hacker can use after like
an exploitation so these are some of the
major processes that if a system is
exploited a hacker can use to gain
further please like CMD PowerShell let
this be an under NDA later or you can
monitor any process if you want but
these are the major processes so I am
focusing when those processes so I
developed an algorithm they take the
information from the event logs and
collate the information with the
processes that are being running and I
didn't try to identify like some sort of
activity malicious activity from one
process to another process how he is
moving and how is he like exploiting the
vulnerabilities so this is a like an
algorithm is like a word used by
programmer when they do not want to
explain what they did so this was like
the algorithm looks like it looks a bit
scary maybe understandable so what it do
I took any like list of event logs what
ordered list of even logs and try to
identify like the information from them
I can explain it like in a very easy
manner so these are the ever locks and
these are the important process
information that we are looking for we
are looking for process ID new process
ID and process ID those are hexadecimal
values and both are unique so check this
event log you can see its new poor
society and process ID now if we go that
did you find anything similar if we look
through so that was like a CMB that was
like a partial process and there is a
like a CMD process and if you see like
this X process ID was actually the new
process ID of the CMD process so the CMD
process actually executed that of
PowerShell process if we go further down
in the row we have like a vmware
processor
so from that VMware process we can see
like that vmware process has a new
process ID of q70 and that executed like
a CMD process so we have like a chain
like a vmware it's hard to imagine that
a vm we are executing a CMD but i will
show you how they are doing this so they
have like very famous guest to host
exploit so even if you are monitoring
the vmware host guest running in it you
are not sure if somebody exploit there's
process isolation he can break the
vmware isolation and move into the host
OS but in the host OS the logs are
coming like in the recursive manner so
you see like the timeline is like this
first the vmware process was executed
after that CMD process was executed
after the powershell process but when
you are reading the logs from the even
logs you see you will read first the
partial process after that you will read
the CMD process after that you will read
the process so you have to read in a
backward manner so you have to look back
in time what is happening so when we get
our hands dirty a bit so there is like
example of like naturalness Dede he
follows the same suit I have like a
whole publication that is explaining
about the type of vulnerability there is
exploiting so you can see like which was
like a snapshot from processor so you
could see like PowerShell CMD and a
portion impaired we can from it and same
with the VMware so you can see the thing
like how it is moving you know no one's
seen are you not expect to happen but
yeah and it is like very raw log from
the detection algorithm like you can see
like how the expert chain is working how
the things are going one there so during
this testing or development of this we
needed some sort of zero today's exploit
to prove our point so there is like an
exploit of my products degree version so
what we did was like we weaponized in in
a PowerPoint
and uploaded it on virustotal and the
the verbalized version was like zero
detection but the PowerPoint was signed
by my name so there was a very famous
researcher from fireEye he detected that
represent of PowerPoint extract and then
he was actually tagging me on the
Twitter that is this guy's actually
exploding those things then like in July
this year I met one of his colleague
marina corte Olaf I think many of you
know him so I told her about that story
and then they like caught it like from
my impressive comment too much from
attribution to a witty sample and taken
down in stone so we can argue that like
our train of like way of testing the
thing works but you know things like you
know like there is some sort of activity
going on but what exactly the activity
is going on this thing in the whole
exploitation so you didn't see like the
processor moving up and down but what
are they are actually doing so if we
analyze the image log again we can see
that there was this command-line
argument we can get the information from
this command line argument so but we we
can see this come online report but
there are like google ways to like open
like a single calico XZ so you see like
you can open collect like this like this
like this like this like this it will
open can so it would like confuse the
defender this is like the research of
Josephus kitchen done by Daniel
beforehand so he provided like a whole
frame framework to like off escape
commands so even if you are like trying
to detect VI Kamala and I were to be
very hard because the commands will be
alpha scary if the attacker is like AB
it's not so it would be very hard for
you to detect it but here we can use the
good old machine learning because we
should use it where we can where it is
usable so this is like the data set from
radial the sofas kitchen shoes so we use
this data set in order to turn our
machine learning algorithm we identify
like four different classification
types on this we like live base elitism
and we were able to achieve like in most
of the classification categories in more
than 90 percent accuracy
so it was like a natural language
processing techniques in which we use
the bucket of words so it can like check
the words and match them from the
command so you can easily identify like
a lot of different categories these are
some of the results from the 50:14
classification techniques from porsche
powershell uninstalling software using
the logs like my binary planting and
stuff like that so you can use this
machine learning techniques very well in
this context so I made this research
public and everything is accessible in
two publications the first was like in
San Francisco where I discussed the
windows-based expert can guess to
exploit with VMware research head and
the second was also in Romania it was
like combining of this natural language
processing techniques on the algorithms
on the image logs so why would take so
much effort in this technique because
there are a lot of same solutions and
what you called like like stuff like
this that doing a lot of stuff but but
we I am actually working on Norwegian
cyber range it's like a 7 million euro
project so in which we do a lot of
cybersecurity exercises for those
cybersecurity exercises like in normal
scenario you use like flags like
hexadecimal values there is a static
that an hacker can get them and put them
in a scoreboard and receive that points
but the way that technique which I
implemented is getting the event logs
from different device different devices
present within a city of platform and
from those even logs can identify the
movement of like the players like how
they are moving how the Explorer are
using and what type of techniques they
are using after that we can score them
automatically based upon the things
thank you
[Applause]
thank you for your presentation now are
there any questions I'm just gonna go to
the closest one to man thanks for the
presentation awesome stuff
love the Bitcoin sticker really cool and
you have such a great curriculum so my
question would be more personal and
based on your presentation like you did
so much stuff what was like the most
mind-blowing thing that you have done in
new world Korea so I social engineer my
way to get a photo so that was a very
interesting photo so we were in like
very isolated place in Finch sake so
there was like the cryptographer heavens
like addition Meade was there John
diamond was there and all the
cryptographic words were there so when
he was presenting he studied his
presentation he took like a selfie for
his girlfriend after his presentation I
asked can you give me that he said no
you have to take that constant of
everybody do gdpr I said okay so we were
there like for a week so in Norway when
we have like lunch or dinner we said
together and then somebody have to like
pour water in everybody glass so what I
did was I took the mood glass of water
with me and pour water in everybody
class except me is for two days he was
so not happy with that and he just gave
me by the way I can show you that for if
you want hi so not not yet but we open
sourced it so anybody can use it
okay yeah we have a lot of false
positive but you know like it is
currently used for like scoring purposes
but maybe in future maybe we use it like
for actual detection
hello thank you for the presentation my
question is for you personally what is
the most operating system that has the
most security vulnerabilities or
exploits I can't answer these questions
because it's all depends upon the user
yeah how he is using it thank you any
more non-debatable questions hi so my
question is the machine learning that
you use for natural language processing
or only work on command lines or exactly
do you use natural language to detect
malware because yeah so when you use
like like normal machinery it actually
divides the words into small chunks okay
small bites so you can have like a
matching scheme with those buts
so it have like allocate a percentage to
those how much percent this chunk of
bytes match with those chunk of bytes in
order to classify according to the given
requirements so you have like a
classifier that specify the things so
language part comes in I mean the
technique is like this so when we speak
to our phone like for it convert into
like text so that text is actually being
classified based upon some set of
criteria so this is like the same thing
but in term of like translating English
from a phone I used like malicious cow
commands data set from danger boom and
run and to train in this data
so my classifier was trained on those
malicious commands not okay I think I
get it Thanks any more questions
I could you please tell me what is the
latest strand in Windows abilities there
is like used to be like a very I don't
know people know about it there was like
an expert like eternal it has like a
derivative I don't know most people know
about it at the eternal romance if your
system is not configured lightly people
can do a lot of stuff right now
the name was quite good any more
questions in terms of your software once
once you've deployed it onto a network
it'll take event logs from all the
computers around the network does it
then have does it have any protection at
this stage or is it just information
informational return that comes back to
you so I forgot to talk about it so when
you have to like domain environment like
an Active Directory environment you can
get all the logs from the like the
systems ok then you can process the
information the limitation of the
software was like that it can like works
on like maybe three have set of 300
computers so now we can host like in our
cyber and we can host I can exercise
roughly 300 parties but it can work on
that but if you put it like an
enterprise environment where there are
like millions of nodes or maybe like
hundred thousand nodes that's where it
will feel like in seconds your
application just just just currently
just for scoring for making like things
like that guy was there so we can look
at some point automatically so we can
have like a track of like people who are
like actually moving within the network
like students so if you compare it with
the real scenario if you have a hacker
in your network so you can track the
activity that how is moving laterally
within the network