we are welcomed to
have the opportunity to share the
research findings
of our team on highly revolvers
today our talk is called x in the media
attacking function charging pairs and
electric
records
first of all please allow us to
introduce
ourselves briefly and we
i'm a senior security researcher at the
disneyland team
now i'm mainly focusing on iot
security research and also about hunter
winner of kiplan and speaker of
blackheart.com
taking both catawas and plc
and the other is my teammate
he is also a senior security researcher
disability
now he is focusing on mobile security
and
lg security he reported military
vulnerabilities
of chrome and android he also was
speaker of
blackheart.com casa west haggis box
an attention breaking was funded by
tencent security platform department
now we are focusing on security research
in the areas of
airt and cloud virtualization
we have reported more than 200
availabilities
to render such as google and from
microsoft
and amazon and if you
want to know more about our team's
research
you can visit our blog
let's move on today's topic i want to
talk is many different kids into four
parts
first part we will introduce the
electric
car charging technology and standard
the second part we will announce that
the attack surface of
negative charging in the third part we
will introduce what is x in the media
attack and finally we will introduce how
we
attack the pack and charge technology in
the real world
as everyone knows early speed expansion
of
electric car markets and promoted
the construction of the charging
instance
infrastructure dc charging is the main
charging technology in the future it has
higher charging power and in order to
confirm the charging voltage
and current the electric weaker and
the charging station will communicate
after being connected
to complete the handshake
there are different charging standards
in different
countries for example one negative car
in china must support the gpg standard
united car use compass to communicate
with charging pairs we are in most
part of euro ccs
standards are used and the electric
cars and charging pairs use a plc
to communicate with the exception of the
testnet
who has either on supercharger network
over the world
it uses a private communication protocol
in addition we also want to talk about
why we choose to study the
electric charging skills
the main reason that we find the
electric
records infrastructure is making
progress
towards a more intelligent more high
power
direction the construction
of the charging station is accelerating
all over the world but there is nettle
or research on the security of electric
vehicle infrastructure
in following section we will briefly
align the
attack surface of electric recurve
charging
first of all uv charging pairs
are also lt devices
which uranium have built in system
and operating interfaces we are facing
securities
in hardware systems platform
servers and communications
and our focus is on the security of the
communication
protocol between the neck cheek weaker
and the charging pad
this will be a new and interesting
exploration
the following picture shows the process
of
charging a car at a dc charging station
charge control communicates with the
and ms before charging to confirm the
parameter such as charging
voltage and current which
involves a lot of data exchange
so if we can implement a main
media attack we may be able to find
the vulnerabilities in vms
and the charging controls through body
or we can
analyze provides vertical
and bypass identity authentication
mechanism
or we can damage the car by temporary
with the charging voltage and current
next we will show the section about x in
the media attack
first we will talk about its
architecture
then we will talk about the challenges
and solutions
we encountered in the testing process
and finally we will share the quick test
conclusion
on tesla supercharger
in order to conduct security tests in
symphony and cabriony
we have given a tool called xcharger
the core of exchanger is a data
processing terminal
based on html mcu
or respect respiratory
which has united canvas message from dms
and the charging files all compass
message
cannot be transmitted normally until
they are transferred
through x charges which allow us to
mandatory
functioning and temporary combust
message
in your charging process
another feature is that we descend the
whole tour into a
20 inch bridge case
which has two charging circuits
one is connected to the charging pair
and the other is connected
to the negative weaker and the
high voltage current is directly
connected
and the only four com compass
communicates interface i exported to
ensure the
high voltage safety
next let's talk about why we do this and
the china chains we face when we do
security research
the most important thing is that
it should be able to ensure the
personal safety and the weaker safety
this charging can reach a voltage
of up to 750 watts
or a current of 120 mp
once the shoot once a short current
accuracy is very dangerous for the test
and the car secondly
we hope the attack equipment should be
honey
complex comfortable suitable for
all electric vehicles with chinese pc
charging standard
instead of requiring customers
customization for each blend of electric
cards
or charging pairs we also find the
compact communication
requires no latency and many media
attacks
into to ensure the brains
we are not good job
we rented a tesla module for testing
and we found that its charging port
exported
the command interface with a separate
stack which means
that we may be able to discard
disconnect
the origin connection in the trunk
to achieve a main media attack
but the problem is that may need
to the night damage which doesn't
seem sweet for such a operation on a
limited record
in addition we have also thought about
transforming tesna's
gb dc adapter for pocket
capture but we believe that these
also have a security risk and
this doesn't apply upland
to other records
a perfect solution we have given is the
equipment
shown below you can see that
it has two charging circuits
one end is connected to the inaudible
the other end is connected to the
charging connector
the compass interface of bmis
and the cameras interface of the
charging pair
are all exported are all exported
on the surface and at the same time
we have customers uh storage
plug charging cable to connect
the equipment under the car this
equipment is designed by us
and made by professional windows
in shenzhen china which can ensure the
safety of
high water age power use
there are many open source tools
available for
combat the mandatory buzzing and
temporary
to use both the raspberry pi and the
two-way cam
extension board we can use
python to develop a test for
testing from work on the built-in ubuntu
system and due to the limited
time we will release more details and
codes in the future
we use exchange to do a quick test
on interest not supercharged in china
and the test
results verified that the device can
capture the message steps funny but we
do not have
any more test just because we do not
have
the dbc file to translate the combust
message
we found that some of the message in
commerce
compass communication between
supercharger and waterstream
use a private verticals and some message
conform to the gpg standard
when testing with the modestry they are
a
high property that it will not be
able to charge successfully the reason
is still being unaddressed if you want
to
so if you want to reverse the complete
protocol it may be a bad choice to
analyze
the firmware of bms or supercharger
in addition to the superstar
supercharger
we spend more time in public charging
stations
in following part we will share how to
attack the
track and charging technology
in public charging stations in china
first we will introduce the print simple
of pack and charge
and how to use x charge to attack it
to achieve free charging finally
we will give some security otherwise and
briefly announce that
the future change of charging technology
black and chart is a new way of
automating
payment for ebay charging users do not
need
to sweep their cards or scan codes
just connect the charging pair to the
weaker
charging port to automatically
complement
the identity authentication payments
that build their own charging pairs
such as the test nut priority
communication
and authentication protocol can be used
to
ensure that security of plug can charge
and there are different implement
implementation
of plug and charge
the plan a is install a camera near the
charging panel to verify the
record lessons plans for
authentication the plan b is install
a rfid tag at the position of the
electric recoil charging circuit
and read the target content for
authentication when the charging gun
connected
the fancy the sdk is the
sdk provided by a charging power
operator
is built into the intelligent system of
nitric vehicles and the authentication
is
automatically complete complicated
when the weaker reach the
charging station and open the charging
cover
another last plan is the weakest
wheel number is transmitted for
authentication
during the charging candlestick process
considering the capability
and cost some public
charging stage operators have chosen
to use rear end to complete
recall identity authentication on basis
of
gpt standard operators
do not realize the via is a
security is not a security
authentication in a insecure
combust communication gpt standard is
the chinese standard for electrical
recoil battery
charging camber charging standard
gpg is based on sae
and uses the campus with a
point-to-point
connection between the charger and the
battery
manager system a transmission rate of
250 kbits per second
is used by default
charging communication involves both
vms and the charging control
with the gpg protocol communication
is divided into following parts during
the
charging process
in the handshake because recognization
the charging connection check is
complimented
and general information such as protocol
vision and
vehicle information for example the
battery temp weaker and dedication
number
and so on is changed what
we are most concerned about is
that during the handshake
the bmx will transmitted the vm number
to the charging pair
after actual testing we use contours
and the dbcpr to successfully translate
all messages during the charging process
we found the emails of electro record
transmitted
the request we end to the charging pair
for a direct case
for identity authentication in yame
in the brm message during the handshake
reconnaissation
the following is the complete plug and
charge the
architecture first the car owner needs
to register and abandon the weaker
server number on
charging pair operators application
and the accept and expert
automatically impairment secondly
when the car owner is charging he only
needs
to direct an implant and
charging gun into the magnetic
card to charge the charging pair
will apply upload the wheel
transmitted from the vms to
operators to the operator's
cloud server under the operator we have
query and
return the user's credence
crescent corresponding
to the vn in the background database
after the charging pair reserves the
user's
credence it will it will
start charging and automatically pay
pay at the end of the chart
weaker authentication number is a unique
code
include including a three number used
by optimal automotive
industry to 20
and the intervention workers
the biggest problem is we are in
either public blind text information
with specific coding rulers and can also
be
obtained from the front or in the shade
of the car
in order to configure the attack spree
script uh quickly we have
written a tool that it means the
function
includes the temporary of
wear and charging voltage and current
it also supports the vms termination
so that we can test the charging panel
with the other weaker
the following is the ruler
of exchange in the attacks process
it can catch the message
between the card and the charging pair
in order to verify our tours
in the real world we wanted five
electrical cars
of different models and the test
new temporal charging stations that
support
plaque and charge we verified that
after obtaining the after overturn
we end on the windshield of the weaker
the charging pair can be successfully
attached by exchange
to achieve free charging
and now all of the availability
we found have been notified to the
renter and
fix it okay
my party is over the following time will
be shared
by my college
thank you thanks i will continue to
share the following part
in this part i will give some security
otherwise
and introduce some of the latest
charging standards
but charging pies operators can display
a risk
control system to crack off battery
information
such as battery time capacity
manufacturers product status
battery pack serial numbers numbers of
charge transmit during the charging
handshake process
of vehicles that use the plug and charge
function
and generates the corresponding
electricity
we are called fingerprint information
since the attacker cannot knows the
detailed battery informations of the
target vehicles in other words
simply tampering with the vrn cannot
pass the fingerprint information
verification and the risk control
systems can
acquire it detects the attacks and
black it the first plane other one
is low cost no need for additional
hardware modification and its
disadvantage
is because part of the battery
information such as
battery pack stereo number charging eye
charging times is an optional
transmission
items in gbt27930
and part of the battery information of
the
of the specific models is public
so the risk control systems may not be
able to
crack enough information to insure
security
for the two-way authentication scheme
charging
price operators need to code
operates with electricity vehicles
manufacturers to
ensure security this may
require adding a public key transmission
function to uh
to the vehicle's vms from various
or implementing a
new fails communication function need
the between the vehicles and the
charging pipe
of use a specific provide protocols for
communication
advantage very secure you can
mitigate mitigate the risk of
middle attack disadvantage high cost
not compatible with all vehicles
according to the new the next generation
charging standard
charity dominated by china and japan
will be officially released it is
improving the security of
many communications and identity
authentication
challenge charting support plus and
trust
v2x and other new technology
applications some of the security risks
mentioned in our talks may be reserved
in addition we also see another new
standard
iso 1511a
is a standard for vehicle to create
communication
use symmetric encryptions
and digital snatchers
to ensure the securities of
communication
between electric cars and charging
stations
and supports plug and charge it use plc
communications
which is mainly used in europe
through the discussions of these trains
we are very happy to see that security
has become
must be considered in
these standards we believe that
in the near futures when these new
technologies and new standards applies
in the real world
they will promote the security
developments of
the entire electric vehicles charging
industry
okay that's all thank you for listening
and if you have any questions you can
contact the by this email