hello everyone today we are going to
share our
writing practice of how to attack our
native kubernetes
as you can see the trend of cloud native
and containerization is coming rapidly
security issues are becoming
increasingly prominent
in this talk firstly we will introduce
the attacks
against the cloud container
infrastructure and new challenges to the
right team
then we will show the details of
different attack techniques
and finally we are going to show the
attacks we encountered
during the construction of the clone
native right team
in addition to let everyone get started
with
container penetration we will also
introduce our open source container
exploitation tool
called cdk according to the honeypot
data we collected from
different cloud vendors in 2020 we can
see that
attacks on traditional visual machines
are growing slowly
however attacks on container
infrastructure are
increasing swiftly because on the one
hand container instances are growing
rapidly
on public cloud on the other hand
we do found some bot nights are
spreading
using the vulnerabilities of containers
based on the data we observed on the
cloud
we noticed that botnets have increased
their attention to continual
vulnerabilities
in the past two years of the 25
cloud oriented bot knights observed in
about 28 percent have its own container
is priced
and the proportion reached 53 in this
year
the figure on the right represents
several common attack measures
and representative one night families
including the well-known
docker hub backdoor image and
unauthorized
excise to the public interfaces of
docker and kubernetes cluster
it is worth mentioning that we found
that
in 2020 a bot knight called borg
has integrated darker escape
vulnerabilities
and the ability to produce kubernetes
lateral movement
attacks which means that attackers have
paid more attention to the automated
exploitation
of the container environment
while the infrastructure used by
enterprises is going to change
the right team's tax skills must also be
innovated
right teams generally divide their
positions into two categories
the positions in the production network
and the positions in the office network
for traditional adc environment the
basic
goal of penetrating production network
is to get a shell of a server and then
we use
different skills to collect the
information such as
house live detection for scanning and
produce the lateral movement to get
other targets
but now when enterprises view
applications on call native kubernetes
after writing obtaining the shell of the
production network through application
vulnerabilities
is quite different from pawnee and idc
server this time you will get a shell in
a container with a slim
environment and limited local resources
at this time if the right team does not
understand
the security design and implementation
of
cloud cognitive technology it will be
hard to get the knife stage
on the other hand the measures of attack
personal computers in office network
are similar to the traditional skills
but the lateral movement from pc to
production network will be very
different
in idc staff usually depend on pam
jam servers and other devices that use
ssh
to log in and manage servers but now
different applications are running in
containers and
use kubernetes for deployment scaling
and management
developers are no longer use ssh for the
operation
but full code ctl or secondary
development tools
like dashboard with the web console
so the target of the write team on pc is
searching the configuration file
instead of the credentials of ssh or
jam server of course with the rise of
devops technology
writings can attack the internal devops
platform to get their job done
these changes also brought new
challenges to the writing
before arbitrary files with high
permissions were almost
equivalent to rce on linux but this
is no longer the case in containers the
information
life circle and permissions of the
container shell
are extremely limited in many cases
we don't have the permission to execute
some commonly used commands
such as p trees s trees and you even
need to
install duplicate and curl
at the same time kubernetes will bring
new container network
dns and security features
obviously the red team needs
new knowledge skills and tools
okay next we are going to show a
practical
attack technique everything starts
with a shell or container you can get a
container shell
from some pfc application
by a vulnerability like a pip unit
remote code execute cve 2017-9841
after this you will encode a different
environment
from the idc your purpose
is to get more permissions of the entire
service
such as opting permissions of other
containers
and parts escape to the current node
of kubernetes updating the master node
obtaining the api server an email
obtaining the cloud
account where the hosting cluster
is located the attack service
of the cloud native ka workloads
is based on what resource can be
assessed
by the container shell we got in
kubernetes network
in it is for kubernetes container
network
you can access more parts
of other product container parts
of the kubernetes service parts
of the current node and other node
the service of the masternode and the
compiledness
service of kubernetes in the past
our goal were mostly the agent
mast server database of the ss password
or it automation master controller
server
and so on include it but not limited to
solder stacks matcher and support master
but in the kubernetes network
this kind of centralized power is
unified
into api server obtaining
the main punches of the api server on
the root commissions
of the master node we'll announce the
end of the war
container escape is like the red team
will try
first after getting a shell of container
as so on this page we cash out an ic
vulnerability
in a possible grass sql container
we can only obtain a limit process list
and permissions restricted by secret
and knee space to better understand the
method of a container escape
you should know that the process in the
container
is essentially just a normal process of
linux
all the behaviors of the process inside
the container
are transparent to the host
therefore nature of the container escape
is very different
from hardware virtualization
vm escape executing qatar container
in my option the process of container
escape
it led a registry process obtained and
restricted
full permissions occating
more privilege for process originally
restricted
by the group and in space it is
much more closer to the privileged
escape relation in the linux host
if you cannot escape in current
container
you may have to think about other gods
in the ka
network normally you try to get
the following types of information
information about the current node
which net space the current pod is
located is that default netspace
where is the current port what is the ip
subnet
of the node server ka service and
custom info can also be helpful in order
to
let everyone understand the service and
need space
better and service then as based on
this tool here are two simple examples
the thing as usual contact about will be
present in every ka custom by default
which correspond to the kubernetes
service under the default space
and point to the api server of the
current cluster
when i create a new namespace need
attention and then
create a service named force the
following thing as you call
will be generate you can rather the yam
of config file
used to create the service on the right
side
this yammer file comes from k8 default
service
native kubernetes the four things as
recorded on the up left are all point to
this service as mentioned above we can
easily obtain
the next base information of the current
pod
in the dns configuration similarly
we obtain a service ip or product ip
we can also easily use the dns revocab
to obtain the corresponding port name
service name
and next base name later we will
introduce multiple attacks against node
server of ka
and the it information of the current
node server
will be obtained from the arp cache
tables
from the current container the default
service
and the currency terminate space such as
the privacy
version kubernetes service in
different space an ip point
by kubernetes can also be used
to infer the ip subnet of ka service
which is the avaya information you can
start
host discovery and pod scanning
of course if you want to carry out this
kind of behave
you need to know the rule of the
security system
used by the tech company in your device
such as hids egr and an ids
and the normal circumstances if you have
the rule the permissions of the
container the method of
post scanning is almost the same as the
traditional idc what you need
to pay attention is if the ke cluster
use services
such as istio then translation
method will bring a wrong result
how to judge whether the cluster is
using istio
or not you can use cpk-run
steel check to detect the noun
it is detection logic is based on sto
inject
into the metadata of the http
request header according to the metadata
and decode you can even get a lot of
information about current pod and the ka
cutter
which is difficult for you to get on the
ordinary ka network
the picture on this page descripts why
the istio network is special
all your requests the sponsor will be
hijacked
proceed and management via the sidecar
container
of istio the request you send
the response you receive will be changed
if you want to perform point scanning
in istio network we think
the best practice is to use
tools like a map only use
icmp feature to do host discovery
and determine whether the point is open
by the application layer
detection after obtaining the disaster
of the pod scanning which service
are noting my words the results we got
can be divided into three types
pause on ka products
pause on node server
and products from kubernetes service
this page shows a lower of each key
component
when user execute commands with couple
code
including api server kubernetes docker
ka dashboard kuber code policy
support command and etcd the draw of the
components
cross-bound to resist if loss
service are controlled by
the drive team and those components
are easy to unauthorize configurations
in the private network
except the bus obtaining
the certificate api keyed password
and token about ka composer end
in the private net is also the way we
are going
if you really cannot find a target in
the private
network you may try the cloud native
api gateway all the current
cloud network api gateway open source
solution
do not have a complete authentication
function
like lex ka with the feature of the
phoenix ability dynamical and remote
config
many project of solution in the open
source branch
can access the main api in the remote
the second most popular api gateway
project api six have a
default access key and the drive team
can easily get a shell by running a
lower code
when we control api gateway we can
connect
controller and hijack the node source
trafficker
which is the management by cloud native
cluster more importantly obtaining the
api gateway
can break through the elimination of
network isolation
and get access of the other private
network
and public network the same reason
for container escaping
after the relative of tens
custom permissions generally
they are not certified which are only
obtaining the permissions of pods and
containers
the dreaded team will create posts and
containers start with privilege
to obtain node permissions
which are used to obtain the full
permissions
for container process and node process
you can use the node select label
to select the target node server
and get a router except
the master node if you want to find some
credential
of a cloud account you can find it
in a following patch the multi-files
the kubernetes search by cooper code get
yammo
result the hardcore ak in project
the etcd the cloud platform
features the cloud metadata api
and the ka port in master node
now we are gonna show a real world case
option red
team in 2020 which contains a lot of
command native
and container related knowledge
this time our goal is a company engaged
in the financial industry
all their online applications and office
applications
are all running on kubernetes
they hope assess their overall security
commercial results
from the public networks to the private
network
it is no end at employees not using
phishing
but only using vulnerabilities
to obtain their custom permissions
which are any interaction with staff
we found that they built a sales
developer
jewish house system so that employees
can work at home and only a mobile
device
this is our first breakthrough
after investigation we found that all
the private domains
of the target company are all in the
subdomain which is inaudible and some
private domain
can be also be placed on the public
network
they are all in the scenic recon point
to a gateway on the public network
just like below but
if the red team directly access the
private oa domain
from the public network in a browser
it will return completed which http
senders code 403
other http requests from staffs
in the tech company want to pass the
gateway
and access the oe website for work
two things are required one is the vpn
and the others is the session token
indicating the staff's identity
in the http request copy
about the staff identity because the 80
credentials
of the employees my bookstores cracking
of the microsoft
server active sync which is exploited
on the public network however
we have been unable to get the
application of the
private vpn cad for a long time
we began to analyze the security issues
in this design imagine that
zgateway.inner.com
is open on the public network
with the method of releasing the source
ip
of the http request is that
vpn client important so that
i try to file the http request that we
send to
zero trust gateway and set some htv
head values to different parameter ip
such as the client ip head about forward
and remote adr in the end
i found that when htv requests sent to
literal charts gateway carry which
the tar forward 4 http header
and the value is a private network ip
salvage chain then we can access the oe
login page
coupon with the employee identity
that we got in the microsoft
service activity sync now we can access
the network
of the text oa
the office network is a new world after
long explorations we finally found a new
breakthrough
in web service for serverless
domain name is serbless.inno.com
when the url of a new
jit project is provided to the web
service
serverless service will have a public
container
to clone and download the project code
install dependencies and refactor
this is a very imagined native feature
for us
we found that there are several ways to
get a shot in this container
first container inject
in url permanent wing data clone execute
second when install node.js depends in
package
construct a special package.json file
to control the public container using
methods such as
pre-installed also evo
python package and using the low-level
issues of city chrome
to the several modules and go get
can get a shout too
all in all we got the jewelry shell
of this public container and found that
this container starts with system
autonomy capability
there are many escape methods suitable
for this type of container
now you can use our open source tool cdk
to detect and escape such container
easily use cdk evaluate
to detect capabilities and use cdk
run rewrite c group device or cdk
run multiple separate commands to escape
this container
now we can access files and get a shell
in the node server of the public
container great
we know that all ages
that acting on containers should
run only host cytaka containers
or democratic containers which privilege
we define lots of self-developer areas
on this host and we found a very
interesting
agent named xiaoi web
console agents and got his binary
project cmd lights and config files
the program is written by golem
and we know that this agent is to
support
web console filters how does
the develops in the target
company manage layout containers
it is a short the web console filter
that you can call bash in the container
to execute commands in the web console
the agent will listen on port
the following http request
concrete instruction of document
exec subcommand
in the end the agent actually called
the default local unix socket
of docker you can see a simplified
process
of creating a web console structure in
the lower left corner
of this page but
how do we get all the content ids with
6-4 character on each server
this is obviously impossible
but the man who was using docker
container
loser we can repay the entire
container id by using the first
field ticket of the container id
in docker unique socket this feature is
also separate
for example if only two containers
only host like below
one i put in four months ago
the other one exists in two days ago
or their container id start with c
request
of the dividend container id will return
different results
including the following three users
container id multiple container id not
for
i did not study so we can use
docker sort id feature too fast
or container sort id on or no server
of kubernetes culture
since we can get a shell of all
containers
on the kubernetes clusters
now we focus on another agent
it is an agent that connect
logs it use
demo set to deploy
and drunks k a node servers
it use a k a demo set
yaml file like this
this is almost the default setting
in the official level of electric bits
many extreme many escape tricks can
work here it is both privileged
to mount the route directly to the
container
for logging obviously we only need to
use
the 3333 part
of the web console agent about
to control the container style by this
data set
and is capable to get a root shell for
any noticeable
unleash them said issue let all
kubernetes
notice run a copy of the pot
all nodes of this cluster are in our
grasp
now in the end
we achieve our goal and we can control
all the resources
of the tech company on the cloud
here are some simple tips first
we should pay attention to the
kuberconfig
file and its permission
second it's important to
obtain the security id and security key
of the cloud api
third in this case we call the master
node sha
and the admin cover configure files
of ka cluster in the last
fourth after escape the nodusha
allowed us to do more things
finally although we did not have a cdk
at that time it is much more conveniency
to use tools like cdk
okay by now we talk a lot about how to
identify and exploit container
vulnerabilities
which is quite a common problem in
writing
so with that problem in hand and
particularly think about the automation
we created a tool called cdk
writing go and release as a bannery
it's not a framework it's a binary to do
the autopilot stuff
inside a container or kubernetes part
it helped us to perform container recon
then use pulse exploitation and later
movements in kubernetes cluster
and i did make the github repo public
available
so you can find its price and examples
over there
it contains three main functional
modules
after we hack into the container upload
the cdk into that container and then we
use the evaluate command to find the
weakness
in current environment it will
automatically
obtain the fingerprint sensitive
information and vulnerabilities inside
the container
then we can search for corresponding
exploits
based on the weakness evaluated by the
tool
the sprite model integrates dozens of
commonly used container attack exploits
which can automatically complete
operations
such as container escape extraction
projections and lateral movement in the
kubernetes cluster
in addition we also restored some linux
commands
and network tools commonly used in pen
testing
to facilitate the penetration process
in any slim container image
in the current major release we added a
lightweight version for cdk
it's prepared for short live container
shells
such as serverless and functions we
added build tags in source code
and cut a few is priced to make the
binary lighter
just a 2mb file but contains
90 percent of cdk employees
you may also pick up useful splice in
cdk source code
to build your own lightweight binary
so that's a brief introduction of how to
attack cloud native kubernetes
thank you for your time and the slides
will be available
on conference white side hope you enjoy
watching it
any feedbacks or new ideas about
container exploitation you can post it
to online chat box
or create an issue in our github project
again thank you so much