thanks for inviting me to this
uh ask me anything conversation
no of course no and that's why it's
going to be fun
right so exactly exactly we'll we will
start with something easy first okay
we'll start with the easy ones first
also i love the fact that when we when
we talk about security stuff we
kind of grow into philosophical issues
uh which are really my thing so i really
look forward our conversation today
okay we'll try and like start off with
some easy ones first okay bro
uh maybe you guys what you might want to
tell the audience a little bit about
uh what have you guys been up to for the
last one year because um i'm guessing
for most people staying at home their
jobs have changed
entire world has changed like nobody's
flying anywhere anymore
and so what's new with you know with the
bounty stuff man i mean
how hard you guys been adapting to that
and how is it well
well uh this is an interesting question
because it's a it's a mixed
bag you know um the pandemic
on one hand created a lot of issues
especially logistic issues
we couldn't travel we couldn't meet in
person we couldn't see people
attend to events sponsor events
and then go and you know
have a face-to-face
relationship with people which in our
field
is extremely important but
and you know it is better than anyone
because
you're organized one of the of the best
events
uh worldwide um but
on the other hand people adapted very
quickly
to the new uh work from home
stuff especially in our field where
basically that's what people do anyway
so i would say that
apart from the pleasure of meeting
people in person
that sometimes also helps to create
stronger relationships
[Music]
the business for us worked
as usual and honestly
i must say that we had more time
uh and therefore we could focus on more
things and we did
more things last year than in the
previous year
so as i said it's a mixed bag this as
you said
the world has changed and probably this
change at least to a certain degree
would be
would be permanent it's difficult to
think that we will
go back exactly to where we were
one year and a half ago
but for us it was not such a big trauma
you know not only that but by
freeing up time and resources
uh we could focus also on
something new or something different so
we took the chance
to you know uh think better
because we were less in a hurry less
you know jumping from here and there
from one plane to another and so on so
for me uh and this is of course just my
personal experience of this of this
tragedy which is
and was the pandemic for me in the end
it was a time for thinking better
and to plan and to
do more so that's fine
i mean with when it comes to bug hunting
though right like i mean in the past
i would guess that you would go and
physically see the
the bug hunter right at night you would
probably get
some kind of like face-to-face
discussion with them or how is that
changed i mean i we're talking about you
know kind of expensive
code right they're worth quite a lot if
you are talking about zero yeah
absolutely
absolutely absolutely but since this
was something that didn't happen only to
us but happened to
everybody in the world at the same time
so psychologically speaking
at first everyone was was taken off
guard
by this problem and then with the
different speeds people managed to find
a
compromise or new approach to
things um i must say that
i think we were very quick to adapt also
because we are used to
work with researchers through our
platform
the so-called brh vulnerability research
up therefore of course
it's nicer sometimes to meet people in
person but
some other times they don't even want to
meet
so everything happens through the
platform or through
online channels anywhere so right so
in your case i mean with uh much
different
because you have the platform right so
what is
sorry i couldn't hear you can you say oh
no i'm saying that the with crop fans
right like so the fact that you guys
have your
vulnerability platform that makes a big
difference right because all of the
communications can take place through
the platform which is secure
so it didn't need to have okay so
in my dreams in my dreams it's like that
in fact it doesn't happen some people
prefer to
contact us through other means
so we receive uh you know nuclear grade
proposals for for assets on whatsapp
and this is of course wrong
or basically should be avoided so
in our vision
the rear age is safe enough so that
even if at the beginning at the early
stages of a negotiation
the part the researcher can be anonymous
and this anonymity is strongly enforced
by the platform
then if we go into a deeper conversation
and we find interested parties for
acquiring that asset then of course we
will need to
to grow each other better
if this happens to the platform this
happens in a relatively
safe environment and i'm saying
relatively because of course nobody is
100 secure
nowadays but we think it has a
good enough level of security anonymity
encryption and so on um
[Music]
when the contacts come from other
channels we try to bring them to the vr
age
and sometimes we succeed sometimes we
don't
of course we cannot force people to talk
with us only through the real age that
would be
wrong because of course we respect
everybody's needs and and
and you know approaches
to opsec and to security
uh but yes having the platform for us
is a big advantage and especially during
this
past year and a half
basically we had the same number of
submissions as the previous years
now this is super interesting because
you know if you go to uh
hagen box amsterdam and you offer
a super cool party and 500 people attend
and then they see you know the logo they
see the brand
they see you blog so maybe they would be
attracted by by working or collaborating
with us
and maybe they will subscribe to the
viewer age and submit
their research this is how it worked
before
now without being able to do these
school parties
unfortunately or to be in person
in these events
more or less we receive the same number
of submissions
because of course of course people there
working from home people
also researchers had a lot of time
because they were in lockdown or they
couldn't go out and start so
i don't know it's uh for us really uh
i understand that we are in a very niche
very vertical and small
field and that for the majority of
others the
impact of this terrible
health issue uh global health issue was
was
was very bad in our case
we were already working from home we
were already working remotely we were
already
using the best possible tools
to connect and discuss and negotiate
very sensitive things uh
so it wasn't such a big deal
of course everything has changed i agree
with you that
uh this is a huge huge blow
to the previous uh state of things to
the previous um
world so to speak the simple fact that
now we are having this conversation
on zoom instead that having it face to
face
in a nice venue is also a consequence of
that right but still we want to do it
and so we
with enough resilience and
you know enough
creativity we can overcome anything
especially in our fear
well hackers right
what do you think i mean for you it was
uh
definitely a different story right uh
but um yes i think that we managed to
find a to adjust
and then we will see what happens in the
next months i'm confident that things
will go back to normal but
the normal would be different from
before
[Music]
and so just coming back to like talking
about bugs right and bug hunting in
general right
i would say that things have kind of
like evolved wouldn't you say that in
the
earlier days right it'd be a one guy
could probably find
a significant exploit but maybe today
that's no longer the case because
there's so many defense mechanisms in
place that
one person can't fuss everything under
the sun right
absolutely yes you see what's happening
is that
this market is now differentiating
uh depending on the class
of target that we are talking about
so while before there were uh
so-called low-hanging fruits everywhere
so you could find them in mobile devices
in desktop pcs server
computers and also in networking gear
everywhere
it was more or less the same level of
insecurity but now we have to deal with
a world where certain classes of devices
uh so i in impressive
increase of their uh security
in the past two years three years
uh because the vendors finally
and and i say finally even if apparently
it's against my my own interest but
if i look at the interests of
society as a whole if security increases
is a good thing so i say
i always say that luckily now
some classes of targets at least some of
them
are much more difficult to to exploit
successfully and in a
meaningful way in an actionable way
but other classes of targets are still
lagging behind
and i'm talking about all this that
crap iot staff scada
a lot of
small home small office home office
networking gear
you know i ip cameras oh
there's a uni universe of broken objects
everywhere and this is getting worse
so while a few classes of targets
improve their security significantly
to a point where it's hard for a single
researcher to find
actionable
[Music]
exploits bugs and then to exploit them
in an actionable way
i mean we know there are a few geniuses
out there
but they are the exception they are not
the the normal
for the majority of people is becoming
extremely
complicated in terms of
knowledge required skills time
resources including financial resources
and so on but on many other classes of
targets the situation is still
the the security posture of these
devices is still uh terrible
and so what we see is that the the
interest is shifting
from those device who are very very
difficult to hack
and to exploit nowadays to the others
because in the end from the point of
view of an attacker
the the attack surface is a very complex
and huge surface that includes a lot of
things
so if an attacker cannot get your phone
they will get your
uh thermostat they will get your wi-fi
they will get your car they will get
your
um you know internet connected
uh scale that will publish on facebook
your weight
every day and so we are uh
we are really um
overwhelmed but the amount of crap that
surrounds
uh i mean in terms of
digital crap that surrounds us so are
you actually seeing
an uptick in uh exploit writers focusing
more on two embedded and iot and also
buyers as in are there enough buyers to
to justify the researcher changing their
focus as in like instead of looking at
mobile like look at the embedded space
or look at scada because
the uh
i must give you an answer which has two
parts
the first answer the first part is since
we don't
deal on purpose with the
development of cyber weapons
but we only deal with the law
enforcement
and intelligence side of things and
when i say intelligence i mean
intelligence
gathering not sabotage for example
so since we are not dealing with cyber
weapons
most of this stuff that is being offered
on the market nowadays which relates to
scada iot
and this kind of crappy products
is not in scope with our
customers needs so we don't
really look into that i mean we keep
track
of things but we don't deal with those
kind of things
but since iot and
networking and scada systems can have
many different
applications and many different shapes
and and can
also be part of an attack surface for an
intelligence
activity sometimes
uh there is a
not no let me say not sometimes there is
a growing
interest in some of these devices
or classes of devices because
they can be used on the field to reach
certain goals so to answer your question
there is not enough demand at least
in our field from for
iot and scada research
but sometimes we have a very interesting
request
for very specific things so um
even uh recently we were dealing with um
some amazing research in this field
and and we found some interest from
from the from the demand side
from from the buyers uh
but generally speaking i think this is
something that will develop
more and more in the next years
so this shift will happen in the next
two or three years
when the mobile
would be so difficult to to exploit that
it will become a liability and therefore
it will
lose its attractive
attractiveness its interest
so now we are like at the early stages
of this uh
shift so but if i understood correctly
your question
is the thing is
how can we support these researchers
which are following their interests
and researching things that are not
so interesting or so in demand well
of course they can do this as a bug
bounty they can
refer and disclose these bugs to vendors
and they or they can go to events and
they can
get a prize for disclosing a nasty
bug on a iot device
there's so many things that they can do
uh if they have something
that they consider interesting they can
still talk to us
and we will tell them very honestly look
this is something that
doesn't fit with uh
[Music]
with with our customer needs or this is
something that
might be interesting and then we can we
can
go deeper and
[Music]
and see what what what is possible
so let's just make a hypothetical
situation okay let's just say i'm the
bug hunter right
how much of the exploit do i need to
disclose
in order to get the discussion going
because if i tell you too much
you could reproduce it and that's always
always a fear right it's like i don't
want to tell you like too much yes
well there are different approaches on
the market
someone is asking to see the code period
and because of trust or because they
have a
very powerful leverage on the researcher
so they will say if you want to work
with us
send us the code and we will let you
know
the way we are doing things is a little
bit different
so basically before we go
into the analysis
and testing of any code
we want to discuss the features
the coverage the artifacts
the corner cases and the
affected versions and subversions
the possible use cases and so on and so
on
and so on without
having a complete
description of the bug uh
also because it's not in our interest to
steal
the bags from uh researchers you know
sure it's not oh
i mean it would be bad
in many ways uh first of all and this is
obvious this would be bad for our
reputation but it would also be bad
because then we would put
we would need to put a lot of effort
into
weaponizing a bug and that's not what
we do so
it's not really useful
for us i'm not talking about the ethical
side of things but of course this is uh
i give it for so so keep for for granted
um so we discuss up to a point where we
can understand if
going further in the negotiation is
useful
or not because many times you know
uh the submission is super cool and you
think oh wow this is a nice
asset and then when you go deeper you
discover that
it only works on friday
you know it only works when you have a
full moon
and and you know because that's
how it works this is voodoo uh this is
uh really
black magic stuff so when you
start to understand that there are too
many
exceptions or situations or problems
from our point of view this is already
a no-go because the application of this
stuff
is so sensitive that you cannot have a
low reliability or very small coverage
or artifacts or
any other issue so
as i also said in my concept track
talk where where i show the
funnel of our
let's say the filter that we apply on
all the submissions that we receive
and this slide shows that
over 100 submissions on
average five end up on the field
so it's incredibly steep
uh funnel so and we don't need
to know about the details of the bug
unless there is a clear decision to
acquire that asset and at that point
since we offer we think that we are
offering
fair contracts we offer
usually unless there is already a good
relationship
with the developer we offer
advanced payment to see the code
and then we test it and then
if all the tests are successful
we will finalize the contract
and at that point there will be a
certain way of paying
which depends on the negotiation so
in any case when we reach this
conclusion that this asset is
extremely valuable and interesting and
fits all our
requirements then at that point is
basically almost done
so we can afford to give
an advanced payment to see the code
so that the researcher knows that we
are committing ourselves to uh
successful
uh to closing successfully the deal
and then we test we discuss we see if
there are problems
and so on and so on until we finish the
test
and approve in such a case then
we sign and and everything
then moves from there
very smoothly so um
people don't have to disclose their bags
and
for those researchers who are listening
now i
advise you to not show your stuff
to anyone uh because
we see many times that maybe we receive
the same submission from different sides
and and the original researcher is just
one of them so be careful guys
don't show your stuff around don't brag
about it
with your friends and colleagues
uh be careful because if you have
something
valuable you don't want to to lick it
and you don't want to lose control over
it
what about a window of exploitability so
let's just say if i found a bug
like do i have to guarantee that it's
going to remain exploitable after you
guys have done your
evaluation because what happens if the
vendor patches it do i
still get paid or tough luck of course
but
this is of course so during the tests
basically let me let me use a metaphor
it's like we are buying uh vegetables
okay but with fresh vegetables without
having a fridge okay so the lifespan of
these things
is by nature unpredictable and usually
short okay then there are some ways that
we apply
to make them live longer this is part of
our
i would say risk management
and portfolio management activities
and in the end it works we can say that
by using this
[Music]
this way of doing things we can extend
the lifespan
the shelf life of this of these
vegetables
a little bit longer okay but still we're
talking about something that
is ephemeral by by nature
so if it is patch while we are
discussing
and or testing then
in the in the worst case for us the
developer
will will have received the advanced
payment for seeing the code and testing
it
and that's it i mean unless
someone the from the customer side is
interested in a and a
version of the same but of course the
price will change and
many things will be different the the
possibility to effectively
deploy the asset on the field will be
reduced and so on
also it will be less stealth because
it's an end day so it is known and
therefore for many reasons that
the fields of application of this asset
will be
uh dramatically reduced and therefore
also the
value will be will be much less
but maybe it is still possible to close
the view
in many cases it's not uh
to give you an example let's say we're
talking about uh
rc for a major browser
if it's patched and that thing is
updated automatically
after one week it is completely useful
useless so in that case there is no
even the chance to use it as a name day
and therefore it's gone but uh other
things
which have a long patching um
windows or maybe the patch is released
and people don't apply it for some
reason
now for those things there is still hope
so to speak
now what happens if it is patched the
detect
the day after we buy then
we are uh we are screwed basically
i mean it is our it's our business right
it is
these are the risks that we that we have
to take
so if this happens
what can we do what can you do like
there's nothing we can do of course we
will not
you know in this case some people would
scramble
to sell it on you know in the in the
dark alleys uh to uh recover
at least some money
uh but that's not what we do we don't
do that so in that case it's a loss
it's a loss it's a loss for both sides
unfortunately
the researcher would have been paid for
the
advanced payment that we paid for for
reviewing the testing the goal
and we would have lost that and
we will not and but if we sign already
he will be paid of course
how often in the past has that happened
as in that uh you know one day after you
guys all okay maybe not one day but a
couple of days after you guys have
acquired the
no no it never happened exploit actually
fortunately
fortunately it never happened like that
maybe sometimes a very nice asset
had a shorter life than that
what we expected maybe after one month
it was gone okay and but
you have to consider one thing that this
government organizations which are
uh deploying this this
assets integrated into platforms
usually um they're not
usually fast enough so a one month
window would be extremely good if
the asset would be deployed the next day
but honestly this is not how it works
maybe
they will it will take them two weeks or
three weeks to put
it to integrate and
put it in the in the
right condition to be deployed therefore
sometimes
the window of practical
usefulness of these things is reduced
because after we finish our part of the
job
it's not finished there's still some
steps uh before it is uh
used and these take time so
basically we try to move as fast as
possible
also because of this um
inevitable situation where when
something is ready
it still takes uh one week two weeks
three weeks before it can be
um it can be deployed
so but luckily it never happened like
the next day
that would be that would be really uh
unfortunate
so until now it needs to never happen
but some other times they get never
patched
so another thing that i showed in the
[Music]
in the comsack talk
is some statistics from our 2019
catalog of course i i cannot
show the latest data the latest numbers
but i can't give as an example
uh some statistics about our 2019
catalog
okay after at the end of the year
of the 125
intelligence grade exploits that we
dealt with
during 2019 93
were steals your day oh okay scary
so we are basically saying that for one
one reason or another
uh
[Music]
most of these assets have a quite uh
significant
shelf life
[Music]
so and this is at the same time good and
bad
because it's good because the return on
investment from the customer side is
extremely high
and it's bad because
these customers will not stockpile
uh or at least they don't do it anymore
they used to do it at the
in the early days but now they don't
stop
by assets so if they have one or two
chains that work they will not ask for
more
it would be a waste of money so
[Music]
again this is also a opportunity
and a problem but
in the end i'm convinced that to help
to manage these assets properly
and by doing this extending their shelf
life
as much as possible is a good
plus of our approach
of our services
and of course also the fact that we sell
to very few
selected customers we don't sell to
anyone
we can sell to large numbers of
customers
which also helps to you know
protect the investments made by
our customers would you say that of the
customers that are that are purchasing
these assets right
uh are most of them using it for
offensive capability or are they trying
to
derive some defensive understanding from
it as well
well first of all i mean
[Laughter]
we have some idea of the field of
application but we don't know
so the vetting that we do is on the
customer
is not on the activity that the customer
will perform because
of course we are not in the position to
know
[Music]
but this said sometimes we receive
different types of requests
this is also very interesting and this
is also
why i'm thinking that some kind of
convergence between
offensive and defensive activities
is needed
so sometimes we receive as a request we
want to know
if our tanks are vulnerable
to this okay now i'm saying thanks
it's just an example it's not maybe
thanks but
to give you an idea or we want to know
if our telco
or we want to know if so
in this case the
the the exploit is used to prepare
counter measures or mitigations
[Music]
again we don't know exactly how and when
but
this is certainly the idea behind
certain purchases in other cases it is
clearly for offensive purposes
also some things are offensive
by nature i mean there's no way to use
them for defensive spots
so uh yeah but i would say that
we have both uh types of requests
depending on
things that we
can only imagine that we don't know but
you know
you know the the fact that sometimes
you can also find collisions you can
find the same bug
twice so sometimes
what happens is that there is a an
attack
and they want to understand how it was
done
and by researching
the same class of bugs we can give them
some
hints or maybe find the game the same
bug that was already used
against them because honestly
and i always say our visibility on this
market
is not 100 so
at this point after five years we are in
a position to see
a lot of what's going on but not
everything so
sometimes maybe someone has already
found
the same bug and exploited it and and we
just don't know
especially those teams that work
exclusively
for a certain customer and you will
never know what they have
unless you find it
in your uh your
in your networking uh
uh locks okay however you find it
uh do you find that it was used against
you so
mostly the requests that we receive are
for
purely offensive stuff and again as i
said previously
very focused on the information
gathering
and for law enforcement and
and for intelligence
so you know i mean i think one of the
questions that uh normally comes up when
it comes to
bounty programs is ethics and the trust
side of things right so you guys know
who your buyers are but what's stopping
them from reselling it
well that's a very good question that's
my answer is very simple we don't work
with integrators
[Music]
which is a big loss
in terms of potential business but it's
also the only way
to make sure that our assets go
exactly where we want them to go
you see it would be much easier
to sell to integrators there are a
very interesting
companies nowadays which are developing
uh
platforms and tools and that could
integrate our assets
into their let's call it armory
okay uh or set off
uh assets but
uh of course we cannot force them to
disclose
who their customers are and
therefore we cannot uh
risk that for some reason something that
we
uh developed or that we found and then
maybe a big package
fine-tuned extended and so on because
this is what people did
also because and i hope the researchers
will not be offended
uh a very good researcher often
is not all also a very good program
so sometimes the the exploits are super
cool but
can be um significantly improved from a
programming point of view
so we invest a lot and therefore we
cannot risk
that our assets go
in places that we don't want them to go
or simply to not know where they go
without any judgment you know on on the
fact that
these companies have customers from all
over the world and not all countries are
giving the same level of
assurance about how they will use
these assets for many reasons that we
don't
want to judge it's just a matter of
facts
so yes that's my answer
it's very simple we know where these
assets go because we don't deal with
intermediaries or we don't deal with
integrators
so from the risk management side of
things basically you guys have
processes in place in order to make sure
that there's some level of guarantee i
guess to the expert writer that
that tool isn't going to fall into
unquote wrong hands you know there's
always that concern right
you see this discussion this topic about
what which are the right hands and the
wrong hands is
super complicated yeah and uh really we
would need a
couple of uh weekends to discuss about
it
with a good bottle of wine because uh
it's really complicated um it's not so
easy as many people think it is
so we need to remove as much as possible
the risks of exposure or liabilities or
incidents or abuses
to the maximum degree possible
of course if you are selling
sidearms to the police
you sell them uh 50 000 beretta
results and if there is one crazy
policeman
that is going to uh kill an
innocent with that director
how can you prevent it so even if maybe
the law enforcement agency overall
behaves properly followed or follows the
rules
and is abiding to to the laws
you can still have
individuals which create problems and
this is something that is
unavoidable but this said
you can choose to sell to a certain law
enforcement agency
and not to another your
your your pistols now
i don't like to assimilate exploits to
guns
because this is uh
simply not right it's not a useful
metaphor exploits are not equivalent of
guns
in the cyberspace blah blah this is crap
exploits are pieces of software that do
very specific things
on a very very few specific targets
for a very short time until they
don't work anymore so it's completely
different from a gun
but going back to your to your question
um the the
risk management is i would say
50 of our job
we are both doing very technical
weird things
and applying
very strict risk management
processes from management
and organizational point of view also
because there are no
good regulations in place so
imagine if you are shipping a can of
very toxic thing uh
there are so many laws so many checks
and this shipment will be tracked
because it's dangerous toxic uh
stuff and there will be a certain way
uh which is a standard that must be
applied to
handle this can uh to
move it from here to there and so on so
but for um exploits there's nothing like
that
nobody knows actually that
the dangerousness of what they are
dealing with
until an incident happens
[Music]
in trying to manage this in some ways so
that everybody plays
fairly so we we found a lot of
resistance
in in the market to refine
a new better
risk assessment standard
we tried but we didn't receive uh
good uh feedbacks from other players
customers are interested but um
many uh at least until now
in the in the market are not interested
into
finding defining together a way to give
a risk score to these things
and handle them differently depending on
what they are
so if you have something with uh and i'm
talking about the i'm
not talking about the cvss score of
course because that is
purely technical yeah okay but
you can have a 9 or a 10 for something
that cannot have huge impacts at the
society level
uh while something else with the same
ccbs
coss sorry could have dramatic
impacts on society so
we are not there yet but we really would
like to
move forward in this direction because
also for us as a company imagine we are
a small company
and we are dealing with things that
potentially can be extremely
damaging so we take all possible
measures
and we really avoid to do a lot
of deals because we don't want to
generate
unnecessary risks or simply
to create unpredictable situations where
we don't know what's going to happen
that is enough for us to stop a deal
many others are not following this kind
of approach
and and i understand it because since
there are no regulations why should they
bother
right but in perspective
responsible i don't want to use
the word ethical because i don't know i
know many people will
you know be um
[Music]
want to be happy if i if i try to say
that this is an ethical approach right
to offensive stuff
it's it's apparently a paradox
um so let me just say that from um
risk management point of view in order
to make
things happen smoothly reduce
liabilities reduce unnecessary risks
and overall having this market work in a
sustainable way we should develop
some sort of standard for attributing
a risk score to
different types of different classes
of assets the fact that we don't have
this
is dangerous how long do you think so
before we see this becoming kind of
commonplace that everybody kind of
agrees that we have a standardized way
of describing it or
attributing a risk score to it yeah you
see the thing is this risk score
is not cannot be purely technical
because when we're talking about
cyber stuff nowadays we are talking
about something that
affects physical and human
assets as much as if not more
technical assets so for example
let's say you have a nice exploit for uh
wearable healthcare device
now from the point of view of research
this is super cool
right but if this ends in the wrong
hands this can be used to kill people
not just to take their emails
from their phone and by the way
also taking emails from the phone can be
very dangerous
depending on the situation right so uh
we need to define a multi-dimensional
scoring system where the technical
variables are together with the
potential impacts
in terms of several
things and and this should
give us some sort of index so that we
know
what we are dealing with and we can
we can definitely improve the way we
work
if we know what are the risks of
this stuff of course we have our own
uh internally developed
uh risk assessment framework
because even if there is not a standard
we wanted to have this
so everything we deal with has a score
and i must say from our experience that
the fact that we developed this
uh helps us uh a lot
in in our activities and in taking
decisions
uh taking decisions sometimes this will
go against the business
this is inevitable like every time there
is some kind of
regulation or self-regulation you will
also lose something but you will gain
more by saving on
on mistakes errors consequences
liabilities
and and so on so
so that's our approach our approach and
i hope it
will slowly spread
in this market because this is something
that we really
miss as a community as a whole to know
more or less what we're talking about in
terms of
potential impacts and act accordingly
uh i would say even responsible if not
ethically
okay but yeah i was gonna say like uh
why don't you guys take the lead as in
like since you already have the
framework in place that you guys use
internally why not publish it publish it
as an open doc that
everybody can refer to and then say that
this is going to be
like you know what this is this is a
great
possibility we have been thinking about
it and
this is one possibility but you know i
would prefer
to find some sort of preliminary
agreement
with some of the biggest
players in this field review this
together and then after this review
after this discussion and this uh
fine-tuning because i'm sure that our
framework is
not perfect and then we could
together share it with the rest of the
of the community for further refinements
and for further discussion
uh this is not something that you know
because this in the end will be some
sort of self-regulation
it has to be embraced
it cannot be enforced so
my hope is to find a critical mass
of interested parties that want to work
on this and then
after this preliminary work we can share
it
for further discussion with the
community as
whole and receive all the comments
receive all the ideas
and and and have in the end something
that was really
shared and therefore can be applied
so definitely this is something i want
to work
in the next months maybe you could
also help us to do this yeah for sure i
mean i was just going to say like you
know if there's any way that you think
we can
play a small part in helping to make
this discussion at least start
uh we'd be more than happy to you know i
mean i can think of katie masuris as one
person that might have a lot of ideas on
how this can be put into some kind of a
framework
that we can at least have a reference
point to start off from it's not going
to be perfect but we have to start
somewhere
this is just for having some kind of
reference
because the fact that we completely
don't have that considering the size
of this market the sensitivity of what
we do
the applications of what we deal with
is definitely uh needed
we can we can't wait anymore it's it's
about
time to to have this kind of
reference at least uh for uh
for taking informed decisions because
the zero days are definitely
not born equal and they will have
different
impacts different effects different
applications
and potentially different adverse
effects excellent
excellent excellent uh i think we're out
of time brother
we have already just got past an hour
but um yeah i know but we can go on for
another six hours
it's so interesting no fine so yes i
hope
i answered uh i mean i tried to answer
in the most open and transparent way as
possible and i really thank you for for
these questions and for this opportunity
to
discuss things that are usually not
discussed openly
which is a pity yeah i understand the
need for
uh confidentiality and of course
those are required in our field but
to discuss about the field shouldn't be
uh double as it is should be the
conversations should be
open and a wider audience should also
contribute
which is something that we're trying to
do right so hopefully
hopefully this is just uh a little
step towards that direction well let's
plan for this road let's plan for
for maybe getting together towards later
part of the year when things hopefully
get a little bit better and let's see
who we can put onto a panel of some sort
where we can at least start the
discussion right because like it's not
like we're going to come up with the
solution but
we have to start we have started yeah
look we don't think we have
now the solutions we think that we have
the questions
at this point yeah we have some ideas of
course also but
uh mostly we have questions and we would
like to find
the answers excellent excellent
thanks brother uh always good to chat
with you and yeah always good times to
hear your thoughts as well man
it was a pleasure thanks dylan and
thanks everybody see you
uh hopefully in person soon bye we'll
see you soon brother thank you