hi everyone my name is zukapram and i'm
the co-founder and ceo
of secops today i'll be giving the talk
on the state of mobile security
at hacking the box in 2021
in amsterdam this is the keynote uh
presentation
i'm very excited to do that i uh i've
always had a great pleasure um
attending hacking the box and speaking
attack in the box
um so this is a very special event for
me i spoke
the first time in hacking the box i
think it was 2011
and i loved the event
ever since the team was just
spectacular and i
really i really love the attention to
details the great quality of
presentations
um and the entire hacking the box team
and dylan himself
uh are just amazing so really happy to
to be giving this talk
and let me share the screen and we'll
get started
so
today we'll be speaking about the state
of mobile security my background before
we get started
i live in san francisco originally from
israel moved here about six years ago
and i wish i could do this talk in
person
but i guess only next year i will be
able to do that
and i've been doing mobile
well security research my entire life
and i've been focusing
on mobile security ever since i joined
samsung
in back in 2010 and um
at the time i was working on hacking
smart devices
smart tvs uh smartphones uh and
i've been given the opportunity of
proving that um
arm devices at the time with new uh
mitigations was still hackable but they
also gave me the
opportunity of writing full exploits and
even publishing
some of this research at
conferences like defcon and blackhead
afterwards i founded zimperio
and in 2017 i founded i co-founded the
zack hopps
i like everything related to cyber
security and mobile dfir in particular
i also am enjoying chess
and cookings and so this is my email and
my
my twitter some of you know me as i
hackbandme
on twitter alright so let's
let's get started this is a very
important topic it's a
topic that is um i've been
giving a lot of energies uh for
and uh i watched it very closely
over the years and so hopefully
i can share some of my experience and
what i'm seeing um
as well as maybe some
heads up on what's coming into endpoints
and servers
and if we don't react now as a community
together
uh it's all known on how smartphones are
important for us but just to put things
in perspective
the 3 billion users out there using
mobile devices about 3 billion these
devices have microphones they have
cameras they have
access to all emails all sms's
and our most sensitive data videos
pictures
contacts and whatnot they're always on
us they're always connected
they expose a quite a big attack surface
from remote um and
um i mean just look everywhere people
are always on their phones
and i think very important to mention
that it's being used as our second
factor
so as an attacker
if an attacker attacks your pc they
still need to hack your phone or find a
way to
receive this second fact of
authentication but if they hacked
your phone they don't need to hack
anything else so this is really becoming
the most
important target to protect but it
it is also the biggest target
with the least amount of visibility that
we have
but always it came back to that oh but i
have old garden and
and i'm protected i'm not downloading
from third party app store so i'm
protected
that's actually not the real the the
real threat if you're dealing with
actors like
um nso and other commercial groups as
well as nation states
it but really it became more intense for
me
in 2017 summer of 2017 so i just
walked around in new york and i noticed
that my phone
suddenly rebooted and
as a security researcher i know that
this could happen for multiple reasons
one of them could be a kernel panic it
could also happen
and when you click accidentally on the
power button it could also happen
when the device is overheated and
but i wasn't clicking on the power
button i wasn't the
device wasn't too hot
in any significant way and
i realized that i just experienced the
kernel panic on my phone
now channel panic on the phone doesn't
necessarily have to be because of
security reasons
but in this particular case once i
looked at the logs
i noticed that it happened because of a
security mitigation that was triggered
uh 99.9 percent of the people would
never actually check the kernel logs
whenever something like that happens uh
but this is where i really
took a deeper dive into the rabbit hole
of
what smartphone's security really means
and how
big the gap is uh that we have to close
asap for for this entire planet i mean
three billion is a very
big amount of device owners
compared to the entire population of
planet health
so we really have to do something about
it and
so i took a deeper dive into this kennel
panic it was a security mitigation that
was triggered
and and it basically panicked when
the kernel expected a certain value in
what ios kernel calls non-poison cookie
but uh it actually seen a different
value
it was one bit different than the
expected value and the current value at
the time
and as a result of that the kernel
protected itself and rebooted
and interestingly enough this mitigation
only runs once every 32 allocations
so as an attacker your exploit would
walk 31 out of 32 times
and that's an acceptable risk
but this is only one bit that flipped so
i mean it could happen for other reasons
it could happen because of memory
corruption
uh it's possible um it could also happen
because of a code because of uh
cosmic rays uh one researcher suggested
that
you can actually calculate that it's
it's very low probability but
it's it's possible and
knowing what i do and knowing you know
the things
i've been involved in and all the
stories about researchers getting
targeted
it wasn't such
an ex it wasn't unexpected to see that
and so i did take a deeper dive and it
definitely
uh looked suspicious but i couldn't
conclude what's going on
part of that was because um i was
blocked for my
analyzing my own device but really two
weeks later
what happened was that my phone panicked
again this time i was at defcon
2017. the taxi driver took a different
route
and as soon as i exited airplane mode
because during the conference
i was in airplane mode and
the the phone panicked i immediately
looked at the kernel logs and i noticed
and my eyes went dark basically i
noticed that
the baseband binary
in this particular case com center
mobile helper
was running an unsigned version of it so
this is why the
the kernel panicked it ran a cs ops
operation and it failed on this
particular process
so at that point i was really curious
what's going on
is my phone compromised and because the
kernel gave me
this path to this file this com center
mobile helper
that was replaced and and wasn't um the
expected signed
executable that and the kernel wanted to
see
um i wanted to extract that file
it's very simple so when i
tried to do it in traditional ways
i couldn't do it when i asked the vendor
to provide me file system dump they
didn't want to commit not on the time
not on what i'll get and
not on anything they did however offered
me a free device but i wasn't interested
in a free device i was interested in the
attack i was interested in the details i
was interested in
what's happening on my own phone and who
attacked me
and i wanted them to pay for doing that
so i uh i needed a local privilege
escalation exploit
and google project zero happened to have
to they have announced uh or i i was
told that they are about to release
uh this local proof escalation exploit
for that particular version of ios
and so i asked i basically begged
ben hawkes from google project zero to
provide me access to that file because
i'm running out of time i know that the
doctors are using time bombs which we'll
discuss later
and if i'm not going to do it fast
enough
i'm going to lose my opportunity to
discover this attack
a few weeks later google project zero
did actually
uh release it ben hawkes didn't want to
share with me
the the lp while um
at that point in time i understand i
mean people
don't always want to show their their
local proof escalations but i was
basically blocked from
analyzing my own device i was blocked
from analyzing the specific file the
kernel
told me that was tampered with and that
was temple
so i uh i was
blocked and this is where i really took
a deeper dive into
what's really happening in mobile
security because if i was attacked
how many other people are attacked i
mean i'm not that important i'm not
important
the people way more important than me
with
with access to to many things i'm
actually not using my phone to access
anything important
so why was i
targeted uh and how many other people
are targeted how many people
viewing this presentation are actively
targeted
and so that's what i want to check
the answer actually scared me more than
i anticipated i didn't know how common
it is now i do know it's very common
and it's not as common as like 50
of the population but if you're doing
something of importance
um you're definitely targeted one way or
the other by one protector or the other
so what's what's the problem the problem
with mobile security is that phones are
very limited in what you can see so if
you think about it
and it was originally or at least
marketed as
privacy solutions so uber for example
cannot see if lift is installed on your
device and then offer you more
competitive rates
which by the way i mean that will be not
bad
if we get more competitive rates um if
they know it was installed on the device
but let's put that aside and let's
assume that's actually a good thing
so if
uber cannot see lyft can our
anti-viruses see
malware or other applications that that
exist on the device the answer is not
but as a result of privacy
we cannot make sure that our phone is
private and that's really a problem
we'll talk about that later
and also one of the other issues is in
our computers you know macs
you know servals in linux we have
local admins root user
why don't we have the same on our mobile
why don't we have the same type of
access
on our smartphone so this is really um
uh something i want to change
this is something that we deserve as as
two to three billion people that have
smartphones we have to change that
because of what these devices include
microphone camera
and and our second factor of
authentication
and for some people even large amount of
cryptocurrencies
we should have the ability of inspecting
these devices
but really when i i wanted to check for
myself like how bad is it like
how how common it is to see
acknowledgments from vendors that are
under attack i mean
obviously they prefer not to acknowledge
at all and we'll see that
uh shortly but when they actually
acknowledge that there will attacks and
there are a few things that are very
similar for example they say
this may be under limited and targeted
exploitation
what do you mean targeted and limited
was it five people was it five thousand
was it fifty thousand was it five
hundred thousand or five million users
i mean with one billion devices out
there you can say five million is very
targeted
and very limited exploitation these four
vulnerabilities
specifically fixed in in the may update
in android they allow attacker to gain
full access
to the device and the attackers actually
get
higher privileges than what you get as a
device owner
and we have to level that up we have to
make sure that we get the same access as
the attackers
we are fighting in happy battle and we
have to
uh correct that now before i continue
you may think to yourself hey this guy
is doing most mobile stuff
he wants higher privileges for his own
good
but you actually couldn't be more wrong
about it
i'm not doing it for myself
i probably have better access than
the majority of the people doing mobile
security research
have access to lps i have access to
to things that are not available
to most of the people out there
the problem and if we actually
share this if we actually receive this
access i will be
equal i'll be on power with everyone
else it will give them
uh to be to be on the same level as
as my access so in a way i'll i'll not
have
this huge advantage anymore um
but i'm not looking at it like that i'm
not looking at it as
okay i'll be um with the same level of
access as
company x or y i'm looking at as
this is what's important for the
industry this is what's important for
every sock
in the world this is what's important
for every politician
that wants to keep their democracy
this is what's important for every prime
minister or every
vip or journalist or researcher
that wants to make sure that their phone
is not compromised and if they are
compromised to make sure that the
attackers pay for
for making these mistakes attacking them
so extracting these payloads
even for the attackers if you are
working for a government and you work
for
or work for a commercial group
this access is actually good for you uh
because same attacker like like you are
attacking others
people attack you so your phone is
compromised probably too
and not being able to analyze it
properly that's
that's a really big problem
so this is how i look at things i want
to make sure that everyone
gets equal access the same level of
access that the attacker gets we have to
level it up and there are also other
problems that
lps do not solve they actually cause
some issues
especially when dealing with them
at scale deployments and when dealing
with
um non-persistent attacks
so we'll cover also this too and this is
why i actually don't use
i don't recommend using lps for
investigations
and prefer to convince the vendors to do
otherwise to do the good
good decision and actually open up a
local admin rights for users
let's continue so this is from january
again another vulnerability it may be
under limited
targeted exploitation okay great uh only
four months about
um and then i just saw yesterday uh then
from house technica actually wrote that
it's a bit of uh odd to write this
this cash like this this
meaningless uh this
sentence in each one of the uh
vulnerabilities that were exploited in
the wild i mean
you want to give us details give us
details give us the iocs give us the
uh the cnc servers give us the path that
the malware used
give us more information about the
exploits more information about the
vulnerabilities
you give us the number how many were
targeted
and i honestly
don't necessarily believe these numbers
or anymore
i don't believe the limited and targeted
exploitation just like i didn't believe
google
when they said that um stage fight was
not exploited
actually knew that it was exploited
and in the wild i mean even in our demos
once we
we demonstrated it uh i mean we attacked
many devices for for demonstration
purposes how can they
say it wasn't exploited in the wild like
how would they know if our demo
was a real attack or not i mean we got a
shell
on the the target device and we've
demonstrated that
it was infected as a result of stage
fright
so how can they say that that it wasn't
exploited and also on top of that
i mean some that commercial threat
actors
told me that as a result of statewide
being patched
they actually lost um some
vulnerabilities that
they were using so i know for a fact
that it was expected in the wild
and i also know as a result of this
that google and we can also infer that
apple
do not have real real statistics on
attacks
whenever the attackers are preventing
them from seeing
those statistics so this is one of the
biggest problems in the mobile world
when you have a single burial
of of defense once the attackers bypass
that
they just make sure that the vendor
cannot see that anymore and
as a result of that they're completely
invisible to the vendor
and by the way while many of my examples
will speak about ios or android i'm not
referring to any specific vendor
i think this is a problem in apple this
is a problem in google in
samsung in lg in anyone else
this is a problem in the entire industry
and we have to change that
the level of access that we have let's
take a look at ios
so here there is a google tag
discovery and
they have basically found an attack that
was exploited in the wild he doesn't
mention that it was exploited in the
wild but it was
and that's a bit of unfortunate but
let's see how it goes in other
disclosures so this was
uh 12.1.4 now we're skipping to a future
version's most
recent versions 14.2 they say
this exploit for this issue exists in
the wild
somebody was exploiting kernel
vulnerabilities on ios devices
but we don't have iocs we don't have the
urls we don't have the paths
we don't have any report we don't know
how many people were attacked
using these vulnerabilities uh where is
the transparency
like we also know that
apple didn't really notify xcode ghost
infected devices about it they just put
it
in a faq page that nobody reads so
were those people notified about these
attacks
share with us something else share with
us more information
um now
i was 14.4 and
same thing it says that apple is aware
that this may
issue may have been actively exploited
it may have been actively exploited like
oh i don't know it's very very vague
anonymous researcher is that like a
government is that something else
um but a kernel bug and webkit bug i
mean
it's always a rest recipe for travel
so it allows remote code execution to to
attack us
but here again no report no ioc is
nothing not even
how many devices were attacked
um i was 14.5 so we continue again this
issue is exploited in the wild a pretty
pretty uh uh good amount of discoveries
recently that that have that but here
again no report no iocs
and also 14.5.1 another version that was
uh fixed and and
let's take let's take an example let's
let's think okay
from the pc world and what
would have been different um if in the
last
20 years we didn't have local admin so
for example
one once i looked into that i kind of
remember the
solarwinds attack used stage two
of this attack they planted the dll into
the c windows directory the windeal
directory
in an alternative universe
an alternative dimension sorry i don't
have dimension
if we didn't have local admin on windows
we wouldn't be able to discover
solarwinds
attack that's how bad it is
but we are not in an alternative
dimension yet
and we uh we still have local admin on
windows
also do microsoft do plan to change that
so
just like on mobile when uh the mobile
vendors basically say hey we have
like we are doing the job for you you
don't need to worry about security
which is obviously not true imagine
microsoft saying that too
so this is why it's really important for
us
to to change that because i mean i i
don't think anyone
can fight malware alone and
by having deeper access to these devices
we are able to find more things together
this is how the solarwinds
attack was found but many many other
malware over the history of windows were
discovered
um in in a similar way
so this is quite important and if we
take that away from us
i mean why do we need to even have socks
in in
the entire world there's no need i mean
microsoft will do well do all the work
right
obviously obviously not so but
just to to get a better understanding
but let's
go back to on uh they mention
and think about mobile attacks in
particular so this is from the
2019 implant implant teardown
by google project zero and what is said
here is that there is no way for a user
in ios to view the process listing so
the implant binary makes no attempt
to hide its execution from the system so
it's actually
the malware autos are
protected by the sandbox and as a result
of that
the users cannot see them it's that bad
the one will simply run the file from
slash temp so this is the file it's very
easy
uh for them it's very convenient nobody
actually looks at that even if
if apple checks that and they will see
that
this file i mean there are many files
like that
uh this structure
it would get lost in the noise and they
would never know about it
but really the important thing is this
folder is blocked due to sandbox
restrictions and you're not
able to access this file
at all without running a local project
escalation
google was just lucky because they had
access to the exploit itself
so they had access to the uh to the
infection and from from the web they
found this malware because this payload
was so
bad in terms of opsec that they
communicated every minute they did
unencrypted so it's a very bad upset but
very amazing exploits and simply because
the attackers didn't care about what's
happening
post exploitation and this really shows
out how bad
it is let's take a look at the uh
uh attack on a journalist of al jazeera
um
and this journalist was attacked by nsos
malware and here the iocs are private
about
db and private file temp you cannot
access both of them
so if your phone was communicating with
nso servers you cannot actually take
these files and
extract them this actually happened
as well i mentioned to the vendor hey
this phone is communicating with nso
servers
their response was believe it or not
they said we have no evidence so we do
not
this is not sufficient information for
us
to know that this phone is compromised
what do you mean like what i'm asking
you
is to allow me to extract the file
system so i can provide you
also the the implants that they were
using
how can you say that based on the device
communicating with
cnc server that there's no enough
evidence that this phone is compromised
so what you're not going to help me to
extract the file system
okay so you're actually not interested
in discovering the attack that's what
you're saying
okay i got that i got that and this is
what we're trying to change
because this is not the best way
not for the vendors and not for us and
smartphone users regardless of who this
vendor is
it's it's really applicable to all of
them
so just some fruitful thoughts so a lot
of missing and confusing mentioning no
reports no iocs
us security updates for unsupported
devices is actually a great way to know
if a vulnerability is actively exploited
also on other devices so you can see
you can see that so if you look at for
example 12.5.3
which is only there available for
unsupported devices you see that they
only fixed security issues and also in
the previous versions
so this is actually a really good way of
knowing what
the risk is so if if you want to even
practice
some exploitation uh techniques you can
look at
all the devices that were exploited and
you can
realize from that which ones are are
probably
the better vulnerabilities to take a
look at
all these examples exist why are we
still blocked from extracting payloads
analyzing the memory i mean
what's what are you going to say that
now
moving forward there are no not going to
be any more attacks in the wild
it's not so believable is it
um and of course we are the iocs now
let's talk about lps okay so we do have
lps
we don't care about anything else that's
actually not true so
when you're running lpes in order to do
extractions in order to do analysis of
devices
there are a lot of disadvantages for
example um
you can you cannot basically share it
with anyone
um you know to to use it right like
you're basically sharing a vulnerability
that's that's obviously not good
um also it's only local public
escalation i
and i personally don't consider it as
too dangerous
uh i mean
you don't want to share this lp
chain with with people you don't know
and trust
and you want to disclose this because
you want to do the right thing you want
to make sure that these vulnerabilities
are not being used against you against
others
but you have to keep it because you have
to keep a potential weakness
and you know to be able to analyze
devices
so every time i actually reported an nlp
i regretted that in the future
and so do i actually advise
um not to share lpes with device vendors
i think until this this changes the only
way to analyze
devices in a deep way in the full way
is keeping those lpes and that's
unfortunate because i actually believe
that the platform should fix those
vulnerabilities
but we are being forced
not to share them with the vendors not
to fix them
to keep these weaknesses open
and that's wrong that's not how it
should be
done i mean not to whitehead at least
whitehead people i mean if you're
working a commercial third actor
you obviously don't care if you're
working for a government
probably use it for yourself but
this is actually not not the best way to
do it
it's also unstable so
let's say this exploit works seven times
out of ten or eight times out of ten
what happens in this other two or three
times out of ten
so basically the device reboots so if
you are checking a phone
that is compromised by a non-persistent
actor
and you cause the reboot you destroy the
investigation you ruined the entire
investigation
and the problem is you ruined it while
you did everything right
because this is what is expected from
you you will
they expect you to run local private
escalations you know to
to analyze those devices they also
expect you that after you do that
that you'll report them both the
vulnerabilities you found and the
vulnerabilities you used
in order to do this investigation
that's just odd and then porting
vulnerability so there's a new
ios update or there's a new android
update you need to port these lpes
into this new version and the time that
it takes you to for this vulnerability
could be enough time for the threat
actor to realize hey this device is not
communicating
communicating for two weeks or two
months we should they
trigger the self-destruct option which
we'll talk about
shortly and also the vulnerability can
be patched so
our new mitigation can be released so it
can prevent access for
multiple uh weeks or months
even so you're basically being blocked
from analyzing
devices i mean the entire file system
etc
and when you're speaking about you know
vendors that can
sell those lps and um
extraction tools the reality is very
different than what is being advertised
so first of all these vendors do not
necessarily have lps for everything like
they
some of them claim they do um and
oftentimes whatever you have public is
actually the same thing that they have
the second thing is whenever they do
have something unique
and i only can think of one vendo
that has it they don't necessarily want
to sell it to you
they only want to sell it to high paying
government clients and they want to do
it for different purposes
they don't necessarily do it for cyber
security purposes they're doing
it for the ability of
bypassing the pin code or or
bypassing device restrictions and
so these are some of the the reasons and
then
if you're waiting for fixing the
vulnerabilities or if
porting it etc and takes too long then
you can you're basically losing the race
and the time bomb can be activated
um and as a result of that you will not
be able to
[Music]
find the malware that was on the device
once you
started the investigation and also
another problem is you cannot use this
at scale
you cannot just take 10 000 devices and
run local group escalations
on them or hundred thousand it just it
doesn't work it causes reboots it causes
problems you can get banned from the app
store or the play store
um i mean it's it's not worth it so
on one hand they do not allow you to use
it on the other hand you have no other
choice
so it's really catch 22 here um and it's
terrible
it's also unreasonable to request every
sock in the world to hold
lps zero days it's just impossible
why do we have deeper access on every
other platform but we don't have it on
on smartphones so
just going back into the time bomb this
is a document from the leak of
the pegasus nso product guidelines um
and this leak revealed some of the
things but
i want to to mention that they have a
self-destruct mechanism so if your phone
was compromised and you want to analyze
it
the traditional forensics method would
be
you need to unplug the computer from the
the network socket you need to
turn it off you need to do um you know
investigation um in a in a certain way
on mobile you cannot do that if you're
going to switch the phone off
if you're going to move to airplane mode
and you're going to be like that for
in in this case the default here is two
months but something
but you can change the default settings
then uh the the pegasus malware would
simply self-destruct
so you ruined the investigation by
taking the phone offline
how convenient so and during that time
it's not like the vendor is going to
help you to
to extract the file system um
now at best you're going to get a new
device but
if you're actually interested in the
cyber details the cyber attack details
and you want to see which other devices
in the organization are compromised
you cannot do that not easily and
you have to get very creative in there
some possibilities of inferring the
phone is compromised but
to actually get the payload like you're
used to from windows
um no no not so easy so let's talk about
common myths
that's that's really what's uh what's
repeating again and again in the false
advertising
of of uh the mobile security space
so the world garden this is the most
common myth people think okay if i'm
not downloading um applications from
third-party app stores
on android or if i'm not if i'm only
using the
world garden then i'm safe
but actually in reality it doesn't work
like that if you're concerned about
threat actors like nso
you feel concerned about threat actors
like um
various nation states and
they don't care about the app store they
don't care about the play store
they basically use either zero clicks or
one clicks
in one clicks and this is also from the
pegasus
product data sheet
they say they have two types of
infection methods one of them is ota
overview
it's a push message no cooperation or
engagement
no indication that it appears on the
device it's silent and invisible and
cannot be prevented
again because there is only a single
layer of defense
which in this case it's it's apple of
google
and but if
this for some reason is not available
they have
a one-click attack basically they send
you a link
uh via sms via email or whatnot
as soon as you click on the link the
installation is
[Music]
silent you don't see it you don't see
anything different on the phone
and your phone is compromised so really
that's that's all it takes
uh entering a website that is
compromised whether if you did it
intentionally or by clicking on a link
or
a water hall attack
let's talk about sld and so these
security research devices recently
announced by
apple in the last few years and there is
a common myth that
srd will help you in analyzing attacks
it's actually going to only help you if
you're looking for vulnerabilities
not for attacks and so
uh just to to to understand the
difference
you have 10 000 devices in the
organization if and you have another sld
device
the sld device is not going to help you
to find attacks on these 10 000 devices
if these 10 000 devices any of them are
compromised you wouldn't be able to
access
the the file system on these devices or
the memory
should you want to and do a deeper
investigation
the srd is going to help you however if
you want to look for vulnerabilities in
the platform itself
but in that case why do you need sld you
also have checkmate
uh you don't you don't need a separate
solution for that so it doesn't actually
help you in the
digital forensics and insurance response
investigations it only help you to find
vulnerabilities
uh which you don't necessarily need that
tool for it uh there are other ways so
another myth is sod devices
it's it's actually not helping any dfir
or socks and then another myth is
users should not be allowed to run
elevated code and let's take a look at
apple's own statements here and i
actually took it from the
epic games versus apple trial that
happen is happening this month
you we have root access on mac os
and apple uh vp of developer relations
claim that
nobody at apple say that
mac os is less secure than ios
they also say that ios and mac os
they allow you to keep the integrity
and and they don't think that it's
unsafe to use
a mac um and
you can run a mac
applications worry free so
wait a minute if on mac os we have local
admin
or specifically a root user
and it's perfectly safe why we don't
have that
ability on ios oh because users will do
stupid things
but guess what users can do stupid
things without local admin
users can simply install a vpn that
turns all the traffic to the attackers
users can install a fake profile or a
work profile
users can install a root certificate
they can
i mean with mdm you can also wipe a
device and that's dangerous right like
why is that allowed
and don't tell me you want to evoke that
too
so really if if we have the same access
on mac os there is no reason
we shouldn't be able to have a local
admin on ios
same with chromebooks if we have boot on
on chromebook questions we have
root on um on android too
another is also supposed to be open um
i mean it's
a bit disappointing the level of access
that we're
receiving as users um and that we cannot
do all the things we could have done one
if we had
a full access to devices
so what we want to do is we want to
change that
and we have announced the last few years
uh
the initiative of free the sandbox for
the sandbox is a non-profit initiative
and the goal is to promote open sandbox
policy for device owners so device
owners get local admin
and they can do many things including
security analysis including
independent attestation of devices if
the phone is compromised you can extract
the payloads
to prevent further misuse and this could
also
mean uh innovation in a way which we'll
talk about in a second
from security perspective we really need
just a few things that will make our
lives
way way better um and of course we
the best way to do it is to be able to
do it at scale so socks around the world
can benefit from that and can treat
these endpoints that have microphone in
the pocket of every employee
in the same way they treat windows pcs
that's how it should be done and even
max or mac os
so we want to have an administrator or
root level
user we need to have
read only access to the entire file
system and also
read only access to the memory the file
system one is for persistent attacks or
payloads that are planted in the file
in the file system and and the read-only
memory access is for non-persistent
attacks
and so it's actually very beneficial
to be able to analyze that because there
are also some of these attacks
actively being exploited out there and
the upside deal is
also that um
liberated sandbox with local admin
can actually lead to a lot of innovation
that we cannot even think of
i mean it can cause things like i mean
if you look historically like
virtual machines we wouldn't have
virtual machines
if there wasn't the option of running a
local admin
and applications on on windows
if we would have many of the
non-traditional tools that were not
ported into
mobile yet to be able to be ported there
and new types of authentication
new things that we cannot even imagine
right now because
there are so many brilliant people in
this
planet that have so many great ideas for
innovation but they cannot
do those on locked and restricted
devices and it's a shame because these
devices are just
amazing right like we have
internet access in our pocket we have
cameras we have we have everything we
wanted
like if you talked to me 20 years ago
and told me that will be the future i'll
be like
this is amazing so what can we do like
we know okay this is a real issue this
is a problem
and if we're not going to do something
right now the same issue is going to
exist on pcs
very soon on mac os very soon as well
so we need to convince the vendors that
opening the sandbox is actually a net
positive
for them and i know when vendors are
going to watch this presentation
uh so if there is one thing you need to
take from this presentation
is if you open up the sandbox and you
actually do it first
you increase your revenues what
okay yes so if you open up the sandbox
that will allow you to win many more
cyod contracts that you're currently
losing
so once you get the csu stamp in an
organization on a specific device model
if they have full access to the device
the sock can investigate those devices
and those would be the recommended
devices for coid contracts now cyd
contracts are not
necessarily just you know one person
buying this device at the store
uh it's thousands sometimes tens of
thousands and even hundred 000 devices
at once
that are being sold to a specific
company
so this is very powerful play that can
be done so if you need to take one thing
out of this
yes there is a problem yes there are
some many issues yes this is wrong
but you can actually increase your
revenues by by opening up the sandbox so
if you want to speak to your manager and
tell them hey there's
this great idea let's do that this is
the way to convince
internally a large corporation to do it
and of course the bonus is that more
attacks will get discovered
more attacks will get discovered more
exploits will be found
the platform will be safer and further
abuse of these vulnerabilities will not
be possible
so this is really the core
of what liberating the sandbox
for local users is about and
give the users the option give the users
the choice give organizations the
possibility of really using
mobile devices as a productivity tool
now we are doing it anyway but because
there is no competition
over time i think it will change if
devices are not going to be
opened up so
this is really something we have to do
to make sure the ecosystem is healthier
and of course this leads to unintended
innovation this can lead to many many
things
depending on how flexible you want to be
but
i would go all in on this i think
it's the user's device they deserve to
choose
what is running and what permission and
not
not anyone else now
in case we are not able to convince the
vice vendors
there are also policy makers in the room
there are people that can help us
change the law so
mobile the bottom line is that mobiles
are becoming a significant risk
three billion devices out there
imagine what one rogue actor can do
with a full zero click chain going wild
i mean they can
[Music]
impact so many different devices out
there at once
it's just insane like this is a very big
very big and very real risk so mobile is
becoming a
very very big risk for us we have to
adapt the law
to false any device vendor that
generates a device
with microphone with camera and with
internet connectivity
they should be providing local admin
users
for you for for device owners
and basically security controls for
organizations to be able to
use these local admins you know to
protect
to analyze and protect these devices
so this is really what's at stake here
and this is what we have to change
once one country will start it others
will follow just like the gdpr
um so why should we care basically
i've i've won about mobile attacks in
the last decade i've seen them
firsthand so many times most of them
were never published
this is happening i'm seeing attacks
on journalists i'm seeing attacks on
researchers
on politicians
we are all using one of two devices
either an android or an iphone that's it
we don't have any other choice
and
apple and microsoft are looking at that
and saying hey we got a way
like they got away with that or in this
case we got away with that
in case of apple with not giving full
access to the device maybe we can do the
same on windows or mac os
and some of the releases for example
windows 10x
is actually they have that like they
they
disabled access to the windows
folder they don't have etw access
anymore
so you won't know about some of the
things happening on that
on that platform and that's really the
direction things are going to so we
really have to
stand up right now and say hey this is
wrong
and we cannot have such a
restricted sandbox policy
and there's also if there's one thing
i'd like you to take away from this
presentation it's
mobile attacks are way way way more
common than what we think
and i wish that someday the mobile
device vendors will publish the real
statistics on this it's
it's just so much more common than what
people think
we need to have the option of choosing
what we want on these devices
so with that i'll wrap up thank you very
much
uh for watching this presentation this
is my email and my
twitter and get in touch
and yeah thank you very much