okay so uh hello everyone and welcome to
battle Power by Windows 11 no code I'm
very happy to to be here with uh with
that with all of you so uh let's get
started
a brief introduction about myself uh I'm
an engineer a hacker I've been so uh for
a long many years now
um I've been working on security for low
code no code for many years now so uh
something like four years I invested in
this topic and you'll see some of the
foods of This research uh today I am the
CTO and co-founder at zenity which is a
company that helps secure those local no
code environments I've been I've spent
several years at Microsoft as part of
the cloud security division working on
iot security and apis and application
security and crypto
um I lead the OAS group for uh for the
top 10 risks so low code no code this is
really unrelated to this stock but it's
kind of in the same area and also uh
writes about these Topics in dark
reading so if you're interested in
learning more uh please reach out to me
I'm happy to discuss any of these things
that we see here today
before we get started it's important to
to know that even though this talk is
given from an attacker's perspective of
course the idea here is to make sure
that we as security teams of uh as
Defenders can make can basically
understand how to use no code in in a
good way in a in a way that is governed
that is maintained uh and understand its
risks we uh we love no code we think
it's it's awesome uh but it's really
important to do it in a responsible way
so what we're going to show you today is
how do you take an initial access
initial access to a machine and turn it
into entire uh malware operation now let
me start by starting by clarifying what
do I mean by a model operation so you
start off let's say that you got into
some some machine where you have initial
access you're running there
this is just the beginning of your
journey as a as an attacker to try and
capture everything to try and basically
uh do kind of achieve your goals using
that machine you need to go through
typically you need to go through a
firewall because this machine is uh is
typically inside of a corporate Network
you need to be able to actually run
malware on the machine or just have the
initial access and be able to execute to
execute something on that machine you
need to be able to communicate through
the firewall with your command and
control
you need to explain data back uh without
being detected
you also need to uh to to avoid that to
avoid detection either by the EDR on the
machine side or on the network or not
many other kind of different places
where Defenders might be looking for you
and of course you want to remain
persistent so even if they try to kick
you off or somebody Boots the machine
you still want to be there and that's
the uh that's the main issue that all of
these things there's so much there's so
much to do other than just the initial
initial access so and and all of these
things that we see here on the list most
of them are actually just grant work
they're just Ops so I'm showing you a
list where this the first thing is
initial access and the last thing is
profit and that's where uh hackers want
to uh want to focus on but there's this
whole bunch of work that you need to do
deploying the malware command and
control everything that we just saw
that you still need to accomplish so the
main question for this talk is can we
find somebody else to do this for us can
we find a SAS Vendo somebody to just
take care of these problems for us
and
um so now that's uh that's a perfect
segue to introduce RPA robotic process
automation I'm not sure how many of you
uh are familiar with it but I will share
enough about it today so you can
understand the exploit but basically
robotic process automation is a what is
a is a new type of product released in
the few in the last few years well the
the valuable position is helping users
automate my mundane tasks so things like
uh onboarding and off-boarding users or
copying and pasting receipts all of
those things that people are doing
manually
LPA can do automatically and RPI is
comprised of three separate uh
components the first one is an agent
that sits on the on the user's VM or the
user's laptop so this is actually
running in the user context with the
inside of the laptop the second is the
robot controller this is the basically
the the uh the service that is able to
uh Connect into the user's laptop and
then send out commands and fetch the uh
the results of those commands and the
third piece is the management portal
where you're able to see all of your
payloads you're able to uh or of your
tasks you're able to distribute those
tasks through the robot controller to
each one of the of those laptops so uh
and then so you understand that robotic
process automation is about being able
to run things across multiple machines
on the user's laptops with the users own
context
and the and the most important piece to
to get about RPA is that it is uh
utterly and totally trusted so the the
agents that sit on people's laptops they
are trusted they run on trusted
executables and we'll see in a moment
that they also use trusted services and
by trusted I mean they are whitelisted
by the uh by the edrs and by any
endpoint protection that you'll find
there are also uh the communication is
trusted as well so the services that are
being used in order to send out those
payloads and to receive the data back
are also trusted by network security
appliances or by uh uh by by stock teams
and so those won't be flagged as well
and of course the cloud services the
Management Services that is trusted as
well
now RPA is really everywhere within the
Enterprise and you see here the kind of
the the major names there are others uh
but actually all of these things have uh
all of these things are are really found
their way uh strongly into the
Enterprise and if you work at a large
Enterprise chances are you already have
one of those agents running on your
machine uh and and this is the main
reason why this is interesting because
if we can find a way to leverage RPA to
our advantage uh there's a lot to
benefit from it especially in an
Enterprise environment
so RPA can actually solve all of the Ops
Ops problem problems for us so command
and control exfiltration defense evasion
we will see all of that how we can use
RPA to basically uh uh do what it's
supposed to do so you're sending out
payloads you're getting the request
you're getting the results but you're
doing it as a hacker rather than the it
the IIT Administration but actually RPA
would give us much more it will give us
the ability to
um to basically
handle our support different OS versions
which means engineering so everything
that we need around building those
payloads and on making sure that those
payloads are operating properly making
sure that we support each and every type
of OS version out there RPA will do all
of that for us so you see where this is
going and this leads me to uh to uh to
show us the to so let's let's try and
figure out how today what is the next
step we're going to do today so here's
the outline I'm going to take a quick
water break
so here's the outline for this talk we
saw why malware operations is important
the next step for us we're going to
understand what RPA is so don't worry we
want we won't dive really into the
details but you'll figure out just
enough in order to understand how to
exploit it so the part after that we see
a really a technical depth of how RPA
works and how does it how exactly an LPI
service is able to uh to connect with
somebody's laptop inside a co-port
network later we'll see how to abuse LPA
and finally you will show we will share
a tool that allows you to do everything
that you'll see during this talk so you
can go go home and try it for yourself
so next up we're going to try and figure
out what RPA is and in order to do that
let me start with uh with a brief kind
of personal story so when I was a
teenager my friends and I were obsessed
with a game called uh tibia tibia was an
mrpg game uh where you basically you
level up your characters you improve
your skills you collaborate with other
with other users to uh to do quests and
and kind of gain influence
um actually a lot of my time at tibia
was spent doing something like this
um which is actually kind of a in-game
fishing so buying game fishing I mean
you click on the uh you need to click on
on on on the road and then you click on
the C and then sometimes you get you get
fish and this was about 90 of my time
spent in this game as a kid
um was was this grant one was this
clickwork so you click and you get some
fish and you click and you get some fish
and you click and you get some fish and
eventually really you understand that
this is kind of uh this this is the
equation that you're following basically
you tell them you turn clicks and and
virtual worms into Virtual Fish which is
really really boring
but it was important for the game and it
was important for us as kind of for my
friends so I wanted to I want to look
good in front of my friend I wanted to
find a creative solution to get to get
an advantage so the first attempt uh at
trying to solve this was
um physical automation so essentially I
put a bunch of books on on the on the
mouse uh and then it was it stayed
clicked through during during the night
I would set up everything just the right
way and then I would go to sleep I would
wake up in the morning and one of two
things happened either I leveled up and
everything was good all uh the book fell
over uh something happened uh the game
was stuck and so this didn't really work
as uh the right way that I expected and
so uh as a young kid I started kind of
looking around and I figured out that
probably there's uh there's a better way
than physical automation
and I wanted to actually automation so I
found uh uh a software that allowed me
to record my screen and my mouse so I I
do a kind of a routine of uh of fishing
and then it reiterated those recorded
actions on top of the uh on top of the
game again and again so uh let's see how
this looks like
so as you can see basically this covers
everything needed in order to uh in
order to fish so I move around I I can
click different parts of the sea so once
this was uh once while once I had this
real automation of course I could also
share it with other people so I kind of
became uh this gave me kind of a became
a shortly for a kind of a hero of my
friends which was which was fun
um and of course this is a silly example
but uh it's also the basis of RPA RPA
works by automating and reiterating The
Mouse and the keyboard or basically
in person I think the user and being
able to run automations uh when uh well
as an as you impersonate a user and of
course it evolved it evolved from there
and we see it in a moment but the main
idea is that RPI can be used in order to
integrate with Legacy systems systems
that don't have an API that only have a
UI and so in order to interact with them
you need to use the mouse and the
keyboard so a quick kind of uh a few
things to note about LPA so uh we
already saw that this is kind of the
idea here that this emulates user
actions we saw the uh we will see that
LPA is essentially was essentially
considered something that will replace
copy and paste integration so you copy
things from one system and you uh and
you move them to the other and the way
that you build RPA is really with the
with no code so you drag and drop things
so you record some sort of a session and
then it will it will uh reiterate and
the use cases we have already covered
some of them but you can see that they
are very strong
business use cases and specifically
Enterprise use cases to use LPA and this
is things this is something that people
are are building within the Enterprise
today
so the next step in order to understand
in order to progress in our story is to
figure out how our API works and before
we uh and this is this is what we're
going to do today uh you know before we
understand how we can leverage RPA for
malware operations we need to figure out
what RPA is uh in a technical level
um and we're going to focus on Windows
11 and on Windows 11 RPA capabilities
and the reason of course is that the
agent the RPA agent for uh for Microsoft
is actually baked into windows 11. so if
you're using a Windows 11 machine I
encourage you search for Power automate
within your laptop you'll find this
agent they're all already there and
that's the reason why we're focusing
here of course any of the exploits that
I will show today are not really tied
only to Windows 11. this is an inherent
problem with RPA
so
um let's start from the user perspective
here's how it looks like if you have a
fresh Windows 11 machine you open up the
start menu and you search for Power
automate you'll find that agent so you
see it it's already kind of baked in
baked in there into windows 11.
the setup side looks something like this
so this is very simple I opened this RPA
agent for the first time I'm going to
need to enter credentials those are
credentials to Microsoft because this is
authenticating to Microsoft services
once I plug in my credentials you can
see that I have a list of things already
available there we'll talk about them in
a moment and now just kind of so you get
a feeling of how things look like this
is the editor that allows you to build
things with power to my desktop
Microsoft LPA you can see that I I'm
picking and two I'm choosing specific
action that writes information to file
I'm going to give a path to that file
and in a moment I'm going to say what I
want to write in that file but you
considered a whole bunch of actions I
could I could take uh so one era when I
run action when I click on action this
thing operates again with my user and
the file is created and there's no real
way to distinguish whether this was done
by that RPA agent on mobile myself now
the crucial piece to note here is the
fact that this is already connected to
this is somewhere connected to the cloud
right because the first thing that I got
when I started this uh when I connected
my my uh uh with my user is actually the
list of payloads here the list of the
different things that this agent is able
to perform now how does that work
imagine that this machine is inside the
corporate Network deep within the
network nobody has talked with the
network security team to open up ports
nobody's talked with the edl teams to
allow certain applications how exactly
does that work
so this is this is what we saw let's see
from an architectural perspective so on
the on this on the left hand we have
power automate which I assume for now
sits in an on-prem environment very
segregated difficult to get outside and
for on the right side you have office
cloud services which are on the public
internet how exactly is the
communication uh being performed here
so first of all power automate is not
actually uh we'll start off with it with
the left side and power automate is not
actually one executable uh but uh there
are a Fields there are several
executables there but also separate
services so as you can see Power
automate itself which is the agent that
actually performs the operation it runs
on the user side within the machine so
we write the trines runs in the context
of a user but it also spawns another
service inside of a new service account
created locally which is this UI flow
service which runs the machine runtime
executable and this executable doesn't
run in the user context and it is the
one that is in charge of of getting
those payloads from the from the cloud
and sending out the results and we'll
see that again in a in just a moment
the uh the capability the one of the
capabilities that uh that power automate
has is also to plug into your browser so
to automate your browser and you can see
that in order to install this and this
is available for all major browsers you
basically need to have uh uh you need to
give this plugin full uh full-on guard
mode on your on your browser and then it
is able to communicate with power
automate to do things like uh change the
behavior of the websites that your
um that you're viewing but also kind of
uh go go to those websites and automate
them on your behalf
so in order to uh to communicate with
the browser there's the extension on the
browser side of course there are also
executables uh on the power automate
side on the desktop side
this is where we typically see the agent
uh this is where it comes off uh
installed pre-installed and you can see
uh that I've I'm showing here the
specific executables that I've discussed
but actually there are a whole bunch of
executables there some of them run on
the user context and others on the on
the service context this is a very uh
these are all pretty new in terms of
their uh putting them into Windows 11
which means that there's a lot of room
for future research here so if you're
interested in checking things around for
yourself I I really recommend checking
us checking out these executables so we
understand uh the left side we
understand how the machine side operates
and when we stop and think about how can
this be how can all of these Services
operate on on your laptop without
everybody without anybody needing to do
a pre-installation because again this
comes built in we realize that this must
be allowed by uh by the edrs especially
Microsoft TDR but also other other ideas
as well so all of these Services all of
these executables
and the and the plugin for the browser
those are all allowed listed inside of
the uh of the VM and the and the things
that are outside of the uh the laptop
and the things that are protecting that
laptop
let's look at the network side so of
course there's a corporate network uh we
assume that there's a corporate Network
here and then there's a question of how
do you go through that corporate Network
how how can you do it without having to
go to Every organization in the world
and ask them to uh to change their
firewall configuration right because
this is what Microsoft has have done
here they have shipped something to
everyone but they didn't have to they
didn't kind of worried out gradually
they just uh put it out there so how
does this work
actually they're using a neat trick here
called using a service called Azure
service bus it used to be called Azure
wheelie which basically creates two-way
communication with when both sides are
using outbound connections and so with
those outbound connections you're able
to bypass the power the firewall and uh
what actually happens is the machine
runtime periodically goes out to this
runtime service bus and basically asked
for uh whether or not there is anything
waiting for it uh in order to uh to
execute it
so uh we understand the connection and
we understand we've seen this the local
side and we've seen that every part of
this connection is actually trusted so
how does this look like from the office
side when you plug in that machine to
the to office what do you see from the
office side so uh it's very cool you get
you basically get all of the management
uh UI that you would require there's a
list of the machines that you have uh uh
that we have imported into your service
I'll show you in a moment how to do that
you can see the status for each one of
those machines you can run payloads from
the cloud to each one of those uh of
those desktops each one of those uh of
those agents that you that you have
infected
um you can also see the status of those
pay of those tasks so each one of those
tasks you'll be able to actually debug
things you understand whether there are
errors
all of those things that would help us
uh make this uh make this very easy or
that would help us basically really run
this malware operation
and so this is what we have what we have
seen so far we understand how uh how RPA
works we understand how it operates with
office and now we are ready for the
juice of the stock which is uh figuring
out how can we use it as hackers to our
own advantage
so this is what we're going to do now
we're going to shift the gear right now
apparently now I've basically given you
all of the uh all of the information
that you need in order to really
understand the exploit so what we're
going to do now is we're going to shift
gear to a practical guide how do you
take all of this information and you
turn it into your own marijuana
and we're going to show all of those
things that we initially started the
talk with calling them our operations
uh and so this is a reminder of the list
of things that we would like to achieve
this is our goal list and now we will
show how we can achieve each one of
those so first of all a bit of setup in
order to use this exploit we are
creating a new tenant a new Microsoft
tenant which is a malicious tenant and
of course this is very easy you can get
a trial you don't have to plug in your
credit card when you start by creating
this tenant you will get a screen
inviting you to add machines into that
tenant basically onboard your users into
that tenant
so in order to onboard our users which
are not really our users but the people
will uh but are victims so the ones that
we would like to plug into our malware
operation after we have an initial
access
um first of all uh we saw that you can
do this registration through the UI
right so I I plugged in my own email and
then uh there was kind of an ORF pop-up
for office and then I was in but of
course we don't really want to do this
on a vector machine because uh well it
would be very suspicious and it's also
not automatable so can we avoid using
the UI
uh yes so fortunately Microsoft has a
neat little script that again is it
comes built in with windows that allows
you either with command line or with
Powershell to register those machines
and the uh the script is is conveniently
called machine registration silent and
so you can see that I I'm simply running
this executable on the victim machine
with and I'm connecting it to my own
malicious malicious Microsoft tenant and
uh the cool thing about this again is
that this uh this command line is the
only thing that you need in order to
onboard your victim your victim into
into the into your manual operation and
you're using as a assigned executable uh
so once once we do that and this is this
is again this is the piece well this is
how you infect uh user machines and so
once we do that
you will see the machine pop up on your
on your power automate office basically
on your management portal
um one thing that I'm not sure if you've
seen if you've uh if you were able to
spot it before uh but the one problem
here is that the script requires admin
permissions which is kind of annoying
and so we try to poke around and see
whether or not we can make it whether we
can make it to run as a single as a
simple user and actually uh it just
worked so we didn't do anything special
here we simply use the Powershell script
and it worked and so you can register a
machine to your malware operation
without having to be uh to be an admin
in terms of the cloud setup once the
machine is registered here's what you
need to do in order to run payloads of
that machine so first of all you create
a trigger from the cloud you plug in the
information related to that machine
because we are starting with initial
access so you should have those
available and then you you choose each
other each one of the payloads that has
already been be created so you have you
can create them or you can create a new
one and then you run those on the on the
machine but this is where we encounter a
small problem what if this user rxg is
already logged into the machine what
will happen
so essentially two things RPA already
handles this this problem
um there are two types of RPA tasks one
is that if Alex is already logged in we
will simply join his session and run
things alongside you know alongside RX
and so uh this this would not be
something that uh that we that they uh
that the 100 will notice we will see how
this looks like in a moment a bit but we
are basically uh taking over their
session and allowing them to continue to
operate uh on their own if Alex is not
uh currently authenticated we will it
will automatically create a new session
for us and then a discount of that
session when we're done
so this is already covered by by LPA
so just from the basics
we've already covered three of the main
things that we wanted to cover the first
thing is deploying malware we understand
how this looks like is simply that
command line defensive version is pretty
obvious after we've seen the
architecture because again these are all
trusted executables trusted Services
trusted uh cloud services and so uh the
only malicious thing here is a malicious
office account but there's no one to
know that it's malicious and in terms of
persistency this again comes built in
because even if somebody kicks us off
that machine Microsoft will will go back
the next time that we're sending a
payload to that machine and and run us
again and so we don't need to be uh we
don't we all we're already covered in
terms of persistency on the machine
itself
now let's see some payloads so let's uh
we're going to see the three things that
are uh that we uh that are still on on
our list which is command and control
exfiltration and cleanup
let's start with a data exfiltration so
this is a very simple payload you can
see that I'm I'm simply I'm I'm giving
in as input uh a file a specific file
that I would like to explain from the
machine and
the output variables contain the actual
file content so and the flow is very
simple I am going I'm uh I do have kind
of error handling there but actually I'm
just reading a file into a variable and
then uh setting out setting it out as an
output now uh one interesting question
is where does this output go
so it goes to the cloud side when you
run this machine from the cloud side the
outputs will uh the input comes from the
cloud to the machine and then the output
gets routed back to your cloud and now
it is let's make sure we understand how
exactly does this work how exactly does
the file content on the laptop reach the
cloud without anybody finding out in the
way so this is the uh architecture that
we've already seen and here's that
architecture with the data data leakage
payload overlay so the first step we go
into office we set up the instructions
the second step we send the payload and
this payload goes out on the Azure
service bus connection
basically the machine runtime will reach
out to other service bus ask for a new
payload and it will get the exfiltrate
data payload from us with the Target and
then the output would also be forwarded
on that on that channel and so
that's why nobody will see inside of the
Enterprise the fact that there's a data
expectation here because again this is
this uses that trusted communication to
office
so uh we saw that acceleration next
let's try and uh let's try and tackle a
command and control so and by commanding
controller I mean I don't want to be
stuck only with things that are uh I
don't want to see that to to be stuck
with only specific payloads I would like
to be able to do everything that I would
have wanted or that I would want in the
future on inside of the victims machine
so here's a a first attempt and a very
quick attempt so you can see that
actually power automate comes built in
with a way for you to run scripts so you
can run a shell script you can run the
command line script and so this is a
payload that basically gets uh asks you
which interpreter you would like to use
and then for the command itself and then
it will run that command on the machine
and send out the script output and arrow
STD out the studio let's see how it
works
oh so the so when we try to actually run
this we encounter the problem because
once this is this runs and the command
line runs uh the edl catches us because
of course uh we are running a command
line we are running uh something uh kind
of a malicious uh a malicious command uh
in one of those uh
interfaces that that uh Power automate
uh uh supports and so this is how it
looks like this is what we get why we
get caught on one side we have the RPA
engine and the drag and drop interface
that is all trusted
so nobody would catch you on the things
that you're doing over on the things
that you're accomplishing with the agent
itself but once you spawn a command line
of course the idea will will look at it
because this is the main thing that it
looks at so anything that you would
write here if you would try to run some
sort of a road kit of course it's
untrusted so it will be caught and so
the question becomes what can we achieve
from the just by staying in The Trusted
part because as you can see there there
is some program in there right because I
I have I have a I need to handle the
inputs I need to handle the outputs
there are things that are happening uh
within that agent itself within the uh
The Trusted part is
and so what can we do only with those
drag and drop derivatives
actually we can do quite a lot so these
are this is a a non-comprehensive list
of the kind of things that you can do so
you can uh you can use a crypto to
encrypt file you can trigger HTTP you
can communicate with that active
directory with Windows Windows processes
and windows Services you can look at
files and folders uh you can you can use
the browser you can take screenshots you
can automate The Mouse and the keyboard
you can go into the clipboard so I'm
sure your mind is racing right now with
the amount of things that are that are
possible with these low code Primitives
and we'll start with a very quick
example uh showing off how do we build a
no code run somewhere only with these
Primitives
so here it is uh basically I'm going uh
I'm getting as an input three parameters
uh director a directory that I would
like to encrypt the encryption key and
the call depth so how many steps do I
take inside of the subdirectories there
and then
um and then what what is what the script
actually does it goes and iterates all
of the directories that subdirectories
it reads out the files it encrypts them
with the very helpful uh encrypt a file
action that is baked into Power automate
and then I override that file
um so let's see a demo of how this works
so I started off at the cloud I'm
entering the parameters that I need in
order to run this uh to to run this
ransomware or send the encryption key
the directory uh and it is already
plugged into the user's machine now the
payload is being sent through the secure
channel into the user's machine and uh
it's back and I'm getting the results
back so you can see that this is very
very easy uh to actually do it you can
see it from the uh from the uh victim
side the files are encrypted
next up uh we actually know that there
are a whole bunch of there's a whole
bunch of telemetry that is being created
by this agent uh when when things are
running so of course we would like to
clean that up uh and this is a simple
flow that cleans up after ourselves so
again we understand we know exactly when
those where those logs are saved so why
not just go ahead and delete them and
this is exactly what this flow does so
it goes out to those uh to those places
where the agent is Towing slugs and
simply deletes them that it's those
loops
so we saw data exploration we saw
cleanup uh and we also saw a way for you
to build any any automation that you'd
like or any payload that you would like
using those no code Primitives and
specifically we saw one so no code to
answer well one more thing I want to
show you which was actually not on our
list but it's a uh it's a nice bonus is
actually what can we do with the browser
because remember that power automate the
power automate desktop is able to
operate the browser on the user's behalf
so here's the idea uh we would like to
basically steal tokens for for other
services the user is already logged into
so in this case I'm going to State the
token of uh of power automate uh Cloud
so the cloud part of that same which is
part of the office suite and so the idea
is pretty simple I go to this uh I open
a browser in a minimized session I
opened it uh that URL that that service
that I would like to steal the cookie of
and then I simply extract the cookie or
the token from that website
so here's how it looks like from inside
of the machine this is the payload I'm
running I'm launching I'm launching
Chrome I'm sending out on a specific
address I'm using the uh I'm I'm
actually sending out the control uh so
going out to see the source and then I
will fetch some things from the header
you can see that when I ran this this
automation what actually happened was
the the browser popped up there which is
kind of not really good but I did get
the token so in order to make sure that
the browser doesn't pop up like that I
can simply change the windows status for
maximize to minimize and that and that
would prevent it from happening again
and so you can see uh that all of these
things are actually covered uh by by
windows and powered for power automate
for us so this is pretty easy and
actually uh after uh and actually we've
actually been able to generalize this
and create a payload that basically you
give it a host name and in return it
will give you the cookies for for that
hosting
here's how it looks like uh from the
Victor machine side so after I go first
of all uh here's how it looks like from
the uh from the attackers perspective
I'm sending out the pla the payload to
to steal the token and again the payload
is being sent to a victim machine and
then on the victim machine uh where
nothing happens right
um so that's that's the main point here
uh users won't really be able to notice
that anything is happening uh because
all of this because the agent is baked
in and we don't have to open up a new uh
new browser or Windows for them
so a quick recap into what have you seen
so far we've seen how to deploy malware
by simply using a building command line
we see now to avoid this we think that
this method inherently avoids detection
and also uh remain remains persistent
because Microsoft will just put you
again and we saw how to do command and
Control Data exploration we also saw
ransomware and cleanup operations and as
a bonus we saw how to fetch credentials
from the browser
everything that you saw up at the Lao
had to use that interface the drag and
drop interface that Microsoft provides
and so in order to make life easier for
us but also easier for you so you can
use everything that you learned today as
part of your retina Arsenal I'm very
happy to introduce to you uh PowerPoint
PowerPoint is a tool that we've built in
order to uh to automate all of those
things so you can basically use it as
part of your uh as part as part of your
scenario and plug it with other tools
that you're using uh Power automate
PowerPoint actually does much more than
just what you saw here so uh it allows
you to uh basically trigger all of the
operations that you saw here today and
others using an HTTP endpoint and then
uh it does it l it it handles arrows for
you it then there's retries for you and
some edge cases where we need to uh
where we hand it for you so you don't
have to think about it
here's what this ends up looking like
you once you install this tool you get a
single endpoint and when you post to
that endpoint and of course it is
protected by a secret but you can run it
without being authenticated so you can
avoid uh kind of attribution
um you basically post a something a
payload or a request for a payload on a
specific machine uh to that to that HTTP
endpoint uh and the tool will run that
payload for you on the 10 points and
return the results
and of course in order to make sure that
is there is much that is even more
easier for you uh there's a there's a
python python convenience layer around
it
um and and you can find all of the
details here in the GitHub in the GitHub
link uh let me click let me uh make it
easy to understand or to give a quick
recap into what you need to do to use
this tool first of all
um you register your a free RPA account
and there's a tutorial there on how to
do it you register each one of those
machines that you your victim machines
with the command line and then you can
just use the convenience layer or the
API itself in order to run the payloads
and the reason for uh raising this this
tool is of course in order to help to to
help you learn to help you teach people
around you about the risks of of no code
and particularly RPA and to be defenses
that defenses around it and so
with that with the tool
um let's let's see a quick summary into
what we have done uh today we saw what
RPA is we thought it's available in
every major Enterprise and we took a
very deep dive into how RPA operates and
how it was able to and how Microsoft was
able to basically turn it on by default
in every Windows 11 machine in the world
without talking to any I.T Department in
any organization this is already there
the second fix that we saw is how do you
abuse LPA how to use LPA to basically
send out those payloads and receive the
uh the uh the outputs of those payloads
and we saw those no code Primitives and
I really called you try and play around
with them yourself uh you you'll see
you'll see it
um we saw PowerPoint and we and the next
thing the only thing that I have left is
to show you uh concrete thing that you
can do to reduce your risk
okay so let me go quickly through that
uh here are here are four uh suggestions
concrete suggestions that you can take
in order to protect yourself the first
thing is you need to monitor for those
registration scripts by Microsoft I put
them both here you also find information
inside of the documentation that I that
I've linked here
um that would really help reduce your
risk you need to find usage of those
executables across your organization
everything that is not that doesn't
belong to your organization that when
these executables are talking with
another tenant is extremely important to
monitor but you should also monitor your
own tenants so if you're a Microsoft
user if you use office or use Windows
this is part of what you your users are
probably already using it for their own
automations and this can also lead to a
whole bunch of security issues
um and and but this is a kind of a topic
for Ronaldo there are I mean many links
here for you to to be able to actually
to learn more and everything that I've
shared here today the links the source
code uh the demos everything is
available in the link right here thank
you very much everyone