so good morning everyone
um reason here from Kuala Lumpur
representing BAE Systems
um thank you for this opportunity this
is our second time
um delivering our research on besides
Singapore
um the last presentation was done last
year
um let's not waste time and let's start
with our presentation the topic today
we'd like to speak about is about
uncovering zero days in Healthcare
Management applications
um three one of the researchers involved
is Aiden Ali and myself
next slide please
the agenda for this uh short talk would
include some background on the the VR
um some past statistics that we have
gathered and then we move on to the
technical findings this disclosure
timeline and last but not least the
conclusion and what we have learned from
this VR
next
slide please thank you all right so we
chose open EMR it's an open source
system it's used in about 5 000
installations according to the website
and because it's fully open source
they are there's a flexibility of us of
using the source code to do a white box
analysis now we we chose this method and
we also chose this particular software
in in in particular because we also did
some background checks on on the
software
um one mainly is that it's widely used
secondly most importantly it has been
receiving and Publishing uh cves
for the few years in the past
um if you see the next slide
over here since 20 2012 this this um cve
history was taken from the uh my trail
website and as you can see there have
been accepting
um security bugs from researchers since
2012.
and this is what led us to choose open
EMR as
um the source of our uh VR project yeah
and as you can see uh um in in the past
there were a couple of critical and high
vulnerabilities reported and the last
one uh was reported in 2021 and in fact
in 2022 we contributed um some of it
next slide please
now the the VR project I mean the VR
analysis is not rocket science but
before we dwelve into the um
um the the project we had to First
analyze and find out what
vulnerabilities were discovered in the
past by other researchers now um we when
we googled we found that project
insecurity
um another
um VR group out there had already
published
dozens of SQL injections rce's since um
when was it in in the last last year or
so right in 2021 in particular so with
this discovery we we knew that there was
a challenge because if the code base did
not change much
um it might mean that we might not find
um the the high severity vulnerabilities
like SQL and rce but any anyway we we
still decided to to pursue this project
open near
um as as our VR project because we felt
that it's a challenge but at the same
time
um we know that the project is open to
receiving security bugs
now a bit more of um research before we
actually start the project
um there was a website sonar blog that
reported in 2020
um a couple of high severity
vulnerabilities were published as you
can see the cves are here this was for
version open EMR 5.0.21
right and this posed a challenge to us
but nevertheless uh it did not deter us
from uh pursuing the the VR um uh
research
now we'll move on to the
um how how do I say the process of
researching uh finding this box now the
box that we found are not rocket science
yeah um we are not full-time security
researchers um we we are a bunch of pen
testers and great teamers
um our job is is not really to do
security research but we take on this
opportunity uh in between projects when
when we when we don't have uh anything
else to do uh we delve into VR so we
have about maybe a month uh in in a year
to to share that time among the three of
us to just have a look and and see what
we can find using the same methodology
that we used uh in in a typical pen test
now firstly on on the left hand side
here you see there there is a manual
source code analysis and black box
testing so we combine these two method
by downloading the the source code and
analyzing it
um manually by our eye and and also
using Black Box testing meaning uh we
use uh burp suite for example to just
fuss the endpoints now what we found um
were two very very common bugs that we
we mainly find in a typical uh pen test
project
um the first one is the insufficient
authorization checks or Idols some
people call it authorization issue and
secondly we found a lot of cross-site
scripting errors so with a combination
of of these two we produce the pocs and
and uh we we just put together a report
and we notified the open EMR project uh
we're pretty sure that they are active
and and they were receiving
um bug reports from us and they they
immediately acknowledged it and um so
after we submitted the POC and the
reports uh it took them a while to fix
it uh we'll go through the timeline and
after they have fully uh rectified the
bugs and published the um the fixes uh
we decided to um how do you say I
registered this this box uh in in my
track for for cves
now this this is the uh overall uh
status of of the project that we took on
so it's a open EMR um open source uh
electronic medical record system
um the version that we we researched was
version 6.0 the latest release version
was January 5th 2021 this might have
already changed
um and mentioned here the security
researchers involved and the type of
bugs that we found in total we found
eight vulnerabilities however is more
than that we didn't want to bloated too
much one particular vulnerability in
respect to the idols we had over 60 of
them and my colleague Aiden will walk
will walk through some of it
but we we categorize most of the
vulnerabilities into just eight of them
and as you can see here this this are
the breakdown of each vulnerability that
we found
um mainly uh two highs
um one two three four five five lows and
uh and one sorry six lows and one sorry
six medium and one low
now let's start with the first one uh I
mentioned about the idol the typical uh
authorization issue this this is a very
typical uh common vulnerability that we
find uh where a non-privileged user uh
such as an accountant or a front office
person can actually view patient records
so the patient records are mainly
reserved for privileged users such as
the medical staff and what we found was
by logging in into a lower privileged uh
user account we were able to see uh
patient medical records that contain a
pii such as their name their their date
of birth the type of medical ailments
that and the treatment that they are
receiving
and um basically this issue is very
easily rectified
um it's the the authorization cookie
um that was not checked there was no um
ACL
um authorization uh check on the the
corresponding page on the vulnerable
pages to to validate whether the user is
allowed to view that particular record
or not so if you look at the bottom here
the affected URL we mentioned
specifically the endpoint the open EMR
interface patient file summary record
disclosure and now this particular URL
is is submitted in the get request it's
it requires authentication meaning you
have to have at least
um a low privileged user account
um and if you know the particular uh if
you know this particular endpoint the
factor endpoint all you got to do is
just plug this into your into your
browser and you should be able to view
the patient record at the end here there
is a parameter
you edit lit which I can't see because
my avatar is blocking um can we go to
the next slide please
okay so this is how the records look
like if you are locked on as um
administrator now these are the a sample
patient record that we just created just
some test records uh as you know um we
downloaded the source code we we load
them into a VM running Apache Linux and
and yeah we just created um some tests
test user accounts we test data and now
as logging in as an administrator you
should be able to see this record that's
normal now what we did was second page
by tempering the the the endpoint the
URL I mentioned just now uh using the
accounting one user we can still view
the patient record
as you can see over here the like the
the demographics the documents the
transactions the medical record panel is
still visible right and it's very very
simple I mentioned it it is a get
statement which we will see in the next
page
so this this is the the vulnerable
endpoint where I mentioned the edit lit
equals to three now just by changing
this this number uh incrementing it um
three four five six and so forth you'll
be able to view other users record now
the only thing is that um the cookie
here
um highlighted in red this is the
accountant user cookie now
by right he should not be able to access
that endpoint using this cookie
so it's as simple as just knowing which
endpoint to browse to in your in in your
web browser and you will be able to view
the patient record it's that
straightforward so moving to the next
slide please
and this is how it looks like if you
don't use book so for example
um if you just open up your browser
login as a accountant one which is a low
privileged user and it just so happened
that you know the the endpoint that
points to the medical record just plug
it into the browser change the parameter
um at the end there the edit equals to
three incremented by by one and you will
be able to see other patient records
which you should not so this is a
typical classic Idol case and uh not
very difficult to discover
um I guess the the last security
researchers were very focused on the SQL
injections and the rce
um perhaps it could be that or perhaps
maybe the the code base was was changed
after uh the research
now in in the next slide here
uh what I did was I went I wanted to
find out uh what was the issue
um we know it's an idol issue so I I
traced back to to the PHP page that was
responsible for displaying this data and
it boiled down to the record
disclosure.php now when I looked at it I
just looked at the at the top uh first
uh 30 lines uh I noticed there are no
ACL checks there so this page is open
for for anyone uh that has a valid
session ID a session cookie for example
now after we have submitted this box
this this box was discovered in version
six uh after we have discovered it we
submitted it took them a while to fix it
and in version 6.1 what I noticed was
from line number 23 to 27 they added the
ACL check
and at the same time line 31 onwards
also they added another ACL check there
and if you press enter Eden
there you go so this these were the two
checks they added after the uh I mean to
fix the bug after version six so it's
quite it's quite straightforward um it
just do uh that's a check
um whether the the records uh uh should
be displayed to this particular user if
the user does not have the authorization
it will just uh spill uh not authorize
uh error message and then exit that
function so that's how that's how we we
found out uh how they fixed the issue
and um next slide please so now I'm
going to pass this to my colleague so I
mentioned that uh we we recorded only
eight vulnerabilities yeah but in one in
this particular vulnerability the idol
there's actually 62 of them but we are
not out to to amass um 62 cves yeah we
just want to make our point so we we
just um open up another uh finding and
I'll pass it to to Aiden to um give his
explanation on uh the further analysis
of the idols found on on the other Pages
go ahead okay cool can you hear me right
uh okay uh good morning everyone my name
is Eden I'm going to talk about the cve
2022-2493 is a missing uh function level
access control issue in this uh open EMR
they are total five user rules that one
is the super admin which have the access
to all the modules
and another four user rule are
considered as a standard user but they
have their own modules and permission
based on my findings this four standard
user Rose were able to access to server
admin modules none other than that I
found that the four standard user rules
have a promiscuous previous issue
meaning that for example accounting
users supposed to view the building and
payment info but in this case the front
office visitation and creation can view
the billing and payment
also this concludes that this is a
access control issue usually this type
of vulnerability can't be picked up by
automator 2 as you require a manual
testing to identify it in total we found
62 vulnerable endpoint in this
application with the last number
instance so we consolidate them into one
CV one issue because they are in the
same category
and I don't think they will issue us a
62 cve for us and the recommendation for
this issue is don't relying on the UI to
implement the access control
and require a server-side validation
and this is the list of the vulnerable
endpoints
I only show part of it here because
there are too many
uh red red color Bots you see here
meaning that the user is unauthorized to
access to the modules green you see here
is the user is authorized to access to
the audience what I would like to
highlight here is that there are several
admin modules can be accessible by any
standard user rules
and also we can see that the front
office visitation creation can be
assessed by any of the uh can access to
the billing and the payment info
which only can access by the accounting
I will show some example in the
following slide
the first POC is any user to admin
modules any user can access to the me
modules in order to export this
vulnerability we need to identify the
employees of the modules this is how the
open EMR mean that spot looks like so
when I try to browse through the effect
module score form Administration
um as we can see the far path is
remaining the same
stratman.php it will be the same if we
browse to another modules as well there
are some process on the back that we
cannot see by our Naked Eyes
in all in order for us to discover the
real path we can use the inspect element
in the browser
and release it but this is not very user
friendly
therefore we can use a POS C2 called
bird Suite
uh this is one of the essential tool for
the web security testing I believe maybe
some of you may use or seen before in
the bird Suite policy we can capture all
the HTTP requests before sending to the
server as we can see that I can capture
the multiple endpoint from the
application but the key finding here is
the form and mean endpoint that I
highlighted
um now we have the effected URL the next
thing we need to do is to log into the
lowest Prius user in the application in
this case I use Frank office what we can
see
from the front of this dashboard is
there is no administrator header meaning
that there is no way for us to go to the
navigate to the admin modules if we
don't know the endpoint
we can browse to the effected URL that
we captured earlier to unauthorize
access to the admin modules with the
access to these modules that are the
unauthorized user is allowed to modify
the phone access control
within the application meaning that this
module is allowed attacker to gain more
access to another modules
Sams go to the this example the front
office
don't have the right to access to a
building manager
as we can see there is no
fees header in this uh uh front office
dashboard
menu
on the bot but this is not this but in
this case we can access the bill manager
on the bottom of the picture we can see
there is a patient uh building record
and we click and go further on the
record we can we can see the patient
payment and we also can issue the
billing without paying any fee that's it
for the PLC for of this cve actually
they are more instant but due to the
timing of this presentation we only
selected these two that I think is the
most impactful example
I will pass it to Lee to present his
next uh findings yeah thank you Eden
um morning everyone my name is Mohammad
Ali
um I will present the vulnerability that
I found which I'm privileged user can
create a new rule and lead to stored
crosstalk scripting
um so this issue is that that
unpublished using that that include
accounting and also front office they
can create a
a new rule and inject a web script on
the vulnerable endpoint and with the
vulnerable parameter
so the payload could triggered a stored
SSS in the plane rules and that can only
be accessible by privileged user or
admin using
our recommendation is quite simple do
not trust any control user input
parameter that sent to the server and
ensure it to sanitize it before
displaying or reflecting it on the
website
and overall we found four store SSS in
one reflected SSS and all of these
vulnerabilities need to be authenticated
to reproduce the issue
so before I jump to the issue
reproduction of the cve 2020 to 1179 I
will show you what is inside openmrcms
so inside this application there are a
lot of forms modules and subcategory
inside the openmsms for me as a beginner
in variety research
you might face overwhelmed and struggle
you can press enter and then they might
be two more yep and with these things
you might want to find what is the best
methodology that you want to use while
switching so I focus more into SSS and
found one simple that need to be used
but also efficient and I will explain it
on the next slide
so
um imagine that when we try to browse
into some pages in the applications
um we might encounter a lot of inputs so
what we can do is we just use a simple
payload like script and alert and
utilize Ctrl C and Ctrl V
so what I did is I take note of the
endpoints that I found and set a range
for that endpoints only
for example on this input that you can
see I put a range 1 until 9
um and take note of that endpoints so
when we browse again to different pages
and found new forms
yeah you can press enter then yeah thank
you and we can see that we set a
different range for example 10 until 11
and again take note of that endpoints so
keep doing this and always take note of
the range of numbers that we did and
that endpoints so by doing this when we
try to browse into different pages we
might see a pop-up with different
numbers
so why we're doing this is to ensure
that we identify where is the payload
coming from and since we are going to
browse into different endpoints and we
might not see the SSS reflected on the
same pages but it might be reflected on
different pages inside the application
and that how how we could get the CVS
that related to the SSS
and now I'm going to explain the issue
reproduction for this cve 2020 20179
as you can see uh in the image the
administrator page will have a sub
category of rules in the UI
but not in the case of accounting user
they do not have any access of the
subcategory of rules in the UI
so what we did is
um we intercept the request of an admin
and trying to create a new rule and we
can change the cookie to continue or non
unprivileged user and we also identified
that one of the parameters is vulnerable
to SSS so we can inject it with SSS
cookie still payload
and using Fetch and by using fetch it
will not redirect but it will just make
a request to the targeted server or
attack the server and we pass the
document cookie in the URL parameter of
C
so for example if an admin trying to go
or browse into the page of rules and
view any rules eventually
if you send a request to
um the attacker as you can see in here
we have the admin cookie in the URL
parameter of C
so with this cookie the attacker could
use it and utilize it to further their
malicious intent so what we can what
they can do is they can update in their
browser of their admin cookie or if they
have the endpoints that they want they
might change it in the book Suite
requests and the cookie headers
and
um if you press enter again all right
thank you you can see that if the
attacker browse into any endpoints even
though that we are Accounting in the
browser but the endpoints will still see
us as administrator and they might do a
lot of things into you and that's how we
can reproduce this issue and I will hand
over to reason for the next slide thank
you
thanks Ali
all right so let's go through the
disclosure timeline
now we initially reported the findings
in December sorry September 2021 uh we
received a couple of back and forth
emails um from the open EMR
from the open EMR security team up to at
least uh 4th of October 2021 after which
they said that the release of the
patches will come in batches and it was
only in April 24th 2022 that all the
bugs all all 60 plus the ones the plus
eight cves were fully touched and only
then we started
um triaging it to my tray to get the
cves issued now this was a challenge
um but nevertheless we made it and the
full disclosure timeline and information
details everything were published
now um these are some of the learning
curves
um learning nuggets that we we learned
yeah
um firstly we focus on bugs with
business impact
um we we skip all the sillies things
like missing security haters weak
ciphers stuff like that
um we use the source code for for
analysis
um and I think the most important is the
third item choosing your VDP targets
wisely this was a tactical move rather
than the technical move because we
didn't want to choose a VDP or a project
where they they did not um how they say
that they don't respond to you or they
say you you are not allowed to fully
disclose your findings
um the worst case scenario is that they
might not even acknowledge the work that
you have given so that's why I at the
first few slides I mentioned that uh we
analyze our our VDP programs pretty
carefully before we decide to actually
move in on it but at the same time we
know that um a lot of the high severity
bugs the the SQL injections the rces
were already discovered but we felt that
they if we dig a bit deeper we should be
able to find and we were right about it
so um don't don't be discouraged if you
see programs where they were previously
a lot of uh Hunters that have already
reported bugs they might still be some
insight there
um I I mentioned about triaging
um going through my trade was um I
wouldn't say difficult but it was a bit
time consuming um so we we used
um uh hunter.dev hunter.dev I really
shout out to them they helped us a lot
um they they triage all
um security bugs reported to them um in
GitHub so go ahead and check them out
um if you have any uh bucks that you
find in in GitHub uh repositories you
can triage it through Hunter and and
they they help you to uh they even give
uh uh cash bounties but unfortunately we
couldn't accept them because we were
doing this on behalf of our organization
and um the money was was not never
claimed
um but um they they helped us to issue
the cve in a timely fashion another
point to to state is that we are
depending on the the kind of targets
that that you um experiment or research
in it's not it doesn't mean it has to be
difficult uh it is suitable for for
beginners too uh in fact we we are not
full-time security researchers we are
full-time pen testers and red teamers
um so doing VR is is more like a
tactical uh move uh rather than a
technical one
um the the vulnerabilities that we found
are common OAS vulnerabilities
and uh I think last but not least is uh
working as a team and sharing your
knowledge so learning learning from my
colleagues and um and also learning from
what's what's out there um it really
helped us uh to sharpen our skills in in
VR and also at the same time sharpen our
skills in in regular pen testing that we
do on a daily basis
um that's all for our presentation uh
thank you for your time uh we'll be
taking questions in uh in Discord or
over here I guess