[Music]
hello everyone and thank you for joining
i'm only i'm from microsoft's azure
defender for iot group
today i'll be talking about two remote
code execution vulnerabilities i found
in a popular
physical security system which you
probably also know as an alarm system
i won't only be talking about those two
vulnerabilities but i'll also be showing
you a full exploit chain leading from
the vulnerability itself up until the
point where the alarm is disarmed
so we don't have a lot of time let's
start
some general background information i
wasn't actually working on this specific
project i was working on another project
i was looking for vulnerabilities in a
open source
network stack called lwip it's a pretty
popular one mainly with the low-end
devices
so while looking around at sudan i found
a lot of devices that
i use lwip and are connected to the
internet and i wanted to figure out
what are those devices so surprisingly
the majority of those devices
a
wall
from the same lwip version
which was super interesting to me so i
looked around it and
tried to figure out what are those
devices
so looking at a some device for example
from spain some endpoint you can see
that it has an interesting
panel and it says you must activate your
javascript
and a some login page in here
so and another endpoint for example for
more mania a as is this
a very
a similar banner and a login page that
looks almost the same
after digging for a while with with this
information i finally understood that
uh it was a product from a company named
paradox paradox is a popular canadian
manufacturer of physical security
systems
and and more specifically
what you saw earlier in sudan came from
this
network model ip 150 internet model
which
works with the whole range of alarm
systems that paradox manufacture
so fast forward
we got the equipment and this is it
so what you see in here in this little
metal box is actually
uh first the control panel and the sp
4000 control panel in the alarm system
jargon
is the main board is the motherboard is
where everything connects to
then we have the internet module in here
with some
cheap plastic on it so after peeling the
plastic you can see that
it's quite a simple board
uh
in here we have an arm chip
on it
which came from st electronics it's an
stm
32f
chip
which is an arm compatible a chip
for embedded devices
then we have
this keypad in here
uh which you probably know it can it's
in most places it's installed right next
to the door and you can put the code and
arm
the alarm system before leaving the
building
uh and besides that we have the power
supply here
so i cropped the image a bit so we can
talk about protocols
uh so first we have the internet model
it goes to the public internet via
standard ethernet
connection
and on the other side it connects to the
a control board
with a proprietary serial protocol so
the ip150 is actually a kind of a bridge
between ethernet and serial protocol
a a down a on the down part we have the
keypad which also connects with the same
serial protocol
and we didn't purchase those but
a generally speaking the sensors the
silence would connect also to the
control board
that's how it looks like on my desk
there is the laptop in here it connects
directly
and we'll later see how and why
so let's start with the fun
a in those kind of project the first
thing that you that i want to do
is normally getting female updates
because i want the female itself and
that's the easiest way to go
so i got this device it's called this a
software sorry it's called infield
uh paradox supplies it
to the clients in order to a install
female updates on the whole range of
devices
so this is actually an older version of
infield than the current one it shows
that because it gives me the option to
select what i want to download and
download it locally
so i chose
the internet model and got the file uh
which is named ip150 the version and dot
path
i suspect that the path is a paradox
update file maybe paradox
update format uh anyways
i asked minwork to check it for me and
didn't get any result and looking at the
entropy it's pretty clear why
uh it seemed to be encrypted or might be
compressed but i guess that encrypted
so let's just take a quick look on the
firmware itself
uh it's a comparison between version 4
and version 3 of the female 4 the same
device
we can see that most of the data in here
is a actually the same
between both versions
uh we can see that we have the version
id
probably the version id here and in here
and that we have the data itself that
encrypted all compass data
in here which is a different
[Music]
so at that point i want i wanted to
either decrypt or decompress the data
i assumed it it might be sold or some
simple encryption simple standard
encryption because of this repeated a
pattern
which most of the time indicate it's a
simple so encryption but wasn't very
successful with that i fought with that
for a week
and doing the fast forward thing again
i finally
looked online
and i was able to find in some github
a post for mega form a guy girl which
goes by the name of nes mogos
uh which did excellent work decrypting
uh the firmware
uh and he actually uploaded for everyone
who wants to play with reverse
engineering
uh in 2018
so i actually reached him uh because
it's an old post i reached him and i
asked
and he suggested that he'll decrypt the
newer version for me
and
finally i got the decryption decrypted a
femwell
which
strings looks like that
so we have the ad there we have some
server in here and we have a lot of
some kind of data so what is that that
data
it's actually x intel hex encoded
and intellects works like that so we
have the separator in here
and in each
a part describes a some kind of data and
where it should
it should go
uh a checksum
in the byte count the size
so i just
took a quickly took a a python library
fixed some bugs in there until it worked
and finally i got the decrypted payload
which the firmware actually loads only
in memory
and did some strings on it and we can
see immediately that there is something
interesting in here although it's not
quite the firmware there's no no a lot
of strings in here and the editor seems
to indicate that it might be some kind
of internet bootloader
so now starting with reverse engineering
i loaded everything to a jira and
immediately spotted that there is
something in here
those other cells that seem to make
sense are taking into account that most
um firmwares start with a vector table
which describes the initial stack
pointer the main function which goes by
the name of reset
and and some other interrupt handlers so
that seems pretty good taking into
account that
uh the memory ranges in here that's uh
an image taken from the data sheet of
the stm chip
the memory ranges of the ram
matched the stack pointer address
and the flash the the film itself
matched those addresses so that must be
our main function
which is a really good indication so i
just went over and and reverse
engineered the film well
i needed to guess the base address so
things would
come along like nicely
and it seems like there is no operating
system no real-time operating system
just a plain female
and it it seems that it does all
it does a only a fetching
a female former remote server
using some proprietary protocol and
which is also encrypted
so taking a deep
breath will start
i set it up a man in the middle
where the device the alarm system
connects to my laptop which dumps the
network traffic with wildshark
when it goes to the server
and on the other hand i used infield in
the vm uh to i
tell him to start that's a newer version
and just tell the device going and start
update then i was able to dump the old
communication with wild shock
and i got that
so
on a brief look i was able to spot the
encrypted firmware because it started
with eb 619c
which i knew
from exploring the puff file that is the
beginning of the encrypted data
and for a fairly good reason eb 1699c
is always this header ip150
on the decrypted path
so that's pretty good news it seems to
be decrypted and encrypted so with the
same encryption algorithm using the
pathfile
and there is some
some header in here
so the header itself is is made up of a
magic number
a
that is just compared a packet size
which is little endian encoded
and a checksum which is a really simple
cumulative
checksum
they just count all of the bytes
together and get
two bytes check some
and regarding the encryption um i did a
quick python script
which is just a python version of the
encryption algorithm from the firmware
decryption algorithm
so it looks pretty similar
the encryption itself is not
i think it's a proprietary encryption
it's not very complex
but not very simple either
[Music]
so i just did the script and i tried to
decrypt the data
and those are the strings that i got
so you can see
that we have some kind of an html file
in here
and that we have several other html
files by name
some memory manager exceptions some
registers in here seems pretty good
seems like the the actual a firmware to
me
so just to summarize up in this point we
got the device
we decrypted the path with the help of
our friend
decrypted the x encoded in memory
payload
reversing engineered it and using the
main individual setup dumped
the a female form network and decrypted
it
and now we'll get into this point
to the point where
we can actually
investigate
how
the web interface works this login page
and we know there is some involvement of
lwip in here and there is some web
server
but that now we're in the state in the
state where we
really want to
explore that
part
so lw ip as i said is a pretty popular
open source um
each vendor has to implement
only the network interface and then we
have like the ip
layer
and the tcp and high level protocols
such as dns and applications like web
servers
specifically the web server that comes
along with lwip
is a pretty nice web server and
it's a static one also
so the way that that works is that as a
programmer if i want to use
index.html for example
i'll a go and a use
a make fs data utility that comes along
with lwip and that utility will will
actually take the data from index.html
and encode it as an
as a variable in a
c file
so afterwards on the actual device i
could use fso pen which is an
implementation of a virtual file system
that will go back to that
c file
and fetch the data
and supply it to the application to the
web server so it could send it back as a
get response
and everything is pretty tight it's the
implementation is simple the http dot c
holds all of the web server
itself and then we have the make fs data
utility
uh and that's just an example of files
that you can
use so that's like the fsdata.c that
comes along with the project there is
some
index.html encoded in here and you can
see
that it also includes like the http
address and the a server adder
content length and the data itself
so
let's talk about the vulnerability
itself um
at this point we have like as the user
we have the a connection page which
behind the scenes uses javascript some
legacy function called
login
encrypt
which
actually encrypts the
a user code with lc4 then it hashes it
with md5 and x encoded so it could be
safely passed as a username and password
i think the username and password split
is for legacy purposes
so it just encrypts hashes and xm codes
and everything is passed as a get
parameters
uh to the server
now on the server side what paradox did
they actually took the
stock server from lwip and they added uh
verification functions so the user must
be logged in
so that's just some general function
that uses um
[Music]
that handles the cgi calls and you can
see there is like a loop in here and
there's the extract ui parameters and on
the other end we have um the firmware
so we have the same function here's the
loop and here's the extract ui
parameters
only with a check to see if the user is
connected
uh is so that that's what they did and
and what we care about is the actual
authentication functions on the server
function only
on the server side
so
paradox login as i tagged it
and and now we
reach our first remote code execution
vulnerability
so labeled under a cv 2020
25 189
uh it's actually a bunch of
buffer overflow vulnerabilities in the
same function
the same login function
so a first thing you can see in here the
stl copy
actually what happens is that they get
parameters in here opacity is a list of
strings
and for each one
they take the data in the parameter and
they copy it to a local uh
a buffer with a length of 100 100 bytes
and
that is done obviously in an unsafe
matter which leads to a buffer overflow
now the more interesting part the more
interest in buffer overflow is another
one
which happens on the x decoding
logic
so what they did in here because they
passed everything next xd coding
they actually go two bytes at a time and
use scanf
to
decode the hex
into one byte so
the thing is that
the loop only stops when it's null
so it's essentially the same kind of
buffer overflow we can put as many data
as we want and then decode it
to a limited size buffer local buffer
which leads us to another buffer
overflow
and there's another with the password
also obviously
a and that's our first and major uh
remote code execution vulnerability
the other one
is actually in a pretty similar function
but
it's not the same function it's also an
authentication function but it's used
when you
already authenticated and they want to
kind of re-verify authentication
because it's like a high privilege
function
and in here
you can see those it's pretty similar
but only there is some more buffers
and that's exactly the same like the
username and password uh in the linear
[Music]
but besides the username and password we
also have in this function the pnl and
pnp and some other um
possible get parameter names i think
i suspect it's for um
like an api kind of authentication maybe
or for legacy purposes
so
that's great we got two remote code
execution availabilities on the device
now
it's time to exploit them so
we need to decide what we want to do
the obvious thing in those situations
would be that we want to override the
allow the return pointer so when the
function ends it will pop back the
program counter and then we get
a control over the
next instruction the instruction pointer
essentially
so we could execute our shell code as
strictly
so we could execute the shell code
directly from stack
but the only problem in here is that we
can't do it because in these specific
arm chips from st electronics what
happens is that the memory
lies in an address range
which starts with a hexa 20
which in asca encoding means a white
space
and
because we are working with get
parameters we can't have white space in
there if we'll send white space what
happens is that the server won't the
vulnerability won't be triggered on the
server
so
that's
that's kind of a problem and the way
that i solved it uh overcomed it was
using an opt-chain
the idea with the option is to use um
a existing parts of
the femur the female chord
each part is called a gadget and we
assemble them together we jump from
first gadget to the second gather
and and the nice thing is that the film
relies in the memory area that it starts
with a
xr80 so we don't have a problem to jump
over there
and in here the important stuff is the
loading of the stack pointer address
well shellcode lies
uh into a register
and then eventually into r1 and
eventually we can we jump using blx the
branch instruction the jump instruction
you know we jump to
this address
and after doing some setup in here and
all of that
so
um
we start with the buffer overflow we go
to the firmware and form the firmware we
go back to the shell code
i just wrapped it a bit so it would be
nicer to use
you can see it's a python code that
handles all of the exploitation and
process
so except the program counter we are
also overriding all of these
registers
and the exploit function would create a
get request to the alarm system
which actually puts um
a a all of the
data that we need to override
um
in in the user parameter and the
password parameter is specified in here
uh and i wrapped everything
with a function that i called safe exec
that just takes code binary code and
execute it
in the memory of the device
leveraging the vulnerability
and their rope gadgets
so all of the gadget addresses in the
firmware are encoded
and and also the code is x encoded so it
be would be x decoded afterwards on the
device
and it's best as the a password
a get parameter
so in that point
we have the vulnerability we know how to
exploit it we're using a rock chain uh
to safely jump back to the shell code
and now the only thing left is to a um
decide how we want to exploit it
so we said that the final goal is to
disarm the alarm
uh and the easiest way in my opinion to
do so is using
an api
and for that api we need the password
so the shell code idea is to dump the
password
and send it back to the cnc back to us
as the attacker
and it it could be very very complex
because
think about it the firmware is just it's
a plain firmware
uh there was no operating system there
was no
api
and i really didn't didn't want to mess
with all of those those things so
creating a reverse shell for example
would require a lot of work
so the idea was to leverage what the
code that we already have in the funeral
and and the way that i did it is um by
changing the original code flow so
originally uh the user would request a
to login
uh and then the function would the login
function would check okay the username
and password is valid yes yes okay
now it would open
some a41 page
and it would set it to be the page that
the device should return
so the idea was that we'll change the
flow here we have the exploit and it's
instead
of opening uh and of simply opening and
returning
on that html page
will modify the behavior
so that the html page um actually a a
would point
to some
a address in memory that we know
that the password is is at
so every html page every page that you
open with the fs function open fs open
function
uh actually returns a descriptor which
says okay that's the file that's the
file name
that's where the data is that's the
length of the data
so we'll open some whatever page
and then we'll edit the pointer to the
data and set it to so the device would
return that new modified
page
which is essentially the password for
memory
that's how the fs open function the
original function from lwp
looks like you can see it sets all of
this data in the descriptor right here
and all of what we want to do is modify
this pointer
and that's the shell code uh which
modifies the pointer
that some initialization stuff not
interesting default html password a
password so string
in the
firmware so that's the address in the
firmware
uh fs open the function in the firmware
which
handles the opening of the file from the
vfs
uh which lies in that address um we just
call it
like branch to it
and then changing
a
a the data pointer to our new data
which
is the password
in memory you can see that's a ram
address
and then we'll continue in with the
normal execution which essentially leads
to
the behavior where the device returns
the password it dumps it for memory and
returns it to us on the same
get request that we created to exploit
the device
now we exploited the device we got a
password now the question is how do we
disarm it so for that there is a bunch
of products in github i chose to use pai
paradox alarm interface
which is a really nice project
it's just
like for automation purposes for guys
who want to um
do like home automation stuff with the
alarm system
and the thing with pai is that um is the
way that it works
so we exploited um
a port 80 like the web interface which
should be open uh from the public
internet but pai
works as this management software called
babywell
babywear is paradox management a
software for a
the alarm systems
and
it's used to set up different tools
different areas different sensors all of
these things
but it's used locally so
a port a 10 000 would normally be open
only on their local network and we're on
the
internet
so
what can we do with that um
and my idea was to create another shell
code
which would switch the ports uh so after
the first exploitation
uh and and
after we have the password we'll exploit
it again
and tell it okay a switch between port
10 000 between the service that goes on
paul 10 000 and the service that goes
with
port 80.
so for that i created this shell code
which essentially used an update config
function which is built in in the
firmware
and tells it to switch uh the services
so now um
what we get is that uh port 10 000 like
the management port is actually port 80
and it would be open
to the public internet
and and that's pretty much it so
um we just to summarize what we we did
up until this point uh we decrypted the
path with the help of our friend
nesmogos we decoded the xenx
intellects encoded payload
we did a man in the middle attack uh
grabbed damped the network a traffic
uh reversed engineered the intellect
payload
uh with that knowledge from the reverse
engineering we decrypted we understood
and decrypted the female from the
network
afterwards we
reverse engineered and found the
vulnerability in the login a handling
function
we exploited this vulnerability using an
op chain that led us back to the first
shell code
[Music]
which is a password dumper it just
dumped the password for us for memory
and returned it on the same get request
then
we
exploited the device the vulnerability
again
switched the ports and now we have
bought 10 000 open
uh to the public internet and we have
the device password together with the
python pai library
uh and and
then we disarm the device
uh and that's pretty much it so now it's
demo time
okay guys so it's demo time and i want
to do this demo really quick so we'll
have enough time for the live q and a
session
so let's start first thing you can see
my screen with the jupiter notebook and
all of the exploitation
code in it so we're just gonna go and
execute it step by step
uh so you will get a real clear view of
what's going on
and if you notice you can also see the
camera view with the alarm system itself
so
here
we have the actual control panel
uh which is used
to control the alarm system
uh and you can see we have two rooms one
is the hallway the other one is the
kitchen
both are system off which means the
alarm is off so i just go ahead and arm
it
code
um area number one
um area number two
and we'll give it a second
okay and now it's on
so uh if we'll go back to the jupiter
notebook um
you'll probably notice in here
the exploit function and save exact form
stack which we talked about earlier
both are responsible to execute to
exploit
the actual device
have some utility functions in here
which are not really interesting
and target ip so
in this specific case in this demo i
just connected the alarm directly to my
laptop but obviously in in real life we
want to access it to attack it from the
public internet and there's probably
gonna be
some router with some portfolio
configured on it
so we need to keep that in mind
let's go ahead
shotgun number one is the memory dumper
which we also talked about
so we can see that it was pretty quick
and we got like the http response back
those are the http headers
this
is the actual law memory dump
as you can see it's pretty well there's
like url in here there's some hex values
in here
um pretty nice
and in here if you notice you'll see
paradox which is our password
so we'll go ahead and decode it
paradox this is actually the
the default management password for the
device
so now we got a password the other thing
that we want to achieve is to switch the
ports
so as we said in real life
the ports
the management ports
probably won't be accessible from the
public internet so we need to switch the
management and web interface
uh so now uh it seemed to
be successful
so
um the management port is actually
opened on port 80 instead of 10 000 and
the web port is on a port 10 000 instead
of 80.
so we got pretty much everything that we
wanted um
we have the the management password and
we can access the management port
so we'll go ahead and use
paradox allow interface which is the
library too that we're using to connect
to the device
you can see there's some configuration
that we need to do
so here
is the device ip here is the password
that we dumped
using the shell code from the device
memory
and we'll go ahead and try to connect to
it
you can ignore those errors though
it's just a
kind of an unstable device
and we got two which means that we are
now connected to the device so we'll do
a quick refresh
and get the partitions
so what are those partitions um there
are actually the representation
of the areas um
that uh you saw so hallway and kitchen
you can also see them on the camera view
always kitchen
uh and what we care about is actually
the key which is the internal id for
those areas
and we really need to know it so we can
uh disarm
those partition
those areas
so in here we're just gonna go ahead and
try to disarm the first partition the
first area which is hallway
and you can see
uh that we got hallway and we got system
off which means
that now the alarm in in the hallway
is disabled is disarmed
so we'll just proceed and we'll try to
disarm the other
partition
and
you should look at the camera view and
you'll see that kitchen switch to system
off
so
that's it everything is this sound and
now our guys can go and breach the
actual physical building and they don't
need to worry at all about the alarm
system
and and that's it
so thank you for watching
and i'll see you in a second in the live
q a session
let's see it