[Music]
welcome everyone to our presentation
today called enter sandbox before we
start with the content of our
presentation let us briefly introduce
ourselves my name is claudio canella i'm
a phd candidate at guards university of
technology if you ever want to reach out
to me ask some questions
feel free to do so on twitter or simply
send me an email hi so
my name is matthew weiner i'm a
i was a phd at carter university of
technology as well when conducting this
research and now i'm a hardware design
engineer at nxp semiconductors so if you
want to reach me have a look at my
homepage and you find the contact
information there
hi my name is michael schwarz i'm a
faculty at cisco helmholtz center for
information security
also if you have some questions feel
free to always reach out to me on
twitter via mail or ask questions after
our talk
so what is this talk about
we already know that memory safety
vulnerabilities they are quite common so
everything is quite buggy we have
vulnerabilities everywhere
and there's this nice technique of
sandboxing that helps in limiting the
impact of vulnerabilities that's
something that we really
want to use in all these applications
that could have bugs and are a target
for exploitation like browsers for
example
and if we are on linux there's already a
nice technique the segcomp filters
and they allow us
to sandbox an application so that they
only have limited access to system codes
but
this is still something we'd have to do
manually
so the question is can we automate that
can we get sandboxing in more
applications than we have right now
a few months ago
so i was
coding
a little application i needed a small
application to copy some files around
and i wrote that in my favorite language
in c
of course i know if i write applications
in memory unsafe languages like c
it's easy
to make some mistakes to introduce bugs
maybe even exploitable bugs
and that this is quite common we can see
that here for example
in this plot
so i looked at all these cves
regarding memory safety vulnerabilities
things that were exploited in native
applications
and we see
we have quite a lot of them and these
are only the known ones that received an
identifier
i don't want to make this graph any
steeper
so i'd like to not have any
vulnerabilities in my code
so
your application sounds to be perfect
for seccomp so let me briefly introduce
what seccomp is with seccomp we have
this application like for instance in
your case your application for copying
files and typically it just wants to
perform some system calls to perform its
task so
you identify the system calls that your
application
does or does need and it installs the
filters in the kernel so it just says if
you get an open system call please allow
it
so we get the system call then after the
filters have been installed the
application performs for instance this
open system call the operating system
the linux kernel checks within the
filters if the system call is allowed if
it is not it is simply going to
terminate your application
because it might have been exploited in
some way or form and if it's allowed
then
simply if we allowed or the system call
is executed and we return
that indeed sounds fascinating
so from the basic idea i get it
but
i just seriously audio so i looked at
that so he explained it so nicely and i
felt like that's a plug-in solution i
just put it into my application
but then i found some tutorials and it
looks like that
so that looks
nothing like c code or anything i know
that looks more like some
type of pseudo assembly stitched
together using c macros and it's
horrible to read
and even worse to write that so
i don't know so it sounds cool
but
i have no idea how i should come up with
things like that i mean it might work
for a simple hello world application
but for anything larger
i don't know
well yes that's because that you use the
bpf filters directly the filters are
expressed in this language called ppf
and it's really complicated but why not
just use lipsec comp it's more or less
an rb it does everything for you in the
background and it's really nice you have
these functions you can just create a
context you call second rule add with
the number of the system call or name of
the system call that you want to perform
and it's done so why not just use that
it's a lot more easier
okay that indeed sounds a bit more
practical so
i looked that up i looked at lipsec comp
and
yes
you are kind of right
so it definitely looks easier than what
i tried to do before that's now actual c
code with some functions
but still it doesn't look very nice and
it looks super complicated and i had to
look up many things in there so we have
something like the rt secret dern or
exit group
open ad like
why did i need all of that i mean
i don't really know but if i didn't add
that it crashed so
it must be necessary
and
after a bit of research i figured out
like these are the syscalls that are
internally used by the code by the c
code
and i have to figure out which syscalls
my application uses
but
how would i know that as a simple
developer
so i have cc functions
how can i map them to the syscalls that
they actually use
and
i would have to do that for the entire
code base
so again for hello world that's fine
but if i have a large application with
thousands of lines of codes and multiple
files
doing that for all the c functions
checking which cisco they use
does that really sound feasible to you i
know it doesn't to me
and then again
typically i use some third party
libraries and have a lot of code again
so
i would also have to do that for all the
third party libraries really
you're right we need to do something
about it so maybe we can come up with a
solution for that
months of research and engineering later
we came up with this solution that we
call chestnut and chestnut is more or
less a two-phase approach so in the
first phase we have this we call it p1
we have the static analysis and it's
more as what you said we have to we take
the source code of an application we use
our tool that we call source alizer
it performs some analysis and at the end
it tells us what are the system calls
that it's the application is going to
execute
and in the other case maybe we just want
to we don't have the source code
available and we only have the binaries
so we also have a solution for that
we use our binary we use our tool called
binalyzer and we again get this
these annotated files
but
this might not work entirely because
static analysis does have its problems
so we have this optional second phase
called the dynamic refinement phase
where we have a third part of our tool
called finalizer
and with this dynamic analyzer
we can simply do some runtime
tracing of system calls and we can
refine the system calls that we find
and we get again these annotated binary
files that we can then use another tool
called either chestnut patcher to
generate a sandbox binary or chestnut
generator
that generates us a wrapped binary
but that's a lot of information for just
this one slide so
maybe
let's take a look a closer look at all
of these components individually
let's start with the first part uh
source eliza as i said we have these
source files like for instance you're
copying files
code
we simply pass it
through our extended compiler we extract
the system call number there
then we need to build up some call graph
we need to know which function calls
which so that we can extract the correct
system cause in the final binary
after this
we take the the object file that we have
we annotate it with the call graph that
we found and the system calls that we
found within this
this single file
then we combine it in the linker with
the additional libraries that we have
and we flatten this call graph we get
the system call numbers out there for
the whole binary that we actually need
and we generate this annotated
executable and once we run it we're
simply going to install the filters
sounds nice right you just need
to use our extended compiler that we
provide and your application is
sandboxed do you even know how
challenging it is in practice i mean
you make it sound really simple
no i don't know
okay so um let me show you how this all
works
with the help of one example so we take
the most important program in computer
science
everyone knows it hello world
and the challenge or that we have that
we want what we want to achieve is we
want to sandbox this application
and
you nicely explained we put it into the
compiler
and he does all the work and we're done
but if we really try and try it and look
at what the compiler actually sees it's
not that simple because when you compile
this program everything the compiler
sees is a call to a function called put
string
the compiler has no idea what this
function is where it has been defined
what it does internally and he doesn't
care
he only looks at one translation unit at
a time
so we can manually look up this
bootstring function we find it in our c
library implementation looks something
like that
yeah on the first glance it's still
really complicated we have we see some
function calls some macros there
yeah and when we can let the compiler do
its work we see internally put string
calls for other functions
but again nobody knows what these
functions are to
and yeah the compiler doesn't care
so one thing which we do in our tool in
sourcalizer is that we extract all this
local information each translation unit
only knows about the code it contains
and uh what other functions it calls and
what we do here is we serialize this
information in this case we simply pick
json
and we embed this
json into a node in the resulting object
file so we can use elf
elf nodes there and just add arbitrary
information
in the second step the linker which
has the task of combining all these
object files
loads also this new node edit node
sections
and uses this
[Music]
information fragments to recombine all
this information and construct a
constitutional a counterflow graph or in
this case a call graph
so when you look at the slides here we
see main calls put string put string
calls for other functions the one which
is important is f put string
if we follow this path further we find
that this internally calls f write
and f write again calls a few other
functions but we still have no idea
where the actual syscalls are we haven't
seen them here
the challenge is that f rat doesn't do a
direct call to the
next functions but an indirect function
call and again
we cannot be sure which functions there
are called there
and what we do here is
we utilize again the compiler the
compiler knows which
signatures
are called so what arguments the
function get and what type they have
and uh by collecting all the information
which we have again
we find that
he has to call in this case standard
outright and in standard outright we
really have the cisco so calling cisco
for an io control and syscall 20 in the
standard ao write is the write operation
all which is left then is to back
propagate this information up the call
graph and then we know what this is
called main users
so to summarize the key aspects that
socializer uses are
that
we use each tool
for what it's best at we use the
compiler for extracting information
he has access to like the syscalls and
function names and signatures
we emit all this stuff into the object
file and then recombine it in the call
graph into a call graph as part of the
linker additionally we use link time
garbage collection to reduce the number
of reachable
functions
which helps with this indirect function
call handling and
the function called signature heuristic
which i mentioned before to figure out
which functions are called indirectly
and the result of that is that no time
consuming whole program analysis is
needed so we can
do this all
much faster than our previous related
work
i think that's a very interesting idea
but the question that pretty much
everyone is asking themselves is does
this really work or is it just working
for like a small example like hello
world uh yeah so i was expecting that of
course you are always um
quite skeptical with this stuff so yeah
we tried that of course and as an
example we also tried it on ffmpeg so
you have all this video encoding stuff
in there you have parsers
a lot of potential uh
vulnerable spaces where vulnerabilities
would be bad and we compiled it with our
source analyzer tool and got the sandbox
binary
we have a quick video here which shows
when we start this application
first we look at what this calls were
found in this case 63 cisco's very
extracted
and when we start the application with a
debug flag we again print
what syscalls have been found which we
are used for setting up the second
filters
and yeah the application simply runs
that's really nice resize so i have to
say i use that
on my simple application and it still
works flawlessly so it seems it
perfectly sandboxed that but i'm still
not fully satisfied
so i have this
old software lying around here
that looks a bit shady i'm not sure how
secure it is
maybe it even has backdoors or something
and
i can't really tell because i don't have
the source code i only have this binary
here i would like to also sandbox that
to make it a bit more secure at least at
least
so
i can't do that with your compiler right
it requires source code as every
compiler so what do you do if i only
have a binary well you obviously did not
pay attention to what i said in the
beginning we also have this binary
analysis tool that allows you to do
exactly what you want here so
we have the spinalizer it extracts the
system calls from existing binaries or
libraries
and for that it simply uses the capstone
framework so it disassembles the binary
so that we get all the assembly
instructions and users so we can find
the system calls
there and then we use the anchor tool to
build a call graph again and extract the
system calls that are actually needed
for the for the binary but claudio how
does this work in detail i mean is
called finding them sounds complicated
it is a little bit complicated so let me
briefly walk you through this so what we
do is we rely on symbolic backwards
execution we look through the
disassembly binary until we find the
system call instruction and duplica
typically the system call is executed is
in the rax register of
of the cpu so you move at one point the
request number into that register
perform the systemcalling structure and
the operat and the system handles the
rest for you
but
we need to find this so we you we look
for the system calling structure and
when we find it in this case we simply
don't know yet what is the value of our
x so we keep the value symbolic and we
move back up a couple instructions
because at one point we are going to
find this move in structure
but in the first two lines that we look
at we don't really find it but at one
point we see that we have this moth ebx
to eax register
well that simply
that still does not tell us what is the
actual syscall that is executed because
suddenly eax is ebx so we need to keep
the value further symbolic but we now
know that rex is equal to rbx which we
don't know the value yet so we continue
our search we don't learn anything else
in the next line but at one point we'll
see that the
uh we see a muff instruction where the
value 1 is moved into the bl register so
the lower part of the
ebx register
so at this point we can now infer that
rax is equals to rbx which is equals to
1. so we know that the syst call that is
being executed is this call number one
and
so help me out there do i have to do
that manually no the system so our tool
does all of that automatically for you
you just give it as an input the
uh your binary we pass the binary so
that we find all uh the dynamic
dependencies of it
and it finds the system calls we built
the call graph with anger
and
using this tool we can then
get the system call mapping where we
know for instance that the puts function
needs right v
um the default function is going to need
right v sysclone and cisfutex system
calls so all of that is done
automatically for you
and
we can also show you again using a video
how this is done for this we use the
application radius and
we applied our binary analysis tool to
it and executed the test
suite of the application and as you can
see
not a single one of these
test cases fails so
it seems like we find all the necessary
system calls for our application
i trusted you with that so i applied
that to my
legacy application that i only have a
binary
and
surprisingly
that happened
it just
crashed it stopped working so it doesn't
work your
vinylizer thingy
destroyed the application so it's now
completely broken
so
why what is happening here you explained
it so nicely it made sense but
apparently it doesn't work yeah
michael i think you've found a corner
case there which we simply cannot handle
so i mean
seconds second filter if you you
configure them statically
it's not possible to relax them anymore
i mean that's a nice property for
uh for having uh for ensuring that a pr
application doesn't gain additional
privileges but in this case um it's
really not not ideal
[Applause]
so what we actually have to do here is
we need another approach i mean second
itself is nice if you know the static
set
but we need additional capabilities in
particular something like uh
like this like an s trace approach where
we see all the syscalls and can decide
during runtime if this belongs to the
application
or if it
is a malicious syscall that we do not
expect
we have a tool for that it's called
finalizer
and what finalizer does is it basically
implements this estrace approach so we
have we have a tracy uh which is the
application which we want to protect and
we spawn a second process the tracer
which monitors the syscalls of our
target application
[Applause]
what now happens when the application
makes a syscall
the kernel automatically delegates this
decision if the syscall is okay or not
to our tracing application
here we can lock the syscall we can
theoretically decide if it's okay to do
it or not or simply uh
take notes and lock that the cisco took
place and use that information for
further refinement later on
afterwards we
the tracer that
compo
the monitoring component uh returns to
the kernel and says okay the application
is allowed to do the syscall and then
the kernel performs the actual operation
um so when we look how where we
implemented that we basically designed a
new small utility library look called a
lib chestnut
this
library
is
in charge of setting up second filters
on application start and it also
implements this finalizer approach which
i discussed on the previous slide
the way it works is it registers a
constructor basically as
i've constructed a function like like in
c in a c plus plus program
but in this case in a c program
which is automatically called on program
startup and in this constructor we set
up the sync up filters
additionally source socializer which we
introduced before uh automatically links
to this library so all you have to do
there is to use the uh
the sandboxing flag and of the compiler
and you get the completely protected
binary at the end
so the question here is then what about
binalyzer in binalyzer we cannot simply
link against it right so
when we think back to the overview that
i gave earlier we had these two other
tools there chestnut patcher and
chestnut generator so they can be used
for this
so chestnut patcher more or less
uses the information that is provided
the number of system calls that are
being executed or that need to be
allowed and directly patches the binary
includes them in a node section and also
links against a lipsec comp and lip
chestnut so more or less you then have
the same thing as you have with a
socializer
the other approach would be to use
chestnut generator so instead of
patching the binary
we create like a wrapper program that
launches that sets up all the filters
using lipsec comp and our lip chestnut
and then launches the binary
okay yeah so that's pretty nice
so
i can apply that to all my applications
now right yes
okay and yes this time it really works
so
i have to admit i'm a bit surprised by
that but it actually works
but i mean still you do a lot of stuff
you figure out syscalls
uh you have to do static analysis some
dynamic analysis symbolic execution
that's a lot
also adding all these filters
so
isn't it going to be super slow
well we obviously
put some thought into that and performed
some evaluation of all this so we looked
at the performance of our tools in
extracting the system call information
that we need
we also evaluated the functional
correctness so our tools actually still
able to do what they want or what they
need to do
and we also looked at the security
because in the end that's what we are
most interested in when we use second we
want to improve the overall security of
the system
and for that we looked at clients server
and database applications and in total
those were like 18 applications that we
analyzed
throughout this client server and
database applications
and when we look at first the
performance of our tools
we only provide the worst compile time
overhead here and we observed this for
the git application and there we
observed an overhead of 28
sounds quite high but you know total
that was like 19 seconds of overhead and
it's actually quite fast when you
compare it to
uh concurrent work
then for the worst binary extraction
time we observed us for ffmpeg it's the
largest application that we looked at i
think the binary was like 100 megabytes
and there it took 11 minutes to extract
it using our analyzer
all we discussed up till up until now is
is basically overhead which we have at
compile time or after
in a pre-processing step before we
actually launch the application
but
there is other overhead as well which we
should at least mention
in terms of runtime and especially so
chestnut itself doesn't add anything in
regards of overhead
during execution but we still use
seccomp and seccomp is
not the fastest if we are completely
honest
um but there is work ongoing uh to
improve this situation so
it's not really in the scope of our work
but every improvement which goes into
seccomp which is part of the linux
kernel itself uh
automatically also improves
our final solution
which is nice i guess
so that's great so
now let's take a closer look at the
functional correctness i mean that's
after security probably one of
developers are most interested because
if your application doesn't work anymore
what's the security worth
um so
for that we relied on the application's
test suites for our checks
so we were not able to test pretty much
all of them but because they simply did
not have test suites available but we
used those that had some available and
let those run and that just checked
did these test tweets complete
successfully because if they did not
then we might have made a mistake
to substantiate that we are actually
looking at the majority of the
application we looked at code coverage
metrics for
uh for the better estimation of
of the correctness
and there we've seen that in regards to
line coverage we were close between 59
and 77 percent and for function coverage
we were able to cover between 61 and 92
of the
of the functions in these test suites so
this might also be a point that we need
better test tweets but this is outside
the scope of our work
what we also looked at or what we've
seen in these tests is that we observed
no crashes during these tests so i think
this is nice it shows that at least for
the main parts that are covered by the
test suites we are able to extract
everything that is necessary
and additionally what we also did is we
performed a six month long term study
using ngn nginx hosting one of our
websites with it and we
observed no crashes over those six
months
okay so another important thing is of
course the security you already
mentioned it the whole point of this
research is to improve security
and uh what we did to figure out how
much we improved this
we looked at how many system calls has
been blocked have been blocked by our
tools
so in particular when you look at the
socializer approach we were able to
block on average 87 of the syscalls
which the linux kernel provides which is
of course a really nice improvement
already
quite similarly uh by analyzer also was
able to block 83
of the sys calls on average which
drastically reduces the attack surface
of the kernel
when we look at uh
exec which is one particular
[Applause]
system call which is quite dangerous in
in terms of security
results were a little bit worse but
still we were able to
block it in nine out of our tested
applications
using the compiler-based approach and
even in 14
using vinylizer
similarly mprotect which makes it
possible to change the execution
permissions of a page in memory
we looked at that in particular and our
socializer tool blocked this system call
in 61
all that is nice but what we also did is
we looked at mitigating real world
exploits so we looked at the meteor
database looked for
for cves that explicitly mentioned that
they exploit some kernel vulnerability
that is triggered using a system call
and there we found 175
uh cves that did exactly that we
analyzed those cves we found that some
of them there is an alternative system
call that might also be able to exploit
this vulnerability so we simply replace
those with with them and got much larger
data sets there so roughly 345
cves in that when it comes to that
and then we just took our applications
all these 18s that we had we compared
the system calls that the cve relies on
what the exploit relies on
cross-reference those with the system
calls that are being allowed
and if we block the system call then we
consider that
this cve to be not exploitable via this
application
and when we looked at the full cve so we
can mitigate all of the variants of it
we were able to block 64 and 62 percent
respectively using sources and binalyzer
and for the sub variants we were able to
block even more so 75 and 72 percent
okay that's pretty impressive but while
you explained that i wasn't listening
too much but i thought about some
exploit technique that
also injects those calls in existing
applications so as thinking about return
oriented programming where i use
existing code in an application to
exploit a program
the idea is to simply
if you have control in the application
because you exploited it to jump to
existing parts of the application so
called gadgets
that do part of the functionality and
then return to the next gadget and so on
and you chain them together so these
gashes could be as simple as
getting some value from the stack into a
register or just
executing a syscall
and
with that couldn't i still exploit your
sandbox application
i mean
if i look at that in detail i'm suddenly
using the stack pointer as the
instruction pointer because i have the
addresses there for all the gadgets i
use and then i'm returning into the
application itself i'm not loading any
code i'm not executing anything with the
x-axis caller i'm not using m protect
for anything so i'm just using existing
code jump to that return again the stack
pointer access the instruction point to
the next gadget i execute that return
back execute the next one and with that
i can build my own code out of existing
code that can do arbitrary syscalls
but yeah mikey that's exactly the point
you you can make arbitrary syscalls we
use something like returner and
programming
but at least in
with the second filtering we can prevent
it on the kernel side so if you build a
source code that was not originally in
the program and which
our tools didn't find
the application simply is terminated as
soon as you try it this demo does pretty
much we show here that it's actually
sandboxed using our approach it reads
from some file and then we start our
attack we crash the application we find
out okay we can have some form of buffer
overflow there we perform a rub attack
that tries to spawn a shell
as we can see here with this pop-up
simply our
uh our system has detected this and
asked us to clarify hey is this
something that you actually want to do
executing this
okay so i think it's really the best to
just give it a try
all our tools
are open source you can find it on
github you find it under the
url in the in the slides and it's the
best simply to try it out yourself and
also
when you're already looking up stuff
also check out our paper it contains
much more information on how the
techniques actually actually work
this really reduces this overhead this
manual analysis overhead to actually
sandbox an application and make it
secure
by having this automated process
yes so that's very nice that we should
through this automated process we were
basically able to show that we can
improve the overall system security
using no manual labor pretty much at all
i mean you need to
modify some make files probably
we were also able to show the functional
correctness using test suites showing
that our applications using the chestnut
sandbox approach still work
and we were only we were also able to
show the chestnut only has a small
performance overhead in your everyday
development cycle so that is something
that should be developed further which
can help make systems a lot more secure
without needing a lot of experts to do
that
so
thanks again all of you for being here
for paying attention