[Music]
hello and welcome to the session in the
next 25 minutes we'll talk about a
recent important innovation in the malwa
ecosystem namely that malicious actors
are using the bitcoin blockchain for
spreading command and call information
and the issue with this is that this
makes it very difficult to detect and
mitigate this vector with the technology
we currently have
in this talk we show you how this
mechanism works in the pony malware we
show you how the actors learned and
innovated over the course of a year and
we tell you how we were successfully
able to take over the operation
when we talk about cyber security and
melbourne in particular we have to
realize that this is a continuous game
of cat and mouse
each time defenses get good enough to
make a difference and affect the bottom
line the criminals tune it up a notch
and innovate and this has been going on
for the past 25 years this evolution
goes on in waves and has occurred in
different domains
for instance
when we look at how malware is written
we saw the emergence of things such as
encryption polymorphism or metamorphism
starting from the 1990s we also saw
change in the way that malware talks the
botnet or the subordinate master while
initial malware used interdrillate chat
to receive and send information irc
stands out quite a bit in normal network
traffic so very soon this malware
adopted http and https based command
control channels
we also changes in how malware prevents
from being analyzed so we saw
anti-debugging and anti-virtualization
techniques emerging the stage
and there has been innovations in the
way that addressing has been done so
while static ip addresses can block
easily and domain names are routinely
being seized in the 2000s we saw the
immersion of domain generation
algorithms or dgas in short and the dja
generates a large number of domain names
that are valid only for a short time
interval and behind any of these the c
and c0 could be hiding so in order to
take it down you would have to block all
of these domain names which makes it
very cumbersome to do
when we look at this we might conclude
that this situation has been more or
less static for the past five years
however there has been the next step in
the sequence of step
a new innovation that we need to be
aware of
in 2017 the kerber malware adopted a new
principle of addressing
it exchanged cnc information via the
blockchain this is now being adopted by
pony and other male when becomes much
more widespread and it is important that
we as defenders are aware of this
evolution step and that we build new
types of defenses to detect and mitigate
this factor
if you're interested in learning more
about kerber we refer you to a report
from our lab while we study how the
malware works the ttp used and how the
infrastructure works you can find the
url to this report here on the slide
when we look at our portfolio of
security defenses there are three main
angles that we used to deal with malware
and botnet infections today if you have
a domain name that you know it's
malicious you block it if you have a
malware sample that uses a dga you take
it apart and you study the algorithm and
from it you print all domain names it
will ever generate and this list you can
now put into your dns server block it
create alerting rules and so on
you can also detect and mitigate based
on the behavior from malware so while
you might be occasionally mistyping a
domain name it is very unlikely that the
client requests thousands of high
entropy domain names and the bulk of
which don't exist so these so-called
annex domain lookups if a large number
of them occurs this is typically a sign
for a malware infection
finally
you also can mitigate botnet by finding
locating and seizing the physical
infrastructure if you take down the cnc
server itself the botnet typically will
fall silent
the work that we're presenting in this
talk is the result of the international
cooperation between fujitsu integration
laboratories in tokyo japan and the
hasselblad institute for digital
engineering in potsdam germany my name
is christian door i'll be working with
you through the first part of this
presentation
how does malware coordination by the
bitcoin blockchain work it's quite
simple you make transactions on the
blockchain and you encode into the
payment how much is being paid by whom
and when the information that you want
to transmit
how is it being done in pony
the transaction itself signals the cnc
information this value is encoded in the
amount of money that is being paid
between ascending wallet and a signaling
vote in this example the bitcoin address
starting with one n94r is the sending
wallet and the bitcoin address starting
with 1bkeg
is going to be the signaling wallet
and if we have the trainment amount of
23900 satoshis if we can translate this
into hexadecimal that is 5d8e we chunk
this up into two parts and we again
translate this back into a numerical
value 93 142
we now have the first two parts of the
ip address if we flip these two values
let's just look at the second
transaction value
52736 or ce0 again you split it up you
get 206 and 0 and you flip these two
values to get the second part of the ip
address so now clients are monitoring
specific wallets on the blockchain
they're retrieving the last payments and
from the last two they are decoding this
in the following manner to now obtain
the cnc ip address 142 93 0 and 206
why two transactions while you could
signal it in one transaction the money
necessary to transfer this information
would be astronomically high so by using
two transactions you keep the cost for
maintaining the cnc mechanism relatively
low
so when we look at the three main angles
that we introduced for how we deal with
malware and botnet infections we see
that we now have a significant problem
in our hands from this latest innovation
step because much of what we have been
doing doesn't work anymore let's look at
option one predicting domain names and
stopping them well there isn't nothing
to predict anymore so there is not a
malware algorithm we can take apart by
looking at the sample
all of the information is being
exchanged on the blockchain and i cannot
predict in the future what is going to
be the next payment that somebody makes
on the blockchain so as soon as i do
something the criminal can make a new
payment and immediately all of the bots
are updating to the new information
i also cannot remove anything from the
blockchain because the blockchain has
been designed to be this way so option 1
completely goes out of the window
how about option 2 detecting lookup
patterns especially these telltale nx
domain lookups well there isn't any dns
lookups at all there isn't a high
entropy domain name that is being varied
the blockchain reveals directly the ip
address so there's not going to be any
dns request to something that i can
track nor is there any nx domains so
option two is also out of the window how
about option three locating and seizing
the physical infrastructure well it
depends in case of the covermail where
we saw that the adversaries were using
tor to hide the cnc server location and
depending how this is being done this
might be also then difficult to do
so we tracked the pony malware authors
for the course of one year and we
continuously observed them and we saw
that they went through many rounds of
redesign and continuous improvement
for instance they experiment with
different tactics for reaching the
wallet they added more apis in order to
make it more resilient we also saw that
they're using different techniques and
change them over time for signaling the
ip address we talk refer to these as the
time lag and the fee order strategy
later on and we will discuss more
details about them and we saw changes in
when and how they were making
transactions so they changed time zones
in order to have lower fees for the
upkeep of the infrastructure two of
these toyoshi will discuss with you in
the following in more detail if you're
interested in in-depth treatment beyond
that you can download our full paper
here below on the
ul not only did the signaling change but
also the inner workings of the malware
and the cnc server itself
so i said two transactions are needed to
signal the ip address and this was thus
done for cost reasons and if you have
two transactions you have to challenge
that these need to be in the correct
order otherwise the ip address would not
be correct so if transaction two would
finish before transaction one you have
an issue because now the client
comparing the blockchain would decode it
and go to the wrong ip address for the
cnc server
but you have another problem
if you have only one transaction that
has been included the last two
transactions would give you the wrong
result because the clients would now
decode transaction one from the new
update and transaction 2 from the
previous update as the current location
of the cnc server so why would this
happen even if transaction 1 is being
made before transaction 2 it could be
that a miner doesn't include it for now
and even if transaction 1 and 2 go into
the blockchain in the correct order
there could be a delay that they are
they are not placed into consecutive
blocks so they may be placed minutes or
maybe even hours apart and during this
time any client going to the blockchain
will decode the wrong ip address
so the obvious question that the
adversaries ask themselves is how do you
get transactions in the blockchain in
the correct order and into consecutive
blocks without really spending too much
money on it
so why is money an issue here let us
first see how the blockchain works in
the blockchain people are creating new
blocks and these blocks contain
transactions that are currently being
made and are cryptographically linked to
the previous blockchain blocks
beforehand
and this
work on the blockchain where people
continuously mine blocks is not done for
free people don't contribute their
computing power for free but they get a
reward when they create a new block
and the money that they get from it is
being paid by people who are making
transactions so if anna is sending bob
some money she pays a fee for making
these transactions on the big bitcoin
network and the higher the fee that you
offer for this transaction the higher
the incentive is to the miner to include
in the block that they're currently
mining and the more likely is to get in
so
fees being paid makes a difference let
us now look in more detail on how the
adversary used the cnc mechanism of
signal via the blockchain in practice
thank you christian my name is from
fujitsu system integration laboratories
from here let's see how the advisory
they tried to evolve their tactics
techniques and procedures and let's
learn about two case studies based on
actual advisory behaviors
the first question is that the advisor
equipped with the market turmoil
influenced by the bitcoin halving
the upper line graph represents a feed
which that buzzer reset on transactions
in order to update the exchange ips
the lower line graph represents the time
conformed by minus
i consider the time as a numerical value
and brought it
the bitcoin halving reduced the profit
of the minus then please temporary sort
the fiscal means the increase of the
cost from the other batteries side and
the advisory had to cope with the
fisa
in order to protect their profit
before the bitcoin hubbing they
basically updated the asian ip during
european working time
after the bitcoin hubbing they shifted
their trading time from working time to
midnight
they avoided busy time in the market in
order to save their cost
here pays attention after the bitcoin
hubbing and they updated their chances
ip and from three to five european time
in order to realize or take over which
is a main topic of this presentation
it is essential to grasp the timing of
xianxi update
the second case study is that the
advisory tried to confirm two
transactions in the correct order as
quickly as possible as christian
explained in the previous slide
the advisory tried two strategies and
time lag and pre-order in this slide i'd
like to explain about the timeline
strategy
the purpose of the time-lapse strategy
is to certainly control the order of
confirmation
they simply conduct a second transaction
after the confirmation of the first
transaction this means that two
transactions are confirmed in the in
different blocks
in blockchain principle a block is
generated every 10 minutes
the program or the timeline strategy is
the time log between the confirmation of
the first and second transaction
the time log is over approximately 10
minutes
if the second transaction is not
confirmed the change update is not
completed
least so to speak downtime reduce the
profit of the ad batteries
next let me explain about the fee order
strategy the motivation of free order
strategy is to avoid the time log
they tried to confirm two transactions
in the same block
since miners in the blockchain prior to
confirm transaction which set higher p
on
and the advisor is set higher fee on the
first transaction compared to the second
transaction
nobody can understand the relation
between fees and confirmation
and this uncertainty is the program of
the pre-order strategy
okay we actually observed adversaries
trial and error of fig order strategy
let's see the trial and error in this
right
the upper line graph represents the
difference of blocks in the first and
second transaction and downtime
the lower line graph represents a piece
which the advisor is set on transaction
the advisory basically is selected the
time rank strategy
we observed over two hours downtime
this means that the change update was
not completed during two hours
and the mario could not uh
decode correct chances ip
and
adversary could not control the mario
two hours is very long time so this is a
big program from the advisory side
then they started conducting the trial
and error of pola strategy since june
while they conduct two transactions in
the same block and they set higher fee
on the first transaction compared to the
second transaction
it seems that they succeeded in
realizing the fee order strategy however
they returned back to the time-lapse
strategy
they might might not be sure to control
the order of confirmation based on the
field strategy
from here let's move on to the main core
part of this presentation
let me explain about our takeover
mechanism
the mechanism for hiding cnc ip in the
blockchain by the adversary was
ingenious
once transactions are covered by the
miners and nobody can take down and
confirm transaction
and these trades
were not a crime of course not money
rendering they simply moved their
bitcoin from their own bitcoin address
to their own bitcoin address
and abused bit blockchain api is
regiment
it is difficult to risk communication as
mauritius
the basic idea of our takeover is to
inject transactions hiding our single
server ip
to the bitcoin address controlled by the
adversaries as the rendezvous point for
mario communication
before the takeover
we carefully tested the feasibility of
the
takeover
based on the dynamic analysis in the
sandbox we confirmed that
the malware made use of incoming money
without checking where the incoming
money comes from
therefore anybody can inject any ip
address to the rendezvous point
we consider this as design mistake
in addition from the sql constellation
point of view we confirm that if the
malware cannot download required dll
the safeguard mechanism of the maria
deleted maria itself
therefore
our sinkhole server did not download any
expiratory pilot from infected clients
and certain infection realized
here please remember cyber security is a
game of cat and mass
of course we anticipated their evasive
behavior from the next slide we will
show a game of cat and mass
offense and defense and actual evasive
behavior by the batteries
okay let's see a game of cat at mass
based on the actual offense and defense
we conducted first takeover on august
14. as i explained in case studies
we grasp the timing of shenzhen update
and during the
offense and defense
and the advisory basically used
time-lapse strategy
they suspended their merchant's activity
for two days and reset asian shi so we
waited and saw
the activity for a day
and they updated the xianxi
so we conducted second takeover on
august 17th
after our second takeover
they changed the pattern of shenzhen ip
update
from midnight to working time and they
updated the asian ship
after that we conducted our third
takeover
on august 19
and it seemed that they stopped their
martial activity
however
they designed their mission mechanism
and restarted their martial activity
from september past
okay let me summarize our takeover
during the battle or occupying mario
random point we conducted three times
takeover
and we estimated the mitigation of the
damage by our takeover
before our takeover the advisory updated
in the ascendancy once a day
and we realized maria offline for 17
days
we identified
275 infections at the first
takeover
and according to
our citing report average 400 us dollar
is stolen
per account
during credential theft
and therefore we estimated that we
prevented 2 million us dollar by our
takeover
okay let's see
and
new energy mechanism by the adversaries
the mechanism for hiding shenzhen ip in
the blockchain was ingenious however the
mechanism has designed mistake
we made use of the design mistake we
succeeded in taking over
our takeover forced the advisory to
suspend their martial activity and we
anticipated the evasive behavior
so in fact it took
17 days to redesign and implement the
new change mechanism
by the adversaries
okay related answers right to the
question how did advisories evade our
takeover
the advisory changes landing point from
the receiving bitcoin address to the
sending bitcoin address
this enabled the malware to download
only the transactions food-sending
bitcoin address is controlled by the
advisories simultaneously release
prevented us from taking over
we could not take over anymore
on the other hand even if they identify
our disturbance
and they did not change bitcoin
addresses
it might be tough work for advisories to
synchronize the
rendering point and changing bitcoin
addresses so we could track the margins
activity by monitoring a bitcoin
operation
it should be the vulnerability
on the adversary coped with the
difficulty of evading our takeover and
they eventually gave up the attack
infrastructure
they destroyed this closed the
vulnerability of
search
the bitcoin search means the increase of
the cost from the advisory side
the value of bitcoin increased by five
times
compared to the
value out of our takeover
when the course was not worth it they
gave up
and now and they suspended martial's
activity
however if the value of bitcoin is
dropped
there is a possibility that they disturb
their margins activity in the future
please continue to be careful
regarding this emerging attack
releasing the concluding remarks and
takeaways blockchain based shenzhen is
the next step of criminal ttps we could
study how the advisor is improved the
ttps over time
a simple design mistake allowed us to
take over the operation until they
redesigned
this mechanism was ingenious however
vulnerable to bitcoin search as a result
they gave up
after bedding i'll take over we could
track
the marshals activity by monitoring
bitcoin behavior
we hope that our findings and insight
will be useful for security people
against this emerging attack
that's all for today thank you for
coming to our session
if you have any questions
please feel free to ask the question
thank you