[Music]
hello the topic of this talk is meant to
image a memory rather than malware
detection via convolutional neural
network
memory injection is a technique often
used by modern malware to bypass
detection
it has become an headache for security
products to defend against this kind of
malware in this talk we propose this
framework
to help us
detect and classify memory resident
middleware
ergon is a malware researcher in team t5
he will walk you through the details of
this work later and i'm charles the
chief analyst of team t5 both of us are
dealing with various malware in our
daily job and we are trying every
possible way to improve our malware
detection capability without
this work
the agenda of this talk
in the beginning we will show you some
recent injection techniques used by apd
attacks
the main part is the data set
and the framework
the experiment result of this framework
in the end we will talk about the
salience map the russia learning and
adversarial attack about this framework
memory injection technique is popularly
used by malware to achieve malware
residents
before start of this talk we will
discuss some novel technique to achieve
injection that might not be easily
detected
the first technique we'd like to
introduce is uuid show code this
technique was first observed to be used
in the wild by laureus and in famous
north korean apd group
its implementation is fairly simple
using api function uuid from string to
encode the shell code to bypass security
product detection
there are two advantages by using uid
show code first
by providing a show called to hip
address this function can be abused to
both decode and write the data to memory
directory
second abusing callback function such as
in new windows candidate through
shortcut execution
both
are typical checkpoint of security
product for defending against memory
injection
attacks
there are many alternative way to
utilize the callback function for
example a new system language group in
this case will take the address returned
by hip lock
and you will execute the shortcut
the second technique we will introduce
is fentanyl halloween typical injection
often results memory blocks with rewrite
xq privilege
this feature is utilized by security
products to detect possible injected
memory attack
however phantom dealer halloween can
effectively bypass this detection
mechanism the code in the provided
screenshot can be found in a public
github page but we have seen various
chinese apd groups including abd27
windy etc to abuse this attack in their
real world attacks
this photo shows the workflow of the
phantom dealer halloween technique
the essence of this technique is to find
a target ello in system directory whose
the txt section is big enough as the
host of the payload show code
the injector component will call
anti-create section and provide the flag
thick image as its perimeter this
results the initial prediction of the
mapped section to be rewrite execute the
payload code can then be copied to the
target memory area
further code to anti-protect virtual
memory
will change the memory privilege can
effectively bypass detection
this photo shows the result of the
technique
the payload implant in implant has been
injected to the tft station of the aa
client.dll but the debugger information
shows its privilege to be only execute
and read
next we are introducing some novel show
called related technique abused by what
bear is an infamous rate tool used by a
chinese apt group
their first technique is to write their
show code in some random generated data
to threat static shortcode analysis
before preparing the real show code the
loader first generate two number
indicating the length of painting before
and after the show code
finally it decodes the show code and
writes the result to the designated
location between the
heading data
this painting makes finding the show
called more difficult and may help avoid
detection
after writing the show code the loader
starts a trade using
begins right ex function begin thread ex
acts as a proxy here and starts the new
thread at the
3 star ex
another function provided by c library
instead of the address where the show
code is located as if using create
straight directly this makes
the show code less detectable as some
antivirus software checks whether the
entry point
of the thread locates in a manually
allocated memory
the data set overview of the machine
learning
before experiment we prepare totally 21
malware family they are actively used by
apt group in asia region including apd32
abd-37 fb10 fb27 windy etc
we also include some
cyber crime malware families including
imitate phone book 3 texts etc
before doing experiment we use tools
such as pec fertility and holofy to help
us find and extract
memory in
memory
malware in memory
our data source including uh
data from real victim computer
also we try to
try edge to find more related samples on
various total or online samples
this is the file distribution for 13
totally 30 malware family used for
training
the biggest category
is
cyber crime malware they have around
hundreds of memory blocks however for
some malware
in apt
some has only tens of memory blocks you
can see some imbalance for the data set
to address this issue we use some
typical methods such as classwise smart
data augmentation transfer learning to
help us
to address this issue
why do we choose transfer learning
because some epd memory rather malware
is only a small set of data transfer
learning uses knowledge from a learned
task to improve the performance
on a related task is typically reducing
the amount of required training data
our framework will transform the malware
binary to an image for classification
before introducing our framework we
would want to show you some generated
photo to give you a feeling
and also this
for some malware families for example
dennis tritex the generated photo looks
very similar however the generated photo
could look very different for some other
families such as cobra strike stager
imotate etc
we will show you our framework and
effectively classify this male ware
this part we are going to talk about the
man-to-image
framework the first step is to
pre-processing the data
there are some continuous strong bias
painting at the bottom or the beginning
of the memory blocks like the pictures
shown on the slide
it must be removed to avoid the model
running those drunk bytes on the
features
in our data suite they often have newer
bias or hex ff
here is to talk about how we convert 1d
array 2 image
the malware is a 1d array
first we convert the binary to decimal
value and call the square root of the
length of the 1d array of the 2d arrays
width and height
and with this 2d array we can convert it
to a grayscale image like the image in
the slide
so the size of the image is determined
by the length of the malware
we construct rgb image to represent a
malware memory block
the red channel is the decimal values of
each byte
also can think of the grayscale image
from the slide
the green channel is composed of local
entropy values of the image we use an
entropy function by skin image library
to count value
the local entropy can show some
complexity relationship contained in the
given navigator
the filter returns the minimum number of
bits needed to encode the local grade
level distribution
the disk is set to 10 in mem to image
framework
the blue channel is composed of shadow
entropy values of each byte
these are schematic diagrams of the
three channels
red channel is a grad scale image
composed of decimal values of each byte
blue channel is the local entropy
if one area is encrypted
the entropy will be very high
and the model may not use that area as a
feature
the output image of the channel entropy
of each bias is very similar to decimal
values in red channel
but they are still a little different
we won't use this channel to increase
the influence of bias value instead of
using the same value of the decimal
again
this is a schematic diagram how we
generating the rgb image
the red channel and blue channel can
directly come from binaural value
the shadow entropy values are between 0
to 1.
so we multiply the channel entropy value
by 60 to increase the influence of the
channel
the green channel is the local entropy
value of the image
we first convert the binary to graph
skill image and generate a local entry
image
improve each bias value of the entropy
image to a green channel
and we also multiply the local entropy
value by 50 to increase the influence
local binary pattern is an efficient
texture operator which levels the pixel
of the image by first showing
the neighborhood of each pixel and
considers the result of binary number
it can represent the texture of the
image
so we also use lbp as features in our
framework
this line is to talk about the theorem
of the logo binary pattern
i won't go into details here
and we are using circular lpp
but we will rotate the picture during
data augmentation
as you can see in the picture the lbp
value will change
during the rotation
we will explain how to solve this
problem in the next slide
to make sure the invariance
there are another feature called lbp
rotational in variance
if we got the value biosecure lpp
and it will try to owe possibilities in
any angles
and choose the smallest one value as a
local binary pattern value
we use data augmentation technique to
generate more data for training
we flip the image or render rotate
and render and scale the image
the data about maybe four times to the
original data
after augmentation
here is the first part of the man to
image framework first we convert the
malware map binary to rgb image and
resize our image to fix size
and why the size is chosen to 224
or because this this size is the input
size of the bgg60
in the beginning it draws from
convenient
and after the experiment
the size also perform the best result
the next step is feature extraction we
use v2g16 inception v3 and one to change
cn network
and the off size is shown in the block
additionally i also add the local binary
pattern as a feature
the weight in bgg16 and inception v3 we
use is imagenet
and the weight of the cn is trained on
30k smaller family
after feature extraction
the feature fusion step
combine the four features to one array
because the dimension after feature
fusion is very high as you can see
is
94 000
so we use pca to reduce the dimension
after keeping 95 feature which is
important to the model
the dimension is reduced to 1000
and last
we use logistic regression to channel
model and math prediction
here is the architecture of the
pre-transdn
there are nine convolution layers and
two max pro layers
we also use some drop-out there's
english cnn network
we split out the data to training and
testing the proportion is five to one
the task is a 13 world class
classification
there are 12
569 memory blocks
and
the uh the
amount is our after the data
argumentation
and the activation function in the cnn
is relu
and we also use page normalization and
learning radical
in the cn network
and the training epochs we set is 32
this table is the experiment result of
different features
the first one mem to image use all the
feature is straightforward 3 convolution
network and the lbp
it has the best result
if we only use cn to extract features
the accuracy is about 96 percent
if we only use vgg 16 with the image net
weight
the result is surprising high of the cn
and so of the inception v3
and if we only use lbp features to
channel the accuracy we are down to s4
here are the experience results for
different forms of the image
if we use all the three channels the
accuracy is the best
and if we just use
red channel and blue channel with the
local android feature
the accuracy will down to 92 percent
if we only use decimal value as a grad
scale image the accuracy is down to 88
so we can conclude that local entropy
can effectively help improve the
accuracy
here are the experiment results for
different algorithm
the result of logistic regression and
sbn are both great
and we choose logistic regression in our
framework because the computing cost is
less
the performance of xg boost and random
flow rates are not as good as the other
two algorithms
from the confusion matrix
we can see that most of the categories
can be classified very well
only four types of malware that have
misjudgement
among them
there are one categories that have
significant errors as you can see in the
picture on the right side
the two categories are poison ivy
and the present iv variant
phantom iv
our model may recognize the common area
of the
vengeance iv and prison ivy
so for some malware variants our model
may not be able to classify them very
well
this is the tsne for invading after pca
of 30 malware family
there are two interesting area
the first one is on the right
we can see that the malware immediately
used by print evp group
are very close like capture keyboards
and whatever it means that the model
used by then have many similar
characteristics
maybe we can use this phenomenon to
attribute malware to every group
the second one is in the left we can see
the copyright beacon the carboxylic
stage loaded and the copper strike
become varied are also very close
so it means that our embedding can make
the marlin variant close to the original
power family
this feature is helpful to recognize new
malware favorites
and inspire our zeroshot learning we
will talk better
a senior c map is an image that shows
each pixel's unique quality
we use it to indicate
which pixels are more meaningful or
important for each model to predict
result
so more light area is more important
in this slide we can see that our
pre-chances may obviously focus on
certain area and the area which bgg16
and inception b3 focus on more divergent
poison ivy and products also have
similar similar characteristics in
sensing map
from these four categories we can see
that bgg16 will pay more attention to
some places on the edge of the picture
and inception b3 will pay more attention
to central area of the picture
if you look a little more closely
on the
sentencing map you can find some
interesting phenomena for example the
focus area of the water bear
is the conflict block of the water-based
stage
and for a captured node the focus area
is in its auditor section
and for phantom iv the focus area is
some shell called snips
are in his
block
we also use this shellcloth section in
gyararoo to detect phantom iv
for progress
the focus area is the section which the
stake stream located
grade cam has some similarity
with selecting map
we also use this method to realize how
our convolutional network them from the
malware image
more red area indicates that area was
more important to that class
in dratix on the top right area is a c2
parsing function and api span bypass
function and the second red area is
composed of some code function before
our data section
in copper stripe beacon
area is part of our data section and
part of data section
in d-pass loader the red area of some
unique strings block shows on the right
in phone book a red arrow is sung on
first casey
stack strings
and when we want to detect unknown uh
unknown malware they didn't in the
trending class we can use neuroshock
learning
which also use mental image to extract
embedding and then use kd3 to find 5 to
10 nearest neighbors
in our dataset
for example if the nearest neighbors are
tears cookie and cubers we can expect to
learn that non-malware may be modified
frontiers cookie and maybe have high
connection to the princeton group
when we improve the sample maori into
men to image next time the nearest
neighborhood maybe the maui input last
time
and they can be new class when they have
reached a certain amount
it didn't need to return a new model
that's fantastic
here are some they will show the new
results we test on everything malware
didn't use in chaining dataset
jingle spy is a new malware used by
abd37
and we can see that the nearest
neighbors are rock great which also used
by ap37
and product as fast version and other
progress variant also shows good results
on your shot learning
another interesting thing is that there
are new malware called friend catcher
named by us
we can't really attribute the malware to
an empty group
but through the zeroshot learning is
embedding is very close to the starting
out rate
so we can speculate that friend catcher
may be relating to the actual behind
renault rate
which was title
machine learning model is embedded in
but inevitably to adversarial attack
so we also think some possible attack
methods to this framework
first actor may pay the most random
drunk bites to make the file size very
large
this way may affect the resolution of
the image and then our framework may can
recognize the real malicious part
the second way is that in liberation we
put the code of other model family into
the original malware
for opposition
and then our framework may have
misjudgement
we have also seen some actual peg file
in mary using upx and medium protect
the last method is self modifying code
it can alter its own instruction where
it is executed
we have simply used this technique in
their malware
usually you sell modeling code
the show code will decrease the code
that is needed and increase the code
that is not needed while executing
and repeat this action continuously
such mechanism may be able to bypass our
framework
for example you can see that only the
function waiting for the cognition will
be decrypted
during executing
and the others are encrypted after
self motivating code
and here's is our conclusion
more and more advanced methods of
process injection have been used in
every group and cyber crime malware
transfer learning have great performance
on memory resident malware
classification
especially on small set of data
the features extracted by a convolution
network can find out the spatial area of
malware which unexpectedly overlapped
with some error rules we wrote to the
malware family
with zero shot learning we don't need to
retrain the model frequently
we also propose some attackable methods
for adventure attack
and the map to image
framework
will
put on the github
so if you are interesting to this
framework you can go to github
and here's is our our talk to the big
asia
thank you everyone
if you have any questions guys welcome
to containers