hey guys thanks for coming out today
signed a standard eight going to
conferences so thanks for being here
before we actually start I want to make
sure to have the right people in the
room so this talk is not a technical
talk
it is not geared towards someone that
has been in cyber security for the past
you know few years five years not
someone from the industry this talk is
basically geared toward people that are
cheaper to practitioners that want to
get into cyber security students that
want to get into cyber security and
other people that has no background and
don't really know the industry that want
to get into this industry so if you're
not from these groups I will not be mad
you could leave the room otherwise you
might be frustrated because you already
know this stuff here we got one leaving
not know actually got one coming in you
can see the screen well as even a better
reason cool so what are we going to talk
about so first bit of intro me then
we're going to talk about the industry
itself to cyber security industry we're
gonna talk about the necessary
background in order to get into this
industry training you have to do and
things of that sort then we're going to
spend some time talking about actually
the industry what is consulting work
what is technology work and what is
consumer work or enterprise work as you
would most likely see it and then a few
pointers for job hunting and some key
points to conclude my thinking
so who am I to have weird history you
might hear an accent here I can talk in
my Israeli accent just as much and you
will recognize me much better though but
you're used to an American accent so
let's do that so I am next captain of
the Israeli intelligence forces
specifically dealing with cyber warfare
the big thing in israel if you've heard
the book start-up nation if you know a
small company called checkpoint that's
us we've done plenty of stuff when it
comes to cyber security we can elect
that field so I used to be a deputy see
so for one of our agencies one of our
basically intelligence agencies the
largest for development the parallel to
DARPA here so I was device see so far it
is really dark I went and will
moratorium why as you might know why are
innocent young more known to be an
accounting firm but the firm does
consulting so they acquired us we were
in Israeli startup doing application
security testing a firm called tactics
hacking tactics for a bunch of like 14
guys we required into ey and we're a
part of the Global Services servicing me
was clients in all matters I T
security-related so consultants from
Israel I transferred to the you s where
I became the senior manager within the
EU I national practice I'm based out of
Houston so took a flight to get here and
I've been talking about cybersecurity
for the past few years around the world
I like to travel I've done a talk here
as well
think three years ago about social media
and intelligence collection why Facebook
is an intelligence officers dream and
one of one of few people sent out emails
and I saw within the content of the
emails that they want to get to know
more about the industry to have a basic
understanding in it it's beyond our
reasonable idea for a talk so this is
the talk so if we look at Cyber s
exciting word or idea security be less
exciting and meaning the same thing it
is a huge industry right now just to get
an understanding the market value of
cybersecurity in 2015 is five billion
dollars that is a lot of money just
think of it I mean you just can't really
take it to any other industry and say it
is so big and by 2020 hundred and
seventy billion dollars that's just
inconceivable you think of this in the
amounts most of the amounts will be
consumed on technology and not on
consulting as we will talk about but
then again that's still something that
you know people are spending a lot of
money
think of the fact that you will spend
even though that the billions of dollars
for just facility for cybersecurity for
cybercrime is just a hundred and one
billion dollars I mean is just if you
just break down cybercrime you don't you
don't take it down with cyber terror
with suburb so much that jurors and so
much money floating around
and it's costing billions of dollars to
business so it's a good starting point
to say europe if you want to get into
this job you'll probably have something
to do for the next at least 20 years so
when we look at this industry we try to
split it down like you don't know
anything about cyber you want to get
into it so the common elements our deeds
first consulting like myself firms that
are here to help you are here to fix an
idea to fix a process to fix a
technology to fix something
ok and who was a damn thing in the
keynote the guy said that consultants
are the guys are paid to read the manual
so yeah
times he's he's absolutely right and
just sometimes the company just doesn't
know what manual to go after so we have
to find out manual and go after that one
and try to implement and then fix it you
have to ecology remember I mentioned
checkpoint to shake the checkpoints of
the world the security appliances of the
world all the big vendors and a big
security technology companies they're a
very big part of this industry they're
21 looking out after 275 billion dollar
statement there like ok I want to go
after that market as I want to own that
specific segment that's the technology
but we're talking about at the end the
consumers people that actually go
through and work with these appliance
work with the consultants and tried to
defend organizations that they're
working with so a major part of the
industry so
common questions is how do I get in like
what sort of training do I need I mean I
went to school i studied I T I did
exactly major cyber security how does
that go so many questions so one of the
things that I do I do recruiting for you
want as well and when I look at this
first I look at experience that is the
single most bang and the single most
important thing that i would tell you to
emphasize they're probably saying women
and Johnny were all without the right
background so I can experience would we
have so going to conferences talking to
people
networking is a valid experience
if you take it on and you'd be able to
have a conversation topic with the
recruiter about something that really
bugs you about I T security things that
you believe that you could have done
better even if you really couldn't have
done it better but you have an idea
really just sometimes on the other end
of the phone interviewing someone there
is a dead silence that I want to be
filled and not by me cause I'm already
working forty why I want the other guy
to tell me so it's very important to
talk about what have you did and it
really could be small things like you
contributed to the community wrote a
script that fixes something and you
believe could be fixed and not
necessarily about fixing sometimes you
just exploiting that's completely legit
but there I would caution you to be very
careful a lot of us when somebody says
yeah well I broke this machine while I
walk walked into this network that's
that's a red alarm for us so do
everything with the right caution you
don't want to go when you know so the
key in the first keynote was going to
BestBuy and tried to hack everything no
you will not you could write technical
but you would probably not get a job
with Best Buy or with a lot of the other
consultancies because there's a man
there's a measure of responsibility to
the tester has we all know that things
are broken and the concept is we want to
make it better if we go poke how these
people nothing nothing will change we
want to be responsible so finding out
the issue is very relevant so yeah so we
have in your experience if you've found
something nobody hired you but he
founded that could be legitimate topic
to talk to someone like myself
one of the most important things is the
mindset everybody talks about this
attacker mindset and you know when even
back in the Army when we interview and
yeah we interviewer like only the
intelligence community is allowed to
interviews as you probably know an
israeli have a mandatory free your
service so everybody goes into the army
so how can you really interview with
everybody going in saudi intelligence
sources get a specific exemption under
like ok we're the only service that is
allowed to disqualify people from going
in serving so as a young officer you
have an option to try and track in and
find these right individuals so we're
out to finding that attacker mindset who
is this person that is 18 years old he
does not have any experience now I need
to be able to tell the world or more
likely my commander that I believe that
he can actually graduate from our course
and he would be a good attacker or
defender depending when it comes to
sweet spot these people so a lot of a
lot of spotting the mindset is people
just then just don't get why our stuff
the way they are you walk into a
conversation and something that is a
conversation stopper you know you go and
you talk to people about even to
stupidest stuff you wouldn't believe
like how on earth would a ship stopped
mid see what like how does it work has
nothing related I D security just
nothing is just a logical question how
are you able to stop the ship so we do
all sorts of these cycle technical
analysis and the whole concept is just a
fine those people that defy that
specifically don't get the right answer
but they tried to date riding you don't
really i mean you can't really stop
fully amid C
and it's it's completely legit but we
want to get that mindset that says okay
I don't know but let's find out so let's
logically breakdown this problem and
find it out so we're looking forward at
balance that is not stressed cuz you
know a lot of people on during
interviews should be asked something and
then you'd be the worst was like ok take
a minute ok good question let me think
on it for a second
don't be afraid of pauses at that point
that's a good time to pause and
sometimes saying I don't know is a valid
answer is we sometimes need these people
as well listen to Freakonomics you
should hear about an episode that talks
about I don't know amazing one so when
it comes to education
most of the veterans and this industry
don't really believe in formal education
the Shockers and it goes for years we've
been saying we don't really get quality
and university people that have studied
something that could be very much
applied onto cybersecurity for years
that has been so it hasn't been for the
past 34 years this has changed programs
have opened up and universities are
taking a stab at this and doing some
good work so there is one thing I can
tell you is that please do not assume
that I know what your program is ok talk
to me what sort of research has your
program did what was the tasks that your
professor gave you go and walk me
through it I don't know it I haven't
done any formal education you know when
it comes to cyber security and most of
us haven't heard anything the next thing
is certifications out of that 75 billion
industry billion dollar industry
certification large part of it
everybody is like ok you know when I'll
get my CH the making going start
interviewing I went into Wikipedia just
get like the rough estimate of how many
security training certifications are
there hence I was amazed I thought there
were like 20 years online that matters
it's more like seventy and we don't like
people that are from the injury would
not necessarily know all of them and
it's not necessarily good or bad they
have a certificate it really really
really depends on where he trying to get
into ok you wanna be a pen tester
training is very good but if you go
after the offensive security
certifications which are very hard
because they have a lot of technical
background they're very good as well so
you need to really fit and see that your
certifications are
towards where you actually want to go to
you could have a valid Cisco
Certification legacy CNN that could be
very valid because somebody knows that
you know the basics of thanks and it is
important because a lot of people don't
know the basics and things and they just
go in applications without knowing what
runs on the back end there's so as the
guy before me said background here is
very very important you're not born a
cyber security guy everybody has
something in their past either being a
developer being in general I T
practitioner experience really matters
here because sometimes people try to
invent the wheel and it's the worst
thing when you're talking about
cybersecurity so it's very important
that you do you choose the right one
not necessarily because it's the most
technical one but the one that really
fits with what you want to do you want
to have a idea risk background is okay a
lot of certifications there but if you
wanna technical one don't get a ninety
risk one don't get a ninety risk one and
go interview to be a pen tester it would
not help you will not help the cause so
a song about the industry first
consulting so I think it's the best job
ever been doing it for like five or six
years so I might be the right person to
ask if if it is or it isn't
when I look at consulting and
cybersecurity I break it down to three
types of of consultants the first you
have done management consulting is the
broadest types of consulting and we will
go one-by-one you'll have the technical
guys those pen tester told the amount
and we have the technology people the
people that help you move along your
organization into the right direction
after the management consulting guys
said you should go there so the
management consulting so management is
only as you probably own though is a
very broad term to everything that you
can manage how to improve processes and
my business so cyber is no different
is a big issue we need now to know what
we need to have an organization how do
we prioritize it and how do we put it on
a road map with proper initiatives and
manage it for the next five years so
what management consulting and cyber is
is a way to establish a program for
cybersecurity in an organization as you
understand i mean cyber security is not
just one appliance that you buy
companies that really take this matter
seriously have big departments you know
people staff with like 50 people that
need to know what are their where they
messing around with its not people that
you know go up putting fires its people
that have ad hoc functions and have
specific capabilities and specific job
descriptions so concerned management
consulting is all about building out
what are they going to do should we have
network monitoring on premise and we
need to build out a network monitoring
program should we have an Incident
Response Program how does that work
order eight people how to recruit
recruit them how do you find them who
needs to manage them all the processes
that could relate to it so these
consultants will go and look after
people technology and processes to see
if they do or they don't they don't they
recommend initiatives and the
organization manages these initiatives
so they move along with it they do
assessments on how mature as the
organisation compared to other
organisation within its specific at
specific industry and sector so these
are these management consulting people
management consultant have sometimes
people don't come from technical
background they know management they
know basic concept of these are the
things that you do need it within an
organization these are things that you
don't and let's try and work it out a
lot of times you will have a lot of
junior positions within management
consulting for cybersecurity because
there is a great demand for programs
like this and it's something that is
easily trained so you can pass on
without having a lot of background cuz
it's mostly structure you have people
with a lot of background but you'll have
a lot of staff people that don't
necessarily have the right back moving
on
are the guys and everybody likes to talk
about I come from this this is what I do
which is the technical dies the
technical consulting guys granted this
is the sexiest part of the industry I
think these are guys that due to
technical assessments in our guys to do
so social networking social social
engineering we break into an
organization with the right approval
walking through the door
officially and trying to hack into the
organization so you would find positions
for penetration testers that do just
about everything for penetration testers
as I said depending on the route that
you take I've replication or
infrastructure because depending on on
companies there's there's a difference
we know that there are so many
technologies out there one person cannot
just rule them all so you'd have people
that specifically to application
security X developers that's great to
come from a background like this because
a lot of the things as the previous talk
was about fixing a Nexus S is a complex
issue sometimes so you need someone
which is actually an ex coder to talk to
the developers and say this is the
things that you need to do and this is
how you should do it so can testers are
mostly very technical therefore need to
have some sort of background and on the
infrastructure side you have people
directs network engineers mostly that
have that relevant background Mindy know
and that's the most important thing if
you don't have the right background you
just run commands you don't know why is
the input the way it is when you come
from for example a network background
you know why would that network engineer
do that and you know automatically where
to go look for in ok this is a financial
company I know that they have a lot of
branches they work with probably OSPF
for MPLS so therefore I'll go in and
attack these types of things
intuition it's not like you don't have a
methodology everybody has a methodology
but if you come from the right
background just spice up that
methodology and you find everything the
real real interesting stuff with a lot
more ease so very versatile backgrounds
here when I say network it doesn't have
to be at work you can come from a guided
does backups but really knows the
organization so much into into specific
Lee so I've tried personally believe
that this is the most interesting part
in terms of consulting no subjective
probably never part are the incident
responders the incident responders are
part of the technical consultants as
well these are the guys that will come
in after the breach and will start to
investigate the business to business
casual business but the actual breach
you'd be surprised people also all sorts
of roles as a background they think that
you know shouldn't organizations have
this capability and sign it when you
come to an organization that has been
breached there is chaos even if they
have good processes in place it's it's
like if you're a doctor ok and you're in
a car accident of course you know
everything to do but you know the actual
chaos that went around you just confuses
you you can't really do anything that's
a very good explanation to why
organizations will take incident
responders because he hasn't responded
and I have done many of those as well
you can come into an organization which
is completely you know this may you have
the c-level executives and a room that
they've never seen in their lives
and they're talking around and they're
pushing people and one of the first
things as a consultant that you come
that people from the country just can't
do is you ask all the c-level executives
to leave the room
guys are stressing out your people
nothing good will happen from this year
to calm guy so if you have good you know
if good capability your eased to do
certain things I like people to come to
instant response that have their older
people because they have the wiser you
know they've seen stuff happen
they've seen stuff brake and that's not
the end of the world so you know it's
very important here a lot of the train
there are certifications on incident
response you know a lot of stands
training there and a lot of vendors
specific training and in cases that the
software that you actually do to work
with pending on you know whatever
preventer you work with solder is good
good training capabilities here and
there are a lot of positions for
incident responders either within
organizations or as specific consultants
please remember this you have to be
someone which is calm they would not
tell you that in the interview and if
you cannot work in a stressful very
stressful environment this is NOT the
work for you so please keep that in mind
moving on other types of consultants are
technology consultants are two guys who
would oppose ok when you talk about the
technical so what's the difference would
acknowledge canceled so no technology
consultants are very focused their
focused on a problem so as you remember
to management consulting guys said okay
guys you need to improve your software
development lifecycle program to match
the relevant advancement within
cybersecurity go okay what does that
mean so you need to start an initiative
what does that mean by means that you
need to recruit the right people we need
to add specific software into your
platform you need to change the
development cycle you need to integrate
controls into your development you need
to train your your programmers to code
better you need to create a ninja
positions somebody there will be a
software security architect within
various departments would come to you
know say but how do we do it you go I
have just a guy for you so these are the
ecology guys have a good knowledge
consultants are here to solve a very
well-defined problem they have
experience with one specific field
they're not depend testers that will
just walk across every specific every
specific field Centre Street will it
need to know just a bit from everything
but you don't have to be an expert on
something specific you could but doesn't
specifically help you so a good example
of software security as we have a lot of
stuff how to actually add the value and
add the right people and organisations
we had people that come from specific
backgrounds and they go in managed a
specific operations will be consultants
that would have long term long term stay
within a specific client
they would spend a lot of time they're
built a good relationship now work with
engagement there are six months
pen tester will come into renovation a
week to free for is like doesn't happen
and then he moves on these kind of
consultants know everything about the
people they're working for its like he's
an employee of the company but then he
leaves after six months you would find
these positions and I M which is
identity management identity access
management people don't want to every
basically every technology that has a
process behind it
ok then you can just so iam is is the
whole way that you manage identities
within the organization so companies
like Oracle will come to you says I have
no idea I'm just install it can't be
easy have to sync it with all the
relevant data bases to the organization
has all the relevant access systems need
to define the processes it is such a
complex issue doesn't mean you don't
have to do it you just need to have
consultants to do it for you because
just wouldn't be able to do it on your
own so I am security monitoring that
doesn't do security operations centers
guys to manage your vulnerabilities in
gaza duty or software security it's
basically every one that says okay we
have a technology we need to understand
the process behind it if I want to go
and say pros and cons then the first
thing that you know I mean I like it of
course and a lot of the consultants get
to see new environments every two to six
weeks
ok depending on the type of consultants
so you need to understand that that's
one of the major challenges times when
used in place of these consultants like
to see more cuz that's that's how you
get better actually if you see more
infrastructure more types of
applications more technology news
conferences are not enough and training
or not enough so the beauty of
Consulting is that you just see you know
you don't go to conferences and you hear
about the latest stuff you probably had
a client that had this technology
installed
every talk within this conference I have
a client that has something related to
it so it's never news that's the beauty
of consulting was your dare you're
always on top of these tough he'll
probably never lose a discussion topic
while we're in the business but if you
like your house this is not the job for
you you get the travel at least 80% of
the time at least really I mean that's
that's the beauty of the U S at the end
you don't know where your clients will
be so you'd be on a plane just about
every Friday are every Saturday or
Sunday depending on the requirement of
the client if you if you're an incident
responder should be on a plane every
potential our you could be on call so
you know it really depends if you have a
flexible lifestyle though unable that
that's ok very good some positions like
technology consultants are you know more
morals they travel less are more stable
so you can find but then again you could
you could have a client that is you work
for six months but he's four states away
from you so it's the same environment
but it's still a lot of travel and it's
a stressful environment most of the time
again unless you're a technology
consultant most consultants are you know
when's the deadline when do we get to
get the report can we get a draft report
because we before we get the actual
report we want to review it but I'm
working on the report and I'm on last
week of reporting now we want to get
address you want me to start reporting
before I'm supposed to locate her so
much stress you end up working in
weekends lot of times to just get the
demands and again that's where the calm
people that have experienced than oh
yeah I've seen clients and asked us for
this before
ok I will not work the weekend fordice I
will wait so if you're not kind of
person who is good for you and people's
person had so you do not know how
consultants are always working with
people or not the people if you don't
like people you don't you're not good at
relationships he can't start up you know
small talks now exactly the business for
you so moving on technology when IC
technology I mean security vendors and
service providers large service
providers so what do they have you want
to go job hunting at these people so
first they have consultants as well but
they have very oriented go into the
pacific consultants so if I me product
company I want to be able to send you a
consultant they will tell you that you
basically need my my product in an
unbiased way ok somewhat but I would
still need to have some sort of rhyme
and reason to the fact that you need the
product some companies have actual
consulting practices small just to
support the overall business that they
have so you would see this existence of
consultants within specific security
vendors it's not uncommon but you know
just be able to understand that's not a
real consultants that works for a
consulting company so all the benefits
of the supporting environment that a
consultancy can provide you will not be
there so you know prioritize it if you
want to be a consultants that's probably
not the best place
then you have the RND guys the guys of
Duty actual research when you hear about
you know the latest and greatest and you
see large reports from i to security
companies nonspecific consulting
companies this is dis will always be the
Department will do it
the guys that basically do research with
the intention to develop their product
think of it of people that try to
develop new signatures have an idea for
IBS so I'll be in the R&D department and
I'll be searching for new stuff but I
will write my report about this latest
and greatest attack but I would only
also make a signature for that specific
that specific attacks oh my my security
vendor could actually spotted so if you
want security research positions
security vendors are the place to go to
their their highly secret out for him
it's when a lucrative position and if
you're not a people person that's her a
place to be in sometimes and everything
that you see as developers so I have a
friend that wanted to go into business
and one of the first thing that he he
said you know I'm a developer I want to
work as a developer and a security
vendor and that's a mistake you don't
get to advance if you work as a
developer you just need to know that if
you're a developer he want to convert
into I T security do not gonna be a
developer in a nightie security company
will not learn security for debt ok you
create and you'll develop would have
done the exact same thing that you would
have done and your previous form so my
personal advice not a lot just don't go
if you want to be a developer that's ok
there's nothing wrong with developing
but just keep in mind
unnerving that you would very commonly
have a pre-sale guys to pre-sell guys
don't tend to be very technical people
who like what
salespeople article just presale Geils
are the guys dad
the client is not sure that he is about
to buy this product of ours free soda is
basically an engineer and is sent over
to the client side and sets up the
system to work just for a short time
period so the client will see the value
of the system so we have people that are
sent very short time period and they
need to know the product the best way to
they can so the client will see the
value of the of the specific product for
presale it might not sound sexy but it's
actually a very interesting line of work
because they yet to have good client
interaction day really really contribute
to the company actually contribute to
having a sale and showing how good that
you're working for can improve certain
clients and they get to be very
technical so it's a very very good
business to be in most guys 900 highly
technical they love what they do and you
have engineers engineers are basically
the support people that run the product
on the daily basis so if you see a
security engineer within a product
company would most likely be a security
engineer that supports the overall
activity of that specific product
residing in client-side just to keep
that in mind
lastly you have account people come
people are not mostly are not technical
people there
people's people their sales ok I want to
create I want you to buy more products I
want you know gives you a discount
whatever it is they want to keep that
Klein on so they're looking into getting
to the business it's not a technical way
to get into that business but sometimes
you just have your old early have the
more you know the experience approach
into this could be a very good job for
you as well and it is within
cybersecurity
it's a very stable work have a lot of
friends that work in security vendors
highly technical people and we don't get
to travel goods if you like your house
and you wanna stay in it so you have
plenty of stuff good compensation and if
you've got in before an IPO before the
company was actually you could have very
good very good compensation sometime
soon after it depends on the type of the
company please keep in mind and that's
something that I've seen with a lot of
people to do are indeed when you do are
indeed you only do are indeed so I have
had friends that did that one of the
reasons that they left pen testing was
you know we just didn't get enough of
each time we want to do more research we
want to get to know more stuff because
when you do pen testing you don't really
do research you do a specific type of
research help your project but you see
sometimes you see you spot that there is
a way in but you need a week to week to
develop it but there's no budget to do
it so and and a lot of industries get
frustrated and they say well I want to
move on
onto R&D work because I want to do I
want to death full time I fall in love
with this most of the guys that have
done this transit that transition would
leave the R&D company within two years
because it's the same thing you're doing
the same thing you're more likely
supporting a specific product therefore
finding out specific vulnerabilities
that are focused on that specific vector
you're doing you know web you will only
do web he will not touch anything which
is infrastructure where as a consultant
a pen tester
does everything so he gets exposed to
everything so keep in mind you know
sometimes I have friends that have
stayed in R&D for five years already so
I mean it could be a stable business and
it could be somebody move on on top
management or whatever you want its low
pressure people that do are indeed you
or whatever it's mostly low pressure you
don't really get pressured into it
75 billion dollar industry would buy the
product almost without it needing to
actually work ok it sounds funny but
every product ok you would buy it and
you would not exactly test that it's
actually doing the work sometimes you
just need to fill in a specific product
saying OK we have an ideas and place
fortunately it doesn't have to be an
actual good I so keep their minds of
there's plenty of money in that industry
now let's move on to consumers so how
would if you're actually looking for
work and you don't want to work for a
company that does I security over
consulting or technology you could just
go work at what we call clients but you
know organizations that have their own
cybersecurity departments so how would
that kind of department look like and
what would be D people working there so
when you go on LinkedIn and you're like
I see this position what does that
actually mean the first most
organizations will look something like
this
ok don't you know i mean you have
variations of this but first thing is
the chief information security officer
you have some foreign governments
Department a friend for mobility
management department added protection a
sock in a consulting small consulting
operation depending on the size to
business it will always look very
similar to this some will be different
different names like someone say no
and that's exactly you'd say to see so
it'd be head of security not exactly
sober so many variants but they were
basically do just about the same thing
so the first guy to see so he's done for
most guy for everything I D security
within the organization
ok d like to say that he's the trusted
advisor to CEO wants to talk about I T
security asks the sea so you will call
to see so far chat
these are mostly executive level rules
you're not from the business you're
probably not going to be the first is
probably not gonna be the first job that
you get their accountable for everything
so basically when you look at Cyber
Security the CEO delegates' know the CEO
needs to handle cyber security as well
but he delegates and creates this person
you know chief says officer of
information security officers IC so this
is OK you'd be my guy responsible and
accountable
that's why a lot of times when big
breaches happen the sea so leaves you
know it's a common practice to just mean
he's accountable for it if you didn't do
the right things if he's really
accountable for it you would most likely
be replaced
you'd see in a lot of the major breaches
you'd be surprised that these people are
not technical did you get into an
interview and and and along the way the
see-saw interviews you don't be
surprised that it's more a one-on-one
interview that he just wants to get to
know you want to see if you're someone
that can work with him a lot of times
because these are executives they want
to make sure that if you're working with
another department you know let's say
your there their guy for software
security for working with that the
developers within the company or person
that they can work with you and your
people person you're somewhat people's
person least for developers so don't be
afraid of you know interviewing with the
big boss he would not always be
technically doesn't always care about
technical because he would believe that
you know certain things could be built
along the way the first apartment I'll
talk about his governance people often
hear about governance has the boring
stuff but not necessarily so the
government's apartment is mostly run by
someone that is as I love manager of
cyber security governance program
surprising and it the first thing it
does is that it creates all done all the
policies and procedures for
organizations so depending on the
industry that you're in you have to have
some sort of securities our security
policy and governance program in place
you have to say ok this is what we're
telling our people to do what not to do
this is our servers RIT guys are
functioning and these are the policies
that we have and you have to have
someone that is basically in charge of
it
as you might honored guests not
necessarily a technical person running
it or technical individuals the pin
depending on the specifics of of the
organization sometimes these people get
the work of disaster recovery and
business continuity management and so
you might see people you might see
positions there for Dr to Dr disaster
recovery is somewhat related to
cybersecurity and it is somewhat a good
way to get into cyber security but it's
not necessarily cybersecurity so you
might see you might see openings for
their they also managed a risk
management program within the
organization which that is more
interesting part of their work there are
two guys that say basically ok we had a
breach ok because a pen test found it
now what sort of risks does it pose on
our organization and how do we fix it so
they have an overarching view on what
goes on within the organization so
someone with experience very related
they also handle all the compliance the
first dog before an added dimension PCI
so they'll be the ones that will work
with the consultants say OK are we
compliant or are we are we not
and regulations of things of that sort
and other department will be the friend
zone ability management department so
these are the technical guys if a pen
tester once to retire he went off then
go into one of these departments he
doesn't want to travel anymore he wants
to do his stuff but on one client and
you'd be surprised because sometimes you
just want to spend your time on one
client sometimes you're like I keep
seeing this problem happening over and
over give me one environment that I can
make sure that I can fix it so you'd see
a lot of highly technical people they're
basically handling all the penetration
testing work
or fret modeling modeling is the concept
of not doing actual penetration testing
but finding the friends that could
relates to an application or an
infrastructure they would actually audit
everything that has been done in terms
of mitigation so if if the finding has
specifically stated that you have to do
this you have to create dispatch if you
have to yes to improve this development
things of that sort
there are two guys those ok you did this
but it didn't resolve it because I
retested it and that's the problem they
will also manage these offers securities
o'dell work with the developers to make
sure that coating the weight that they
should make sure that there's training
adequate training within the
organization
very technical people and think it's
kind of challenging work another part
will be the data protection so you'd
you'd hear head of data protection made
a prediction is a subset of
cybersecurity that is specifically how
we handle data so you've probably heard
of products to do the ALP work which is
that a leak or data loss management
products these are the guys that would
say okay this is the way we classified
data within our organization by this you
know by this system of classification
sensitive nuns and other public whatever
they decide this is the technology that
will support this specific day the
specific classification methods and they
will added it to make sure that works
adequately they're the ones that will go
and seek out each and every department
within the organization and work with
them you know I'll go and help out going
to work with the help this to make sure
that were working on our encryption the
way that we should because we have to
have full disk encryption saudis will be
DS
will work with each and every person
within the organization to make sure
that they're on track so plenty of roles
there sometimes managerial sometimes
technical depending on the size of the
organization
a lot of people that come from
consultants as technology consultants
because one of the practices of
Technology Consultants is deal P systems
GOP is very similar it is also a
technology that requires a process
behind it it's a good place to
transition into either to or from
depending on where you come from
so another one then you have the sock
the security operation center most of
the positions that you would see out
there are four stock analysts so these
are the guys that basically monitor
everything that goes on within an
organization on every part of your
infrastructure ok we all know that we
cannot the perception within 90 security
in recent years have changed from
perimeter security to monitoring ok with
the date the old conception was we will
defend our perimeter as hard as possible
and we will not get the attackers into
the organization we understood that this
is a fallacy and will not work they will
get into the organisation therefore we
need to monitor them so is is closely
monitored as we are we have we have a
way to actually find them so the stock
would actually be the staff that
monitors each and every part of the
network and the analysts will be 21
analyzing each and every request
vicious activity so they would have all
the times similarities to incident
responders but at a triage level they
just start they know that they have a
procedure to have to follow so they
start it but it's a good place to go
into the business because you need to
have some background but that background
can be covered with certifications or
with formal education and it is it's
it's very welcoming to start as an
analyst with a sock department in some
in some businesses
you also have consulting so health care
and financial organizations have come to
the conclusion that there are spending a
lot of money on consulting work and they
could be easily do it on their own for
highly critical systems so you would
have very good security practices for
consulting with in large organizations
and of course they have all the benefits
of not traveling and not having as much
stress as the standard consulting box
they'll be highly technical or highly
technology oriented and highly
mission-critical that they really helped
organization it's kind of rare nowadays
I mean it's a drawing thing but it's not
something that is so common as I said
throughout this label work it's
everything is reasonable
it's a good thing to start with a good
way to get in
and its European on the same environment
which as a consultant I can tell you
something which is exciting because he
really get to improve something you
really have your you know you have your
finger that to help fix and meant to
close this out we know that not
everybody meets the requirements now we
have right when we recruit it is
completely let you know trying get a job
that you don't know 400% that you do fit
what you believe that you have the
capabilities to learn for it to develop
on to it as recruiters understand that
ok when we're on a call with someone we
know that no he doesn't tick all the
boxes but he has great potential please
won't learn how to write a cev it is so
important please remember that because
I'm too technical guy and I'll be a
manager getting this this would have
gone through for recruiters until I will
get the cev it's no different with any
other company just find the right way to
rate your cev on a one-page nobody looks
after the second page and you must be
drop you know CBS that have two pages or
just don't go after half of the first
page so please write paragraphs of how
lovely you are
be very precise and focus every cev has
to be focused to the position you're
applying to don't have a standard one
you have to fit it to fit the right
position ok it so you need to fit in a
bit but not so it's not something that
is too hard to do
you have to love this business I don't i
cant even extend how much you have to
love this person to be good at it
your friends have to be ICT security
guys his you want to talk to them about
it that's one of the first things are
you reading in the morning as I to
security news you have to go to
conferences you have to network with the
right people you have to spend enough
time
ok it's so many jobs are just not like
that I come from a line of Baker's ok we
have been making sense you know
seventeenth-century I think and you can
go home and shut everything off he'll be
a great Baker afterwards that's not the
way it works with cybersecurity ok you
have to give your soul into it
not everybody wants that work life
balance 2011 to be able to shut it down
and cut it off so we go to their
practice I don't believe that I security
is the right person the right place for
that person but you know I'm not the
expert I just have some some some sort
of experience of a decade's worth of
experience in this industry so that's
our guys think almost exactly on time
any questions as good as