kick this off couple notes of process
except her first of all so one of the
tenets of speaking is to tell people
what you're gonna tell them tell them it
and tell me again I'm not gonna do that
another element is don't put slides up
there I charts some of these are in fact
some of these slides are meant for you
if you want to read while I'm talking
find that they're meant to be able to
download later in read this is
essentially more of a brain dump kind of
knowledge transfer if you do have
questions raised her hand I do you keep
it interactive to an extent try to keep
the pace moving as well this year I am
next away from the podium have a mic
finally he probably figure out very
quickly
hyperactive I walk around a lot and if i
moving too fast
also raise your hands they won't do slow
down so again Mike my goal here is we're
going to cover incident response you've
heard that the acronym DFI our digital
forensics and incident response to focus
on the incident response part will
allude to some of the stuff in the
digital forensics world but this is not
about forensic sign in necessarily here
it's a process of learning and talk and
again at the end I may have a second
section it depends how fast or slow this
goal is to go through a bit more
material my goal here is knowledge
transfer and again the focus of this is
how to respond to incidents and having a
process having a plan ahead of time for
if and when something bad happens your
thing I don't do too is out to like
stupid miles whatever I'm Derek
hopefully find this shit useful if you
don't you know something that's my goal
is here to give you some guy some good
stuff so you can go back to work with
something to look at differently
something to do you know action items so
security incident was my other slides
and assessed event of attempted access
unauthorized access or information
attack on automated information systems
blah blah blah him Google stuff you'll
get answers a paragraph long two
paragraphs long you can drink beers with
people in debate the ship for hours on
end what is a security incident someone
I used to work for actually said I want
you to go with DUI destruction of
interest information unauthorized access
use or disclosure modification or
interfering with systems operations
kind of covers it for the most part cool
I'll steal that he said go ahead so I
can use the DUI model for that each
organization's gonna be a little bit
different so I can't really answer this
question for anyone in this room even
myself as I change jobs and different
employers what people consider incident
and what they don't the tough tough
question I always think of incidents as
three different kinds right so human
resources related someone's
investigating someone for improper web
usage emailing off stuff you're not
supposed to email etc that schools in
the next 12 confidential leakage are
they stealing company data and giving it
to a competitor you know call this
customer lists etc
attack related incidents have we been
hacked whether it's humans are
combination humans and malware and stuff
like that
trying to export trade data from the
company also remembered nowadays to
keynote thing for his response it's
impossible to get hacked by something
basic it's always gotta be complex just
read the news right choice a
sophisticated attack remember that's
gotta be sophisticated always your
marketing people in legal people put
that in their email way related also
falls into the third category third
categories where I live I avoid human
resources shit like the plague anybody
support proxy locks her company over I
don't wanna know my fellow employees are
surfing on the web that I had to once
and it may going to some meetings really
weird it's like while you're a freak you
know you're thinking in your mind
holy shit I thought I was twisted man so
I have a way that stuff like the plague
confidential data leak incidents just
get so legal so fast and it just makes
it sound like fall asleep to me the fun
stuff trying to figure out whether or
not we then attacked or someone stole it
should offer network
again difference between privacy right
privacy incidence other ones we're
trying to say maybe somebody put out the
plans the blueprints for the new
whatever which we make etcetera wright
also sometimes it turns the privacy and
since when you have lost or stolen
equipment we might have to notify if
their stuff on there it wasn't encrypted
properly customer data etc right and
other thing to keep in mind too and I'll
just throw random tidbits in this is one
of them something I'm socializing I
company now is cuz we have PCI stuff
like PCI is not your biggest concern K
the FTC is gonna come after your ass for
customer information that's what gets
you a twelve million dollar fine on the
spot in 10 years full of external audits
gotta pay for the credit card shit if
you think PC to get their shit credit
card right here wanting anybody want my
credit card or debit card it's one
frickin phone call even on my checking
account I don't lose 50 bucks I make
goddam phone call I'm back in business
by the end of the day I don't give a
shit customer information for identity
theft different story so the privacy
word always reminds me that its
classification k the next to slide suck
and that they stopped because they've
been updated in years there's a point to
them meaning you can pick the stuff
appoint a part here you've got incidents
usually a rainbow color just three
colors these are like five from way back
when severe high medium allow that goes
off maybe had an incident response
process for just
I T incidents in general for the service
disruption etc
number of customers affected number of
systems affected etcetera
the point is you're gonna need a way to
differentiate stuff to some of the
significant loss of data large number of
systems compromised you know your attack
for sure you're not sure yet you know
it's these end up having to be in your
documentation somewhere how do you make
differentiate a really bad from a really
good one so I put these slides and again
some stuff you can download it later
look at this is meant to give you some
ideas
this is what I've seen other people do
this based on my view some of this as
well
all so I just to be complete put all
three of them there which one is like
bullshit just getting scanned right so
what is your response process have to
address now I start flipping everything
goes in acronyms right so priority of
incident response versus SLA work what I
mean by that
bau responsibilities the world can stop
you can have everybody from every team
working or security incident
necessarilly if you get so need you
might get a really bad attack is taking
down enough you're not working and have
everyone all over the place doing
everything right priority of your
containment example you've got a system
that has compromised his just a malware
type thing it's not really stealing data
might be infecting other companies
what's it worth to you if you make a
million dollars an hour on that system
you may not take it down to patch it and
remove the infection till six o'clock at
night right idealism for high school and
college students were in the world of
business if you work for a company that
makes money start learning business
that's why I learned business get a
checkbook best way to learn risk by
insurance that's the business you're in
you're not here to say no as part of
security that includes you know to say
I'm going to contain this right away and
shut down the business immediately gotta
stop all third-party connectivity right
right off the bat
no you're not gonna be allowed to do
that usually you need to know about your
emergency can't change control
procedures the next point i think is one
of the most important points in the deck
long ago probably over a decade ago
sands made a step-by-step instant
response guide that I read that changed
my life forever and it had in it and
that newer versions don't know why the
hell they don't you gotta have a gold
and silver team gold is management age
are legal etc they decide when to notify
business they make all the decisions
about what you can and can't do this
going to cost millions of dollars by
cutting connections silver team keep the
geeks on their own bridge keep the
managers the hell off the bridge the
silver team get their work done
silver teams usually runs essentially by
someone home security team right and
then you have a Siamese your primary and
secondary preferences but if people are
on vacation
you know they're on vacation right
the gold-silver teen model seems to work
out very well that means you have to set
the bridges and sometimes don't people
from the Gold team bridge will come down
and hang on the silver team bridge to
find out what's going on in figure out
how to put it into like non-technical
speak to give the executives of an
update
anybody ever been on incident we had
just one combined bridge freakin
nightmare right oh my god you talk about
people get in the way and you know what
else you don't want to be thinking about
shit out loud is geeks in front of
leadership and it sucks they don't
understand what you're saying and
anytime you say something that sounds
innocent to you they might be panicking
they just hear certain words not knowing
what the hell the context as they start
freaking out on the call
bad news he want to get the gold and
silver team in place there you go
Gold team start expanding over time to
worship it's hell God gotta call the
lawyers and again you want lawyers on
your phone when you're trying to do
forensics and containment stuff
hell no marketing people know where to
go to market people going to say we were
hacked by a sophisticated threat right
it was a double advanced persistent
threat who has been hacked by some easy
we were hacked by a kindergartner
by some African YouTube video right on
how to do shit and then ten minutes
later our data is gone you could do that
with the sequel
there you go that's like 40 or 50
anybody remember security reforms never
talked about how cool net products ten
years later
coordinator for the security what does
that mean means you're the portion of
the esta document as shit out of
everything you've got to be able to say
who did what and when you've got to make
sure whatever people are doing things
are gathering the evidence properly the
chain of custody shit right you're gonna
have to write the after-action review
from those meetings and then use a
Siamese subject matter expert various
platforms I believe in the hub and spoke
model and I believe no matter how much
earlier environment is you could be CMMI
capability maturity model 3 on all your
shit everyone in your company you're
always going to have some means that no
stuff right that inside now is that you
get from being there for a few years
those are the people you're gonna
desperately need of something really bad
happened at work they're going to know
about the radical segments that were
added last Tuesday that you weren't
notified of his you're trying to figure
out where the hell this thing can spread
to her what they can get to write their
gonna be there was no actually we had to
disable the personal firewalls last week
right shit like that that's your not
necessarily get that from the change
control thing anybody here believe
change control the save the world I am
an ideal guy man change controls been a
pain in my ass for a decade we still
have our just based on plan changes he
change Advisory Board meetings and all
that stuff so can't be just internal now
from people
has a typical incident flow reported by
Acts any SIM vendors in the room
bummer ok this one nice pisses off
lattice inventors thank you for being
honest raise your hand
really pissed off a lot of bodies good
friends that work for some companies by
the way and log management some also
been involved with for well over a
decade
well worth the time most of the weird
incidents in the really bad ones incomes
have been over the years have not
started from an alert from my symptom
management too or my IDs they almost
always start with a phone call it's
always the most elaborate member the OSI
model Larry humans it's the layer 8
ideas assisted men's or the users that
start the ship is just weird we did all
this other stuff even if you don't have
shelf where we implemented the stuff
correctly in it how does how it happened
we get notified frickin phone call right
to get notified of a potential incident
you sign into the coordinator now you
want to determine if there's an incident
are now whether or not need even pull in
the Gold team start making sure your
chain of custody stuff is there that's
where you start the timeline don't
forget the timeline but if you're
running in the middle of the night
trying to reconstruct the timeline hours
later you don't want to do that that's
like getting really really drunk in the
next morning get the other group of
people I'll try to figure out what the
hell happened the night before you don't
want to do that on an incident in and
you're also responsible for the report
so again if it's not an incident that he
might throw it off to a cleanup effort
for a triage you like okay nothing
really really bad happened we need this
malware clean off 10 PCs it turns into a
ticket inside remedy or whatever and
again the coordinator starts making sure
the channels are for communication open
up gold bridges silver team bridges etc
another one of those key points today
now understand in my mind I'm always
speaking for the enterprise that's at
least a hundred thousand PCs at least
10,000 servers I just go on that scale I
have work environments much smaller I'm
currently in a pretty small environment
I like five thousand servers 10,000
points and I know that there'll be
people that are an even smaller
environments so sometimes this can't be
done absolutely but you want to no
matter what obey the rule of two if
there's any way possible to do it if
you're a two-person shop I had my boss
start learning for answers when I was in
a two-person shop a little bit as far as
we could both do this stuff you don't
want to put someone on incident alone
cover rule of to no one's perfect as
much as I've done some of the stuff I
guarantee Oscar showed up I'll guarantee
you is specially at 2 or 3 a.m. I'm
gonna screw something up
rule of two you violate it at your own
peril is typically you're going to pay
for that if you don't feel bad
sequestering the IR team kind of
old-school ish at least some of the
stuff up here by the way like these
slides are over ten years old that's a
lot of the content so I it's it's just
there's a new twist on it in here but
that's one like from the old days
sequestering the IR team is anybody in
the same physical location anymore I
guess it depends on geography of your
company's facilities size a company
except maybe after virtually sequester
people maybe have places they go to
quiet room so people don't over here
talking in the cubes something to think
about ahead of time right
you need to know the policy for incident
details that means your gonna right now
our policy that's why you want to review
in know it to gold he's gonna throw at
you that's just to get job seems but in
the policy it says this psycho shit we
can update the policy that you're
getting called up by the gold bullion
frickin response has got a better thing
that you do not have a better method
that you didn't regress back in your
policy don't forget to keep all that
stuff in line and again sometimes legal
will will have cut off point where they
take ownership of the incident was
golden so I just put a lot of stuff to
keep hammering people's head on things
like the golden silver team I really
believe in this work for me everywhere
I've been
it has saved me so much time and effort
hassles big believer in that
so again how the incident communicated
basically management bridge deck bridge
is what this comes down to it again here
I'm doing and that's why it if you down
with us later and go through what's the
other thing I repeated it's one of those
I do you some basic tactics there is
again that damn rule of 2 I've been
burned my that bad
embarrassingly bad luckily I didn't get
burned paycheck bad by it so try to get
at least two people on stuff this one
again has a different view
yeah gold blah blah I have are you tell
us about that and they tell you to do
more to change controls all this kind of
stuff silver team right they have the
conference bridges they know all
gathering evidence all that kind of
stuff what's this
so some of you may have incident
management teams and they manage
incidents throughout the company
San went down right domain controllers
died 7 now just stuff like that
sometimes they're gonna front-end your
IR process not necessarily a bad thing
worked out in advance in larger
companies incident management going to
set up the goal bridges gold timber
doesn't still retain bridges they have
all the protocols for how to get the
business engaged even a lot of times
they have the status updates that they
did you text messages without any real
details to you know get sensitive
information away so make sure you talk
with those folks first is your
architecting all this process and
procedure on how you gonna respond to
incidents they may have half the
communications stuff documented and
maintained for you where they do it
cause you'll see some of the download to
get off the internet communications
login have your emergency contact log
well if you have an incident management
function that might already all be there
and if it's only missing a couple
contacts add yours into that a lot of
times this will help front end and take
a lot of almost like admin work off your
hands he can focus on more on getting in
some response process in place which
have to do that
you can start focusing on getting the
forensics in place
process before tools every time you will
get burned if you don't do that now
another thing I use for sands six-step
process preparation identification
containment eradication recovery
follow-up lesson learned I live and die
by this I've implemented this literally
at least half a dozen companies
personally as an employee and as a
consultant I've had dozens more flip to
the smile I told you buy into this model
right so again when something's
classified you've got incident this is
the way you run through it
preparation buyers play on the slide you
don't put arguably it is the most
important phase without preparation
you're going to have really a lot of
problems you can we get to a certain
extent been there for I learned this
kind of stuff
nice to win it so been there again our
policy processes forms and report
templates forensics tool kits and
scripts here's another important point
prior me repeat myself a few times when
I do there's a reason it's caused some
have been burned on anyone here a
standardized company images pretty much
ok if you have desktop standard images
in a change hardware they're doing a
massive hardware change did you read
test all the live memory acquisition
tools on it to make sure they still work
with the new shit you don't want to find
out at 2 a.m. been there done that so we
see later I mentioned tabletop exercises
for me now it's tabletop + always do
your evidence acquisition practice it
bi-monthly if you can meaning every
other month when you get new people on
your team if you're a larger team test
your processes best way to process
document said now someone knew the team
throw it to Manhattan do it if they
can't do it gotta fix your doc right so
it's more process procedures doc
more detailed instructions but
you've gotta run through this stuff on a
regular basis that's part of preparation
is making sure your shit works have
three different images can you image off
all 3 images
getting the hard drive images easy to
find where a lot of times you gonna do a
lot more live forensics nowadays we're
already seeing that ten years ago
yeah we could do that Runde against the
RAM and go ahead and run strings on I
got shit like volatility right so I mean
it's it's you're going to do more and
more live friend asked a lot and point
to start at the ability to do a little
I've forensics and get shit out of
memory on the machines out there in the
world to see what's going on so that's
that's all part of preparation again
policies
needless to say approved by upper
management clear into the point
practical practical and enforceable not
gonna go to stupid thing again this is
actually a nice one source unknown found
on the internet I wish I the damn source
for this actual copy and paste that shit
all over the place for policy document
it seems to shut people up
it works as a definition cause people
don't question it is just the normal
stuff and actually has the DUI stuff
baked into it is good policy process
procedure policies a statement of intent
in my world I know this another one
people have tons and tons of
conversations on processes the workflow
the framework right behind us specifies
named resources are teams when it has
two procedures are step-by-step right to
update your toolkit updates member
procedure document people afraid of all
this to like our can't do this much
documentation yes you can print screen
prints bullet points that's mostly what
your procedures documents are workflow
you know the process detailed work for
telling what steps do things in outlying
that that the two or three pager you do
if you look at it now and then you're
good policies high-level statement and
they shouldn't change that off and it's
like we're going to respond to shit in a
structured way cool
free download out there to terminate
maybe make a separate form for
determining whether something is in it
since you're not filling out too much
paper on it but you want a paper trail
this goes back to where you're trying to
justify your staffing overtime newsflash
company they gonna make money
about budgets which leads to headcount
staffing justifications etcetera
of metrics on how much stuff you look at
the time you spend looking at it as a
determinant is nothing that's the kind
of stuff you need to do so people know
why any the amount of people you do for
Internet response right incident reports
same information as the above plus
what's the exposure of the companies
involved locations details of what you
do when you get detailed eradication
your detailed timeline is in here
there's a lot of good stuff
document template you could stand on
this something I did something I chain
of evidence the report itself would make
sure you do your follow-up like what it
cool if I mean let's face it work in
corporate America and also might be
governments that might be america has
everything you want something to happen
put it in Excel
work but especially Excel so I just
started doing my corporate geek
cross that bridge long ago lost all my
idealism sold my soul to my paycheck and
all that shit right why despite
everything Excel so that's kind of what
I do now for everything we have DLP
incident form that we do
guess what Excel cause someone's gonna
do something with it
you ever see someone that's why it's a
great attack vector by the way anyone
see any company in general especially
our user population whether as I T or
not people open Excel files because they
figure all that work I have to get done
they attached to the ticketing systems
all kinds of stuff cheat sheet one of
the things I do when you download this
now thrown up in PowerPoint format by
the way I'm such a moron with so this
MacBook I'm speaking off of I finally
got its an older one my mom had it
didn't use it for anything so I guilt
her into giving it to me now I realize I
Harley is max at all and I'm like I
couldn't get the PowerPoint Trans Am I
speaking off a PDF for proof right but
when you download the presentation I
gave a presentation to take the slides
and modify to your needs right now lots
of links the links are always hot ladies
alters cheat sheets those packet life
dotnet cheat sheets for other shit too
they got regular I T cheat sheets good
stuff
checklist and cheat sheets there's a
reason astronauts and doctors and
emergency medical technicians use that
shit we need to kind of copy that from
now right
help you not forget something at 3 a.m.
they're not the end all be all you may
go off script on some things we don't
have enough checklist and cheat sheets
in our industry and people don't take
him down in customizing enough for the
organization
kind of an opinion piece I know but I'm
just obscene not been burned by it
shit I forgot to do such-and-such didn't
do a write blocker when I took that
image now it ain't worth shit in court
cheat sheet what a savior again
tabletop exercises I can see this part
of preparation not meant to find every
process gap does reinforce your training
for silver team members out the
different platforms right Gold team gets
time used to some stuff I focus more on
silver team for tabletops
include evidence acquisition anybody
here had to figure out at 2 a.m. how to
use a tool when they're doing in
response as I have in it sucks it sucks
bad the time to figure out how to get
something done the you need done in an
investigation is not two or 3 a.m. it
gets really really ugly at that point of
the night so you want to figure this
stuff out ahead of time that's why I
said preparation is absolutely priceless
you know it's out of the six steps the
rest of them there's less material on
the most materials on preparation that's
the biggest thing you have to do is
prepare all this stuff what tools are
you going to use are going to use FTK
imager I can use didi off a Cali CD
whatcha gonna do what what are you can
analyze stuff we would use man in red
line are going to use volatility what
commercial tools he gonna buy and why
you gonna go with NKC DK if so what
components of those tools do you get the
lead all modules with you gotta think
about all this stuff but it starts with
the process that's something you'll see
me get on later as well to number one
thing that pisses me off that I think
makes us look amateurish people
qualified people that you invest in
process in technology you don't get to
talk your way out of that shit ok for
some reason everyone thinks it to you
box won't do it for you box now
recovered installing a tool versus
implementing a process is a big
difference
installing a tool you can use a tel
number once you've installed the system
partition cause people don't have I T
backgrounds and don't know you never
install a damn thing to a system
partition right so they just install the
shit they click through
you think a few things out at the
command line holiday you need to read
the book and see the movie anybody ever
done both and he compared to when you
you just see the movie vs read the book
forces both need to do both in this shit
in our field and by the way if you're
picking tools in buying tools without
the process already in mind you got a
problem how the hell did you know what
you're buying something for what are you
trying to achieve by the way party
process documentation is going to tell
your scope purpose assumptions and
dependencies how many people support
forensics on max
people support forensics on iOS
currently where I'm at we don't we
stated you want mac forensics the fee
for an outsourced that shit we gotta
contingency contract prepare for 30
caddy African budget for the
investigation we don't do androids right
now we don't do iOS test shopped out to
so why would we worry about buying tools
that can do that actually put on the
ranch where we can do more stuff easier
for free you don't have your processes
and procedures in place a lot of a live
acquisition stuff just gonna be open
source any way a very good way I'm a big
proponent open-source how the hell do
you buy the all these frickin tools to
help him for what he's gonna buy that
she needs click the Install button
figured out man if you read the book
RTFM that saying is older than I am and
I'm 48 years old
there's a reason the same as that old
thomas' holds the fight fire with fire
people knew how to write a freakin
manual that saying came out right you
gotta do both so far preparation knowing
why you're doing what you're doing
identification again LA Times a phone
call
make it with your sim to get it tuned
properly or other solutions right so
here's the thing identification also
includes that people don't think of
scoping shit if the sign of this
compromise now known as IOC's indicators
compromise are these five reg keys we
run a quick script to see who all is
infected that's part of identification
see know what you have to contain right
also anybody ever hear it when you're at
work
go to command prompt on your Windows box
you're on your corporate machine type
that space if you know what happens you
know your domain controller is who your
mail server is you know what you can in
fact from your machine to other machines
by the way my favorite pet peeve that
pissed me off that commands been out
since I don't know before Windows XP and
people get into a network ports can find
other targets for Microsoft targets 108
user-level Commission on a machine that
view dumbass nine or the domain
controller is why make noise scanning
for shits it'll tell you can see helpful
it also in forensics lot of system in
tricks or friends except for indicator
tricks are pen testing tricks they're
all kinda combine that way but you want
to figure out what all can happen bad
from what you think was compromised
containment can be removal after you
gather evidence especially live evidence
network cable right away nowadays we
never did you got to gather evidence
first to figure out what's going on
you're live data stuff could be AC else
I remember having a see all the old days
when it was the worm day is having a
sale that would shut down parts of the
network automatically the network team
had those ready to go for that next
microsoft word that was going to come
out now is back obviously early two
thousands right don't forget when you're
containing the Gold team involved change
control procedures stuff like that
eradication again make sure you have
your evidence first follower live data
disk images eradication you can use
avian cleaning utility sometimes custom
scripts now sometimes your AV vendor can
be your best friend if it is a malware
related thing or has an hour later
component that can make a cleaner if you
already have the shit deployed here ten
thousand desktops use that
infrastructure allow your fix vs
inventing a new wheel right
recovery could be rebuilds especially
the workstation realm patching and
updating everything verifying systems
afterwards you can watch in your sim
tool if they start doing stuff again are
you not slow tools to see if the system
is behaves you can scan to look for
stuff got active listeners with a
vulnerability management tool sometimes
part of recovery is the implementation
of new technology and I know how many
worms it takes to get personal firewalls
and it made her insurance company took
three after the third when we finally
got our damn firewalls on the laptops
and desktops and stuff kinda interesting
took forever
follow-up I'm gonna put this number to
your simpy got all the stuff to do
everything to be prepared for it then
you do it you execute this can be really
important to what do you do after the
incident figure out process gaps fix
them maybe technology gaps technology
that you need address that right
architectural changes that come to mind
sometimes it takes a security incident
to get that IPS in line in between you
and your third party people that are a
dedicated third-party VPN concentrator
he knew that was the right architecture
all along
couldn't get it sold the incident report
from the shit that just cost you a bunch
of money says this is actually the way
to go now suddenly you got your third
party connections all audited all going
into the same concentrator and all
behind an active IPS in with other
monitoring etcetera followed can be very
important that's the last one but I just
put example for now I like now just
because it sounds like too much work but
things out there some people use
successfully by the way anybody if your
gonna do now in a corporate environment
you know he would anybody have an idea
who they want to talk to
go talk to a major university they've
been doing that for years
try to follow their model he even if
you're not BYOD they've got experience
with it just saying
follow-up after-action review separate
line for each class think they're both
important followed by think more for
following up with the architects
architectural stuff trying to get
approvals off stuff that you know
affects the environment after actions
were you really fully documenting the
lessons learned
you're looking deeper policy you know
sometimes lessons learned can be an
indicator of a lack of a countermeasure
as well just not one that just failed
sometimes something that you could be
that you're missing completely like some
advanced protection he hadn't thought of
that actually would work and here's why
another one the first one I like to be
lost as user awareness training not open
that can of worms have seen a lot of
people argue for an enhanced user
awareness training and depending on my
date either makes me laugh or to
structure it frustrates the shit outta
me because you know you an example my
wife to give a crap what I do for a
living in fact she does he really want
to hear about my career and also just
not into technology at all yet for the
past 10 years she's always amazed at the
people in her workplace that click on
stuff she never does see the user
training work with her now you're not
paying money to see if you can find out
how much money takes us on a person to
work station to fix the shit so I do
think there's a big bang for the buck
for user awareness training you want to
feed stuff to learn on security
incidents India user awareness training
what type of file you're not blocking
cause the business won't give you
approval no matter what then you need
your users know that the shields are not
beyond that I Kr business won't let us
block
taxis da texts through email they just
won't say I'm is using pulling example
out of thin air here you can't win that
battle no matter what will then you
better make damn sure users know that
they're not cover their cause users
might assume automatically the security
team is doing her thing protecting the
environment so you want to be aware of
feeding back into your training as well
on this thoughts on outsourcing desires
can ask a question
live forensics determining whether
something is an incident is pretty much
in-house malware analysis can go either
way depends if you want people doing
sifted rednecks all day
figure out exactly how the virus works
for you want to try to get it from your
AV vendor maybe a combination of both I
can't give you the right answer on that
right it depends on your staffing
profile in your operating model for your
security team companies budgets etc
maybe only outsourced imaging and
advanced File System Analysis know do
you want to go to court yourself you
want to pay someone else that's good at
it
here's your thing you better learn how
to gather evidence is you have to gather
evidence for the consultants there
probably around all over the country
gathered evidence for you or the world
that's why the IRS to keep in-house it's
one of the things when you outsource you
might get some of the DFT digital
forensics outside the incident response
you own that shit or your company does
right
see private have all this in place where
they're going to go with an outsourced
model or not I think of outsourcing that
which can be commoditized that's why I
said a lot don't have the time or don't
want to build the infrastructure for
stuff
pretty obvious point of this slide
always have a plan you don't want to be
in this stuff learn how to structure
stuff quickly in the middle of an
incident your live and die by the 80 20
rule
you're not going to get perfection any
more than any other service offerings
kind of implies that info second general
stop trying to get perfect you can
troubleshoot anything to death he can
nitpick anything to death he can take
any conversation to 15 levels lot
further than you need to write just like
I I hate using analogies to contain any
analogy apart gotta kind of using any
way to get your point across but I
understand that you need to structure
quickly that's where checklist and
templates have they also help enforce
consistent methodology like anything
it's all about the methodology when
people come to the security team get
different answers for shit all the time
it's a sign of an immature security team
what kind of brand are you putting out
there should have all your stuff
templating looking the same process
procedures checklist service offerings
track the maturity of makes this is no
different than other stuff you do versus
bill we just installed a product we just
look at the thing every now and then we
just click on ship the hell is that
right
you're there to offer services why I
don't hide the fact I'm big on high till
not the ideal that leads to a hundred
page manuals the ITIL that leads to shit
you can do with the screen print utility
right if there's something you do then
you can do in your sleep and you can
take the screenshots and write the
bullet points to do it
bullshit and if your manager your people
and got time to do this you got the
wrong people that boring when you're
doing screenshots golden rule
I've seen as one violate a lot don't
panic don't let other people panic good
responders don't panic and keep the
panic level down it's easy to start
panicking by the way so that when the
few times actually legitimate work
Hitchhiker's Guide to the Galaxy until
presentation so tools the DAF of DFI are
what they call instant discovery
forensics lives forensics
have we been hacked term if humans
attack he was kinda what you're getting
behind it I like to give links to stuff
for people to follow up the things last
week I went through every day and one of
these links to make sure they're still
alive not even change some new ones out
for you and if they don't gonna be
pissed cause I literally just last week
the Internet should not change that fast
but so we've got different scripts for
Windows some of these are pearl some are
batch files I think there might be one
in there that has some that's using
powershell here's the issue on these
kind of scripts that have it it's kind
of a weird debate I have with myself as
well I'm not sure I'm and on this I
started out with batch files calling
external utilities knowing that if I run
like file minor problem on your gonna
see that he was a shift on the system
some of the deal all that makes calls to
it but it's mostly off system so I take
copy and that . XP for Windows and put
it off on a on a USB I'm getting the
routing table not if it's rooted what
the rootkit routing table would give me
right in its sole PowerShell you can't
do that with but I'm seeing people use
PowerShell more more for forensics
anyways I'm like but you are on Boxee
remote PowerShell you if that systems
rootkit its gonna lie to you and there's
really no chance of knowing that with
PowerShell it at this point in time it
appears I always speak disclaimers cuz
man as she gets really weird just
something to keep it keep in mind by the
way my customer batch files I had some
of the banks that everyone's name
knowing you're using that shit cuz it's
fast give it to someone out the field
from this batch file get back to me is
you back like 10 or 12 different Andy
five text files like a true what the
hell's going on whether I gotta call an
incident
call incident determination I told you
made that up probably a private find
that thing anywhere pry not result in a
search by zyce trying to figure out is
this shit real or not these little batch
files work man I put him on a network
share somewhere in let people run it
might have been the most friends of the
sound in the world but I did have MDN 5
in Dolton to its like you know I was
building a little das Norton Commander
many at one point on it just get the
event logs or don't get the event log
that's a lot more time to take some time
but i wanna know what the hell's going
on within about 15 minutes right so
again
bats + utilities our speaker mount slide
by the way so our show on WIC is always
local and again if you look in Proc mind
when you're running your utilities
Sysinternals are awesome by the way
totally I used the shit outta
Sysinternals anyone window systems and
abusing a lot but look in Prague and
you'll see that it does make all the
stuff on the system I don't know what
that would mean if you had a root canal
in all cases take the time to really
enumerate all that out my nice to just
do shit outright a batch file for
something that I needed to get based on
OS now but call the other batch files
from within that won him the basic
response is that all the routing tables
netstat ano Natsu A&B all that kind of
stuff and for those you so in Windows
they're cool command netstat -a and be
active network connections but it tells
you the buyer like Outlook Dec see what
exact words using the Indies to have a
staff report from found stone back in
the day or other utilities see seaports
to get that info I can get it from the
OS by the way that's also good for when
people don't know when you're trying to
firewall stuff we don't know what parts
are abuses UNIX Windows netstat Ashby
just do the be given that list out to
figure out these ports were right
admin tools help with forensics and vice
versa
and why do you want to customize the
scripts versus just download what's on
the internet was obviously it's
different AV Solutions right there logs
different place for servers web logs URL
scan logs detail this light as holy shit
wow that's an oldie add-on for Microsoft
Internet Information Server what was it
6 the last time I think that was used
how know it's been too long I can
mention volatility really cool right you
can either on dumping a tool called
memorized or you can use a search for
you know something to dump live memory
you can use DVD as well but many run
volatility and it actually gives you
stuff like that staff and look if you do
not stay on your computer and that stat
that a no show you your active network
connections try to figure out what the
hell you're things talking to and where
else can go and stuff we get a lot of
that pulled out of the memory of a
system now that's just a listing of some
of commands so again to reiterate the
point if you're using a tool for the
first time in response be where do you
have a lot of fun something I'm into now
what about environments where you're
doing desktop virtualization where the
images dissolvable hell of a business
case for this saves on licensing and
stuff so it's probably gonna happen in
some environments they gonna be getting
your choice whether or not it should
happen right what do you do in as we
move to cloud that kinda gets in here as
well but a Citrix environment got
NetScaler devices that can actually look
inside and see who's doing what in the
sessions as far as how long session
duration of what applications are coming
off what server for disc forensics
agents are kind of a no go right it'd be
hard to snap a memory image for
volatility officer the head terabytes of
RAM that all these sessions again serve
what can you get what's good enough as
we get with a charger legal when you get
your plan together what's due diligence
you know dis forensics gets a little
tough you can snap to VMDK is that the
stops running on talking on persistent
images not persistent images persistent
images without their VMDK is bau right
stuff business as usual stuff like that
folders during a remap folders for their
profiles as well as their files now you
got two sets of folders are gonna wanna
look at from a friend that standpoint
that might be worried the old trick the
absence of an artifact is itself an
artifact
or vice versa if they had their old
terminal server keys are all empty it
means the admin cleared out where they
were going to if you look at the
registry can see where people town it to
your party to or RDP to where the hell
is that going to solve the environment
you'll be in the config files that get
written up to their profile directory
make sure that start figure now hired
into forensics in that environment to
figure out what someone did when they
were connected into the dissolvable
thing you're not going to get everything
he used to figure out what you are going
to get I'm actually working on this live
now that's why there's this much thought
put into it cuz I'm actually running
into this scenario and it's a bitch so
you're going to depend on your proxy as
always
DLP and environment virtualization is
going to change your cat categorization
they're all gonna look like they're
removable drive events have to alter
some process their families normal anti
virus seems to work in these
environments they've made it so it'll
work pretty well and you get the logging
from it you can still get value from
antivirus even know whats pattern-based
and therefore supposedly completely told
me that just like firewalls even though
they work great for segmentation write
an instant response you think a
segmentation and slightly different way
segmentation think of it like a
submarine turn off valve so that room
doesn't floods of the ship doesn't think
so I'm actually at my house read on that
way when I do the plumbing second turn
off one room inside the entire freakin
house right
a memory problem with one saying I
should be able to turn off one room that
room but anyway
segmentation they're also for that yeah
that making those kinds of boundaries
that's why they're not dead
ideas didn't die like everyone said it
was going to either just rolls they
should be aware of the classics helix
fire Cali sand sift rednecks for reverse
engineering I just put these out there
if this is news to you you want to get
it so this is not news to you you want
to be familiar with this kind of stuff
and what it does and you can use the
hell outta sands and RAM next 44
response tough just put some links to
rootkit detector people ask again disk
imaging you can get hard hardware
imagers if you're doing enough imaging
you might have the money for my justify
the expense for you just plug the hard
driving for one year
workstations and an image it real quick
I'll just put a thing for network
security only not to forget you don't
network type forensics security onion is
awesome very worth the time to learn
again Sysinternals is pretty standard
thing I put links to these books hackers
towns anyone heard of these books three
books full of real-world scenarios I
can't believe they wrote these are
awesome they give you the evidence walk
you through how they found it but then
you get to solve it and they have the
answers in the back of the book the
stuffs kickass you talk about great free
training and they're tough I felt stupid
somebody's have made me feel really
stupid some of the scenarios I made it
through all three books right but what
I've done in these books some of it made
me feel humbled in a good way holy shit
it's the real world stuff in the back
and in Europe working through files
tracing through what happened it's kind
of cool right I always like to give
references to books some of the stuff
sands courses I had a hacker sand SEC
level four course was good but I was put
in the latest version of the books are
some of the older versions and mentally
having read the newest version but this
is the newest version of that book I'm
going to blast through something fairly
quickly I like to put bonus material at
the end and I've got the time for right
now
operationalizing InfoSec this applies to
everything I've already talked about
half the stuff to you somehow that's why
put these lies in as a reminder you're
trying to provide a service think of
your incident response like anything
else you do like your intrusion
detection service like your
vulnerability management service for the
company you're building and operating a
service you need to get as mature as you
can I took this right off Wikipedia
initial repeatable define managed
optimizing their ego
what the hell does that mean even
there's an idea for a log management for
you this is my free to take back you can
take these slides and change in four
different tools you have in your
environment in general
how do you tell what's mature and what's
not how do you tell if your tools that
optimize your process just a way to get
you thinking about it from a maturity
perspective right basically looking for
integration automation documentation
standardization can you repeat the stuff
over and over
right operationalization who can do your
imaging you gotta see our field techs
can take a proper forensic image for you
in a big enough organization you might
want to write that's how to build and
here's the other one people process
technology you cannot talk your way
around this if you think your just gonna
buy tools and run tools to secure your
company or your environment we're going
beyond its a response here to security
in general that is probably the industry
everyone's right here if you skip these
two don't even bother with the third
time I can take the third whether it's
open source home-grown some are better
than others some require more automation
more work to automate than others but
the reality is what the hell you trying
to do you need the people to do it right
need to know what you're trying to do
that's the process a process by the
processes you know your scope purpose
and intent of things right so again
processes are flowcharts and bullet
points procedures are just a shit ton of
screen prints with bullet points we've
already covered this one
installing a product overseas
implementing right anybody can install a
product and this is just an example for
process documentation when I mean by
could be a little section of a bigger
doc sometimes you have a separate doctor
some of these things what's the roles
responsibilities how to handle the tools
naming conventions for forensics tools
to have a naming convention have a
different incident number for each one
does that reflect in the file structure
using two-story residence right what's
the architecture gotta think about where
you gonna how was all your stuff just
have Dr locked in a cabinet that the
building burns your daughter doing now
and then moving to backup tape and then
have the backup tape they come outside
like an Iron Mountain unlock the bug you
unlock the box put the tapes and they go
off site that's party architecture right
how do you maintain your products how
often do you update your friends experts
solution stuff like that and again when
there's racy models talk to the people
here to make a racy model with you can't
talk about how teams are going to work
together not have all the teams are
going to expect
to work together in the same room and
again you're offering a service here
some of the solutions you some people
look at solutions Morris tools based
services more as process-based
whichever works best for you are you can
combine the two
this book will get you into branding I
think we read enough technical books we
need to read some non technical books to
get you into being conscious of how to
build your brand and maybe build your
team's brand my favorite pet peeve again
this gets you a quick intro as with
always I'm not saying everything and
every book is correct the redbook think
I should be required
think people should be allowed to be an
InfoSec if they don't read the redbook
my own personal opinion cuz it gets you
think about structuring having your shit
together it's a little bit too detailed
your priority dial it down a notch but
it is only like that fake right and then
the Phoenix project is a story that
kinda introduces concepts and a box and
stuff it's an idealistic story but a
great way to get some of the points
across and then I will have this posted
Monday sites.google.com / site / dep
millroy
my dogs security people get some good
shit out of this good ideas good stuff
my goal that is this is like an hour
hope you have to stop you can take back
to your work look at things differently
help you enhance what you're currently
doing so I appreciate your time and if
those questions if not you know I'm here
for a while he can catch me on Halloween
ask me stuff to download is gonna be at
sites.google.com / site / dep millroy
I'll have it up there Monday I'll put it
up when I get back in it back home to
get back in town give you the power
points you can edit the stuff that we
can just take it and use it
a recommendation for is it incident
versus not incidents starting point
first I try to figure out if its a human
doing something versus an automated
script when I try to figure out if there
is data exfiltration attempts are not
right off the bat of something really
bad otherwise it's just a nuisance to me
thanks