defended to citing know as my buddy Tom
Richards and he's gonna talk about some
stuff some software security in the real
world so I'm giving up for Tom thank you
good morning everyone thanks for comin
bright and early to my talk I really
appreciate this is like one of the best
crowds I've ever had here which can go
with you go either way we'll stay too at
the con right ten o'clock if anyone went
out there still sleeping
and you know Chris Polk yesterday so
it's whatever it probably came for a
rape he did you have a good he know I
don't show up until yesterday night so I
mister fortunately but thanks for coming
out to my talk I really appreciate it
quick run of the crowd who here is a
consumer security services have penned
testers comment has to go through
reports and figure out that who here is
a practitioner in the security field
actually doing the pen testing and all
the fans of great pretty good mix
perfect that's what I was hoping for in
this talk I've been given the talk to
students for the past two years so is a
first talk in front of actual people so
we'll see how this goes against my name
is Tom Richards I am a senior security
consultant whistle we are a software
security firm based around the USA and
internationally
that's why Twitter account if you want
to follow me at school sometimes a tweet
sometimes they don't
I presented previously for I think this
is my third or fourth year here probably
the third speaking time here it's great
I love this conference I'm so glad to be
back I have also presented at Carolina
con Derby Conn and also be sized San
Francisco in various topics I'm an
organizer for besides rocky had these
sides
great congress's it have a b-side
locally to you definitely go to it
they're fantastic also a member for a
local 2200 this talk hopefully read my
description I'm gonna talk about some of
the things I've run into in the field
and what it means to do software
security and a consultant and I'm also
gonna give you guys some pointers when
you're looking at vendors and sort of
the other side of the table right when
you're going through this this life
cycle so the projects I have worked on
in my three years as usual have been
staff augmentation and a large financial
firm
where I was helping them in 2013 they
finally realize that they want to do
mobile so we were helping them securely
develop their mobile banking application
also their employee initiatives for BYOD
they were a large firm traditionally
blackberry there's anyone have to manage
mobile devices out there and have
everyone go I want my my Apple Android
to get email so that's what they were
facing people coming in with those
requests and they had some very
important information on there so I'll
talk about that later
bullpen testing traditional mobile
assessments web app assessments network
assessment you know traditional pen
testing sort of things that I've been
going through I also do quite a bit of
red teaming actually I'm leaving Sunday
to go break into a building in LA so yes
it's a lot of fun I get to do a lot of
fun stuff here in now with my more
senior position I do scoping calls in
helping out with the clients so if
you're on the consumer consumable side
of security when you get on the phone
with a vendor and go hey here's what we
want I'm usually the person on the other
end the phone going ok here's what we
have not sales I'm I'm after-sales
construe the sales process we figure out
how much you gonna charge you for this
that's when it gets to me so make sure
we understand your need and also make
sure our services are going to meet your
expectations so I'm doing that side of
the house now too and that's some pretty
interesting stuff to talk to clients
about that I've always viewed security
as the second level in industry right
coatings hard right writing software is
typical computers are hard
designing things as hard insecurity
is really hard right when you're going
through this tough as a consultant I
need to know as much or more than your
developers I need to know as much or
more even of your own system then your
system architects system engineers and
support staff this when I'm shy Indian
issues that relate to the security side
of your business I need to be able to
explain those and confident and
knowledgeable terms so that you
understand us you're not going to have a
vendor that is gonna sit there and go
all blah blah blah that's an issue
because it we say it's an issue you have
to have facts you have to defend why
it's an issue so we need to understand
that so why even tell kids I know
college students looking to get
insecurity I tell them do one or two
years maybe yeah what about one or two
years in industry in whatever you are
doing
network support system support or
developing as you want to go straight
into security you're gonna have a huge
curve you're gonna have to get over just
21 understand how companies work I've
had people work with me who had never
worked in an office before and we had to
go on a client site so if things we
might take for granted like office
etiquette and just interacting with
people in office where the break room is
and what's typically in the breakroom
these kids have no idea so I strongly
encourage if anyone is one person so one
person's gonna have benefit out of this
DNA industry for a little bit if you're
going into security before you do it
right down the long run
I have a really crappy
know if there's a from these he is the
CISO at somewhere I forget where he has
this is from one of his tweets and it
really brings to the front what software
security is then what we're talking
about my software security the network
layer is taken care of right we got that
padlock in the corner were good at SSL
were fine but this is where the software
security turns in you put a negative
number in your quantity
now the shopping cart owes you money
right this is the perfect example of
what software security is the network
layer is taking care of we got our
secure communications but the apt is
broken like I was saying I was at the
bank
a large financial investment firm
helping them design their mobile
application and that was really
interesting because you had to explain
to this bank what a secure mobile
application looks like what does that
mean what both Android and iOS because
that's the two popular ones you know
what what would that be you know what
things are we concerned about both on
the client side which you know you can't
trust a client at all and also on the
back end and that's where all the juicy
stuff was and that's what the line is
here with the devs they thought that its
mobile only the mobile phone as well
talk to our back-end web services like
no do you put a published web service
out there on the internet and the thing
is going to talk to it you have a
restful service fantastic but you need
to secure that system and that's why
he's into my next line was mobile
pushing security of accident I Indies
it's gotten better more lately but when
will was first coming out in 2010 2011
people were pushing his outset when
Android and iOS four really taking off
developers we're forgetting all the web
security stuff that they had been doing
for the past 20 years and we were
finding simple dumb things that they
were building into their backend systems
assuming that the only thing talking to
their backend was going to be the the
mobile device they still can't hit from
a web browser or through burp or
anything so we we told them they had to
fix a great cause you can't trust and
some decline you have to validate what
comes in and we built a pretty robust
system for them to to use BYOD this is
one of the worst ideas anyone's overhead
quite honestly I don't have to deal with
BYOD but it is just a pain yeah so you
know this investment firm deals with
very sensitive information they deal
with mergers IPOs
people acquiring other companies and
stocks that are coming out so very
critical information to have gone on
their and their staff are requesting to
use iOS and Android now for business
purposes and we're deal is really
sensitive information where email and
email on someone's device could
literally either make someone a couple
million dollars or lose someone that
millions of dollars so poking the bear
our iOS and Android as secure as
blackberry when looking at that sort of
data it is
any kind either a pro work on procon in
my opinion it's not there's no way the
security controls that are available in
iOS and Android re years behind a
blackberry could do when it comes to
securing data on the device securing
communication between the device and the
backend server and just
the attack surface of the platform there
is no root exploit for blackberry now
they're coming out with an Android phone
in a couple months it was just announced
so that's going to change things in
vietnam be interesting but the
BlackBerry OS there is no root exploit
there is no root you cannot get root
access you can get real iOS and Android
every time there is a version right you
can do it I wasn't and read our consumer
devices adapted to the business world
Samsung has done quite a bit with Knox
and safe to produce some blackberry like
API is available for businesses to
manage but not every MDM vendor supports
everything that stayed put out there
that Samsung put out there so in my
opinion oh and we had to they had
classification levels for what was
sensitive data what was not and if your
email was too sensitive you are not
getting iOS because they could not
properly secure it in a way they would
secure blackberry in the government
looks the same thing to write government
still primarily uses blackberry when you
start to get into the design stuff right
Obama's out walk around with an injury
he has a blackberry so that's my two
cents and welcoming anyone talk about
that after the park are moving on simple
mobile at Penn testing sometimes you
know apps are are pretty good
other times they're just complete
garbage this one this example those who
are a fast food
vendor of beverages I I see some cups
from them in the room so we'll have them
nameless they split their code per
region so they started doing their
mobile development here in the states
and then for each localized region
basically each language you know Europe
was its own app or whatever they fork
the code for them to be able to develop
services in futures natively this one I
had to stop after two hours of testing
because literally just looking at the
application I had to stop at 29 find it
ridiculous that's an incredibly high in
number of findings within only a few
hours of testing they clearly didn't
smoke or do anything it was tough on
disk stuff going in the log file
passwords be inspected the logfile in
plain text and everyone knows on Android
any other app can actually requests the
the logfile to read so that's just
asking for trouble and SSL issues oh man
everyone sucks it to it as a so pls i
should say as a cell's dead we can't say
any more salty less every assessment
every assessment we find a cell issues I
did find her plain ones after it was
published which was pretty cool out in a
red team engagement against a law firm
and their the Kashi X externally exposed
McAfee's server was vulnerable to
harpley so we were not only not only
able to pull down the private key of the
server which you can you know it's true
that there to do that with are pleased
we were able to pull down their
corporate AZ policy we knew what apps
they were excluding
from being scanned and we knew what
directories they were also excluded from
being scared so we were able to directly
target our attacks to basically go after
office because the baby was not scaring
office so the first two we don't find as
much anymore
poodle we're still fighting s overs in
30 mins appreciate a fifteen years ago
turn it off invalid search that's a
pretty big 10 people have stuff that's
already expired out there or South
signed out there in weak ciphers
supported that that happens quite a bit
in a low little bit string cipher suites
it's just a second week and fixings very
easy to upgrade the software web app
testing you know it's one of the mill
when we get out there we're still
finding things that we found since the
nineties and early 2000 still injection
flaws we do find authentication
authorization issues here there there's
maybe a couple things on the top ten
specific loans and I haven't found the
request of testing but it's just you
know other people have here in there
right
larger companies have their act together
you know the banks to large ISPs they
really have their act together when it
comes to this so when we do QA testing
sometimes we don't find a lot of
interesting things sometimes we do just
one Development Group test isn't doing
stuff up to the corporate security
policy right cause these companies will
have development standards for
developers to use to have guidelines on
what to do and what not to do to make
sure their code isn't totally broken so
you know we find stuff when it gets to
us injection code level issues it's
someone's missing something smaller
companies tetramerous you know we had a
client come to us because their client
said that we had they had software
security issues so they need to get
tested and they recommended us so we
went through and did it
APIs just thoroughly broken you know
full sequel injection I dumped the whole
user database it was it's one of those
things where it's so broken you're
trying to figure out if you're going to
have enough time to finish the report
did something happen no ok you know
those those are still finding fun things
right where it exciting have a lot of
highs and you know you feel good about
yourself going through the report again
we broke this app smaller firms
definitely need like more help they
don't have the structure that larger
firms have to even have coding standards
or really know what a secure secure code
looks like when they're going through
I'm a client of this painting when a
client of this bank in one recognizes no
they do ok so I was given a username and
then also a token to sign in a
two-factor token right and that's the
primary method of signing in to the bank
is using your username and this to thank
her token which is pin and a randomly
generated number eight so it's fantastic
but you also have a password
could be instances where you're a dot
able to sign in with your token certain
functions of the app were disabled when
you did password off because they were
unable to really prove its you right you
don't have the token gesture password
could be anyone noticed tokens kind of
the same way but then this pops up when
you ask for your password right so they
didn't ask for me to just put my
password in they asked for the first the
second toe first six and second-to-last
password what does that indicate it's
encrypted yes they're not hashed
or plain text right to know it's
actually a versatile increase abacus
harassment that's awful so they were
story in the passwords in reversible
encryption and this is another large
bank doing this well it also changes
each time so it doesn't ask for the
first six and second elastic could be
like the second death and like the 7th
or whatever last night you said they're
going what the hell to first when you
pull up notepad or WordPad you write
down your password then go okay first
good yeah this is we said they were
store in the end reversible encryption
and only their backend servers can talk
to it so that's that's a positive
doin architecture was pretty interesting
to we had to do something for some
mobile apps to sign their system and
when it came to guidance for a secure
client side right that's pretty common
injury to Google publishes stuff Apple
publishes stuff that's pretty well
documented how to write a six sure
Android or iOS application things to
avoid things to include do when you're
going through the code it's the back and
that no one has a template for to figure
out that is secure and not and what does
that mean to make sure your back and
insecure validation authorization all
those issues are going to pop up in the
security line for this one yet so far
this one we reviewed they did have the
API said it was a RESTful API and this
client is a rewards application for fuel
ok so you buying gas so as you buy gas
it gives you were worried points to use
at other retailers or other nations to
save a couple sense offer to pump right
I was on the phone with this client
before they they get in and the security
group that brought us and was not you
know the developers right so we got on
the phone with developers in the
developer lee and this lady just says
straight out to us I only care about PCI
ok but there's no other things to worry
about here other than just PCI you know
there's you know these kinds of issues
in this is a testing for their going to
the conversation she was like whoa wait
wait wait is that a PCI issue or is that
a normal security issue
you and I was like you know that's
normal security issues like I don't care
the only thing this lady was concerned
about with the developers is to make
sure that your credit card number is not
stored in plain text for use in
plaintext transmission that was her only
concerned everything else be damned dump
everyone's information to screw
authorization just have a whole bunch of
fun as long as a credit card number is
an exposed you know we were good which
that's kind of silly you know when you
look at looking back at appreciate it
happened with the health care companies
you know and I get that email from
anthem and they go you know we got
preached yet all this information got
stolen but the good news is that your
credit card number was a compromise has
the story that I different server that
will fantastic the one thing I can
change overnight was the thing that was
installed in right so now my you know
four-year-old six-year-old
three-year-old in one year old kid has a
credit card numbers stolen which is
fantastic and thank you for the free one
year of credit monitoring for my one
year old kid that's really going to help
them when they're 18 and the people who
now have all their information
start opening up credit cards in their
accounts fantastic thank you anthem and
brand so indication they did have this
is back to the rewards application they
did requests you know then it have some
00 off like saying here they told us it
wasn't true awesome how random is in
there like it's random and we said ok
that's random user name password right
and the POST request so there was this
is the body so you have the body so they
were imposed you know putting get
quarries gets rings in which is good you
got back this information account number
was actually sequential across the
entire system this member I D was
interesting because that's what the user
would actually use a set of their
account number of your account number
was just how they kept track you on the
back and the member I D was how you
would also indicate at the pump if you
don't have your card to get your words
and the funding was is that member I D
was your phone number
blustery other digits so that was data
is a plus right decibel a things just
type in the pumps failed to get rewarded
but okay that was their system said it
was bad and then you would get back this
access token so separate from the header
access token which grants you access to
talk to the API's the access token was
supposed to be unique and highly secure
per session per user
right that's that's the goal they're
right so no one can take your token and
try to make calls on another user in
some method but then they do this so
this was a transaction history right
a member so you have what you're looking
for is this is public in business public
knowledge right up until here is public
knowledge by just looking at the traffic
of the application account number which
I already said with sequential that's
even more fantastic brute force this in
the only bits of information it needed
was the transaction number eighty I
access token and a start and end date
you could go through and enumerate every
person's transaction number
Christie were into passing the member
access token which is that token that's
supposed to prove that its you for that
session and tie it back to the account
number to make sure that access token
was actually supposed to talk to that
account number they were in doing it and
they also were in doing it for the set
preferences I could change things on
other people's accounts going through
because I could just enumerate account
numbers and change the preferences that
preference eighties I didn't get into
too much to know what it was like email
alerts and
some contact information nothing too
dangerous but still pretty juicy that
you could easily messed up a few
people's days by doing that and they
were not requesting the member access
tokens to that report was like copy and
paste implement proper authorization
authentication checks on you 'cause make
sure using actual token for each call
that was that was fine they the security
group liked it
the TCI lady did not like what all these
high findings for but an independent
este did implement all this stuff so
that's that's always fantastic goals in
the wild before I got professional
insecurity I was pulling down apps from
SourceForge get home anywhere I could
find web apps and just running free
scares out and seeing what would break
and this is only a snippet of the stuff
that I found in cross site scripting is
actually very difficult to fix as
opposed to a normal injection flawed
lexical injection legal injection you
just do privatize queries make sure you
don't mess up to parameterize query in a
good cross site scripting you have to do
input validation output encoding you
know there's more steps out there in
this was almost every app I look like
you know see we're going back to 2011 is
what I was getting a series of Science
in there were public instances of this
family connections at web calendar
you know on the internet I found it
wasn't as people were internally there
were public instances of the stuff that
they were trying to fix what they I
don't think they actually fixed because
the people stop developing this stuff
but that's that's dangerous writes a
pull-down open source code they're like
oh I need I wanna Booking Calendar
I want people to be able to submit
requests to book a room resources out
there and there's issues in it so code
has issues
everywhere open-source you know
commercially driven software it's all
their methods
going through these sorts of assessments
tends to be the same whether you're
doing a web app mobile app or a network
this example we're going to focus on a
web app going through the workflow
always follows this receptor first is
discovery information gathering what
does it do what does the app with his
dad lets its business contacts how does
it work and then you wanted it what's it
supposed to do and what's it's not
supposed to do according to developers
identifying inputs that's where the app
is gonna break right wherever the user
can input something in is most likely
where the fun is going to be injection
issues authorization issues as into
these issues will all be inputs using
password for the token or the cookie
that's where that fight that's what
happens and then US and the business
launder you know what is the pay is
there money involved is your shopping
cart is it a bank can you move money
what things are you not supposed to do
when you move money cross accountants
authorization issues those are the fun
ones to play with the business logic the
first two can be automated right running
crawler on the website looking for the
inputs any automated tool can be easily
do that it's the assessing the business
logic of the application that requires a
person right we don't have a i to the
point yet that can understand whether or
not you know you're supposed to you can
put a negative number in your shopping
cart and then retrieve money back from
the bank how is the computer gonna know
that
so that's where this ends up being fun
is poking at a soft spots of the
application you know what happens if I
do this here what happens if I do this
over here what happens if the parameters
are out of order
there's a system care about that we're
doing that properly to we're doing black
box testing will end up doing is trying
to figure out how it works behind the
scenes right if I was developer how
would I designed this system if I was
looking at this what what could this be
doing on the back and I'm surprised rash
is not here
his fender here for a number of years
but how much the owner of summer hits
company has broken box right anyone here
familiar with us right arm is right
rash is a fantastic I this quote really
speaks to the hacker mindset that we're
going through and and trying to do you
know the number one trait of a sexual
harasser its ability to reason with
things one cannot directly observe right
black box testing I cannot observe what
your back and is doing most of the time
sometimes we get access to you know to
the developers and we can see what
things look like on the back and which
helps to validate or invalidate
different findings but we're poking with
something that we can see what it's
doing we're just hoping it's doing what
they wanted to do or not wanted to do as
we're going to the testing and this this
quote is what I share with a lot of
folks going through this is all we have
to be able to do as a pen tester right
to be able to reason with that box that
system the application
to figure out what it should or should
not be doing is figure out ways you can
break it ok so now we get into all the
fun stuff for the consumers of security
out there after the assessment people
complain about report writing but
obviously that is the only piece the
only output of the assessment for
consumer for the most part is to report
the only tangible piece as a consultant
I am going to give to you that you will
share with her developers share with
their system admins share with their
software engineer is a system architects
is the report the findings that we find
throughout the assessment when you're
looking for you know we're going through
the performance you wanna make sure this
property tail right you want a decent
description most things are pretty easy
we have some templates internally you
know what cross-site scripting is and
you know weak ciphers you know that
language is all pretty much standard
going through right you want to make
sure that the affected instances are
there what's the IP address what's the
parameters on what page is it there what
line of code has the issue you also want
to make sure that the vendor gives you
steps to reproduce so that you can then
go and verify if the vendors full of it
or not is this a real issue
you may also want screenshots which is
proof from the vendor that that issue
has actually existed right if there's no
screenshot in there what proof do they
have how can they say that's an issue
remediation that is a big one that is a
huge one for your developers and I would
encourage you guys to our consumers of
security when you're trying out new
vendors definitely get a sample report
from them everyone has their own we have
had ties reports for every one of our
offerings right companies should have
these things that you can look at what
their reports look like you wanna make
sure they're finding good things right
that's that's always a good thing or bad
things for you you don't want us to
fight him hit the thing that's always a
phone call Friday thing oh yeah we're
having a lot of fun that means I'm not
gonna have a lot of fun next week the
inverse relationship of security testing
but the remediation advice is really
what's important I have seen folks put
on remediation device will work with
vendor will work with developers to fix
issue what the hell is dat that's not
actionable that's horrible advice for
someone you know especially want to do
in Lake code level stuff like if we find
single injection and we know you're
using JSP Java using JSP we can give you
examples for what a proper privitize
currie looks like your vendors should do
that issue getting software security
OPSEC stuff back and there should be
actionable real contextual advice for
you guys get back to your developers and
have them fix the issues very very
important I'm gonna trade kind of
lightly here missus could go either way
depending upon your stance on this
report outcall
is personally and my least favorite part
of this I love writing the report cuz it
kinda like you know going back through
in documenting what you did you know
reliving the hacks for sure we get to
the right team stuff a curly braindump
how I stole your users passwords and how
we got into your building that's a
really fun exercise I i find to do but
the outcall the alcohol is we're not
that it's bad because we'll be
challenged by the client it's bad
because some clients have the process
where you have to have a report alcohol
and then you'll get on the call in read
through the report why why you had to
report for like a week you read it is
shared internally all your dance teams
are on it you're on the call come with a
fluid discussion I would much rather
have a fluid discussion to address your
exact points and get the call over with
not because I don't want to be on the
phone with you because our time is
valuable on those and trade I'm sucking
up an hour of your time your developers
time your lead near Leeds time and my
time and my leaves time to go through
this report and I've been a report
alcohol's where he was I read the whole
report and they said okay thank you and
hung up the phone like what is what was
the point of this you know come with
question did you have no questions don't
have the call but that's cool too I had
that some clients as well they've gone
no we understand the report we have no
questions
developers understand what they have to
do and if any issues will come back to
you guys said perfect great and I've had
other calls with clients where I get on
now that you have any questions aside I
really don't like it reads you like
you're my five-year-old kid I would
rather you know address your questions
that you have on your notepad casino to
have no training in know what issues
they're going to have with it and I'd
rather have that discussion is right up
front and get everything out of the way
you know you read the whole report and I
had a client I went through a whole
report I got 21
love finding and we don't think this is
a real find it like you don't care about
the highest the loans were you gonna
care about and he spent 15 minutes
arguing with me whether it was a real
issue or not the fix for the issue by
the way was just to update Apache so in
those 15 meant he could have just done
apt-get update and solve the issue but
no he decided to spend their time
arguing whether it was a real or not for
a low which was just a rough please
don't do that to us or do it and
challenged us at school just a low
findings but a lot of teams big
companies will have a timeline for when
issues how to effects in ohio State has
to be fixed very quickly within days or
weeks depending upon the severity of the
application and all that jazz mediums
are released within a month or so shitty
days thirty they Windows is what the
client end up doing in Lowes and that
being like the next release cycle right
so a lot of my arguments I have with
clients and if you are the consumers of
security here in probably that speaks to
you in some way you're going to argue
those highest down to a medium every
time you can write because you don't
want to have to go back and fix all
these things that we think is a high and
in some cases we will lower severity
I've done that plenty of times where it
turns out there was additional controls
on the back end that actually would
prevent a full blown issue with this
great cause we're looking for issues we
just have to prove it they exist and you
know in its low vacuum what its risk
rating could be to the application we
don't have all the insight into your app
in how the back and always works so
they'll go you know we actually have
like all these things that would prevent
that from actually happening
ok then will will lower it down to a
different story level we've done that
we've done that that will never take a
finding out of a report I had someone in
the middle of a tests found a whole
bunch of cross site scripting go back
the next day it's not they're going what
the hell happened someone was watching
what we were doing
saw that we were fighting issues and
then fixed it overnight to try and have
a good rapport luckily we screenshot
only find things so even though these
they fixed it that finding was still in
the report we market is closed right if
you and I had other instances where you
know high in critical findings are
reported a decline as soon as possible
so they can get a head start fixing
those things and then we shared the
report in there like we fix all these
things as they can we still found them
you know we're not gonna say we didn't
do any work in your app had no how no
high issues right there gonna be in
there will market is closed and put it
in his active some reason you're up
higher-ups know that we close those
things you close a thing which is good
right
find it closed it before it has even
over thats improve the good doctor allen
times but we're not gonna take it out
never think about double the points
remember when you're consuming security
services is that these are any
assessment is a point in time
review of your appt network or system
right we don't know what it was like
before we got there and we're not gonna
know what's gonna look like after we got
there and neither will you as you look
at it right are issues that we find are
found within that time within that time
period
and they only demonstrate how bad an
application is right this is Gary McGraw
our CTO famous writers block building
security here to build secure software
he calls this the badness matter right
when you have a pen test its not good or
bad it's we don't know or oh my god we
need to fix everything right
a pen test does not prove good it only
proves bad and so does SecureCode you
most you no point in time assessments
will justifying the bad things will find
some good things too I guess we could
say you have proper controls here and
there
these sorts of attacks were not possible
in the application or system which is
good to know but you don't truly know
how good the application is going to
apprentice
thank you guys for coming out ten
o'clock in the morning to hear me speak
I really appreciate it I will be around
all day so if you have questions wanna
chat
tell me I'm wrong I i love you have any
questions now I guess we got like 10
minutes or so
yeah
yeah we've had that end classic example
of that happening is when we will do
like of honorable server version so we
know that their version of Apache is
like super old are likely find I S five
ever like fix that and then they like ok
we fixed it and we go and look back and
all they did was turn off the header so
we can't really tell that it's I S five
anymore or they're vulnerable and then
end in code as well we've had on trying
to think back right leg 2012 one
instance XO will give the scripting is
also really bad with this to rate so
we'll put it in and say you know you
have JavaScript in here is the payload
that we used so they would go back in
and I went to go testament to the
crosscutting was fixed and my first
payload wasn't working as I try another
one and the other one were to busy today
blacklisted by 12 no script alert one
hundred to make sure it doesn't go
through but not actually fixing the
output issues cause I can still get you
know I can tell with the responses back
that output encoding the brackets you
know it's not your not sixteen it even
though we gave you advice
fix it but yeah it happens not i mean as
much as we want to we can write in it
for the crosscutting example we can say
no you're still vulnerable to be this
this other thing worked and oh by the
way stop black listener one line and
actually fix the code right that's we
can do that with the software version if
we can actually prove it still I asked
we we have to close it because we can't
prove it still bad even though the Apple
has acted the same and a few dresses and
I doubt they spun up a new server
overnight to deploy this you know system
odds make sure everything worked out yet
the header is the class until it turns
off the header so we can actually tell
if it's tomorrow version
yeah yeah yeah that's a loaded question
my opinion is if you're afraid of it
breaking in production your app is
really broken asia's burn it anyway if
you're afraid if you're not gonna be
your server and production dude you got
problems right time we do end up testing
UAT energy to expose environment or in
internally in a dev environment that's
where it financially makes more sense to
do testing for especially AB stuff cuz
if we're finding the issues while
developers are still right in
there's 66 out there I have included in
the slide but it is significantly
cheaper to fix software issues in
development compared to when its
thousand in production right so you know
in the report alcohol in our agreements
that you know for testing in prod you
know we're going to try not to break
stuff but stuff can get broken right its
nature testing and if the difference
between us and like
known bad guy or an unknown bad guy is
they're paying us to do it right no one
wants to pay someone to take down there
they're banking system but that
enforcing what happens I had it had
actually happened twice and the first
issue actually a framework issue is what
they were using and that will kinda cool
well for me that much for them and
sometimes i fix it just like restarting
the box right to free up the server yeah
there were some weird like crypto issue
where if you made the crypto malformed
let the blob now formed what I was
trying to process it in the back and
that end up going in the loop cuz it
then have the proper try catch to make
sure it was it was not breaking it so
abysmally sucked up all the RAM
the backend process and it's already
rebooted but yeah we we try to tread
lightly i mean it happens and sometimes
the clients like we want you to test in
prod because if you can knock this thing
over we're gonna rip developers a new
one right
the flip side to that is to be new
security testing and something goes down
how much time do I have anything goes
down the taxes get blamed right away
right for my protection practitioners
who has been blamed for stuff that you
did it actually do when it goes down we
were doing a network ten tests for a
client and they call us up at the
weather systems went down overnight and
I wasn't testing 12 testing that night
but I woke up to seven missed calls
three voicemails and 22 email from the
client trying to get ahold of me
overnight as well their systems were
down and they couldn't prove whether or
not it was me which we give him our IP's
we test from no known IDs they had the
idea testing from their systems were
down and they could improve they were
trying to get ahold of me to see if it
was us or not and the guys email was I
find this unacceptable that we can't get
ahold your testers dude it's three
o'clock at night mostly I tell you when
I'm testing and then for the same client
their internal SharePoint were doing the
external network Pentastar unnecessary
items in their internal SharePoint
server went down and the email call or
stop in the SharePoint down is it you
and we were like ok internal what's the
IP address of that public facing and
then we'll see if it was in our scans
that we ran and they were like oh oh
yeah you're right there's
I'll let people go now I'll be around
all day
wonderful thanks for all the questions
they get