my own interests here now you don't have
any idea why you're here you you won't
care and two minutes anyway alright well
as keeping this is this is not the talk
to bring your kids to you brought your
kids take kids out or you know tonya
from here on out cuz I am sure this
isn't the first talk that somebody's
going to say fuck in but it is in fact
my mission to save more than anyone else
ok so who the fuck am I am Dunkin Donuts
exchange student from Deutschland thank
you I've been in InfoSec for 15 years I
T 44 a little more than 20 and I'm sick
of all of you doing here on that's my
talk I'm going to talk about how your
bad here job and if you think I am using
online you have some homework ok so by
the way right just a PSA alright let's
get this started
damn straight it is so I've been in
information security for 15 years I just
said that
scorecard information security
raise your hand if you know what the
Triad is so much to shout out what the
triads dance for Chinese described that
was amazing
now that the well that's so much more
right that's such a bitch I that's a
better answer those guys on so many
levels ok but the information security
CIA triad rate is confidentiality
integrity and availability
sex drugs and rock and roll now that was
a derby can talk you're not a derby
and I have not been to rehab but perhaps
I should go so so these are kind of the
three promises that right we're supposed
to keep for the the organizations that
that we served at the pleasure of so
confidentiality quick check how we doing
real good like not at all so these this
is just a bar graph data lost the baby
and you know maybe last year wasn't the
worst year ever but is still fucking
look at all the bridges that a lot of
breaches that have been reported you
suspect there may be more than I do
about availability
there's optimized dee da dee da boss is
so fucking cheap now there's literally a
group out there called detox for Bitcoin
and they will stop D Dawson you for the
grand total of two Bitcoin that's how
fucking good you all are at your job
right that effectively like this is like
their lake
internet squeegee scam artists right
you're getting beat by them
how about integrity now in the stands in
the centre the CISSP and the CIA tried
and all that they're talking about your
ability to protect the integrity of data
but I think we have a different and much
bigger integrity problem within this
industry
yeah this is kind of a shitty thing fuck
these guys sorry we weren't good enough
to be man tax guess we're gonna sell too
oppressive regimes that rape torture
commit genocide that's fucking rad
Eugene Kaspersky that crazy bastard so I
but yeah unfair practices withdrawal our
own competitors actively right fake data
breaches as an extortion as business
model like this is all shit that's going
on in our industry that is so fucked up
so there anybody who wants to tell me
that they think that they're kicking
after that we're doing a good job so I
got a lot more slides to go that kick in
as you're not even employed tell me I'm
wrong
know it's I'm an asshole and I'm not
right but okay so what's the fucking
point if we're not coming through right
for not delivering what the fuck are we
doing here and and and it occurred to me
though right that I had to stop and
think about this because companies are
spending record amounts of money
talent is at an all-time high yes sure
there's a massive shortage but I can't
blame the shortage for the last round of
bullshit I just showed you right that's
too many of the wrong people in the
field in my opinion so with that being
the case why why do security sock why
are we fucking up why is this industry
so ineffective and I got to thinking and
I'm gonna tell you why let's start with
your deja so if you follow the sands
library ISO 27 K
there are 23 mandatory policies 27
optional policies to be deployed under
ISO that's fifty security policies
averaging somewhere in the forty
eight-page range your employees never
fucking read it
you read it just the once a year you
have to read it when you have to update
it so that the auditors like it tell me
I'm wrong this guy hates you I hate you
too but here's the thing it's not even
your fault right because you're forced
into this regulation in industry
standards are fucking oppressive there
are months there there are two hundred
and forty-two controls in the PCI DSS
version 3 right and everybody knows full
well that lots of those controls have
subparts in multiple tests and then you
have to scope them so they grow
exponentially the same is true high
trust which is a leading framework for
health care and then the Cloud Security
Alliance hundred 3436 controls but by
the time their scope then applied right
how many individual tests are you
running and validating and processes
that you're following and boxes that you
are checking out a lot of shit isn't
working so let's ask that question is
PCI working since 2010 there have been
eight hundred and seventy-eight publicly
reported breaches involving PII there's
a follow-up first so for those of you
wondering if that includes bhi it does
not give slides coming
the top 10 breaches of the biggest jumps
of card numbers that we know of so
that's going to be primarily in the you
s all passed their rack right there they
were all certified they were all
compliant they all followed the
framework at some point a third party
who is paid to be an expert in that
standard vetted ehman said that they
were doing a good job within 12 months
prior to their breach you're offended by
a fact go fuck yourself over there is
not okay I write it was so you wanna
argue with me about this would cause
you're right there are four brands but
they're really three companies he would
agree I'm actually counting the ship box
you just quit troll harder bitch
anyway the fact remains that right
the card brands that are enforcing and
requiring this in issuing this they've
been hacked 20 shit I think we can all
agree BC I write to pick 2010 we can go
back and see more before the spot-kick
2010 because that was the full
implementation date for all the level
ones right so it's a mess about hip-hop
you had one job keep those records
private nobody wants to know about your
valtrex prescription
well that's not true the Chinese
government clearly wants the no budget
valtrex for sure
anyway so 1183 breaches economy is
really interesting as I got this from
the Public Policy Center on privacy they
have a fantastic searchable database
that you can find out all these
humiliating tracks from so 1183 reported
breaches of pH I so here's the thing you
should know about health care if you
don't already though is that cool rules
around so that's 1100 unencrypted
laptops and backup tapes and USB drives
right like that's what that shit is
eleven hundred of them didn't have an
adversary 1100 amor just sloppy and
careless and here's the thing
that's only half of the reporting period
right because mandatory public reporting
didn't go into place until five years
after compliance was mandated by federal
law so that 1100 that you know about
thats all since 2010 but everybody was
supposed to be fully compliant by 2004
at the absolute latest by a third of the
record stolen all occurred in eighty
three of the of the attacks were there
was a natural adversaries they were
doing we got the data took it left oh
and the enforcement body health and
human services they've been run through
so bad that they actually took their
budget for 2014 external audits of
healthcare providers and payers and
pulled it back into their own security
budget to fix their own shit on one hand
that's terrifying on the other hand
kudos to them for at least recognizing
they had no fucking credibility last if
they went ahead and audited other people
will hackers are still active in all
their shit
regulation kickin ass making a
difference i watch
Regulation and Enforcement let's turn
back to you and your shitty gazillion
pages of policy at work when was the
last time you fired somebody when was
the last time you pick up the phone and
called a jar and said this person put a
sticky note with their password on a
monitor walk them out tomorrow and it
happened and how many of your policies
have ever been used to fire somebody I
know you got at least 20 you probably
got about fifty you may be one the
somebody's ever been fired for price and
that's the one about porn so maybe it's
time to recognize the policy enforcement
isn't even a thing we're doing so what
do you have those policies for other
trade the auditors my favorite thought
is that next year will come back to go
and I'll be able to troll the sky as the
president you know it's fucking scary
they really that would be a huge problem
do so but forget forget the forget the
future president let's talk about my
favorite past first lady sorry wrong one
so I actually have a point here though
I'm not trying to get political although
it's funny right now
politics is very funny right now funny
said anyway so Secretary of State
Hillary Clinton has been in the news a
whole lot lately because she hosted a
private email server where she put all
of her email and there's a good chance
that she was doing some state business
email server seems like there's some
backup tapes though I'm missing
apparently she heard people from
healthcare and well I'm just connecting
dots that's all I do so so here's the
thing though is everybody's up in arms
and I've heard a lot of people from our
industry like go on the press and talk
about how much bullshit that is and how
that's inappropriate and I want you to
stop and think about how you would feel
if you found out that a key executive in
your company was running their own email
system on the side instead of yours
right but how pissed would you be right
if this person wasn't following the
corporate standard in using the central
email system and solution
the you served up to be pretty fucking
pissed you would wish you could try that
person but you can but you can't
actually not mad at hillary I'm actually
not pissed you know why this chick how
quickly everybody forgot that an easy
one
private from the Army docs the whole
state depart- setback Foreign Relations
in some circumstances over a decade
blame somebody who's charged with highly
sensitive negotiations for whining
better control and a tighter loop around
their calm but what do you want to bet
that there's a FIPS certification for
the mail system where the communique is
the Chelsea Manning ripped off right I
mean like you get it this is military
grade compliant which for those of you
in the military that you can laugh at
school but but right like should but
that's the thing right this is this
isn't this isn'ta hey where business and
we don't want to deal with regulation
and cost effectiveness right like this
is the military nobody budgets they just
do it so at the end of the day the
standard is broken you get it so
flattered couple of the cows I'd love to
take credit for this by the way I don't
know like if anybody else is old enough
to actually read basic or too stupid to
teach yourself in the next five minutes
let me explain these go in order and go
to means go to that line number so
here's the thing about vulnerability
management I'm not going to tell you
that in the real world bad guys aren't
using exploits to pop systems and really
do really damaging shit but you you have
a failed premise here this is a lot of
time and a lot of energy and a lot of
work spent on trying to make this
perfect right and PCI forces a lot of
this but but Ivory industries got this
great so we're slamming in patches where
we're scanning all the things which
means we're probably not going over a
few of the things right the whole group
of people dedicated to make something
like this happen but they only know what
they know whether I should say they only
know the vendors know right so so an
interesting thing happened by the way
the MJR in the bottom there is my
favorite Security Commission in the
world Marcus Ranum and this is right out
of a paper of his entitled The the top
six stupidest security ideas there is a
chapter on vulnerability management
right penetrating patches is
fundamentally broken because straight-up
penetrate is not what the attackers to
rate if you patched everything they just
choose a new avenue oh and just because
you deployed all the patches who thinks
that their entire external facing
infrastructure right now fully patched
has 0 vulnerabilities you're retarded
in fact I'm sorry too retarded people so
funny things that happened over the last
year you've got you got packing team got
the text and then there was also some
some news about it was it was discovered
that after after a particular o'day I
think it was heart bleed came out was
made public that that the PLA right that
the chinese hackers whoever the hell
they are you get to the boogie man
syndrome later but they were co-opting
these exploits very quickly in turning
around and using them really really
quickly or it could just be the fact
that now you notify can look for and now
you see it right that's really by and
large that's what's happening in the
hacking chained up they paid thirty
grand for a couple of a couple of flash
exploits that would work very well and
phishing campaign or watering hole
attack right now anybody who's really
good at that
better lately that's my point great
you'd already sold this to a lot of
places and it's not like his research
wasn't recreate Apple so you already
know that there were other adversaries
by looking at hacking team we get a
chance to finally see yes this day we
went public when they got docs and all
of a sudden we started seeing exploits
but at the same time it's also right
there in the dump the day bought it from
a guy who didn't give him an exclusive
on it to everybody that drew the
conclusion that China quickly co-opted
that is in China bought it actually
probably founded by the way I love your
monthly publication UPenn testers deal
he had that thing I got like 12 more of
them but they couldn't read on the slide
i just i just pick the ones he probably
is he has a shitty job so user awareness
training right because hey if we can't
patch the servers let patch the bball
Bell ok so but has any of you ever said
there's no patch for stupid and they
hear users are the weak link I expected
way more hands the rest of you you
should be ashamed for feeling that way
not the cheer on necessarily but i wanna
talk about something when it comes to
security awareness training caused this
is my new favorite piece of bullshit so
mathematically speaking security
awareness training is never going to
work right what's what's a passing grade
right like 90% is like a really good
grade right what if you got 99% of the
people in your company to be so good at
spotting fishing that they never click
the link you got one percent your
company that's a foothold every time
that's right so admittedly something's
better than nothing but your fucking
that up to we're going to play a little
game called spot the fish is this a fish
or is this something that your corporate
company security awareness training
program would have sent you the headers
users don't get to see headers you can't
train them
sorry maybe you should write better
detection and prevention so how about
this one had two black this one out a
little so that might give you an idea is
this a real fish so so which ones the
fishing line is that the first one or
the second one of your wrong the answer
is neither the first one is a bullshit
training exercise in the second one is
an email sent by a vendor hired by that
company that requires mandatory
inclusion by employees your training
people did not do something that turning
around and making them do that thing
where to go I T department that's
fucking brilliant so why isn't this
working because we're stupid
this is for
follow me on Twitter for the last point
I want to make the thing I want to get
to
is as much fun as it is to laugh at
other people's misfortune this has a
huge negative effect on our industry and
our ability to be effective
gonna spend the rest of the talk talking
about this because ultimately this is
the problem we are blaming people that
are broken into by hackers and had their
day to stall right and I get that
there's two sets of victims right if
your data is ever stolen if you were one
of the people I'm fortunate enough to
come to learn that the Chinese
intelligence service now has your
military record that's a victim but so
is a p.m. right they were broken into
they have done more potentially possibly
if they weren't you know too busy with
other things
that we force on them
but so here's the thing you have to
understand everybody's been popped or
will be popped great stop and think
about the vertical the industry that you
work in right now think about who you
know is due date got the best they're
good but we learn from them every time
we hang out with them I would like to
work there
r right org and you are vertical they've
been hacked and you know it like you can
probably Google the article that talks
about their breach cause that's how it
is
work you know South America which by the
way so long as flight so but that's the
thing there are no sacred cows
and every breach has the same root cause
what do I mean by this right because you
know if you study these things closer
look now that was a phishing attack that
was that was a lost laptop that was you
know they used heart bleed right sequel
injection right so but that's not the
root cause the root causes the same
thing every time the root cause is that
all of the security resources that they
had available to them we're looking at
the wrong thing right they were focused
on the wrong stuff and whose fault is
that
laugh it up at you
so I wanna spend a little time thinking
about this why are we blaming victim
organizations for getting popped why is
this thing why is there so much press
about this why why does everybody in
this room know who Brian Krebs as you
know and and and he's hardly the worst
he's probably the best in our field at
reporting the terrible things that
happen right but his readership is
because this is salacious and it's
interesting so why does the public love
the data breach the public loves data
breaches one cos hackers are amazing
no but really I mean by and large right
technology even though everybody has it
is still magic to a lot of people
especially outside of our industry right
I just downloaded the whole movie to the
little box in my pocket I'm gonna watch
it on the plane that magic now if people
knew the fog and leg baling wire duct
tape that was required to make those
servers like stay up and and be
functional and provide that service like
they had any idea what the backend
infrastructure look like they may be
horrified but but it's magic in my hand
but the other part of it right as the
actors aren't tangible right i cant too
so if somebody walks into a bank and
robs a bank what we get we get camera
footage somebody looks like me right and
you can say to yourself a look at those
jeans and and maybe he's got like a
ruptured at me like I'm in bed
upbringing I could probably get on
Google Maps right now look at that bank
and figure out you know maybe which
apartment building a trailer park that
dudes running back to like we all feel
like we might be able to solve that
crime because we've seen the guy and you
know that if I saw that guy come into a
bank I would do something
me too I believe hackers are tangible
man the fuckin ghost right I can't you
know we have all sorts of means but for
real right like what are hackers right I
like lava hoodie
latex gloves typing on the keyboard so
so that part of it right there an
interesting story in the reason that we
blame the companies that were broken
into his because we don't feel like
there's anybody to point that great I
can't explain to my mom that an army
unit in China just told her information
right leg and it wasn't really an army
it is really a contractor and the way we
do this shit to you know but that
doesn't register but she can be really
really mad at the company that lost her
data as they should have protected it
that her but the reason we do it is even
worse
reason we do it is we're lying to
ourselves
we want to focus on what they did wrong
what they missed what they should have
been doing better so that we can
convince ourselves that we can be good
enough that it won't happen to us we're
focused on the how they did it
we're focused on the mistakes were
focused on trying to grab some last
little shitty bitter hope that maybe if
we do all the things that won't happen
to us so we blame the victims because we
have to because what's the next thing
like a winner when a story breaks on
Friday afternoon what's the email
waiting for you on Monday afternoon so
you know the words right hey I saw this
story could it happen
so you have to run around you are
required to run around and figure out
what the fuck went wrong over there and
figure out whether or not those same
issues apply to your network as I
promise you this because I've done this
when you just send them back an email
that says yes . send they show up at
your office your CIO don't think that's
funny that's not
the answer he's paying you for but it is
the right answer the right answer is it
absolutely could happen to us because
the attackers don't need that one
vulnerability or that one stupid
operational mistake that one thing that
made its way to the papers which by the
way was probably wrong anyway right
journal like for real I have no faith in
anything I see on TV or the news anymore
just room having worked in security so
long that now that we're in the
headlines man they really fucked that
story up
looking up other stories to they are
never goes so here's the thing though is
a really want to talk about what the
solution is what I got a lot of shit
last year for late just leaving on a
bummer no but sorry man it's a bummer
when I'm gonna try and make this not so
not so fucking terrible so shaming does
a couple of things that really enable
some of the words and prevent some of
the best that the industry is capable of
providing shaming justifies litigation
and conceals data you've ever been
involved in a data breach you know that
the only thing there are more than I T
people and consultants in the room is
lawyers and so everything's a secret
because we don't want to get to tour
because we know we're gonna get suit so
we're gonna get sued and we don't want
to share anything they gotta figure it
all out they've got to discover all of
it and we are clearing no one because
what if it got out he answered a
question about what if it got out the
thing is that the mistakes aren't as
important anyway as it is the
information about the attackers the
tools the tactics what did they do so
how helpful is it for me as a security
person to hear that your company up
because you had something that was
vulnerable to hurt lead sitting on your
network and that's how they got in that
useful to me
no not really but what if I knew what
kind of day today we're after what sort
of tools they were using where their
infrastructure from there bob was what
the phishing email looked like what the
address was right what if I had all that
information what if everybody had all
that information what if the attacker
had to burn it all every time all of a
sudden we're going to price some people
out of the game but thats
did they don't have to
right so we've been watching kind of the
the the year of the healthcare data
breach unfold and then lead in 20 p.m.
season and I'm sure we're not done
somebody else is next
we'll talk about them in a minute
but not to shame them because that would
make me a hypocrite and I'm a piece of
shit but I'm not a hypocrite some
interesting is that right so why did we
have why do we have the seasonality
right cause the same thing happen to
retail two years ago right it was just
like one after another because the first
case breaks and now somebody knows what
to look for and they go looking and they
find it everywhere right but what if
everybody had that information as soon
as it happened what if they had to start
over time they don't it's cheap it's
easy and that's our fault that's on us
right who also supposed to do this I'm
pretty sure security is in your job
title
sharing is caring so something happened
the other day as Gurgaon was was getting
started and that is the Dow Jones media
and also Rupert Murdoch and his company
whatever they're called I forget anyway
thank you for the rest of your going I
don't know either
so they've been compromised going back
to 2012 huge infiltration potentially
looking at sources right but so that's
been part of the statement so they they
issued a letter
admittedly right this is like three
years of breach its not the best this is
kind of bad news but they came out with
a public statement but then you've got
the CEOs of both of these companies also
going on the press yesterday telling
people yeah we're pretty sure that this
is widespread other people need to be
looking for this information and we're
willing to tell you more about it if
you're in our sector and you reach out
to us privately budget that's amazing
a CEO it's weird that a CEO had to go on
the news and say this is this is
impacting other people this is not just
us these people were after a lot of
information from a lot of different
sources and we have a good reason to
suspect why if you might be one of them
call us and here's the thing it's not
that intelligence sharing doesn't happen
now what is what is what is threatened
tell these days it's a
second product it's a
so let's talk about that for a minute
just the second now I'm not saying that
the altar at intel has bad some of its
good some of its not but how do you know
I do know one thing I do know that
there's an actor out there that some of
you may know he likes to call me btw
three strikes to call them three
different names and that's the problem
is is that the Intel is so focused on
attribution that even their missing the
point
anybody
buying intel that disagrees that pay
that Intel's really solid he like all
those MDN 5 emailing you they're pretty
badass those are hard to change so
anyway that's my point is that until we
fix this aspect of our industry until we
get over the shame and the secrecy
around a compromise because it happened
to everyone and if you're sitting here
going hasn't happened to me but that's
going to be a bummer when you have to
come out in 2016 and talk about how you
were popped going back to 2013 yes okay
so this is our mission
moving forward if you want this industry
to stop sucking
it's time to start gearing up i mean she
came to hacker conference got drunk with
a few of these people told him
embarrassing stories may be worked on CT
Ave had some Shiite forensics challenge
shared some info
it's not hard it's fine should we go out
of our way we make vacations out of
doing this stuff so professionally as
weird as this sounds our industry needs
to move more in this direction right the
community can't just be where we go to
have a good time the community has got
to be turned on all the time and it's
got to be about working against the
adversary
compliance fuck their rules right like I
mean yeah you probably don't want to
walk into the office on Monday and open
with that I depends maybe your severance
package is better than mine
you could trigger that shit have a good
time
but realistically right like it's time
to stop pretending that there's a
framework of this asset of things that
if we just do all the perfect things
perfectly then would be perfect I will
not have any problems like 10 years ago
we could have debated about them
the validity of external attackers
trying to really do damage to companies
but I think there's no debate left the
adversary is real it's our job to defend
our organizations against them they
collaborate they sell information they
sell tools
they have a marketplace we have lots of
marketplaces so we've got to stop
claiming and stop talking and not
talking about them and not talking about
what happened to us and instead open up
as a community and begin making more
general sharing of information because
right now tell you this it is a haves
and have-nots game and there are not
very many halves in this game right now
but as I have do you know what else you
don't have you tell from all the have
nots because they don't have it but
they've been hit two so by being better
than them you're not helping them years
ago I when I was consulting i would tell
people about the you know the the joke
about the about the the the the to the
two hunters in Africa came around the
corner and there's a cheetah about ready
to pounce on the one guy grabs a parent
make your running shoes out of his
backpack and he throws and the other
guesses dude you cannot run a cheetah he
said i'm not out running it she down on
you and by customers you think that shit
was funny cuz that's it we don't have to
be perfect we have to be good enough to
let the business go on but just enough
that your harder target that someone
else and that shits not true anymore
either I actually feel bad about telling
that joke now because it turns out I was
lying I didn't know it so maybe I was
just wrong but that's the problem right
there are so many adversaries and they
are so under addressed the walls are not
high the challenge is not hard by why is
China famous for using fishing
cuz they fucking can be right leg
why because it works because we're still
using forty year old protocols and still
asking people to do stupid things on a
daily basis
a lot of work to do but it starts here
it starts with the industry has starts
with us trying to bring everybody up and
make everybody better that's really the
secret I need all of you to stop sucking
and her for me to help you not stop
sucking I have to admit I said not know
definitely do stop socket we have to
stop sucking together right because
whether I'm whether I'm actually any
better at this than you are not as
irrelevant as long as there's a problem
you guys are bad people you think I can
hear you but I i
pieces so ok you don't have to stop sake
or swat away love you too so anyway
well apparently this should I get the
fuck out