alright good morning how's everyone
doing this morning what's my name is Tom
don't want the company called sky-high
networks and basically the premise of
what I'm going to be talking about the
day is what happens when we no longer
have a network everything happens in
somebody else's data center and what do
we do about rights that's kind of cloud
access broker and that's one of the week
before I start to a little history just
to give you my background I run the
Midwest sky-high but I started back in
the early nineties one of my first
companies are on a consulting practice
and when we first start with computers
they were giant I actually worked on the
movie Independence Day it has remember
to have eighty pues as much as my laptop
that was a room of his Giants looking
graphics machines and so I live in this
whole process that we're going through
today which is back in the day the first
thing that we had to figure out why was
I have a machine and I have to control
what people do it right next we kind of
figured out maybe we should put stuff
causes viruses malware and so we started
focusing on the desktop and then this
thing the internet came out and now
things are leaving rights are not work
had ruled ball and ultimately what
happened is kind of like where we are
today as we ended up with devices that
are on our network that try to figure
out how to categorize how to figure out
what's a bad websites go to its a good
one and that's kind of what we're at
today the next-generation firewalls the
web to dot all that that's what we're
experiencing and this kind of cloud
right you know what happens this control
point what's happening is we're starting
to see an emerging technology which is
what we do when this information is now
happening outside of my network what I'd
do I protect it how to understand it how
do I get that risk that's what a cloud
access broker is a couple years ago we
started Gardner had to come up with a
name to figure it out we help them
through that process they were never
heard of Cloud Security Alliance CSA
it's a great organization and you should
really get to know them and understand
what they do
Jim Reavis is on our board of advisors
and he's helped us when we first started
the company and that was how do we
define what we should ask cloud services
in terms of questions like how should we
interrogate somebody that's providing
the service to us are they doing a good
job I think you know providing secure
means of access and where they located
all those kind of things you expect
smaller so if you look at it the average
enterprise today is running a thousand
cloud services it's a shocking number I
we do these preferred consoles for
people will take the logs from their
internal network just banging against
our database of known cloud services and
we'll find out how many cloud services
they're really running most people
believe it's around 5,200 we first meet
them and then once we do this we realize
there's a lot more to it a lot of people
ask me what is a cloud service you know
for stuff like what's the definition of
it to us a cloud services anywhere where
somebody can put your data log in right
you know they can access it with
username or password even anonymously
they can put your data and you don't
have any visibility control over its
outside of your not work outside here so
even Twitter would be a cloud service
because I can post photos from inside my
network or sensitive data right which
happens all the time so many different
things are cloud services
the average company has 94 high risk and
roll me my high risk is if you take a 50
. risk assessment score you know you
think update addressed the encrypted and
transmitted by they saw complain all the
things that you want to know some cloud
services court very poorly on something
like a bit torn you know are you know
there is a cloud service call can box
which nobody's ever familiar with if
you're going to quit and encourages he's
a steal all the information company
uploaded 2 I'm being can box there's a
cloud service force there's cloud
services out there are things
even imagine there's a cloud service for
that's what we mean by high risk and
typically we see at least that the day
temple tration abouts per quarter and
that's with customers that we see using
now recently in the news I'm sure you
guys off earlier with the you know the
anthem breach the Sony you know these
things that we've seen that's kind of
the challenger dana is moving out from
our network to the cloud
well the next challenges we have a lot
of data that lives there
you your corporation and you believe
that the state is yours you paid for
your employees are putting it there or
you're putting it there and now people
are accessing that data without ever
going to your network and there is no
visibility to it you might get up in the
cloud service but as I mentioned before
you have a thousand cloud services
running are you really gonna log into a
thousand cloud services admin councils
and go who did what try to correlate
that together so it gets to be very
typical 21% of the data that we see in
the cloud contains higher pH I typically
there's a hundred and forty-three files
when we do scans of data at rest in the
cloud that have stuff like the word
password and it recently did a scan for
a large corporation we found the CEO had
textiles violence passports inside a
cloud storage because it was convenient
you know people don't intend to do
things bad they just do it right and
when I first started we had about 1,200
cloud services and our database of known
cloud services today we have over 16,000
has only been a couple of years so what
happened was there is a little bit of
opportunity couple of years ago to use a
cloud application now there is a
gigantic opportunity everybody believes
when they go to work today if you're
going to start with a business starting
today there's gotta be a nap to do what
I'm trying to write this kind of the
mindset there's gotta be a nap to do
what the problem I'm facing I'm gonna go
to let find and install it and so they
don't even think its cloud they just
think of it as I want to use a nap and I
want to get something done what turns
out those apps typically put their data
in the cloud now that demonstrate no
exiting that 36% of files shared
externally and you know some of the
other stats 85% companies
anomalies in the canyon insider threat
and that could be somebody that's trying
to do something that or it could be a
machine that nobody caught an example
somebody had a Twitter account inside
their network it was twenty more treats
than a human being can get it was
nowhere in it was putting it together on
the outside once we did a time does it
was very small and people to notice so
those are the kind of things that we run
into and so what what has been created
as new space call the cloud access
broker in the idea is to put the control
point out at the cloud to give you that
visibility at the cloud providers so
that when I'm sitting here in this room
over network that has nothing to do with
my corporation if I'm using data that
you all in the cloud you get the
visibility to it as if it was inside
your pants that's what we're trying to
do is to bring the network that is here
to you and don't think of it as a
network anymore the way we think of it
as if you on that data is your identity
you know if you have access to it and
you paid for your you know when you sign
up for it then you step visibility into
it so think of it as the identity data
that you own should be protected forget
about the network it's really the day
right where's my data were right on it
and do I have this ability to it so the
purposes of texas poker is this ability
what am I using you know what's the risk
of that threat protection you know if
somebody's doing something the cloud
that they shouldn't be helped and I see
access to that and compliance this is
one that I touched on this a little bit
but compliance is really a big thing for
a lot of people right now trying to
figure out how do I B complain that
things are suddenly moving in places
that we don't even know where they're
going right so clients is another one
and the data security can I get that
data with my own he's been doing all
that it happens ability to what happened
to it so that's the that's the nut shell
of what this is you know the cloud
access broker Gardner said this is the
number one security technology of 2015
so this is topical so if if you're
thinking about what is important what is
Gardner talking about their talking to
your company's about or anybody that you
work for work with they're talking about
products is broken it's something you're
gonna hear often couple of years ago
when I started nobody even you know
there was a man named port which is that
how to protect the cloud outside right
but now they put a name on to it there's
a lot of people involved with it so
something that definitely pay attention
to
the way that if this is deployed the way
this works is there's a couple of
different ways that we can get this
Taylor access to the primary method is
cloud providers are now providing API's
or access controls that we can get
directly from the cloud provider so for
example we have relationships with box
sales worse than normal players that you
would expect so instead of you having to
go and install something on them or us
and install something on your network we
just gotta feed directly from that cloud
provider into a dashboard that you can
use to see what's happening today the
loss prevention that's kind of the
deployment architecture there is not a
planet anymore if you have an
administrator rights that service you
can put it into our cloud dashboard or a
card access brokers dashboard and now I
can see get visibility and and actually
take control and do stuff with the other
method that and then you need two
different methods there that is directly
to the cloud provider but for compliance
sometimes we can't let the day to go in
there and then have us to do lots of
ranch another figure out what happen
sometimes for compliance for him or for
health care and some other industries
you have to stop that data before it
even goes into that cloud service if
it's against your policy or something
that should be shared the other way we
do that as we actually do the identity
of the individual so when they go to
login that service do single sign-on
it'll look back and say okay with us
once protected with us a sky-high for
example our cloud access broker it'll
send it to a cloud-based reverse proxy
and then into that cloud service and
that's where the decryption of that trip
that data that's where you dey loss
prevention and you'll be able to stop so
then you can look at what's happening
and say oh this is a violation of our
policy you can stop that day warranty
right there so the kind of the primary
methods that we use to control the data
going into the clout and we can get any
questions
so one of the first to use cases that I
wanna go over is Ralph laura is now the
CEO of HP came from he was using Skype
for example o'clock someone came to HP
the first thing that he kind of coin
there's a lot of people never heard the
word channel ITV rebrand up a lot but
remember that I I like to joke that
shadow I T used to be somebody bring in
a server and stuffing out of their desk
that nobody asked about its a cloud
service now nobody is caring service
into work and plug it into the network
in san Tomas satellite TV help people
get a cloud service they don't know
about the use it and they'll tell me
about it is easy and because it goes
over encrypted web connections very hard
for employees to tell if your
insecurities are trying to figure it out
you don't know when someone and you
don't even know if it's really bad if
you have a proxy they'll put
kickasstorrents and one driving the same
category cloud storage and how would you
know which one is the the name is
obvious but if his name something like
the best five stories about securing the
world you would know it's bad you just
start right so that's that that concern
so what ralph does is every time someone
comes to my business units as we want to
use this new cloud service more
interested in the business unit says
this href this gonna save us a ton of
money and time and we want to use it
he's coming to terms shall I T which is
he goes to a sky-high dashboard our
cloud access broker he looks up in real
time where the cloud services those
employees are using and you can see here
it's one of those is ranked on a scale
of one to ten in terms of risk so the
risk assessments automatic been done and
he knows already using these cloud
services turns out this one is got a
really great security rating and more
people are using it to the one you want
me to use why aren't you guys using that
one half the time it's just they didn't
know they're even using it for
corporations are so big we have so many
people doing things in them there might
be a business on business unit that we
purchased that company purchased and
nobody even knew that they had an
application they're using it worked
really well right so that's the
collaboration for the benefit the old
way of doing it just to send a survey
out and ask everybody whether using
while I don't even remember what I
that's very difficult so having
something that can detect in real time
what people are using and how much day
is going to win this season is very
helpful that's one of the disabilities
and other visibility is Brian Lilley
he's the sea CIO next which is where
office 365 is hosted they use a method
where they do just in time
education so they had a problem where
people were not collaborating by cloud
storage at least they had about fifty
seven different cloud storage and use
and if everyone's using two different
cloud storage then we lose the point of
the collaboration of the cloud right
where the giant pile to each other
everybody is just using it as a personal
sort so he looked at that and he
integrated his cast me with this proxy
and that's a really important thing to
do is you can give your proxy the
intelligence of the cloud risk
assessments so what they do is if it's
outside of their policy of forced to
higher risk it pops up a message to
employees when they go to use the proxy
that says you should use this you know
here's our policy please use a simple
thing like education for people they
don't want to use a really bad cold
storage they just think that's what they
use right cuz they found that's really
helpful in helping people guide them to
where they should go and then this one
is really something I'm very passionate
about we have one of my customers
proctor and Gamble and they'll have over
700 times a year someone come to me and
say we want to use this cloud service
security team go back them right glass
demure 500 questions
figure out of their secure and then out
of the ten pick one that can take a
month sometimes I can take more we've
had customers like peridot and I've had
customers like Procter and Gamble those
local here that's where they'll say they
actually taken that time
90% reduction the time if somebody's
already done that risk assessment for
you like a cloud access broker they'll
go to the dashboard and sky-high look up
that cloud service all those risk
assessment answers already there if
there's questions I need to ask that are
on there had that to it
price of their team only has to do a
little bit of the work on top what sorry
they're not all the work to start with
this is something that I think is
extremely important I'm seeing every
company that I talked to this is really
important to them and being able to
figure that out and if you don't know
how to do this and if you say to the
people that are coming to that why use a
cloud service but we have no idea it's
going to take us three months to bet
that turns out the employees want to get
their job done so they'll just go use it
not tell you and that's why should white
chicks right shadow I T exist when I T
department is so difficult to work with
instead of enabling them they just cant
get used to have the time so if you can
find a store that has that stuff done
for you
it saves you the time and now you're
helping your neighbor Brian Lilley if
you google his name
chief enabler is what you get because of
his work with sky-high his goal was to
be the chief enabler not the chief
information officer that she helped them
and that is really I think the critical
way to think of it as an opportunity to
partner with the business units with
security and say well we don't have to
say no we can say instead of using this
one
use this right this technology if you
have that it becomes incredibly powerful
compliance is really important in there
some other examples like selling had a
requirement to do on demand skinny right
after the bridge that their customer and
one of their concerns we have stuff out
in the cloud we need something to go and
look in for the stuff that's already
sitting there apply our policies to it
is their Pio there is there something
sensitive and then grab that report
that's not the case
threat protection i think is the next
most important thing to think about and
to me threat protection is everyone is
probably familiar with the words no
event is on the news all the time and as
saying
took all their data from them a lot of
people still ask what how did the NSA
with other intelligence nothing how US
intelligence how do they not know four
days he was dumping data out to the
internet so much right to use copy the
reason is they were not running behavior
they were not running behavior learning
on what he was doing right so he was
allowed to
absolutely do whatever he wants the
nobody checking one use case after the
anthem preach we got a major health care
provider that wasn't same size and they
said
sky-high would have caught it because
what we do is we do behavior learning on
the cloud service so we have a duty to
model engine running in the cloud and we
have tens upon millions of data
transactions happening every second
so we'll do is we'll take several
million people using Facebook every day
and will do machine learning a what is a
normal user and what's an adenoma I'm
extremely passionate that behavior is
really the security that is the next
we're going to you because you're not
gonna be able to stop people from going
to cloud services you're not going to be
able to control them all but if you can
do the learning and behavior and figure
out what's abnormal and what's normal
that will alert you to the second
something happens I had a large Michigan
manufacturer I went to meet with the CIO
before he was gonna buy high and we
looked at this anomaly page right this
is the kind of the screen that you're
seeing there and I said well you got a
real problem so many movies 62 gigs to
Google Drive this morning that's to
outline right out of a hundred thousand
people that was the anomaly or the event
that showed up near the needle in a
haystack needle he's like yeah that was
me as trying to see if your stuff work
and great you know that's what I'm
looking for
so that's the kind of stuff that i think
is critical is who's watching the back
door who's watching your behavior and if
you can get a tool that automatically
watches every cloud services in news and
already has baseline that's the way to
effectively do that without having to
hire new people its really automation
the second thing is geographically you
can see threats and so one of the other
things that i think is a critical
feature in this was CIA
they were looking at issues that started
with the passwords being used across
geographies and so what this is is being
able to detect in this about thirteen
different behaviors that we can detect
now and this isn't behaviour learn from
your traffic if you have five hundred
people you can't do machine learning I
don't care what software you put in
place if I only had 10 people using
something like sendspace or storage I'm
not going to be able to do good machine
learning behavior analytics because that
fifth person is there's no one out there
it takes millions of people to really do
machine learning out what is bad
behavior and what's a good behavior
because we can tap into all that
behavior that we have we can do it we
can help you out that's a good cloud
access Rakesh do this one is the
Superman so many logs from China to a
cloud service with the same credentials
to login here with a few minutes that's
impossible we see a lot of people who
have hurt security and that's something
you wanted I'm running out of time here
a little bit so the last thing I wanna
talk about its compliance and will take
will take an example here
Lubrizol is a local machine Ohio
customer and so one of the things they
are looking for is there he had on
promised a loss prevention they wanted
to take that and apply it from the cloud
in and so as a cloud access broker we
could hand off those events to their on
premise deal peace they have to relearn
everything they can use existing tools
and just integrate with that bring that
it so with that I'm going to get into
the end of this is we're kind of running
low on time so from four years of
deploying this seminal earnings that
we've done far we've come into as you
cannot have friction for the users of
you apply something that has something
installed on their machine will never
work they have to not know that it's
happening all has to be done from
backend process straighter there you
have to leverage the existing
infrastructure and investment so if you
have something like powell out or if you
have websites leverage that use that to
apply this to it and add this into it
you gotta think of cloud access broker
as a new piece of technology these
include any are not necessarily get rid
of Technology this is that it's this and
then the last thing we have is these are
all in which we have this I think this
will be online so these are all people
that would be willing to talk to your
companies that have done this and are
willing to speak and they're they're
great references are leaders in the
corporations around the world they're
using products as brokers so this is a
great opportunity for companies to have
someone to talk to reach out to
and finally a call to action right you
can become an enabler in your business
what we typically will do to meet people
will say how do we take a couple weeks
of your logs were banging against this
product's broker tell you the visibility
of what you're doing the clout and then
give you a report that helps you make
decisions out well I am using the cloud
and maybe I should do something about it
maybe I shouldn't but this is how we
usually meet most people as it's a great
way to say all right with at least a
compliance report to see what are we
doing the cloud of what's the risk of so
many questions before we run out of time
here nobody I'm not there yet so I think
your time and be sure