ok and guides wireless it's really just
wifi will talk about that in second
normally when people say Wireless
playlist though they're talking about
wi-fi amateur radio personal so he talks
on northern I read the summary yes you
did I wrote us up last year for external
and it's actually out there on the web
sites got some in there if you follow me
on Twitter or volunteer training
understand when dressed like this after
all this is my twitter profile picture
from last year's Halloween costume and
when chris said hey we need a picture
for you for your schedule like here's
here's why they took it worked as a
professional looking in jerusalem
halloween costume your corporate hacker
picture it's like ok I'm awake at the
mask I have a BS in Information
Assurance from Eastern University
they're actually currently a grad
student at University of Maryland and
this constant texting very very hot so
anyways the guy behind the mask that's
me I got my OTP in 2010
realists pretty much since 1998
helped design college classes at the
college have done a lot of other things
and expect to incite a merging of
inspiratory less than 10 minutes
so going beyond that who also I used to
do research and testing for general
motors as a contractor the biggest issue
was I wanna make sure people were
hooking up their own access to the
network there is a big problem with with
p.m. because they have people there
while walking through the plan between
their office in the machine at work on
another access point and say well I'm
not gonna walk back and forth I'm
chairman my laptop with me
problems they also use the same wireless
network the same frequencies to control
the robots that the plants and I've got
a chance so that's that's that I just
checked out because now it's funny cuz
this was actually started as a grand
jury has one credit hour short of
graduation so this was a one credit hour
directed study at university I don't see
Joe eastman in here is my advisor type
but during the researchers here so I can
get similar things larry is actually his
paper 42 Sands was fix all the problems
I was having ever built everything in
the restroom so he did it with the WR
cheese the old Linksys routers and
hearing all these weird issues and I go
there is paper
docking station there's a lot of people
have helped along the way to go as far
as to why were driving so are you here
hopefully like security tools that louis
vuitton with the logo is
gestures drug use a truck so as to be
plus gemcitabine thinkers gonna watch
Tron uprising disaster in the Gulf is
really popular they are you see the logo
on trance chessen first movie and in the
last week very briefly so I also liked
his replies are you liked this network's
so where you want your last chance for a
public security tools with was made to
go to build one going to other
regulations all the requirements all the
energy regulations government
regulations and PCI DSS is a regulation
because if you don't follow you can't
hear her please do business so it may
not be a government regulation but that
is an interesting one such as a
guideline PCI DSS cordless can I don't
like order this cancel call that a
second data loss prevention you know
what your IP walking out the door to the
parking lot and so we see in a siege
engine called the Car Talk earlier he's
like I don't know what the current
because of his agency would be talking
about medieval stuff and it's all the
cars gas and then policy compliance are
people expecting a premier without your
permission
you I'll show you where the scans
documentation you start off the new
company you want to watch their network
that doesn't just mean map your wires
that means
transfer problems turning off wifi will
usually do testing before they turned
off and if you search teams problems
when they're going to they're built in
hopes of stopping before they do the
replacement is going to come from the
same office park is you afterward and
say you're causing interference on my
such assistance channels they don't do
it early enough when they're in the
testing phase and say hey you're causing
problems were together to fix
interesting things let's see what's
interesting things guys to Nokia n900 in
bathroom ceiling tiles power charger
that was really hard life I had fled
into the word that way so it's like a
nice little choice but to be honest if
you go into more one of their session
beyond just just wifi you get smarter
tools that were talking the talk you can
start fining people broadcasting from
with and rebuilding other sites just to
find even more problems so like this one
contractor for for a while and I'm in my
department meeting agenda proxy proxies
like and he's like ok whatever nobody
else is what your problem is finally go
through phones like you are using your
phone as a hotspot that's good policy
well I got justice and i cant get to
work through the company goes ok so very
made in 10 turned on his proxy setup and
Roger so he set that up it's hard work I
don't get this is like a developer got
to have all your hooks in place for us
it doesn't hurt so as well as you are
scanning you know if I were caught the
guy doing the Dolphins hot spots her
husband to be over talk to you in favor
of his power without having spent three
weeks are working full-time for
snapshots of the reasons why I don't
like snapshots things like to move her
out they'd like to move around as you're
doing your snapshot and some general
motors we go to a plant we got to be
real about 10 of us
there's a logjam so we go around every
quarter you walk in and people working
for get to know us because that
engineers IEEE stuff chair the wifi
password he had 14 just left it wide
open so those guys get on certain that
to be like hey those I T guys with the
weird antennas are here again you might
want to do something about that
go over and shake that thing because I
party / stuff you know nothing engineer
the camera cuz I would take security
with people would get locked out of the
device in four different times in
Carmichael wants smashed from I said you
have been told no he bring about now
it's been destroyed if you do this again
as I can change my schedule and he just
looked at me like against you then I
guess I can cause your own policy I hate
heights they were sent out a plan to the
roof so you're gonna have to walk on
that edge and you don't usually have to
unclip 1.0 clipping and other funny
because you know you gotta go around the
device I don't like how it's also got
hit by one of those nice happy the
trolley cart that holds all the parts
from one machine to another one that's
open and left little scar and lastly
timing so you a snapshot at two o'clock
in the afternoon during or after 6:30
and might do I know what happened at 3
a.m. in the morning and we're also going
on the softest part besides I seen
business fall another guy down the
street using his office building as a
rave have been there done that
so respects the sock with that cuz
resume by Tues me so this is now version
to the first version has done a great
great great baby the beef prices came
out is a special projects like Manzana
46 of those desires politician
prices on you this time I could afford
that like wow this is great
are now in this must be better so skip
to be losses and straight to the 2012
plus my collection
TV links I like these cards I really
like these cars especially when using an
expression here because this car doesn't
require compile safaris grasp Ian arch
or any of the other just have to sit and
compile the card is so slow I can
compile things for Linux administrator
I don't like feeling when packages are
you done just downloading now the
downside to these carts there the ATL
and BTL 722 and the downside in
Scarsdale you have power you've got a
couple of options
the president pious don't do pov but you
can buy POS printers so it takes off the
POV fucking are you catch through
regular cable put the power to the park
for Cisco's big hit on walk
do 66 devices at Cisco equipment you've
got to go out and got to have a mobility
services engine that can either be a
physical appliance a card that plug into
your switch or it can be a virtual
appliance randomly boxes heal and
control work
so we're talking about $3,000 her
virtual in about four and a half were
physical right now we got that language
was another thousand at closing price
which I've lost you lots they get access
point in the first their accountants if
they do have some limitations but
they're great for persons house after I
justify spending that money is spent
about $35 by your party's starting at
mine and are $30 each
they're always on sale for something but
if you don't cost about $15 WN 722 on
our supplies the runs at the Rashtrapati
logos on them are 99999 industry go to
you and then $8 k so that will still
work with your right so far to build six
drones and that's what we call them as
well
his ps3 popeye for $100 at the door
the Cisco Cisco same six voices is going
to cost you less than $1,000 the fan who
you are is the wireless engineers at
ford said thats cool song on $20,000
from the ability engines not so what's
wrong I miss before Scott Kelly out a
history of of Kelly
pat pat capture and then again another
pass catcher know I really really love
kids don't get me wrong like a great guy
great work it just misses one featured
and we'll talk about that and second
mitchell also have 20 time for this so
welcome to resolve
will see a picture of all the minute but
this is what I actually presented to my
advisor for a great here's what we got
we got three device plugged in space
love for we've got all the staff
equipment I can see all these different
cool things are here got a couple of
hitting up a society's dug into more I
want you to play a secure which is what
they used to do their taxes on Sat I've
got the secure wireless network
responsible for faculty most since then
the soft and that's fine I can cialis
real fast it's kinda hard to see cuz I
start talks on dark background with this
last couple of years seen by and I
foresaw ITC i three saw flashes her name
I devices for him because that's a 10
character hard set so yeah that's that
and he hasn't asked questions any point
is good sorry asking her to see so I
look at one of the network side I
drilled into it and this is where is not
failed me here I have real fast
hard to read this close to exotics mouse
but there was never an 86 TBM Ortiz
excuse me that tells me that it's a
native 86 power said this on me that
there's a big difference between you and
a little drone if you guys notice
there's actually four devices since
right now we're going to lie for
personal but that tells me that negative
40 p.m. which is great but where do you
host trying at least that's how much
possession find this is just like the
PowerRating of one device and you log
into one by one in this case re locked
onto the Society's I wanted in 1891 a
negative 71 and in classrooms 9459 so
that tells me is his closest to suffice
so how this work
picture that's that's where the
transcripts out of so-so where the old
building built in 1918 so far high
school campus is actually a lab in this
room here professor head the rogue
access point by the other lab and we
were able to figure out where it was by
using challenger so I missionary couple
warnings aircraft nice it's fun to use
but he need to be careful so every year
about the hotel chains were gonna find
recently got a night suggesting we also
reserve locking so what they're doing is
basically injecting to prevent you from
using your own device which is a
built-in feature to that Cisco device
here we do it manually through so the
actual relevant law is 47 USC USC USC
USC code subsection 3 33
and the main point is you don't want to
get caught and then you have chairman
saying consumers must get what they pay
for so I pay for fhe for the service you
can not blocked by service just because
you want me to jordan says he finds mary
was fined $6,000 back in October and
then actually last year she was summer
of last year
look at later on sort ce holding company
was fined $7,000 are you seeing those
numbers go up to you know I say a
holiday and last night that doesn't make
me a better for businesses who have
houses wifi we don't know yet cuz it's
not interesting I don't wanna
I don't have to find out what check and
see if she goes on she sit there and try
to take this off long as you see it
coming up here and you know that's
between you and make sure they know they
can get find a large numbers so idk the
gods among us talk for time so this not
talking 25 and 50% working this time and
I'm really testing it because I've got
to use bringing laptop and charger
Andy Carroll
chicken over so let's get this party the
speaker single
coats
ok so I've got his laid out throughout
the device can see change name not your
baby names have fun at school so I
switch over to IDE mode guess IDs
addresses
phones for verizon mifi their respond
I'm actually not mine but let's look at
this one was less like this one
specifically so drawn to it there's a
school where he got the 1998 TV I'm done
here and this is what I can see so far I
can scroll down this route that runs
this year all i want i two or three or
four again the name that because you had
in the last seen by filled so everybody
sees it but back to the whole point
everybody sees it but I gotta make
society for in a guy max per average or
1998 so see if this works fine
richard is hard to hold talk at the same
time cop sounds like it that's fine
size
and the workers are in the same bus it's
a little slow so it's true
audience asked questions now and later
it's there's more slides on that later
take this time to put you in now so as
to be smart about this over its word
very heart of your product as its next
month
other things I kinda forgot its ok so
sorry guys are we watching things are
for
so what is up here in the corner that's
why to they had the surgery innings into
stronger so I'm gonna head or certainly
for that device now you can use your
cell phone at that point using the tools
they have all their life which is way
better than walking off a laptop with a
narrative he knows he's done that or you
can walk around with something else I
don't have the hand scanner over his
reply now because it's more stealthy
anything which is
so I can do that with any BS SATA pick
up even the non broadcasting names cause
I'm still have the necessary it ever
have a society join them at work but
I'll still have its mechanism so that
this light where we're talking for the
purpose of this last seen how characters
including spaces that's hard set can be
changed my feelings change if you can't
use the main screen you'll find what
you're looking for
so limitations last June by the network
of you doesn't you powering this Friday
devices just give you our readers rely
on those used by the show
Microsoft hardware limitation I love
this network card that works out the box
it doesn't do a it doesn't do you see it
only gets happen then so it's a
five-hour network you can see it and
know the cards that are currently based
on testing I've done in testing that
juror chaos Rick project is done we
haven't found any yet she working
separately but we haven't found any yet
they'll actually do both bandwidth at
the same time I can lock on the one side
or the other side but I can't do both
together there's no bluetooth in these
they've had a couple of amateur actors
able to hear in here and the sites we
got one general actually attack me
Realtek
so the exercise hang out with Marina
club like he had written on the same
frequency as like this church i've seen
nobody believed her words like not
according to the chart sightseeing and I
can't pick them up with wifi card so i
cant see Bluetooth
there are using the same frequency bands
but I can't see those because they're
just often nothing with israel has set
up a pickup salary so so why is it that
matter I can't catch a guy using his
blue 2004 I can't catch a guy brings the
reasons he office and open while a guy
using the software for data voice but I
can see his cell phone use his house so
if you've got the hotspot setup I can
see it if he's got other day so I think
that he brought the USB cable and plug
it into a cell phone but in that way I
can take that that's limitations of this
hardware system failures the raspberry
power source again Sorry Sorry failure
in the system the party before departure
use if you don't forget the trash so
they actually called him properly I have
to plan everything has to be financially
before you powerful device otherwise
restored your hard drive crashes six
that you have our hard work in the same
virus so you're in the shape of yourself
is also was a device's because all the
trappings persons who are the same way
if a plug and USB dongle with you it
does nothing for me because I'm still
fighting the bus if it's a larger church
environment
what's a cafeteria at large are among
the company's headquarters is your
presentation good luck talking about all
you can have such data and that you that
you'll never went back to the other side
so I might see I saw high 62 was sending
me all the data from other devices over
there I could actually a cessation to do
anything with it all again if you power
off the Raspberry Pi without proper shut
down here is corrupting are you sure its
own problems moving into the party's use
and Kelly 2.01 so what about when you
some fun Kelly no longer does interest
me card because they realize we're going
different sized cars I'm using sixteens
and just because you buy a car that says
a sixteen year but it doesn't mean 62
the car they bought were actually
fourteen to sixteen at the same minute
manufacturers to her as the ones that
have the 15.9 but their own fortune
organized and we're going to mess of
system do you like it so they tell you
to go proper file and at sea / for / ap
/ Marcio which is great if using the
system file system right here it doesn't
go see their calls that file searcher
stuff how is it that doesn't really work
on Cindy Cindy so-called that file but
it takes 20 seconds to run it kills it
so either have to put to sleep
or you have to go through and say it's
not quite working right and spend about
$20 trouble is killing it because it's
taking too long run but only seven trips
were canceled and then if we go back to
work is what's real fast
the bar on here as he channel airs
screen and see it says i cant such
channel 165 such a channel 161 those are
a chance that occurred in a second but I
can do the channels there so it's hard
work but if you block out the chalice on
that config
servicemarch Alastair here is ABC's
moscow is the Saudi Arabia channels so
it's picking up all the networks so than
36 which is your age you're at your
higher and it just doesn't see those I
come in this line out his parents are as
a control and I found that out last
night at about two o'clock in the
morning weather is making sure this
presentation work so I had time to tear
out why that is not fix it can't be
fixed if you want to play your own
suggestions cuz I do actually have
people contact me on a regular basis and
they say hey by Jordi Gola sure all we
want you something this is a proof of
concept at work
do it this way you use the same hardware
limitations use Kelechi 4.1
basis base install now it doesn't come
with her rescue program for Google to
expand your heart your drive to the base
R and saw her only
scripts and the scripts work there i
read your heart and because I'm a
programmer the these artists really ugly
shell scripts will soon as I can but
there's two in there is also called our
party with which is designed to expand
your drives as well maintained about
three years and was using RCA local 269
that is active installs the software
needed from Cali and pulls a file from
the W repositories install them for you
to tell you what changes you make your
own and then drops you into the
configuration
configured prone to ask you things as
you go along and seven times all the
configuration files for you to all the
senate for you and take your time
45 minutes to an hour to about 15 to 20
so it's fast so this one shining shows
were there is no network connection to
the outside world
so this is the the final configuration
file to transmit right so they will
likely start start out so
so let's go into it before and can you
to it so this kit clone and then
you are a person file which is required
here it tells you is going to view and
download install happy about 5.1 who the
hell you're positive worries that goes
and does it start download press you can
download this file here perhaps arrested
for trial so if I say $30 alter happy
for you fill out because it does have
another connection somehow stories for
starting jobs you into change change
your filesystem
assault Kelly indexing stalls for
desktop mode so I'm at the larger role
but I like logs you into your desktop or
not but load you into an actual system
so I changed the file system and then
you are come down and change your desk
desktop scratch
you reboot your full-size heard
portion of it through some configuration
questions there are many but first I
need to go and staff and TV
funding is the very surprised don't know
the date and time you saw last time
required to actually keep updating the
date dealing with a laptop won't hurt
you add a comment on these are now they
don't think they're starting October
that's right
questions about stuff everything sorry
your version of cameras in there to see
things in school by too fast
might go back and change those times I
don't always box with us updates
throughout the strong you are a
cholesterol raspy two years for a dress
for mr marcus 48124 she for your mask
sort of these are deploying forgets this
is where what is it what do I tell the
kids would serve as what what's my
server ninja strong so that in this case
I for what mike hasn't sorry
by several cases 65
so at this point it's already created
for reclaiming our trials for her face
card so sorry skip static IP address
configuration files system to actually
start untrue and now it was no what's my
password and it goes through and change
your acct SSH keys because it was
covered with a tarp reconfigured and it
hasn't quite a lot that was intense
pressure to this photos to recreate CRC
he's received
and we're done you have a converter box
it'll be rooted device rebooting to grow
shouldn't do that and that's what they
want your toes if his hand you have to
worry about typos you have to worry
about center there's your file they're
all that for me it's only been tested so
I don't have to worry about issues
before that this doesn't like having a
number you call a drone and you learn it
normally like this one up here to start
of the user been kissed her own space
test test demonize system he doesn't
like that and it kills process we just
got hotter
working now so you can go away so she
took the time to tell the people they
are you guys have fun with it sounds
like now suggest they'd been told that
these were very surprised if they don't
work unless required to do the dräger
ever finishes production of these things
we do you get these devices who actually
pick up to the radio signals and do the
scanning devices and then her phone
again told that this website has replied
no this doesn't work on Raspberry Pi to
see what other frequencies like pick up
between thirty megahertz hand was ten
years or six years so tonight her
six-year hurts me way more radio
frequencies associated with this is wifi
not wireless that currently wireless
dealers to find contact info on my name
is outrageous I get home is serious
there's a long story behind that goes
back to IRC fight many many moons ago
when I rolled her at a store and buy six
companies on freenode you can find me as
radius and my blog write a lot of
talking about chains of ice is working
on the raspberry PI's is registered net
told us the best the main underlying
architecture there that's the main 2009
second I want to actually work through
it that with Jasmine which I've been
told it works but people told me that
doesn't work with raspberry Pi it's just
as there's not a power there so does it
work does not work I don't know and
that's where the question comes in and
that's where I'll see if I can I know
very large automotive company that
offered by the song because it's cheaper
and Cisco people ask me a lot times any
other questions
I don't
just took the opportunity section of
avenue to do so may go to that
ya gotta get six it was cos like shaping
of those and other questions so it is
one slide last night that didn't make it
to the final decade don't know why i got
clear eyes fixed on something else
a lot of people ask me about similar
immigration employees in the same so you
don't actually know you can go pretty
same instead I tried making this work
last night with alien vaults I couldn't
get started p.m. I don't know why I'm
not going to sit there and spend half
the night troubleshooting something
we've done it before and been too old
for that
pushing 40 so you have to offer that the
owners are behind me so stop aging don't
get old young girls over here he told
reporters actually has hooks into it so
if we go back to
they'll pull the state into alien vote
for you so you gots immigration is
haven't done it yet but there's plenty
of documentation of the network that
every weekend