I
alright so my name is Billy Hoffman some
of you guys might know me as a siddhis
I've spoken at a lot of conferences over
the past couple years on a wide range of
topics today I'm here to talk to you
about covert Carly which is basically a
mechanism of how to use a automated
process to crawl a website and gather
information without leaving a forensics
trail I tend to talk a lot and really
fast so if you have a question please
feel free to interrupt me I have fun
schwag that I brought I've got some bag
from when I spoke at shmoocon and some
whoo that would have been bad some stuff
from black that federal and stickers and
stuff so if you have a good question you
get schwag if you have a bad question
we've riddle quote ridicule you on
that's kind of how it goes all right you
guys ready alright cool so what am I
going to talk about we're going to go
through and first start talking about
what is the state of web application
attacks we're going to go ahead and talk
about what there's a covert crawler
pretty much kind of changes the
equations on how attack and defense of
web apps works we're going to talk about
the obstacles it took to create the
covert crawler specifically how do you
make an automated program act like a
browser how do you make an automated
program act like a human and how you
throttle one of these things we're going
to talk about how actually implemented a
covert crawler and if those questions
but like I said ask me questions the
entire time okay so State of the Union
how many people here have ever hacked a
web app how many has ever thrown like a
single tick or something into a search
field to see if you get a sequel
exception there all sorts of fun stuff
like that you know hacking websites is
really easy you know I'm sure a lot of
you read bug track like something like
seventy percent of the volens I've been
reading on bug tracker last several
months have all been web app attacks
sequel injection cross-site scripting
this place trust you know improperly you
know created SSL connections all sorts
of nasty stuff they are laughably common
to find i found a cross-site scripting
vulnerability in weather com this
morning when I was trying to figure out
what to wear so it it's crazy they're
all over the place people are hacking
websites because it's in the news there
was this awesome attack on myspace back
in October somebody actually wrote a
cross-site scripting virus which use
Java code and Ajax the Prophet
there's someone here who was doing
cross-site scripting stuff so this was
an awesome virus that used ajax actually
propagate itself and infect more
cross-site or more of my space actually
gave a presentation at black hat federal
about web app worms and so if your
answer than that come talk to me
afterwards people are hacking websites
because they can make money attacking a
web app gives you the same payload and
the same tank as you know doing say
layer 3 or a layer for attack you're
trying to you know gain access to
systems you normally don't have access
to to grab passwords credit card data
confidential information you know
identity theft anything you want to do
you get access to the information
through a web app just as easily as you
can get access through you know a
anonymous account on ftp so
administrators are patching some of the
holes pretty much the PHP whatever the
hell exploit of the week because
seriously I I love open source i use
open source but god bless sourceforge
and all these PHP projects because they
completely keep my company in business
so you know but that's why I come and I
talk to you guys about how to actually
write secured web applications so it's a
given to take a lot of times people rely
on their logs if and when they get
attacked they're like oh crap somebody
you know totally just dumped my entire
sequel database out let me go to my logs
and see who was connecting to me a lot
normally they contact the IP owner which
is almost always an open proxy that
shouldn't have been open in the first
place and then the two people go after
the attacker with limited success so
whether you're actually sneaking a web
app attack by an IDs or an IPS is
debatable there's some pretty cool tax
dan kaminsky actually had a really neat
timing attack with IP fragments so that
an IDs would see a regular you know HTTP
GET you know index.html and the web
server saw you know get sequel injection
attack so you know they're there are
ways around IDS's but the point I want
to try to attack here is that attacks
just don't happen out of thin air people
recon sites ahead of time they try to
say hmm I want to attack this Bank let
me start analyzing and let me start
pounding on this Bank a little bit do
some reconnaissance and see if I want to
actually attack them and a lot of times
forensic people will tell you it's this
reconnaissance there
to see in the logs and that's how
they're able to attract people because
people will almost always launch attacks
through proxies compromised machines
botnets you know open access points but
almost always they do their
reconnaissance from their home machine
and so administrators rely on these
server logs to try to find this initial
probing sometimes they can actually see
Wow you know I normally get each visitor
my website it's like 10 or 15 pages this
one visitor which isn't a bot from a
search engine hit all apply pages I
wonder if they're going to if they're
you know trying to scope me out and so
they'll proactively put a rule in their
IDs or their IP tables and say don't let
this person come back so why would
someone even perform reconnaissance well
running a straight audit of a web app if
you're not allowed to really isn't
practical takes a very long time our
product I work for a company called spy
dynamics and we make products that scan
websites for vulnerabilities take
something like four days to run all of
CNN com which is excess of eight hundred
thousand pages it's way too much network
noise do you know what our bandwidth
bill is when you scan CNN it's pretty
big reconnaissance definitely provides
information about what you can you know
use for your attack version numbers
about what technologies are using you
know I love looking at HTML comments and
seeing I'm using you know this version
of vb bold or you know PHP BB or
whatever it lets you know about the
structure layout of the site you know an
HTML comments you can find developer
names email addresses you know you can
do your traditional reconnaissance stuff
you know go hit google groups and see
what you know if they're making post to
use net also it provides a subset of
pages you actually attack you know let's
say CNN that's a good example eight
hundred thousand pages right well CNN
only has a couple of interesting pages
they have a search page they have a page
for email alerts which by the way is
cross-site scripting they have I totally
send my mom like news stories like on
her birthday says Billy is says his mom
is greatest in the world and it's
written by like Bob Woodward because you
just you know you sequel injection and
it's shirt and cert a story in there
it's fun you guys should do it it's kind
of like sending a look sending an email
well the reason I say you should do it
is that you're not actually injecting
into their back-end database it's what's
called a reflection cross-site scripting
attack so you're actually not exploiting
you're technically breaking any hacking
laws it's kind of like sending an email
to yourself from God by finding you know
who has it tell them it it's a you know
port 25 and send emails to people it's
like that it's fun stuff so again like I
said it lets you know what you want to
attack oh they got search engine oh they
got an email alert system let's focus on
those instead of hitting all their news
stories because those tend to be the
same so you can browse the site by hand
in a web browser that's certainly a type
of reconnaissance it lets the user kind
of direct where they want their search
to go you know when i'm looking at site
I immediately go to search engines
things like that to take user input you
know you can mess with the query string
but you know it lets you kind of target
it as opposed to a crawler which is
stupid and hits everything the problem
is it takes the time that the user could
be using to do other things you know
like read / 10 times a second and it's
certainly not an exhaustive search of
the entire site it's very possible that
while I'm only focusing say on the
search engine aspect of CNN or the alert
of the stock ticker I'm not focusing on
this you know survey which happens to be
embedded inside like every 10 news
stories or something like that maybe
that's vulnerable but I didn't even look
there because I wasn't exhaustive
automated crawler is the complete other
end of the spectrum you know W again I
wrote some perl script I hit every
single page however and so I
exhaustively find all your
vulnerabilities which is what our
products by dynamics does but of course
I didn't come here to sell you something
I came here to talk about web security
so very obvious in your server logs if a
crawler hits you for both from what I p
you can also see exactly what they hit
so you can be like oh thank god they're
you know they aborted their their
crawler right before they got to my
super-secret vulnerable a sequel
injection and dumped my customer
database page thank God so covert
Crawley is the best of both worlds and
of course beetle you already know this I
gave this presentation at your
conference of course you were running
around like a chicken with your head cut
off so thank you alright so covert
crawler really is the best of both
worlds it's all the prawns all the pros
of automated crawling all the prawns
get some shrimps and prawns some crabs
if you go about three streets that way
and need someone in savory so exhaustive
search it's automatic saves the
resources for later analysis awesome it
also uses various tricks to make the
crawl appear as if actually hundreds of
different users we're crawling your site
from different IPS they only browse
certain target parts of your website you
know so it doesn't have a giant
bandwidth spike so to speak when they go
visit their aw stats page now this is
not actually used for attacking the site
as I said you know whether you want to
try to employ the lib whisker I don't
feel all heard of it it's rather old but
it's kind of traditional mechanisms to
avoid IDs and IPS things when you're
attacking web apps I don't even want to
try to cover that let's just focus on
finding things because if I can crawl
your entire website without you knowing
and find a couple of things that look
interesting I can go through an open
proxy I can go to an open access point
and I can spend two minutes hitting
those two pages in hacking you as
opposed to spending several hours
crawling an entire site so the beautiful
thing about this is that you know you
you have you can later use IDs
techniques like I said and also the logs
are unable to show the reconnaissance
happened because there isn't a single IP
address that everything came from now
you're our don't open proxies it's no
big deal it's a lot more complicated to
write a covert crawler than just simply
spanning it across multiple ip's so
something I get a lot when I talk about
this is why don't you use a search
engine cash I mean if you want to find
out about someone's page just use the
google cash this is a really bad idea
because the HTML comes from the google
cash but the HTML has references to
images objects scripts all of those
other things on the original site so if
I'm the administrator of you know good
calm I suddenly see all these requests
for images and scripts and all sorts of
things but I look through my log and I
never see a corresponding get for the
HTML that link to all of those things
start going wait a minute why did
someone have this this is actually a way
that banks will try to detect fishing
you'll see that someone's grabbing their
HTML but being lazy and not actually
copying all the resources of the site as
well Google respects the robots
exclusion standard
and let's be frank if you're hacking a
web app that just is no good because you
know it's always fun whenever I'm
attacking a site immediately go to
robots.txt because it's basically a road
map to where you're not supposed to go
so our crawler certainly can't respect
that Google doesn't catch everything if
I have you know a script tag and it just
references an external say j/s file with
javascript in it which is what my space
does Google doesn't cash jas files so i
won't be able to see the entire site
things can be removed from the google
cache at people's request you're limited
to two thousand queries a day google
also doesn't serve beyond the top of
thousand results for any site so if you
search for you know kitty cats you can
never see result 1001 for the kitty cats
and also you're limited by Google allow
you use the cash in the future I mean
and then important I'm dugu could clamp
it and make it very difficult for you to
actually access the Google cash you know
it's just what's crawling the site
yourself is really the only way to
guarantee you one download everything
and to that you'll be able to do that in
the future so why would you want to run
a covert crawler well a malicious user
who's performing reconnaissance and
wants to reduce the forensic trail a
company who's monitoring the progress of
another company without leaving a trace
you know say I talked about the IBM
patent database here you know for years
IBM ran the patent database but what
people didn't seem sees IBM was running
the patent database because they could
do a reverse lookup on the IPS and go
wow Seagate's really interested in these
patents and it's also interested in
these patents and they were trying to
deduce what people were working on it's
true so if I'm seagate and I want to
monitor you know the comings and goings
of these you know researchers that work
at IBM i can keep crawling their
personal pages on a repetitive manner
looking to see what conferences are
going to just basically i want to
repetitively hit certain information
without you knowing i'm interested in it
a lawyer monitoring a website looking
for statements that are you know nasty
on behalf of one of their clients you
know miscellaneous intelligence
gathering or you just you know you're
really really paranoid and think they're
all out to get you so you covert crawl
everything so all right one of the
obstacles to overcome because honestly
when i thought about covert crawling I
really was thinking about you know how
can I make a program that i'm writing
act
or like a browser or more like a
computer and only kind of after the fact
when I actually had written a covert
crawler did I start thinking about what
you could do with a covert crawler it
was really you know kind of the tail
wagging the dog so the Cobra crawler
consists of a requester a bunch of
requesters eat the thread that somehow
control by master program so already you
have some fun thread synchronization
issues you have to mimic a browser being
controlled by a human which is not an
easy task because crawlers don't act
like browsers and crawlers and humans
make fundamental different choices about
what links they crawl in the order and
we're going to talk about that because
that was one of the hardest things to
solve multiple IP addresses can be used
to reduce the bandwidth footprint you
know we must control all these thread
now here's the interesting thing we have
to maintain session state you know if
I've got a crawler that seems to be
coming from India and another one that's
coming from New York and a website
issues a cookie to the one in India and
then the one in New York sends that
cookie back you can analyze your logs
and see that you're these multiple
threads are collaborating so you need to
find very very strict ways to make sure
that the person simply looking at their
logs cannot tell that all of these
people are actually collaborating to
crawl your site and also the crawler
must be throttled not to overwhelm the
site so the first obstacle is definitely
acting like a browser so first of all is
anyone have any questions we're good
captchas very good point there are some
things I actually get to when I'm
talking about crawling through leaks
there are some things that you know I
simply decided not to solve there are a
lot of people who have done a lot of
good work on cracking CAPTCHAs it's also
when I get to how does the crawler
behave like a human I mean people write
doctorate thesis is on this and quite
frankly they don't pay me that much did
we give this up for them so there are
some things I just kind of gloss over
and didn't investigate fully captured
well I'm not a person to answer that
question well yes
a botnet could be a good approach but
again you're still going to be I mean
sometimes it's not sometimes site
administrators don't necessarily care
about the identity of who did it they
simply want to know it's coming and if
I'm if I see a botnet and I see all
these people massively blindly
requesting pages and they they're all
seeming to collaborate and things like
that they're all talking amongst each
other simply the very fact that I'm
getting scanned lets me know that that
something is going on well like I said
if they're sharing session state I mean
there has to be some type of
coordination otherwise they're all just
D dossing you by requesting a bunch of
pages ultimately for a covert caller to
be successful all of these crawler
threads have to report the results back
to a central location you parse this
information you pull stuff out so trust
me what if we get a little further in I
think this will probably be a little
clearer so the behavior of a crawler
versus a browser is pretty distinct
crawlers never visually render anything
so HTTP headers describing the browser's
abilities are minimal specifically what
I'm talking about is right here this is
a request made by ie6 and it tells you
what languages it supports it tells you
actually the one for Firefox is much
richer it'll tell you you know hey if
you can't get this character set degrade
to this character set crawlers don't
send that because they never worry about
woo they never actually visually give
you the information there we go crawlers
never visually render it so they don't
have to browsers are very rich user
agents and so they tend to send lots of
HTTP headers crawlers really don't have
to so they don't crawlers also request
HTML and just simply parse it for links
browsers request HTML and then grab all
the supporting files so you know if I'm
a crawler I just grabbed the index or I
just grabbed the HTML file and then use
a regex and extract all the hrs and then
I stick those in a queue and proceed to
go but you know when when a browser
grabs it grabs the fav icon the
stylesheets the JavaScript the images so
simply the signature of requests a
crawler makes is distinct from the
signature of requests a browser makes so
we're going to have to somehow replicate
that crawlers are also very simple where
browsers are extremely complex they
contain code for you know parsing Java
applets flash JavaScript activex you
know and the crazy thing is these
technologies can make direct HTTP
connections themselves so if I if I have
a crawler that visits it that visits say
an index page well that index page maybe
contains some JavaScript that uses Ajax
well Ajax is a way that JavaScript can
make HTTP connections so if a crawler
just requests that page it's not going
to make the HTTP connections that the a
browser would make because the browser
is going to take the JavaScript
interpret it and make those HTTP
requests so again it's just another way
that crawlers simply don't make the same
request that a browser would make when
looking at a page so again I showed the
browser's making lots covert crawler is
going to have to duplicate both the
order and the value of these headers so
I picked the most common browser which
was ie6 at the time and the most common
version and that is the type of debt
request that my covert crawler will send
so obviously i needed a mechanism i
wrote this in java but i need a
mechanism for manipulating HTTP headers
in java first of all anyone here ever
done some java web programming not JSP
stuff but writing kind of like pearl lwp
button java because you're lazy in Perl
scares you so this really pisses me off
Java's built-in library they have they
have a nice class for making HTTP
connections for you and it allows you to
specify a proxy to use you know use this
HTTP proxy for me the bad thing is is
that what happens is if you say hey go
use this proxy if the if java can't
actually connect to the proxy it'll just
make the request directly for you anyway
without going through a proxy assuming
you know of course well I should make
the best effort to get this resource
well of course if I'm running in covert
crawler the last thing I want this to do
is make a direct request I always wanted
to use proxies so I found a beautiful
HTTP library for Java that allows you to
manipulate you know all the headers it
allows you know fail overs for proxies
it's excellent this is really cool you
guys should check it out here's a little
snippet of code but basically you know
I'm replicating all of the headers that
a browser would send also we need a
mekinese
for getting these page resources like I
talked about 1 HTML pages causes several
other ACV two HTTP transactions I've
images image maps scripts complex media
fav icon style sheets all sorts of junk
this are all the sites off of O'Reilly
calm and you see you know right there
I've got you know almost two dozen
images alone that I need to grab just
from visiting the main index HTML page
of O'Reilly and that doesn't even
include they have so many freaking like
RSS feeds and style sheets it's
ridiculous so we I needed to browser fly
a crawler and so basically this is a
dump of one of the log files but I
grabbed a weight I have the laser
pointer so up so right here I grabbed
the index page and then the browser fire
all these red dots are other requests
the mic covert crawler needed to make to
look like a browser so I'm grabbing AJ s
file for JavaScript I'm grabbing a
stylesheet I'm grabbing a gift and then
the rest of these are just a bunch of
gifts so definitely you have to make all
the HTTP request that a browser makes so
more browser emulation because acting
like a browser is a lot more than just
sending the HTTP requests that a browser
would send and it's also how you send
them browsers use what are called
persistent HTTP connections we're
basically you leave the connection open
I make a debt I get the response and
then without you know destroying that
connection and redoing the three-way
handshake I just send an AR HTTP request
crawlers typically don't implement this
there's some weird HTTP like pipelining
persistent connection stuff it's not a
lot of people don't implement it very
well and again the library really helped
me out so even if you need to also you
need to find out whether your crawler
even needs to send them because browsers
implement a cash so my crawler had to
implement a cache because there are
certain things like HTTP oh here's the
e-tag on this this resource doesn't
expire for you know till 2010 so a
browser would never make a request for
this image again my covert crawler to
look like a browser obviously needs to
respect all these you guys can see this
gets really complicated really quickly I
have to respect caching controls you
know respect caching directives use
conditional gets saying hey get me this
resource only if it's
expired I mean there's this was not
trivial to two really interesting well I
it's funny because I use IE as my my
HTTP headers but I was doing everything
in linux on java so i was using firefox
i was doing a lot of you know running it
through a proxy and then making sure I
was doing the same thing so there are
some features about HTML that make
browser flying or crawler so to speak
quite difficult the HTML can contain
objects like I said that making HTTP
connections on their own we talked about
Ajax already flash can use sockets Java
can use optics sockets activex can use
sockets you know you've got meta refresh
tags so other objects will continue
downloading I grabbed an HTML page which
says hey refresh to this other page in
five seconds but I proceeded to download
the style sheets and all sorts of other
junk but as soon as five seconds happen
I got to go get this other thing you got
timing issues that's that's complicated
so obviously writing flash and
JavaScript and activex parsers we're
outside the scope of the project so I
just ignored them so that pretty much
took care of making the browser excuse
me making my covert crawler act like a
browser when it would request a resource
it would request everything else that
needed to the exact same way of crawler
would and respecting all the caching
information now the tough part was how
do you make the crawler browse like a
human browser web site because crawlers
navigate links and make requests in a
very obvious and predictable pattern
they're extremely easy to detect in logs
humans make browsing decisions based on
the content and whether they like it and
not only that is the the the request
pattern is very different from a crawler
but the request patterns different from
person to person you know if akari here
is looking at hackaday he might be
interested in say some RFID hacking
stuff or some fpga hacking stuff but if
George is looking at hackaday he might
be looking for I don't know George what
hardware stuff do you like porn yeah
like animal i q no Hardware porn whoa
I've talked to Elliot about getting some
of that stuff on hackaday that'd be
great so you know it's how you make the
the request patterns differ not only
from person to person but certainly from
all people and crawlers the title of the
slide really should be behavior of
computers versus humans and replicating
human behavior is very very complicated
and this is not a master's thesis on AI
and frankly my company doesn't pay me
that much for me to you know figure this
out and solve this problem so what we
really needed to do was find a good
enough solution that was practical to
make a crawler navigate links as if it
were a human so just real quick almost
all crawlers I want to call breath burps
crawlers it's really simple you've got a
link of you've got a pending queue so
you pull the link off you grab the
resource just or a local copy if the
content was HTML then for each link in
the HTML you know check to see if it's
already pending in the link or if we
visited it if not stick it in the cube
move on it's really simple and you you
can write a crawler insane pearl in
about eight lines of code it's and
probably three if you're really beat so
here's how pages are retrieved by Brett
Fritz crawler they use a queue data
structure which causes the crawler to
visit all pages of equal depth before
going deeper so you know I make you know
a request for one and then I make these
pages before i go to four even though i
discovered four off of one so this is a
very simple design and there are tons of
examples this is basically the this is
the definitive way you write crawlers
everyone does it this way the cons of
this obviously it's very obvious non
human behavior i'm going to hit all of
these pages that are linked off the site
route before i hit one off of it no
human browsers that way you know pages
can be request when the previous
response contain no link to the page i
mean it's just very obvious to see that
this is a crawler you know browsing like
a human is different because all weeks
for a crawler all links are created
equal you know it doesn't differentiate
between how important the link is but
some links are more equal than others
for humans for example you're looking at
a Riley's page this is really
interesting
this is really interesting these things
maybe not so much so but humans just
move being conditioned by the way web
design has been over the last several
years to look for a table of contents
along the right side you know you're
more likely to click these things then
you are to click you know something over
there like more or at the bottom of the
page their privacy policy so how the
link is presented in its context really
kind of signifies how likely you are to
click on it and so this is a problem
because how do you teach an automated
process to understand the context of a
link luckily some to our people at
Google have been working on this very
thing so i actually have read a lot
about page rank which we'll get to in a
second so paid retrieval for a human
like I said the pattern is completely
different than a breadth-first search
crawler each human will access resources
in a different order based on personal
tastes and crawlers almost always act
the same regardless of whether Google
bot is crawling you or you know Yahoo's
color is crawling you there pretty much
going to request pages in the exact same
order that's not entirely true for
search engines because they they
actually keep track of how often the
pages ritas updated and visit those more
often than others but basically the
lesson here is link selection is
extremely important for a covert crawler
a human you know goes down this way and
then goes back and give us here so we
somehow need to find a way to do
intelligent link selection so as I said
humans in crawler see the HTML
differently the crawler simply sees the
release list of links so humans filter
what links they want to click based on
all sorts of con all sorts of factors
all of which we need to try to find an
equivalent for you know they filter
based on positive link content is this
something users interested in for
example hardware porn for George you
know is it negatively content not
hardware porn for George you know he
wouldn't click on it how is only
presented you know is the presentation
of the link itself interestingly
interesting enough to warrant clicking
on it I mean who hasn't want to punch
that monkey in the face everybody's
wanted to punch the monkey of the face
it chances are you punch the monkey in
the face before so understanding the
context of the links is pretty important
we can kind of fake it by examining the
contents of the links text which is what
I did understanding the presentation of
a link is
relatively easy you know it's defined by
its structure inside the HTML inside a
cascading style sheet for example you
can tell whether it's bolded whether
it's text is larger than the surrounding
text is it a image link how large is
this image in terms of area reference to
their entire screen you can kind of use
these mechanisms to determine how is
this link actually presented to the user
unfortunately we can't evaluate actual
images there could be an image that's a
link and the links and the image says
never never never click on this kind of
touches on the CAPTCHA stuff you were
mentioning earlier you know I am NOT
attempting to analyze images doesn't
Google have to do all this I mean
PageRank link link scoring I mean this
isn't a this isn't a abstract problem
people are working on this and there are
a lot of interesting solutions to it I
had to choose a very simple solution
because you know if I had been able to
choose the Google solution I would be
making billions of dollars and I'm not
so I came up with something a little
easier what I did is I would score a
link based on a numerous factors and
basically the link score would be
calculated and it would kind of give me
a for lack of a better term popularity
rating for that link it would tell me
you know how likely the user would be to
click on it does it contain emphasis
these are the things i was mentioning
earlier what's the length of the links
text both words sighs and word count
matter so if you've got if there's a
link that just says download my latest
project here and here is the link and
that's the only word in the link you're
less likely to click on that instead of
download late download the latest
version if that was the link and that
was all underlined simply larger it
contains more information I also tried
to rate the goodness or badness of the
words inside the link so good words
would be things like new main update
cell by free porn stuff like that and
I've got a list and you could tweak it
so every time I'd see a good word up the
link score every time I see a bad word
you know who reads the copyright
statement or the legal statement or the
privacy policy on a website nobody reads
it so I had you know about things like
that no one ever clicks on those links
and so a covert crawler shouldn't click
on those links because
trying to replicate a human so I would
decrement a link score if I saw those
words also if the image is a link or
excuse me if the link is an image what I
would do is I would say all right well
what's the length and width of this
image let me take the length of this
woman's figure out what the area of it
is and what percentage is this area of
their entire screen size let's assume
you are using a 1024 x 768 screen if
I've got a image that's 400 x 200 that's
a pretty damn big picture relative to
the entire screen real estate did you
have a question it's possible you have
to understand i'll get to it when i talk
about spreading the crawler the way the
covert crawler works is there a bunch of
threads and the threads pretty much try
to pick the most popular links and visit
those first but every now and then I
will promote an unpopular link to make
sure I exhaustively crawl the entire
website but there's overlap like if I've
got 10 crawl threads all 10 of those
will request the most popular page on
the site because it would look
suspicious if they didn't but maybe only
one of them or one out of every hundred
will actually request you know the legal
policy or something like that because
who knows maybe there's a sequel
injectable form on the legal policy that
would be pretty funny considering it's
the legal policy yes
yes trying to I try to I I looked doing
that and it's certainly something you
could do I try to make a completely
self-contained solution that way I'm not
dependent on say some third party to
give me information now I do when we get
to throttling i did use google to try to
determine the size of the site i use
netcraft alexia some of these are people
to try to determine how popular site is
because if you own you've got a
geocities page that only gets a hundred
hit today you know if you suddenly get a
thousand hits a day but they're coming
from a hundred different people
scattered across the globe now looks a
little weird so but we'll get to that a
little bit also if there's an alt text
associated with the image I do the
traditional link scoring image on that
so this is kind of abstract let's
actually show an example this is a Riley
calm and sure enough you're seeing there
was a link to a rom-com which contained
an image so it got plus 5 and also the
image area gave it + 57 popularity
points this one was a link for actually
a book we'll see and it had you know
image bonus it contained the word shop
and hot so it got plus words you know
right here we see a word punishment
there was a jobs daughter Riley calm
obviously if you're curling you know
monster or something like that you'll
want to take jobs out of the bad word
list but typically most people don't
click on that little jobs link at the
bottom you know your mileage may vary
and here we see a sorted list of the
links it found in the scores and we see
things like it's kind of hard to see
events I'll show you this on the next
page there's a riot event this Safari
that's a book that they're premiering
O'Reilly and actually kind of sucks
there's a rally com change their web
layout like a month ago but this Oh
Riley calm a link to arrive calm that
big image at the top that said O'Reilly
was just simply a link to the homepage
and sure enough we see it here is the
emerging technology conference which had
this the image and this text is all for
the emerging technology conference that
was that little thing we saw four events
daughter Riley and actually it was this
book right here for Safari that came up
pretty high because it's got a picture
and an extremely long number of words so
those links you know obviously this
allow a comm link came up so
like what we saw in the previous picture
all kind of the the links we had a gut
feel that it would seem like people
clicked on this algorithm does a good
job is actually ordering those as
popular links yes now that's very
interesting i'm about to talk about that
position in HTML is not a good indicator
and i thought it would be and the reason
is this you know it's it's not stupid
it's very good but this this mentality
of we need to get away from everything
that was bad with HTML from 1997 and
separate content from presentation the
structure of the site should be
different from the content of the site
how we present the site if you guys ever
been to CSS zen garden awesome sights
you perfect example separating content
from presentation well because you're
separating content from presentation
you're using absolutely positioned div
tags you're doing all sorts of stuff so
just because a link appears in the top
of the actual HTML file has no bearing
on where it will actually be rendered on
the page that's complex i mean i could
write like is that style shell that's
another thing I I could write something
actually interpret style sheets and
tries to actually render HTML but again
really complicated and frankly I'm lazy
so didn't get around to it style sheets
also can make emphasis detection rather
difficult you know you can just you can
declare this you know I'm going to say
that this is you know a a heading 6 tag
and h6 which is a pretty wimpy tag when
it comes to how it's actually rendered
but you know I could style that so it's
big freakin flashing red letters and I
can declare that style multiple places
you know in line I can I can have an
external style sheet I can declare top
of the page I can you know have a style
attribute on that one particular tag
worse browsers are really bad at
forgiving badly formatted cascading
style sheets back when I gave the
presentation at orochon on fishing I had
to actually write a HTML parser in Java
which is not it's great if people are
following a standard but malformed HTML
is really freaking hard to parse and
parsing cascading style sheets because
it can be malformed and browsers are
still deal with it is not trivial either
and again lazy
Oh like I said you can do it in line
also bad words are relatively static
here's something that I learned you know
regardless of wet website you're
visiting hardly anyone reads privacy
HTML so you know some of the things like
I said you might have to remove jobs or
insert hardware porn into your good word
list something like that good words can
vary from site to site so you gotta
tweak those and also you don't want to
score links whose target is a current
page this was kind of interesting
O'Reilly actually their new web design
it's a good example a lot of times
people have like a bunch of tabs amazon
used to have this now they've got like
three tags but they used to have like 50
tags across the top of the page you guys
remember that like books electronics all
that junk typically the page are
currently on if they have that type of
layout that tab will be bolded it will
be larger than the other showing oh
you're currently at this page well
obviously if you're currently at that
page you know you you need to say all
right well if I see a link if i have a
link whose target is the current page
don't bother scoring it because chances
are it's artificially emphasized to try
to show the user hey this is the pager
on also a table of contents style uh
linked lists or hard to you oh yes so
that was the other thing the o'reilly
page we had that table of style table of
contents down the right side it was a
bunch of links but they were all very
small and not very long and so having to
deal with table of contents all those
links didn't score as high as say the
you know the picture for attack or the
safari links and things like that even
though it's a table of contents and it's
very likely a user will immediately go
to the table of contents simply because
they tend to be smaller so i never
really came up with a good way of
dealing with table of contents style
linked lists so um are you guys good am
i boring i can't tell feedback are we
good enjoy it all right fantastic i I
see that a give me the thumbs up and I
know you're a hard man please so all
right so most people what I went ahead
to do how the Cobra crawler works is I
used a priority queue of pending links
instead of a regular cue and the
priority queue was sorted so that you
know the lower your link score was the
farther down the queue you would be so
technically
whatever link is at the top of the queue
is the most popular link that I haven't
visited yet and so when inserting into
the queue the first thing I do is check
to see if it exists if so I some the
link score of the what I found what I
want to insert and what's already there
now it's interesting this is something
else I learned I originally thought I'd
just average them but that actually
hurts it because consider if I had on
one page a very big image so it had a
very high popularity score linking to
say you know shop here calm and then I
and that had a link score of say 100 and
then on another page I found a link to
shop and that was just a small little
text word that said shop and that had a
popularity score of like 10 well if I
average them I'm actually losing the
overall popularity of the link so you
have to sum them all so the the issues
of link equality with multiple threads
was interesting you know when you start
getting lots of URLs have the same
popularity score how do you make a
decision and we'll talk about that in a
little bit so as I said the front of the
queue is always the most popular link
that the crawler has seen but we haven't
visited yet so acting like a human well
a human needs time to process what the
browser presents so each crawling threat
of the covert crawler must wait a
certain amount of time before it
requests a new page I mean if I'm
requesting a million a second or you
know more realistically ten pages a
second no human is going to be
requesting Ten HTML pages a second
unless you you know like open up a tab
bookmark or something in Firefox but you
most like we don't have ten bookmarks
all of the same you know website unless
you hear bookmarking your hard butter
porn George I don't know so obviously
each crawling thread has to wait and now
this is interesting I weight based on
the action the size of the rendered
content so what I do is I take the HTML
page I strip out all the tags and I say
how much content is actually here being
presented ignoring images which of
course could be huge and I just wait and
I say well how how quickly can most
people read in terms of words a second
and so that's how long I wait for all so
I figured this all out by using by
visiting netcraft and reading some
interesting stuff on search engine
optimization about how long an average
user will read a particular HTML page so
actually you can quick these up because
most people are very click on over
not what I want close click so people do
navigate pretty quickly but you know
it's certainly not 10 requests a second
quickly also this is pretty cool I gave
the different threads personalities I
would i would keep track of all the HTML
pages i visited and I'd keep a word
count and I would determine I would try
to deduce what is this page about this
page seems to be about apple or this
page seems to be about Intel or
something like that and so I would give
each crawler a of the most popular words
I found on that site I would give each
crawler threat as i spawned it out the
keyword hey if you see if you see a page
that contains apple or firewire you're
going to spend longer time reading that
because you crawler thread you're going
to pretend to be an apple fanatic or
something like that so the crawler will
actually throttle itself and the
different threads will react differently
to the same page again just trying to
throw entropy in it to make it all
harder for the people looking at the
logs so obviously on pages that have
keywords I look longer other pages I
quick leave it leave those pages because
that crawl threads not interested in
those all right anybody have any
questions we're good so far this was
going to get kind of complicated kind of
quickly so I warn you in advance
hopefully the graphs will help clear
things up but this is how you actually
spread a crawl over multiple IPS but
also maintain things like session state
and cookies and it gets kind of nasty
yes
okay their ways of what I mean you could
just say here is the page what you could
do is say here are the pages that's
interesting I don't have a mechanism in
it currently to do that but what you
could do is say look here's the site
I've already crawled it before so I have
a is let me bookmark these pages now
when now you know on a weekly basis i
want you to covertly crawl this website
but once you've hit these pages you can
stop so it will say you're only
interested in 10 pages well the covert
crawler on whole probably request
something like 70 or 80 pages but the
rest of that's just noise all you're
really interested in are those 10 with
it gets those tens it'll throttle all
the other threads down that'd be a cool
feature that's certainly doable it
doesn't currently exist but yeah you
could do that so obviously we're going
to be leveraging open proxies we have to
spread this across multiple IPS and the
last time I checked I didn't have a
Class A so I had to go find people's
open proxies this is a possible weakness
of the covert crawler surely funny
there's a guide spy dynamics named Aaron
and he developed a tool called log alert
which was long before I got to the
company you could basically feed it a
server log and it would try to tell you
crazy stuff was happening like a lot of
requests for resources without a request
for the HTML page that links to those
resources things like that and it would
actually try to find out whether you
were being recon door not and so he and
I kind of went through a good to weak
cold war where he'd said like well I'll
do this and I'd go home buttering a
damned air and fire and I'll come back
the next day go over the whiteboard and
big smile on my face be like ha what
about this and he'd you know a lot of
back and forth and basically the only
thing we were able to deduce with the
final design of covert crawler was the
weakness of using open proxies the
witness of Cobra crawler is were using
we're leaving the IP addresses of known
proxies in the server logs and so that
was one of the things that his tool
would do is it would take the IP
addresses and then check a couple of the
known websites that list proxies and see
if someone was visiting you through a
proxy also the choice of proxies is very
important here you know obviously if
we're crawling a US bank looking for
vulnerabilities we only want to use
proxies in the US possibly some from
Western Europe there's a wonderful thing
called IP to country it's a giant
freaking
comma separated value file that gives
you basically IP number ranges and the
resulting country and so I use that but
obviously you want to minimize the
number of proxies that announce their
proxies normally when you send an HTTP
request through an open proxy it sticks
all sorts of HTTP headers in there you
know via max forwarded for max forwards
I mean all this stuff that you don't
want the resulting site to know your
proxy so I would I actually built a
little app that would grab a list of
proxies and Oh basically connect back to
itself through a proxy and look at the
HTTP headers and kind of rate you know
whether it's passing whether it's
announcing it's a proxy or not also
sometimes it's not so bad to admit
you're a proxy I mean the end to end
Internet as we know it is doesn't exist
anymore I mean NAT proxies these are
commonplace and so it actually would
look a little suspicious if all of my
traffic never came from a proxy so
sometimes using a proxy that announces
its a proxy with HTTP headers isn't such
a big deal so one of the big things I
noticed pretty early on when you've got
multiple threads all working together
you have whether it's called the deep
link problem basically I've got to crawl
threads and here's a very simple website
and I've already visited these sites
blue is already visited these sites and
so I go ahead and I want to spawn
another crawl thread and in my queue of
stuff to crawl i still have c and d and
f well if i just out of the blue send a
request for f from this crawl thread
it's going to be like where the hell
that come from because really users
navigate to deep linked web pages in
three ways they navigated there by
clicking through a series of other pages
they bookmark the page in which case
your HTTP requests won't have a referer
header or they followed a link from a
search engine or something directly deep
into your page in which case you'll have
a refer from a search engine so
obviously I can't replicate a bookmark
this is also you know this is very much
not the norm most people don't bookmark
deep parts of your site that happened to
talk about a particular product so for
the most part I couldn't use that I
mainly had to focus on navigating to a
page from other internal pages and also
some doing some fun search engine
spoofing stuff which I'll talk about men
so if green wants to make a request I'm
spawning a new thread and I want to make
a request for F green has to first make
a request for that that that and then F
to try to hide the fact and that's
that's when I start saying the covert
crawler starts making lots of requests
it doesn't have to make because it's
trying to mask what it's really
accessing so obviously green requests a
page has never seen that's a problem so
like I said I p is that make requests
out of blue look suspicious the covert
crawler never makes a deep link request
from an IP address that has no business
making that request so what we do is
instead of telling our crawl threads
traditionally the way a multi-threaded
crawler will work you'll have a control
program and it will simply tell a thread
don't make a request for this URL and
then the crawl thread will make a
request for that URL well shit we can't
do that so what we do instead is we say
go get this URL I don't care what you
have to do to get it but ultimately I
want you to get the contents of this URL
and the way we have the crawler the each
curl thread know how to do that is we
keep a shared graph that represents the
entire website you know this is where
some of that Google knowledge comes in I
mean Google said ah the Internet it's
really just a bunch of nodes and each
node has a link to other nodes which is
an edge and a graph and graph theory is
very well defined there are algorithms
that let you find the shortest distance
between one node and another and so we
think of this as a graph problem it
really becomes simple basically all the
edges are unidirectional there are
cycles you know page a complete to page
B which points to page see which points
back to page a each node is an HTML page
and each edge is a hyperlink so what
we're doing here is the crawl thread
knows its current location and it knows
the content of all the pages it's
visited and so it used basically when
the crow thread is told hey go to this
URL it consults the graph and says hey
graph I'm here find me a path to this
URL and then it goes ahead and makes the
request for the pages along the way and
so it gets the desired resource so like
right here if green and blue are my
crawl threads and green is at E Green is
right or blue is right here and green is
that
a and I've told to go get F green goes
green is told to go get out so green
consults the graph and finds that the
shortest path to f is going BEF and so
it goes ahead and makes a request for
being even though we've already
requested it with this other crawl
thread in terms of our grand scheme of
things we already know the content of
that page but we go ahead and make the
request anyway so we request be e and
then we'd crust f so we made to request
we didn't even have to make just to try
to mask what we were really interested
in so as I said the key here is to use a
shared graph solely for finding the path
to the links but you still have to keep
session state on each you are on each
crawl thread you know if I give a cookie
to this crawl thread that cookie can
never be shared with other crawl threats
the way we do this to finding paths
through the graph is we use a modified
breadth-first search to find paths
inside a graph that getting too
complicated you you know typical if
anyone has the MIT white book there's a
lot of stuff in here on this but
normally you use either a stacker or
queue to find paths through a graph and
the thing is that that always gives you
the shortest path and so I determined
well you know possibly someone analyzing
logs could say hmm this crawler thread
always seems to find the shortest path
between this HTML page and this as to
HTML page let's say to go from you know
main dot HTML to porn dot HTML there's a
really long length through like 10 pages
to get there or there happens to be one
link in the bottom of that legal policy
because nobody ever reads that you know
we don't want it to take the shortest
path we want it to take a reasonable
path and so what we do is we use a
random collection instead of a queue or
a stack so we actually just say stick
nodes in pull them out and this actually
gives us a reasonably short but kind of
random path through the website so if
I'm here I will kind of and I want to go
all the way over here I'll kind of fine
just it's not short not too long a path
to get me there so since the graph is
unidirectional it's possible there isn't
a path from where the crawling thread
currently is the destination but
remember our crawling thread is acting
like a browser which has a back button
so what it does is it says let me go
back let's go ahead and say that
there wasn't a link from A to B and
green was at a well green can always hit
a back button and when I go here and I
don't rearick West the route I would
respect all my stuff that's been in the
cash I would send maybe conditional gets
to see if I need to make this request
again then green would send a request
for be e f so you can implement a back
button so alright so moving along uh
anyone have any questions on that we
good yes you cross-eyed once across I
want to store that the graphic used for
all of this website what is still
detectable as I he needs as you need to
get that side everyday randomly create
ass based on that graph you already have
set you can do that yeah i was using
this as a initial one shot
reconnaissance you can obviously
optimize this if you're only interested
in certain pages you can basically say
i've already got a graph i already know
the link structure of the site find me a
random path from the main page to the
ten pages i'm interested in spoiled
spawn ten maybe actually spawn 15 crawl
threads that way they overlap a little
bit and these 15 threads get me those
ten pages using random paths and do that
on a scheduled basis yeah you wouldn't
necessarily have to do the entire thing
i was mainly focusing on let's do an
exhaustive analysis of their entire page
but if you want to do you know
repetitive stuff you could obviously
optimize it and by else we're doing okay
on time i know there's a break after
this but i will i will hopefully not go
more than same like five minutes into
that because you all want cookies and
milk and other fun stuff so HTTP is
stateless in case you didn't get the
memo which means that web apps have to
keep state using other mechanisms mainly
cookies and sometimes in url session
state in url session state is when you
see something like this for sites that
don't have their cookies turned on so we
must ensure that session state
associated with one crawl thread that
found a link doesn't get rep doesn't get
resent by another crawl obviously since
the crawling threads don't share cookies
we're okay there the cookie that this
girl thread finds never is going to be
resent by this one because they're
keeping their own cookie
just like a normal browser would however
crawling threads that have or when
there's in url session state that's a
problem because this crawl thread finds
this link and the link contains this
session state I need a mechanism of one
crawl thread going oh I need to go to
this page but I can't use their in url
session state I have to use my in url
session state don't worry if this sounds
confusing because it's it is and it's
easier to see with an example just know
that again the graph and the paths
through the graph is what helps us here
since a crawler never directly jumps to
a target page but instead follows the
path to get to that page we will find
our URL session state along the way and
you really need to see an example for
this so let's go ahead and say that
we've got you know the same website
again and that blue has visited the root
C and E and green hasn't even done
anything and so my list of pending links
that I still need to visit our be F a
and actually d but DS not popular so we
don't care about it so the graphs nodes
as I said in this in this in this graph
when each node is a URL the URL that's
for you know say oh never mind green is
spawned and told to go to be so be
because that's at the front of our queue
that will be we would visit we already
know what the URL for B would be we
haven't necessarily visited it yet but
we do know that we need to we know what
the URL for it is however the URL for be
that we know about it's polluted with
the session state from blue so if green
makes a request for it it's going to be
using blue session state and that's
going to be corruptible and you're going
to be able to tell that the two threads
are collaborating so what we do instead
is we go ahead and we spawn green and we
tell green hey go to be so green goes
ahead and it looks at this entire graph
and so soon well to get to be I make a
request for the root and then I'm a
request for being so green goes ahead
and makes a request for the root which
obviously has not yet been polluted
because the the root is you know like
oreilly com / index dot HTML it's known
that is not polluted but all these other
pages are polluted
so what happens is is that green makes
the request for the root and it gets it
now Green knows that the root is going
to have some link to be and it knows
what be looks like that when it's
polluted so what great but like we said
it knows what the link to be looks like
but that link that it knows about
contains be or it contains blues session
state so what green does is it looks at
its copy of the root and says find me
all the links that have the same it
basically dips the links it says I'm
looking for a link to be hey all the
links that are on this page finds me the
link that most closely resembles the URL
I know about and the difference between
those links will be the in url session
state got it good all right so we scan
all the links we go ahead and green
looks at a diff of the links finds the
link to be for that will contain its
session state beat our green can now
make a direct request for be and it will
contain green session state and so we
have solved the session state problem
doesn't coming for X and say oh I know
that the session state is going to be
you know variable best idea so I'll this
you you could I mean all that really
would do remember the crawl threads it's
not like we're doing a special case of
find a path through the nodes because we
always have to find the path to get
there so all that really would do is
reduce the amount of time it would take
you to you know do a diff of all the
links and we're having to throttle
ourselves to be acting like a human
anyway so it's like you could you could
optimize it but all you're really doing
is you know you know increasing the
amount of time your cpu's just going to
sit there being idle before it has to
make the next page so some beautiful
thing about this it it works so well
with my laziness because it's supposed
to be lazy because of its a quick it
won't look like a human so it worked out
well for me uh anyway this is i'm
showing how if green wanted to go to f
it can just keep going along the way
finding its session state you know
basically if you
guys got the whole thing about dipping
it you've got this concept so the the
conclusion about path to pages is that
any link mmm well never buy this all
right so crawl threads the big thing
here is that crawling threads have to
overlap right if I've got if you've got
a hundred pages and I spun ten Carl
threads and each crawl thread only gets
ten pages and they're never the same
pages that another thread got looks a
little suspicious so there is always
overlap we always use a path to get to
where we're going to help resolve the
session state issues and really it's the
only way to make it appear as if there's
actually a separate user on each
separate IP it's really the only way to
make it look like no one is
collaborating with anyone yes well that
was great than my prop my company had
wrote a tool to do exactly what I'm
trying to be they will simply I actually
deliberately didn't look at log alert
source code because I didn't want to
know how it worked I simply ask Darren
what does it look for and then try to
counteract everything it would look for
but it's my understanding it would what
it would look for is let me find groups
of requests that even though they're
coming from multiple IPS in terms of
time they occurred at the same time all
right well let's look at what pages were
request by the supposedly different IPS
and see whether the request seemed to be
coordinated in any way like is there any
overlap and their requests are they
hitting completely different thing are
they hitting it would keep track of what
the popular pages are are these things
hitting the popular pages they're not
that's kind of weird it would look at
you know hey what's this IP addresses in
an open proxy are all these IP addresses
maybe they're different ip's but they're
in the same block owned by the same
company things like that so just really
quick alternative with paths the pages
as we said the other way someone can get
to a deep linked page is through a
search engine so what i could do is the
covert crawler can create fake google
refers and directly jump to a page so
let me just show you real quick ignore
all that text let's say I want
make a request for F and sure I could
spawn green and have it you know take
maybe this path or maybe this path or
you know whatever I could do that but
that means I'm sending a lot of quests I
don't have to what I could do since I've
gotten I've already gotten II I know
about F oh and one thing if you guys
haven't been able to tell the leaks on
your graph those are pages we haven't
visited yet because if we visited them
we know there are links off of them
presumably and obviously it wouldn't be
a leaf node so if we want to go get F we
don't know the contents of that but we
know it exists we do know the contents
of e so we just do that modified looking
for key words we say hey let's do a
keyword word count find out what e seems
to be about great now let's make let's
have green make a request for paigey and
send its referer header to look like
it's being sent from a Google query so
we'd say Google query com you know the
keyword that we've associated is with E
and so basically out of nowhere II would
make a deep link require green would
make a deep link request for e using a
fake google refer and then proceed to
make a then proceed to make a request
for f so that's a way you can kind of
get around having to make a lot of
requests you don't have to so real quick
some throttling issues we need some
mechanism to determine how popular site
is because you know if you get a hundred
people a day obviously we don't want to
be hitting you with thousands of
requests so you know there's this fun
thing called the IP fragment ID which vo
door talked about and how to own a
continent basically a mechanism of
determining how many people are
connected to a server based on the IP
fragment ID that's returned if you're
using say H ping or something like that
we can do a who is to find out how old
the site is we can use archives or to
find out how often it's updated excuse
me we can use Google to find the number
of inbound links you know you can always
say hey show me the pages that link to
you know to work on org we can find not
that I'm advocating you guys covertly
crawl to work on door to exploit them
you know we can use Google to find out
what the size of it is we can use Alexa
or other services to find out popularity
this is all really kind of a pain in the
ass first of all who is there's no
standard about how the information of
who is is returned you know this this is
really fuzzy and nasty and you know I'm
still refining it
works in kind of doesn't one thing is
traffic escalation now this is just fun
so this is I mean a site receives an
order of magnitude more traffic than
normal if say it's got linked to from a
big news story or blog have you ever
been slashed on it I run a magistrate
project called strike snoop and I got
slashed out at once a night this were
the page views very on early in the
project and then I got slashed on it and
that was like in one day I mean holy
shit so you know obviously if I could
escalate the traffic of a site I could
kind of hide a covert crawl inside the
buzz of all these you know people from
slashdot that are coming so you know
obviously should do we still need to be
covert you know if we focus on
throttling to crawl back to match the
site's traffic patterns but if it's
getting flooded with far more traffic
than normally gets those traffic
patterns aren't relevant we can increase
the speed of the crawler we can increase
the number of crawl threads that are
appearing to be users we can do all
sorts of stuff and increase the number
of pages each crawl thread visits there
are lots of things we can do I'm getting
to that so so obviously the Cobra method
still need to use just more traffic
doesn't negate having to emulate a
browser or intelligently follow links I
mean we can't suddenly unleash a breath
fridge crawler just because I happen to
slashdot you but you know we we
certainly can increase the speed and
this is certainly helpful well how do
you predict a flood I mean how do you
know a sites going to get traffic
escalated well you know you can ask why
traffic escalation happens it tends to
happen if a link appears on a popular
site to a relatively less popular site
escalating the traffic so a major news
site or a blog has an RSS feed you know
thousands of people are reading in the
suddenly say hey here's a really cool
link go check this out or goes out on a
mailing list so you know I wrote a very
simple agent that subscribed to a bunch
of RSS feeds from major news sites and
what I would do is I would scan the
stories for links and then I would check
google and alexa and try to determine
what the popularity of that site was and
I just kind of had a rough
okay if it's a pretty unpopular site
chances are they're about to get pretty
heavily assaulted by traffic assuming
it's interesting though this is not very
good and it was kind of a crappy tool
but it worked it did a pretty good job
of kind of saying wow this is about to
happen now the only problem is is that
you know my my tool got the RSS feed
when the thousands of other people got
the RSS feed so it's like it wasn't so
much a predictor of track of traffic
excavation it was more of holy shit
traffic excavation is happening right
now and also it didn't let you pick who
you wanted to crawl it just kind of said
hey these people are about to get
escalated or are being escalated do you
want to you know you should probably
curl them if you feel like it well how
can you cause traffic excavation
sometimes traffic floods need a little
bit of a nudge so what I what you
couldn't do is find an interesting site
and some interesting content on the site
you want to crawl and then submit to a
popular news story and see if they pick
it up sometimes you got to blow up the
dam to make it flood and the way I would
blow up the dam is find across site
scripting vulnerability in a major news
site like CNN com because there are a
lot of them and then cross site
scripting exploits are everywhere and
you just do a very simple one that
allows you to reflect something into a
link so i can send you a link and when
you click on it not that I've polluted
the backend database but simply the URL
itself has something that's reflected
back into the page and almost always I
reflect back into the page a little
block of script which accesses another
site and on that other site I'm
containing the content of the story I
want to have so I quickly you know whip
up an inflammatory article you know Bill
Gates sucks it or something like that
and see how is the suck and then I
submit it and I sit back and I watch the
flood happen as you know thousands of
people like whoa no I seem to think that
he sucks it only in this way and not in
the way you said
you know I mean come on if there's
anything that slashed on nerves love to
talk about it's what way things suck in
to what degree things suck so you know
you just kind of play with them a little
bit so yeah escalating of trap or you
know intentionally causing a traffic
exhalation is fun all right so real
quick implementation of a covert crawler
so I wrote this thing in Java it
emulates a windows XP civ respect to IE
browser that has javascript turned on
but Java turned off and doesn't have a
flash parser yeah exactly except for
render is much better I don't even have
a visual interface and it probably
renders much pathetic-er I this is a
funny side story so I actually met a
couple people from the IE 17 and I had a
lot to drink they came down for this
thing in Atlanta called sip which is
like security industry professionals but
really it's ship as in take a sip
because if we hold it a bar each month
and it's really just people in Atlanta
who are in the security industry
drinking and I'm pretty sure I told them
he deserved a kick in the nuts for for
IE cuz i was like you guys disbanded the
IE division and it's only because of
firefox you guys even exist anymore and
this was a big guy but it luckily he
agreed with me he's like no you're right
we it was our bad so anyway i use link
scoring two are you scoring to make link
decisions multiple threads right across
multiple IPS i use a graph I I create a
graph of the site and I used a modified
breadth-first search of the node to find
random but reasonably short paths from
any one node to another node the session
state issues are resolved because I
don't share cookies and I dip the URLs
to avoid in url session state issues i
use personalities to determine how long
a page should be viewed and also that
kind of ties into the key words of the
link scoring source code should be
really soon I kind of was doing this on
the side I have a really fun position at
spy they're just like think stuff up and
they're like having to be web stuff but
it really is kind of a blank check to do
it interesting web based research I want
and so I did this and I kind of said hey
you know I'm going up to this thing in
Atlanta called shmoocon and the vp of
engineering is like shmoo what
hell is he didn't know what that was
beetle he thought it was a noise you
made while you were starving out so I
had to explain and actually really funny
he went to the school called website and
I guess maybe he didn't have his glasses
are something he thought the shmoocon
logo with like the the shades was
actually a woman's a woman's chest like
it was a chick like it was a chick
wearing like a black bikini in a white
belly and like cuz you got the nose for
the shmoo thing it was like the belly
button he's like there's a chicken a
bikini I'm like no that's like this
moose steal shit I don't know what it is
it's the shmoo so I had to after
explaining to them what shmoocon was
like yeah sure and then I demoed this
presentation and I actually showed them
the covert crawler they're like holy
shit you can't release the source code
to that I was like oh man so I'm working
with them on them I'd say you got
probably a 70-30 chance thirty percent
chance they'll actually let me end up
releasing the code but luckily I
basically told you how to write your own
I mean seriously it's not that
complicated if you buy me a beer
afterwards I'll totally spilled my guts
so you're are you still filming this by
the way you can blow that right all
right all right so anyway final thoughts
cuz I've been keeping you here real
quick sanity checks you brought this up
someone doesn't have to crawl the entire
site just the interesting stuff to learn
the methodology that's totally wrong I
don't know why I said it was only two
hundred thousand pages because I just
did a crawl of them last week and it's
eight hundred thousand-plus but CNN has
all those pages right well they're
really only a few interesting things a
stock ticker a story content system
email alerts search engine a malicious
user really only needs a few samples of
each to go home you know what there are
some interesting things here I see that
there's a page here called you know air
dot PHP or something and it takes in its
query string air equals you know could
not find a page you were found I wonder
if that that string of texts could not
find the page you requested is ever
reflected back into the page if that's
cross-site scripting or you know I see a
page called story dot PHP and in it
squaring is ID equals and it's always an
integer and it's never negative and it's
never larger than
four billion I wonder if that's a
primary key in the database so you know
you can normally by applying a little
bit of logic you can pretty much quickly
figure out where the parts of the site
are vulnerable and you may not need to
grab everything and that gets into the
exhaustive search versus intelligent
search so yes how so like oh oh no I
probably should have I probably should
have had some mechanism with like hack
ability like this page has you know form
inputs and contains query data and it's
actually not a bad idea you get schwag
you can have anything you want actually
I have been giving out schwag you guys
just take this stuff it's good but you
know beetle you guys do good work but I
don't really have a use for this and
it's they work so hard I couldn't throw
it away so if you've got here yeah it's
which which I but the funny thing with
my bosses I have no idea what he thought
these whiskers were whoa go so everyone
come up for their swag I'm not going to
do that again so in summary crawlers can
be programmed to send requests just like
a browser does crawlers can make
intelligent choices about what links
they should follow that mimics human
behavior to some extent covert crawlers
can be spilled across multiple threads
and IPS without revealing that there's a
mass crawl going on that all these guys
are collaborating session state can be
handled you know so that's not an issue
throttling is tricky still working on it
but it can be done you know increases in
traffic can hide any mistakes I happen
to make in my algorithm because you know
if you've got a hundred thousand people
visiting you or whatever it doesn't
really matter that I might have had a
little problem algorithm one second a
proxy selection is a possible weakness
in the system but it can be mitigated by
trying to pick intelligent proxies you
know if I'm crawling a bank from North
Korea that's pretty big red flare right
there so what you should take away from
all this you can't rely on your web
server logs you really can't because you
know you can't rely on them to tell you
where they're being scoped out as a
target simply by looking at traffic
volume you can rely on your logs to see
if an attack happened because you know
you can always see that holy shit the
web server did actually receive you know
a sequel injection attack but you can't
use it to find to tell you whether a
single users routinely grabbing large
portions of your website and you can't
use it to reveal who's been testing you
after you discover an attack trying to
find that reconnaissance because we can
hide that and laws are simply logs are
simply a passive defense and you need to
stop being passive so the funny thing
about this is if you fix your web
vulnerability it doesn't matter if they
covert call you because you're not
single injectable because you have a new
user reg is used parameterised queries
instead of concatenated strings together
with user input to create a sequel query
I mean there are ways you can mitigate
this stuff you can't make so you can't
protect prevent someone from covertly
crawling you but you can certainly make
the fruit of that covert crawl worthless
so anybody have any questions yes no I'm
gonna hold this till the end and if
you're very good yes uh I just kind of I
could tell you some super-secret
scientific method but I just kind of SAT
around drinking one night thinking of
what are fun words I like to click on
like xxx and porn or something like that
you can pull meta tags out to use a to
pull out the keywords but I mean I guess
I could do that to the have it like have
it like a feedback to dynamically change
what are good and bad words right that's
not a bad idea yes the lady in that
please do I would be interesting to find
out how you can use a covert crawler for
anything I have to quote the simpsons
and professor frink when he says well to
be honest the Ray only has evil
implication if you could think of a way
that it could do good more power to you
but I didn't bother
you people write better code yeah right
there he took care of it for you there
are lots of hands I think you had your
hand yes certainly you could um but you
know I beat you again they could just go
yeah they could go to see a flight if
it's actually on slashdot I mean they're
certainly I didn't cover everything you
could do that's not a bad idea either I
like that you can get swag yes it is not
necessarily the crawling parks but the
score in the park yeah hopefully you get
it up I want to take that piece and use
it on our website for marketing
department so they can understand how
the interface is crappy it make you
better that actually was the kind of a
fun part of this is I got halfway
through it I'm like wow what I'm really
kind of doing is I'm figure I'm trying
to take a site and figure out derive
meaning from it which is exactly what
those slimy search engine optimization
people do and so when i created this you
know here's the here's the graph
representing your website how
interconnected it is you know i can i
can determine metrics like how easy is
it to get from this page to this page
how obvious it how obvious is it to your
users based on the size and presentation
of their links how they navigate I mean
there's certainly other implications and
to be quite frank that's what my company
was most interested in was the link
scoring and the the kind of the using
the graph and determining popularity as
we go I pretty much pulled you dogger
them that I used it's not very complex
and if you give me drink drinks I might
actually show you the chava code it's
it's very trivial if you know go through
a word list if the words there increment
a score and it's pretty simple yes
traxxas really
isn't the easiest way to do so to just
use your next-door neighbors open access
point minus longer probably like uterus
you could but the point of this is I
didn't want them to know something was
imminent everyone does reconnaissance
before they attack and if I suddenly
know that I noticed you know I have a
really anal cyst admin and I have
something email me if when I in a cron
job if a log is too large and I'm
compressing it be like holy crap i just
compressed my log why is today I'm doing
it again let me go investigate I just
wanted to show that you know you you
don't know anything's coming but
certainly you can go to your neighbor's
access point and you know do whatever
you want get your hardware porn or
something yeah I'm going to take like
two more questions and then you eyes
have already been very good sorry
annoyed I don't mean to run over I'll
tell you what I'll do one more question
and then you guys can talk to me
afterwards that's so good who has a very
good question I like heineken alright
that's a good question ok I'm done