alright so my name is Charles edge I
wrote that book that I've handed out
today I'm going to talk about just OS 10
security I guess for the most part this
might be like synonymous with security
44 in OSS or something of that nature
how many people here use OS 10 server
specifically and how many people use OS
10 so in just a couple more right I yeah
I see those velcro da fone closets all
the time these days like where's your
ftp server oh it's right there hey
velcroed that's but whatever works right
I'm not going to play my slideshow if
that's ok I like to do this so i can
switch between apps someone complained
one time than i did that so hopefully
you guys were all right with it and then
before i get started just a note on what
she was talking about before I'm all for
greater transparency at the corporate
level for security and stuff I can't
tell you how many companies I come in to
where if it weren't for socks they'd
still be running smtp open relays and
all kinds of stupid crap and I'm just
totally all for all that stuff so just
on a side note all right so yeah
security through brute force by the
government I guess for lack of a better
word yeah yeah I mean totally no talents
us admins running around deploying
solutions 400,000 users bugs the hell
out of me but I'm all right so Mac os10
server i titled it kind of open source
made easy because that's apples tagline
back in the day OS 9 totally easy kind
of difficult to crack just because no
one ever played with it but now it's
just a standard old next distribution so
anything that works in the next
environment is going to work in OS 10
for the most part if you can get it to
compile so users that require easy
solutions often don't have the skills to
secure their own solutions kind of like
with Microsoft small business server so
whereas Microsoft has for example
deprecated the use of small business
server as a terminal server OS Mac is
there
still you know three or four years
behind Microsoft and a lot of this stuff
and they haven't been started to do
things like that so when they can sense
so far all right and then in users and
the Mac community are pretty resistant
to basic security concepts because they
haven't had to practice those a lot of
times with OS 9 traffic wasn't routable
so people really didn't worry about
securing perimeter and stuff like that
you have a question or no all right all
right so Mac specifics to a standard
nixed distro apples really hardcore
about plist files they really like the
XML format so they've been trying to
convert that CF and dot com files over
to PHP lists they keep everything in a
net info database so whereas you won't
see dot password files or things of that
nature you do see a lot of stuff locked
into the net info database which is kind
of interesting because later down the
road when we start talking about how
they've got openldap built and stuff
like that they they lock all this stuff
in there so that everything is encrypted
at a higher rate and stuff like that so
file system is normally not ufs on a Mac
os10 server is normally OSX extended
which lazarus up in San Francisco can do
a lot of recovery stuff for a little
better than some of the places down here
like drivesavers all the files and apps
are in the wrong place for those of us
who have used Apache for a long time if
you sit down on an OS 10 server you're
going to be like where where's
everything at or pretty much any other
program for that matter that Apple
decides to implement they're really good
about taking code out of the open source
community and they're getting better
about giving code back but they're not
really very good about conforming to
kind of the standards of where we put
things so not that it's very difficult
to find anything with allocate command
or something like that but you know just
a good point to make and then server
manager server and grd is sometimes if
you do at it let's say the httpd.conf
file you're going to notice that like
your timeout value doesn't actual
change so where are you supposed to
actually do that and a lot of times it's
locked inside of net info and rather
than be able to edit some of those
values directly you actually have to use
the server manager demon does that make
sense and then another difference
between the Mac community there's a lot
of GUI tools for pretty much anything
including chmod if you can imagine that
so I'm serious like Mac the Mac
community in fact I haven't installed
here a show but batch mod it's just like
a little you know click for boxes and
there you go so and it even does Rick it
even does recursion for those of you
haven't figured out how to use an R in
your command line segments exactly but
um but but you know with with a lot of
this stuff when it starts to get more
complicated than like a chmod or or
shown like by building these types of
tools with programs like Coco you're
kind of sponsoring the deployment of
them on a wider scale for example I can
deploy hen wen or snort to a client and
they can manage it even if they're not
an IT company because it's got a GUI
front end whereas maybe they wouldn't be
able to if it was a command line only
tool so it's kind of by having GUI apps
for a lot of the security tools that we
use it actually sponsors more Spurs more
in-depth use I guess from the client
side so so entertainment specifics
obviously the mac is pretty heavily used
in the entertainment sphere I kind of
subtitled this slide no they target if
you're doing penetration testing or
security and a Mac environment one of
the biggest things is that a lot of them
are graphics houses where people don't
want to use passwords or in some cases
according to the application sets that
they're using they actually can't use
passwords and things of that nature so
we do a lot of physical subnetting or V
landing to get around some of this stuff
but still it's it's great stuff to know
about the users really aren't used to
even having passwords much less having
to change them on their own every
any days or something that nature so
when you're talking to someone who's
been using computers for 20 years and
never had a password for logging into
their computer it's kind of hard
sometimes to say okay well you need to
change it every 30 days so no one brute
forces that or something of that nature
so especially with those root passwords
I actually had a situation a couple
months ago where a client had their root
password on 20 servers as the word root
which I thought was kind of special and
there's lots of open wireless networks
in the Mac community they can't seem to
remember the passwords to bandy about
and things of that nature if you're
driving through West Hollywood that's
probably one of the easiest places i
would guess around to actually do some
some more driving users often want to
set up their own servers they walk into
the apple store some guy in the apple
store talks me into an xserve they take
it home they still can't figure out why
it's only this big but they put it on
the desk they turn it on they click
start for web server and they put the
files where they go and that's it they
don't do anything else and by default a
lot of I'll cover that later but a lot
of things are enabled that really
shouldn't be they should be explicitly
enabled kind of the way that a lot of
other distributions now are doing it
like selinux so and then I guess for
ldap as well you know any other program
it's just like you click on the start
button and it's suddenly an ftp server
and that that's not always a good thing
you know so AFP specifically most of the
things that that I've written as far as
exploits go target AFP because everyone
else has already done openldap and
everyone else is already done a patchy
so it makes it for in for a little more
groundbreaking or interesting type stuff
although the same principles that apply
to like SMB would apply to AFP AFP is
just what happened to Apple talk and and
it's like Apple talked with multicast
DNS to find other servers and stuff like
that so for those of you haven't used it
AFP by default runs over port 548 so if
you're actually looking for open servers
out there you can just search for you
know do a port scan
4548 AFP had a known vulnerability that
gave a root most of the vulnerabilities
for apple stuff give or just straight do
s attacks specifically there have been
three or four now for AFP that actually
gave route and and that was included in
metasploit last year at Def Con I guess
someone demoed that AFP still has
similar vulnerabilities but because of
the way Apple patches things like that
they just patch the specific buffer they
don't actually bother to figure out why
why the algorithm was able to to do that
if that makes sense so they'll just
patch each specific buffering then the
next one you can always like he was
talking about earlier fuzz it and find
another one that'll kind of do the same
thing so and then one nice thing about
AFP is you can actually run AFP over ssh
it's just a check box they made it nice
and easy to do all you have to do is
check that box and that kind of
mitigates that as a as a possible
exploit so I'm one of the thing like I
mentioned just a second ago Apache with
its mods by default when I okay by
default all these these are the modules
that are enabled I know an OS 10 server
that when you start up apache personally
some of these i I don't I don't think
should be enabled the I I don't know
what what else to say about that except
for I've yet to see someone who set up
an OS 10 server other than myself as a
web server that actually bothered to
disable the module so they weren't using
and a lot of times people will argue
back if I do do it well what if my
developers need to use Jakarta it's like
well then let's install a later version
of Jakarta than the one that Apple
included you know like with something
like if you're installing a centos box
with webmin you want to keep the
everything up to date and you know
that's not always done by Apple's so so
I'm SSI PHP
luckily they didn't enable folder
listings this revision intend to by
default folder listings were enabled on
every directory performance cash has
turned on by default which I personally
find to be quite quite annoying when I
find a server that's been turned into a
fishing server because someone exploited
performance caching on it or something
like that so a lot of these things are
just kind of not to use a buzz word but
best practices you know you turn off
which are not using I personally think
that by default you should be turning on
what you are using rather than turning
off what you're not using but um but the
mice equal distribution and OS 10
servers a little bit old there aren't
any any root attacks for this or
anything like that but there are a lot
of dls attacks every client that I've
worked on so far that uses my sequel
actually also uses PHP my admin and of
those I've only seen maybe two or three
that actually bothered to put a password
on PHP myadmin so if you're trying to
exploit OS 10 server that's always a
pretty easy place to look just because
the users don't understand and they
leave it to the web developers to
actually do both the development and the
security and right yeah putting a yeah
just doing an HT access realm and OS 10
server there's actually a feature called
realm and it'll do all that stuff for
you but I have yet to see ya the Roma I
don't know if I I've got these red dots
so i don't know if it's actually going
to show me but when you go into a site
you can click on realms and then you can
just add e at a realm which is
essentially like a gooey friend and for
HT access it just doesn't use HT access
files yeah exactly um no it's it's it's
not although you know when you are
logging into an htaccess file a lot of
times it does say realm so you know it's
kind of easy to correlate what they do
and I cover it in my book realms
specifically um because a lot of times
clients will will refuse to
troubleshoot with their clients if
they're having ftp issues and you know
ftp behind nat sometimes you have to
step people through enabling or
disabling certain check boxes which are
totally far too difficult to figure out
so every client that used my sequel that
I ran into so far in the field has had
the allowed network connections turned
on only maybe two of them needed it so
that's that's kind of another thing to
look for and then I'm sorry well just
you know with with my sequel you can
disable the ability for any IP other
than localhost yeah so and that in OS 10
you can't see it I can grab the
screenshot and bring it over here but
it's just a check box so all you'd have
to do literally is uncheck the box but
no one actually bothers to so fun stuff
in other words they make it really easy
to do security audits and Mac
environments because it's like okay well
let's figure out why you have 80 open
ports for a web server so post fix the
there's not really much to say here it's
a typical post pics implementation it
does have claimed assess and claim AV
already integrated which makes it kind
of easy you click on start you check a
box and you're you're golden another
nice thing is that they've integrated it
with sasal so your passwords are all
stored and secure hashes which is kind
of kind of nice does anyone here work
for Apple yeah right on shows that they
care a lot about their security last
year or two years ago at Def Con when I
was speaking and asked that no one at
raise their hand either which is always
kind of fun well you know they yeah they
ran out of free iPods to give people so
that they wouldn't get hurt so
ah it was too far flight from cupertino
so samba um it's a slightly older
release of samba it's SMB signings not
supported by apple yet which apparently
they've promised me it's going to be
changed in leopard by default every
every sharepoint you create for like a
FPE or ftp or whatever you're creating
the sharepoint for they enable SMP guest
they are SMB guest access they enable
SMB even if you don't mean to and most
of the Mac administrators that I know
don't think to hit that little drop-down
box right here where it says went
normally that says Apple filing protocol
when you first open it and change it to
windows and see if windows if they're
creating SMB share points and ftp share
points both of which have guessed
enabled so you know you're just kind of
an app and you can disable those
globally and kind of mitigate that but
at the same time you know you don't
really want to be doing that so sorry no
nothing is read only by I mean by
default by default it's read read and
write for owner reading right for user
and then read only for her guests for
everyone yeah so right but but ever
since they integrated ACLs like I've
been seeing a lot of Mac administrators
do some pretty pretty retarded things
with file permissions and they'll add
like the ww user on a on their
executives sharepoint where they're
keeping all their financial data or
something silly like that and you're
like what what were you thinking and
their responses usually nevermind so I'm
for samba they I do think that they've
done some nice things GUI tool wise
although something like webmin is going
to give a few more features they've got
ntlm v2 ntlm and land man all turned on
by default I think that they should just
do maybe ncl m v2 and uncheck the other
two I guess a lot of this is about like
just disabling defaults and the same is
true for a lot of other OSS but like an
Active Directory they've actually gone
the extra step
and pseudo secured the box before you
turn it on you know password policies
are enabled and stuff like that whereas
a macro Austin they haven't really
bothered to do that yet and I put this
down for samba but logging is set to low
by default that's true for every module
on OS 10 server so you actually have to
if you want to get decent logs turn up
the verbosity I guess for lack of a
better word of the the logging and in
some cases there aren't doing tools for
that in some cases there are them and
samba connect an OS 10 server as also
unbekannt i guess but there's GUI tools
to make it just act as a PDC although
there's only like four boxes to fill in
for it so it's not really highly
configurable virtual shares are turned
on by default and every box as a
workgroup master by default so in cups
one one interesting thing when you turn
on the cup server and OS 10 server by
default it turns on the web frontend for
cups and there's no password on it which
was always really nice you know and I
can't remember off the top of my head
does anyone else know the Pat the port
for the for the web frontend for cups
right so if I were to write if I were if
i were to install that right now i guess
you know if i were to turn it on you
guys would just be able to see it but by
default it also listens on all adapters
and the other day i was at a client who
had for some reason they had put an
airport card in their own stun server
and it was their wireless access point
but it was an open wireless access point
so i mean if you can imagine like inside
your server having an open wireless
access point is it's just yeah i mean
the the level of security stuff and is
pretty amazing and the in the
entertainment space i guess as far as
market share goes but it makes my job
pretty easy i think so I chat server
they're definitely using a pretty old
version of ichat or a jabber I don't
know if anyone here is implement a job
or two point oh but there's a whole lot
of new stuff in it and it's much better
and I think they should update it but
like with almost every other service
they have integrated jabber whip
so they just don't turn it on by default
I this is minus this default ssl
certificate is actually something i
changed but by default nearly every
service is SSL integrated they just
haven't turned them on did I say that
already so and there's there's not
really any encryption so i use
personally I'm fire as my jabber client
I don't know if you guys amused that but
as far as Mexico it does does support um
encrypted message traffic so in an open
directory open directory is Apple's kind
of code name for openldap sasal Kerberos
slapd slurpee they kind of just threw
everything that they can find to make it
easy to build something so kind of like
Active Directory together and called it
open directory so so they do all the
integration of that stuff for you so if
you're building like a an ldap server
it's just it's pretty pretty simple and
straightforward all usernames and
passwords are stored in the net info
database and leopard that's going to
change their totally deprecating that
info and they're just going to use sasal
for a lot of other stuff then then they
have been now all usernames and all
policies are disabled by default so by
default there is no lockout on you know
three times when you're out for
passwords and stuff like that which you
know you can enable it but but it
doesn't work for administrative users
which is always kind of kind of nice one
thing I didn't think to put on my AFP
slide there's a checkbox that's enabled
by default for masquerade for AFP and
what that does is it means you can use
any administrative password with any
user name so let's say your user is root
or let's say your your user is Bob you
can use the root password to log in as
Bob so if you if you you know though and
this is on OS 10 server specifically for
AFP SharePoint's so that's always kind
of a fun thing when you know yeah I
guess they put it they put it in there
and take it back out every release or so
so if you're running like 10 36 it might
not be there but if you're running 10 10
3 4
or it will be it's it's like a argument
they have within the development team
for OS 10 server as to whether or not
it's a good idea so Mac admins are lazy
for the most part and they don't well I
mean I guess it's for the administrators
to be able to troubleshoot permission
issues for local for users I'm right
there with you I think they should just
take it out as a feature period even
when it's not listed as a checkbox you
can actually enable using server manager
so but but in 10 46 and is currently
there and and like I said they take it
out sometimes put it back you know it's
it's always and it's under the AFP and
server admin anyone cares so so that's
open directory the next part of open
directory I guess is client management
Apple has implemented kind of Active
Directory style client management using
mcx files and this is always fun to
blast out to a whole group the fact that
their screens do that when they boot up
but but never a good idea so the I guess
this is just indicative of them having
new policies that they're trying to
implement we did this with a couple of
different federal agencies that have it
where no discs can be inserted and
drives and stuff like that rather than
you know put gum in the driver whatever
we we just used use this for for roaming
profiles and stuff one thing that's kind
of nice about this is you can actually
push out File Vault and you can push out
that every time you say empty trash it
does like a secure empty trash or
something of that nature so but I'm but
this does that make sense mcx style
updates for clients you know control the
appearance of clients control the doc
control that they can't put USB flash
drives and their computers or that the
computers won't even boot without you
know going into netboot or something
like that the client management it's in
it's a workgroup manager and it's just
under the Preferences button but the
yeah I mean instead of issuing policies
to clients when they log on us you or
policy files like dat files you're
issuing AMC x-files to control their
environment and you you can customize
the mcx files and say okay well if
you're running Photoshop you don't have
these features or right yep it's exactly
like like policies yeah like windows
style policies I mean it's and you can
actually load mcx files into active
directory if you extend your schema and
had have active directory apply policies
to max using the active directory plugin
on in OS 10 which the active directory
plugin is is really well written i think
almost no active directory
implementation is perfect and so we see
a lot of max falling off because there's
an issue with you know some weird flag
in some weird part of the forest you
know but but overall it's it's pretty
good if it could do anything better I
would say it could be that it would be
more forgiving to active directory if
there's an issue with active directory
for for heterogeneous and our hybrid
environments like that we we do a lot of
what we call the Golden Triangle where
we put an open directory server for an
Active Directory server we bind the two
together and that way for authentication
and authorization they're using Active
Directory but then for password policies
they're using open directory we try to
do that if they're willing to extend
their active directory schema otherwise
we'll just implement an openldap and
maybe pull four or five records from
that some of that nature and hope that
they don't fall off we see a lot of OS
10 servers when they're plugged into
active directory networks that just fall
off and then you have to rebind and in
the process of rebinding then your
clients are active you know um Apple has
a big firm right which you know in
graphics environments that they'll start
crying you know literally I mean graphic
designers or like that they cry at the
drop of a hat yeah it's must come from
living in Santa Monica I live in santa
monica by the way so Ashley I live in
Hollywood no but so DNS you know older
verte you know just to get back real
quick before I move on so using it and a
apple selling OS 10 server from on the
their enterprise group is selling it
pretty heavy to like companies like
Disney and Universal as a replacement
for Windows servers and they're they're
having really good sales and then I
sometimes contract with apple
professional services and go in and fix
the issues that they've they've left me
with from a sales standpoint and you
know they don't support SMB signing as a
file server which is or as a client to
file servers which is pretty huge they
also don't yeah
we're in the man in the middle room
right I mean yeah exactly all windows
file servers by default ship with us and
be signing turned on and if you're in a
star box type environment you want to be
able to share files from the mac side of
the window side you have to get a third
party piece of software like Dave to do
it if that one feature is required if
they would insert that which they say
they're going to do in leopard then that
would remove the need for something like
Dave for the most part so so DNS same
thing most packages that Apple has
implemented in the list and server do
have do s exploits so that's you know
but then again what doesn't right so
this is kind of interesting from a DHCP
standpoint ldap oh open directory can be
settings can be configured to be sent to
clients of the network so clients will
bind automatically to your open
directory environment so you could
theoretically install DHCP on your
laptop go into an apple environment fire
it up and have people binding to your
open directory server on your laptop and
therefore you can implement mcx files
against them things of that nature it's
it's kind of wildly the options that
that are the loopholes or whatever that
they've thrown in there but um but the
one of the ways to get around that is
just to make sure that everything has
sasal turned on or SSL turned on in
there in the OS so firewall in that they
don't use IP tables they don't use IP
chains they use ipfw which is kind of
cool but because it's really easy but
it's a little more limited you can't
block based on a mac address of a client
or something in that nature dummy net
can be used to shape traffic with open
directory you can have an open directory
master in an open directory replicate
kind of like having two active directory
controllers but your open directory
master is always because it's the
password server going to be the primary
server that everybody logs into so if
you want to balance your traffic you
have to use something like dummy net to
do it which can be kind of frustrating
for people who don't know how to open
amlin shell you know because that's only
available through the command line they
do have a you know the ability does to
build rules but the rules are just for
accepting tonight and then they built
this I don't know why they actually
bothered to deploy it because it doesn't
really work right but they built this
s2s bpn program that is supposed to
allow you to build site site VPNs but it
really doesn't work very well well
rather than half I guess the idea was
rather than have to you know install an
ad on one server and install an add on
another and then bridge them that you
would just use estás VPN to
automatically do all that eh it doesn't
support aggressive mode stuff which is
pretty typical amongst most routers but
be it just doesn't the like you give a
hash key give another hash key and it
just doesn't find like it doesn't work
reliably I've made it work and I put it
in my book but I wish I to put a
disclaimer saying you know that it
doesn't really work reliably which which
really and deployment strategy means it
doesn't work right so but but it's still
there and I have a feeling that in the
next version though they'll fix it they
do have a program called the Gateway
setup assistant which will build NAT and
all your IP Ching oh I'm all your ipfw
calm stuff for you and the ipfw stuff
that you can configure from the front
from the GUI is definitely very limited
compared to what you can do with ipfw
calm so the configuration file can do a
whole lot more than the GUI can as in
almost any case right and then they
wrote their own rather than deploy
openvpn they just wrote their own VPN d
that that really has pretty limited
support this is the extent of their
options for it so if you want to do some
some pretty serious VPN stuff you have
to use open VPN which has been compiled
in as easily available through Darwin
points and if you're running an OS 10
box and you're here I'm guessing that
you've heard of
importance but darlin ports is just a
collection of compiled software that
works in Darwin that guys have
contributed so I'm personally a huge fan
of Donovan ports so their ftp
implementation is TN ftp has anyone here
used that every user has to have a shell
account which which isn't true for all
ftp software of course i find this to be
an incredible limitation because every
user in the environment has has a shell
and you can use jails but no one ever
bothers so so in any OS 10 environment
that's that's always kind of a pretty
big issue especially if you're running
an anonymous FTP server because a couple
little lines of code and someone can be
sitting there at the root of your volume
they might not be able to change
anything but they have complete access
so and then rather than use an ftp users
file all the ftp user names and
passwords are stored in that info of
course if guest is enabled then that
really doesn't help you very much but
I'm kind of doing this service by
service is that cool or all right so
quick time streaming um has anyone here
ever tried to intercept streams or do
anything like that not just for quick
time but for real right all that stuff
is pretty freely available for quick
time as well the one nice thing about
about quick time as you can use SSL with
it which can help to mitigate that as a
risk communications between two OS 10
servers running quicktime streaming are
all in clear-text so that's pretty easy
to just sit there where they are with a
hub and TCP dump and the rest is history
and I haven't really given a lot of
thought to different ways to attack
quicktime streaming servers a lot of my
clients use it and I'm kind of afraid
that if I build something that
it'll go bad on me so so frenetic
netboot um netboot is a way to boot your
mac with tea if any of you have ever
accidentally held the Tiki down or not
tea but in the end key down when you
boot your computer it's just it it has a
little network logo where it's spinning
and looking for a net boot image to boot
off of net boot images have to be stored
in either a tftp server or an open AFP
server so no passwords which means that
you can easily download or boot off of
anyone's volume if they're running if
they're running netboot and a lot of
clients that I see actually have netboot
open to the world so even though it
would be very very slow someone could
easily boot off of their server which
you know is probably never a good idea
you can use open directory to kind of
mitigate that so that you know you have
to have a username and password to
actually log into the system but you
know it's still out there and you can
also use file bulb with those to kind of
make things a little more secure in the
OS 10 world bio bolts is just an
encrypted folder that all of your data
from your / users folder let's in so um
don't try to put more than 100 nodes /
xserve on it yeah I wouldn't definitely
not do that I mean you know four gigs of
ram dual core maybe but otherwise
definitely
I use filevault for everything the only
time that I don't use filevault is if
there's an application and compatibility
so that it really doesn't seem to slow
down performance because a lot of this
stuff like if you're in Photoshop you're
you know you know your your swap files
for photoshop or stored outside so the
most of the read and write stuff
entourage works fine and filevault a lot
of the Adobe products don't and that's
that's really you know pretty pretty
heavily deployed in Mac environments so
I like foul ball to let I mean you know
I I don't think i have it turned on in
this laptop because it does seem to slow
it down a little bit but the the big my
big problem with file bolts is that
every now and then it wants to compact
or filevault image you know and then
you're sitting there waiting for two
hours and there's no cancel button on it
so you know it's like and then if you
reboot it it's automatically going to
start doing it again so that yeah so I'm
not a big fan of that personally so
images must be stored on servers with no
security I can't i already mentioned
that but but i mean in school
environments it's i guess it's no big
deal because what's a third grader going
to do but you know when you get to
companies like you have to you just have
to architecture your network around that
concept we were doing some work for a
government agency and they couldn't have
any discs so they had to use file on
they had to use netboot but but they
were physically segmented as to which
image you could boot to and Apple talk
is incredibly bad about hopping across
be lands you know I'm we see it at big
film studios all the time where you may
work for a company who's renting space
and you should be veal and where you
can't see anything else but you do
because there was an update two days ago
to rendezvous and now it Hopsin does
something new that's kind of weird so
so multicast DNS is always fun to play
with but rendezvous seems to go a little
beyond that sometimes anyways so
forensics specific stuff for Mac servers
before you plug a drive in yeah apples
have disc arbitration d running in the
background so if you're going to try to
do forensics on a drive you should
definitely either use a write blocker or
rename this file right here whoops to
rename this file right here to something
like you know dot old and then either
reboot or kill your disc arbitration
demon and that should that should make
it not do that and then you know I guess
last year at Def Con there was someone
giving a talk on secure channels and
using secure channels to trade credit
card information or something a couple
apples specific file types and I guess
not Apple specific anymore because
itunes are so widely spread now but AC
files or definitely have all the same
fields that an mp3 file might for
example so I mean you know I'm not gonna
I'm not here to talk about forensics but
when I have done work like that it's
like the second you plug in a drive to a
Mac it rights to it so that's that's
never that's never a good thing so some
of the tools that we use a lot i
mentioned snort I'll deploy snort pretty
I probably deployed at least once a week
on Apple servers just because no one
else seems to and like I said it's
really easy if you've got you can
download hen wen top version tracker com
it takes about two minutes to install
and you've got a fully functional
version of snort if you want to actually
go further and just use snort from the
command line then Darwin Darwin ports
has it in it as well and you can also
actually CD into the hen wind app and
it's it's located I think two or three
subdirectories under that
so and then in in my book and also i
think on AFP 548 which is a big mac
website I the check boxes that work
versus the check boxes that don't and
stuff like that so so anyways I'm a big
fan of that also in hand when they they
have the guardian perl script that
automatically updates your ipfw file if
someone is doing something to your
system so someone's port scanning me is
supposedly will automatically update my
ipfw com file sometimes both it's
according to who it's for yeah and you
know even on the server side in an
organization with 80 people and no IT
staff it's you know some of these snort
options like the trading pornography
feature the snort has and stuff like
that will i'll usually disable those for
clients because yeah you know i mean a
file called porn dot doc might be a
script about for a point or you know
whatever porn clients pay really well i
don't know if any of you have ever done
work for them but usually they'll pay
anything I t work specifically I'm not
there yeah yeah but I had to do some
work one time at a post house that
solely does porn and if you've ever
watched the same scene you know 50 times
in a row you just feel gross you know
like you're like ah ah you hit her in
the act you know it's terrible terrible
stuff but but you know it's sad they pay
really well and they want everything
right then so they have to so I use I
use checkmate sometimes for for tripwire
check sounds especially on servers on
the workstation side I don't i can't
imagine really deploying
that you can automatically deployed
tools using apple remote desktop it'll
automatically install package files
which hinman is in a package based
installer so you can deploy this to 500
max at the same time which is kind of
nice because you know obviously we've
always been able to do that with
Microsoft servers and you know now with
Linux you can do it as well so it makes
sense that Apple's kind of following
that trend so metasploit obviously has I
don't know 15 exploits maybe for the mac
that you can run Nessus obviously works
for OS 10 yeah but you know for I I read
an article I don't know six months ago
where they said that out of the box OS
10 is by far the most secure operating
system around I was like well obviously
like most media people this was written
by a mac guy because out of the box
that's really OS 10 workstation is quite
secure because they don't enable many of
the services i mentioned that in a
minute I actually give the link for it
the NS the NSA and yeah um they have a
secure deployment strategy so a lockdown
strategy it's published yeah i'll give
the link in just a minute gosh darn it
so um so I I feel really bad because I
did and I turned on all my services and
I on a default server and I did an SS
can against it and it was about 50 pages
but I didn't save the report properly i
guess so i can't show it to you but
necessary is available for 40 s 10
server and austin darwin ports is a
great place to look for different
updates for binaries so you don't have
to build them yourself everything from
GD on i don't think i mentioned this yet
i do so and then by default all logs are
at low levels but you can turn them up
and there's actually a program called
consult appt
gives you access to all the logs so you
don't have to go hunting for him because
none of them are in the right place so
which is kind of frustrating sometimes
console yeah it's just under
applications utilities it's called
console yeah so some some apple kind of
specific utilities that we use
rendezvous browser I think I have it
running right here bonjour browser i
guess i can look at kind of you know
automatically it's just going to go out
and tell me what services are open on
different people's computers so you know
who else has OS 10 server running
isshikawa anybody sweep I don't see many
people with OS 10 server running on
their ID box it's I mean you know it's
very very rare oh and you have so also
there's a there's a totally awesome
exploit for X an and then you know by
default NEX in if you if you have X an
installed and you fiber in you can see
the root of everything and you bypass
all quotas just by going through your
metadata which is pretty fun anyways so
I don't really go into that because I
actually have another another thing I i
did on that but the sub Bonjour browser
is kind of cool to just see what
everyone's running on a network really
quick secure empty trash someone had
mentioned earlier in one of the
forensics talks I think writing data 20
times you know writing zeroes or random
arbitrary numbers they just write zeros
over it 20 times which you know whatever
but any when you go to secure empty
trash any of those files they just
overwrite that that those blocks 20
times so filevault obviously can slow
down performance personally I don't do
anything that requires a lot of
performance I do most of my work in
terminal so so for me the performance
really doesn't matter if I'm riding i'll
use i'll use another machine basically
so that's that's a cipher filevault it
takes your you're in mac OS 10 your
users file your users folder and it
turns it into an encrypted disk image so
oh I'm sorry yeah it's it's like EFS
plus I i can't remember that right and
it's encrypted with i think a s 256 but
it's pretty pretty I you know and it
obviously the bigger it gets the more
issues you might have so right when you
boot they mounted right to it personally
at home the machine that I right on that
i use for writing and you know from I
prong i actually have used a
concatenated raid on it so to turn the
machine on you actually have to insert
my USB jump drive but i keep with me all
the time so you know there i mean you
can actually get pretty pretty crazy and
on that machine file vaults enabled and
all the word documents that later become
my books are in those those folders so
so think commander um think commander
will go through its and install all the
fold all the programs like if you're
trying to install GD live or something
it'll download it install it and install
and download all of its dependencies
which is kind of cool so it's kind of
like the ability to deploy you know one
package without having to go through all
the problems that most mac users can't
kind of figure out squid squid man is
you know if there's not a friend and for
it chances are most mac shops aren't
going to deploy it so squid bands are
front end for being able to deploy a
proxy the proxy built into Mac os10
server is just crap so you know squid
man is maybe two years old since its
last update and I asked the guy who
wrote it if I could have a source code
and then I just update it for him and he
didn't want to let go of it so
but I but it is still pretty decent app
so I wish it would do I map s but that's
aside from the point so the concatenated
rate thing I already mentioned gpg and
PGP are both available for for Apple
products gpg zan degraded straight into
mail that app I would open my mail that
app but I think someone here is going to
take my password and that would suck but
it's just same as anything drop-down
list check you know ling on 11 weird
thing about OS 10 server or OS 10
workstation as they deprecated cron
Apple just didn't they just couldn't
work within the confines of chron
anymore I guess because they wanted more
windows style service offerings so what
they gave us was launched d which no
apple administrator that i know of other
than maybe four of us have been able to
actually figure out how to use
efficiently so one of the guys actually
built this program called ling on which
which allows you it's basically like
opening the services box and a windows
server so you can start stop and add or
remove new services from a GUI and
launch the how many people here have
used launched d yeah it's kind of a pain
i mean you can re-enable cron on an OS
10 bucks but like apples trying to get
away from it and every update that you
run is going to blow out your update and
stuff like that and I'm another thing
about when you update software in an OS
tense environment you never know what
effects that's going to have on the GUI
so for clients when they want me to
update them to let's say they're failing
in Essos can because by default OS 10
server uses think open SSL oh 9 7 B or
something so in some cases rather than
actually updating openssl because when I
tried it would blow out the GUI and that
was the clients requirement that they
had to maintain their GUI I would just
change the headers for it then it would
pass the nessus can so so GUI tools Mac
users love and and I don't think they're
going to use anything without it like
there's a there's a you masks you know
with the define how new files that you
create
or have their permissions and what
attributes that different things you do
as a user have there's there's actually
GUI app for that for creating you masks
and stuff like that so they get you know
like like I showed even even CH mind has
has a GUI and I know it's 10 which is
kind of kind of wild so what's next more
information okay so this is the link to
that that NSA white paper for anyone who
asked about I think John asked about it
so there's the link right there and I
eldest annoyed last night so he's got
the updated copy of my presentation it's
only missing one screen I can't remember
which one it is but I'm sure it's one
that doesn't matter it's a it's a good
year and a half old almost but but at
the same and i think it was written for
10 3 so it might not include launch d
but it does offer some pretty basic
guidelines and pretty pretty good things
to do I mean you know if you're
deploying OS 10 as a specific type of
server like a ldap server or a web
server it doesn't really cover that as
much as maybe i could i think i'm gonna
i'm one of the next books i'm going to
write as OS 10 security and i'll
probably you know reference some of
their material frequently yeah i didn't
know that and i just affirmative
yesterday sorry I just had to specify
that I you know I don't want to pretend
I know something AFP 548 a great website
for a list and server stuff x anna t is
a pretty decent site for x and stuff
I've got they've got a pretty big
backlog of article so I've got like four
articles that I wrote for them that
haven't been published yet so they're
you know they're not as up to date as
maybe they could be but secure Mac Mac
security you know sans doute
Orange has I think eight Mac specific
articles out there so there's plenty of
other information although not as much
as you might think so so anyways that's
it QA unless it wait you want me to go
back where you're still writing yeah
I'll totally leave that up there so QA
everyone's just tired of layer 1 and
wants to go home now I can dig that so
yeah I'm about to wrap up a book on PHP
and perl programming and my next book is
after that is going to be on Windows
Server 2007 or whatever they prefer can
call it 2010 I don't know and then after
that I think the OS 10 security book
probably with her Riley you know and
other than that i'm open you know i'd
love to actually do more contributing to
books than writing books because it it
doesn't really pay that well and you
know over the long run you know just to
contribute something to me seems better
you know you had a question Oh is just
say when you going to do for instance
these updates like
the updates of blood VLAN immigration
over onto
things like that are you you're like a
lab is in sort that you're testing these
things in for you
oh I i personally test everything I mean
recently have like a setup link in your
office you said we just test out
everything or is beforehand or is it for
project-based both a little bit of both
I have 24 machines at home and that's
that's where I do a lot of my testing
and then at my office I've got another
maybe 20 and and so for the office stuff
you know I'll usually like if there's 10
4 6 update you know I'll have someone
else in my my company do those right but
about somebody will do the updates but
you don't specifically know that it's
breaking that specific configuration
until you're actually going easy what I
what I usually do is Allah I'll rent a
trip wire before and then I'll rent a
trip wire after and then i'll look at
everything that changed change can
change review yeah so um so I mean that
that's just the way I do it I'm sure
that there's better ways you know if
anyone think you know can mention any
please but um but i'll i'll also try to
try to install it then i'll make sure
that like i can still have to key into
it from windows make sure i can still
have to pee into it from or SMB in from
whatever OS you know and a lot of times
they're really clear they do document
some of their files pretty well ever
since all this plist file conversion
stuff they really aren't documenting
stuff like they used to or not and then
a collection of people at AFP 548 have
actually started doing kind of since
apple doesn't provide knowledge bases on
what they updated AFP 548 it's actually
starting to review everything that they
update and then you know say okay well
they updated these lines in this file
and it has this John yeah there's
there's one yeah if you go to version
tracker and just look for P list under I
think there's like four or five of them
now I'm sorry other is yeah i just use i
just use terminal for it but you know
thank you yes just xml exactly so as
long as you're you know
yeah yeah and I mean there's a lot of
GUI tools for like k destroyed so that
you can destroy Kerberos tickets I mean
there's all kinds of GUI tools for every
imaginable thing on the Apple side
they're pretty pretty good about making
GUI tools for things
third-party you mean as a client as a
server as a client cisco and and as of
ten 46 they built in the cisco ipsec
into huh yes did I update to 10 46 yet
on this machine and ya in 10 4 6 and no
i didn't an internet connect they right
yeah yeah and I yeah yeah so now you
don't have to buy now you don't have to
buy digital or whatever you were using
before you know yeah they I mean on the
GUI side or just straight you like
able to utilize messes up
from the GUI side I don't think so from
the terminal side if you can get it to
build and bsd you know I'm sure they can
I haven't tried that specifically none
of my clients actually actually use that
than I know of sometimes they do things
about telling me that however much the
router is I mean yeah I mean it's free
right I yeah i mean if if you can get it
to build you know in openvpn you can use
almost anything but um but you know and
it definitely works on Windows but you
know you need a Cisco device to do it
either running you know without NAT and
with nat you know so either as as just a
VPN server as your firewall with VPN my
final slide my crappy credentials and
whatnot so and at our company we do a
lot of a lot of Mac audits that's kind
of become one of our things and
regrettably a little bit of actual Mac
forensic work but forensic work I don't
know if who hears done forensic work of
any kind it's it that's pretty fun in it
you just always feel like you're going
to screw something up yeah well yeah
everything with mac stuff kind of is is
kind of weird its corner what city
you're in and what what industry you're
targeting like if you're working
specifically with print shops like we
don't take on new friend shops as
clients anymore because they just don't
don't pay well but if you're if you're
working with them anyone here work for
universal studios or if you're working
for universal or disney or someone like
that then they usually pay pretty well
okay but he works for them right not as
a contractor I guess he's an employee
yeah they don't know one in the film
industry plays employees anything I mean
even if you're even if you're a staff
like director you're not going to get
paid crap but if you're a freelancer
then you know you get to make kind of
you know in the in the entertainment
industry at least which I think comes
from just the fact that everything has
to be done right then you know so
anyways any other questions no love on
the questions I should have brought more
swag right I just want to say that your
talk was awesome you did the talk from
yeah hey so and and also I gotta give
give it up to all the guys at layer 1
this has been probably one of the most
highly technical conferences that I've
oh yeah totally so all right well that's
it thanks guys oh hey vsd box which is
on a nice high speed so thank you guys
for coming and it alone the field of
that access well thank you guys forgive
that layer 18 thousand six through be
paid up i agree i like it is the harder
on my lap time no no no they're trying
this is all you need the book I just
need a client huh oh yeah we've got some
you can run an open at EPA and if you're
running BSC station without awesome like
you're if you're not running a Mac you
just running straight open your steel
probably just use openvpn Oh open BPO
commence I'll write what i would do is
just go to cisco like when I what kind
of device are you connected to on the
other side us let's go whenever the last
night looks like you could actually just
use them as a pc
also on your way out at the bottom of a
box I found a bunch of thirty percent
off coupons for O'Reilly books so fill
out a 10 d feedback form grab yourself a
thirty percent off coupon and we look
forward to seeing you guys next year
we'll definitely be doing another one