I
all right hey I'm David Holton or hikari
this is johnny cash and also beatles
going to be doing a quick thing he just
figured out something last night so I
thought he'd come up here and present
something real quick so yeah this is a
contact info here I help run a torque on
down to San Diego and I am part of like
the soap and ciphers project we're
basically we're trying to get cool stuff
running on fpgas so mostly related to
crypto stuff but anything cool and here
Johnny Cash went you increase your job
okay I'm a Johnny Cash I currently hack
on why are the stuff pretty extensively
I'm going to talk about most of my code
a little bit later and I go to the Naval
Postgraduate School and also i'll be
graduating September and looking for a
job so uh hire me I guess people came
true some self later when does a little
thing yeah you don't only doesn't need
to any injury introduction or anything
so first thing I'm gonna go over cow
patty is anybody here that like heard of
cow patty at all yeah couple people
anybody heard of air crack yeah ok cool
so yeah if you don't know what cow patty
is is basically a WPA cracker I just
stole a bunch of slides from
presentation that the church of Wi-Fi
people gave and yeah I kind of signed up
on the church of Wi-Fi site like a few
days ago and so I am NOT like officially
a part of it but it's kind of pending I
guess they they weren't opposed to me
stealing their slides so then Johnny's
going to talk about air base which is
WEP cracking kind of framework that he
built he means 802 11 sleep by the way
it does there are children sweet yeah
sweet and we'll just talk about like how
everything ties together
so first I'm going to steal some slides
here wow that works too well it's
twitching a lot in channel yeah so
here's some like introduction stuff I
haven't really read over these slides at
all so this is kind of a history of the
church of Wi-Fi if you think that you
want to work on some cool Wi-Fi stuff
just check out their website and sign up
and they got a bunch of different
projects going this is just one of the
many of they presented on at X mu con so
they called this project basically
modifications to cow patty the J dumbass
project or Dumas if you're French or
something like that and basically a cow
patty normally you'd kind of like
capture some data and then run it
through like a huge word list and see
which word list matches you know the
data that you collected and they just
wanted to make it so they could
pre-compute all this stuff and look for
like really easy and dumb passwords that
people usually choose and so you can
just precompute everything ahead of time
and then you know like scan through the
list really quickly and and brute force
everything like while you're driving
through a city and stuff so it's Lee has
access points come up he just look
through a file if it matches and you
know you have you've cracked the network
and you can just move on so yeah they
really just tried to speed everything up
and catch the low-hanging fruit with
this so yeah they they called the J
dumbass project because as an user J
dumbass and yeah a dumbass has his
username as his password so yeah just
just basic passwords they wanted to
easily check for so I'm going to cover
this little more in detail so I'm just
going to skip over this right now
essentially they they want to make it as
a standalone application and they ended
up just modifying cow patty they got
Josh right to do all the modifications
and so they built this new program jen p
MK has anybody mess around with that at
all oh yeah butyl ok yeah yeah so it's
basically cow patty but it creates the
hash file and then you can use cow patty
to look up in the hash file instead of
actually computing everything
so they basically took the top default
ssids and and ran it through jen p MK
because essentially with them when
you're computing your p.m. k the set s
society is kind of like the salt and so
you can't just compute a hash table and
use it for any SSID it's for a
particular a society that you compute it
for so they took the top thousand SSIDs
and used a perl script to basically like
run a gem tmk on all these cells in s
societies for a given word list and it
essentially makes kind of like rainbow
tables for wpa but is dependent on the
SSID so this is what they did at
shmoocon and i'm going to talk a little
bit how we expanded this whole thing so
yeah so yeah i'll just go on to the meat
and stuff so essentially how wpa works
is you basically have your master key
which is like your passphrase and that
gets hashed and turned into a pair wise
master key which actually is used with
like your whole actual connection like
setting packets and authentication and
the less sort of stuff and basically
what's used to transform the master key
into the pairwise master master key is
this pv kdf to function which is
actually an RSA standard and essentially
what what pbk df2 is is sha 1h Mac
that's run like essentially about 32,000
times total all Shah ones run about
three two thousand times Sean 1h mac is
ran about like eight thousand times and
so this is the basic algorithm it
basically Shaolin H Mac like your master
key which is your passphrase and your
SSID and just like a little counter
identifier which is one up here and then
you take that output and loop it back
into into sha-1 H Mac is the input and
do that four thousand times and then
whatever you get out of Shaolin H Mac
that's like the first 20 bytes of your
hash
and then and then you do it with a
counter of one and do another 4,000
times so this is really time consuming
it takes forever on a PC and I'll get
into the performance stuff but it's
extremely slow if you're trying to you
know go through tons of pass phrases so
when you look at sha1 looked in depth
into sha-1 because I was implementing
this on an FPGA and I wanted to optimize
some of the stuff so essentially like a
sha-1 H Mac is you take your data and
you XOR it with like a constant which is
5c and you have an inner shell one where
you XOR your master key with a constant
over here and basically that whole
output of this whole function ends up
being you know the the t value over here
so one thing that's kind of cool with
this is that inside the sha-1 functions
the master key is never changing and
your ex soaring it with a constant value
so this value right here it can be
cached and so you don't have to compute
that shot one every time so you
basically start out with that value and
just like it saves you let's see you
have a total of like four shot ones here
so it cuts that the mound in half and so
you can even do some cool optimizations
like that see ya then essentially once
you have that then you just analyze the
network traffic and then try a certain a
certain master key certain passphrase
and if it matches up then you know that
you have the right key so it's kind of
like you know basic sort of password
cracking you just brute force everything
so I ended up building the stuff on an
FPGA that uses eight sha-1 cores and
uses block Ram to buffer all the
different pass phrases or going into the
sha-1 course and then I it's basically
set up kind of like a FIFO where as long
as machine is able to fill the buffer
then you can get full utilization on all
the cores and when you start like
running slow on filling it then it just
drops down the performance a little bit
and I'll go into how that works a little
bit so essentially you have your
computer and your huge buffer where
you're storing all of the all the
different pass phrases that you're going
to try and so you fill
like the slot 0 here slot 1 2 and you
fill it all the way down to like the
bottom of the buffer which in this case
is 255 and so now your whole buffer is
filled with different passphrases you
want to feed into the Shaolin course and
then you basically have some FPGA code
that takes out of those buffers feeds
them over to the shot one cores and then
the computer over here is just kind of
waiting for this whole block to finish
one step block finishes and it moves on
to the next block here then it starts
filling up here so essentially like
you'd if you start running slow on
filling up the table then it can still
go through all these values down to 255
and still like fully utilize all the
cores and you don't end up with any sort
of like performance loss and stuff so I
don't know this is a really simple sort
of kind of like a fifo thing that I
threw together and it works pretty well
for this so the end up kind of
developing custom sort of buffering
schemes to like get extra performance
out of things when you're dealing is
hardware so this is one thing I three
together so here here's some of the
performance results with cow patty on a
pentium 3 I was getting about 25 per
second like so you could actually only
try 25 per second on 3.6 gigahertz p4
like my laptop I was getting about 60
per second a friend of mine tried on
like the highest end AMD system that he
had he got about 70 beetle tried it on
his intel core duo and on his macbook
and he got about 70 with cow patty
supposedly you can get like a hundred
hundred plus has anybody done any
performance like stuff with air crack on
a pc no least try that okay well it's
bilious a bit faster because they use
MMX so on the fpga on one of our low-end
cards which is basically just this
little compact flash size card as
getting about 430 per second and in this
cluster this machine right here I can do
about 6500 per second and on our
higher-end cards that are about the size
of a pcmcia card i can get about a
thousand per second per card
maybe about 15,000 for a system like
that and okay so render man already
computed like he did like the top
thousand passphrases for the top dolls
in SSIDs and his next goal was to do the
top million passphrases for the top
dolls in s societies and so he started
computing this on his cluster and it
took him about a month to go through
this whole thing and then he found out
that he had returned characters at the
end of every line and so I left you have
returned characters in your society yeah
he was kind of screwed so yeah after
computing for a month so he sent me an
email and he sounded kind of pathetic
he's like oh you know can you help me
out please and so i coded this thing up
i finally got it working and actually
started this cracking the same sort of
job earlier this week like on tuesday
and i finished it before I left for
coming to the conference and basically
took two days like 48 hours and actually
I have DVDs it's 40 gigs worth of stuff
i have dvds here that we're going to
give out at the end of the talk I've got
four sets here so good questions will
get DVDs later and thanks a lot to a guy
over there selling the dvds what's that
let me use the use the burner last night
so it saved a lot of time so I'm going
to do a demonstration it's basically cow
patty running on fpgas with some perl
scripts involved so i'll just run
through this real quick
here
ah so i'm using rendell man's account
for this so yeah he he basically just
hooked together some perl scripts run
yeah this is this is just as perl script
is using for for computing the tables
and it's really simple just like reads
in a file of s ascites and then just
spits off jen p MK for everything so
it's a total Hackford just computing
stuff and building all these tables so
first I'll show you how fast this runs
on on the pc here i've got like a full
dictionary file which is see 10,000
lines i think there's only like four
thousand that actually are more than
eight characters yeah and if you
actually look at it I put the actual
passphrase for this test is family movie
night at the very bottom so that's what
I'm going around the FPGA basically four
thousand i created one for this demo
because it would take way too long doing
it on the real computer here let's try a
small one so a small one is like less
than three hundred and so it should be
pretty fast so I i just might play these
little scripts so I didn't screw up the
demo here so this basically just runs
cow patty with the test dump file with
dictionary oh yeah faster with addiction
to the small dictionary and ness society
of something clever so
so took two seconds it did about 44
passphrases per seconds that's not too
bad now I'm going to run it on one of
the FPGAs in this cluster here and i
just added the cat the dash capital F
option on to here and so you can just do
dash capital F and the index of the FPGA
you want to talk to and then it just
offloads everything to that so its exact
same cow patty syntax for everything so
right now it's going through all these
pass phrases yeah yeah yeah it's just
one of them so did 434 passphrase per
second and found family movie night as a
as a pre-shared key went through four
thousand and 9.4 seconds and if you've
looked at jen p MK it's it's kind of the
same signet syntax is cow patty so i'll
just run that real quick so you just run
jen p MK with a hash file dictionary
SSID
so this is for the same really small
word list with something like 10 past or
89 pass phrases in it and then then you
just run cow patty with the dash kappa d
option you specify the hash file that
you generated and it just goes through
and uses the hash file instead of
computing so 16 2000 per second you can
look up in the hash flow so it's quite a
quite a bit faster once you actually
compute everything and see so here's
here is it on the FPGA for the big one
so it'll take the same amount of time as
the cow patty thing
so there's the hash file and I just
looks it up and it's pretty fast right
so basically like if you happen to get
one of these dvds or you bit too are
numb or download them off a website or
something all you have to do is I've got
this test file that render man sent me
and like if I'm trying to crack a
linksys access point he's got this
capture file linksys 01 cap so I have to
do is specify your hash file I've got
like a linksys hash pilot here that's
each one of these is about 40 Meg's and
see specify your capture file and a
society which is linksys of course I
think it's towards the end I hope so
yeah
there we are yeah so yeah that's
basically it if you happen to get one of
these one of these dvds here try it out
and see if you can crack some cool stuff
with it yeah yeah yeah we'll probably
put them up on a website where you can
just download the links this one and so
yeah once you stumble on something you
can just download the file for that
particular one or if you want you can
email me and I'll like compute like a
few billion word word lists or whatever
for her like that particular SSID
probably faster to compute him so yeah
last night beetle tried I'm looking
around at some of the stuff with OS X
for doing PMK stuff and he found some
cool stuff so I I just wanted to have
him explain something that seemed pretty
cool yeah yeah real quick um you know I
like there's IW config for linux and
that's pretty cool and OS x is pretty n
scott it's got nice little stuff for you
to point and click and i think it was
like two years ago or so that I figured
out how to write IW config for like
windows XP because I couldn't stand like
you know having to change as this idea a
GUI so look for wireless weapons of mass
destruction for windows and you'll find
out how to write IW config for windows
XP so i was thinking well just do the
same thing for OS X right and lo and
behold they've already done it I'm like
yay because they were smart enough right
there working off a bsd subsystem so I
mean it's great this happens to hide in
system library private frameworks Apple
802 dot11 dot framework virgins current
resources and there's a command called
airport and you can do all sorts of
command-line stuff just like I did we
config with the airport command so if
you type airport desk h you'll get like
all sorts of crazy stuff so you can do
manual scanning you can actually join
the different network you can change
your preferences you could look at your
actual depreciate keys that you already
have stored for your current networks
that sort of thing but I was looking I
was like oh that's great but
I saw wait a second there's just a
regular flag that lets you just generate
a pre-shared key or a pmk for a
particular SSID which is basically what
gen p.m. k is for cow patty so as long
as you just want to generate a whole
bunch of p.m. case for a particular SSID
you can do that with a shell script
inside OS X by default you don't have to
download anything else but the
performance is not great I don't be
silly sure go back yeah system library
private frameworks then Apple 802 dot11
dot framework from from from ford /
versions fork / current /resources and
then there's a command called airport
that sits there yeah i MA and the first
half the first thing I did was like you
know create a symbolic link and use your
husband right see it's nicer to have it
in the path right so a performance wise
here's like the show street or you know
a little bit pearl that I wrote and okay
this is all it does it just basically
takes a dictionary file and then runs
runs the airport command with those
flags on that particular society and
then creates like your PM case for you
now the problem is that this format and
what it's creating here isn't an actual
hash isn't an actual hash table it's
readable by cow patty but I wasn't about
to figure that out right then I didn't
know exactly how he was storing like the
header on his hash file to determine
what the SSID was so I was going to do
that for later so later on it'll it'll
actually do this I'll maybe I'll throw
an update on like my website or
something like that anyway if you run it
you get about 10 10 10 and a half
passphrases per second that you're
actually generating which is decent in
comparison to like pentium tues or
whatever but what's nice is that you've
got a you know if you're doing this on
you know a macbook then you've got you
really have to processor so you can run
it twice and you actually get better
utilization you get 20 passwords per
second if you guys single core you're
sucking now what's interesting is that I
thought this is kind of cool and I
thought well I'll just I'll do this in
comparison to you know Jen p.m. case and
I tried to compile jen p MK and of
course it doesn't compile cleanly on OSX
but i commented out a couple different
includes and then jen p MK does run OSX
i have gotten calc ID running on there
but what's nice is that you can act
to get about 35 36 / poor and so you end
up doing about 70 passphrase per second
with jen p MK so josh is still got the
cool shit with jen p MK don't think
about this shell script replaces that
name any way shape or form but it's just
kind of cool that you can actually just
do this on the fly with the shell script
okay cool thanks a lot no there isn't WK
to support yet I think that the only
difference is that wpa2 uses AES instead
of shot one and so I think it will
actually end up being faster to do on
fpgas but I haven't really looked at it
much so oh go ahead oh ok yeah so that
yeah it's just I think the job right is
going to be doing some sort of support
for wpa2 in dekalb addy and if somebody
else comes up comes out with something
before then I'll probably do have PGA
support for it okay go ahead
uh yeah sure um yeah yeah the this
company that I helped start we
manufacture see I've got some cards in
my bag over there he's alone okay so
this is actually a compact flash card
like inside a pcmcia adapter and it's
pretty small but basically this thing
plugs into a pcmcia adapter and then it
plugs into a pcmcia a pci adapter and
this motherboard kind of a backplane
things supports up to 20 PCI cards and
this actually has two motherboard blades
in it so there's two motherboards in
here and one can do like eight PCI cards
another one can do seven so it's a total
of fifteen yeah yeah they're they're
these little tiny things inside like
yeah 22 adapter is basically into PCI
into the motherboard yeah so it's
totally like off-the-shelf hardware that
we just worked together just to have a
bunch of these in a single machine these
things we sell on our website at PECO
computing com I'll have a link at it
link for it later on the presentation
but these are pretty expensive so I
don't know if your company is paying
forth and that's cool if you're trying
to do something by yourself you can buy
like pretty cheap Ebell boards from
different places and they're a lot more
difficult to set up you're going to
spend a lot of time like building
interface to actually talk to them and
stuff but
oh yeah yeah these are really convenient
I mean you just pop them in and you can
start doing dev work and stuff so but
yeah they they're really expensive
manufacturers that's mostly why they're
really expensive this box right here is
like 50,000 each card is about 2,500 so
yeah it's a little pricey if you you can
go out and buy some dev boards like if
you just go into xilinx calm and search
around for dev boards they range between
like maybe 300 and like five or six
hundred dollars for like kind of like
bare-bones vertex 4 Spartan threes run
about like a hundred to two hundred if
you want to play around with those and
the code that I'm going to have up on
open ciphers you should be able to port
it to pretty much anything it's all yeah
it's all pretty open so go ahead it's on
Verilog on that PGA any other questions
for the to the section yeah you create
bottom then some so I could do the
stupid
uh yeah there isn't really a whole lot
of a whole lot of bandwidth going
between you know the computer in the
cards because it's only doing like 400
per second per card and that's maybe
averaging like 50 bytes per like
passphrase or something so I mean it's
not that much bandwidth if you consider
like you know how fast the pci bus can
go up to but i was running into some
limitations with up with eight of them
where they're kind of like fighting over
the bus and so is it wasn't running as
fast as it could have been so it may be
getting about like 380 per second
average over across all eight well as
seven it was working perfectly fine go
ahead packets um six or yeah I think
it's a 4 Way handshake that we had
somewhere in here oh yeah yeah these
these four I think that yeah there's
some sort of like for a handshake thing
that goes on or something I don't the
earth wait Hey Ya Ya sort of kind of
yeah yeah distorted over there see I
think you just have to capture that
thing or something I don't know I just I
just crack the codes I don't really I
don't really mess around with the other
stuff yeah so yeah um see I Johnny's
going to talk about your base now if
there are any other questions oh okay
um yeah well okay so so like say you
know cow patty does like 70 per second
or something like that then yeah like
one of these does forty three or four
hundred and thirty times 15 so 6500 /
it's yeah yeah basically about a hundred
laptops yeah 100 dual-core until
something like that yeah so yeah so it
so if you can buy a hundred laptops for
fifty thousand dollars and it's yeah
this probably drives withdraws a lot
less current than 100 laptops though and
it's green yeah yeah and it's green it's
green that cost extra yeah leavin you
leavin still it was like like some
bling-bling lights and the spoiler on
the back to any other questions decals
everybody else all right okay go for
Johnny alright so I'm going to talk
about air base for a little bit because
the other thing we've done so method is
hardware accelerated our c4 inside a
left boot for sir Justin quite as sexy
as brute forcing WPA but still you know
get your bases covered and so uh talk
about Air Base Air Base is actually a
lot more than just an 80 tool or a WEP
password cracker and since i'm talking
about it i want to go over so many other
features very briefly because I wrote
them and I'd like people to start using
it hyperlinks and powerpoints this is
amazing i think i could do this okay
eres eres has pretty much three large
components to it it's got air where
which is a library written in c++ and
it's got JC wet crack JC aircrack and a
bunch of tools JC aircrack is Mairi
implementation of air crack it's uh it's
written in c++ and it's way easier to
read than Christoph's aircrack that it
has less features i'm not going to say
it's particularly
sure yet but it's definitely easier to
experiment with and I'll show off some
other things it does then a JC web crack
is the thing we've actually gotten
hardware accelerated so far that's just
a plain old Bucky brute force or
redistributed you know looking at like
city at home cracking WEP keys and tools
has a bunch of other utilities I'm going
to mention briefly because you're really
handy if you're into developing wireless
tools assuming my spacebar works what
button does this take none of them in
the frozen it is frozen okay so
hyperlinks and PowerPoint a bad idea all
right this takes two hands hahahaha oh
meet all of the info yeah beach bah you
can't see this but Microsoft's crash
reporter crashed hey yeah
okay so no no hyperlinks in this version
worked fine with the other one it did oh
where is there
okay much better all right it's reversed
it is me versus I had this all working
before
one more time I'm a brilliant computer
scientist I swear I just can't work
Microsoft products all right it does
work okay so as I was saying airbase
there's three major components air crack
WEP crack and a bunch of tools and they
all use the same library everywhere
because I've this started as a bunch of
legacy code I had written so many
different wireless utilities and I was
so tired of maintaining different code
bases i spent like two months and rotor
but i think it's badass c++ library to
do everything for me so if there's any
function that I ever had to write twice
inside any of these things they got
crammed in the area where for better or
worse so so I just go to the tools that
are included in this briefly there's a
pcap to air file so that those what
you'd imagine and take a peek app and
inject it a pcap web crypt which is a
little program to decrypt and encrypt
you know peek at with web it's got some
more useful features for developers you
can specify things on the command line
like I'd like to encrypt this packet end
times with this probability of a week I
ve or set this IV to this so it gives
you a little more power than some error
test is a nice unit tester for air where
and it does actually have some features
prints out pcap so it will do some web
benchmarking prism strip is a little
program that's poorly named that'll
prism headers but actually it will strip
out abs headers and you want to believe
the number of crappy ways people write
down pcap files it's terrible they'll
set the data link type to this but then
will append a 4-byte frame checksum
which shouldn't be there or maybe it
should but you can't tell handles all
that for you actually the library
handles all that for you so I have to
think about it simple replay is a little
program that will just replay packets on
one interface or just kind of nice so it
sits there and you can tell it replay a
data packet with this probability or you
can tweak it to do over only whatever
packets and craft test is a little
program and it'll just run through the
different crafters to show you how easy
it is to craft ferries packets none of
these are directly really related to
cracking up with hardware except maybe
he can't replicate
handy so let's get to you know the
cracking utilities first we have JC
aircrack a reimplement ation of you know
ever popular statistical attacks against
aircrack aircrack has 17 korek attacks
implemented i only have 16 because one I
could just not read or figure out contd
out and says XXX don't put this in so
anyway so there's a JC aircrack binary i
have my own version of i wrote my own
arrow dump actually because i wanted to
be able to run aircrack in real time on
a mac and the version that christophe
had you know runs great on linux but
doesn't run on OSX in real time so you
can use this version of aero dunk to you
know dump IVs or packet files in real
time using the pasture driver for your
airport card if you get the latest kids
mac and fiddle with it correctly it's
not the easiest thing to do but it does
work getting the driver working is your
problem however other than that pretty
much free and said everything else pcap
two IVs murdered IVs those do probably
what you think they will and these are
all file compatible and buffer
compatible even with aircrack so if you
wanted to run my arrow dump on OSX and
actually Christoph's aircrack on OSX
using you know they'll talk to each
other just fine so that's bc aircrack
and here's a screenshot in case
something goes bad with my computer
while I try to demo it hopefully we
won't need the screenshot it's a second
alright
okay okay so here I am sis the latest
version release of air base which isn't
actually up on my webpage yet but it
will be shortly i hope i've just not
brave enough to post a virgin server
facing the internet so i've got a got a
little script here that's generally
going to use pcap wept ripped to uh to
generate some pcap files for an air
crack against and you know it's not as
good as cat capturing packets in real
time but at least it's not that much
tricks up my sleeve right so so it's a
using t cat flap trip to generate easier
like pcap files that are easier and
easier to crack with more packets in
more week i've used so you can kind of
see how the cool runs and later you'll
see how we're going to accelerate a
second so it's a now saves you time from
actually trying to collect this data you
just generate it but what does this work
with them with like access points of
filter week IVs uh you see access points
there plenty of access points that will
filter week I we get sir pains they
won't use them but there's nothing that
can stop an old client from using them
so you got some old windows box saying
around with a crappy driver and it's
still gonna you know use these week IVs
and it's also it's not that easy to
filter them as people think there's the
classically weak ones that everybody
knows about with ffs but there's a 17
different statistical attacks it's not
that easy to filter for all around are
very few people do I think so if there
is filtering it's filtering the one
attack that pays off the most but
alright so let's give this a shot tell
the key size some debugging output is
handy pass it a pcap file
so this is the week the hardest to crack
pcap file that I've generated and it's
probably not going to crack it right
come anywhere near cracking it but you
can see how it works so if everybody's
used aircrack before they probably
recognize what this looks like it's it's
a brute forcing a 13 bike key and you
can only see 11 bytes up on the display
the bottom two are getting root forced
in real time so the time it takes this
9f to slide over is the time it takes to
brute force 16 bits of the key at the
bottom so uh basically the way this
whole program works is reading all these
peak apps or packets compute some
statistical functions over them and
generate weighted guesses on the value
for the key and all these weights are
pretty even and they're also pretty low
the key is 0 0 1 1 2 2 and you don't see
0 1 1 2 2 in here so didn't do a very
good job it's just not enough data
available let's try it with an easier
file jump up a little bit
okay this looks a lot more promising 0 0
1 1 2 2 it's got a lot more of them you
can see the weights are higher up the
one handy thing for this is if you're
actually trying to develop some sort of
new attack these the display down here
showing the number of the pack the
number of like that attack week Ivy's
it's found and the weight you've
assigned to it so the classical attack
is a pack 0 it's found 687 of those and
they get assigned to wait 5 this is a
you know different attacks and this
one's got wait three so I that's useful
for trying to see you know if you're
trying to gather some more intelligence
on how these things work or I really
like to see for example what happens if
I'm only using the first attack you can
specify the end so if you're wondering
maybe I should wait this one higher
let's see how it goes all the other ones
are have their weight set to 0 and are
displayed and red at the bottom so you
can see that if I don't have any of
those other attacks I didn't do nearly
as well I got 0 0 no 11 no 22 you know
kind of fell out a little bit kind of
handy can also do the inverse which is
again useful if you're kind of
interested in how this stuff works so
the way your hardware accelerate this
thing is I've explained this to some
people I'm going to go into it
apparently a lot of people think the
thing to accelerate is the computation
of the statistics and really you only do
that 17 functions over each packet you
see it once so it's not that much
computation time really the real problem
is you're saying their brute forcing the
bottom of the key space so you can
change that and let's say now i'm going
to brute force one bite at the bottom
and you'll see the display updates a lot
faster and there's only one bite you
don't see similarly i can to his little
fault so if i jump up to three it pretty
much looks like the program stopped it
actually isn't stopped it's just
brute-forcing three bites at the bottom
so you're going to sit here for a while
I haven't even waited it out honestly so
hit me an hour to what we'd like to do
is get it so that you can brute force
three bites at the bottom with an FPGA
and this pays off better than you might
think because
she the further you get from the top of
the key the harder it is to generate
these statistics reliably so it's
actually better than not only in my
brute forcing one more bite just as fast
I'm brute-forcing the three hardest
bites which is you know good so that's
aircrack let's get back to my
presentation and hope this doesn't crash
again any questions on that before I
delve into other tools you ask me later
to
okay so all right I didn't need the
screenshot it all worked out so JC JC
web crack is the just plain old key
brute forcer there's no no clever
statistics is just sitting at home for
cracking WEP keys I actually wrote this
ah like three years ago and I use it
pretty effectively on a cluster and so
if you're curious if you want a brute
force in the entire 40 bit key you need
about 24 hours with about 10 or 11 f on
MP 1108 your disposal that's the worst
case so 12 hours on average which is
very handy it's also the only way to
know if you've got 104 bit key really if
you try all 40 bits of a lower one and
doesn't work then okay I got to start
trying to do stuff to 104 of it so JC
web crack now has support for the pie co
client which is going to talk to the
FPGA so this is a picture of the JC web
cracked server which is responsible for
handing out chunks of the key space that
clients now start it up later with fpga
so when I can get into it too much now
so this is the way it worked before you
just start a tasty wet track D on some
server somewhere you get a bunch of
clients to talk to the server and check
out key spaces how you obtain these
clients is up to you the client would
probably even compile and run on cygwin
though I've never bothered it all the
stuff runs on OS X and Linux and top
cross talks for each other so OS x
server linux boxes whatever all plays
nice so you just gotta get a bunch of
client computers to do your work
someone's they're gonna be the JC web
crack worm no comment so this this is
actually I mean people kind of think why
would you brute force a 40-bit key and
I'm like because I have a head Hannah
clustering now I have fpgas I had a
cluster so it was really nice for you
know 24 hours whereas case turn your key
around so to accelerate it now we just
bring in the pie co client into the pic
you know so we've got our normal client
sitting there and talk about the server
check nike spaces and then we bring this
one guy who's a little smarter and he
talks to fpga and fpga does all the work
for him so he can intermix them as well
currently the way this works is that JC
wet crack teen talks to the pike Oakland
the Pikeville client talks straight to
the FPGA Lucy aircrack plain get my
mouse over here yeah JC aircrack doesn't
have any hardware support yet which you
know I'd like to get in there but I was
not going to hack it in too fast like a
kit into you know the client and then
hack it into JC aircrack but I'm going
to do is I'm going to do this which is
I'm going to try to throw all the
hardware support I can inside air where
so all the programs suddenly crack stuff
as fast as they can on that platform if
anybody's ever seen core image on OSX
that's pretty much the motivation for
this it's really slick you give it a
little program to do manipulations of
graphics and it'll either run it on the
GPU or run it on the cpu in parallel as
fast as we can and the client go doesn't
have to deal with it well I'm trying to
do the same thing here I'll probably end
up writing some other cracking tool at
some point in the future and I'd like to
not have to rewrite all the code to the
hawk to the FPGA so it's going to happen
in the near future hopefully is that air
where is going to have all this code
that will talk to hardware right now we
got fpga code and you know software if
there's other things you could try to do
this on GP user you know something
people have toyed with and there's
compilers to target them that cool
physics engine thing I don't know how
the hell you talk to that but that's
another idea and so then all the client
code you'd have a sort of simple JC web
crack client no longer does it keep
track of the fastest way to do anything
it just calls earlier an area where
figures it out and as soon as I do that
JC aircrack will immediately be
optimized which is nice so that's going
to happen shortly i hope so this is a
little bit of details on how we actually
talked to the card right now basically
the pike old client gets a key from the
server room it's like okay figure out
what I'm supposed to do and it tells
fpga
where to start at where to stop at the
size of the key and the hopeful prva the
way this is implemented is that we we
know the first six bytes of the random
output from RC four because they know
they snap header of every packet so we
can extra out six bytes of every packet
and get the output from RC four so like
okay then we just tell fpga do all these
keys and if you've seen one that outputs
these six bytes we've probably got the
key there could be collisions I mean
it's only six bytes it's pretty unlikely
so then the software actually has to
kick in okay hardware says it's this the
software is going to double check and
make sure it works and then you know
it's like okay we got the key so that's
just everything I have an air base so
now we're going to try to do a demo
right hope for the best oh don't know
the oh that stuff yeah oh I got some
slides outside I can go over that real
quick okay you can do the demo yeah
that's how I didn't crash again okay you
kind of kind of already explained some
of the fpga stuff but I've got some some
diagrams here that might illustrate a
little bit
Oh
okay so right now on fpga we've got 16
RC 4 cores that we built uses block ram
4s boxes so basically the the main
problem with running rc4 and hardware is
that you've got this S box that you know
it works great in software because it's
just Ram but when you're dealing with
like 256 8-bit registers it takes up a
lot of space and so with block Graham
it's kind of like little tiny Rams that
are almost kind of like cash on your
processor so it really fast to access
and so we we just decide to use those
for for this boxes and yeah it just
tries every key between the start and
the end so if you've seen rc4 before
it's a really simple algorithm you
basically just have this initialization
step where you set your S box to just
like a permutation from like basically
zero through 255 inside this buffer and
then you kind of do a bunch of mixing
and the KSA and then for the prg a you
do some more mixing and like pull out
values here and there so it's a it's an
extremely simple algorithm and software
and it's actually pretty simple and
hardware but you just have to pull some
different tricks and stuff basically for
an RC for module you have you just look
at your inputs in your outputs and you
try and tailor something around that
where you get a certain input and you
know gives you the right output so for
this particular module basically your
key is your input and your PR GA is
going to be the output and what one of
the problems here yeah and this is
basically how it cracks it you have like
some sort of expected PR GA and it sends
out like key 0 key one key to and then
it gets back some sort of PR GA and this
is this is this is normally supposed to
be like hex values but just for like
artistic value here through those in and
so it keeps on going along and and then
you know finally oh yeah there's bling
okay yeah I got some bling you got some
bling yeah we're real good and so then
it says okay so that must be the key and
then it just reports it back
what issue with this is that you end up
wasting lots of cycles just initializing
this s Fox value here and so essentially
there's like two hundred fifty six
cycles to initialize this then I was
another 256 maybe 512 to do this whole
step and then an additional like 8 16 or
something like that to do that step just
because there's so many iterations that
are dependent on the previous ones with
this initialization step you can
actually do that kind of in parallel and
how we do this is we have our initial s
box that you know the computer writes
the values to and then we just have the
S box write it out to these different
block grabs that are associated with
these different rc4 course and then
after those are filled then the rc4 cord
uses that s box and we'll end up you
know writing values into it and I'll do
all sorts of like mixing and stuff and
meanwhile while it's doing that we fill
up these other block Rams and so we're
actually doing the initialization step
for the next rc4 run in like the
previous one and so then after it's done
with this rc4 step it moves on it uses
this one you know police that one then
yeah switches back and forth and so that
that's kind of like one optimization
that we came up with for doing this
whole thing so now here comes the demo
basically JC web crack + FPGA plus the
matrix crashing Feeny's
all right also my cert the card the
right way okay so this is startup so
just starting up they see web crack be
the same old server we've had for quite
a while so got the pretty cursus
interface if you haven't figured out I
like curses and I've also clearly had a
turbo Pascal influence my interface
design since I was a child just can't
kick it so it's you can see it's got a
chunk size you can tell how many bits a
client wants to check out or how many
are out and how long to wait until you
think that all that chunks not going
back so let's start up a client cross my
fingers okay good it's reading the keys
off the FPGA right now in real time and
it can redraw the screen this quickly
because yeah thank you so the real
beauty of this is I've showed these
people they're like John you're wasting
CPU cycles drawing the screen and then
I'm like no I'm not I'm doing everything
on the card there is no you know the cpu
usage right now is like zero percent so
you can sit here and draw whatever you
want as quickly as often as you would
like and you end up with something as
pretty as this um I think Nikki I
started to that was 0004 so it'll get
there in like a minute or so ok let's
see a top
oh we got to see the finished all right
we'll make it oh here we go ah so cpu
usage 0% right so you could just start
up another you know JC web cracked
cpu-bound 12 and do twice as fast but
let's go watch this ok so gross her
fingers yeah he starts his you 004 there
is no spoon oh the suspense there we go
hahaha thank you you would not believe
how many nights I spent sending riot
terminal codes to get that thing to look
right because i didn't use curses cuz
i'm just old school hahahaha that's the
next release oh there is one more thing
you can change the color as well for you
matrix purists got to start the seer
huh so don't ask me how I did the matrix
thing because I won't tell you because I
showed some of this like dude that's
awesome like yeah how do you do it and I
told them and they're like that's way
less cool so it's a secret oh right okay
can't change it on the fly yet that's a
future feature there you go so any
questions on anything I guess we're done
with the rest of the presentation 42
next
did you actually what I mean is this
using the previous code I wrote yeah
yeah this is talking to the same server
that I've been using for a couple of
years ago yeah the first distributed web
crack version yeah this is still even
using the same protocol so still still
the same server still the same protocol
the interoperates technique so any other
questions if you're really really lucky
but yeah packet injection helps the air
crack hasn't been accelerated yet or
like I said I got to get this this code
merchant the area where and then
everything will be accelerated but yeah
it would it would help a lot there's no
bus packets and stuff yeah still the
thing is there's a huge trade off
between like a hundred more packets and
like an hour more CPU time you would
really rather have a hundred more week
packets and another you know gigahertz
probably so more data helps more than
more CPU cycles anyone else
hard to see with the lights all right
sure hmm I guess at the end or we can
try and figure out who asked questions
before earlier yeah yes yes they are how
much you guys got yes that's me profit I
don't know I think that I think he can
burn seven dvds at a time and probably
has a bunch of extra DVDs laying around
yeah so oh yeah there's a see huh oh hey
slides yeah there's a couple of slides
but yeah whatever yeah well no we got
four four summers on some yeah yeah we
actually computed some yeah its
performance stuff so yeah that's the
performance and yeah I'm one of these
cards in here we're getting about two
million per second we can probably
crease that to like three or four if I
optimize stuff some more that's a bit
faster so you can weaken like brute
force 24 bits really fast instead of two
bits they're 16 bits or whatever or one
what's up so conclusions get an FPGA and
start cracking make use of your hardware
to break crypto add cool matrix ascii
effects when you can choose bed please
please or 40 bit password be anything
you want then and so yeah now we're just
we're going to do questions I guess
people that ask cool questions before
just ask them again and we'll get nice
and stuff or something but um yeah so
any questions even though we've already
probably gone through much okay why
don't you come up and get some DVDs I'm
not going to answer it yeah did you yes
a couple questions right yeah one of
them um like I'm one of the cores or one
of the cards one of the cards um three
yeah yeah one of these elex 25s is
equivalent to supposedly like one and a
half million gates roughly so yeah they
they've kind of switched away from the
whole gate concept to like lots or
slices and so they're they're using
totally different metrics for everything
yeah you have to take all three yeah
there's 90 VDS total yeah so yeah I just
take a stack of three oh okay
yeah yeah it definitely would be we're
just uh yeah yeah yeah exactly like yeah
we didn't have like tons of budget to
have a bunch of different projects going
on at the same time so right now we've
just got this compact flash one we've
got a card bus-based one and we're going
to have an expresscard one pretty soon
and pretty much all those you can adapt
to like pci or pci express or whatever
so that's good enough for now we'll
probably do a board like that later but
right now you can you can find lots of
pci boards out there so oh yeah yeah
yeah yeah I don't know that we're
thinking about doing something like that
but there's there's other places out
there that do stuff like that so okay uh
I don't know actually I almost forgot i
got some guinness up here so you get a
beer anybody else have a good question
needle you want to get us okay here you
go do I get one okay I did oh yeah
Spartan threes are really cheap you can
just go into xilinx calm and search
there they have a directory of all their
different dev boards and you can get
like a starter spartan 3 with like I
don't know 500,000 gates for like a
hundred bucks or like one with like a
million gates for what's um like a
million gate one would be maybe be about
like half half as fast as this you could
probably get maybe like like a two or
three million gate sort of range 14
which would be about equivalent to this
for maybe about three or four hundred
bucks like in this part in threes and
kind of the same for vertex 4 if you got
one of those
if your student like an engineering you
want to be on a beer or you want some
tables no there's an or there ya got to
know your priorities tables review yeah
sure when I ok ok like say at home yeah
um yeah I don't maybe a speed all about
it in six months or something right beer
CD go ahead yeah yeah yeah we can if you
want to these boxes and you give us 50
grand will give you a box so if you're I
don't know how yet any color yeah any
blinkies IM you doing if you're doing
like some sort of yeah it doesn't look
like that yeah yeah um yeah so yeah what
was the question again yeah you can you
can buy one of these from us right now
if you're going to do is like some cool
projects with it we can give you a good
discount unlike the cards and stuff so
just uh yeah I just give me a call or
send me an email or something any other
questions
ya know it's kind of the same thing I
mean yeah I guess it would probably a
little more efficient to compare like a
smaller counter than like a huge value
but I'm really really incrementing by
like a maximum 32 bits or something like
that and so I know it's yet it's not too
bad like on that PGA the difference
between guys there's there's a lot of
other stuff on there they're slower so
yeah so I think you get a beer and petty
gets beer and any other questions I
think we're all out of beer so I don't
blame you if we yeah okay alright thanks
a lot guys by the way