so i don't really know a lot about apple
tv so i'm also really excited about this
let's get around
so for those of you who don't know me my
name is kevin bradley i go by neato tv
on twitter and associated other areas
irc
slack
discord i've been doing
i've been hacking these devices since
the very first apple tv came out in 2007
and 2008. it didn't do what i wanted to
do so i was like let's make it do it
like i saw other people hacking it i saw
they were in the chat room awkward tv
and i decided to join in on the phone i
said why not you know
it doesn't do what we want let's make it
do it
fast forward to 2010
and
check out sorry i'll check way too early
on that one 2010 and the second
generation apple tv came out it had an
arm there's six or seven processor
pretty sure it was six
and
that meant that meant you're no longer
on intel because the very first box in
2007 was an intel machine is pretty much
a mac mini that was shrunk down
like like so it wasn't really so
squished but then widened and then you
had your hdmi port your component output
your optical audio
and a usb port which we made great use
of
but now since it has arm everything
you've done on ios up to this point is
helpful in some way but they know
nothing about apple tv so you have the
entirety of the chronic dev team
streaming into an awkward tv channel
because they're like oh this is where
this is happening let's join forces and
figure this out that's how i joined
chronic dancing
now what brings me here today i work for
guardian if you haven't heard of us we
make a awesome vpn app for the iphone we
have a sort of other things we're doing
as well that we're working on that i
will go over as well but that's like the
main thing we're known for at this
moment excuse me
and i've also developed a series of
products projects whatever moving up to
this point when check brain checkmate
and all that stuff happened and i'm
going to outline that first and then i'm
going to get into the you know the the
media details
that's right
i'm used to having to use the remote
so these are some of the projects these
are some of the icons for them you can
look down there too
so you have ethereal reprovision
air photo
uh breezy and and control i will cover
all those in
some different form as we move forward
so september 2018 if you aren't familiar
with the anvils i always have to have
them in my presentation at least once
i'm usually kind of aggressive and it's
every single point this time i'm like i
don't have time for that
but yes melissa they're there
excuse me so
while working on neto tv the app store
for tv os
so to backtrack a tiny bit
when you want to buy an app or a tweak
or anything else on the iphone ipad or
things of that nature when it's
jailbroken or just outside of apple's
parameters you got to go to a jailbroken
store you have cydia you have a bunch of
different i mean so city is how it all
started
silio supports it installer supports it
there's a bevy of installers that
support it but for the apple tv we
didn't have one that had any store
infrastructure until the store that i
recently released and launched around
the same time that this all happened
so i started on the untitled controller
project working up to this that soon
became end control
and if you've never heard of controllers
for all what it did is it made it
possible for the playstation 4 xbox one
wiimote and
i can't remember what other controllers
but there's maybe one or two more work
on your iphone your ipad if you were
jailbroken because you have
the mfi product of the mfi program that
i'm sure many of you if not all of you
are familiar with
that you got to be certified for it it
needs to have a lightning port it has to
have these number of buttons i don't
know if the layout is mandated but
either way it's very strict playstation
4 xbox one things of that nature we're
not on the list
sorry i realized my laptop wasn't
plugged in
last but not least
so my aim because the author of that
project i can't pronounce his name
properly so i'm not going to try he
works for um
forgetting the company name
celebrate he works for celebrate now
so
since he was too busy to do that because
that is his nine to five gig that's all
he does now
i took over and i'm like all right so
let's figure out a way to not only make
it work on ios but make it work on t or
make it work on ios again
tbos as well
so i started investigating what what uh
matthias ringwald he wrote his own
custom bluetooth stack for all of this
to work on the iphone but what that
meant the side effect of that was that
you had to completely tear down the
normal bluetooth stack because you
couldn't have two competing ones
so i'm like all right we'll just try to
use his make it work on more modern ios
and then after that
see if it works on tv os
there's a little tiny problem
the siri remote
that uses bluetooth i did not feel like
rewriting something or updating bt stack
to make that work
never mind
so plan b from there which should have
actually been plan b plan a for being
honest make it work natively the less
dependencies the better and it's also
harder for apple to restrict it or break
it if you're making things work native
sorry they kind of
nope they're not slow i'm slow
[Laughter]
march 2019
so 3 15 19 was the end control tbos and
ios release it was soft for tv os
because i didn't have my store up yet
but i was sick and tired of people
saying shut up and take my money
who wants to hear that and like not
actually be like okay
i wanted to launch it all at once but i
couldn't so i'm like let's just get it
out there and uh and patreon i started a
patreon account and patrons were the
only people that initially could get it
for tv os
but it wasn't like you had to continue
contributing it was like a one-time
thing so
buy it and cancel if you want or if you
continue to contribute it's up to you
there was no
requirement it was kind of like a thing
to get there to get it in people's hands
as early as possible
but yeah it was uh essentially as i
mentioned before the revamped version of
controllers for all but it worked it
works completely natively so you didn't
need bt stack and i thought it was gonna
be harder for apple to break it but they
actually broke it pretty quickly so
we'll get to that later
oh and if you want to see more info that
you can go to the wiki the awkward tv
wiki is the source of truth for all
apple tv jobs we have maintained it
since the very first apple tv and i
still maintain it to this day
so then
about 10 days later apple's like hey
guys apple arcade
it's going to come out playstation 4
xbox one all these games all the stuff
i'm sure you all heard of it at least
so it's like all right that's uh awesome
thanks guys
so i kind of felt like this
so at this point instead of being down
in the doldrums and like you know oh
what was me because this is the thing
like they sherlock stuff all the time we
have a term for it it's called sherlock
based on something they called sherlock
when they stole something else what did
they even steal or was it
i don't remember the exact story at this
point but it's
it's that bad that you should be ready
for it that's the point that's that's
the bullet point
so thinking of ways okay how can i make
end control attractive again so people
still want to buy it and i hadn't even
launched my store yet i was like if i
launched the store and it has the lap
where's the beef
so excuse me sorry
people had highly requested it to work
with this game called pub pubg
and they gave you one joystick support
really slowly so you have your right
joystick whether you like pan left and
right up and down and then the left
joystick as you imagine is supposed to
move you around they got as far as the
left joystick the right joystick ah we
don't feel like doing this so it's
partially there
just the rest of it didn't work which
was nice for me because that's the
hardest part because the way i made it
work i took it so it was just a
screenshot of the screen size whatever
so it needed some work it could have
been smarter but it's like oh this
button is here expect them to push here
i'm going to send this command that it
expects so it was just like
it's kind of like actually uh another
product that uh matthias made called
blue troll or blue control where you
literally would just be like take a
screenshot you would tell it where the
buttons were and then it would just
automatically click those for you
through mimic touch
events but since it was such an easy
thing and it was such a good template i
decided why don't i support all of these
other things as well sorry i'm
modulating a lot i need to like
all right anyway so like okay mobile
legends was highly recommended or
requested fifa was pro-evolution soccer
was so i supported all those as well
with very minimal code changes i cranked
all of these out after pub c was done
in maybe like a week so
pub c took a while because getting it to
move around based on navigation for the
left control that was still a disaster
so in august 2019 about six months after
all that happened
i finally released the neato tv store
and if you would like to know more about
it there's an introductory blog post
here and i will be releasing this it is
an app as you noticed i'll be releasing
it as the app and the slides as well
because what i did is i took a keynote
export it to html and this is loading it
through a web view this is how that app
works
so
once you first open neato tv the first
thing you would see is this app store it
has i tried to make it look as close as
what you're used to if you have an apple
tv and you go to the featured section
you go in here you see the top section
it kind of banners through it passes
through those are like the biggest most
important projects and then everything
is just categorized gaming is the first
one multimedia is the second there's
other categories below but this is kind
of just to give you the gist of what you
should expect if you actually go through
this process
end control is currently the only
project for now but that is going to
change in the near future and initially
you could only pay with amazon pay but
there is now paypal support as well
i will support next to other developers
selling on this because it's no fun if
it's just me as soon as possible that's
the next step that's the next phase for
the store setup
so once you actually select a paid
product or any product for that matter
but this is an example of a paid one you
can see you have the some info about it
you can say your name what's that what
uh what category goes in you have
screenshots below you can actually have
a screenshot to the right as well but i
didn't feel like i needed to go in
through every exhaustive detail just
kind of give you the gist of it
so after this
checkmate was released and this is one
of the most monumental occasions in the
history of this community i cannot
understate how amazing this is
so in late september
27 2019 to be exact uh checkmate slash
iphone dfu was released by axims
and i i just say we should run him for
president next i mean i'd vote for him
so as i mentioned there hasn't been
anything like this in about 10 years
shatter and lime rain were the only
things that are analogous to it they
were both boot rom exploits but they
didn't cover as many devices
as i mean you compare like the a4 and
that was all they could work on actually
the
i think shatter only worked on the a4 no
they both were a4 only but i think like
shatter even worked on more limited
devices than just that but the apple tv
will support it so i eventually had to
use it because the usb stack between i
think
let's see what became before i'll catch
the time what was that before that those
two like between there it just they
rewrote it and just broke everything so
i had to actually use it and
it was a lot of work it was fun but it
was a lot of work
so
what you can do with this the most
important part about it is you can
pretty much do anything it's like the
wild west it's like a renaissance right
now you can dump keys you can disable
kttr kpp uh
pack like all of that
gone
and it makes everything so much better
your phone actually runs better
jailbroken now because all those things
take cycles to get their thing done to
try and block and see are you doing
stuff you're not supposed to you get rid
of those cycles you're burning less
battery and your phone and device are
actually running better it's
like a miracle
um excuse me so the third and the fifth
apple tv or the third through the fifth
apple tv this exploit applies to all of
those
when he released iphone dfu it didn't
support any of them because he has a lot
of devices to support like you can see
the soc list he supported all of those
initially so i mean i couldn't begrudge
him
so
i mean he just released the best exploit
ever nobody could have wrote him
so moving along while everyone was
really buzzing and excited about this i
was really busy working on other things
at the same time playing catch up so to
speak because i just launched my store
or whatever so
i was not really i was excited about it
but i wasn't involved in it i was uh
discovering the fact that you can
unidirectionally which i will be demo in
a moment
send and receive files with airdrop on
the apple tv why apple left this out and
doesn't let us use it you're in your
guess is as good as mine i have no idea
but i wasn't about to let that go
sliding like that's amazing there's so
much potential
so i released breezy and ethereal in
really
horrible iterations it uses it used ns
distributed notification centers and if
you listen for that notification you'll
be like oh i like this file somebody
else be like oh i also like this file
thankfully it was just me in the
playground at the time so it didn't
really matter it was a nice little stop
gap just to kind of wet people's
appetite this is the kind of things that
are going to be possible what ethereal
is it allows you to airdrop videos of
pretty much anything that vlc or ffm can
can play straight to your apple tv and
they will play immediately
excuse me
i'm sorry aside from that i was also
updating uh chimera and elektra so
there was a lot of things on my plate i
didn't have time to be working on
anything with it
okay so here comes the airdrop demo
so i was going to try
and demo it through this app and i had
it working a moment ago and then it
tripped up again but i still want to
show you what it looks like so because
i'm doing this through an apple tv and i
wasn't anticipating having this awesome
screen down here i rolled my own thing
into air magic and what air magic is
it's a web server that runs and it just
listens for a few different uh
get commands you know like uh remote up
remote down whatever and it'll do that
for the remote it'll move it left it'll
move right so your apple tv can support
anything that supports a web browser
curl even to do the navigation
so i took air magic and i'm like why
don't i just augment that and have it do
some extra commands that it listens for
through maybe a different web server
because air magic is kind of old and not
my best code base and listen for a few
other things like you know current slide
next slide what are the things that i'm
looking for you're like what am i
working with so
to demonstrate it better so i don't
sound like a crazy person i'll just show
you what it looks like
after i ear drop it
okay
so if all goes well
oh and also i tried to implement it the
same as you expected anywhere else so if
you airdrop to this and other things
support photos which air photo does it
can also accept it but we want check
green tv to do it instead and there you
go
so that is an example of airdrop working
on the apple tv accepting
pretty cool right
i was very excited about this i was like
why aren't they letting us do this
i'll press menu get rid of it
ah tell me that
what
it's still showing up there
that's weird
this one i don't think is my fault
oh it probably triggered something over
there sorry guys
the siri one is really finicky so i only
trust this one i'll make sure i keep it
down here
thank you
so it actually wasn't my fault
[Laughter]
never mind sorry guys
so on to the juice the the meat the the
you know the whatever the best part of
the talk the thing that you're here for
i actually didn't make sure the speaker
works i should figure that out in a
second but we'll get to that so on to
check ring
there we go
okay so this is the first ios job ios tv
os whatever anything i guess t2 as well
now
he did that stuff while i was working on
this talk i wasn't even like aware of
what he was working on until he
announced it
that's pretty cool
but it's the first ios jailbreak using
checkmate to
actually because
nothing else used it was just kind of
like a proof of concept like this is the
cool stuff you're capable but this
actually put it into production and
released it out into the public and
could be used end to end to do the
entire the whole magilla
at the beginning of it i was not doing
any coding because it didn't work on the
apple tv at all so my main job at that
point was just debugging
and if this plays automatically that's
going to be awesome because since it's
not loading through
a web server and it's loading locally
it's a little finicky
so give me one second to get this one
properly
so i'm actually going to use scikrift
right now while ssh going to get this
moving
there we
go so when i was first doing this i was
using an iphone 6s plus and i was
filming the screen of my tv to get them
debug output i'm not kidding you
but wait it gets better look at this
next log
[Laughter]
did you get any of that
so
challenge accepted
uh the first thing that we ran into is
as part of stage two i can't get into
too much detail until it's completely
open but as part of stage three or at
the end of stage two somewhere in that
line
it looks for status check and it runs it
i don't remember exactly why it runs it
but it does it doesn't check to see her
i'm sorry it didn't check to see at the
time does this binary exist you assume
except they assumed it
existed i can talk on ios it'd be on tv
os didn't even think to look it did so
when you try to run a binary that wasn't
there based on the code and the way it
works it just completely shut down and
crashed and we had no idea why so once
that stump that once that uh roadblock
was
um
basic work sometimes once we got past
that roadblock
uh the next one was that for anything on
ios or tv os with arm64
can use could could i'm sorry could use
the same binary before this day you
could take an uh arm64 binary and then
just run it on tv os all the system if
all the frameworks are there and all the
dwld cache stuff is in place it would
work
flawlessly with 13 that all changed they
got very strict about this like you can
no longer do this and we didn't know
that so that was another one of those
things so like since we're doing this
while 13 is still kind of fresh and very
fresh for tv os it hadn't even been
jailbroken yet there's a lot of new
things we're looking into that we have
no clue about because nobody's figured
it out yet we're we're blazing that
trail to get to the next point tonight
that's next zone
um also i still actually have no jtag or
cereal on my apple tv for none so
debugging stuff especially when working
on check cream is very very very
challenging
[Music]
so when i finally got a monitor to do
this to film and that was like the main
reason i bought i mean it wasn't the
main reason but it was the reason i
bought it that day
it got a tiny bit better i mean this
part's still the same we hadn't made the
frame buffer smaller which is another
challenge because once it gets past the
screen you're like i don't know what
it's doing now
excuse me
so yeah once it's passed the asps
support then
does it get to the next step i mean we
know cause we see these next logs but
they're still not that much better
filming from this monitor so that was
still
very very challenging to
to debug
the next hurdle that i had to overcome
was
there's no loader for that we needed a
specific loader that was different from
ios for tv os and there's a few
different reasons this was the case and
i'm going to outline them now
so we
don't have multiple package managers
neato tv is the only game in town so
there's no need to have a bunch of
things to choose from if there's only
one like why are we going to make the
user press an extra button
if it's just gonna be what we choose for
them automatically anyway why even have
a button
there was also
is also a different payload and the
reason this is because things are just
different on apple tv you don't have the
same frameworks the ui doesn't work the
same you know the buttons are
essentially the same ui kit it's mostly
the same there's there's augmented parts
and there's also parts missing
so
all these things but like all these
things combined together
you shouldn't even try to combine the
code base for the ios and tbos loader
you're covered with a bunch of if defs
and it's just you know it's it's dirty
code and nobody really wants to do that
the unit the the post and installation
flow was different as well so on apple
tv the it still uses or not still
because ios never did it uses uh code
injection to get your icons showing up
on the screen it's messy i don't like it
but i still haven't found a way around
it yet so that's another thing that we
had to
overcome and figure out a way around
because as i'm going to mention later
tvos 13
added additional challenges to this
plate as well
and
on top of that i had to make a control
center widget so 13 tvs 13 introduced
control center
for the first time ever on apple tv
because we didn't have it before
so
i was like alright how do we get our
plugins there well one how do we write
plugins and two how do we get them in
there it's actually really easy you just
put them in this folder code's on them
they're good to go and the way i added
another domain is
normally you can only do system or
system library now you can do library i
felt it was good to keep them separate
what if somebody has names something
sleep or name something something else
apple's already used if you overwrite
them you're going to have a bad time
but i decided since i discovered this
around the same time let's make a check
brain widget
if the loader doesn't open up
automatically because it has to because
it's still invisible they can just go
into the control center open it up the
loader will kick off so it's kind of
like a stop gap but also it kind of
looks cool
it's obvious you can see the arrows
pointing to it
it stands out obviously
so the next step how do these things
work i took the sleep module that was
already in there that you probably saw
on the previous screen and i just class
dumped it and started reversing it it
was very simple i didn't imagine it was
harder to call one command sleep
whatever it does or whatever it did at
the time
and you have the content view i'm sorry
i'll start with the button style you
have three different small medium and
large the small is kind of a square that
doesn't even fill up the entire
the entire like control center section
and then the medium does fill up half of
it and then the large fills up the whole
thing
so for the check grain you don't really
need like the whole size so it was just
the the medium one
the next up is the content view
controller
and that just tells you what has what
does the button look like what image is
it showing it doesn't have text on it
things of that nature it's pretty
humdrum i made it a template image so if
you go between light and dark mode it'll
still work uh let's see here handle
action that's what happens when you
click the button
and dismiss after action so if you don't
have that as true the control center
will stay far not like stay up until it
automatically goes away from being idle
or whatever as long as you wanted to so
if you wanted to go away afterwards
dismas dismiss after action true
um okay yes that's right so about the
hidden section or the hidden issue
if you add any of these tags that
they
i honestly i tried to figure out this
entire process and it was just too much
reversing it too many boards board all
the boards they have like
springboard no sorry pine board
backboard headboard uh
splashboard let's see there's a few and
but all of those things it's not just
those things as applications they have
daemons they have frameworks they have
helpers they have so many different
things that you have to reverse to
figure out this process as far as i got
so pb application to backup a tiny bit
you don't have springboard on ios we
have
uh pine board and headboard those are
like two those two apps combined give
you everything you expect from
springboard but on the apple tv so pb
application obviously is board
application so the shared info store
uh the policy that you get from there
the exclusion tags are the exact same as
the pbs exclusion tags in ls application
workspace i think i hit pay dirt on this
at one point a while ago and i just
didn't remember exactly where it was so
i know that somehow those
variables those instances interact at
some point and that's where pine board
gets it from in ls application workspace
and it stores it in this array how it
gets there i haven't completely figured
that out yet
but hopefully once i do you know that'll
get rid of the whole code injection
thing the reason this is important is if
you have any of these three tags inside
of sb app tags in your info p list they
don't check anything about your
application except if it's code signed
so it'll get right through the door does
not matter but there's a caveat you
can't see it
kind of a bummer
so here's an actual demo i have to play
this video the same way i did the other
ones let's hope it works out oh did it
play itself nope okay
there we go
so this is what you see after you plug
in
or after you run check brain on your
apple tv once it reboots after you see
like the whole the the loader and
everything else and all the text up
there it goes to this very quickly like
you'll see your home screen from home
screen for one second and this will pop
up automatically start downloading
after it downloads once it's done the
first thing you'll see immediately well
not immediately but within like 30
seconds is neato tv
so end to end
end to end after you do this
the next thing that happens as far as
you know as a user you don't touch
anything you just get neato tv
immediately
so
i tried to make a pretty seamless
process
big money big money no i mean
stop
and there's the light mode version
[Applause]
thank you
so some of the issues that i mentioned a
moment ago with the ui cache obstacles
you still need code injection and on top
of that tv os 13 as i also mentioned
uh it had an extra challenge added it
had another layer of protection it went
through for you to be able to see the
app so i had to figure out what that was
thankfully it was really really really
easy
so as you see at the very top
that was the way i did it up to 12. so
nine through 12 this was sufficient with
the code injection i don't even think
nine or ten actually nine and ten didn't
need it at all 11 and 12 did and then 13
pbf info is enabled true done
[Music]
yeah i got to get there there's me being
a little dirty on twitter i had to get
believed
so
i was
one of the things that was another issue
with this because there's so many issues
piled on top of each other is substrate
mobile substrate we use that for code
injection again because on when i worked
on chimera and electro before this we
use substitute instead and comex made uh
an open source version of mobile
substrate that's called substitute
nobody ever really adapted till this
point so it's still missing it was and
still is missing things that mobile
substrate had had long hand
but since i couldn't get any kind of
code injection working because that all
worked based on stuff i'm not going to
get into today there's just too much
i had to use this old method which was
possible again to get code injection
working
so i took the pine board app renamed it
to pine board bro and then made into a
shell script in places that was
executable and then when i re-sprung
everything it would just give me code
injection it would work again this is
something we hadn't been able to do in a
long time because nobody really bothered
to do all the patches necessary we
didn't need to make as many i don't
think just because the virtue of the
awesomeness of
checkmate so 10 16 19 it was the very
very first day that check green had
worked on an apple tv for and it was
awesome it was a lot it was a labor of
love that took a very long time and it
was a very exciting day
the very next day we decided to or i
decided to tease the pins that we had
found so
based on some stuff i'll kind of get a
little bit into in a moment we found out
that the ethernet port has a trap door
inside of it that has some pins exposed
that some special cables can get to or
some enterprising people can figure out
how to do stuff with otherwise
and it turns out this is from the ifixit
teardown they completely miss these pins
these pins are on the ethernet port and
they connect inside of that trapdoor but
we didn't give that whole reveal at this
point we just teased these pins and
people just started guessing because it
was fun
on the 22nd we had the first diag the
first
it wasn't serial but we had some kind of
diagnostic output like when you plug
something in an eye recovery and you you
boot comes up or it's not even in
recovery mode it has to be in some maybe
dfu in dfu mode you'll get this whole
printout that you'll see in a minute
that says i boot your serial number cpid
bb ddid all that stuff so that was the
first time at that point we also got
that as well on the 4k
[Music]
let's see oh and the code code injection
i showed on the previous slide
and this is probably going to be my
favorite part but i can't talk as much
about it as i'd like to
so allegedly on this day uh a sand paper
a piece of sandpaper and it's not like
one of those things that you
professionally put down on it an actual
piece of sandpaper might have gone
directly onto a nand inside of an apple
tv
allegedly to get it into dfu mode
to back up a tiny bit normally on any
apple tv up until the 4k
you press menu play pause on this on the
serial mode as illustrated in the
picture to get it into dfu mode as long
as you're plugged into usb which is also
issued because they don't give nearly
took it away
but as long as you're in there and it's
powered on that should kick it into dfu
mode on the 4k it does not
so we found out you can get into
recovery mode still with this redacted
device that i really can't get into um
that i may or may not have
um you could get into recovery using a
special version of the bimobile device
that nikias had put together that had
wi-fi support he hadn't released it at
the time he may have by now i'm honestly
not sure
we figured out it does see it in
recovery mode but the next question
doesn't see it in dfu mode once we know
it sees it in dfu mode you know game
over we own this thing for life
when we did it we did verify that dfu
mode worked i guess i should have said
that too
so a friend of mine that follows me on
twitter decided if you're not familiar
with the virgin and chad meme format i'm
hoping everybody is i don't have to
explain it do i
okay nobody said anything okay good
so this kind of explains itself red snow
was a way that things were jailbroken
back in the day that nobody really uses
anymore so they thought it'd be funny if
that was the verb virgin and the chad
was supposedly me supposedly sanding
dance
[Laughter]
so then from here i decided to have some
fun with radian he is the head of
security for apple i think software and
hardware i could be wrong i know
definitely hardware though um
and you know like have a little fun with
them show them a picture of stuff in dfu
mode add the little eyeball emojis those
come in later too because i needed those
later to find these tweets
the next thing here you can see there's
the diagnostics i was speaking about
earlier so you have
the you know the iboot info you can you
can verify based on all these things
except the redacted serial number that
this is indeed an apple tv 4k in dfu
mode
from here you can see the first time
that little steve ran it on the 4k and
if you actually take a good look you can
kind of see his outline
like taking the picture
and then of course
i had to point out my name they're very
tiny
there was oh and you can also see here
this is a good illustration remember how
it was really big when the frame buffer
like kind of went off the screen this is
how we solve that issue make it smaller
so moving on to the 4k stuff and little
steve and uh some people from
celebrating i hate snow and some other
people put amazing amounts of effort
into isolating where these pins were
because there's a ton of different pins
we don't have any kind of um diagnostics
not diagnostics any kind of blueprints
on how these things work there's a
proper term for that i can't think of we
didn't have any of that stuff like none
of that stuff is leaked as we know for
any of the apple tvs
so it was kind of just like hey test
this pin test this pen test this pin
it's very challenging and he went
through amazing amount of work and he
did apple tvs to get what he did
as you can see here so this was him
actually spilling the beans on if you
pull that down there you can see the
trapdoor there's the pins and
presumably we can get dfu and everything
else through these things we just
haven't figured out how yet
this is an example of his first
generation of the breakout board and all
this does i say all this does is if it's
like a small thing you press that button
you get in dfu you run check green you
have a jailbroken 4k
this is the first version of any of this
that has ever worked or ever existed we
obviously want to move more towards
something that doesn't have the
necessity to solder stuff or take it
apart at all you know we won't be able
to actually utilize that port that we
teased just a moment ago
so i'm literally just going to read
these verbatim because he wrote this
slide for me so i don't even need to
write read it they all just kind of just
go through it and say what i can about
it but
the first things that he was doing to
trying to get into dfu mode didn't
succeed to get it into dfu in any kind
of useful way at all it i think it was
aop that would get in the way so you
would boot into dfu and then within i
think 10 to 15 seconds it would panic
and then just go straight back to user
land to just normal mode
so i think that yeah the third time it
was the third time that he did that he
had two different times the first one no
dfu the second one it was an
illegitimate dfu and then the third was
to use the pcie set and nvme or nvme
to enter dfu with no discernible side
effects so this is the way that he
figured out these are the things that
you need to touch in this fashion with
whatever crazy technical equipment to
get this thing in dfu mode
any further technical explanation we'll
have to be on another day when he gives
a talk about it and as we move towards
products that will be easier for people
to use so you don't need a soldering
iron keep your eye on guardian app.com
for more information on that
so the aftermath i was absolutely
consumed with tv os 13 support because
we were working on the jailbreak at the
same time that i was just being
introduced to how tvos 13 is different
in the first place i had a ton of things
to do i had a lot of stuff to update
there was much work to be done
so part of that was the fact that
elektra and chimera used substitute for
code injection but substrate was used on
check brain so i had to i didn't have to
split into two separate apps repos but
running an app repo really isn't my
specialty i can do it i've been doing it
for a long time but i'm no expert at it
like sam banger like he's a he's much
bigger much better expert at this and
that's why i tried and i actually didn't
try i started to migrate over to
electric products because at that point
i don't have to manage app and d package
anymore any of those things with the
repo just my own packages and just the
stuff for the store
and also at that point then it would be
merged with however the rest of check
rain works because they use his repo i
want to use his repo too there's just a
lot of things to sort through and i
don't want to rush it out because i'm
not doing that anymore
that's empty
so next slide
so here because up to this point with
apple tv hacking there's been other
people involved but i've kind of not to
be like
you know boast about it but i kind of
single-handedly kept the thing alive for
a very long time releasing most of the
projects on my own
so at this point since all this stuff
had happened a few other people started
getting interested now we have theming
as you saw when the big reveal came from
the apple tv open there was theming on
the apple tv so spark dev introduced
that he ported his version of his
snowboard theming engine over to tvos
and he's done a beautiful job with it it
still needs a little bit of tweaking for
tvos 13 but for the most part it works
perfectly
and then i i don't know if this is going
to demo properly hopefully the audio is
going to work let me plug it in but the
next slide is going to be me demoing
something from uh
i killed apple called uh harlem shake tv
which is
only a demo can explain it oh sorry i
skipped over my class part
so
i've been talking about this for a long
time and i've been promising and i it is
still coming just more things have come
up i'm going to be teaching a free class
on everything i know how to do on the
apple tv and everything i've ever known
how to do completely free no strings
attached
hopefully as soon as possible hopefully
this month
by latest next month it will absolutely
start
it i don't know the full format of it
yet and this talk isn't about that but i
will say briefly it'll probably be like
a video every couple of weeks and then a
forum and
maybe discord or one of those kind of
things where you can just group together
i'll have time every couple of days that
i'll devote just to that to answer
questions so that's kind of something
that i want to launch and i want to let
people know about it because i really
want to get people involved
okay so instead of showing a video here
i want to actually demo it in action
and i don't think this is paired right
now so give me one second to make sure
that's going to work
oh it is okay now it just connected okay
so hopefully
i'll put this in here
this just
works fingers crossed
it is not we are not getting audio
oh there it is
so i'll just have to do whatever he did
in that movie
i didn't plug it i'm sorry i'll plug it
back in
it's almost over anyway
i should use the mic sorry
[Music]
you get the idea though
it's not useful but it's cool as hell
and the next slide was just questions so
questions
oh sorry thank you for everything thank
you for the confidence thank you for
bringing me here guardian love you all
questions
one of the things i wanted to do is one
more thing is i bought a raspberry pi
for this i wanted to make it so i could
have an untether on the apple tv using a
raspberry pi because it's totally
possible but i just didn't get it done
in time
so
that's going to be one solution
obviously the that isn't the best size
of something i mean it's okay for the
apple tv to tuck behind something you
don't have to worry about looking at it
but obviously you want something more
minimal and we're gonna work towards
that but we gotta get it working in some
form first proof of concept and then
move forward from there
i don't see why it couldn't work
i haven't played with it but
completely feasible
for check
i think like
30 megs 40 mags something like that if
even that
good question i'm hoping we can use some
of that amazing text loading stuff we
heard about earlier
all right awesome so bringing a few
advice schedules
again round of applause
come on