a San Francisco before we get started I
just want to thank the organizers
volunteers and speakers for beside San
Francisco and to all of you for spending
time with me today my name is Miranda
and this is my first conference talk
ever so thanks for being so warm and
inviting to me I go by oh hi Miranda on
Twitter with a 0 and a 1 in my handle if
you'd like to tweet at me and I'll also
be making a b-side slack channel called
arcades and audits after this to post my
slides and and to answer any lingering
questions you may have and it also
really like to hear your stories and
connect with you this avatar was made by
the amazing Tim Walsh and thanks to him
for accurately capturing the stickers
that live on my Chromebook although you
can tell it was made a little while ago
because I have even less real estate on
that thing now I'll link his contact
information in the slack channel if
you'd like to look him up I work at duo
security a company that helps protect
all users devices and applications using
a zero trust platform I specifically
work on the team responsible for duis
infrastructure and operations or as some
people call us the guys who work on
resolving issues in the middle of the
night when everyone else is sleeping
here's where I give a quick shout out to
the ladies and Envy's who work in
operations and security but being fast
on our feet is necessary when our
service goes down our customers who have
configured duo to fail closed or
protected but that means that when our
service goes down so does theirs to make
sure that we're fast and efficient we
practice responding to outages we're
obligated to perform business continuity
disaster recovery drills twice a year
for our EPCs audit but we also have
other obligations throughout the year
and we also just practice Incident
Response to make sure that our ops game
is strong and our team has individuals
from varied backgrounds in operations
insecurity and having these drills hones
cross departmental collaboration root
cause analysis and also just builds up
confident levels around these sorts of
alerts
so storytime think about where you were
when the last time a natural disaster
affected you or your work if you live or
work north of here perhaps you were
affected by the California wildfires
that happened in October in November
last year I consider myself really
fortunate because I haven't been as
impacted as that I've never needed to
evacuate my home when I was first hired
at doooo though I remember how I wasn't
allowed to have computers that my first
week on the job it is incredibly
difficult as an engineer to go through
onboarding without a computer but it was
because of the devastation that was
happening in Puerto Rico because of
Hurricane Maria the agency they're
responsible for reporting as part of my
background check was unreachable and ooh
I didn't want to give me access to
production systems without verifying my
background check understandably it was
the least I could do to be patient and
thankful that my friends and family were
safe while I was frustrated the it was
found out that the total death count
attributable to hurricane maria exceeded
4,600 people I don't know the name of
the agency but the fact that this
organization was able to resume business
operations to ensure the security of
their customers is a testament to their
disaster recovery plan in action I was
able to get my computers in about a week
and that's pretty incredible here's a
less devastating example fire causes
company customers to lose access to
accounts this one happened recently just
last month and I've blocked the name of
the company here because this is a
blameless presentation we see examples
like this all the time when everything's
fine companies using reliable services
and micro services are able to maintain
three or four nines of uptime for most
companies that level of uptime is
appropriate however when your company's
service is being relied on for the
standard of living of for other people
or basic human needs you have a
responsibility to build resiliency and
redundant
see interior platform identifying single
points of failure and planning for
disasters is paramount but that's why we
plan for this just as no services immune
to outages no one is exempt from natural
disasters either your company doesn't
have to be using chaos engineering right
now in order to rock at BCD are planning
all it takes as a plan and proper
preparation now that we have our frame
set let's put your big beautiful brains
to work and make it be a business
continuity disaster recovery plan now if
you're wondering what a business
continuity disaster recovery plan is
think of it as a plan that assists
during disruptive catastrophes that
would otherwise interrupt business
operations but there are really two
parts here so let's break them out the
business continuity is about making sure
essential functions continue to operate
with minimal or no downtime whatsoever
during and after a disaster or
disruption a business continuity policy
can be for a specific business unit or
it can apply to the whole organization
on the other hand a disaster recovery
policy it counts for restoring data or
applications if infrastructure is
damaged or destroyed these two concepts
can get smooshed together but it's
important to keep them separate and
distinct you can see the examples here
of payroll during an earthquake and a
data center availability issue of
California were just to fall into the
sea as addressing different issues the
continuity of business ops and the data
restoration in order for a drill to be a
true BCD Artest it has to involve
disruption of operations and prove that
your team is capable of the data
recovery an important aspect of BCD our
drills is to learn your acronyms the
recovery time objective is the maximum
expected time by which your service is
expected to be restored when your
service goes down what is your service
level agreement to your customers how
long would it take for you to recover
your data and reinstate it in the new
system
the RTO is related but different to the
recovery point objective the RPO
describes the limit of time that can
pass during a disruption before the
quantity of the data loss during the
period exceeds the BCD ours maximum
allowable threshold when you lose
customer data what is the oldest
allowable backup that you're willing to
restore your RPO defines the policy like
no backups older than a day old then
there's time to resolution or T TR t TR
is defined as the elapsed time at which
you can fully recover a file or a full
system from the disaster and this
measure has a certain RPO and RTO
associated with it here's what I hope is
a simple example of RT o RP o and T TR
in action suppose your company backs of
databases to tape and the process takes
two hours you've scheduled your system
to back up the information twice a day
outside of peak traffic hours at 6 a.m.
and 6 p.m. with this in mind your
company doesn't believe that it should
restore backup that's older than a day
24 hours old because that information
will be too stale and it's already
getting backed up twice a day they also
believe that restoring a backup should
take no more than two hours so you have
an RTO of two hours now imagine you're
living your best life going about your
business when you realize through
monitoring alerting or otherwise that
one of your tapes failed at 1400 hours
or 2 p.m. the most recent backup should
have been made at 8:00 a.m. 6:00 a.m.
plus the two hours to backup so the most
recent backup would have been made at
8:00 a.m. between 8 a.m. and 2 p.m.
means that your recovery point actual
would have been 8 hours and if it takes
2 hours to restore data from tape then
the recovery time actual would have been
2 hours so you would hate your RTO and
RPO if you were able to restore data in
one hour your T TR would have been one
hour and it still would have satisfied
your RTO and RPO but what if your backup
at six a.m. was faulty and you had to
use a backup from
6:00 p.m. the day before that would be a
20 hour recovery time actual but hooray
for you that's still under your RPO if
your team took three hours to resolve it
however your art TTR would be three
hours and you wouldn't have satisfied
the arty oh that was a lot but let's
move on okay so the first step in
designing your organization's BCD our
plan is to inventory your company's
assets and prioritize what to protect
start with some basic questions like
what does your company do what are your
customers do what do they rely on you
for how do they use your service across
the board restoring your primary service
to customers is probably priority zero
or the most critical need that and
expectations that your customers have at
duo we focus on whether or not one of
our customers can authenticate we
collect key metrics around
authentications what kind of
authentication is it is it a mobile put
passcode a push a phone call a hard
token or something else what is the
latency associated with that
authentication is the latency associated
with a specific customer or does it
encompass an entire deployment depending
on what in the production path has
failed and is impeding authentication we
also prioritize bringing certain
services up again the question then
becomes how do you test the team
responsible for bringing these services
back up naturally the National Institute
of Science and Technology has a standard
around these exercises they have a
standard for everything while 834 is
specific to contingency planning for
federal information systems these
standards can be used for a multitude of
audit requirements they break it down
into two realms tabletop and functional
exercises tabletop exercises are
discussion-based s-- participants meet
in a room or video channel and for a
given example our given scenario explain
what steps they would take to respond to
an emergency scenario this is akin to
dungeon Dungeons & Dragons
tabletop game in which a person called
the dungeon master or diem sets the
scene of her players maintains pace and
provides dynamic feedback the
facilitator of the tabletop exercise
drills participants on what roles
responsibilities coordination and
decisions they would make its tabletop
exercise is discussion based only and
doesn't involve deploying equipment or
other resources for this reason tabletop
exercises are easy to set up don't have
the infrastructure that needs to be
doubt spun down after the event ends and
might be more comfortable for less
experienced participants on the flipside
tabletop exercises can be tricky if
scenarios have a lot of complex moving
parts participants must say what roles
they're assuming what actions are taking
and who they'd communicate with which
can be difficult for a large team taking
concurrent actions across multiple
departments understandably facilitators
or DMS must also be experienced and able
to improvise with target objectives in
mind lastly I've found that it can be
harder to get a sense of urgency if
participants are and familiar with
role-playing tabletop exercises or games
and if you saw Mel Masterson's
presentation on tabletop exercises
you're all experts at this now the other
kind of exercise that NIST recommends is
the functional exercise participants in
a functional exercise are given a
simulated environment which they need to
respond to an emergency scenario in and
the exercises can vary in scope from
validating specific aspects of a-b-c-d
our drill to full-scale exercises that
address all elements of the BCD our plan
this could be something as simple as
restoring a database or it could be as
complex as an entire availability zone
outage a functional exercise provides a
more practical experience with systems
in the event of a catastrophe it's also
way easier to get a sense of urgency
when you can send tests Victor ops or
pager Duty alerts to people in the same
room as you which I get great personal
satisfaction from
it's kind of like the movie wargames if
you haven't seen the movie a high school
student connects to a system that
doesn't immediately reveal itself and it
in an attempt to change his grades in
actuality he connects to a supercomputer
capable of the go/no-go decision making
in the event of a nuclear attack a
supercomputer was programmed to
continuously run war simulations and
learn overtime in perfect 1980s
cheesiness david the high school student
thinks he's really playing games when
he's about to start World War 3
I won't spoil the ending although the
movie is 36 years old and you all should
know that there are spoilers on the
Internet but the computer concludes that
nuclear war is a strange game and the
only winning move is not to play
unlike wargames your functional exercise
should be separate from production
systems not accessible by the public but
still providing that exhilarating
experience that will help your BCD our
drill participants learn what their
roles and responsibilities are in
disaster scenario however functional
exercises can take a large time
investment to spin up safe systems
parallel to what you're using in
production all artifacts and
infrastructure will need to be
deconstructed after the event as well so
if you're short on time a tabletop
exercise may be the way to go at this
point you may be thinking I know I need
to do a b c d air drill for compliance
reasons which could be for the
electronic prescriptions for controlled
substances or service organization
control - or FedRAMP or a dozen other
regulations out there but unlike you
Miranda I'm not a huge gamer nerd why
should I make this into a game and I
would say well friend I got news for you
and by news I mean science backed peer
reviewed journals
there are studies being published all
the time that tout the benefits for
playing video games and I can bomb that
Valier and green's article video games
play that can do serious good the
authors discuss how video games teach
players to
seed on a set of tasks that are
initially quite difficult levels in an
arcade game start with more simple and
introductory controls an increase in
difficulty over time as players begin to
master them not dissimilar to the
concept of spiral curriculum in
educational psychology when a game is
constructed correctly players have been
shown to have higher levels of retention
and are able to call upon those skills
more quickly in the future
in addition applying skills in a variety
of contexts helps with decision-making
for example if you have operations
engineers they might be familiar with
the concept of bringing up services and
a new availability zone from company
documentation but if they haven't done
that themselves they might not be super
familiar with it and a functional
exercise or a video game would help with
that the article argues in favor of the
idea that games that constantly
challenge different aspects of
perception attention and cognition in a
variety of contexts are likely to help
result in enhancements of these base
abilities the interactiveness of a game
also has an effect over methods of
learning Indy biasing decisions improved
decision-making with a single training
intervention a team of researchers from
cast Business School Carnegie Mellon
University and others pondered whether
different learning tools would affect
participants cognitive biases
participants either received a single
training intervention watched a video or
played a video game the interactive
games provided participants with
personalized feedback on how biased they
were during gameplay with the
opportunity to practice decisions and
learn strategies to reduce their
propensity to commit various biases
which the six tested by C's were biased
blind spot confirmation bias fundamental
attribution error anchoring projection
and representativeness it was a
page-turner
the first experiment addressed three of
these biases and the second experiment
built on that foundation and addressed
the other three biases the average
reduction of bias over these two
experience was 17% more effective using
video games over just a video in the
short term and 10% more effective over a
longer term two or three months period
in other words gamifying the lesson
instead of using traditional classroom
style learning or videos provided more
of a benefit in the same amount of time
investment so don't get overwhelmed when
thinking about preparing a/b c/d our
drill or participating one if you're new
to the fields it might seem a bit
overwhelming
however gamifying drills is positive
reinforcement it'll be fun while you're
training and when the real thing happens
and you need to be quick on your feet
the steps you'll take will be second
nature to you now that we've looked into
the why and how of organizing a/b c/d
our drill I'd like to share my three
best practices for running a successful
event care make it remote in time box it
care this is more than just having
empathy for the people that you're
orchestrating this PCD our drill for
it's actually caring about your drill
making sure that the details are
accurate that it tells a whole story and
that you're able to define what is and
what is not part of the drill that part
is key make sure you provide enough
context for participants and let them
know what the boundaries are for the
drill your people might get distracted
by a red herring so make sure there are
enough people scribing are not actively
participating who know what the scenario
is that can guide participants I find
that one facilitator to three
participants is a good figure
but scale up with complexity also keep
in mind that your teammates are human
they are mere mortals who require
sustenance
when the Adrenaline's going they might
not think about basic human needs like
eating I love to eat I have found that
food is an excellent bribe to get
volunteers to participate and goes a
long way when energy starts to wane
during the drill there can be a lot of
excitement
the drill so so just like with phishing
campaign exercises make sure your people
know that they don't have to feel
ashamed if they make a mistake it's all
part of a learning experience even if
they don't hit their RTO or your
company's RTO lastly in my experience
there's always something to iterate and
improve on during a/b c/d our drill and
when you care about your people and the
exercise others will be more likely to
help out and take on action items after
the drill is over
make it remote it's difficult to have
everyone on the team get together for a
one-hour meeting let alone one that
spans a few hours or all day with this
in mind plan your drill so that people
can participate without having to be in
the same room while the convenient part
of a drill is that you don't have to
evacuate earth to get to a safe spot in
a real disaster you might have to
relocate or work remotely even if you
don't have a distributed team there
might be a chance that someone who
wanted to participate had their own
little disaster crop up and so making it
remote will help them be a part of that
also make sure that your people know
where to look for clarification or
resources in a shared folder directory
or safe branch of your repos to work in
on my caring slide I also mentioned how
food is great bribe and that I love food
if it's within your company's means
letting remote employees expense a lunch
goes a long way and lets them feel like
they're in the room even if they can't
be timebox it all arcade games have a
set limit for you to complete a level in
having a be CDR drill that lasts all day
is inhumane and you will make many
enemies if you do that unless you want
to fight in some epic boss battles keep
your drills time box to a couple of
hours enough time for participants to
take a solid try on hitting your
company's RTO and if you feel up for a
debrief work where participants can
share feedback on the drill and
processes to improve on I like to
schedule the debrief later in the same
day so that participants can decompress
and compile what they just went through
but not so far in the future that it
isn't fresh I would also caution
organisers to avoid scheduling the
debrief
more than a week or two after the event
in summary business continuity disaster
recovery drills may be mandatory for
audits but just because you and your
team have an obligation to practice
doesn't mean that it should feel like a
chore establishing feasible recovery
time and recovery point objectives are
important to balance your service level
agreements to customers and practicing
often will help your team's mean time to
resolution making sure to prioritize the
right aspects of your business
operations and gamifying the experience
for your team will help set them up for
success when the real disaster comes
remember what formats are available to
you when conducting your be CDR drill
the tabletop exercises discussion-based
and while it's easier to set up it
requires that the physical facility is
experienced and can provide dynamic
feedback a functional exercise uses
infrastructure similar to what you'd be
using in production while participants
may get a more hands-on experience with
a functional exercise spinning that
infrastructure up and down might be
harder with a time constraint also
remember the three best practices for
running a be CDR care about the drilling
your team and support them with the
proper resources make it remote friendly
since if you had to do a disaster
recovery for realsies you wouldn't have
the benefit of being co-located plus you
can never prepare for all the little
disasters that might crop up lastly make
sure you time box the event to a few
hours so that your team can try to hate
your company's RTO and TTR and all of
those other acronyms as well but not so
long that it's insufferable these are
the video games that I referenced and
their release dates and thanks to you
all for being here
[Applause]
awesome thank you so much Miranda we do
have a few minutes for questions if you
have you can raise your hand and I can
bring the mic to you it's oh hi Miranda
with a 0 and a 1 instead of an O and an
eye you're welcome you're getting a lot
of fun
the question was what is the best way to
get buy-in when doing a tabletop
exercise for that I would say making a
great argument and getting buy-in from
leadership goes a long way at duo our BC
DRS usually involve our operations team
and our security team because we try to
bundle like Incident Response with
security response and so we have a
really great relationship across
departments and that helps a lot but
there's also a really strong argument
for you know if you're feeling a time
crunch a tabletop exercise is definitely
the way to go
great question yes the question was what
elements of gamification do you find
most valuable among employees my team
gets really competitive and having that
sense of urgency is really great for
finding things to really hone in on we
have a lot of subject matter experts and
I try to construct the drills so that
the subject matter experts don't make
decisions for the entire team like I had
one drill where I split the team up into
three sub teams and I named them Atari
Bally Astor Cade and Commodore teams a B
and C and I had one subject matter
expert on each side
team and I found that that was really
great because the subject matter expert
could disseminate information on their
sub team and it wasn't like those three
subject matter experts were driving the
drill I hope that answers your question
I can't see in the back if there are any
questions up there I think we're good
awesome thank you so much once again
Miranda and here
[Applause]
[Music]