Josh please take it away Thanks good
point it's good this could potentially
replace some products you're gonna see
at RSA this week so thanks everyone for
coming to my talk and thanks to the
organizers for inviting me to speak this
talks focused on tools and techniques
you can use to identify and detect
malicious files in your enterprise the
first third of the talk is going to be
an overview of detection oriented file
analysis while the last two thirds will
be a bit more technical we'll end up
walking through a real world example of
detecting malicious attributes in a
document file so before I jump into the
the details I just wanted to quickly
highlight my background I've been
working in threat detection for six
years currently work at Target I'm a
lead engineer in their cyber fusion
center and you can find me all over the
various social sites with my handle
right there also I work from home so I
wanted to give a shout out to my
perennial co-workers of the year over
here on the right so my talk today
really is to try to convince you to
consider adding detection oriented file
analysis to your threat detection
program because it resolves a data
visibility gap that goes unaddressed by
tools like antivirus and now our
sandboxes and it's a data visibility gap
that you definitely or probably have to
start sometimes it's helped a little
look at a definition I consider this
kind of file analysis to be any that
enables real-time threat detection
through enrichment extraction and
metadata collection the goal of a system
that does this kind of analysis is to
collect enough data to allow defenders
to either automatically or manually
identify adversaries in their network so
systems that do this have two defining
traits to me first
they generate a lot of file metadata
from which you derive insight and second
they are or should be relatively easy to
integrate with the detection systems you
currently have while also being
customizable to your needs
so definitions are nice but the
the real question is you know what's in
it for you if you decide to use a system
like this so the important thing to keep
in mind about what I'm going to describe
next is that these systems need to do
all their tasks quickly and at scale in
order to support real-time detection in
a large enterprise
so first the sis this kind of systems
provide a pretty comprehensive level of
detail across all kinds of files and
that's important so defenders always
have a consistent data set to work from
this includes most commonly performing
simple tasks like hashing every file
with md5 or shot 256 next these systems
commonly perform recursive file analysis
that is they extract files from within
other files and submit them to the
analysis and analysis engine for
processing you might normally think that
this only applies to something like
archive files but it also equally
applies to documents images even text
files can contain other files and it's
important that all those files are
supported and finally there are just
some files that you see in your
enterprise that are more interesting
than others and those always tend to get
special treatment and these kinds of
systems
this would include something like
targeting a specific type of metadata
that's used to identify adversary
activity for example doing verbose data
collection of an executables import
address table could be important to you
that kind of idea having you know file
specific metadata inspection applies to
dozens and dozens of kinds of files so
what's especially interesting to me
about this kind of analysis is that it's
a really very underused in the active
threat detection space there aren't a
lot of organizations who are doing this
despite it being highly valuable this is
a release timeline of systems that
people commonly reference when they talk
about doing this kind of file analysis
the main thing I want to point out about
this list is that these systems share
common design patterns but they have
different intended purposes the three
I've highlighted here are commonly used
as detection and intelligence-gathering
systems while some of the others are
more focused on scan
malware or automating mundane analyst
tasks so in this presentation I'll be
talking about strelka which is the
project that I open sourced under target
last year but you know if any of what I
say today piques your interests
I'd suggest you take this list review
the projects on it and see which ones
may best fit your requirements and use
cases so now we'll talk about Strelka if
you're not familiar with her she's one
of the one of the second-generation
Soviet space dogs to achieve orbital
flight and the project is named as such
because it borrows the system
architecture from Lockheed Martin's like
a project so when it came time to name
this project I wanted to pay homage to
their work through the name the system
can be simplest described as a recursive
static file analysis system that's built
on Python and 0 mq one of the most
significant changes we've made to this
project compared to some of the other
ones that were shown earlier is that we
don't support Python - when it came time
to start thinking about what the design
of a new system like this would be I
knew Python - couldn't be supported
because it's a you know it's end of life
is supposedly coming up very soon next
year so out of the box
strelka will produce event data for over
60 unique kinds of files and we place a
pretty significant focus on files that
are likely to be used for malicious
purposes normally you might think of
documents and executables as files that
are likely to be used maliciously but
something like HTML could be just as
malicious as an executable given the
right context this project has a what I
think are a number of unique features
many of them are described in the github
page for it some of my favorites that
are real differentiators are the focus
on scanning text-based files I mentioned
HTML we also support xml visual basic
code javascript batch script many more
and the project is heavily focused on
language neutral components so we use 0
mq for networking we use protobuf for
the messaging format we use Yammer for
the configuration files the project call
or is written in Python but you know
technically you could write portions of
it in nearly any language you want that
is supported by those components so here
we have a system architecture diagram of
strelka the two important things they
immediately call out here are the dotted
lines running north to south those are
Network hops so this is a distributed
system and the second thing is the
components in the center so those two
components constitute a cluster now from
a deployment point of view strokers
primary goal is to integrate with
whatever existing systems you have for
detection as seamlessly as possible on
the front end that means that clients
tend to be things like network security
monitoring sensors and that they just
continuously push files to the cluster
on the back end the event data is
written in Jason and you really can do
whatever you want with it most users end
up sending it to a centralized log
aggregation system like Splunk or
elastic you could also just stick it in
an on pram or cloud database we don't
limit what you can do with the data we
just make it available to you what is a
cool about that system architecture is
that it makes it really easy to scale a
cluster so the cluster I manage
regularly scans up to 150 million files
a day which is also approximately three
terabytes of file content a day and the
system will keep track of how long it
takes to scan each file so for the
cluster I manage at the 95th percentile
it takes 13 to 14 seconds to scan a file
as soon as you go to the 85th percentile
and lower you hit sub second scan times
so the speed of an individual scan plus
the distributed design really means you
can scale to whatever volume of files
you need to handle when I introduced
this project to people for the first
time there's always some questions that
pop up right away and these are those
questions I don't consider this to be an
intrusion detection system I say that it
enables intrusion detection you still
need a human to decide what to do with
the data that gets produced that could
be writing automated alerts from the
data or manually crawling through the
data
something like threat hunting it's
written in Python because Python has
good third-party packaged sport for the
kinds of files we care to scan and it
really is just good enough the system
architecture lets us bypass any
inefficiencies it has through brute
force scaling and when it comes to
scalability we don't use micro services
because they're way too difficult to
manage and really are overkill for the
vast majority of users we use cookie
cutter scaling which means you build a
cluster if it hasn't met the scale you
need you just keep adding carbon copies
of the same server to the cluster until
you either hit the scale you need or you
run out of hardware so those are really
the introductory details this is where
we kind of get to the interesting part
of this talk which is what you could
actually find with this data and to do
that what I'm gonna do is call on
someone I follow on Twitter so this is
John Lambert he works over at Microsoft
and he shares a lot of interesting
malware samples online many of which
unsurprisingly include office documents
what we're gonna do here is take one of
the samples he shared late last summer
walked through the Strelka data for that
file and try to determine if we think
it's malicious or not so what we'll be
looking at our three files in total the
first files in office document
it's a resume from Amanda and the second
two files are files that are nested
inside of that document and while we do
this I just would like you to remember
this stat that's over here on the on the
Left 6 only 6 out of 59 AV engines
flagged this document as suspicious
which is a pretty low percentage lesson
well approximately 10% so this is the
literal JSON output of the strelka
engine or system this is the this is
file 1 of 3 that we'll be looking at
this is the document itself before we
really dig in here I think it's
important to call out some of the
structure of the data the first is that
at the root of the Jason event there's a
variety of metadata dictionaries and
they're all very literally named for the
data that is encapsulated within them so
hash metadata is the result of hashing
funk
zip metadata is artifacts related to zip
extraction XF tool metadata is related
to the output of the EXIF tool utility
things like that these are very
literally named so it's easy for an
analyst to understand what the data
represents the thing that is a little
weirder and not literally named is this
thing called flavors at the top so
install Co we don't identify files by
type we identify them by flavor and
that's because sometimes it's useful to
identify a file by more than its type an
example of that would be say you have an
XML file that is simultaneously a
malware configuration file those are
both valid ways to identify that file
and we use these flavors to assign
scanners that produce the metadata you
see here so it's important that we're
flexible in how we name these things the
two primary methods of tasting flavors
in the system is through Lib magic in
Yarra represented by the my manyara
fields in the flavours dictionary so
what we're actually gonna do here is
we're gonna walk through this almost
line by line and we'll talk to the
interesting points here first if we
didn't already know that this was an
office document the flavors are the
thing that tell us that it is this
happens to be a docx file this is that's
what it would normally appear to be on
an endpoint if you were looking at the
file that's a that's a office open XML
file the other interesting thing about
the system is that we we hash every file
no matter what so it always gets md5
sha-1 shop 256 etc we also assign a
unique ID to the file because you need
to be able to keep track of files that
are directly related to one another so
we tagged it with this unique ID if you
keep an eye on the value of that UID
you'll see it pop up here again
momentarily now this is where we
actually kind of get into the
interesting bits of detecting
adversaries when we look at the EXIF
tool metadata for this document the
interesting so if you're not familiar
with XF tool it's a fairly popular
utility to parse generic metadata out of
a variety of files hundreds of files
documents image files archive files many
kinds what is interesting about this set
of metadata for this doc
that is that there's nothing interesting
about it you can see from the word-count
that the document appears to have a
reason about reasonable amount of words
in it it's got a basically a word
reasonable amount of content for a
resume creator value contains Amanda's
name which matches the resume content
you could actually go back and look at
Jon's tweet to confirm that so what's
interesting about this being
uninteresting is that it isn't uncommon
for adversaries to flub the values of
this metadata you know for example they
might do something like send you a
resume that has five words in it which
is weird or send you a resume that has a
creator value that is just a random
string and not someone's name those are
interesting things that you could use as
a detection breadcrumbs to figure out if
you're dealing with something that might
be malicious so that's really all there
is to that this is going to kind of come
into play later what's interesting is
that they the adversary in this case did
a pretty good job of trying to you know
obfuscate their their delivery of
malware but it ends up being pretty
futile in the end the last point here is
that these files they have the structure
of a zip so that means that when they
are introduced to the system they get
extracted as if they were a zip file so
we just take all eighteen parts out of
the file and parse those out and that's
what we're going to be looking at here
next is one of those eighteen files
I believe this document has eighteen
parts in all so this is the this is the
second file two of three and the thing
to call out here is the existence of
this dictionary called VBA metadata
that's Visual Basic application metadata
that's basically the thing in this
metadata tells you this document might
have macros in it macros being you know
the thing that is intended to help end
users by automating document related
tasks but is typically used by
adversaries to automate the installation
of malware so if you look at the flavors
there's really nothing too interesting
here this is identified as an oily
compound file what you actually don't
need to know too much about it's just a
kind of file that stores other files and
in documents it commonly stores macros
once again we hash all the files we
assign a unique ID to all the files in
this case there's a new field that's
called parent UID it could
the value of the UID from the previous
file so this is how we very explicitly
relate files together it's important if
you're looking at this kind of data to
be able to pivot between files that are
related and finally the VBA metadata
actually doesn't say too much that's
interesting except it confirms any
suspicions we had that yes there was a
macro code inside the document and we're
going to be looking at the actual code
of one of the macros here and the next
slide the VBA scanner also tries to be
helpful and tell you about suspicious
things in the VBA code like base64
encoded content we're going to look at
that more depth here in the next file so
this is the third file it's three of
three this is the visual basic code from
one of the macros this isn't like nested
pretty deep within the document and
what's interesting is that nearly
everything that's detection worthy about
this entire document all 30-plus parts
is can be found in one field here which
is the VB metadata strings so these are
literally strings defined in the in the
VB code as like variable definitions
right like a equals blah that's the kind
of string we're talking about here we're
gonna spend pretty much the rest of the
presentation on that in particular
because there's just so much to unpack
there if you look at the the flavors
yarra successfully identifies this as VB
code let magic has no idea what VB code
is so it just says it's plain text which
is a correct though a little inaccurate
I'll skip the hash metadata and UID once
again you know we hashed everything all
the time and this is how you relate
files together but the VB strings is
really where things kind of pop off here
in this document the first thing that's
interesting is this Python one-liner and
as I'm going through this I want you to
just recall like this is a resume from
Amanda why does it have a macro that
contains you know a Python one-liner
that is basic ste for decoding a very
long string in this case the string was
so long I had a truncated for space
otherwise all of this would have been
illegible there's also something else
that's interesting here which is that
they explicitly call a function to
filter out and ignore any warnings
thrown by the Python interpreter I'll
kind of leave you to think about that
for a minute we'll
we'll come back to that at the end here
why they may want to do that so that's
weird that that exists at all on
someone's resume but then it gets even
weirder when you see this reference at
the end of the first highlighted line
here to a watch agents directory and a
Spotify browser API property list file
so this is really your first indicator
that you're looking at something that's
targeting a Mac user and not a Windows
user if you're not familiar with launch
agents or property lists they're used to
control system level processes on a Mac
what's even more interesting is that not
only do they reference the file they
they actually have the actual structure
of a property list file that follows it
so you can see on the second line here
there's the header of a plist file at
the end of the third line there is a
label that gets set that says Spotify
browser API which is clever so there
they seem to seem to be from me from
what I can tell I mean I'm not doing
forensics here I'm just looking at
metadata so we're making some guesses it
appears what it's probably happening is
that they are inserting the content into
that file location right so they're
either creating or over writing that
Spotify browser API plist but it goes
even further because they actually
define you know this is all non encoded
data this is just plain text in the VB
code they go even further and they say
they define what program is executed by
the plist and what they have here is
they have an array that says Python taxi
and then a blank string space and so we
can't prove what is included what would
Python is actually executing here right
but a pretty good theory is that it's
the one-liner we saw earlier in the
video
right they could assign that they could
insert that into the plist via a
variable definition which is very likely
what's happening here and so if we're
right what that means is it means that
when the plist initializes and runs on
the system it's actually executing
whatever that Python blob is so we can
actually go even further
it really gets crazier the plist
attributes that there are attributes
that that really kind of clue you into
adversarial intent and how they're
attempting to maintain control over the
system here the run at load key means
run the program when the system boots
the start in
and keep alive keys our methods of
ensuring that the program is always
running so these are methods of
persistence for processes that are
controlled by a property list file this
guarantees that that that Python
one-liner is always running the last
thing here is this curl command and
there's a lot to unpack just even in
this one bit of the VB code but and this
curl command they do some interesting
things so the first thing they do is
they override curls default user agent
string and they set it to mimic a Mac
which is pretty clever so that's the
that's the first indicator like if you
don't know anything about launch agents
or pee lists or how the Mac OS works
that's your thing that tells you like
this is certainly targeting a Mac user
but they go in further and they they
actually suppress the output of curl
which is a fun callback to the technique
they use in the Python one-liner to
suppress warnings so python and curl
have these utility like portions built
into their code to to suppress output
essentially right and that's an
advantage for the adversary because it
means when they execute and you're
invite or code in your environment that
you're less likely they see them the
only two things that are interesting
about this are the domain that's used so
a very attentive analyst or say a domain
reputation service that is keyed into
that domain would eventually be able to
tell you that it is not a legitimate
Spotify domain and then finally they're
not downloading data from this domain
they're uploading data to it so the tech
D flag says that so once again we're not
doing forensics we're just looking at
metadata so I can't authoritative lis
tell you what they're uploading but
what's suspicious is that immediately
after that there's a definition first or
a variable assignment for a shell
command substitution which contains the
system's hostname and current user which
if you think about it makes a lot of
sense because when an adversary gains
access to your network what kinds of
things do they need to know they need to
know where they landed in the network
which you could glean from a hostname
and they need to know what level of
access they have to the network which
you could glean from you know the
current user that is running on the
system you've you've just popped now if
you're if you're not familiar with
mightor's attack matrix which
it's actually been mentioned a lot
during this conference so maybe you are
now what I've done is I've mapped the
techniques I just walked through to to
the attack matrix the tactics on the
right the techniques I just walked
through on the left and I think so one
thing I want to stress about all these
techniques I'm not going to read them
because we just literally went through
them but you know these individual
individual II may not be detection
worthy on their own but in aggregate
they create what I think is a pretty
compelling argument for a file analysis
system like Strelka and its use in
detecting adversaries so remember this
document had a low antivirus detection
rate malware sandboxes are not designed
to collect this kind of data and make it
easily available at large scale and in
addition to all of that adversaries
don't really expect you to have this
level of insight into the files that are
moving in out and around your network
because if they did this adversary
probably wouldn't have left all that
data uncoated unencoded so that's kind
of where I'll wrap it up once again what
I'd like to say about this is that if
any of it Peaks your interests I'd be
happy to chat with you about this
project or point you in the direction of
project owners for any of the other
projects that were shared earlier I
think if you're interested in maturing
your threat detection program I'd
recommend you take a look at this kind
of file analysis because it opens up
levels of insight that adversaries
really don't expect you to have and that
gives you a pretty big advantage when
they try to jump into your network
I consider this kind of data to be fifth
tentpole in the in the commonly thought
of tentpoles of threatened tection being
network data endpoint data cloud data
authentication data
I think file data like this could easily
become a significant part of a threat
detection program that's really where
I'll leave it to any questions that came
in online or or in the room we have a
question from Ron you stated six out of
fifty-nine AV engines marked the files
as malicious which AV engines were those
yeah that's an interesting question I
actually happened to look that up right
before this talk and it wasn't any
engine
you would you're probably running it's
it's stuff like Sentinel one not to call
out vendors or anything like that I'm
not recommending vendors here but it was
it was vendors that are more geared
toward behavioral analysis and not
signature analysis none of your top five
AV vendors detected this great work as
someone who does file detection I had a
couple of follow-up questions do you
guys have this struck handle packed
extraction of features from packed files
or office kated file samples well so
what's interesting about it I don't
think I don't know that it does out of
the box so we have support for we jump
back here so so the these are the five
main categories we support but it's all
just Python code so you could very
easily write your own scanning code to
handle whatever kind of file you like
and then the way it works is you write a
complimentary yarra signature to
identify the file generically okay so
this is plug-in friendly and you could
add your own text overlay Cabos does
absolutely yeah it's big it's designed
to be very easy to add your own code to
it and when you scan they use in the
sample you scanned 18 levels of
associated files what's the limit do you
guys have you had a zip bomb or anything
yeah okay boom like that yeah yeah
there's there's yeah so there's a lot of
nuance built into this that I really
don't have time to go through but yes
zip bombs are our threat to systems like
this so all of the all of the scanners
that extract files they do have file
limits the default limit is very high
like a thousand files things like that
in the case of a zip bomb you're more
likely to run out of memory before you
actually hit that file in it so yeah you
do need to just you know do like a
system like system hygiene system
hardening to to protect yourself against
files that might be actively trying to
to mess with systems like this yeah
thanks
first thanks for the presentation
awesome stuff a couple questions about
what the project supports that's okay
yep so when you're doing VBA extraction
are you relying on external libraries
like oh le tools are you yeah something
custom Oh le tools so so the so one
thing I didn't really talk about is this
project is all pretty much my work so we
don't have a team supporting this it's
just what I do and my equivalent of like
10% time so it's heavily reliant on
third-party packages cool and this kind
of bleeds into the previous question how
difficult would it be to expand analysis
like pipeline so if I wanted to treat
the oo XML file is like a straight zip
yeah look at timestamps within the file
is that something yeah it's very easy I
mean as long as you have written code
and Python before it's it's all very
easy to do the readme is absurdly long
and very detailed to help you with that
cool and have you looked at RS IDs in
RTF soro xml files not specifically cool
thank you yep
one last question do we have anyone yes
we do in the far back way up near the
top of Mount Everest
so I kind of tricked you it's actually
statement not a question first of all
thanks for your talk thanks for
contribution and this is being recorded
right your boss should totally give you
a raise well then thank you Thank You
Josh it's been a pleasure thanks thanks
everyone