thank you everybody and sorry for taking
so long it's been a very wild and crazy
day first of all thank you so much for
participating really it it you know it's
it's been a very wild and fantastic
piece as SF 2019 so thankful that we had
a lot of people come a lot of great
conversations happening it's it's been a
pretty awesome the last two days so
let's dive right in attendance by the
numbers we hit about 1,600 tickets
purchased with about 83 percent checked
in 101 procedures total including both
the talks here and the workshops on on
Saturday to about 250 volunteers 33
villagers 10 Press 194 sponsors that
came and about 30 staff members for a
total number of about 2200 participants
that actually came which is a record for
based at San Francisco let's just give a
round of applause for all the people
that came yes awesome cool let's talk a
little bit about Internet we had a one
gig link up uplink from web pass we did
about a hundred and twenty Meg's at peak
pushed about a 480 gigs 408 total
wireless devices overflowed three
different tracks of video which is a
first for us this is the first year
doing that and we're pretty well we have
some some things to work on eighteen
different Aruba APs
and fun fact we actually in the CTF
overloaded the AP enough that it took it
down just due to the sheer number of
people playing on the CTF so we had to
actually get more equipment in there
so it's pretty cool I talked about
speaking of CTF we have 41 different
challenges completed over the course of
about 32 hours
[Music]
1112 players which is a record for us
organised intimate 676 teams with a
bunch on-site the winners third place
open to all second place was perfect
blue and first place was a DCU a second
year is first place for that team
villages we had a lot of awesome
villages thanks to all our villages
we had the lock-picking village we had
tool we had a IOT village crypto and
privacy and spymaster challenge all this
year and hoped add several more next
year already planning on that living
secure and also the Libyan security
escape room they had twenty different
teams play rabid Badgers win one the
other competition in nine minutes
puzzles if you didn't notice that there
were some puzzles in the in the program
and we had several things spread out
around the the conference area including
some hidden AP's as well and we had 25
people actually signed up for it and we
had one person finish in time Maya I'm
not even gonna try to pronounce okay and
more details we have a full write-up
that will be posted to our blog in the
next day or so for that t-shirt proceed
down donations for t-shirt charities BFF
raised 1944 dollars and sixteen cents
plus people put in forty seven dollars
of cash into the box so pretty awesome
for the FF hack the hood raised a
thousand eleven one thousand one hundred
eighty nine dollars and some cash and
then hackers for charity
a little ver nine hundred and seventy
two dollars so let's give a round of
applause for all the people that donated
and both t-shirts thanks again and again
a well-deserved thanks to all my staff
there's about 30 of us that put this
conference on it takes you know almost a
full year to put this on I want to do a
special shout out to magnet to Megan my
right-hand woman come and stand up Megan
come on she keeps me in check so really
do appreciate her for all she does we
have again all of our staff all of our
many many many volunteers special thanks
to Jim McLain for all the graphic design
he's been doing gravity design for the
past at least four years for us and so
all the different things that you see
are all done by a one-man team
and he spends a lot of time on it so
great great appreciation to Jim in
putting this together takes a lot of
time and a special commitment if you
feel that you have the ability to help
out we're always looking for more people
to help out either on the day of
situation and as a volunteer or in the
many months preceding that do feel free
to reach out to us at info at besides SF
org we would absolutely love to hear
from you and again I want to talk to you
about our sponsors special thanks to all
of our sponsors especially our for
leading sponsors Dropbox hacker one
Qualis and Simmel we would not be able
to put this conference on without them
it cost a lot of money to do this and so
it's we're very very thankful to all our
many sponsors and hope to see them all
again next year and please provide
feedback
we can't keep improving the conference
making it better for everybody if you
don't give us feedback about what you
liked what you disliked what you
absolutely loved what you hated just any
type of feedback that you have for us
please feel free to let us know
besides SF dot org slash feedback for
general feedback if you have feedback
about a specific session you can go in
this schedule and at the very bottom of
that particular session there's a place
to put feedback in there and then we'll
also be sending out a post event survey
to everybody who registered in advance
and not not nothing but less but we have
besides 20/20 which would be our 10th
anniversary
coming up next year will be February
23rd and 24th of 2020 so look very much
look forward to having all of you attend
again and and join us there and thank
you again at all for coming this year
it's it's a lot of work to put this
conference on but it makes it worth it
to have all the different participants
here see all your your smiling faces
your the the enjoyment that people have
the great conversations they're people
having so again thank you so much for
everything that you've done and and as
far as participating and enjoying the
conference and again hope to see you
next year so without further adieu
pause again for everybody's helped out
and all for it all of you as well thank
you again and if you do have some free
time tonight we do need a ton of help
with cleanup so if you want to stick
around and do a lot of manual labor we
would really much appreciate it we
literally have to clear out this entire
space so this is gonna begin immediately
after we're done here so if you have
time love to have the help otherwise see
you next year
Thanks