good afternoon everyone welcome to be
sighs I'm supposed to make an
announcement that there will be a
private showing for the hackers movie so
if you just go to be sighs SSS org slash
hackers to find out more information so
without further ado let's welcome mark
hillock for do you even talk anymore
cool thank you so just really quickly
can everyone at the back see the images
on the screen just give a hands up if
it's good cool just conscious of the
light so my name is Mark hillock I'm
here to do a talk about even tech
anymore which is essentially what some
of the people who would be considered my
direct reports often like to tell me as
you can probably tell they literally do
it because they know it's gonna like you
know tease the hell out of me and annoy
me so the talk is about the transition
from being like an individual
contributor so technologists engineer
etc or whatever could be even a finance
person into management and it's based on
my experiences working in InfoSec the
talk split into five sections who what
where quick introduction to me write
games the security team at riot and then
talking about hey you want to be a
manager before we move into a story time
section which talks about many occasions
that I failed before we move into like
from the what to the how which is
literally we all know what to do we
typically just don't know how to do it
and then finally we're going to
summarize the key points at the end in
the post game section so who what where
I'm the product leader security at Riot
Games which means I'm the person
accountable for the vision for InfoSec
or security and the execution of said
vision there's five teams up SEC SEC ups
riders which is corporate security
platform security and then anti-cheat
I've been working in info SEC for a lot
of years hence the gray hairs which my
wife loves reminding me about every day
but I'll get over that this is my
twitter ID
but I typically don't use Twitter
anymore but if you want to reach up a
check it about once a week so quick show
of hands who has heard the right games
who has who plays video games who plays
League of Legends okay Wow
a lot of hands just on twitch who plays
fortnight okay that's so many that means
everyone here is too old so if you play
League of Legends you will get this is a
fantasy world 140 plus champions two
champions on the screen this is from a
recent cinematic Riven and Draven if you
play the game you will know that if
Riven is anywhere ever close to driven
that Draven is dead other than that it's
a beautiful image I get to work in you
know folklore essentially every day so
for me it's pretty cool it's kind of
like a childhood dream I never really
thought you know playing shinobi on an
Amstrad CPC 464 8-bit system tips Trek
trying to copy one taped it all there
that I could literally work in a in a
games company anyone here heard of
eSports cool everyone here think it's
like the work of the devil and stuff
right so this is our like 10 year
history season 1 basically shows a
conference in Dreamhack in Sweden that's
what the League of Legends world
champion was all the way down the season
6 which was in 2016 in the Staples
Center
you've got like 22,000 people that have
a kind of surreal advancement in year so
that makes sense still blows my mind
went to the bird's nest although wise
known as the stadium essentially built
for the Olympics in 2008 so yeah you can
play video games for a living you can
get a college scholarship you can
essentially get the same visa that you
know someone in the NBA NFL maybe even
the MLS although I don't know what
you're going to play in the MLS but you
know same visa right we have a lot of
offices across the world 20-plus offices
basically all continents apart from
africa antartica we are owned by 10 cent
which means we've a different kind of
philosophy towards China that most
people have
a security perspective I mean this is
the key statement like this is our
mission everything for us is about the
player and we actually walk the walk
it's not just talk so has anyone heard
of the poodle vulnerability from like
2014 okay so hands up if he patched
immediately right so we didn't actually
PI to immediately the reason is is
because a lot of our players playing on
XP sp2 which means that you don't have
the correct ciphers to support the
correct version TLS you couldn't upgrade
sp2 sp3 because it wasn't supported you
couldn't upgrade from ie6 that I ate
because that wasn't supported either so
we actually sat down on those two
security team we were like hey can we
actually patch because if we patch will
lock out millions of players for those
of us in the Western world XP is like a
distant memory but in in Asia it's still
a very popular operating system and
video game and see you in Asia
ultimately we did patch but I just
wanted to use it as an example like hey
we genuinely think of what's the most
important thing from the player like we
can't take the traditional security
approach so how many managers to be on
the audience how many people do we have
that used to be monitoring or like stuff
thought that okay cool totally
legit how many people want to be a
manager okay you crazy so going back to
my earlier career the big thing when I
did interviews was like hey what's your
five-year career plan I was in my 20s
like I didn't know I've no I just turned
40 I still don't really know what my
five-year career plan is and I don't
really like these questions because I've
never had a really good answer and the
answer I get from a lot of people is
like hey I'm going to be made engineer
in year two and then two years later I'm
going to be senior in two years later
I'm gonna be in monitor and it doesn't
really work like that I'm a huge
believer in goals and measuring the
goals like okay ours and stuff like that
but I find these type of questions or
you know this type of advice from your
manager in order to be a manager or be a
leader like not really very good I think
it's much more important to actually
build a relationship
context understand what the person wants
to do and build it from there and Dan
actually measure now when I did some
research into like why people want to go
into management these are typically like
the four most common reasons does anyone
think these are good reasons so
typically these aren't like they're very
short-term you're not gonna last there's
always going to be something that's
going to drive you like absolutely
bananas you gotta want it for the right
reasons which is which can be anything
but for me it was really understanding
that I want the people to grow I wanted
to achieve more I wanted to like help
others teach them you know things that I
made mistakes on that I don't really
want them making and then ultimately
it's really nice to see a team of 10 a
team of 15 a team of 5 collaborate
together and achieve a lot more than you
could have as an individual person
however prerequisite side with Pokemon
if you're wondering why there's Pokemon
here that's probably the wrong question
I have a six-year-old boy I know like
the whole Pokemon universe at this stage
so unfortunately in in in our industry
now you can go multiple different ways
right so you don't have to progress your
career through management and that's
okay you can stay as an individual
contributor you can become an architect
like have a still a technical influence
but more holistic or you can go super
deep in your tag can become a principal
and when I was younger like these pots
didn't exist so I think it's really
exciting to see those pots and I think
it's ok to say you don't want to be a
manager right but ultimately if you do
want to be a manager you want to get to
like the price right you want to get to
the endgame where your team is
contributing successfully where they're
collaborating and they're all in sync
towards a common goal does anyone know
what this is great answer $10 so this is
actually legal Legends World
Championship cool and then when everyone
is collaborating you're essentially
going to be the leader you could be at
the front or you could be at the box
but ultimately I think your goal as a
manager is to support your team always
be there for your team and ensure that
everyone's collaborating
I'm ensure that there's two-way
accountability but that's more difficult
than it actually sounds so I'm going to
take you into the next section now and
walk you through some examples of where
I I guess I made complete nutter scripts
so please don't love so this is our most
popular champion in the game everyone
loves this guy
it's called Teemo the mistake that I
made is that I I guess if I look at
myself and myers-briggs I'm one of the
doers I like to get stuff done if I see
someone like taking too long I'm like
I'll just take it and like do it by
myself and then that's leading by
example but it's not really leading by
example it's actually hitting into like
micromanagement it's damaging the
confidence of the people that you're
working with and it's not really set in
an example which is something that you
should be done so for those people that
are managers would you say that
management is the only half that you
wear yes no okay
so I was kind of hoping for a more
immediate response but for me at times
I've been wearing for huts right and
that's because people have left
that's because business priorities
changed that's because we may have had
new hires and I needed the ramp load in
your arse up but the problem with that
is that you can't focus on any one thing
so instead of doing one thing really
well you end up doing four things
average or really bad and at the start
it's pretty hard because you people
typically don't have the self-awareness
to actually recognize that but as you
get more experienced you're going to
detect uh the other thing that is really
recommended in hindsight is that when
you become a manager like have a mentor
have someone who's been a manager for a
while like a senior leader in the
company or someone on the industry
because when you talk to that person
they have the third party objective our
third party observation and they will
actually recognize
the things that you're doing because
most likely made them in themselves but
they're also they have an independent
view and like even today I typically
wear two to three hats but I've been
doing it for a while so I can handle it
a lot lot better but this is one of the
biggest mistakes I made it to start
trying to do too much and not delegating
enough stepping back one of the other
key learnings for me was like the weight
of my words so in California people
traditionally are not very direct in
their communication which for a European
is very very challenging in Europe
people will literally tell you exactly
what you think what they think at that
time so as a European coming into
California that doesn't really go very
well so I was a big learning for me but
the more important point is holistically
the weight of your words have a much
bigger impact as a manager then as an
individual contributor so as you become
more senior in the company you know new
people join more junior people are there
people that don't have that like
contacts about you they don't have that
relationship with you so when you're
seeing hey I don't think that work was
very good that's literally taken by them
as I suck or I'm not very good and it
also carries more weight because of your
seniority so when you're given that
feedback or when you're having those you
know bad days it's really important that
you figure out a better way to you know
share the message or in some cases not
share the message but for me like this
was this was a big learning that as I
became more senior in the company be it
from an individual contributor to a team
lead to a manager to manager of managers
every step I made my role changed but
the weight of my words also changed and
I also interacted with an increasing
amount of people that didn't know me so
they didn't have the context and how I
communicated which when you have a dry
sense of humor at direct communication
does not really work in California I
eventually figured it out otherwise I
would have been fired so how many
managers do one-on-ones and okay
anyone ever feel like a 101 in one
machine or your day is likely already
won at once yeah it doesn't feel really
good at the end of the day right where
you're essentially listening to all the
people's concerns and issues and you you
don't actually get any time - I guess
consider what people have been telling
you like take it all in
you're literally jumping from one one
and one and in case you're wondering I
feel like Aurelia which is a smaller the
lady I don't feel like the Scion so when
you look at one on once and you google
or you read books like saying Michael
ops engineering blogs are is book like
one-on-ones are super beneficial you get
a lot of context even when you're like
direct reports like hey I don't have
anything if you just go for coffee
typically something comes up and it's
super educational and it helps the
strength of your team however you can
also become a one-on-one machine which
literally means that you don't feel
you're achieving anything you don't feel
you're actually getting into deep work
you don't feel anyone is listening to
you because you're listening to everyone
else and you need to like schedule time
in your calendar have focused time and
for me that every time I change role the
problem has happened worse because
there's more people that want to talk to
me and older people who previously had
one-on-ones with me still want to keep
those one-on-ones so then there are days
that you go into work and you're like
from like 9 a.m. to 5 p.m. I have
nothing but one-on-ones and it's super
hard to get out of because as humans
we're not really good at saying no right
because we don't want to offend people
but the only way to do it is to actually
say no as long as you explain the
context and give the impact of like your
schedule that makes sense the the other
thing that has been challenging as a
manager is the amount of communications
hopefully there's no one from slack in
the audience okay
I love slack I know quite a few people
from a slack security team however if
you do not use slack correctly it can
literally like just take your whole day
all right so you have an hour you're
like I'll just respond to this message
45 minutes later right and then you can
email coming in and then people have
your phone number so they want to text
you and then you're like I want to stay
a little bit technical so I'm gonna
review pull requests I'm gonna watch
this repo and it's like ting ting ting
ting ting and then it's like where did
the hour go and then you have drop drop
buys even when you're wearing like the
really big headphones and it's like Do
Not Disturb unlikes is it up here people
will disturb you but it's really tough
because as the manager you want to be
approachable right you want to be
collaborative with people and you want
people to come to you because the worst
thing you can do is if anyone has ever
dealt with performance management issues
is like hey why didn't you come to me
three months ago that this person on
this team wasn't collaborating with you
so it's like literally a fine line that
every time you change role or every time
you harp someone you start the whole
process again and trying to make sure
that you're on the right side of the
line trying to stay technical and
watching every single repo is probably a
bad idea probably only need to like
watch ten ten percent okay anyone read
this book do you like it so when you
move from an individual contributor to a
even to like a principal engineer and
architect where you're like a team lead
and you're not just concerned with your
own tech but all the people's tech
trying to get into like that deep work
is super super hard and similarly moving
into manager it's also hard because
you've got other people's challenges
other people's issues to deal with and
to support and to help them improve and
to help them achieve their potential the
concept of deep work also changes when
you go from being an individual
contributor to a monitor it's no longer
like I'm going to sit and write code in
C++ or go or
it could be for example during this
presentation so in order to do this
presentation I had to block off like two
to three hour chunks for several days
for preparation for dry runs and the
other thing I learned about my calendar
this year is for four years at riot last
four or five years I've had it public so
people could see what I was doing and
where I was in the last like six weeks
I've made a private that was I was not
going well I was like getting invites
all over the place so recently about
four or five months ago
I moved from leading like two to three
teams to leading five to six teams and
as a result I've influenced there were a
lot more people and a lot more people
want to like just grab 30 minutes but
when you multiply that out across all
the people that you're potentially
collaborating with or that are reporting
up to you it's just not sustainable and
if you don't get to do deep work it's
not rewarding so doing like shallow work
like going through your email going
through slack the best thing to do is to
actually schedule it so in this book Cal
Newport talks about you literally have
to schedule every minute of your day and
that's like taking your own calendar
back so that you can manage yourself so
you can basically be in the right frame
of mind to support other people okay so
we basically know what we need to do but
it's typically really hard to move from
the walk to the how ultimately this is
what we want
we want a team that's having fun
collaborating moving towards the one
goal and in sync as you can see I have
really cool artists I have nothing to do
with the creation of this stuff but I
get this deal so Andy Grove said the
Clayton Christensen in the mid 90s I
know what I need to do I just don't know
what how to do it and that was when
Intel was being hit by AMD with cheaper
chips and they were like hey we need to
like come up with a new solution I think
they came out with a Celeron so he he
knew he needed to pivot the company he
just didn't know
to do so I'm gonna try and give you some
tips on what I've done I think the most
important thing is you need to monitor
self you need to figure out what is the
most important thing for you to do what
you need to do it and then you need to
like make sure that your tools and your
objectives and goals and and how you
work every day's is lined up so you can
manage yourself this is a typical sort
of day as a manager otherwise known as
chaos right so if you moneyed yourself
though like you can stop this but it
literally means owning your calendar
owning your schedule
saying no but at the same time ensuring
that your people can work with you can
collaborate and that you're still
staying close enough to the team but you
need your own focused time you need your
own separation one of the biggest
learnings is being transparent and
collaborative and this really means like
making yourself available for the team
explaining the decisions so if you have
to fire someone for example that you're
actually upfront and honest in terms of
why the person has been fired if you're
hiring similarly in terms of interview
panels because not everyone is like a
thumbs-up for the person coming on you
got to explain what why your thumbs up
while you're hiring the person my people
don't mind being told no as long as they
know why and the minute you start not
explaining that or being secretive then
that'll be the start to like losing the
team so accountability this is super
important this is where you want to be
accountable for your actions
but more importantly you need to hold
your people accountable so if you're
delegating which you should do as a
manager if you're asking people to do
stuff you need to hold them accountable
so you need to be explicit and clear on
what they're doing and what they need to
do and why and then you need to hold
them accountable if you don't hold them
accountable then they're not going to
learn they're not going to achieve what
they can they need to achieve however
the more damage and aspect is damaging
to the team if people see that people
aren't egde of
other people on the team are
not been held accountable that
eventually leads the toxicity which is
like just it's going to take you an
astronomical amount of time to remove
that toxicity from the team and it
typically leads to like being fired
now think about accountability is
feedback really helps so feedback is a
two-way system again remember your your
words carry more weight so you have to
figure out how to communicate it's not
like you did a bad job
you're not strategic enough in your
thinking you really need to like
approach the person from a learning
perspective such as hey what was your
thought process in terms of making that
decision or I'm I recognize some of the
things you're doing let me tell you
about something from my personal
experience where I did something that
was similar but had a bad effect now how
do you think you would do that and
there's also a couple models that you
can follow for feedback
it's like action impact desired outcome
or you can do SBI which is like
situation behavior impact and that's
really bringing everything into the
third person and making the feedback no
one personal but also improvement
focused so there's a Harvard Business
Review in terms of feedback and how we
used to be back so what do people think
is the ratio of feedback and in most
places so like good feedback improvement
feedback and then it's roughly 0.75 2.8
to 1 so that means like roughly for
every 3 bits a good feedback
people are getting 4 bits of areas of
improvement that's not really successful
it's a similar statistic for people that
get divorced which take that in for a
second the recommended ratio is for
every one bit of feedback that you give
for area of improvement you should be
given 5 I wasn't hitting that so the
other thing is you need to modify your
approach so we all have done
myers-briggs personality tests we're all
different right that means world
all different we shouldn't have the same
approach for people here we manage some
people need the far away approach other
people's need to close up approach right
now if you do the close up approach on
the wrong people they'll consider
micromanagement or if you do the distant
approach on the wrong people they'll
feel you're not supporting them right so
this is where emotional intelligence
comes in and trying to figure out what's
the best approach but you need to build
that relationship in order to understand
that we don't think of management as a
practice we typically think it is like
an end result or a goal or something
that we just do but it's not our core
thing we need to think of management as
a practice in the same way we think of
like I want to get better at Python I
want to get better go I want to go to
the gym and get stronger right this
means like self-improving studying
getting mentors reaching out to other
people and until we actually think of
management as a practice then it's going
to be diminished and not at the you know
the standard that it needs to be has
anyone heard of the Reid mace that go
around texting so there's mixed opinions
on this I've done a readme that I've
shared across riot I've shared it with
actually shared it publicly but it
literally describes hey I'm not American
I'm Irish I communicate in a certain way
it's intended as an icebreaker it's been
received really positively by people who
report to me and people who collaborate
with me and it's something that I work
with all any hires on and it's like hey
here's how I communicate here's how I
don't communicate and it's really to
give context on on how I work but also
because it's intended as an icebreaker
I'm really looking for feedback and
while I think about it when you're
looking for feedback from direct reports
or people who you collaborate with be
really specific don't go hey do you've
any feedback for me because that
literally leads to like nope nothing and
then three months later you find out
something so it could be like hey when I
did this thing X at that time Y you
seemed like a little upset what can I do
better and that will actually generate
feedback
is it breaks the ice and encourages
people to give you feedback and then
thirdly it's actually so specific that
it makes them think on the actual action
that you did so summarizing everything
together if there's four takeaways
manage yourself it's a practice so
self-improve reach out continue to study
always be transparent and collaborative
and two-way accountability and when
you're looking for that accountability
look for a specific feedback
oh yeah we're hiring if you want to play
video games and any questions I think
I've few minutes I still have it because
people keep oh sorry the question was I
don't use Twitter anymore why so I've
just found that it's like too noisy and
it doesn't hugely help me I guess in the
earlier days I found a really good Club
for collaboration but there's literally
so much noise that it just takes the
attention away from what I want I still
check for direct messages because that's
how some people communicate with me
so you'd mentioned that one of the
things strategies they use to improve
yourself as a manager is to find mentors
if you work at a smaller company how do
you find mentors and how do you build
out your network to improve your
management skills so context I haven't
worked at a small company I guess
outside of maybe MongoDB which isn't
that small anymore so it's really
through the industry like establishing
relationships going to conferences I did
a lot of volunteer work with like certs
and stuff back in Europe and that's how
I I built up contacts there it doesn't
it doesn't have to be
a monitor in your industry also it can
be like from other industries I had like
my mother and I friends a family that
had been like directors and stuff so I
was comfortable asking them questions
also I'm also happy to answer questions
if you have questions specifically but I
think it's really just about trying to
establish contacts and three family
friends are in the wider industry we
have one last question what are the one
or two resources you would advice to
aspiring managers probably books so
thanks for the feedback is actually a
really good book a lot of the books that
I've found that have helped me most of
being around communication radical
candor is really good
just want to take your candor to radical
principles by Ray Dalio is also really
good just in terms of amount of stuff
that he's learnt throughout his life
like that he shared I've heard good
things about the monitor's path by calm
Kamel fournier but I haven't read it
what else work rules bylaws of a buck is
really good talks about a lot of the
stuff they've learned on Google the
particular section on that that was
super useful was wasn't the lessons that
they learned with regard to interviewing
terms of like how the brain teasers and
stuff didn't work
Michael ops engineer minder handbook is
really good too and I think I talked
about deep work thank you Mark for
coming to speak at the sides and let's
give mark a round of applause
[Applause]