awesome thank you so much everybody for
joining us the next talk is by Hannah
West Elias on friend or replicant if you
have any questions during the talk
please go to SL I'd do slide or app on
your browser and code to get in is
besides SF 2019 so once you put in the
code just choose the track and this is
Taylor 14 so once you do that you can
put in your question then I will take
this at the end of the talk thank you so
much you can take it away yeah thank you
and just to introduce with a bad way
like I thought I had 40 minutes which I
don't so questions I'll actually take
later after the talk but thank you all
for coming
I'm Anna with stylus I am super honored
to be here this is the 10th
besides SF so it feels good to be here
for an anniversary Who am I
I'm a former security researcher and
analyst I have been in the security
industry for a while now
I started in systems and network
security I did everything from pen
testing to IDS monitoring I ran a stock
for a while the last decade I've spent
focusing on solving fraud and abuse
problems at scale as I've been working
with and for various companies to deal
with fake information fake accounts
distributed bought attacks stuff like
that so quick disclaimer my favorite
quote about ml is that if it's written
in Python it's probably machine learning
if it is written in PowerPoint it is
probably AI and because this is a
PowerPoint presentation I have taken the
courtesy of using the terminology AI for
things that some people might refer to
as ml and other refer to as AI so don't
get pissed me so why am I talking about
this um throughout the history of humans
we have always tried to game the system
whenever we assign value to something
people find a way to abuse it and with
the rise of social media platforms likes
users user activity become the one
number one value
commodity right so not only do we assign
a dollar value to these things you can
trade likes followers ratings up votes
activity for sums of money right you can
get a thousand Twitter followers for $12
actually real followers supposedly but
it's interesting to me that we've never
really put a lot of security or security
thought into these problems or did we
assign a value to it but we don't hold
it to the same level of scrutiny from a
security perspective as you would
transactions right if you log into your
bank you expect there to be a certain
level of security on a credit card
transaction or credit card information
but with life's followers similar things
we don't actually put much security into
it so what is the real value of activity
activities influence influence and
credibility infos and business and
companies and thoughts and items you can
actually value a company today based on
their ratings online if their consumer
facing right if you have a business that
exposed to consumers three or four stars
actually changes the value of that
company in real time right and again we
don't put a lot of security into it so
that's something additionally these fake
accounts that are being used are used
for other malicious purposes so we can
influence someone's ratings we can
influence someone's value as a company
but we can also spread information like
malware phishing scam etc and again if
there is no security in these steps of
things then why wouldn't I as a person
go in and abuse those resources from my
own benefit what concert is real so if
you go online and you're a social media
or you are on a website that has ratings
or comments etc how do you spot a fake
account can someone please tell me how
you would identify a fake user someone
tries to friend you
on social media what do you look for
anyone then you reverse search their
profile picture that's pretty advanced
Frenchie what lack of activity that's
one anyone else no common friends you
don't have any friends that you are very
suspicious don't friend this guy okay
age of account okay all these are great
thank you
so as these things have become more I've
gotten more attention from the media
users have been taught rudimentary means
to identify things that are real or fake
right so you know that if you have no
friends in common if there is a lack of
other friends if you have no photos if
there is tons of activity so you Sofia
here or a marvelous robot by the way
this is the most advanced social robot
that exists um she has 18,000 or 1800
reviews no comments no photos no friends
right and she might come from a location
that is unexpected from the place that
she is revered right
these are means that are very very easy
for people to emulate and to pretend to
be like because we set the framework for
what is real we give attackers the
ability to emulate that behavior the way
that they look the same things this does
not increase the bar for attack at all
actually it's actually very easy to
emulate it's very similar to the way
that we introduced more secure password
practices if you all remember the eight
character password with you know and
number a special character a capital
letter it actually gives people the
format of which your passwords are
rather than you know making it more
secure wait I think we're all in
agreement so if we were to create our
own fake information campaign online me
being Swedish I'm fairly tired of seeing
other Swedish people in the workplace
I'm tired of having to listen to
comments about ABBA
and really nobody wants an Ikea maze in
their neighborhood right so we're gonna
start spreading this false information
how do we do that well okay so how do we
fake it what do we need in order to fake
it another anecdote about my native
Sweden so my country of Sweden just
recently got voted the most unfriendly
place to move to this might not surprise
many of you if you ever met Swedes but
apparently if you as a foreigner move
into Sweden you can't make new friends
because what sweets do is that we don't
make friends or interact with people who
don't know a person we already know
right to be invited to a party you need
to know somebody there to talk to
somebody in public we never talk to
strangers I mean engineers love Sweden
because of this right wait we are fairly
unfriendly but what's important with
this is that it gives a fast-track to
closer friendship because you already
know somebody who is in the clique
you've been verified
you've been validated and therefore you
have access we think the same way when
you think about fake accounts online
right if we have friends in common we're
much more likely to accept that person
as real because it's been verified has
been confirmed it has credibility right
so when we generate fake information we
need to do two things one generate new
accounts which will create all the
activity generate all the content that
we need distribute the fake information
that we want to spread but secondly we
need to access pre verified accounts we
need to faster gain credibility through
already verified pre-existing old
accounts usually accounts used by real
users so two parts then we need to start
generating content and normally in fake
information campaigns you take
pre-existing content and you repurpose
it in other contexts so information that
has been published is being reused to
serve our purpose
so for example if you want to spread
information for Swedes we might find
articles or pictures with Swedish fish
and repurpose them in a way that helps
our campaign swedish fish causes food
poisoning or other things I don't know
anti Swede propaganda but what we also
need is content that makes us look real
so you know the human inspection that I
just talked about right real profile
pictures age location name username
things that passes a normal user
expression inspection as well as a human
one so we need to gather that lastly we
need to start generating some activity
to make us seem real over time we need
to not overdo it and we need to do the
things that we built this army to do
right we want them to generate activity
for us spread our anti sweet propaganda
but in a way that seems real and normal
so now we know what we need but how do
we get those things and it's important
to understand that a lot of these
companies that one might target and
foreign fake information campaign you
want to target many different kinds of
websites right you want to spread your
information in as many locations as
possible and the way that people protect
against these are three major categories
and these are like developed over time
right so as people started stopping
bought attacks and other types of
automation integration they started
blocking things by IP address which is
the first so IP reputation and IP rate
limits they need you something called
browser or device fingerprinting and for
those who are not familiar browser and
device fingerprinting is essentially
gathering client-side information about
a device or a browser in combination
with HTTP headers to create an identity
so you track a user through some
client-side information like screen
resolution plugins font set cetera and
you combine it with user agent string or
other rudimentary HTTP features what's
interesting with this is that one there
is HTTP like there's feature parity in
HTTP so you don't have that many things
that you can gather there is fairly high
entropy in finger
but they are not trusted by the people
who used lastly and this is kind of new
people have started gathering things
they call behavioral fingerprinting or
biometrics which sadly is just a more
fancy way of saying mouse pointer
movement and click locations which is
not very reliable so if we're just gonna
very quickly see how we surpass these
things I piece ip's are fairly easy IP
today if you want access to rely piece
and then this sends real being high
quality user access eye piece you can go
online and go to any service that offers
them whole la vie bien for example is a
peer-to-peer VPN proxy that churches you
almost nothing for direct access to
other people's connections right we have
a business service version that you can
subscribe to that give you access to
other people's home IPS and connections
continuously
and what's interesting with this is that
the price model for these services is
the same as the value that we assigned
to online accounts so a real IP meaning
user activity IP validated real is
priced higher than an IP address that
comes from a data center or somewhere
where you expect that traffic so I don't
things that are being validated our
price higher if we don't want to go the
more legitimate route we can go down the
Renta botnet Rhett and lucky for us the
button industry has gone down the path
of software as a service as a business
model so you can actually get a diamond
level subscription month-to-month to get
access to residential IP addresses for
only $40 a month's Diamond level that's
fairly nice I think
so we've got our IP addresses then we
need to bypass fingerprinting techniques
and I find this hugely interesting
because all of this is client-side
information and anyone knowing anything
about security or information transfer
works if you give something to the
client they can send anything
back to you they owned the information
that you then sent back to you so if
you're basing your identification on
client-side data
well yeah you're pretty much fucked
because you know they own that right so
when attacking any of these targets that
you might target for these types of fake
information campaigns either you own the
information and therefore can send
anything back you can pretend to be any
browser or you can just not load the
JavaScript because they don't expect all
users to load JavaScript and so a
JavaScript based fingerprinting solution
you can just not load it because that's
not what they expect of their users
right usability versus security in this
case usability wins and you can access
right lastly if we have biometrics again
one of my favorites
and this is because the people who build
these things it's like they never talked
to an attacker before they're like oh
you're gonna go home and you're gonna
program mouse movements so that they
move like a human and therefore we're
gonna catch you because it's
programmatically calculate able and I'm
like oh I'm just gonna go home and like
record my own mouse movements and replay
them back like those are human movements
they cannot be identified as
programmatic because they are mine and
there are actually so many software's
out there today
that just adds a layer of randomness to
whatever movements you record so it's
super easy and as you will see in the
rest of this talk is that most of these
things they used to be difficult we've
built tools for them now so it's super
super easy to just bypass all of these
protections right so this that I just
explained is referred to as a single
request attack it means that we ideally
record our own biometrics we add a
little layer of randomness to it we
distribute ourselves so that we access
it through different IP addresses for
each request and either generate a new
fingerprint or don't generate a
fingerprint at all meaning we're always
looking like a new user right so we want
to generate and
Meishan we want to generate new accounts
we want to not get caught by IP limits
we want to not get caught by biometrics
or fingerprints if we just distribute
ourselves with those features for each
request we look like a completely new
user that they cannot in any way blocker
stuff right so it is just time to
assemble the robot army we know what we
need we know what we need to avoid to
get it so let's start collecting those
things and just as a quick recap we need
profile content and content to
redistribute we need new accounts that
will generate our activity we need to
start generating that activity and we
need some old accounts to give us
credibility in our activity right so we
don't get caught
so before we start looking at creating
accounts I wanted to talk a little bit
about content and it's important to
understand that the most common means of
stopping or identifying fake content is
advanced reverse image search dan
mentioned this very briefly as I was
asking about fake profile content but
the way that most companies today look
for a fake content is that whenever you
post an image very very advanced
unscalable expensive models look for
similarity and older pictures so you
post a picture the models are looking
for things that look kind of similar to
that and they may look for the first
original context of that image so the
first time it was posted in what context
was this image posted and then it
compares it to the current context this
is hugely expensive very advanced and a
lot of companies have invested so much
money into trying to do this at scale
and so I was going to talk about image
scraping I was going to talk about very
advanced you know image manipulation
techniques that we can add to our
automated process as long as we've
downloaded she tell us of other people's
profile pictures but I don't have to
because of recent developments in the AI
Department are any of you familiar with
this website
yeah a neat show of hands seen this
before yeah so this person does not
desist come it generates new pictures
and photos of humans for every reload
none of these people exist they have
never existed there is no original
context for any of these people right
there is no way you can put these into a
reverse image google search and say who
is this person originally and has this
been repurposed is this fake so this is
great if we want to start generating
fake profiles right there are no
security on this website this is made by
scientists they don't know security so I
can download hundreds of thousands of
these images and build up a large
inventory of fake people things AI so we
can beat this lady it can be this lady
or whomever we want and I also hear that
from a marketing perspective that being
AI powered is like the bee's knees so
our robot army is now a I powered isn't
that a little bit scary tiny bit but
this is not the only part of this that
is AI powered the all the other stuff
that we needed from our profiles to seem
real to pass that manual user inspection
well if I am enter training data for
user profiles training data is used by
machine learning models to understand
the context better so there are large
sets of data pre-existing for the
purposes of science online there's a
Wikipedia article with listings of just
this specifically so I need hundred
thousand user profiles I can download a
hundred thousand user profiles and I can
use that to my benefit no longer do I
need to scrape the shit out of the
internet to gain this information to
seem real I can just generate it on
demand thanks AI so we got our content
yay when we start looking at generating
new profiles we're gonna use the same
tools that we use for generating new
profiles as well as generating the
activity that we need it always baffles
me held little Co
do you need first of all what you could
do is that you can go online and you can
buy a purpose-built tool for less than
ten dollars that can generate any
accounts on any website but if you want
to do it yourself you can pop up
something like a headless browser like
selenium chromium utilized centum j/s to
build a bot that registers that logs in
and then starts generating activity like
following and liking people again the
amount of code necessary to do this is
baffling it's almost nothing also this
is not mine this i googled right like
how easy is it to create user profiles
okay here is a social media bot for you
and again it requires almost no work to
start generating the activity and they
self replicate so ass friends validating
friends as a concept they start
generating and then they go back to the
previous bot that they made and they
friend it so it replicates itself the
network validates itself pretty easy the
important thing here though to remember
in order to not get detected is to blend
in like a sweet my country moto which is
called the law of Yount a it's
essentially don't stand out and don't
think that you're better than anybody
else this is not fake news by the way
this is absolutely true and it really
much resonates with how we need to act
as we generate fake accounts online
don't overdo it right we get caught if
we jump in and we generate a hundred
thousand accounts and they start liking
one thing they need to do it slowly and
consistently just like it's if you ever
find yourself in my native country of
Sweden and you have to stand in line
always ensure that you have nine feet in
between you and the person next to you
or you will you know it's the most the
biggest social faux pas so we have the
accounts we have the activity we have
the content now we need to gain access
to other people's accounts
and this will do with something called
credential stuffing I can't take over
credential stuffing was the next most
common cyberattack last year after DDoS
which we haven't sold yet by the way
come on guys
and what a credential stuffing attack is
is that you have a set of credentials
which is email addresses or usernames
and passwords these are leaked
constantly right we see leaks in the
media all the time I think there was one
yesterday with 7 billion user accounts
and because our users have not started
using separate passwords and separate
websites this is the most effective way
of gaining access to pre-existing
accounts so what we'll do is that we go
to pastebin one of my favorite websites
and you download a set of credentials
what the biggest one you'd find may get
size matters and then we'll play it into
one of the the most common off-the-shelf
ATO tools and so like I mentioned before
this this is very easy it doesn't
require any coding some of the most
common ATO tools out there essentially
MBA account hitman and anti-public
and also something called sniper most of
these are made by Russians and are
normally in Russian but because of a
growing community of crackers online
they have been translated into English
and well made available for anybody who
does not speak Russian um yes and then
just asked how many much malware you get
by installing this you do it in a vm
right
don't you vm bro yes yes that too but
without going too much up topic the way
these work this is a great overview by
the way I promise is that you have three
different resources that you put into
these you have a combo list which is a
set of credentials that you get from the
pastebin you have a list of proxies so
the IPS that we gathered originally
these residential IPs that we want to
come from we just put it into the tool
they have a target list you can target
multiple different websites at the same
time
this is awesome because that makes you
not seem so aggressive right and if we
want to start generating accounts and
multiple places to spread information
everywhere it's great to be able to do
that same time and then they're highly
configurable so the fingerprints that we
have identified previously that we might
need we can pull them into a
configuration have a change for every
request we get that single request
attack without having to use any
higher-level technological tools or I
really understand the environments in
which we existed right this is plug and
play it's also free generally so what
normally happens and the way that
account hitmen works is that you
actually get a web interface in the tool
so it opens up it loads the website in
an iframe in the tool for you
and then you actually get to choose if
you want to be Chrome or Firefox like
whatever browser you want to pretend to
be it loads it and you actually you'd go
in and you do a successful login
yourself manually and it records that so
it sends that first manual request it
validates success gets that back and
then launches all the credentials in
your combo list an individual request
new fingerprints using the biometrics
that were recorded when you went through
the tool with a certain level of
randomness and you have attacked all of
your target sites at once with new
individual fingerprints for each request
and bypassed all identification because
you seem like a new user for each
request what you get back is a list of
validated credentials that we can use to
validate or other accounts so we build
credibility through our friends or
friends well it's also very common is
that people do this and they don't
actually you overuse the accounts they
get access to so a lot of famous people
will verified accounts they get people
going in and doing small amounts of
activity and they come back from time to
time but they don't overdo it so they
stay under the radar because let's face
it most users don't check their email
for like security alert to Twitter right
like someone's logged in from your
account we care but most normal users
don't so
we have all the things that we need in
order to start generating some activity
and thank the a whilst all this this
entire economy and echo system is
completely fueled by the way that we
value user data and user activity I
think that the recent development in AI
and machine learning data science it's
really fueling the new fake account
economy right
if we can't validate that information
that's been put on the Internet has a
real context we can't say that this
article which features a picture of a
beaten woman like we don't understand
what the pictures come from we can never
validate the original context it's very
very difficult to battle fake
information and fake news especially
seeing that all the investments that's
been done recently go into image server
search capabilities and similar type
technologies so I don't know if you guys
remember this user does not as East come
this is my other favorite website this
Airbnb does not exist calm so these are
actually four different individual
machine learning models that generate a
new room in the same house so they work
independently but together to generate a
similar image of different rooms in a
house it also automatically generates a
description and a fake account picture
this could be used in real time to scam
people in Airbnb I mean I don't see
really another use case for this except
for science and my point here being that
making this available to anybody to use
only fuels the fake account and fake
information society right the economy of
spreading false information is
completely fueled by AI if we cannot
validate again original content how is
it that we should be able to believe in
anything or
have any faith in the content that we we
look at online and if someone can build
a purpose-built
air B&B ad generator right like there is
there is no business content for this
like why would you do this then you can
create content for other purposes right
if I want to create fake anti Swede
propaganda I can feed a model tons of
pictures of Swedish fish and sad IKEA
may situations for people get lost and
it's easy for me to send them online and
no one can prove to me that these are
not real right there's no way of proving
so I managed to get it all done in time
so in conclusion it has become
increasingly easy for attackers to
execute on these attacks and I've been
I've been doing this for over a decade
and it used to be hard when you used to
do distributed bot attacks you had to
write like your own little botnet and
you had to like inject yourself and
people's browsers I remember a few years
ago there was a guy from Wix sitted an
awesome talk and extension based botnets
at DEFCON right like it used to be
difficult but now you can just plug and
play tools and get your get your access
right get your fake information out
there you can generate new fake content
easily by just building a model right or
find a bunch of scientists whose
research project they get really super
excited about generating new fake Airbnb
ads so conclusion is there's an
impossible problem I don't think so
I mean it looks it sounds like these
attacks are so sophisticated but they
you don't need any understanding and the
technology is really available my take
on this is that the security industry
all of us we've been neglecting these
problems for the past few years right we
haven't actually cared about this ever
when I moved from networks and system
security into web almost all
conversations seem to be that this
wasn't real security and that we didn't
care we need to care because again
credential stuffing was the next largest
attack of last year and if we can solve
this I don't think anybody can
in my opinion having worked with large
companies I mean just really interfacing
with the identity team or the fraud team
or the abuse team whom by the way never
seem to interact with each other I don't
know if any of you have any experience
in that but very rarely with the
security team and in my opinion what we
need is a security mindset we need a
hacker mindset in order to understand
these attacks the environment in which
they exist and the technology used so
what I'm asking of all of you is to
think about how this might impact your
business and if you can help fix these
problems because there is no one silver
bullet in security and I believe that we
need multiple different efforts in order
to try and solve this and we need to at
scale so that was
[Applause]