next up first for the afternoon we have
ryan chapman with implementing a
kick-butt training program lutein go my
good oh there we go hey folks how's it
going today good everyone's good you're
not too tired after lunch like laggin
gonna fall asleep right right everyone's
alright a good deal so my name is Ryan
Chapman and we're here to talk about
Simpson this five-week training course
so they put together I was a trainer for
almost like 6 years like a technical
trainer you know corporate trainer and I
do instant response now I've been doing
it for about six years but enough about
me you don't care about that
so why baseline training we're gonna
this is here's our agenda no one even
cares about the agendas either but
there's two items in bold that are very
important here one of them is the core
tenants of the program I'm sorry I'm
moving around a lot well bad I got to
see the camera guys look come on Oh
so the core tenants of the program and
then the five different phases are
basically the five different weeks and
we're gonna talk about how like how
they're designed why they were designed
that way their module you can kind of
move them around and they're flexible
and blah blah blah blah blah so here's a
little bit about me I absolutely love
retro gaming anyone here like a retro
gamer huh look at there's a picture of a
power dog I'm using a power gloves hack
is that so I at one point I have a
problem with collecting at one point I
actually had five sick a Dreamcast five
of them and I thought that was a bit
Daffy so I sold two of them and now I
only have three and that's just far more
logical right I just still have three I
don't know why but yeah I also also how
do you know if someone does CrossFit
they're a doctor or in this case they do
Brazilian jiu-jitsu
that's they'll tell you or they'll
include a picture in all the damn
presentations alright so there's me
getting choked out I still get choked
out pretty bad I'm actually not very
good but I love it
so yeah know enough about me this is an
80s retro gaming themed conference right
so I was like the power glove everyone I
figured everyone was gonna play on that
movie kung fury he watched kung fury
right and so I had like a hacker man
shirt that I was gonna wear and he wears
this in the movie I was like wait a
minute I know what I can do so I
modified it and I basically just pulled
it apart took all the stuff out and I
put a little presenter remote in it and
now I can just go oh great is that and I
enjoyed that a little too much
so why baseline
training first off anyone here supposed
to be participation right back and forth
anyone here throw your hands up if you
are actively on our blue team now or you
have a blue team at your place of
employment okay how many times will blue
team or come in and know exactly how to
do the job that you want him or her to
do it's extremely rare there's so many
different frameworks you can follow
there's so many different methodologies
and ways to approach a blue team the
defense side of things you can't just
pull someone in opposite half the
streets so to say educational
institutions and certifications are
typically rote memorization you pull
these folks in and they're like I've
seen this content I've got like you know
six different certifications and you're
like okay that's fantastic how many bits
are in a byte they're like what no I
don't know there's been so many people
who have come into our place with like
graduate degrees with forensic analysis
some graduate degrees and like the
building block basics they just they
just don't know them so that's part of
why we designed this at my quote-unquote
day job but I'm not here from day jobs
let's just move on so the goal for this
is that red teamers when you hire a red
teamers typically they come with always
these varied backgrounds right you might
have one gal whose primary focus is like
just web application firewalls and she
could pull the heck out of those things
right and typically what red teams do is
they hire a diverse set of people blue
team's a lot of times as they try to do
that but then they don't ensure that
every time they're responding to an
incident that the same steps are being
taken to have kind of like a unified
defense so that's what we're trying to
kind of get over we're trying to fix
that essentially so speaking of which we
want to develop people who are Jack's of
all trades Jack's and Jill's of all
trades now some of you might be thinking
oh we don't have the personnel for that
you know we have to we actually have to
compartmentalize if you will
well a problem with that is if you have
just a deeper team and then you have a
reversing team and then you have the
tier 1 or tier 2 triage responders the
problem you run into is you know
something comes in it's a weaponized
JavaScript file you know a PDF of
JavaScript and they go oh I can't do
that I have to wait for so-and-so to
come in they work in three days and
meanwhile that threat just lingers and
just kind of hangs out and sits there in
the network and that could be a bad
thing
so again day job slash what I really
like to see is a responding group where
everyone's capable doesn't matter what
comes in doesn't matter what that ticket
or that email or whatever it was comes
in
able to handle it or someone on the
shift is able to handle it and in the
kind of work in unison so the goal is
essentially not necessarily like tier 1
tier 2 tier 3 and capabilities matching
that tiered group but rather anyone
there can handle the situation a lot of
times in security we have very few
people in order you know like how many
people here again with your blue teamers
how many have more than 5 people I saw
really that's all a couple hands alright
cool so a lot most folks don't they have
one or two people sometimes you know so
having a varied skill set is very
important alright to start off you're
gonna have to have some type of subject
matter expert or a trainer to train the
trainers so if anyone wants to start
looking into this there's a program I
forgot the name of it it used to be a
STD now it's a TD it's a technical
training organization they certified
trainers and one of the things they talk
about is a t3 session where you train
the trainers so if you have sneeze like
from reverse-engineering host-based
forensics network forensics or what have
you
then those people would be the ones who
are training your trainers and the
trainers will then be training the
analysts or you know so on and so forth
alright core tenants this is this is the
really important stuff right here ok we
want people to understand the how and
why behind what they're doing too many
times we have people who can basically
like like a technician right I don't
mean to bang on geek squad but just the
name came up right they may know how to
replace an FF are you a field
replaceable unit but they had no idea
how that actually fix the problem you
know their program might say like I pop
it into graphics card and they go ok and
they put a new one in and they're like
problem solved right what was the
problem we want our text and our analyst
especially our responders to actually
know why so we don't want silly monkeys
hitting buttons and getting bananas all
right we want intelligent monkeys wow
look at that guy he's got an idea
alright so this is what we want we want
people to understand how to do things
and they typically learned through
experience all training who here listen
to the keynote yesterday dance right
Rachel play the first name right Rachel
Toback she was talking about how she
doesn't learn something else she
actually does it hands-on does it and
those of you who may be familiar with
Malcolm Gladwell and it's 10,000 hours
concept unless I'm not doing insert
response for 10,000 hours but the idea
is the more you do it you're going to
understand it a lot better so we want to
foster a go here to find the answer
mentality
we have a lot of people who become
dependent on others especially when they
come into a tiered infrastructure or
team if you do happen to have one and
the tier ones are typically like well
how do I do this you know where do I go
to get the ant they don't ask where do I
go to get the answer they ask what's the
answer and they become reliant on that
capability well we don't want that we
want them to know where to go to get
that answer be it internal or be it
external a good example of which RFC's
this is not meant for you to read the
text or I know it's all small don't
worry about that but this is an RFC for
HTTP the protocol so understand the
protocol at a lower level at the very
least you need to understand response
codes right what's a get request what's
a post request when you're initializing
an initiating an SSL connection why
you'd get a connect request what's the
purpose of all that where the response
codes that come back as opposed to
answering a question when someone says
what's at 3:03 and you go oh that's a
bell you get all happy near like oh you
know no like go over here there's an
entire list of them they're all there
all right so we want them to give them
the tools to answer their own questions
going forward if you have your own
knowledge management system you know a
glorified wiki basically if you have a
wiki whatever and you point them to the
articles it's over there go find it over
there and then they find the answers
themselves hopefully going forward
all right different types of learners
come into play apparently this is now
debated some people say this is bunk it
worked for me for years so whatever
there are visual cues that people will
give the trainer typically that should
kind of show how they learn best
kinesthetic learners they learn by doing
and often when you ask them a question
they will literally like look down and
they're trying to visualize themselves
performing that particular action or
activity if you notice that in a
training course or whoever is doing the
training that you pick up off the idea
here whoever is noticing that can kind
of give them assignments or tasks that
involved actually doing auditory
learners will typically look to the
sides and some in fact there's a guy hey
art where are you hey I've got a guy
back there that I work with and whatever
he I tell him something if he really
wants to say what do you say to me he'll
kind of go like this and look at me like
okay
rephrase it again he'll be like I got it
he's a really auditory learner and I
just kind of picked up that on that
whenever just communicating going back
and forth so you also have your visual
learner anyone here look up when you're
thinking a lot of people are visual
learners and look up so depending on
what type of learner the person is and
you can identify just with our visual
QS you give them tasks and assignments
within the training sessions to kind of
foster that you know someone who may be
a kinesthetic learner or a visual
learner you know you start talking about
like having them draw diagrams on paper
or showing them diagrams and having them
replicate them things of that nature
everything should tie back to the real
world
so whatever ticketing system you have
would however you manage your incidents
whatever it is you want to bring those
up as examples like let's just say you
know say you have Splunk and you say we
have 147 different alerts that are
active right now and Splunk okay that's
great how many of them usually fire or
do the cop top ten they're like oh these
six fire all the time okay use those use
those as an examples go over two of them
each or something like that and make
sure that why you're doing that
excuse me you're also reviewing other
people's work ticket review and
shadowing are critical especially
because they serve as really good jump
off points for your training so you're
going through a ticket and you're like
hey we talked about DNS like look here's
the actual query type right here in this
pcap and they go well how come Bob about
that and they use that as a jump-off
point and start taking notes on what you
covered with that particular individual
so you can cover it with the rest works
really really well shadowing is also
indispensable if you have the personnel
and capabilities and overlapping shifts
to be able to do that so the framework I
come calling it a framework it's really
cute I just came up with five different
weeks of training okay you can do them
all the one oh sorry you can do them all
at one time
you can do a couple weeks here and then
a couple weeks there whatever if you
have someone who's brand-new the reason
I'm calling it flexible is if you do
fall five weeks of training a row which
includes host based forensics and
includes Network forensics and includes
worse engineering up like dotnet code
and all that it's gonna be extremely
overwhelming so I don't really recommend
that all right here are the five weeks
here's the breakdown week one is intro
setup and this sim I'm not checking my
email by the way I'm just checking my
time real quick that I never started
cool I never started the timer moving on
alright so week one a lot of companies
you know HR will do like a half hour
session and say hey the work company X
you know we hired you because of
whatever and thanks for being along and
you get paid on these days right
we're going to talk a little bit more
detail the next slide about actually
introducing them truly to your team the
reason that team exists why do you have
a response capability there's probably a
very specific reason by the way setup is
going to take multiple days right
setting up the machine setting up your
VM setting up your accounts organizing
all your passwords all out of this stuff
that's those the first couple days those
are really boring and then you end up
the first week with your sim training so
how many folks here use the sim or
having it work just yell at the name of
it Splunk I hear Splunk spottier Splunk
okay we got Splunk alright so cue radar
our site now whatever you focus were
using you want to introduce that to them
in thorough detail the team origin was
your team developed out of a reaction
did you have a little bit woopsie in
your network that you're responding to
right I know some folks who have gone
from zero active continuous network
monitoring analysts to having over 40 on
a team obviously they didn't just think
like oh we should probably have a really
big team for no reason right so what are
the real threats your company faces and
what caused the formation of that team
why are they really there what really
brought them into your environment and
then for that matter how are the team
formed we've had it let me pull back for
one second I've heard of I've completely
not at my place of business at all I've
heard of people working in this type of
capacity on a sock for example four
years at a time and then asking the
question what does NSM mean like what we
haven't innocent team and they're like
okay what do so how do the teams operate
what are the capabilities what are their
tool sets and then how do they integrate
and that's all really important for them
that can go back to the whole
whiteboarding you know with this type of
training you do a whiteboarding and you
say here's our tiered infrastructure
here's why it was set up this way and
then you erase it and the next day you
point to it I don't know whoever you say
hey you go over there and draw it in the
board and they go okay and then they try
it and then they mess it all up and
they're like I suck do it again right so
you just kind of keep fostering that
idea oh the very bottom here it's very
important folks know your capabilities
what works well on your team and
although this is controversial I stand
by it 155 thousand percent the things
that don't work well on your team the
issues that you have on your team if you
let people know about them upfront and
of course a positive way then they can
help focus on those things
they're being integrated into the team
to try to ease those things otherwise if
they're not aware of it it could be the
exact opposite so your sim what logs you
have available why do you have those
logs what's the duration of those logs
for you Splunk folks how long do they
stay in cold storage before they go to
frozen storage like what can they what
do they have access to and on top of
that where they not have access to
that's critical say your company has
packet captures and you say hey we can
get pcaps
and they're like oh cool well are you
SSL offloading and for that matter how
long do your pcaps stay in play like we
can pull peak apps for up to 5 minutes
ok awesome that's super useful right
whatever so it's very important to let
them know what they have access to and
what they don't and then your tickets I
don't know how many times you know
there's a lot I'm from the Phoenix
Valley so what tech time for the Bay
Area but I live in Phoenix now we have a
lot of security teams but they're all
very close-knit so we kind of know each
other's tools and things that they use
on a daily basis really and there's so
many times people come in and they're
not even just taught the basics of like
hey we would prefer that you document
your tickets like this like use these
types of code blocks or like put you
know we want this type of information or
something like don't put ephemeral links
because that's not gonna help when we're
doing ticket review a month later or
something like that so that's just
critical to kind of get up front and
then again using example very common
tickets as examples is super helpful
okay networking in forensics anyone here
want to come up on stage until I've
learnt exactly how DNS works exactly how
DNS works anyone I don't know how many
was their hand over here maybe in this I
don't know how many times someone's like
I have a CCNA I've got a freaking degree
I got a grad degree in networking you're
like okay how does DNS work well you put
the name in and then it gives you an IP
okay well how's that how's that worked
what gives you an IP stupid like oh no
no all right so actually understanding
these things the core fundamentals those
protocols is critical for the
understanding especially when it comes
to response the more data you provide
them like a peek at the general pcap of
a freaking DNS query couldn't like to
spin people's heads so how do those work
those pro
calls your networking logs do you have a
Zeke environment I hate that name
bro I'm gonna just call bro right do
using bro what are you using for your
log parsing right how are those being
bucket eyes and dumped into your system
where they look like what format you can
follow are they tab separated or the
comma separator the key value separated
like well they look like alright and
where can you go to get information on
those damn logs email and again so many
people are like god I've been tree as
you can email for years now and you're
like cool what does it mean when the
field starts with the X - and they're
like it's it's an X field ok what does
that mean like would some stuff has X
stuff like okay it's just an optional
field right but why are those there and
what uses those you know what's the user
agent what's where they call X mail or
excuse me
an X - mailer why are those important
how can use them for pivoting taking an
example email like a hundred lines and
the headers and just going bottom the
top can be like tell me everything you
see you'll notice a lot of newer hires
even with like a decent amount of sock
experience we'll know like maybe a third
of them if and that's being generous by
the way and then we got Wireshark and
pcap which is Network forensics coming
up over here DNS is my favorite if you
take away anything in this talk right
now except for the fact that the power
glove is bad and I really like these
aside from that you gotta take away the
following there's a video out there on
YouTube it's called a cat explains DNS
it's made by a fella yeah fella in a nil
Kitty phenomenal the guy really knows
his stuff and so you a me he's eccentric
as you can tell right so you're looking
at him you're like it's really
knowledgeable so I show it in every
classic 15 minutes it's phenomenal but
this goes to the example of asking your
class you know like how does DNS work
right and I'm gonna be quick here
because of time I'm just gonna give an
example of some things that we cover
right you pop in an email or I'm sorry
domain name up in the address bar what
does your computer do it looks at the
local cache and it goes the host file it
doesn't do that it reaches out your DNS
server DNS servers most likely a local
resolver the local resolver doesn't have
the answer is gonna go where first to
the teal these to the top low payment
the root domains 13 of them made through
em right if they don't know the answer
they're not going to it's gonna send
them over to the TLD domain so if you're
looking for like farts comm it's gonna
go I don't know where that
go talk to the calm person right when it
goes to the dot-com TLD they're gonna go
like oh that's the authoritative server
over there go get the answer when the
answer comes back they're gonna get the
a record it's gonna have a TTL time to
live if those are very very low and they
repeat or change often I mean that could
be something called fast flux so where
are these things important like all
these lower level protocol things are
extremely important to Train there's a
video of me writing on a board I like
white boards too I can modify this you'd
be white board something oh that's my
project
Wireshark a lot of people don't really
understand how Wireshark even works
right you have a peek at file what is it
there's a bunch of zeros once that's all
it really is right so how does Wireshark
know to represent that data visually to
you well if you look at the top right
hand side here we have an example ipv4
header remember headers Noor when you
read about it in a book and then never
carried on them again I do I don't care
about them until I put them in a
presentation like oh they're really
important so you have the header over
here on the left hand side there's an
arrow pointing up where a shark is
pointing to what I believe is the first
blue line there I'm color blind blue or
purple or something and it's pointing to
the IRS's version for the actual value
of which way over on the left is zero
zero one zero zero the binary value
right you look down at the bottom left
hand side or the other arrow is pointing
down and you see hexadecimal value of 45
you're like well 45 is not 4 well as
taking the first 4 bits what are 4 bits
it's a nibble what's a nibble how many
nibbles are in a byte it was 2 depending
on the architecture blah blah blah this
type of training is critical for people
to understand how something as simple as
Wireshark is actually show like
visualizing what traversed over that
wire ok so starting with the peak app
and not just saying like this means a
packet was sent back and forth but
actually talking about the packet bytes
here's the actual bytes here's how they
mapped to the header and that's how
we're shark is then displaying the data
to you starting at that lower level can
be extremely helpful okay
host base forensics again I typically
recommend what I call week 3 and then
week 4 host based forensics and reverse
engineering if you have a fledgling team
or folks with not a lot of seat
experience I would take this out and
kind of push them off maybe couple weeks
or a month or two or something like that
cool
so in this case we want to talk about
artifacts from your local types of
operating systems if you're a window
shop that's gonna be Windows artifacts
starting with the file system stuff like
NTFS and the MFT parsing the MFT what's
in the MFT what the user journal file is
all that kind of stuff is very important
registry analysis its windows so you
know registry for you Mac users it'll be
all your pee lists and their locations
and things corporate forensics tools
alright do you have a forensic
capability like in case I'm sure you do
because everyone does right so you go
over any case and talk about how you can
remotely connect to the disk and why
that's important Erik Zimmerman's tools
just google them you'll see why they're
phenomenal the artifacts that you need
how to obtain them parsing them and what
that actually tells you just a loan you
could spend an entire day on like the
ten tools on his page and then we've got
deep dive into memory analysis some
examples of artifacts in our classes we
spent an entire day on this poster it's
a sans poster it's hard to get away from
sans content because they provide a lot
of it and a lot of it's really good so
this particular poster you just google
the damn thing it's called Windows
forensic analysis poster you're not
meant to read that by the way if you're
like that text sucks duh but if you just
look at when you download it right
you'll see all these different artifacts
and it's like oh the artifact lives here
and when you parse it it tells you this
and then going through each and every
one of those is what we do if it takes a
day okay if it takes a day and a half or
two days ok whatever memory analysis
take a look knead the water take a
memory image of something like Stuxnet
or black energy mid-sentence water there
we go or something that's like driver
base you know lower level Kitty kind of
malware you stuff and just run every
damn command you can find in the
Volatility command reference do you
never use volatility literally Google
volatility command reference and then
Google volatility example memory images
and then with one of those names slides
available online by the way the example
names I gave up there and just run every
freaking command run every single one of
them and every column why does it exist
why is there a pig there why is there a
handle there
what's a mutex has a mutex different
from a pipe all these different little
things that like core OS concepts and
fundamentals
a lot of responders don't actually
they're not familiar with that if they
haven't worked or had that low-level
friends experience good example of that
in volatility there's a command called
PS list stands for processed lists
there's also one called PS scan PS lists
will what's called wok the doubly linked
list that's referred to in memory as the
eat proc structure and it just goes like
from one to the next from one of the
next and it enumerates all the processes
that are shown in memory and it goes
these are all the processes that are
running right now there's another one
called PS skin and that's because what
malar can do is it can take that eat
proc structure and simply unlink some or
one or whatever of the processes from
that PS list just walks that list so it
just misses that process of memory PS
scan is called pious scan because it
scans through the entire memory image it
looks at all different pool tags and it
looks for anything as tagged as an e
proc and it goes like oh hell that's a
process and it's in memory maybe that's
running in memory and it will list them
if you see an output difference between
PS list and PS scan there's a good damn
reason for that and so having your folks
be aware of that is you know critical
that type of analysis that's the type of
stuff you want to show them like the
differences between the individual
modules and plugins why do they exist i
hadn´t know how many people be like hey
so they show the same thing it's just
different names like ok cool story I'm
sure reverse engineering the primary
thing I want to focus on here carrier
files if you have a PDF and that PDF has
JavaScript in it or if you have what
we're looking at right here which is I
believe this I think it was an imitate
dropper I may have been wrong on that
but our downloader excuse me whatever
you have the visual basic that's in here
if you've become fully reliant on
sandboxes right say you use the Falcon
sandbox or just virustotal they've got
like 4 or 5 in there I think Tennyson
does one of the ones is default in there
or the names hybrid analysis is Falcon
online you drop it in there's something
like imitate that actually uses
typically a loop where there's five
different URLs and if you throw it
through an analysis sandbox as soon as
it hits the first one it goes there's
your call out and it provides it to the
analyst meanwhile the other four because
you didn't manually decode all the code
that's actually in there you might not
even see it
so that's really if you look doing a
meta-analysis by the way by just using
sandboxes and if you're getting five or
six okay you're probably cool but if
you're getting one you're probably
missing indicators Sam bone is a teacher
here well not here here but San
Francisco City College phenomenal fellow
if anyone knows him here you know how
great he is Sam's class dot info okay if
you go to his website he's got tons of
curated content like odd ton whenever
someone asks me where's one of the best
places I can go for free training Sam's
class taught info it's phenomenal all
right so he's got am our course on here
and we spend at least half a day just
going through it so if you're like oh I
can't get the URL the slides are online
or just tweet me or whatever it's
available finally the last week is
working tickets thank you and working
with intelligence so intelligence we
start right off with iOS ease indicators
of compromise what is a computer to
indicator what is a an atomic indicator
how are they similar how are they not
similar why are they important so on and
so forth so a lot of folks are not
familiar with iOS indicators of attack
so we start to start talking about those
and why those are important just seeing
that PowerShell launched on a Windows
machine it means nothing it launches on
Windows all the time right however if
you see PowerShell launch and then you
see these four specific processes launch
in a row and you see that happening on
multiple hosts in your environment and
that never has that could potentially be
an indicator of attack so we talked
about all those kinds of things and then
we've got threat hunting wait for the
banana I know the the dirt the d'azur
thing right now everyone's like oh I
throw it hunting me yeah it's extremely
important I was gonna ask folks here you
know just shout some names out of what
models you're following but everyone
knows you're following the same damn
model everyone's following miters attack
framework anyone not following miners
attack framework using something can you
say what it is it's like okay all right
well okay so any threat hunting is
critical so we tried teaching that right
up front using the Intel that you get
from your own
tickets your own alerts and then
spinning that and maybe pivoting off
that to find other related attacks or
threats something as similar as an are
as simple as an email coming in with a
given subject and you search for that
subject over the past 30 days and you go
like look our email plans didn't catch
that campaign right and there could be
30 300 whatever emails and that one so
then you go review that reinforcements
final concept here I don't on the right
it talks about quizzing I don't like
quizzes in terms of you need to get a
70% or above I don't even want to score
when it comes to quizzes but if you look
into some of the learning management
systems or the LMS is there's one that's
like the king of all of them open source
called Moodle I'm sure folks have heard
of it here so if you grab Moodle and you
make some quizzes I recommend making it
such that if you get it wrong it just
goes like a dragon and I go okay and you
look it up it's like that try again like
they just just try to get them to just
find the damn answer right and just put
it in it's just it's almost kind of part
of that whole rote memorization thing
that we don't want to focus too much on
but it's still good to have also if you
folks have ever heard of Mnemosyne
nemesis ii i believe i'm pronouncing
that correctly I'm probably butchering
it cuz it was a Greek god of memory or
something like that there's an
open-source tool called nimah seen in
scene and if you look that up it'll it's
really really good for memorizing facts
over time and it's really good for these
types of concepts oh and then of course
your tabletop you know you show them a
file you say hey this came in and you
downloaded off virustotal or whatever
but you tell them I get this came in how
exactly would you respond to this and
then you kind of just go over it and and
hopefully they didn't suck okay and
that's it I heard we wouldn't have a
whole lot of time for questions because
I get yep yep yep I love to talk which
you can already tell I'm well aware so
we are using the SLI dot do with the
code or access code besides SF 2019 I
don't know if I can personally actually
answer those and a few flows from where
that but we'll try to get those answered
my twitter by the way is RJ underscore
chap if you want to hit me up on there I
love communicating and networking all
kinds of crap so if you have any
questions about the kind of training
concepts or maybe a little more detail
on some individual things just for sure
let me know and yeah I also have two
classes on Pluralsight comm there by the
way to breakfast pong
right great right there so if you want
to trick those classes out we have some
cards for free access so you can just
check them out with that painting a
little self plug there but yeah that's
it I hope you enjoyed the talk and
thanks very much appreciate
[Applause]