so a good morning for some of us it's a
little bit early but some of us is not
my name is Sasha Foust
I am a product security manager for lyft
I presented last year and gave kind of a
quick introduction of what my thinking
was when I was started building the team
this year I'm following up sort of a v2
version of how we're looking at
automating some of our security
decisions but also enabling
democratization of that data as well
quick background on in terms of the
agenda
I'll give kind of a quick background
what we've done a little bit of the
platform overview we are releasing a
platform or piece of our platform today
what are the modules and enrichments
that are currently available and what
are the extensibility available to poor
people to add their own context into our
systems as well as upcoming release what
are we thinking what it's coming up next
so on and so forth if you want kind of a
recap of the the initial thinking I
would recommend to revisit last year
presentation I'll just give kind of a
quick recap this year so most of the
business owners are taking risky or
basically accepting risk without clear
information it's very often hearsay or
we're making kind of like somewhat
educated guess but for the most part
we're kind of blind a lot of the
security reviews are done in isolation
we actually go see the subject matter
expert they do the security there things
are kind of addressed but they're not
globally shared so there's kind of a
communication challenges there as well
dependence of view and transitive risk
view is also very challenging we don't
really have kind of a we don't have the
ability to zoom out and look at blast
radius of particular asset being
compromised or as we are accepting risks
we don't really know the blast radius of
transitive risk of for example a low
value asset that gets compromised what
does it really leads to think about a
single user being spear phishing in
domain environment is there rather than
that Spearfish user to domain and then
like we really don't know so to try to
solve this thing when I was kind of
building teams over the last year one of
the core thing that came to mind for me
I didn't really want to fix everything
because that's not scalable as a team so
I defined the team mission as empowering
lift initially and now the community to
make inform an automated security
decisions so my goal is to enable the
decision-makers to make good decisions
and also find a way to automate our
decision loops so we want to codify the
goal is actually to codify our thinking
as much as possible and for that we
needed some sort of decision loop
framework I personally use Oda loop for
some of you that are familiar observe
orient decide and act and a lot of our
pieces part of it we're releasing today
is part of that mostly on the observe
and orient piece and moving forward will
give out more and more decision enact
piece as we're releasing some of our
components so the idea is to take
subject matter experts and get them
together if they're solving pieces of
the puzzle on their own
why don't we enable them to share that
as much as possible make that cohesive
view available to all so that one
security can be observed but also other
things can be done as well so if you
have good like good visibility about
your all infrastructure and you've
solved like asset attribution which is
like a big problem to solve
yes security can kind of leverage that
and says ok if we ask that X is
compromised we can go reach out person B
but also from Finance they can look at
building information like who's spending
more money and compute for example so
it's yeah now it's not a narrow view of
just security we're using it for
security but it can be used for a bunch
of other things as well so the idea is
to get everybody to work together in a
cohesive consistent language that can be
observed validated and also augmented
over time as we're kind of figuring
things out so the platform that we're
releasing is called cartography and the
main objective of it is to build maps
that's all it does Bill Maps refine the
Maps take notes on the maps and then
share that share the map enable the map
viewing for a bunch of people but also
enable automation because we're kind of
building up the GPS capability for our
decision loop and codifying them as well
so we're releasing this it's been
I think the bits been turned on public
last Friday so if you want to take a
look at it today it is available now we
will continue updating it and also
adding individual projects that leverage
it so that's really the core of our of
our thinking of our system at lift at
least in terms of security I'll credit
Mike Johnson for coming up with a name
we had like a bunch of other names but
cartography was like the one that kind
of stuck and I think I thought it was a
good idea really represent what we're
trying to do from a platform perspective
it's pretty simple we're talking about
Python code we kept it pretty generic
the way it works is the user calls a CLI
either a user's or a cron job or some
sort of automation the CLI runs a global
sync process that can call multiple
intelligence modules so it is modular
where you can actually stitch part of
your global map into individual
components that are responsible for
creating that schema and maintaining
that schema and all that schema kind of
connects together we are backed by neo4j
graph database I personally started
using graph database to solve automating
kind of attack flow about five six years
ago and I felt like graph database
really solve my problem in terms of
transitive analysis having the ability
to compromise one asset and move forward
that's when I was like heavy thinking on
red teaming and Azure so we are still
backed by a neo4j that can be replaced
over time with different graph database
but neo4j is kind of a low entry point
it is free there's a community and
desktop edition if you want to move to
cluster and so on you can move to
enterprise and that would work
so once intelligence modules are
gathering the data and putting the data
and part of their schema into neo4j we
do a cleanup job so think about like
taking a snapshot updating the whole
graph and then deleting basically stale
nodes and edges as well so our doc
project documentation details like how
we actually achieve this but we actually
do a cleanup job so think about like the
graph is constantly updated as frequent
frequently as you want
and then the last
peace is are its enrichment job which is
basically the ability to run a series of
neo4j statements to do admitted labeling
on nodes and edges and so on so we do
have two extensibility point one is the
intelligence module so we can continue
adding new Intel modules in there it
requires a little bit of code change in
updating the core sync service but
that's definitely durable it's pretty
low entry the easiest route and what's
available as of today you can just drop
a file and we'll work is the enrichment
job and I'll give some detail in terms
of how that works
so the remark Leasing today
looks like my mic not always working so
the first module that we're releasing
today is our AWS I've give kind of an
overview last year what we're thinking
about that we have completed it or at
least a v1 so we're releasing AWS lyft
is heavy investment in AWS so we
definitely invested there and the module
supports or basically provides
visibility of dinamo tables the whole
compute ec2 elasticsearch load balancers
mi Alma going through a mic change okay
let's do that now before I get started
[Music]
all right hopefully we're good so going
back to AWS so we have diamo DB ec2
instance load balancers elasticsearch
the complex world of I am which we've
simplified for now and there's
definitely more work there RDS route 53
or DNS and s3 quick overview of I am we
kept it pretty simple because we weren't
really focused on those questions am
questions that much I basically the
policy worlds and I am language is very
complex so that's an area we're keep
investing but at the base you'll have an
AWS account our platform does support
cross
yes so you can have multiple a DBS
account so we have a relationship from
AWS to the users the group's AWS roles
the infamous access keys and AWS policy
as well so we kept it pretty generic on
I am just the basic things for s3 we
have the relationship back to the
database account the s3 buckets and the
S ACL as well and we do some enrichment
on that so we analyze the bucket policy
and on also the S ACL to infer that that
bucket is anonymously accessible or not
as well as providing information which
methods are available so that's kind of
a very simplistic enrichment that can
provide immediate value you can get some
of that information from the console but
it's not necessarily as detail is what
we provide so very simplistically in
neo4j you do match a DBS account
resource as three buckets that is an
anomaly accessible equal true and then
you can return account name s3 name and
anonymous actions so you get sort of a
table view results which you can consume
as an analyst but you can also consume
as basically building some automation
ec2 is an area where we had a lot of
question initially like what is exposed
who owns what and so on and so forth so
we invested a little bit more our schema
is a little bit more I would say mature
in this sense and has better coverage so
we do say the same thing as AWS accounts
ec2 reservations ec2 instances and the
ec2 instances are connected to their
network interface auto scaling group
subnet security group as well and we
also connect security group to IP rules
either inbound or outbound and IP range
also so you get kind of a quick view of
network the networking infrastructure as
well as the ec2 instance so a very
common question is people are asking is
like what is exposed like you can run in
map and so on you may get some decent
result or a TPS is going to block you at
some point so you'll get partial result
or you can ask the graph a very simple
question of okay if I have I want to see
everything that's available
that IP range that have basically an
inbound permission so you can craft that
question and then automatically infer
and enrich your your easy to know that
instant that says it's in an expose yes
or no right so what it looks like in
neo4j and this is not a primer in cypher
language it just to demonstrate the
capabilities and the type of query that
you can you can do so the way we've
implemented that enrichment is matching
the inbound rules of like 0 0 0 / 0
basically open to the world and create
that mapping in the schema down to the
ec2 instance down to the AWS account
easy to instance or not always real
connected to auto scaling group so we do
have an optional match there if it's
connected we're going to get it as well
and then we return the auto scaling
basically the AWS account name order
scaling group group names the rules like
what is the what is the port range
that's open as well as a number of
instance open to that specific exposure
in addition this is kind of an example
of how we're leveraging this for
automation is we end up building and
exposure signature out of that so we
connect all these all these dots and
says ok let's create a signature that
represents that exposure if we've
accepted that exposure let's keep track
of it let's say you have port 22 open on
certain machines and you say ok that's
totally normal and you want to build
instead of keeping this as tribal
knowledge you want to keep track of like
oK we've actually reviewed this we see
we think it's ok let's create a
signature so we end up building drift
detection out of that where every time
the graph sinks we have a baseline
signature of all the exposure that were
there initially on day one that we
eventually kind of review and every time
something else shows up in our
environment we actually get notified
it's a bit late you should catch these
things as they're being pushed but it's
better than nothing so at least we have
that drift detection so what it looks
like again it's just a blurred view we
have kind of a table when we run that
query we have a table of the AWS account
s G group and so on
and as long as well as a baseline you
can further extend that to exposed to
something right so let's say you say
okay we've globally identified their
assets that are exposed to the Internet
well there's other assets that might be
exposed to very specific IPS out there
so you can change that in and basically
modify their enrichment or basically
enhance it or complement it by looking
at all basically excluding non-routable
IPS and says okay give me everything
that's not a goal so as you're doing
that further analysis you can start
saying oh okay we've identified these
IPS as part of a partner X or vendor Y
and then you can start augmenting and
labeling that and says exposed to
partner X for example so you can start
adding this we cannot solve the problem
of figuring out the context for every
company but what we can do is give you a
language give you a method for you to
actually augment that baked-in we can
provide some common enrichment and the
schema and then we enable you to
actually make in your contacts within
that platform so that's another way that
you can do it if you're also interesting
as an analyst hey I want to run the same
query and I want to kind of look
visually at the data with instead of
looking at kind of table and charts you
can leverage an ear for J in terms of
instead of returning nodes and edges
attribute you can return a path so you
can say P equal that path and then you
can return it so this is what we're
doing in the in terms of the P equal as
well as our optional match p2 and in
what we've done is p1 a P and P 2 and
visually what it looks like is like this
this is comes and bakes in as part of
your neo4j stack and in free you can
still connect this to more advanced
visualization I'm a big fan of link
curious you can also do I think Tom
Sawyer as it or other API as well but
baten as of like day one you can get
that by with our project quickly
visualizing this there's we have three
atps accounts which are represented by
purple nodes I don't actually I didn't
expect the screen to be so big so I
guess
guys can see so you have abbs accounts
in purple and we can quickly infer that
there's a common pattern in the middle
or across those AWS accounts in a comic
pythons are related to IP range and
inbound permission so as an analyst you
can run this query and quickly get
visualization of like hey there's a
pattern that's being defined there maybe
I can identify what those IP range are
and then augment the labeling to expose
to whatever that is and then over time
you can continue again go back to drift
detection over time you can sort of
build and bacon that knowledge base in
the graph instead of here say for
example or tribal knowledge when I
joined lyft there was a humunga-truck of
knowledge and this is my attempt to
start capturing that furthermore you can
also look and I'll go fairly quickly
because I think the concept is fairly
hopefully understood where you can go
back to the video we also have at live a
common naming schema for our order
scaling group hopefully you have this in
your environment if you don't maybe you
have other problems that you need you
may want to address first but if you
have a naming convention which for us is
basically service role usage and some
sort of grid for our deployment you can
do the analysis and do the enrichment
and infer that this ec2 instance into
production or staging and you can start
looking at aggregation per service right
so now we're starting to build kind of
our own customizable map of our
infrastructure in our platforms support
set furthermore you can propagate that
information to other nodes as well so if
you have an ec2 instance that our
production staging or basically so
either staging or production true
you can propagate that information to
your ec2 see a security group and ec2
subnets as well so this again goes back
to enrichment and propagating that
information and customizing the graph
for your needs so in terms of enrichment
is pretty simple you can take neo4j
statements and combine them so the first
one that we have here is basically
identifying an auto scaling group that
has a name that match a reg X that is
looking for production
and then if there's a match we label the
group and the ec2 instance as production
equal true and then the next one is okay
give me the subnet and the ec2 security
groups that are associated with that
instance and label them too as well you
can combine these things and represent
them as a ground what we refer as a
graph job which is adjacent serialized
version of our graph job class which is
available in our project and you drop it
in the analysis folder and every time
the graph sink these things will run
every single time so that particularly
enrichment for example will enable you
in a very simplistic way to look at Isis
gaps across your environment you can ask
a very simple question is mass or ec2
security groups that are both production
and staging and return them so if any of
them return for example you have
isolation gap or your basically your
staging environment can talk to
production you may accept that risk and
again go back to creating some sort of
signature for it but at least you have
visibility they're going briefly moving
forward a little bit on other components
we have load balancer load balancer
associated with AWS accounts easy to
instance DNS records and load balancer
listener so we have that and we do look
at the internet scheme internet-facing
scheme to infer in turn expose true or
false and then we propagate that to ec2
instance we're trying to drive consensus
consistency and in our labeling route 53
again that's your DNS world or at least
part of it
you have your DNS zone DNS records and
they are associated with elasticsearch
domain ec2 instance and load balancer
this came in particularly useful for a
common scenario of we have vulnerability
on service comm like where does it where
does it land in our environment what's
what's basically is affected so we can
ask that simple question of a we have a
bug bounty on you know API that live
comm for example where's where are these
things basically deploy like let's start
doing
analysis of the impact so that came in
very particularly useful and I'll have
another demo later where we actually
even go further than that
we have elasticsearch as well in an
elastic search we analyzed the access
policy to infer in an ex post or fall so
you you do get that labeling there's a
lot of elastic search out there that
gets that gets exposed and unfortunately
many of you actually realized a little
bit too late there's a lot of scanners
out there that are looking for these
things so that can become particularly
useful RDS is pretty simple it's
basically RDS instance and ADB SRA
provides a public publicly accessible
attribute which we leverage and label in
and expose as well you can either
further go down and see it at the RDS
instance which security groups are
enable and start we visit are going back
to exposed to partner X&Y as well so you
can further dig down the RDS instance is
currently not connected to easy to
security group
I think the person working on that will
make that happen I think we didn't
hopefully within the next week I can't
see him but I wanted to point finger
anyways connection from RDS instance to
Institute security group should come in
pretty quickly dynamo very simple what's
your dynamo DB tables this can come in
particularly useful to some degree for
privacy looking at table names and so on
and start digging a little bit further
maybe at some point but overall that's
what we're releasing as of today we've
somewhat opened the floodgate now we
have several Intel modules that we've
completed internally we just need to
kind of massage them and transfer them
to open source some of those includes
github Jeff jump is kind of interesting
connection of humans computer and policy
in applications as well so there's good
visibility there pager duty a good way
of actually sending up attribution
between service and owners like who's on
call for a service usually gives you a
ballpark of which team owns it workday
HR world like who reports to who who's a
director and so on and so forth becomes
very useful for attribution and
consolidation of
that at some point envoy if you're using
one of our other open-source project on
void this became very useful when you
start going beyond wws api that live
comm slash something then we can
actually have that map back to the
specific service because envoy is a
reverse proxy G suite is come in Google
Cloud as well so I'll go very quickly
github this is what it will look like so
we're taking the a BBS world and we're
connecting it to github together so you
have an ec2 instance and order scaling
group and then we through our enrichment
we've connected the ASG with the service
in the github world what we've basically
done is map github in terms of the
information that we're interested and
then connect the project to the service
which is more contextual to us right so
now from ec2 instance you can route back
to the actual branch and you also have
which may become very useful the branch
dependency in terms of Python library we
only started with Python library we'll
have like go and other ones as well but
you'll get the picture in terms of like
some of the information that's available
so if you're interested in like which
service has which dependency you can ask
the graph and get that fairly easily 0
so the concept here is like I keep
adding just nodes to the graph based on
what we look meant it
so we've connected AWS and github we're
introducing JIRA which basically is a
service has a JIRA project so we added a
single node it's a little bit more don't
look at to see sometimes single node
will thank you a long time to achieve at
least 80% of coverage but we have
service to JIRA we've added pager duty
now we're diving into kind of the HR
world with humans where we have a
service now we have on call to the
humans so that's another augmentation of
the graph that we've done and then we
introduced a workday which now has human
can report to other humans we also have
teams and then we connected the teams to
the service that they own
and membership of that of that human as
well right so as you see it drives
forward momentum every single investment
that you're making and every module that
you're we're either adding or that the
community is adding will augment the
view and the possibilities and questions
that can be answered over time so
nothing is lost every time you just keep
adding adding adding what does it mean
so if we have a graph like this where we
have a service we have four
unfortunately some of you may not be
familiar with on board but Unger is
basically a reverse proxy so if we have
a service you have the reverse proxy of
which part of the Earl actually maps to
a given service you have your JIRA
project you have the human who's on call
yet the team you have the ec2 instance
all this information can become very
useful in terms of incident response
right so common questions like okay we
have an incident or an alert popped in
like who do we bring on board like who
do we call so we've actually leveraged
this graph and we basically hopefully
okay sorry this thing goes red some time
so we build a slack bot and connected
specific commands on the slack bot to
queries so now an incident or anyone at
the company that is interested in
specific services can say who is the
owner of that particular Earle and then
the slack bot understands that question
runs the query and returned the data so
that's becomes useful for instant
response becomes useful for bug bounty
handlers as well like they know exactly
where route and they also becomes useful
to actually kind of like bring the right
people in place another piece of the
graph which is basically connecting JIRA
workday in the service world where we
have or we have teams we have humans and
we have JIRA project so if you're having
JIRA project and you say ok you have all
my dear project I know how to look at
security bugs but I want to measure like
how we doing
you can still leverage this graph and
because you've solved the JIRA project
to service and then service the owner
you can now measure like here's all my
security bugs and you can
zoom out to the org owner basically zoom
out to org Warner or individual team so
you can take that and actually start
doing some measurements furthermore like
another example that we've had is
through our investment with Von D B
which is a vendor that provides a data
set of all vulnerabilities across
multiple assets so for us when we ingest
assets we actually try to normalize
through CP Eve naming convention and
then we can query that that particular
data set and get the vulnerability that
avoids us from running like necess for
example on our infrastructure like it
scales a lot better we don't do networks
camping at all we don't need to so if
we've connected the HR world and the
github in JIRA and Volney be together
then we can at the bottom we have a risk
that affects a specific dependency so
now we can start measuring that
dependent basically measuring the debt
that we've accumulated in a way that we
can zoom in and zoom out zoom in is okay
what service or what library zoom out is
like who's the owner of that debt right
and then you can start building out
charts and so on which is what we've
done so we call this basically intel
juice we take intelligence information
from the graph we have some jobs that
are basically requesting those specific
pieces of the map and then we store it
for in a database for historical data
and then we use our standard business
intelligence platform which I lift this
superset I've done it with power bi at
Microsoft you can probably use it
tableau as well I've seen people do it
so you can actually take that graph data
set create some snapshot historical data
what you want to measure and then use
the other more powerful charting and so
on and a platform that people are kind
of accustomed to at the exact level to
actually go and look at that data I see
you I know I'm always done I'm almost
done so moving forward we want to move
more to close real time graph update for
example cloud trail like instead of
taking a snapshot like how can we
connect as close as possible to resource
lifetime as they are created as they're
being basically destroyed so that the
graph it becomes like much more of a
living thing
cloud trail is an example of AWS
we're looking at GCP as well and so on
sokovia in AWS I was very impressed with
zelkova presentation reinvent on the
work that Bridgewater has done in terms
of analyzing I am policy role during
check-ins to see if it deviates from
expectations so I'm looking at sokovia
right now how can we actually leverage
that or other components to codify more
and more of our decision-making more
automation much more module coming out
and hopefully we get more from the
community as well and I'm looking
forward to do that to actually see that
this is more the red teaming thinking a
Mayan is like looking at leveraging more
of our Observatory and decide platform
to drive actions so a grafter ring draft
driven security chaos monkey or
extension to bloodhound and so on is
something that I'm kind of like
interested in even though I'm managing
kind of a global team in terms of
security I still have that that very red
team kind of automation automated weapon
thinking so that maybe come in in the
future thank you we're hiring if you're
interested in helping us solve these
problems I need help
we need help so we're definitely always
hiring as well thank you
you