well thank you very much for taking the
time to come and see us today well we're
going to talk about profiling VIP access
patterns in user CENTAC centric data
streams the TLDR that is basically try
to find out if a a VIP account and I VAP
account Ain can vary depending on the
context and is at times is very
difficult if you're able for example to
do a lot of moment type of attack like a
pasta hash or or pass the ticket and
impersonate a VAP account is it's almost
impossible to tell if you follow
patterns of behavior of an administrator
a technique that you can do post
exploitation and that's where we're
going to talk about today how we're
trying to approach this this problem so
who are we
my name is rod sorrow and I've been in
the industry for a little bit I run a
hackerspace here in Silicon Valley
called Pacific hackers we also have a
conference in November and I'm here with
Joe today which is my partner in crime
we've been working together for over
four years now since we started working
together at capito because fear was a
you be a start-up was acquired by Splunk
then we were sprung for two years and
then we move on to jasc
and now he says core light so like I
mentioned previously the the goal of
this talk is a the bottom line is can we
tell if a VIP account either an admin
either a sequel is a a root account or
he's super admin I seen that and
organizations I have a very long tenure
as
windows engineer and I've seen a lot of
admins of admins and super admins can we
tell if this accounts either had been
compromised or they are behaving in a
manner that is dangerous so we will look
a little bit of the malicious insider so
how is this defined as VIP the AAP is
defined as the account that has the most
privilege within a system of application
we try to include application as well
because we try to make the definition a
little more broad they're just simply
rude or system administrator and because
when you go to in certain environments
there are levels and sub levels of
system administrators or super users
usually some of the privileges that this
accounts have is they can create
accounts they can change user passwords
they can write or change log files
install software
add themselves to specific groups create
groups take over specific files and
these accounts are needed because within
an organization you don't want to have a
flat structure where everybody has the
same sort of the same privileges when it
comes to creating I'm in a straight of
tasks or creating users or resetting
passwords so there's just sort of a
hierarchy where basically you had to if
we follow the principle of least
privilege you had to do obviously
segregate duties and you had to assign
every each user according to their tasks
and obviously you don't want to assign
any user a test that would allow them to
take over that happens sometimes with
administrator accounts that's been seen
in the past I was part of a team that
was protecting a organization you
probably I Sarah but if you
the industry long enough where the
system administrator had all their
passwords and a excel sheet there were
the this individual was targeted
he was fish and it was a resulted to be
a a nation state and that nation state
basically took over the organization
took over content and won ensued
afterwards was basically a very
stressful and difficult to deal with so
what happens sometimes is depending on
the organization and the way things are
structure usually you you want to you
want to prevent somebody from taking
over everything and you want to
distribute tasks and pernicious and
privileges accordingly to whatever the
users or group of users are doing and
that's that's a way to do to at least
the 101 of system administration and
basically these are things that would
allow you to keep your your organization
protected I'll give you an example I had
a customer where basically they were
attacked by ransomware and because I
said a GPO that basically said the user
cannot write outside of their documents
ransomware came in once executed but all
what was encrypted was the My Documents
folder so even though I had an ass where
the backup was written to they couldn't
write to the nest even though I had a
software and shares where they could
pull software they could pull for
example payroll they couldn't get into
it and they couldn't get into it because
the end they simply didn't have rights
and they couldn't pass the hatch because
I do a little trick which is to create
an account just to join computers to the
domain then I disable it and get rid of
it so usually when you do that you had
to sort of remember what was the
password for the administrator 500 if
you do that then you're screwed you have
to reset but usually that's one of the
things
in case the somebody gets popped they
can retrieve the hatch and then
obviously you're sure that it'll pass
the hash and access everything and if
you had something like eternal blue for
example which it was one of the things
that want to cry was doing then you can
encrypt everything so by by this example
when I try to explain is it's the
relevance of the the isolation of
privileges and the power that this
accounts have so I think I've already
been through this the analog account and
UNIX or Linux systems it's usually the
root account
so usually we look either a system in
straighter and T system or route to put
it a little bit more into a context of
how these are defined contextually and
conceptually usually what a supplier is
called role based access control or DAC
and rbac basically allows you to create
other organizational units or groups
where you can then apply it right and
apply privileges that supersede the
individual that is inside that that
group or organizational unit and it's
usually very very common in Active
Directory environments the active
directory basically is the the
operational application of RBAC
and it's usually done through a protocol
called LDAP and LDAP can be used in
Linux environments and Windows
environments and our investigation had
mostly data thrown at the directory so
here's a a overview of how the
permissions are usually distributed you
have the
the director of service service
basically checks the schema the schema
is like this this hierarchical
information about who is who what they
do what they can and they cannot do it's
usually resides in the domain controller
and then from there using diverse number
of technologies it gets distributed to
there were stations to servers and the
ultimately the applications here's an
example many of you probably are very
familiar with this this is how you
manage an Active Directory you have the
users the users can be moved in to all
users you can create groups you can
create different types of special groups
if you want
and in this case basically what Active
Directory allows you to do is basically
create you get very granular or who does
what and where can they do it like I was
saying before this can get complicated
and I want to we want to say this is a
caveat because this is an initial
approach of this research and there are
environments where there are super
admins there are all you admins they are
hidden or use their service accounts
within my career as the system engineer
many times I was just telling products
where we have to test connection to LDAP
and then one administrator will see in a
specific of you and then the other woman
come to find out and he didn't even know
it I guess because it was a need-to-know
basis I was working with a a company
that basically they were making military
developing military helicopters so there
were a lot of all use and parts of the
schema that were not seen by everybody
and that were seen by the specific
individuals obviously this may
this research are a little more
complicated and difficult we try to
basically approach this research in the
context of a specific or reduce or you
data where we knew at least what
accounts based on the schema and on the
description of these users where
administrators and if you even go into
into cross-domain trusts or or forest it
gets even more difficult so once we
basically agree on what what the VIP
accounts of what are the activities or
the behaviors that VAP accounts have we
were able to do it by certain tasks so
in this case we looked at backups
password resets creation of accounts
software installs and then basically the
reason why we did this is because we
needed to try to approach to see if if
we if we if we can tell what they're
doing if we can establish a benchmark of
what they do can we tell if they have
been compromised either by an external
actor or by a rogue insider so it looks
like I got ten minutes right yeah so
that means that we're gonna have to
speed it up a little bit so here's a a
some of the the quick reasons why you
target EAP accounts you say one tool
called hound that tells you almost like
the degree of separation that you had to
get domain and then obviously if you get
the main admin you want pretty much
everything here's a tool
call me me cats you probably very
familiar with this where you could do
things such as pasture hatch and you can
do pass the tickets it's a little more
difficult nowadays we still can be done
mostly if the year forest level is based
on legacy 2003 2012 or 2008 rather so
this accounts can constantly targeted
and lately why we most of us have seen
is fishing spear fishing because
obviously like I said before I've been
in situations where once the
administrator was compromised
basically the organization was done and
there's been other cases wrong it's
wrong inside there the administrator or
in a specific administrator leaves takes
the passwords or research the passwords
from others and then it locks up or or
or disabled to extra trade information
so here's the problem
so not only Joe take it from here and
he's gonna talk to what we did with
Kafka and how we approach this problem
all right thanks all right you guys hear
me okay so yeah now we're just gonna
kind of dive in the last few minutes
here into some of like the technical
implementation we were kind of doing to
prototype out this sort of kind of
intuition about there's important users
in enterprise data sets and and there
should be a way to kind of fingerprint
and and maybe sort of assess
automatically some notion of like risk
the the the account represents the
overall and uh the the overall sort of a
user hierarchy so I think you know how
we did did this problem in an
implementation perspective is just kind
of more based on the contracted
I was originally exposed to it at when I
was still kind of helping with
professional services services and
engagements and so you can kind of think
of this as like a cookie cutter pattern
we use that a few large customers doing
consulting work and the reason it's sort
of a fun story to tell and kind of like
extrapolate some of the ideas here is
because sort of this workflow we're
talking about a led to like creating two
prosecutable cases against insiders so
people are stealing data and stuff like
that in in a really large
kind of bank card network or I don't
know how to say it without giving away
post basically a really big financial
organization one of the interesting
problems we sorta had to think about
this time for kind of modeling kind of
important users in LDAP data was how to
kind of do the anomaly detection or the
the the scoring of the of the user
behavior in a real-time framework so in
our in our implementation we were using
at the koepcke streams API and basically
spinning up like a little distributed
app that can run more it's gonna be more
some of the scoring metrics I'll show
you at that at the end here so kind of
like what happens with this this
algorithm is there's there's there's two
kind of steps there's a sort of a
ranking step that is about kind of
deriving information from whatever
datasets we are sort of curating for the
problem of like identifying specific
user types typically this for us this is
Active Directory in different forms and
kind of how we derive a behavioral
fingerprint for the the user activity is
leveraging a lot of Kerberos in this
case so we Kerberos is something we
spend a lot of time kind of on like
cherry-picking little little pieces of
that data into into like a analytic
schema and also like the Kerberos ticket
granted without which all kind of talked
about a little bit but at the end of the
day we're sort of inferring this kind of
like social graph which is a
relationship of inherited like
permissions and trusts and how they can
access certain resources and so because
there's sort of a graph kind of implicit
in like the social structure of these
these kind of user accounts and sort of
where they what their functions are the
the first step in this problem was to
model like create sort of a nice
scalable graph data structure to compute
some some classic graph metrics so kind
of what we have here is like that like
that the the algorithm that we
implemented broke broken down into steps
and basically what what the point is to
is to sort of kind of do some intuitive
processing of a social network like a
website or in this case it's just like
it could be thought of as like something
like Facebook where there's a bunch of
users connected they may be connected
between they may be linked by by devices
or something else other than another
user account but because it's a graph we
can kind of leverage some some breast
best practices and assign a couple of
metrics to the ranking of the users in
this in this this kind of large
collection of sort of related entities
and so with with with graph like with
like with the graph it gives us a couple
of different like counts of metrics that
are important and we basically kind of
have a under the hood it's kind of where
we had to spend some time building up
our sort of hearest heuristic so we're
using PageRank a couple of other kind of
hand-built features to describe for each
user the relative rank in the graph
that's that's kind of like the key
intuition for the first step and then
from from there we basically take a like
a sort of a time like a like a time
series point of view for each user
account that we find important and I
think maybe I forgot to say this but the
reason we sort of like ended up with
these first two steps were kind of why
we're sort of really thinking about what
does it mean to be like a high risk high
risk individual in an organization in
terms of their potential to just elevate
trust or target like different keys to
the kingdom like like walking and ldap
tree is a perfect example of a sort of a
attack technique we'd see a lot when
kind of a campaign was was successful
and the target was like just exfiltrated
with all the user accounts so we're just
kind of going after these these these
these accounts that are able to do a lot
of kind of high profile permission
Changez and and in this this sort of dis
metric like we have a a just like an
intuition for reducing false positives I
mean that's it's not really said here
explicitly but step one and step two the
first time I implemented this algorithm
I we weren't doing any sort of like
ranking of important individuals and
what happened was when we kind of get to
the the actual meat of this algorithm
which is kind of this little graph here
so for every user and in the environment
you kind of get this graph it's like all
the heat map but really what it is is it
just kind of tells you like in a nice
simple picture that's gonna be
represented by like a single number
number when we hit it with a special
algorithm this single picture of user
activity is is is something we can kind
of maintain in a nice scalable
distributed fashion so it's kind of like
a really lightweight way to sort of hack
a baseline together of internal access
patterns so this is more like east-west
kind of behavior where typically some of
this stuff would be we'd be leveraging
is about kind of Kerberos authentication
Xand and tickets being granted from kind
of Windows resources this this kind of
gives us visibility into those access
patterns where oftentimes in a large
organization like if the traffic isn't
routed through kind of borders or kind
of north north south we would kind of
lose visibility at scale so this was
kind of a way to kind of get around that
see some sort of insights in the land
and then kind of the the modeling of the
vips is sort of a fancy way to say like
we've got to figure out ways to produce
false positives that are that are clever
the the issue we had when we ran this we
this algorithm at like some fortune tens
was that the time to validate like for
an operator to like basically escalate a
ticket around this and say oh we might
have the admin account compromised we
gotta go you know pull all the all the
servers and just kind of you know do the
triage associated with something and you
know like that is specific just to like
the LDAP and Windows
environment and and also kind of the
network-centric behavior in the land it
would take on average the operators in
this large large organizations like 24/7
Sox I think it was 20 hours of working
time to open and close a case around
this this hour so it's you know it has
its drawbacks but if you're able to know
and I think I picked the wrong slide
deck correct I mean there's there's
basically like I missed one picture here
this is like an older version but
there was basically one more picture
that's gonna like what what happens with
the the scoring step for every person's
individual kind of like act set of
access patterns is we hit this with an
algorithm that's called PCA or SVD yeah
all it does is it takes a matrix under
though this is a matrix of counts and
the the x-axis is just sort of the units
of time usually days or weeks and what
we do is we ended up we end up only
scoring matrixes or heat maps of users
that we think have a high risk and this
this lets us kind of target a very small
subset of the population that poses like
a larger risk and also can make make
that doubler alerts manageable like if
you don't kind of do some of this kind
of clever filtering you can run into a
lot of just strange access patterns but
you know like the key idea here is like
after after you're sort of running our
algorithm and you kind of build up a
picture of usually it's weeks of time
and for an average user like I've done
tests on my account when I was at like
EMC and I'd have about maybe 50 rows
each each rows sort of like a like a
like a share or an asset that's being
accessed and so when you kind of look at
like what happened with the people who
were prosecuted because of this so two
admins basically were were fired a
really large financial organization the
day they were fired like or maybe like
the last two days basically like their
heat map history here I had a picture
and I am sorry I think I just screwed
the slides up selamat last minute but
basically we add like one more day of
information and you you see that like
intuitively in the and they're kind of
the coloring of the access patterns it's
just there's a really noticeable
deviation just with the naked eye and
the way we're able to sort of like kind
of hack together an algorithm that that
that sort of targets that intuition is
for every for every every update to this
matrix we rerun something that gives us
a single number it's the principal
eigenvector matrix with a new day of
information we
compute that number again if the two
numbers are different by like a
threshold that we sort of define with
with the the organization itself we have
a we basically have an anomaly and
that's where we sort of kind of go after
the investigation side of things so this
was just sort of like a way to to kind
of build a prototype around this problem
with some interesting like our
architectural constraints mainly the
real time constraint makes us sort of
choose like a real lightweight
representation of users access patterns
and and yeah so I think there's looking
we're out of time right okay
the way I have Q&A or that's it without
any questions from the crowd because
there are none online well you guys have
two more minutes if you want to tell us
some more cool stuff about your
algorithm I'm a little confused which
matrix do you think the SVD
decomposition for is it for the times
here that this matrix yep so on each one
of these sort of like bins with which we
sort of bucket time over could be like
this could be an hour just some
resolution we choose like for the real
sort of production environment we have
maybe 40 50 days of individual data and
then we build this graph which is a
single matrix each one of the like like
row column rows is basically just an
account or normalized count and then
when we get a new day of data or we have
enough information to update this matrix
we build another one wait and we compete
you would compute SVD on both of those
the one that was from like the day
before and then the one that's current
and and then we just take the like the
first eigen value from the result of
that computation to give us serve an
approximate number that the serve
represents the current state and the
latest column
could the fact that there's a big
anomaly yeah exactly that's the key
intuition yeah well thank you guys it's
been a pleasure great job