good afternoon everyone we're ready for
the next session from Tyler Patterson on
the secure metamorphoses streaming logs
with kappa and TLS welcome all right
thank you we give this work in alright
today we're gonna talk a little bit
about Kafka the few things I'm gonna run
through are gonna be just a quick
introduction of myself the data that we
deal with what Kafka is and what the
security considerations are for Kafka
how to secure Kafka and then some of the
lessons that we've learned as we've been
doing that at our organization they
asked me to do this as a reminder there
is a slide oh and then that's the the
tag for the room if you want to have
questions and we can we can review those
at the end so I'm I work for distill
networks we protect against automated
threats I'm a product manager there I'm
responsible for our research and our
data so we have a lot of data that flows
through we sit as a layer 7 inline bot
mitigation and some of the things that
we protect against are people that might
be doing account fraud web scraping
trying to do card card cracking or any
other type of abuse you would use an
automated automated piece of software to
do because of that we have a ton of data
that we collect we use the data for
monitoring our systems for visualizing
the data for doing detection and then
also use that to provide professional
services to help consult with our
customers so some of the pieces of data
that we have are we have web mobile API
protection we do browser interrogation
we have a Mobile SDK and all of that
data flows in to us and then we
consolidate that and use it for those
various purposes we take in about five
billion messages per day and it's just
growing rapidly
so our messages are typically in some
sort of structured format like a
protobuf or JSON
but we have them coming in in various
various formats depending on different
parts of the system so these are an
example of some of our producers there
are different ways that you can
integrate with this still we have a
global CDN you can have your own virtual
private cloud you can have a dedicated
device and your infrastructure you can
take our connector and install it into
your application and then in addition to
those those are constantly reporting
telemetry access logs there also we also
have the browsers where we have
JavaScript that goes to fingerprint the
devices so that we can track them all of
that data comes back to us and includes
information about the browser it
includes biometric data that we're
gathering to determine if you're a human
or not and then of the same thing and
coming from a mobile sdk we've got the
same sort of telemetry data so all those
things produce logs and there are a lot
of different things we want to use those
logs for I've mentioned a few of them
monitoring we enrich the logs with
additional information to make the
analysis more complete we use it to do
machine learning and detection it
eventually all ends up in our data
warehouse and then that can be used for
reporting and our portal for dashboards
and then also for our analyst to you to
use now if everything wants to get all
of the logs without something like cough
can place a a messaging broker
everything would have to be aware of
where the logs were and try to gather
them and it gets pretty unwieldly and
messy and that's where Kafka comes in so
how many people just for a sense how
many people here are familiar with Kaka
Kafka or used Kafka alright cool
all right so not this Kafka the author
instead it's caca the pub/sub message
broker so in Kafka some of the basics
about Kafka is there's two different
types of clients you have producers
they're the ones that are publishing
logs and then you have consumers they're
the ones that are consuming logs then
they typically what they're the logs
that are sent or considered messages
those messages can be sent as individual
messages or also sent in batch so you
can reduce how often you're calling out
to the the broker the message a message
schema that can be varied
can be whatever you want that you put
into there you can have no schema if you
want I guess
and the Kafka's or Copco organization is
organized by topics so you publish to a
specific topic you can also subscribe to
a specific topic and consume those logs
once they end up in a topic the data is
broken out into partitions Kafka uses
sequential writes to disks they get high
performance those partitions are spread
across multiple brokers and then every
but and then the consumers can go in a
consumer group and consume from each of
those partitions and we'll take a look
at just real briefly what that looks
like
they then use an offset so you know
we're in the log stream you're consuming
and that way you have some feel over
redundancy if you need to go back and
reconsider Group has their own offset so
they know where they are in the stream
of data so this is sort of what it looks
like on the left you have the producers
on the right you have the consumers they
publish in they'll go to a leader broker
for each topic that leader broker how it
can replicate the data so that you know
one broker dies that data persist and
then the consumers consume from the the
lead partition on that for the for that
topic this is an idea of just what the
partitions look like clogs are just
being sequentially written at the end
and then you just know where you are and
consuming those logs all right so with
coffee you have Kafka itself with the
new all set and the brokers within that
you also have zookeeper zookeeper is
used to help orchestrate the work that
the brokers are doing so zookeeper is
just a distributed open source
coordination service and this helps you
make sure that you're coordinating
services across each of the brokers it
also a man is a couple of other things
that we'll talk about like access
control lists and and some of that so
with Kafka in place instead it can look
a little bit cleaner like this you have
one Kafka service obviously with
multiple topics
you know it might be a little bit
messier than that we might have you're
not gonna have just one topic
everything's gonna push to otherwise
your
have to spend a lot of time parsing
those logs figuring out which of them
you need to consume and throw away so
you can segment them so that you're only
consuming each service is only consuming
the logs that are important to them so
today we're going to talk a little bit
about securing Kafka some of the reasons
you might want to do it is just for good
security hygiene you might have some
requirements around compliance for PCI
GD P R people pH I like HIPAA and then
you also want to just avoid any problems
you might have if you just let anybody
publish you could have abuse and and
contaminated data so there are several
things you need to consider when you're
using Kafka the first is that you're
encrypting the data in transport so that
is data that's coming from a producer
into the brokers or out of the brokers
to the consumers and then also from
server to server as well this you also
have authentication so you want to make
sure that you're authenticating the
clients that are communicating with you
so a client in this case I'm gonna use
the word client and when I say client I
mean either the producer or consumer
consumer authentication again just make
sure that you're communicating with who
you intended
you also have encryption at rest and
this is to ensure the data is protected
while it's being stored on disk and then
you have authorizations so you might
have encrypted communication you might
know who you're working with but you
want to limit them to certain privileges
within the service so out of the box
just within each of these so transport
encryption all messages out of the box
are send in plain text by default
authentication there's no authentication
required by default encryption arrest
there's no special accommodations made
for Kafka with within Kafka for it we'll
talk about what options there could be
and then for authorization again open by
default so let's take a look at some of
these the first thing we're going to
look at is the khakha defaults just to
take a look at what that looks like
so in here the only thing that I've
changed is instead of listening on on
any address I've changed to just listen
to my my Kafka service this is just a
single ec2 instance there's there's
you can see that I'm listening on
plaintexts on port here is 1992 and then
zookeeper is on port 21 81 we'll talk a
little bit about securing zookeeper and
the challenges there again there's no
default authorization or authentication
so that means that anybody could create
or delete a topic so what that would
look like is here I have a sample Kafka
client that I've connected to my Kafka
service I've just asked it to create a
topic there's no authentication going on
here and once I've done that I get a
created topic and everything's happy
again this is just what it looks like
out of the box and any client can
connect and then a client can produce
messages and anybody can consume
messages so up here on the top this is
my producer I'm gonna connect I get the
little shout I get my Chevron I can type
in if I get another Chevron that can
confirms my message was was published
and we can see that being consumed on
below for my consumer again they're in
transport that means that we can see
everything that's being sent that means
it's prone to sniffing and tampering and
other PII can be exposed so here I have
again let's say I'm sending a you know
social security numbers across the wire
using my publisher if we send those then
I can just you know I'm just listening
on anything that's going to my Kafka
server and I can see in the bottom right
my social security number I'm showing up
that is not my actual social security
number so Kafka transport encryption so
Kafka just has normal transport
encryption and through TLS you can set
it up as either one way meaning that the
clients only need to encrypt what
they're sending to the brokers or you
can set it up as mutual TLS it supports
TLS 1.0 1.1 and 1.2 what this looks like
is a quick TLS overview is on the left I
have a caucus server on the right I have
a copy of client the caucus server is
going to have a key
door and a trust store in the coffee
client in this example is only going to
really need the trust or the Kafka's
server will have a signed certificate
from our certificate authority or your
certificate authority the Kafka client
will have the public certificate and
then in the when the copy of client
wants to initiate communication they'll
get back the signed certificate they'll
validate it and then they'll initiate
secured communication this is an overly
simplified version of TLS and so let's
take a look at that what you need to do
to set cock-up to have this one-way
encrypted communication first you need
to identify your CA so hopefully we have
something to have a CA at your
organization or you can you know create
your own CA and I'm gonna do that in
this in my examples here you'll generate
a key store on the server you'll
generate a java key a java key store
you'll generate a new key you'll
generate a server request get that
signed server cert from your CA and then
install that server cert into your key
store install the public CA assert into
your key store and then job generate a
Java trust trust store and put the
public CA shirt into that trust or as
well then you'll need to go into Kafka
and configure the server properties and
then you'll need to ensure that the new
the ssl port that you've configured is
open and then you can go ahead and
restart your server so let's go through
those steps really quickly I'm gonna
blast through these because this is all
normal just like CA cert stuff but just
for an idea Here I am generating a new
key store within that key store I'm also
going to just look at what I have in
there after I generate a new key I can
see that I have a key for my my don't my
host caca de taille Lee Paxton comm and
then I'm gonna go ahead and import the
root certificate from the from my public
CA and then I'm going to request a sign
certificate using that public
certificate in my
my key that's in my key store so now I
have a certificate request I'm going to
send that over to my CA if you're paying
attention this same server also has my
cert of my CA cert and key on it so it's
pretty easy for me to do normally you
would you know send this over to whoever
it is that's responsible for the your CA
in your organization so I generate that
and now I can verify my sign cert I have
a signed cert for my host from my CA and
I'm gonna go ahead and import that into
my key store so now in my key store I
have my key I have a sign sign key and
the the cert from the public CA so again
that's all pretty pretty straightforward
if you worked with any sort of
encryption in the past and then the next
thing that we need to do is open up our
server properties file so in the server
properties file again I just initially
was set up to listen on port 90 92 and
I'm going to configure it to listen on
port 1993 I'm gonna still listen on port
1992 as well you can have both in place
obviously that's not you know if any
it's not going to be secure but I'm
gonna use that just as I walk through my
examples you could eventually remove
that or if you want to not have inter
broker secure communication you would
need to continue listening on port 1980
to 1992 as well there's some additional
configuration settings that I have here
that point to where my key store or my
trust or are and have my my passwords
for them the last thing that you can do
this is an optional setting so you don't
have to set this but you can set the
protocols that you allow so ideally you
would limit it to TLS 1.2 you could do
1.1 optionally as well hopefully not 1.0
as it's no longer considered secure the
next step is to open up the your port so
I'm going to open up my port for SSL so
I can allow secure communication and
accept income ends and accept incoming
requests on that port so now that I have
my server set up the next thing that I'm
going to do is set up my client on my
client I want to go through and I just
need to generate a trust store here so
only a trust door in this first step
unless I'm doing mutual TLS and we'll
get to that
I'm going to import the see a public
cert into that trust door what that
allows me to do is confirm that the sign
cert was signed by I my trusted CA and
keep that chain of trust now neck the
next thing that I want to do is set up
the client properties and then change my
connection information to include those
client properties in them so again
creating a trust or using key tool I
have a now I imported the see a public
certificate into my trust store and then
I'm gonna go into my client properties
and I'm going to set the security
protocol to be SSL and point to my trust
store and give it my password so now
that's all set up I'm gonna save that
into a file called client properties and
in my connection information I'm gonna
create a topic and you'll know that when
I'm creating my topic I'm pointing to
not the I'm I am pointing to sorry I
went once led to many there we go right
there so when I'm creating my topic I am
pointing to the zookeeper port so
zookeeper is responsible for creating
the topic so even though I've been
forced as a cell I've set that in my
client properties I can still create
topics at will but if I want to connect
to as a producer and want to produce on
my new topic called Kafka secure I will
I need to pass in the parameter for my
client properties file and now I'm able
to successfully produce messages to my
Kopke broker so let's take a look at
what that looks like here I have the
khakha broker with the client properties
passed in my consumer does not have it
and it is still listening on port 1992
so in this example I have both in place
I'm publishing
I'm encrypting messages as I publish
them but when I consume them they're not
being encrypted on the way out so still
not quite what we want so I'm going to
update my consumer connection to have
the same properties let me use the same
properties file and in this case my
consumer my producer are both on the
same box so I'm just using the same good
properties file I'm gonna update my
connection and now that I'm connecting
over both on port 1993 on both of them
I'm able to both encrypt as I publish
and encrypt as I consume all right let's
take a look at the next thing Kafka
authentication so within Kafka
authentication this is going to
authenticate the clients that we are
communicating with we trust so we
already have the see a public
certificate in our trust store so now we
just need to get a signed certificate to
the clients so once we have the client
sign client certificate that enables us
to have a mutual trust and then we can
have security communication to do that
will configure the Kafka to require off
a Kafka server properties to require
authentication when connected over when
we're using SSL there are a bunch of
other optional parameters that we have
here so within the client we've already
talked about generating a key store I'm
gonna skip through these pretty quick
and just look at our are here we have
our certificate our signed certificate
we install it into our key store and now
we're going to update our client
properties to include the key store in
the client properties so now I've
actually changed this is this is SSL off
property so I'm gonna start using that
in my connection and I'm gonna use that
in my connection as well for my consumer
again still communicating over my secure
SSL port so in this example example now
I'm I have mutual TLS I I know as a as a
client that I'm communicating with the
server that I want to and I know as a
server I'm communicating with clients
that I want to so what are some of the
lessons that we lack we've learned here
a couple of things that we found is that
or that job is very slow and especially
in 1.8 so we get we got significant
increases in performance by going to
Java 1.9 and zookeeper as I mentioned
doesn't support TLS so
to enable secure communication between
them easy they're gonna take a lot of
effort or you'll want to take other
measures to help secure a zookeeper and
then the other another thing that we
learned was that we wanted to confirm
the cipher suite compatibility with the
different client libraries that we're
using our producers actually have a go
Kafka library called sarama and only
supported a certain subset of cipher
suites and so we just needed to go
through and ensure that we were using
one of those that was compatible other
things we learned is that it's this is
just really tricky to automate I'm doing
it on one broker and just one consumer
when publisher you get a lot of keys
you're going to want to have some sort
of PK PK management and the other issue
that you have is if you issue these
certificates there's no easy way to
revoke them there's nothing in Kafka to
ensures that so to ensure to do that
there is there are a couple of options
that you can that are outside of Kafka
that you can pursue to support of the to
use the native Java certificate
revocation list by jumping into
authorization so authorization is the
next level this is when we want to do
additional authentication of individual
users and then we want to manage what
those users have access to ideally
you're doing authentic authorization
between all your brokers from your
brokers to your zookeeper and from your
clients to your cluster as well
authentication comes in a few flavors
there's plain this is just a simple
username password
there's the salted challenge response
and authentication mechanism which is
again username and passwords with a
challenge or assault and then there's
Kerberos which is a ticket based
authentication and it would be the
recommended option to pursue Kerberos is
obtained and so it's going to be painful
hopefully you already have Kerberos
setup and you can leverage that and you
have an expert somewhere that you can
rely on today I'm going to walk through
just doing plain
authorization so you can see what that
looks like for that we're gonna have to
update our listeners we're gonna have to
enable Sasol and then choose the broker
protocol and then configure the Java
authentication authorization service and
then add users to that and on the client
we're just going to need to change the
client properties to include the the
username and password so what that looks
like is in where before I had plain text
and SSL I've changed SSL to be sasso
underscore SSL and then I have a couple
of additional server properties here
telling it which type of
Sasol to use and I'm also telling it to
use
Sasol authorization between brokers and
we're not gonna be able to see that
today because again this is a single
single broker cluster so you can add the
Jazz config to your server properties or
you can you can have an external file
and point to that we've had some issues
just pointing to an external file and
found that it was a little bit less
troublesome to put directly into the
server properties if you wanted to do
that this is what the the the Jazz
configuration would look like so in the
server file I'm just gonna add the
listener I'm gonna put a listener SATA
config on the listener name that I want
it to be on and then the other nice
thing is if you use the external Jaz
file you can include that in Kafka ops
which is an option that runs all the
time and just starts out blank when
you're starting your khakha brokers so
this is what I've created a user I've
called it Kafka client giving it a
password now I have a password and I'm
gonna include that in my client
properties so and I've told it also to
use Sasol in the client properties so I
also created a bad password and I'm
gonna go ahead and test that out so
first I'm gonna try it with the wrong
password properties file and we can see
that I get an error saying I have an
invalid user name or password so
before when I had that's one of the nice
things about using the authorization as
you get a little bit better messaging
around if you're not able to
successfully connect when I don't know
if I can't remember if I had an example
but if you were using just encrypted TLS
and you connect and you try to produce
you know you don't get any message back
telling you that it didn't produce or
why all you get is just you know that it
didn't produce it doesn't it doesn't
produce so this is a little bit better
for troubleshooting now I'm gonna change
it to the correct properties and here
I'm gonna go in let me hit play manually
so now I'm gonna go ahead and connect
and in this case now I am
I'm authenticated using my username and
password and the messages will publish
so now I have authenticated messages the
only thing here is now my publishers and
consumers can read on everything
everything is open open to the world so
now I want to go in and add some access
control lists to do that Kafka ships
with a pluggable authorizer the Ackles
are stored in zookeeper typical
operations read/write create the
resources include the topic the cluster
and then a consumer group and here's
some examples of those I'm gonna jump
through a little bit to do a
configuration you're gonna edit your
server properties you're gonna add the
authorizer add super users which is an
important step it's really easy with zoo
P zookeeper Akal management - it doesn't
depend it's gonna overwrite so it's
really easy to wipe out the the
authorization that you've set up and
then we're gonna add some ackles and
edit the client properties so here I'm
adding the authorizer
I'm setting up a super user and I'm
gonna go ahead and try to connect we see
here that I was unable to connect
because I have no allies access now to
kafka secure so because I've setup
enable or I've added the user I'm
connecting with the user I get them and
I have
added any Ackles I'm not able to do
anything so same thing on the client I'm
not able to access the topic so I'm
gonna go ahead and I'm going to first
create a user a wildcard user there are
no groups in these Ackles so you can
either do wildcards or specific named
users and then I'm gonna set that up to
be able to any user to be able to read
from my Kafka secure topic we see that
that takes and now I'm my consumer it's
you can't tell here but I've started my
consumer it's consuming I don't get an
error message but my producer does get
an error message that it can't access
the topic to produce to it so now I'm
gonna go add for Kafka client my user
that I set up in my properties I'm gonna
add the operation right I'm gonna make
sure that that takes and then now I I
can see that I have secure messages that
are authenticated authorized
appropriately so some of the lessons
that we learned here again Kerberos is a
pain I can't say it enough Akal changes
I talked about those being overwritten
making sure to set up a you super user
there's also if you do end up using
doing a coal management using sass a
plane or sessile scram you would there
is a tool that helps manage the the
those ackles and has also appropriate
auditing in place for that so that'll be
useful another thing to consider is that
Kafka is responsible for the ackles that
has some metadata in there so you want
to separate out zookeeper and limit
access to it and then for encryption at
risk really the best option is just to
increase encrypt your filesystem and
we're using if you're doing it in AWS
you can use encrypted EBS volumes or in
HDFS you can encrypt there a couple of
resources there's all the documentation
it's dry as you'd expect but really
thorough and helpful and if you're doing
an ad above us there is a best practices
for that there's also a couple of things
that I recommend one is the the O'Reilly
Kafka book and then there's
there's a course by Stefan and GERD I'm
not gonna attend their last names but
this is a they have a Kafka security
series it's $15 super thorough helps you
go get through setting up a basic set up
so I think I'm out of time I don't have
any time for any questions right now so
I apologize but if you want to find me
I'm happy to jump in and answer any
specific questions that you have thanks
everybody Thank You Tyler
there was one question what is the
relationship with Kafka and gdpr so
maybe you know that's something that you
can oh sure yeah so just for gdpr
you need to keep track of PII and you
need to ensure that it's that it's
secured so for us it's just ensuring
that our data is encrypted in transport
on behalf of besides we thank you for
your presentation thank you appreciate
it thank you everybody