Hello everyone. My name is Adam Ruddermann, I came to talk about
how to use Bug Bounty to get a job in Silicon Valley.
So let's start.
Nice to meet you, call me rudd. My name is Adam Ruddermann, but there are millions of Adams in the world. I was
of the United States Army, so I do not call my first name a long time ago.
A little about me and why I'm here. I started
in the United States Air Force. I was technical leader in the Red Team of the NSA (National Security Agency).
Basically, we could attack everything in the .mil domain, it was a lot of fun.
I worked on the Joint Task Force - Global Network Operations (JTF-GNO)
who became the US Cyber ​​Command. So I helped set up the cyber-commando network defense.
After that I worked at Booz Allen Hamilton
in several contracts for the US Government making strategic cyberoperations
and operations management consulting.
I did not leave the government. I talked to a friend who was one of the founders of Synack, one of the three big Bug Bounty startups I'll tell you about later.
I asked for resume tips because I wanted to leave the government, and he offered me a job. So I was one of the employees there.
I had a child. And I went to Facebook. Much of my time on Facebook was not for Bug Bounty, though I was hired for it.
Most of my time was for data protection of users. Was not...
very popular at the time, but it's a big deal now.
The NCCGroup invited me to stay ahead of the Bug Bounty services for one of the
original providers of Bug Bounty services in the industry. We stayed there
providing team expansion and strategic support for some Bug Bounty programs many years ago.
So, a little about me.
So before we go into details about exactly
how to use Bug Bounty. What is Bug Bounty?
Basically what happens is: you can use any word you want,
some companies call security researcher, some white hats, some hackers,
Those who wear suits and pay bills call them "damn children and millenials"
They encounter vulnerabilities in organizations, by accident or on purpose,
and then spread the vulnerability to the organization.
Ideally responsibly, it gives you the opportunity to fix the bug.
The goal is not just to find bugs, it is to fix them to make things better.
And then the organization might give a reward.
On a high level this is it, but there are many details about it.
What's up?
So why do we care about it, and why is it relevant to you?
These are just examples. You know most of these logos.
All these organizations have some Bug Bounty program.
Many people make lots of money from it. I was driving
the Facebook Bug Bounty program, and was happy to pay, often ...
A million dollars a year while I was there, and
Google, well ... Facebook paid 5 or 6 million dollars,
Google paid a lot of money, Uber already paid a little more than 1.5 million dollars,
the US Department of Defense, for "Hack the Pentagon"
already paid enough money, I think about 500 thousand dollars.
So there are many opportunities, and these are just a few logos. So just so you know.
But let's be tactical. How does this look?
These are the pages of Uber and Twitter's Bug Bounty programs.
It's all there. You can literally go there,
see which parts of the project you can attack, and in what ways, and then
click "Submit a Report". That's it. And you are submitting a vulnerability
for Uber or Twitter. And it's incredible. The security field was very successful in this.
Uber has published what they call the "Treasure Map"
which gave an insight into how your product works,
to allow researchers, people they do not know, to find vulnerabilities in their products.
A report is like this. Again, make things tangible
This is cool. The cool part of Bug Bounty is that ... Snapchat is on the HackerOne platform
and this bug is public. I did not need special access to find him. Has the bug been fixed?
They just closed the bug for other people to see.
This is a phenomenal way to improve security in the world as it promotes transparency.
And Bug Bounty is fast. Look at this.
7 hours. This is crazy.
If you're doing intrusion testing - that's the main activity of NCC, and I support this
and invasion tests take place in this area -
but the reality is that Bug Bounty is phenomenal to narrow the gap between intrusion tests.
And you can make good money from it. Without complaining, there are 15 thousand.
It's incredible.
When I was on Facebook, I paid $ 10,000 to a 10-year-old for finding an incredible bug.
You could delete a comment
of a user in another user's Instagram. So imagine Taylor Swift
commenting on a post on Connie's Instagram and out of nothing the comment disappears.
Not good. 10 year old child found?
He won $ 10,000. He met the Prime Minister of Finland. This child goes far.
Abuse of user data is something important on Facebook now. This is something I like. But this is incredible.
HackerOne is probably the biggest platform today.
In the first 3 or 4 years they paid 20 million dollars for bugs
and in the next 4 years they plan to pay another 80 million.
That's 80 million dollars available for people to pick up.
Literally, they are paying $ 80 million. Go get it.
Okay, I hope you're interested now. There is money on the table,
no one to stop them. It's all about you, what is it?
Incredible and I love it. So how do I get started? I'm waiting for the translator to follow.
Let's start simply. I'll assume you know very little, which is OK.
There are several sandboxes for you to start learning web security. We have Google Gruyere, it's
a Swiss cheese because it has holes in it, so it is vulnerable.
And there are also the iOS and Web Vulnerable Applications, which are great products for you
practice on your time and learn how to hack Web applications and iOS.
I mentioned platforms; then Bug Bounty works like this:
the company says "I want a Bug Bounty program". If it's not Facebook, Google or Microsoft,
and without a considerable engineering support,
they go to one of these platforms to host their
pages of the program, with rules and scopes,
and is a communication platform to submit your bugs
and have a safe and consistent conversation
and also have recognition, something about which we will speak later.
In fact, I have no opinion on which is the best. I worked for Synack, which does not host public programs
Cobalt makes invasion tests,
Bugcrowd and HackerOne make public programs. We'll talk about this later.
But it's all about money. If you are not in this for money,
Of course, it's great to build a reputation and increase your skills,
the important thing is: leverage Bug Bounty to make it a career. That is
what I want to talk about. Some people do it only sometimes, and that's great.
But you can make money. With the right incentives, you can do the right things and go after what gives the greatest return.
So how to start? Focus on programs that pay rewards.
You may think that going after those who do not pay rewards is easier because fewer people go after them. It is true...
But these programs may not be good, may have limited scopes,
and they may also be slow to respond, because they have not invested so much in this.
And you should make money because it will be sustainable for you. If you want a job in the security area and are using Bug Bounty
to enrich your CV, you should make money so that you do not fall behind and have to find something else to do.
One exception: government programs do not pay, as they have a unique situation,
Government programs are very impressive, and look great in your CV.
Another thing to focus on:
there are thousands of bugs out there. You will see several incredible vulnerabilities that have been found and everyone talks about them on Twitter, people talking about Black Hats,
Start simple. Focus on OWASP Top 10. If you do not know what it is, literally go Google and look for OWASP.
So focus on mobile and web applications first. The reason is that, technically,
and many bugs look similar.
A CSRF bug often looks like another CSRF bug.
So it's easy for you to find, make money and increase your skills
and learn to find certain classes of bugs over various products and technology stacks.
Another great trick - this is the next topic I'm going to talk about - it's
Some of the biggest hackers post at all times and talk about their findings after they've fixed it.
So if you do not know what kind of bugs to look for, if you do not know what Cross-Site Scripting or SQL Injection is,
but there is more to it. These guys talk about what they find, and sometimes they're complex, and pretty cool.
So, look them up on Google, and seeing your tweets is a good way to learn what types of bugs you could look for.
So if you pay attention and really try,
and if you're really taking it seriously,
some things will happen.
First, you will quickly notice what you do not know, which is great. You need a little insight.
You'll also notice which types of bugs matter to businesses and which ones do not.
The reality is that when you are new to the area of ​​security,
everything seems important and serious.
And this is ... true.
If you have ever used a web scanner, they are notorious for this - web scanners are
give hundreds and hundreds of vulnerabilities to companies. Most of them are theoretical.
If you are trying, you will notice fast what you do not know.
This includes finding your own bugs, but also
try to find the same kinds of bugs that more experienced researchers have found.
And, if you're really trying, you should take it seriously because it's a job.
Follow it. If you find something you do not understand, write it down. I personally use Excel spreadsheets,
so I can prioritize this list. Sometimes
there are things like "What do I learn next?" And I simply
I see something I do not understand and I go back. This has worked well for me professionally.
And just challenge yourself.
In Bug Bounty, it's easy to just find CSRF bugs, only finding Cross-Site Scripting bugs.
Challenge yourself, especially if you want to make a career.
You will get good money only by encountering the same bugs because there are hundreds of programs out there.
But if you want a job, you need to be more balanced.
Companies look for more than that, and you need to challenge yourself.
Let's say you will do this for a while. Give yourself 6 months.
You are finding bugs consistently, doing a good job,
and wants to challenge himself more.
To do this - what happens when you have a good reputation on BugCrowd or HackerOne.
What happens when you have a good reputation
is that you are invited to private programs.
And there are far more private than public programs.
There are better payouts,
and private programs often have larger scopes and more interesting targets.
And there are more advanced private than public programs. The symbol on the left is the Facebook Bug Bounty program.
This is Google's Bounty Bug program. They call it Google VRP.
And there's Microsoft, Uber and others that are great advanced programs to learn.
This is the example of Frans Rosen, a Swedish friend of mine. That's his reputation, that's what I'm talking about.
He is one of the best known researchers.
This guy makes a lot of money finding bugs, and he travels the world now
such as a Bug Bounty Hacker. You will find it on Instagram, it goes to incredible places.
The benefit of challenging yourself is that there is gamification on these platforms. That is
of gamification, you get insignias and such. It's crazy.
You can do a lot to build your reputation and prove yourself publicly.
with Bug Bounty. And catch the attention of companies, companies in San Francisco.
Then you advance in these programs, you succeed in them.
What happens? You need to dig deeper.
You need to dig deeper and prove that you know their technological heap.
What a company looks for when hiring a Product Safety Engineer, which is in fact
which I am suggesting, the career of Product Safety Engineer.
They do not want you to know all about their technological heap on the first day. This is unnecessary, not expected.
They want to see that you can adapt. And this is an example of Facebook,
Facebook lives on the Graph API. All you do is with the Graph API, and it's a unique API.
And this is a screenshot of their site, you can mess with it now.
And there are researchers out there who know the Graph API better than Facebook.
And they handle a lot.
They do a good job finding bugs, and they make lots of money. They find the most complex bugs.
And this is a simple example, from which I can show a screenshot.
But the reality is that there are many such examples, in which you can demonstrate deepening.
and experience without the help of anyone. Just go there and do it.
Another person I told you about, this is Philippe.
One of the best hackers that Facebook has. He focuses on this program, especially.
He makes a lot of money, he knows more about some products than the engineers.
Honestly. He knows the APIs, submits the bugs and asks questions.
And he's very transparent about what he does, and he helps the community. Post videos of everything you do and teach you how to find bugs.
Cool, you can find bugs and you're very good at it. But can you fix them?
The problem of finding bugs is reactivity, and companies want to be proactive. They want to prevent bugs.
And while some companies have internal teams for intrusion testing,
what happens is something like "This person is a great pentester"
but to hire her, she can also fix bugs.
Well, knowing how to fix bugs means you can work with engineering teams and help them improve.
and help them make software safer.
and work with them without judging them, and this is critical. Let's talk about this soon.
And also, if you can write code, you will get paid better, which is way better than being a pentester.
Again, let's assume you know very little about this. What to do?
Let's say you do not know anything about software engineering. Crawl. Reinvent the wheel. If you do this often,
you'll use tools, some with open source, easy to find.
Automate something that is already automated, just for you
try and see how other people did. It's a great opportunity to learn, there are several quick tools.
Inevitably, if you do it seriously, you will find a process of your own,
which is manual and you can automate.
This is difficult in the beginning, especially if there is no model to copy,
but it's a great way to stay in the middle, and you can post something.
if you can leave it tidy. And it's a way to make your name.
And if you want to run - this is extreme, hardcore nightmare level, okay? I...
few can do this, but it is the maximum level,
Google has Patch Rewards. There are several pieces of code
open for which Google pays Bug Bounty rewards
if you submit and have your submission submitted.
Now you must trim your edges. Nice.
You find and fix bugs.
But that does not mean being a good employee. You can communicate, you can help people, you can
to set up a security program? Then you need to trim the edges.
Write bug reports in detail.
Detail how you found them, the impacts. It's very important.
Show that you can help others, do trainings 1 to 1. You have a friend who
works in a medical laboratory and wants to make more money, and wants to go in for safety.
Help him out. Challenge yourself.
And give lectures. There are several examples of how to give lectures, and
in Brazil, I have a friend from Sao Paulo who gave me a huge list
of Hacker Clubs around the city, are everywhere
of Brazil. These are places where you can learn
and help others, and continue to challenge and grow as a speaker.
Important, and we will have an adult conversation about it.
You need to be professional, okay?
For even if you do not work for this company,
does not mean you have the right
to be rude or mean. This is not how the world works,
especially if you want a job. If you do not want to, you can even do this, but there are consequences as well.
Look this. We're having fun, I'm using
shirt, wearing my old sneakers because they said it was going to rain,
It's all right, right? But the reality is that
the people on the other side of submission are dealing with so much more than you.
I have some screenshots of a lecture I gave, for new clients,
to manage your levels during presentations.
That's what they deal with every day. Deal with
lawyers, executives, public relations,
if they are meeting Service Level Agreements with other companies,
and what charges occur if they do not reach SLAs.
Partnerships with engineering, all sorts of things. They are busy.
And they do not have time for bullshit. They have time for professionals who want to help them be successful.
Look from a legal perspective. This is a nightmare.
It's not fun at all.
So,
On the other side of submission are people like that. But those are your contacts, your mentors.
They are people who will recommend you and will be your contractors.
It's who's there So even if you do not want to join Facebook, Google or something,
they know each other. Some time ago they were 10 minutes by car from each other, it was funny.
The reality is they need to like you.
They do not need to like you as a person, but they need to like you as a professional.
Super important.
For behind them there are people who look like this.
And these people do not have time for drama. They want professionals. They are willing to pay money,
they want to pay him the righteous. But they do not have time for bullshit, let's face it.
A key aspect of communicating with these teams
is to understand the real impact of their bugs.
CVSS is not a good indicator of impact. So, it is valid on some points, but for most security issues it is not.
Be realistic. Cool, you've encountered a "Reflected Cross-site scripting"
OK.
So often it's no big deal. Sometimes it is, sometimes it is not.
It depends on the company.
The important thing, what companies want to see in a person
with a good history of Bug Bounty, is that you understand the
context and impact of the bug to them.
An important bug for one company is not for another, and that's the reality. And there are good reasons for that.
Understand priorities. There is a lot going on, and priorities change at any time.
A good example: a screenshot of all the unique Bug Bounty programs that Microsoft is hosting right now.
There are start and end dates for Microsoft Bug Bounty programs.
And if you stay out of those end dates ...
I'm sorry.
The reason is that it is a massive engineering company. Need to keep an eye on Bug Bounty and resources
needed to fix the bugs. Bug Bounty programs exist to find bugs and fix them,
do not collect them and keep looking.
Then they will sometimes get Bug Bounties if they know they will be able to fix them.
As I said before: treat as a job,
follow the rules. Programs have rules for a reason,
follow them. You do not help anyone by disobeying these rules.
They are not trying to limit you,
are dealing with barriers. Usually legal barriers,
Communicate professionally. Imagine you're talking to your boss. Talk in a professional way.
And listen to your audience. She gives feedback. "We think it has no impact because of it," "We think it's not valid because of that."
Is everything alright there? OK]
Listen to them and receive feedback. They are not trying to fool you or be hard-boiled.
And this creates mutual trust and respect.
and helps you create local and global relationships.
The person with whom I spoke to redo the Facebook Bug Bounty program is Brazilian.
That's why I'm here, she introduced me to the people here.
So, this community is great, but you need to calm down and understand what's important.
That this happens if you do not understand. This is a submission to Uber's Bug Bounty program. Famous on the internet.
He was out of scope, out of the rules. The report was not valid because it was out of scope.
"This domain is not valid for Bug Bounty submissions". Very straightforward. It's on their page.
He did not like it, and he decided, well ...
call all Uber "**** kids and taxi drivers".
And last and very important: you need to speak English.
I know it sucks a lot of people,
I'll be honest: I'm lazy, I only speak English.
Sorry ... but many people on the other side of this
speak English. I do not want you to say that even Obama, a great American speaker,
I do not care if you speak like the queen.
I do not mind you talking like this guy. You just have to be clear.
And professional. And do not talk like this guy.
Because, really. This is what you saw
This happens when you behave like this.
That happened to this guy. He was banned from the Uber program and suffered additional penalties from HackerOne.
I hope it was worth it for disrespecting Uber's guys.
For he is gone.
This is the reality.
So briefly.
One more thing came from my friend Reginaldo.
Maybe Silicon Valley is not for you. He loves Brazil.
Sometimes he says, "I want to go home," because he lives in San Francisco now.
He had the biggest pay for Facebook at the time. He was offered a job, and he accepted.
And that's straight from him.
A quote I took from him yesterday.
"Working in Silicon Valley is great, but it may not be your goal."
"Make Bug Bounty and be paid in dollars living in Brazil
"It's really cool, and it's not that hard to do."
With that, I want to thank you for your time.
Focus on impact, not what looks cool. Focus on impact
and we will help the internet to be a safer place.
Thank you.