[Music]
[Applause]
we'll start off the second day of Balcon
I'd like to welcome Albert he will lead
us into the depths of Android and how to
liberate it so good morning I hope
everybody is awake it's this time of the
day that can be a bit of a challenge so
it's probably a bit fast so what what
what is all it about what is it all
about I mean you have an Android phone
and well it kind of works the way they
deliver it to you but it might contain a
lot of software you don't want to run
and it might insist on putting your data
in some clout or well some other places
you don't want it to or also if you have
all the hardware some vendors stopped
supporting their devices quite early and
you don't get any security updates which
is also not nice to have so I forgot to
change the date of the presentation and
the location yeah no but so yeah that's
the reason why you might want to install
an alternative operating system there is
of course also the reason that like
myself I prefer to mostly run free
software it's not that easy to only run
free software on your mobile phone
because the drivers are usually with a
lot of binary blobs in there as well as
the actual modem in there as well but
you can get the situation gets quite a
bit better so
what is free software actually free
software is about well user freedom
it's not about three years and free beer
well it might be but so the the four
freedoms you have is use study share
improve so to use for any purpose
because the software should not the
license should not say like I've seen
that with with Android roms for example
well you're free to use it but only for
non-commercial use for example that's
annoying the other thing is of we
obviously you should be allowed to study
the software you running to find out if
it does what it should do and if it has
any problems or how to do things
also you should be able to share
whatever you found because there should
not be an NDA that says well it's nice
that you have looked at our software and
found all the security bugs but you're
not allowed to talk to anybody about it
and obviously also after you're done all
the work you should also be allowed to
actually improve software yeah so I mean
for the basic stuff it provides you with
it allows you to actually look at the
software it's investigate audit the
software without any restrictions and as
I said before there is no NDA so yes you
can publish your findings it might still
be nice to talk to the offers of the
software first so that you can have some
responsible disclosure sorry but they
cannot force you not to publish yeah so
now for the actual for the actual
part of actually replacing the software
on your mobile phone the first and most
important part of that is actually have
a backup I've listed a few things that
are good to have a backup
it might not completely might not be
complete it depends a bit on what you're
actually doing with your mobile phone
I mean people do different things with
it have different software on there also
if possible please test the backup and
see if it really contains all your data
because once you've all written data
well there is no way back or no
straightforward way at least they're not
the next thing is I mean for most people
replacing the ROM on your Android phone
it's also about freeing it from things
like the Google cloud and and other
stuff so please make sure that you're
able to get your data out there out of
out of that before you deactivate your
access I mean with Google you can
probably access all of it via the web
interface with other cloud-based
applications that might be a problem so
please check beforehand that you can
access all your data or at least only
all the data you want to access anymore
because I mean if you have any data to
say well I don't care anymore
that's fine but you should not find out
by accident and it's not good so well
preparations well apart from having a
backup we already had said that read the
fine manual and I really mean it
read the fine manual completely before
you start because I've seen situations
where people started
the process by while basically starting
while they were reading the manual which
is fine most of the time but it can
happen that you get stuck in the middle
of it
because you found out that you need some
additional information some additional
tool you currently cannot access and
then you're stuck with a non working
phone in the middle of the day which
well if it's just a test device then
it's fine if it's your main mobile phone
your fact also of course depending on
your mobile phone
you might need different software
packages most common one is that I've
used so far is the Android SDK is nearly
always you nearly always need that
depending for example for samsung phones
they have their proprietary have a
proprietary flashing process I've also
seen that with what was it I think some
Lenovo devices also have some
proprietary stuff some of them also use
the more or less standard Google way it
really depends and it's also a thing
that you really have to look at your
exact model it's not like well my
previous device is from this vendor work
this way that might that's true most of
the time but unfortunately not all of
the time so well yeah so there are a few
basic steps that I want to go through
for the whole flashing process the one
thing is usually first you have to
unlock the bootloader because Android
devices by default
come - come in a way where you can only
install a signed firmware signed by the
original manufacturer it's quite a
device specific yes with most devices
you have to enable developer mode first
probably not with all I've seen it on
devices like for example Google Nexus 5
it's just well you send a command and
you're done I've had devices from
Motorola for example where you have to
create an account on the website and
enter some data you get you you have to
extract from device it's usually
depending on where your get your run
from this part is usually in their
instructions I've I mean for example
with line at us the instructions are
quite good for the officially supported
devices there are if you have a device
that's only unofficially supported
because somebody wrote something that
can be a bit of a challenge sometimes
because they leave out some of the
people then leave out stuff because well
for me it was clear yes for you maybe
[Music]
also most of the devices will shows in
some way that bootloader has been
unlocked I've seen that from while a
small unlocked padlock on Google devices
up to a full screen read warning while
booting on some Motorola devices you can
actually override that image so if it if
it advises you but still don't get
confused
yes of course there are some there are
some implications if you don't run sign
software because obviously if you can
install other software somebody else can
as well so that that's that that's the
downside but it's not a major problem
actually that's one of the examples of
the warnings you get from some of the
devices it's just an example a friend of
mine took that's on the not so obvious
side as I said it's really device
dependent some of the some of the
manufacturers actually I think UI at
some point said that while in in the
past was easy to unlock our devices they
said well you're not no longer allowed
to do that with new devices
unfortunately you have to check ideally
if you if you plan to unlock your device
it's even a good idea to check before
buying it that's obviously not always
easy and sometimes you might even have
some device that you already have and
then you have to check if it's possible
yeah the actual the actual installation
is usually quite painless and usually
it's usually it's not you cannot usually
you cannot really prick your device so
most cases there is no step where if you
don't completely up you cannot
really destroy the device it might not
built at the moment but usually you have
a second try
I've had one instance where that was not
true for installing the bootloader
because for some Android devices have
multiple boot loaders and usually you
use the first one to flash that the
second one and the second one is the one
you want to change and I have had
devices where you needed to say working
second bootloader to get into the first
one so usually the face backup but most
of the time it's it's really not an
issue and I had the problem before that
I had a problem with the cable or the
power went out or whatever and then you
just start from beginning it takes a bit
more time but it's it's really not a
problem the same with the firmware
installing it it's usually another
problem you can i mean it's it's usually
not not dangerous to install it the one
thing you might have to take in in mind
is some manufacturers actually provide
you with the original firmware so you
can go back but not all of them do I've
I used to have unfortunately I
physically broke them so I don't have
them with me today for previous
workshops I used to bring Google devices
for people to experiment with without
risking their own phones as I said
unfortunately they are physically broken
at the moment these are quite nice
because you can actually really get the
original firmware so if you try it out
and you don't like it you can really
just reset it to factory mode and go
back to how things were
also
there's some strange typos in there also
if you want to install some additional
stuff you also have to do that at this
step and some of them for some of that
you really have to do it by when
installing I mean you can get back into
the bootloader and install additional
stuff unfortunately for example if you
want to have some of the Google services
there is an option for that with my
Croce I personally don't use it but some
people prefer to do it for example to
have post push notifications working
which is a bit better for battery
runtime for that you really have to
install it while installing the the
original ROM because if you do it later
it will do a factory reset and clear all
your data which well is a bit of a
problem there is also for example what
put something that's quite useful is the
F Drive privileged extension on which
allows the f-droid store to
automatically update stuff and not just
notify you that yes there are updates
please apply them but with with the
extension you're actually able to say
well if I'm on Wi-Fi you're allowed to
update yeah so yeah the pictures as I
said are taking my friend of mine
well picture in this case so that's the
completely theoretical part about
flashing so are there any people here
who actually want to try to flash their
phones
okay two of them are you are any of you
interested I mean it's one thing to
uninstall software to kick out the
Google stuff the other thing is
obviously that you need replacements are
any of you also interested in
information about how to replace stuff
with other software show of hands
okay there's also some so I might start
a bit with that I haven't prepared
presentation slides for that so I have
to do it from my head but that's fine
so we'll just do a small overview before
trying to slavica that can take a bit of
time and I mean if not all of that all
of you are doing it so obviously while
people including myself do not want to
use the Google cloud it's still
convenient so there are quite a few
services that you have to replace for
example the whole contact
synchronization stuff is really useful
because well if for example you lose
your phone and you all your contacts are
gone or also with the calendar you might
want to use that on your laptop as well
for that there is the web tough protocol
that you can use for calendar and
contact synchronisation there is a
relatively good kind for Android it's
called a tough droid it's done by some
Austrian guys it works quite well on the
server side there are depending on what
you want I mean most people that I know
runs some kind of next count or own code
that unfortunately is a relatively big
package that you'd need to wrestle with
some like radical servers that only do
one only to contact and calendar
synchronization yeah if you need only
the calendar and contacts next Scouts
probably overkill I mean it works and
yeah it has some critics but it works
the some of the other stuff I mean I can
really did the other thing is of course
the App Store
I've made some quite I think after it is
quite good but some people criticize it
that they only provide free software
which I don't think it's a downside but
well some people think that they sell
needs some apps there is the App Store
which you can also install the wire
after it so you can install a store wire
a store which actually allows you to
extract epic extract and install certain
applications from the Google store
obviously quite a few of them will not
work if you don't have any Google
services because the Google services are
it's that's not only the part that
Google provides on the web but it's also
some libraries and stuff on your local
phone if they were missing quite a few
applications don't work but one example
that quite a lot of people that I know
install via Yelp is signal the single
messenger because while it's more or
less free software well it's from the
license it's free software but the
offers sometimes has different opinions
than other people and how you have to
interpret the license and therefore it's
not there there is some friction why
it's not included in F right directly
so yeah that's the the big part is any
services any of you are using that you
might think that you need replacements
for
so um I was going through through for
services and software that you might
need to replace if you kick off the
Google stuff from your phone and take
out stuff not one I just wanted to ask
is there anything specific that any of
you might think about that you might
need replacements for well Google Maps I
usually reply every place with awesome
nan which works great in my in my
opinion I'm it's I mean it has some
downsides for example I mean it's great
it routes great and it actually has
quite good maps in places where while
the official hiking maps are a bit
broken but yeah the problem is a bit
that at least for some people it does
not do public transport routing
unfortunately that that's a bit of that
that's a bit of a downside for that I
usually use transporter which is also
quite useful it's a small app that can
interact with quite a lot of public
transport providers all over the world
not all of them because well some of the
providers don't provide an open
interface to their to their systems some
of them we had this problem you know in
in Austria the vanillin Ian at some
point even threatened people when they
tried to Wendy reverse-engineered the
interface their proprietary application
uses to come back to contact their
servers they threatened to sue because
well it's
you know you're not only allowed to use
that with our software I don't
understand that but well it happens but
I've really made quite good I've really
made quite good progress with that and
in most cases it works obviously if the
data it gets is broken well it's because
for example I know the problem in Vienna
that the application now works correctly
with it but for some reason the API does
not say if it doesn't have data because
for some reason it does not know where
the underground is at the moment which
is a bit frightening because most of the
time they drive automatically and then
it's a bit frightening if the system
doesn't know where it is but well they
start to put in the system where they
usually put in it comes in five minutes
they start to put in the actual wedeck
come because of the timetable so they
just put in instead of five to put in
their 11:15 or something which well if
you know it well you have case you can
interpret it but you have the same
problem with their normal signs because
well they don't they do the same stuff
because they just write the time there
and tell nobody that well actually we
don't know when it's coming so any other
stuff that
how do you do basement of these
well if they're updates they will will
be included in some way in in the
updates for Iran hopefully a bit of
problem of course is that if you have
some phone that's no longer supported by
the original vendor and then it gets a
bit complicated because usually then
there are no basement updates for that
anymore or while there might be because
some other some other phone might have
the same chip and you could extract that
but then not I wouldn't I wouldn't count
on that actually happening
when I suspected
the basement
go Kampai
well I think the problem is that with
Lana CH you have the same problem like
with quite a few other projects it's the
individual images are prepared by
different people and some of them work
in other ways than others also the
problem is also that for different
vendors it's they have different
licensing for the base band and how to
get to it obviously but yes it's it's
it's an issue but for most devices that
I've seen so far there I mean lots of
devices that I've had in hand for
flashing don't have render support
anymore as it is so well you at least
get the software updates but yes of
course it's the base band is a bit of a
problem the other problem is if you have
if you have a line interest device that
they support even for the original
vendor does not support it anymore and
it they sometimes take quite a lot of
work to actually port a newer Android
version to your device unfortunately
Android winders took like the annoying
way on handling the Linux kernel because
usually the chip manufacturers fork the
Linux kernel put in their Traverse there
and then hopefully provides security
update for that branch
unfortunately that model of course is a
problem because as soon as they stop
supporting the device it's harder to get
security fixes also sometimes I've seen
that with relatively new devices where
there are no line interests had to drop
them because it's for new Android
versions because that well for the new
Android version we need a new kernel but
we can't really do that for this device
because that would mean to extract all
the drivers from the render tree and
forward port temp to some other kernel
which well I don't know if any of you
have tried to port forward port kernel
drivers I've looked at a bit at it and
it's a bit of a pain in the ass
sometimes I think yeah
but yes I mean that the point is valid
that baseband and other firmware that's
in there might be updated by the vendor
and might not be by language or s or I
mean there is there is not only lambda s
of course there is there are others as
well lining is one of the bigger ones
that have support for quite a few
devices yeah
other questions
or things you might want to point out
okay I think we could start
I mean it's unfortunately only two
people wanting to actually flash the
phone it's a bit with the size of the
group that's even hard for watching but
we could start with that now yeah so I
think the presentation part is or less
over uncle
continue continue with the with the
actual flashing part I'm not sure how so
which one the guys who wanted to flash
the film so you don't know nobody I
tried to be honest it's because it's
what kind of device do you have I'm not
sure I haven't had any Nokia devices yet
flash I'm not in love or even sure about
the procedure we would have to look at
this
okay
well with tablets it's the support is
kind of lacking depending on the on the
model I'm not sure what kind of model do
you have
I have not so far I have not seen any
runs for that because four and then I'm
working with stuff like that
at work as well and for whatever reason
the alternative roms seem to ignore
tablets at the moment there used to be
some support now they ignore it I'm not
sure if it's just that the market share
dropped for non
caplets or the people who yeah now that
the problem is if we don't have ROM we
won't start porting Android to in the
language rest to new device today
because I don't think that that's a
feasible way to go I've invested some
weeks in that okay that's a bit
unfortunate as well as I said especially
since I don't have test devices
[Music]
okay what do we do so okay
yeah okay yep look it's fine
I fished some most of the Samsung
devices that I know apart worked quite
well at the phones tablets is a bit of a
different thing they tend to work
relatively well from my from my
experience of 50 s7 is on the support at
least it's the procedure is a bit
different than for example for Google
phones but it mostly works
yeah well it's as I mean it's usually
somebody has a reason to run it in a way
I mean friend of mine also said well he
needs for example the Google payment
services as a bomb
but yeah it's so for some reason I don't
have internet at the moment
but yeah it's a if you tried the first
time I would recommend to have ample
time available where you don't where you
don't immediately meet the phone because
okay now because a friend of mine once
said well when we got the phone he tried
to flash it and does it okay now I don't
have a working phone and I need to leave
for a business trip in two hours that's
the situation you should try to avoid it
unless of course you say well I don't
care I have a backup phone but okay
doesn't like me today I look it up later
for you you know it's the I mean the
Samsung device is depending on you if
you run a Linux or Windows on your
device it's usually either heimdall or
olden olden usually works for more
devices because the heimdall guys are
have to have to keep keep up because
from what I've seen or them seems to be
more or less of directly from Samsung it
seems actually not usually we have have
been meant for end-users so I think
that's it from the look of it it was
more geared towards that the shops where
they obviously also sometimes have to
reflash stuff the nice thing is with the
Samsung devices usually can also get the
original firmware if you know if you
need to get back to some point one
problem they have is that while from
cool you just go to the Google side and
then say well yes yes yes and then you
have to agree
to some terms but you can get the
official image from people for Samsung
there are official sites where you can
official sites where you can get the
images which well mostly works but it's
of course from the trust there there
might be some trust issues if you have
to revert to it I didn't care that much
for the devices I had to do it for work
because they well are running in some
isolated Network anyway and don't handle
any private data because they're
basically feedback devices that display
stuff and have some buttons there I
don't have an issue if it's a phone
where I handles personal information of
other people that might be different
considerations
yes yes well it's I would not I mean for
first some of the tablets I mean some
time for some some of the devices you
cannot relock the bootloader once you
unlock it that that's one issue
especially if you afterwards install
some more or less untrusted stuff it's
one issue the other issue is that for
some of the Samsung devices I'm not
completely sure what they exactly verify
because even if the bootloader and the
kernel are trusted that's usually the
part they verified by signature there
still might be some user line stuff that
has been replaced and it's running in
the background as if they replace some
demon in the user land part that still
might have quite quite a bit of access
to stuff if it's running as a root user
so that that that's also a bit of an
issue for that you would have to check
the exact what RT actually verifying why
because as far as I know I mean all of
them verify the kernel that the kernel
is signed which is a big part obviously
but I mean obviously you can also steal
stuff from userland
even if Android tries to isolate
applications as far as possible
any other questions
yep
okay
I mean xda-developers is definitely a
good a good starting point I tend to
it's easier for me because it usually
select my phones for various methods
beforehand
I usually go quite a bit with official
language supportive devices because
there I also know that I get updates and
the nice thing about line choice is that
they also have over-the-air updates for
the official supportive devices so that
you told me to go through the whole
flashing procedure for every security
update which has its advantages that's
that's the one thing there is obviously
there are some roms that today because
I'm missing missing a name here but I
mean there are some roms that go even
quite a bit further about kicking out
all the non free stuff it the problem is
that they tend to also kick out drivers
with that and personally I would not
recommend around for the phone for
people to people that says well yes you
now have a phone that doesn't contain
any proprietary code but unfortunately
you don't have Wi-Fi you don't have a
camera and you don't have Bluetooth
anymore that might work for some people
it might not work for others I mean yes
then there is the option I've seen
people who then actually have attached
USB connected Wi-Fi dongles to their
phones
yeah actually I find it quite a bit more
convenient if it's built in I mean I
don't care if you it's a bit thicker but
it should have built in my thing yeah
well I mean that's at its I really saw
the difference over the years that some
some vendors well I mean as I said you I
think they said well we won't provide
that anymore because we won't provide
the option to unlock anymore
there's some I have had experience with
some Sony phones a few years ago where
well officially they provided the option
to unlock but they would have you jump
through hoops with creating an account
and calling the the service hotline and
well you get you get the impression that
they don't want you to do this yeah I
mean obviously people also change over
time I'm not sure it might be better now
as well
[Music]
no no it's yeah yeah as I said I mean
company policy changed over time
partly because while different also
because different people are at the helm
of companies over time but well as as I
said as for me I made at some point
start to look into the whole procedure
can it be unlocked is there is there a
chance for an alternative firmware
actually before buying the phone which
well enhancement it's easier but yeah
any other questions
well I think then we'll close the
session even if it's quite a bit earlier
than expected because I was hoping for
the for the practical part I really have
to get new phones for people to play
with yeah so thank you
[Music]
[Applause]