[Music]
[Applause]
we're going to start our next lecture
now in which McClement is going to talk
to us about email and how does it even
work hi thanks for your resilient and
bearing with me through maybe another
talk I'm still McClellan I'm still
available on the ferry verse on master
Dan and somewhere on the interwebs if
you want to find me and this is about
email let's start with a brief history
very brief history in the early 60s
mainframes were common mainframes are
like a large room with a single computer
in them because computers were larger
back then and stupid simple terminals
that were connected to it so people
could enter interact with that computer
and of course humans being humans they
had the idea well we could send each
other messages using that computer so
they started putting files into each
other's home directories because the
username was unique on that machine and
so we already had a messaging system
that was multi-user
but on a single host at least at most e
sixties in 1969 they started to be more
formal like having like message
transactions and there were two commands
back then on the mainframes they were
called message sent and read mail like
very simple things but they could
already transfer messages between two
computers so now we're multi user multi
host for certain definition of multi
then in 1970 the universe began now we
have a time frame my timeline which
started zero of course before there was
no time and in 1971 ray Tomlinson said
well now we're having usernames and we
need to somehow designate on which host
that user Reese will receive the
so we need some character to the limit
between the username and the hostname
and so he said well I need some
character to do that and this one was
available it was not in use anywhere
else and that it in English it's called
the @ sign was purely by accident so
they used it and it was fine so email
addresses or message addresses looked
like Ray at 10 X 8 n X was a popular
operating system back in the day and why
does that hostname look like that
because DNS will be invented in the 80s
so in about 10 years and they were
passing hosts files back and forth the
world file which contained all the known
hostname IPS and names and they were
passing that around mail was not DNS was
not invented yet in 1973
people started formalizing message
headers so they were easier to pass
around
I became an RFC standard by then in 1975
the message transmission protocol not so
simple yet was invented to have some
formal way of passing messages around
and also the first message groups
probably what we call emailing lists
appeared and then even a standard for
the format of the ARPANET work text
message was made an RFC and now we have
pretty much everything we need for
something like an email system we have a
header format for addressing we have a
protocol for message transport and we
have a message format so yeah email
we're done
okay it's it's a little more complicated
than that I admit of course these are
see were worked over and made a little
better and improved and in the 80s
yeehaw
this is what started it all it's
probably what we the thing that's most
closely already to what we use with
email today started with RFC 821 which
is SMTP the simple message Transfer
Protocol and RFC 822 the message format
so oh okay I don't I want one of bother
you with what was the single charts back
then you may remember and it will hurt
so who of you still uses this email
thing is that anyone okay that's about
ninety seven percent and a few shy
people who don't dare to admit it that
would be me yeah so how does email work
today around 2018 well that's it that's
email you have a phone you have another
phone and between there's magic and you
get an email that's pretty much it
isn't it oh another one
damn okay it's a little more than that I
guess so let's let's get ourselves a
small recap of the terminologies ordered
everybody knows what we're talking about
we do with an author she's on the left
on the slide we do have a recipient
let's call them author and recipient
that would be convenient probably and
that authors using an email application
or in email terms that is called a mail
user agent your standard mail
application like motto mail app or
outlook uh from the bird or whatever you
use and yeah our author has a menu a a
mail user agent and since it's the
authoring mail user agent we call it the
authoring May
user agent it's pretty simple that
concept you get it so when that author
wants to send a message
she needs her mail application to talk
to something and that is called the mail
submission agent it's nothing to do with
submitting email messages not even if
you're running open PDS M is an
operating system but the mail submission
agent accepts emails from clients so
that is that connection
and once the mail submission agent has
accepted the message it hands it over to
a mail transport agent commonly referred
to as mail server and since it's the one
of our sender or author to sending mail
transport agent so we're here and then
that sending mail transport agent wants
to pass that message over the Internet
to somewhere else probably hopefully the
receiver there may be one or more
relaying transport agents in between but
we'll pretty much ignore that because
they don't add a lot to the concept and
at some point hopefully that message
arrives at the receiving mail transport
agent which is here and that transport
agent now things well what do I do with
that message where's my recipient can we
deliver that somewhere oh there's a
delivery agent how convenient
let's pass the message on to our mail
delivery agent that would be probably
your Duff Curtis Cyrus so whatever you
may be using so we're here there's no
bad jokes with MDMA here and our
receiving mail user agent or recipient
she is using her application to collect
the emails and you already see our parts
are interconnected in each of the
connections each of the sparing
symbolizes something where things
communicate with each other and to
communicate these things need a common
language so they understand each other
and this is what we call protocols so
far so easy
so let's see how these things talk with
each other lesser offering the
user-agent
our mail submission agent commonly
referred to as sending email quite
boring that's this part in the in the
picture and a common misconception is
that mail user agent and submission
agent stalk smtp they don't they call us
they use something called message
message submission it looks a lot like
smtp many things look like smtp in email
but there's a few very minor changes to
it what does the communication look like
it's way too small to read so don't even
try I'll give you a brief overview the
client connects to the mail submission
server server says hello client says
well hello and then the clients as well
let's start encryption isn't that a good
idea
services well okay let's do that and I
do it here let's handshake and this is
what the communication looks from then
on okay oh yeah since we're the user
agent we already have the keys because
we did the handshake so this is what it
looks like
server says well who are you are you
allowed to do this
may I see your password please user
agent sense authentication credentials
server checks if things looks plausible
enough I'll let them pass and then the
mail client starts sending email by
passing on the recipient and all the
data few headers and then when it's done
it says single dot on as the first
character on the line services okay
I've cute that message and they say bye
very friendly conversation quite easy so
that's pretty much it
that mail submission agent has put that
message into the so called incoming
queue because there may be multiple
messages coming in at the same time and
they're just lining up like you do at
the bar and the message
submission agent says well I'll hand it
over to some transport because I'm just
here for accepting them from clients let
somebody else do the rest of the work
so they hand it over to the transport
agent that's usually something quite
local to the server and the transport
agent takes the message cleans it up a
little bit
checks if it's a local delivery or if it
has to pass it on over the Internet for
this example we'll pass it over the
Internet to somebody else and so this
sending mail transport agent will pass
try to pass the message to the receiving
mail transport agent that's this part of
the scheme we'll ignore the intermediate
mail transport agents because it's just
the same over and over again so we'll
simplify this looking a lot more
friendly now even the slide is smiling
and now we're actually talking SMTP the
RFC 5 3 21 so what does that look like
and where does my mail transport agent
actually know which other mail server to
contact any ideas MX record yes it's
consulting DNS and asking so I've got
email for that domain do you know any
mail servers I could talk to so it looks
up the MX record which is store phone
mail exchanger you can easily check that
from the comfort of your command line by
issuing a host
- t4 + MX command for the domain and
hopefully DNS will tell you whom to talk
to which is in our case smelled of Alken
dork simply enough so mail server starts
talking to another transport mail server
they say hello I'm here the other one oh
I love anguish and then they're
receiving mail services well I can do
this kind of things ok that's nice but
the rest of the conversation is pretty
much the same as we already saw
they pass on a recipient they pass on
message headers the message itself and
when they're done they finished with a
single dot as the first character on a
line and the return and then we say bye
everything's fine message cute and the
receiving mail server has accepted that
message for transport
since mail transport agents want to get
rid of messages as soon as they can
usually they won't okay this is for
delivery now where's my delivery agent
it's pretty much local that's hand
handy and it tries to pass that message
on to the mail delivery agent and these
two are speaking another protocol it's
called LM TP the local message transport
protocol and as you've guessed it by now
it pretty much looks almost like SMTP so
they did not reinvent the wheel and just
changed a few things again to make it
easier and that conversation pretty much
goes almost the same as we've already
seen two times now they say hello and
then there's a tiny change because the
transport agent passes each recipient as
a separate statement and the delivery
agent either accepts that message that
address or rejects it immediately
there's no queuing here so if a mess
recipient does not exist it will say
well no such user I can't deliver it to
that one but that's pretty much almost
all of the difference
what don't need to go into any details
here a question
because if you cannot deliver the
message to a recipient that's not there
you have to send a bounce and inform the
sending message mail transport agent of
this is not possible so you get an error
message base it back and yeah the
delivery agent is sitting there and
waiting until our recipient comes with
their mail user agent and starts
collecting their messages we're closing
to the end of the game there's usually
IMAP these days in use the internet
message access protocol but one keeps
your delivery agent state of your emails
and their client state of the emails in
sync they update their changes and it's
also convenient if you need to access
your email from multiple clients like
your phone your tablet your computer or
whatever you may be using your fridge
obscure things use email these days
there's also another protocol it's still
in use and there's some good use cases
for it it's called pop we post office
protocol and buy ones even simpler
client comes says give me all the
messages and then you never talk about
it again no observer does not know what
the client does with the messages but
it's telling you we don't want to go
into details they are both about 100
RFC's themselves so that's probably 7
separate talks I'm not going to that and
now we have message delivery from a
sender to a recipient let's have a look
what is on a server of all these
communicating parts of this large puzzle
game since passing a message one way is
pretty much the same as passing it the
other way we can reverse that and we end
up be a mail server very basically being
this you have a transport agent that
accepts incoming messages and delivers
outgoing messages we have a submission
agent that accepts messages from a
client and a delivery agent that keeps
messages for a client and that's usually
your postfix
cut or Exim Cyrus combination on the box
for small email systems that's a single
machine on larger systems these parts
may be spread across multiple VMs or
even Hardware what else do you need to
run a modern email system because with
if you put that on the internet you will
be receiving a lot of email and at some
point your primary reproductive organs
have been enlarged enough that you won't
accept any more of these because you
only receive spam mostly so there's a
lot of things more you need to have a
fully fledged email system because your
users will come up with ideas and annoy
you what do you need you need some
common email addresses some are required
like having a postmaster at your domain
email address because if somebody needs
to contact the person running that email
system they use the postmaster Esther
address that's the standard to use you
also need an abuse address if some of
your clients start spamming strange
things you want to have an email address
to contact and tell them well this one
is spamming stuff can you please make
them stop and look at this and there's a
bunch of other ones I highly recommend
also implementing a security at email
address that is actually right by human
beings at your domain because if
somebody stumbles across a security
problem with any of your systems please
make it easy for them to tell you
because some people will actually do
that and be fine with it and not exploit
you so make it easy for them to tell you
about this you'll benefit from this and
it's easy to do what else do we need we
already had the MX record for the domain
name system that tells other systems
where they can find a mail exchanger
they will either look up an MX record if
no MX record does exist for a domain
they will fall back and trying an a
record or quat a record which means they
will probably try talking to
web server which usually does not accept
email but it's a piece of the SMTP
standard how to handle this and this is
what they'll try there's other things
you can put into DNS to make your
message delivery more convenient there's
the so called sender policy framework
SPF since you can look up where to send
email but there's no way to find out if
that server that's sending you email is
actually legit and allowed to send email
for that domain so people came up with
SPF and you can put your sending email
servers into that DNS record it's a
simple text record it says I'm an SPF
record any box that has an MX record for
my domain is allowed to send email and
that one legacy IP and that one IP
subnet is allowed to send email with at
my domain and you put that on the
internet and you have a policy part that
is the - all - all which means and any
other system on the Internet is not one
of the ones I'm allowing to send email
you could put a plus in there which
means these ones I know about and
everybody else is allowed so that's
pretty useless I would not do that and
there's also the tilde all the wiggly
line which means there might be others I
have not yet discovered don't care too
much about it that's also pretty useless
so please think about which systems send
email for your things and for the - all
in it
SPF has side effects especially if
you're running email mailing list
servers or if you forward a lot of email
because that from address before what is
probably not one of your own mail
systems and the receiving mail server
checks that and sees well these don't
match up and now we're running into a
conflict with your SPF record because
that says not one of yours somebody
else's and they may tag your email as
spam even if you only forward it and
that's correct
if it wasn't that way SPF would be
completely useless in at all
and we would not need it so people came
up with some solution which is called
the s send a rewriting scheme where your
email server will rewrite the envelope
of an email so that it matches your own
SPF record for your own mail system and
that problem is solved so if you publish
SPF records you're giving others a hint
that your mail system is legit and
others are not and if you forward email
you need other mail servers to implement
send a rewriting scheme getting kind of
a problem so if you put up SPF records
for your own domain please also
implement sender rewriting on your own
system others will benefit from it and
if everybody does it we're all happy of
course we're not it's the internet what
else can you do to make your email look
more legit to other mail systems there's
the domain key identified email dekum
where you have a little more work to do
to implement it D Kim tells your email
server to sign digitally sign with an
RSA key that's different from your TLS
set up to sign email that is outgoing
so this is a digital signature done by a
mail server with signs that it has
passed one through one of your email
systems you also need to come up with a
string called the selector in this case
it's just a basic text string 7-bit
ascii in this case you're limited to
that and an SPF DNS record which
connects all these parts the fruity unix
is my selector for my domain then you
have the dot underscore domain key dot
McClement dot 80 or dot your domain
where do you know the selector from
because you need to look up that DNS
record well the selector comes with the
email you receive so you just take it
from there and the rest of the record
just says I'm a deacon record I am using
these hash functions my key type is RSA
the T equals s means I'm in production
this is not a testing setup and it's
valid
or email and the part after the P means
it's the public key in base64 and that's
a lot of base64 public key giver ish
you'll have all kinds of fun with that
the benefits of setting up the hymn is
that other emails servers can identify
your email as legit and give it less
spam points which is good for your email
because it ends up in the inbox are not
in the spam the tropics are you need to
have some plug-in on your mail transport
agent to sign outgoing messages and if
your incoming email should be checked
for tecum signatures to verify which I
highly recommend you also need some
plug-in to do that
conveniently most plugins that do tecum
can do it in both ways and since you
have to publish an hour a text record in
DNS and if you're using RSA keys larger
than 1024 bits 2048 is the absolute
minimum you should use I recommend 4096
as usual you get very long public keys
which means you get very long dns
records and most web interfaces to
manage DNS are like really really
terrible when it comes to multi-line DNS
records which are totally valid but they
will silently cut it off at some point
order will start oh there's quotes in
there I'll need to escape those and put
back slashes in front of them and all
kinds of weird things
please open tickets with your dns
providers though they fix that
because DCAM really helps us deliver
email better so far you're announcing
which system are sending for you you're
announcing how to verify that a message
actually passed one of your systems with
the signature by publishing the public
key to that but what should a receiving
mail system do with a message that's
come from your domain there's D mark the
domain based message authentication
reporting and conformance and that one
connects these things if you're either
using SPF or give him or both there's no
requirement to use them all together
I highly recommend using Demark anyway
because that adds reporting so a
receiving mail system can report to you
hey I've received a message from some IP
that claims to be you but that does not
match up here's what I got you probably
have guessed it there's a DNS record for
that ionically sneaked the DNS talk into
this and it's always underscore D marked
out your domain it says well I'm Adam AK
record and it has a policy that can be
either none do nothing with it just look
at it keep an eye on it but I don't
remake recommend any any doing anything
with it it can be quarantine which means
make it likely spam or outright reject
it at all if it has not been signed by
my system don't use it it's not legit
and then you have the argue a in our UF
fields which means where to send
aggregate reports and forensic reports
and you can specify the format and how
many how much percentage of your emails
should be checked usually you use 100
when you're in production and how often
you would like to receive these reports
86,400 seconds is usually in central and
western europe good for three hundred
and sixty three days a year
because there's one with an hour more
than one with an hour less you'll
receive a report nonetheless and that
gives us gives receiving email systems a
policy on how to act on emails that fail
a verification with SPF or DKIM or both
and handle them as spam or not and give
you a report on how often that happens
since you also have a policy for
subdomains and some and our domain name
system is not entirely clear there's the
so-called public suffix list it's an
initiative originally started by Mozilla
it's now community maintained project
and it keeps a list of separating domain
names with organizing entity
meaning belcando torque that simple or
torque is the top-level domain and
Valken is the domain and mail of
belcando Royal Mail would be the
hostname but what about company dot code
at UK dot Co is not a host or or it's
not really a domain UK is certainly a
topple a country top-level domain so
this is not entirely clear and the
semantics are not technically there for
humans to understand but not for systems
so this public suffix list will actually
connect these things so that your mail
system can correctly manage these domain
separators what are the benefits of
running Demark well other mail systems
get an idea and as a suggestion on how
to deal with your emails or emails that
claim to come from you and when for
example in SPF and the diem record check
verifies is okay that's a strong
indicator that this email is coming from
a legit system and it's a legit email
and you also get reports that you have
to read that's the drawbacks you have to
read these things there's also several
companies and tools available that make
automated things to give you a lie
support with charts and everything so
you get a good overview what's happening
out outside on the internet with systems
cleaning to send email for you you might
even discover a machine that's
legitimately sending email for your
domain that you have forgotten that's
still out there so what does our email
system now look like you remember the
small thingy with the three pieces
well we've ended up here now we're
signing geek in by verifying geek him we
got SPF records on the dns we verifying
that incoming as well we have the sender
rewriting scheme so forwarding email
works we have d mark and we're regularly
pulling the public suffix list and
downloading that one so your mail server
now needs to talk to web servers as well
getting a little more complicated now
what's tillage it's okay it's a few
pieces add-ons for your transport age
and then a few DNS records and a little
key handling but so quite okay then we
need TLS it's contemporary let's encrypt
makes it easy makes it free to use so
what do you need for that you need
something to deliver an acme challenge
so the handling of that you're proving
that you're allowed to get these
certificates if you want to use cert but
by de ffs or if you're running
dehydrated which is my personal favorite
to use it works very reliable to get
your certificates works fine on any BSD
or Linux system so you need certificates
what are the benefits of TLS well you
don't leak any username and password
credentials when people send or receive
email that's quite handy
you also don't leak message content on
these parts and the drawbacks are well
you have to maintain it you have to make
sure that your certificates are
regularly updated and replaced and that
your mail transport agent and delivery
agent also loads in the new certificates
from time to time because they change so
you can happily be replacing
certificates and forget to restart your
post fix or dovecot and they will use
the old certificate and you know it has
been replaced I know
just give him a kick one up once in a
while and it'll be fine and since email
sending between transport agents over
smtps opportunistic well we don't get a
lot of security or privacy there it's
purely hoping that it works and nobody
checks certificates anyway so at least
we can secure the client connections but
that's better than nothing so now you
have some kind of web server because you
need to deliver Acme challenges
needs a web server of course you can do
that with like two lines of Python but
well nginx or an Apache it's easy to use
and we might use it for something else
in the future who knows users come up
with ideas so now you're managing
certificates and a web server as well
then your users come and say well I'd
like to filter my email and sort them
into mailboxes probably so you say well
you can do that with Seif on a server
because they come with them the phone
does not have a rule system to pass
messages around and what to use what do
people use see for sorting mailing lists
that's probably pretty common for us
like you get a mailing list and sort it
into a folder and let it rock there and
look at it every two months and om is
that one I missed yeah then people
automatically forward email to other
people also happens but there's one
thing and to be honest that's the only
thing people really use and that
absolutely has to work and that is the
out of office reply when they go on
holidays especially if you're running a
mail system for a company if that does
not work you will get phone calls at
probably 6:00 in the morning very
inconvenient another benefit for you is
a postmaster is that you can integrate
that with your spam system and once the
user moves the message to the junk
folder you can tell see if it should
take that message hand it over to your
chunk your spam filter and oh learn this
as spam and if somebody takes out the
message of the junk folder and puts it
somewhere else it's probably not a spam
message see if can take that message
pass it on to the spam filter and please
learn this as ham as a good email so you
can abuse your users to train your your
spam filter which is quite convenient as
well so your middle system looks like
this
you now have see if it integrates with
the delivery agent side of your system
so far so good
how do you manage these rules there's a
protocol for it it's called manage see
if you need an interface for it
users are usually not happy with having
the Thunderbird with a plug-in where
they have to edit code some of you may
be happy with that most are not they
will just want to click I'm on holiday
you
so most email clients do not have some
plug-in to use so ok let's go with the
webmail interface I mean it's easy hmm
there's my solutions out there for
example roundcube or rain loop they look
nice they work on phones they're pretty
accessible these days they're free
they're open source they're pretty
regularly patched so that's fine you
already have a web server because you
were thinking ahead when implementing
your let's encrypt certificate handling
and Ron keeps fine it's got a lot of
plugins available for the future maybe
let's go with that so now you have a
webmail interface you're running PHP on
your server
and while the web server was there
anyway so it's not that hard you knew
you would it would come in handy then
your users start complaining about
getting spam I don't know why they
receive it there's some cheap tricks to
let in less spam to your system for
example there's block lists they come
via DNS and your mail server incoming
checks if the sending mail server is on
one of those blocked lists and says well
you look suspicious I don't like a go
away I can recommend then that's been
hostile work for this they have a pretty
good list that catches a lot of crap and
especially if you're on the European
continent there's a project by German -
lark and the X Magazine it's called Nix
spam that block list works a little
different it automatically puts mail
servers up on that list and it
automatically ages them out after a few
hours unless they keep sending spam so
if you end up on that list for for by
accident it's easy to get get removed
because you can just submit a web and
web form and say remove and you're
instantly gone
and it catches a lot of spam servers and
systems in Europe especially Germany
Austria Switzerland in the
german-speaking parts of Europe so that
one is a very nice thing and it has
almost no side effects it's really nice
one then there's this thing called great
listing I don't mind if you prefer the
English or the US American way to write
it so that rags matches the ideas that a
proper mail system is quite resilient
when it comes to sending emails so it
will try again if the mail system is not
available and usually a spam Concannon
will not so you say well new email hmm
no not now coming coming in later and
alleged email system will do that
spammers will not the problem is with
large mail clusters they send an email
they get a ticket
you're great listed they come back from
the next cluster no I don't know you get
a ticket next to us the note comes to
retry and send the email I don't know
you you get a ticket and after six hours
that Gmail cluster is rotated through
and will send an email your users don't
like these delays they sometimes happen
so what can we do about it we'll see you
can whitelist them meaning you'll
maintain a list of safe servers from
Gmail outlook.com whatever a large
company and you say well they probably
have the together I'll allow to
send them anyway so your system looks
like this you know great listing you
have DNS whitelist you have Dina's block
lists it's becoming more and more
complicated you're maintaining automated
lists you're maintaining human
maintained lists by manually writing IP
addresses and host names into files -
nice
then there's spam or expensive
countermeasures there's the so-called
Little Shop of Horrors it's a quite
common implementation to combat spam
it's a Maoist a new spam assassin and
razor of Peyser there
pearl monsters like
with a lot of modules in Perl and once
you update one module three others break
that's quite a common scenario every
postmaster has encountered that and they
usually are slow they catch quite a lot
but they're slow and they cost a lot of
CPU cycles and might take an email to be
filled of like one second two second
three seconds
that's quite a lot on this on a mail
system that has a lot of traffic a more
modern solution that I can quite
recommend is are spendy it's a BSD
license thing written in C and assembler
it already sounds faster than Perl and
it's nicely integrated because it can
handle these grey list thingies on
demand so it will not gray list any
message but it will check an incoming
message and if it looks pammi it might
delay it by gray listing it and if it
does not look spam it will not great so
that's how you handle these delays
you'll get rid of them pretty much
completely that's a very nice thing our
screen D also checks your SPF D Kim D
mark things and also aggregates reports
and sends them out for you so that's a
very functional thing and if you want
more performance you can add a ready
sketch to it that is used by it and if
you don't get along with one spam
filtering system you can add multiple
cluster them and have a proxy that
handles that all for you so your mail
system now looks like this you have
large spendy cluster with real-time
block listing gray listing and the Redis
cache then some of you users receive
malware you want to get rid of that
common solution for that is to use
clamavi and clam d the standard rule set
that comes with it is about 20 to 30
percent detection rate which is funny
there's the clam a be unofficial
signature set it's available as a
package for BSD and Linux systems and it
integrates also with our spam key so you
are spending an on-demand fat check for
malware and if you integrate the
unofficial signatures you'll also get
definitions by saying security by sector
I'd info malware patrol and
ytc and now suddenly that boring clamavi
thing has a really good detection rate
even for newer stuff and they're free
and just please use them and now your
mail system looks like this you've added
a V and some cron jobs that download
these definitions automatically and
integrate them with your clamavi since
many of these components already try to
use dns you're hitting your DNS server
of your ISP quite hard especially our
spam D you have some latency for each of
the DNS requests some may fail that has
a timeout and takes time so you add a
DNS cache on your local system because
it's a lot faster less packet drops and
now you're managing and either in a
local unbound instance or a DNS mask but
it improves the performance of your
system and you get less rate limiting
from your DNS server from the ISP then
users come back from holiday they find
this nice web interface turn off the
holidays thingies close it go on with
their phone search for a message they
want to send something but they don't
find it on their phone because your
phone does not have a full index of all
the gigabytes of messages they have what
phones could you always pass the search
on to the mail server the delivery agent
and ask it could you search for this
thing in all your messages and if your
IMAP server does support full text
search that actually works and it works
pretty fast and even with attachments so
you go out there and say well there's
either C Lucine or soul Apache Solr as a
full text indexing plug-in that you can
hook into your mail delivery agent now
you're running java it works with open
JDK so that's a good thing yeah you see
your bolt on things then users are again
using your web interface they type in an
email address or a name and there's no
autocomplete
then they say why I've been
communicating with them for a long time
and there's contacts what do we do
well there's carte def it's an extension
to web dev it allows you to sync v cards
across clients your phone probably has
one def Droid or iOS has one implemented
to sync an address book there's a plugin
for round cube that can talk CalDAV so
would be convenient to have a Caliph's
car-theft server so addresses and names
are passed across all these agents and
users and then you think well there's
also calendars and these fancy calendars
can keep events and you can invite other
people to events via email and they can
respond wouldn't it be nice to have a
calendar server as well
it has Mike help mm-hmm the some even
can look up availability and find the
most inconvenient spot for you in the
morning
so you add a cal def & cardiff solution
that might be radical too or well you're
looking ahead and might think what it
might be other things that these users
may want you're implementing a next
cloud instant which is quite okay these
days you're already running PHP for the
web into webmail interface anyway so PHP
is already getting updated regularly by
you does not matter you had card of
CalDAV thing is at the plug into around
queue and everyone's happy but now you
need to authenticate against all these
systems to log into a web interface to
multiple web interfaces so you have a
problem with authentication not all
users are using a password manager still
not and now you want some kind of
central authentication instance you
probably have a database server already
running because roundcube uses one your
next Claudine's to uses one tough
cutting plastics can authenticate it for
like a Maria to be a MySQL or postcards
yeah let's do some single sign-on thingy
so now you're managing one or multiple
databases or an LDAP server for
authentication then you want to host
multiple domains and you have friends
they all you're running a mail system
you're doing that really well it's
awesome to use your email system can't
you host my emails for these three
domains as well yeah you're paid to
three domains doesn't matter anymore but
they want to add users and aliases
themselves so you want to delegate
handling of their email to me into them
now you had a web interface to add email
addresses and maybe even email domains
to your system and if you're running
elde up you have like a lamb interface
that can put users and email addresses
and aliases and all that stuff into LDAP
on your system so yeah you're adding an
admin GUI
to your Frankenstein monster and then
these people coming in with their phone
and said well I can now search for
messages that is awesome but I don't get
notified when I get an answer I won't
push notifications this is the part
where you start screaming and say AHA no
please there's no real standard across
multiple platforms of course there's
IMAP idle which is kinda pushy but only
if you already have a connection that's
up and running and that drains your
battery on the phone it's not really an
issue for for laptops but it's an issue
with routers that cap and cut off more
or less unused long-living
connections and IMAP idle is pretty much
an open sockets just sitting there and
doing nothing so your firewall would say
well that state is not used wink you
need to reinvent acade there are Mac OS
mail systems that integrate with Apple
push to push to iPhones like real push
messages these have been
reverse-engineered to have some weird
plug-in to your dovecot email that
actually you're receiving mail delivery
agent sends out a push message that is
received by an iPhone there's probably
solutions with Google cloud services to
have the same thing with Android I don't
know about these things there may be
available
and then there's these weird email
applications that leak your credentials
to some cloud service that pulse your
emails email box and when they receive
an email they send you a push message
one candidate for this is Microsoft
Outlook they will happily use your
username and password in the clear
somewhere in the United States in the
cloud and do that so now you have a
security problem as well and need to
somehow keep your user agents tied
together no if I did push there's still
some space left wait somewhere to do
that now you get new people into your
organization or company and they heard
about this awesome system that does
contacts and calendars and email and
fight spam like the heroes and they want
to have all their devices configured and
they come with their phone that tablet a
laptop the HEPA desktop at the office
and all of these needs to be configured
yeah but as an admin you don't want it
come on the seventh email box for you
really so you want service auto
discovery so that you just email address
password return and the email client
automatically discovers where to talk to
which email is sent via which server
your submission agents your delivery
agents everything should be
automatically including the calendar
yeah there's different things for user a
mail user agent Auto config there is RFC
6186 that would be convenient but nobody
implements it there is a proprietary
solution by Apple there's one by Mozilla
there's a third one by Microsoft which
is the most sane of them all at the
moment yep but they usually involve
adding some DNS records and serving some
well-known files like in this dot
well-known folder and then some magic
text file they can use so you end up
implementing all three because you have
a highly mixed clients landscape and are
your three auto-discovery systems to
maintain and of course you want the same
for Cardiff and Cal deaf clients as well
we can find these you're lucky in this
case there's RC 60 67 64 which tells you
all just implement these four SRV
records in DNS again and that actually
works with most clients so that's an
easy part there's one thing and most on
use that one actually so there's fine
solutions for cardiff & cardiff the
benefits is of course less support
burden with your users it's faster it
gives them some autonomy in configuring
their machines less outdated
documentation because the documentation
becomes your auto discovery system and
it can also be used by the not so
technical inclined people which is fine
sadly much does not support any of these
so that's a drawback certainly and of
course for a mix landscape you implement
it a multiple a few times so yeah you
add discovery there and now you have SPF
d km d mark SRV records MX a quat a
there's a ton of dns stuff you have a
cache it's fast but is it secure
[Music]
probably not because nobody actually
uses DNS SEC because most people
actually can't use it because the DNS
provider doesn't support it and with
Dane you can actually cryptographically
shoot yourself in the foot with the
domain there's even a high score list on
the internet for how long somebody has
killed a domain to be unusable with the
cryptographic sign that it is is
unusable and the top rankings are over a
year so please be careful with the key
management there if you really add DNS
SEC but it's the only way to secure your
DNS where all this magic is already in
to support and secure your email
transport then there's the fraction of I
will not really want to touch there's of
course mailing list servers they do all
fancy kinds of fancy things Rob fancy
things with forwarding emails which you
run into a problem with SPF with peaking
Demark so you might want to use mailmen
3 which is the modern mail system after
it's been 4 released since 6 years so
it's probably stable well so really you
need to run it from pretty much get head
and a few patches and then you're gonna
make it work but mailmen 3 is great it
comes with mainland core that handles
all the message passing and Demark
mitigations and it works with SPF and
sender rewriting scheme which is awesome
but you have no web interface you need
to add Pistorius to that now you're
running Python on your webserver as well
and since people would like to look into
an archive from 3 years ago you also
need an archive which is hyper kitty now
you have another django application
running on your server and that
integrates all with your posture fakes
and starts configuring things but at
least these things work with a modern
setup then you might have a support
ticket system something like our key or
Zammit or whatever these things receive
email they send email they fail
authentication because you're they're
not supporting that creme md5 scheme you
would like but they want plain or login
format
so you're reconfiguring your system to
allow these authentication schemes and
they add a ton of headers to your system
that contain IP addresses of internal
systems and other things so yet
filtering of these headers and
normalizing that you're not leaked all
your internals with every email you send
via your support system the marketing
comes along and says well we've got
these twelve thousand three hundred
forty-seven customers and we would like
to send them a newsletter and they have
gotten this list somewhere which is of
course completely gdpr compliant and
some emails for some reason are bounced
and somebody needs to handle that
bounces hopefully not a human these
systems can handle bounces automatically
so they want to retrieve email but this
new
let the system of course does not speak
I'm it because it doesn't want to sink
and keep the messages so you're
activating pop on your delivery agent
that you have not used until now but
these system collect the bounces we have
pop and delete them on the server so it
actually makes sense to use that yeah
and then there's other problems with
robo clients that are sending email but
are probably not a real email system
like a web server that is sending form
data like this PHP form mailer still
happens on the internet it just tries to
send and if it passes through it's fine
if not poof it's gone
it does not try to resend there are
services that do not support
authentication with email like crumb it
just tries to insert into a queue there
services that do not support TLS like
crumb
there's alerting systems like crumb or
your hardware enclosure for rate or your
uninterruptible power supply that will
like to tell you that on Thursday
evening
there was a slight fluctuation in 50
Hertz power and it has compensated for
that which is nice that's what I have it
for another email and some people even
do a machine to machine communication
via email I don't know why but these
things are real and you probably can
come up with a lot of novelties in that
regard of systems that are not mail
systems that are sending email so sneak
peek into the future very brief what is
your next end post challenge as a
postmaster there's MTA STS you know HSTs
which is strict Transport Security for
web servers this is the same thing
pretty much for mail servers the mail
server can announce via you guessed it
DNS that you should only talk TLS via
SMTP so you had a DNS record with the
timestamp you know another TLS a DNS
record
let's as well please send reports when
you have problems with my TLS to this
email address if that email address is
the same system that it has problems
with you might have problems receiving
that report
but work similar to Demark and since
mail servers also have to use curl or W
get or fetch to get things from the
internet like the public suffix list we
already had well now they need to pull a
text file to get the policy that is in
MTA STS it's a simple text files it says
well enforce TLS for this time on this
machine whoever come came up with the
draft RFC for this had the wonderful
idea of telling us you must use carriage
return line feed as line endings for
that so they have a heart for Windows
users they're not using UNIX endings so
you know how to use them and configure
that to properly make characters or and
line feed endings now if not you'll find
out because it won't work otherwise the
benefits of this more or less downgrade
resistance for SMTP which is a great
thing with start TLS and since you're
using let's encrypt you already have
valid certificates which is also nice
and it's explicitly designed to work
with Dane so it won't interfere with
your DNS SEC record and TLS a records
it's an explicit design goal so somebody
put some good thought into that of
course it has drawbacks there's more DNS
records to maintain more files to put up
on web servers that have to hopefully
not interfere with how your CMS works on
your website and now you have the web
server that you also must secure with
HTTPS and HSTs hopefully HSTs preload as
well and all kinds of security headers
that you're already using to secure your
webmail interface then there's another
effort by the FF it's called start TLS
everywhere it's like HTTPS Everywhere
for the browser
it's basically your preload list for
mail servers the FF has put some thought
into it and digitally signs that list
with GPG so now your mail server has to
retrieve a text file over https and TPG
verify that you already had GPT on your
clients isn't it wonderful your server
uses it well
great what else is there if you're
running mailing lists especially nice
authenticated received chain you're
already signing your outgoing email via
deacon and receiving mail server checks
that signature and when it forwards it
that signature breaks because it maybe
adds this is the mailing list footer and
you can unsubscribe here and this is how
to and all that stuff that breaks the
signature so receiving system of the
forwarded email will have a problem
authenticated received chain keeps all
those message systems that pass on the
message multiple times and keeps those
dekum signatures intact so that you can
I
it's a linked list of hashes more I
don't see the B word but it helps to
keep an eye on who passed on this
message and verify that it's all been
okay so that's roughly what you ended up
with as a mail system now you're pretty
much running every programming language
on the planet there's certainly Perl PHP
Python Ruby C C++ assembler there shell
script s transcript data beta s crypto
all over the place there's probably some
brain-fuck and COBOL in there I'm not
sure but I would not be surprised
so in conclusion just sending and
delivering email is pretty easy having a
mail system that actually survives the
internet and survives user support calls
as a lot of work like a real lot of work
keeping everything running smooth
keeping it updated not having some
update here break something else there
that's also a lot of work and if you
hate email now like I do and I hopefully
I've made myself clear why you can
really hate email I have a solution it's
called RFC seven 505
it's a DNS record you probably have
suspected that
it's in vine format it says well there's
a mail exchanger it's priority is zero
which is it's the most important mail
exchanger for this system and you can
reach it at a domain that's called dot
which is the top top top top toppest
level of dns the nice thing is that's a
valid DNS record any mail system can try
to resolve that it will think it's
important and it was unable will be
unable to resolve that so it will never
find a way to deliver email this is
really the one way to tell this a mail
does never accept this domain does never
accept email at all never
don't even try there is no such thing oh
that's the vodka thank you are there any
questions left now okay we need to be
quick because I'm already over time you
missed you missed two important services
one of them is the WebKit directory for
PGP so that would be another web servers
to bolt on for for supporting clients
when they want to do end-to-end public
key public PGP key discovery through
HTTP 4 million yeah and of course what
about the old important facts facts
gateway facts gateway I missed that yeah
I don't miss facts either but yes please
please do a lightning talk on that next
year
excellent presentation you covered like
97% of my own mail server so one comment
give you dimension about the PTR the
importance of having your PTR of your
IPAs yes delegated correctly so the
recipients can verify your mail servers
yes I absolutely spotted that correctly
I lately overlooked to manage another
DNS record that you need your mail
exchanger has a host name that points to
an IP but you also need a pointer a PTR
record that the IP address points back
to that host name and
please don't forget there's a PTR for a
record's meaning legacy IP and for
quad-a records for IP so you need two of
them absolutely correct they were not in
there
thank you one last question okay yeah a
small question you said that you have
users who actually want a web archive
for your mailing lists yeah
have you any sensible solution to be
gdpr compliant if somebody decides that
he sent a mail and he now wants to
delete it gdpr well if you trend the the
case with GDP origin is not that you're
not allowed to keep an archive it just
needs to be transparent about it that
you do this if you don't want your
emails to end up in an archive don't
send email it's all about informed
consent and the GDP are also mandates if
a user removes that content and wants
you to delete the things you have that
you must follow that as far as you can
but if that is technically not possible
or if it's an very extreme overburden
for you to follow that request you are
allowed to refuse it that includes a
right to complain for the citizen with
your authorities with the so called off
seat speaker in German well it's in
English oversight body they're allowed
to complain there but you probably don't
want to go there and start deleting
email messages that break threads so
that would be considered way too much
burden to actually follow for not much
gain so you can probably relatively
easily handle that so one more thing do
you have a darker compose for everything
I certainly don't I run BSD thank you
very much
[Applause]
[Music]