[Music]
[Applause]
okay guys we're gonna start in our next
talk now in which a meal and a bar is
gonna tell us how he survived I see Oh
enjoy okay it looks like yesterday party
was a blast
right now everybody is recovering okay
my name is Milan Gobber and I will be
presenting you not some technical stuff
but actually my experience from the last
year when I was let's say participating
in securing one of the IPOs
so this quick note is Who I am
I'm actually pen tester I'm researcher
company owner from Slovenia ethical
hacker I'm also part of the b-sides
Ljubljana organizer so if your next year
somewhere in march around Ljubljana
you're more than welcome and I'm so I'm
also welcome fans I've been here
presenting for several years last year
I've been missing but I really like also
hacked good Serbian food so this is from
yesterday we just came from another very
good meal so it's gonna be a little bit
easier because I have to digest my food
so okay so what's actually ICO has
anybody been part of the ICO already
well let me yes we have one successful I
see our it was you're still running yes
because it's over yeah but you didn't
take the money and run out no you're
putting up cool because yesterday why am
I asking because yesterday one of the
ugly and I co announced creative
destruction so this is kind of new term
they gonna buy out they're gonna destroy
all the tokens and they were quite
successful they managed to raise more
than 12 million of euros last year and
this year they're closing down who's
having the bitcoins or some other
cryptocurrency okay some of the guys
cool
so the ICO it's actually initial coin
offering what does this mean if you have
good idea before you went to the
Kickstarter today you make ICO and
you're raising the money actually the
people are donating here the money right
yeah so it's actually you get the tokens
you send some cryptocurrency and you get
the tokens and then these tokens go to
different kind of stock exchanges and if
you're lucky you might be a millionaire
or billionaire or who knows something so
this is we only ICO but first before I
will explain my own experience we will
see three parts of the icos or at least
crypto krypter krypter world so we're
gonna see the good part the bad part and
the ugly part what's actually happening
or what happened or it might be
happening also in the future so the
people are saying you know imagine
blockchain blockchain everywhere so last
last year at least in Slovenia I don't
know how was in Serbia but I guess it
was pretty pretty same now it was
everything was turning around the
blockchain
also the big players like CEO of
JPMorgan now first he said bitcoin is a
scam and after that Bitcoin drops and
when the bitcoin was dropping actually
their guys were buying the bitcoins and
making the money so on the other hand we
have people saying that bitcoin is only
joke same it's a blockchain so that's
another our way of we are looking at but
around this blockchain use cases we have
several startups so several different
companies trying to build or to see or
research different kind of usage work
and be so where can we stop blockchain
actually at the moment in Slovenia we
have all one public tender and if you
mentioned blockchain in your application
for this tender you get a huge amount of
points so it's a good way to win this
win this tender so blockchain and
blockchain uses was almost everywhere so
they were saying Bloomberg intelligence
less February this February this year
said that blockchain is coming every if
you're ready or not
so it means every wherever you look so
the banks insurance companies healthcare
everywhere we will have a blockchain in
healthcare we also have some slovenian
no i co widow healthcare it could and
travel industry pain points they said
and of course russian official said
blockchain will seriously change tourism
industry and you know what they mean
with that they buy all the graphic cards
in the russian market so actually the
russian bank bought all the graphic
cards in russian market so gamers in
russia they had quite problems getting a
good graphic card for
for playing the games so this is how the
Russia deals with it and if we take a
look at the most vibrant Isis is Eocene
what do you think who's in the first
place and world who China
no no Slovenia nope Slovenia is close
but not the first the first place was
Estonia so this is from last year so the
first the most vibrant countries works
Estonia
the second was Cyprus right because also
a lot of ICO companies they have
companies they have actually companies
in Cyprus and the third was Slovenia so
that was really good and VA also last
year we had ICO during the summer and
after the summer and autumn we had
almost every two weeks some kind of ICO
coming around and some say that the
blockchain is a new hope for IT industry
and IOT security and the data from the
Star Trek sales mean you know I'm not
quite sure you know because they imagine
several billion IOT devices generating
transaction and putting rank transaction
in the blockchain now at the moment now
there's not so many transaction that you
could put inside the inside material for
example we have seen examples for one
simple stupid game like something with
the cats could stop actually the aterial
the whole network so crypto kitties yeah
so actually one game so could actually
stop the whole whole ecosystem so that's
the good part so actually you can there
your money you can move the money to
Cyprus or Estonia if you're starting
company there and of course you have the
bad parts
we have seen that the last year there's
rough estimation how many ICO project
rates how much money they they raised
and here we have that they they managed
to raise 3.7 billion and hacker stole
370 million dollars from it so it's
roughly around 10 percent so hackers
managed to stall 10% of the all
donations to the IC I cos this is
assumption that the Ernst & Young made
and the others on the other hand we have
also attacks to the against the
different kind of exchanges like coin
check they managed to stall 400 millions
from crypto currency exchange and we
have seen also some other very
interesting stuff when we have been
doing some kind of pen test last year we
already found our customers machines
infected with a crypto miners so this is
also a new way not just to hack very
good server which is customer running
but let's let's try to make some
earnings with with it and of course
you have also kind of zombies
see you can also mine with raspberry
Pius or some other our devices but you
know you don't earn that much for
example as if you would have some kind
of very powerful server on the other
hand there have been also some kind of
new new trends how to find these miners
that have been open to the Internet
why because if you gain the excess
access to the miner and change your
dress where this miner is sending the
cash from the from from from its mining
you can actually also learn a lot of
money especially if this is kind of if
the this possible open mining Creek is
quite big or it has quite some graphic
cards in it so I try to find some some
of the some of the miners and you can
actually easy find it with a show done
and on the other hand you also have some
miners in Serbia open to the whole
internet so you can check what kind of
performers they have so if they're doing
good for example this one you see that
they're having they this mining Creek
has six rather on Eric's 500 to eighty
cards and it's providing around one
hundred and seventy six mega hashes per
second and he's kind of they're still
open to the Internet and that's on G and
then the last thing thence the Augie
part we had a good part the bad part and
the ugly part
so who's thinking to make some kind of
ICO nobody no ideas for ICO you can
actually have very good manuals how to
create us ICO scam in five minutes
online it's true that this this manual
hasn't been updated last couple of year
or two but still use you can find some
good information how to create an IC
o---- scam version and we have because
of this
I'd say attacks and scams we also have
trackers who track actually this kind of
scam so actually the whole ecosystem
also the let's say the guys who were
interested or maybe even scammers we're
providing and creating some kind of
dashboard so you can find where all the
where all the scammers are online and of
course you have something like this
you have the lead designer the lead
market here and the lead developer and
guess what
it might be they're all same persons
because after after I have been part of
the ICO on my LinkedIn profile I got
several requests from potential ICO ICO
teams just in a way can we borrow your
name and you will get like so much
percentage well you just get your name
and because if you if somebody let's say
if some guys who were actually have
present on the Lincoln or insulin
security area this means that they're
standing behind behind the ICO and it
kind of gets you let's say more
credibility and of course with Alec
booting created the Terry on platform
some other guys and we got the smart
contracts
has anybody written already some kind of
smart contract yeah want to are they
really smart
[Music]
okay but what is actually the smart
contract you see that smart contract
were first proposed by Nick Szabo who
coined the term in 1994
so did Bitcoin exist in 94 or aterial
or at least some kind of idea of
ethereum or some kind of blockchain but
a smart contract was already there so
the terms marc-andre was already there
but we have a problem with the smart
contract because they were written by
developers right and with smart
contracts and not properly designing or
even developing or implementing it
actually the guy's the researcher had
discovered that over 30,000 contract are
open to exploit and some of them they
even prove that it's possible on the
other hand they're saying on March 1st
the deterrence mark on trigger fool
holes smart contracts are still way too
dumb but it depends who write them or
even more important how they were tested
or who was auditing them if they were
audited at all and also the bad part
since I'm coming from
since I'm coming from Slovenia I
couldn't pass without telling you this
story that the last year the Slovenia
was witnessing the biggest robbery in a
whole slew in yar in last 20 or 50 20
years since lavinia exist and it was
robbery from the nice hash somebody
using a nice hash client for for mining
did somebody you were using your use you
lost some money
a little bit yeah you lost - did you
take some actions did you get your money
back how because they are returning now
money yeah but the problem is that this
was the biggest robbery in Slovenian
history and there was no press
conference from the police side so
nothing since December totally silence
regarding this and this there let's say
robbery in crypto world does have other
and bad but let's say ugly things
why because with Bitcoin and blockchain
you can actually track all the
transactions so the the guys from the
police and prosecution and everybody who
were chasing the robbers they can
actually see where the money is going
so you see you see that money is going
there but you cannot do anything so
that's the real real ugly part part of
this whole ecosystem so you know that
somebody is getting money out or in this
case for example he's laundering the
money they actually see that this is a
mixer and they are laundering the money
but you cannot do anything you just can
see and watch and cry and that's it and
this is a real ugly ugly part ugly part
of this
and of course last but not least who's
having device to store the crypto crypto
tokens or crypto bitcoins or Italian
oaken's you're using ledger
yeah with updated firmer you're not sure
now why is this acoustic because this
whole ecosystem is like I say it on the
last picture we're gonna see you're
gonna see and you're gonna understand it
it's like really not so very mature
because we are talking about this device
so ledger so the next question is what
do you think
how old is a guy who actually managed to
hack this ledger
[Music]
yeah it's somebody 50 year old so 15
year old programmer anybody 15 years old
here around 15 16 7 okay you still have
a chance
so 15 year old guys are hacking security
devices that are storing your private
keys to your crypto Kingdom it's not
that bad
for example Microsoft the youngest guy
hacked Microsoft Xbox was four years old
so it's not that bad at all but anyway
you know with 15 years not know anything
playing with little device that you can
actually actually he rested around $100
or what was the price of the lighter and
he Wesson it was playing and he managed
and he succeeded so he was not some lead
cool hacker he was just playing around
and that's the as I said but that's
happening here you know in a crypto it's
like wild wild west where almost
everybody gets die he's gonna die and
here it's another case before that I
forgot you see that overflow error shuts
down the token training so I talking
trading so one overflow
it's pretty basic overflow you see if
you're if you're multiplying he actually
managed to put in so big number that
actually the overflow was triggered and
he managed to get all quite a lot of
money from from that smart contract and
that's the simple things that's no
rocket science that no high
mathematician that's maja not high high
mathematics
it's just simple overflow as we know it
from see from you know seventy years
eight years from the last century and
this is the code that's actually running
inside of different blockchain
ecosystems okay
so we've seen this so we have the good
and the bad and the ugly part but where
does this fit since I said I'm I'm
hacker I'm not I'm not developer I've
been developing for several years then I
switch to hacking so because it's much
easier to hack them to develop and it's
a lot of fun and I want to share my
experience with this so last year in
Slovenia there was one ICO and they had
idea like decentralized energy market so
you can if you own a solar power plant
or hydro plant or some other that you're
producing or you're buying your energy
they said okay we're gonna create ICO so
you can actually buy electricity from
each other and all those power
parameters from your from your homes
they're going to be put into the
blockchain and you can have like the
whole platform for trading energy and
some other products or you can actually
donate the electricity to I don't know
let cross your grandma or some kind of
friends or even sell it in different
price that they are selling electricity
beauties to you so they actually managed
to raise that time almost to some little
bit more
two million dollars somewhere between
when there was a high they actually
managed to have market cap like fifty
million dollars so it was kind of huge
so it was also I'd say our
responsibility to keep this money so the
the bad hackers won't steal it so that
was our task and it was kind of we were
not let's say since we were pen testers
and trainers and researchers we are not
quite familiar with everything that that
was needed so when we were studying
should we take this challenge or not you
know it was kind of interesting why
because we had a opportunity to learn
something new to see their actually how
this blockchain works so and what's
behind and there's a lot of clout of
challenges were quite new also for us
and it was let's say challenging enough
to accept it so the first issue was you
know who should develop all the key
components for the ICO or how should we
how should they start it should they go
with an application should they go with
some already proven solution where to
get a smart contract who should be
testing the smart contract so there have
been a lot of issues around that so the
first issue was what kind of application
should we have for raising the raising
the money let's say crypto money so
should we go with some app custom-design
app should we take something should they
go with I don't know some proven
solution from other ICO what kind of
platform what kind of environment should
they go on premise to put on a service
servers in premise or should we go with
a cloud what kind of technology dotnet
core was running up at that time should
they go with Ruby on Rails
or some kind of other thing an
interesting was that platform for
raising the money was actually developed
it was already there but last let's say
last moment before the launch the
decision maker actually since he had two
possibilities he changed this whole
tragedy strategy so they went with plane
github page and a mailing list so there
was no app there was let's say area for
for security issue was quite quite
lowered so they didn't have problems
with the denial of service attacks
because the github was protecting them
and they went this way so the simplicity
so it's one web page with only
JavaScript that was counting down and
some good mailing list manager who was
actually shipping out there all the
emails to interested customers or
interested potential investors so that
was the easiest that was the most
easiest way because when we were
evaluating the application that was
supposed to be installed it was complex
and it has like several I'd say possible
injection points or possible dangers
which could be let's say critical for
also for this application then they had
problems with smart contract since they
did outsource the smart contract you
know they trusted kind of outsourced
company that did a smart contract would
be let's say very good that it won't
have any issues we have been reviewing
it a little bit and when he we have been
reviewing we found also several issues
in it
although that smart control swans
contract or some kind of variant was
already used before and then was the
testing part it was really interesting
that testing part I was sitting on that
meeting you know I said okay smart
contract is kind of almost final how
should we test it what do you think
developer said how does he test how did
he test the smart contract
yeah kind of well he said well I'm
testing this on my notebook you know
it's like I'm running it and it's works
okay how should we test it since they
have been they have been designing it's
a smart contract in a way that it will
give in some time time intervals so for
the first comers would get even more
more tokens than the the the other ones
that way they would come later and all
the exit phases so it would would it
work so for example if this block is
already ended will it close down should
it should actually tokens end at centers
address and everything this was really
really challenging I remember that in a
conference room there was huge decision
tree regarding the testing so if happen
this then it's going to be this and very
good thing was they actually went with a
full public its my contract which is
actually over even at that moment
somewhere somewhere out the whole source
code and then was some other thing I
know on the other meeting he said the
developer brought the code he said
that's the final code we put it in in in
in our testing environment he didn't
compile at all they messed up the final
version didn't compile and of course
when we were setting up also the whole
testing environment
[Music]
it was also some fun because we just
wanted to compile something and some npm
repo disappeared during the weekend it
was like some guy decided to take it
down and the whole build process died so
it's like how come you know it's
impossible then we google it and said
yeah yeah this this is missing when it's
gonna be up we don't know or so
it's a lot of I'd say a lot of
challenging also during this it's my
contracts my contract issues during this
this part
and of course you know with smart
contracts and blockchain there's also
one one issue you cannot say this ICO
will start on Saturday at 9:00 a.m. why
because you're not tied to the clock
you're tied to what you have tied to the
blocks yeah
so they kind of calculated the blocks
you know because you have to make okay
we're gonna start on 28th of July but if
you made a mistake this 20th July is not
the 28th July because if that if some
kind of block generation it's let's say
time block how fast the blocks are
generated a little bit changes so too if
difficulty were change was changed then
also the block generation and all your
calculation is wrong so actually it was
it was the same thing here because they
they actually calculate it and they said
it's gonna start in the morning by the
blowpipe but the theorem said no it's
gonna start at afternoon so actually
people were what we have seen people
were already sending the money because
the address was already sunk or cheque
was already in a terraeum but since it
was not that block time the money is gay
was getting back to the sender's and we
saw one guy what was really interesting
that he sent around 1,000 Eaters and he
never gave came back so he sent it the
money came back he said well they don't
want more money I won't send it again so
they lost one thousand heater at that
time and also some other issues were
very interesting because smart contract
also had the issue but we actually they
discovered it a little bit later
somebody sent some other tokens to that
address
and these tokens are still there they
cannot be put back and when we were
seeing how much money is actually that
somebody lost 20,000 euros sending the
wrong token currency instead of material
he sent some other tokens and tokens are
frozen at that address and they cannot
be sent back because the my contract
didn't let say was not prepared in this
this kind of scenario so actually there
a dearth so some guy some guy lost
20,000 euros in one transaction and then
you know when you already when the the
ICO was started then we had like
interesting times you know it was really
I'd say it was really fun part and here
are some abbreviation but probably here
in in Slovenia we have this one in
Serbia I checked in Google you have this
one who's from Serbia stop is natural oh
no no no I see
some all guys mr. Ness Ness Mia is the
narrative
so you should be prepared you know that
was nonsense since that time from
Yugoslavia we had neatness dismay place
in Italy so this richness dismay is an
oddity object so it's really when we
start at the side when the side was open
it was it took less than five or ten
minutes and they were already scam fight
all around the world so actually the
guys will investors sent money to some
other addresses because if you make a
mistake or somebody scams you into
sending the other ascending the the
cryptocurrencies to some other address
now there's no way back and of course
since we made the see actually they made
a decision we helped them that they
should go with single page it was easy
to clone it because just you know W get
minus error this page and just change
the address where the money should go so
there have been a lot of a lot of scam
pages there have been a lot of attacks
kind of attacks over the telegram or
even on slack so a lot of fake profiles
who were actually looking as they would
be coming from
ICO owners or ICO administrators were
actually telling the people send no no
no this is not the right address their
art address this year we change it now
they were also sending out the emails
and some other stuff so it was really
you know it was really interesting it
was like how come you know it's like
just this URL and this URL and now it
was it issue how to take this urls down
now you cannot just say take them down
well you can actually DDoS them right we
have seen yesterday's presentation so
it's quite cheap right but it's not
legal yeah kind of but no that's not
that was not that was not the way and we
also had
different Twitter accounts which were
already spitting out you know the fake
fake URLs and trying some different
scams so it was it was coming 24/7 so
when the guys from China and Russia went
to sleep then the Europeans came when
when Europeans came to bed and the
Americans came
so it was like 24/7 so it was all around
the clock and we discovered that since
we have been held in helping them that
it's the easiest and fastest way to take
down the fake side to notify the cert so
the low cursor so the low cursor it's
actually contenting the cert from iron
ore from Ukraine or from Romania from
vulgar Bulgaria and some other countries
that we're actually taking down the
sides because if you note notified the
ISP who was actually hosting that site
too so so so long it and those fake
sites were also helping attackers to
steal some kind of money well actually
in this ICO I think they only lost
around several thousand several thousand
euros so they didn't lost so much money
so several thousand euros went to some
other addresses and they didn't go to
their ICO ICO address and of course if
you had some kind of side then you have
to monitor it so are we under attack are
some kind of strange activities going on
or did some kind of loads and this is
actually it was kind of around the clock
so because a technician never stopped
now as I said some other guys from some
other parts of the world were attacking
with trying to something something to do
something new and then at the end when I
co was done and some already in they did
the Sun contract managed to get into the
second phase now they didn't have any
bug bounty program because it's really
important to have it because if you
don't say you have it or you don't have
it you will get some kind of these these
kind of emails you know I would like to
report the security vulnerability in
your web application please please let
me know and of course if you award me
it's even better so do let me know
and during the ico and afterwards we had
several of these kind of let's say
issues but the interesting point was
that although they reported some kind of
ability issues they didn't manage to
find any it was let's say low to low
medium severity during this IC o---- and
also during the platform so hopefully we
did a good job there okay but some at
the end some kind of tips advices how
should you start if you manage to get to
ICO or you're going to be the part of
the ICO or you're having a good idea to
maybe to go ICO even on the other side
at the moment you know the crypto no
it's more going down then it's going up
so we're to start I found it very good
if you want to cover all the details so
all the areas I found a really good
presentation from from from from this
URL what should you should protect so
actually definitely the endpoints
security data manipulation and also
don't forget this because now if people
are seeing a lot of money in one place
their mind might get twisted know why
because if you see several millions and
you have the private key to steal
suburbs several millions dollars euros
whatever you know you might think
different way you know you might think
how
I get that money you know and also some
other things but I think this one if you
cover all these areas you're in good way
to make a good ICO and since we are also
at the Balkan and the Balkan is running
the CTF also some companies you know and
it's really interesting that we have
seen that also this ecosystem around all
the blockchain and the smart contract
and everything is involving and some
company saw actually also the
opportunity for them because here
security innovation is actually offering
the blockchain CTF challenge so to try
to hack it to know all the all the let's
say bad stuff that might happen it's
also the point in good it's it's it's
going into the right direction with this
one in if you have some good idea like
CTF platform for support contract
probably you're in a good way to get
some to get some fun funding and some
other hints at the end if you don't have
enough dollars euros dinners whatever
don't start it because you know if you
say I don't have anything but I have
good idea your idea won't be successful
because marketing today it's everything
if you don't manage to do the proper
marketing you know even if you have a
good idea it's all off on the other hand
have enough resources another let's say
resources and also people from different
kind of areas because this if if you're
let's say going into a real narrow like
only in a blockchain and don't see the
the white angle of it you might get
problem you don't get problems be
prepared to everything I mean really
everything because the creativity of the
hackers you know there's no limits so if
you manage to to secure all they will
find a way some way somehow to make your
to make your night nightmare come true
maybe it's also this one good don't
share everything with everybody so let's
say it's I have seen here at this ICO
although we have been taking care of for
security the guys who were actually
doing the ICO so actually the
decision-makers they didn't share
anything everything so there was some
kind of details they didn't tell or some
day-to-day share with some some guys and
it might help sometimes and last but not
least I really like this principle Keith
kiss so keep it simple stupid no that's
the best way because if you're trying to
make really complex system if you're
trying to make let's say if you're
introducing complexity complexity you
will have a problem and maybe at the
last what I have learned I think this
last light actually tells everything
about the blockchain and the Bitcoin and
all the ecosystems around it because we
have seen that a lot of people are
really talking about it but it's like
sex in high school
now it's really you're you're laughing
but it's really true
because I have seen a lot of guys I have
been talking to a lot of developers
testers blockchain experts it's fine
when you're talking but when it's time
for action you know then you're
discovered that everybody's just talking
about it not practicing it so that's it
okay that's for my presentation thank
you very much
are there any questions
[Music]
so when you were contacting the
certificate authorities about the
scammer sites how did you prove that you
just saying hey that guy's a scammer you
know that site is not valid ha ha whose
authority did they take your word you
know just like anybody can say hey that
guy's a scanner the this validate his
certificate no actually they were not
having the certificate certificates at
all they were just putting in on some IP
addresses the site so they were actually
cloning site since they were okay some
contractor contact the third set okay
this is our page this is the fake page
that they are trying to steal the money
take it down or at least contact I'll do
something or block it or contact it so
actually they they were saying you know
it's the same as you were say okay this
is my page these are the scammers so but
they are not they were not using the
certificates for SSL or HTTPS or some
kind of fake address fake fake domain
names which will go with some check some
contract but probably they were using
some kind of hacked servers they were
just putting on the static HTML which
only changing the address where the
phone should be sent
okay anyone else no questions okay thank
you very much again then I hope to see
you next year
[Music]
[Applause]