[Music]
[Applause]
okay
our knifes dhaka cipher log secrets and
time say as the talk area states this is
an experimental torture session we'll
try to find out how long I have to punch
you until you give me your password of
course it's not because I'm not that
violent a person I'm actually an IT
person not a violence person I mostly
work in black I T which is IT projects
nobody wants to admit here you know no
we don't have that database no we don't
use that communication system my main
focuses covered communications and in
the last few months I have started to
not just work for corporations but for
journalists and activists and that is
actually what the talk is about so we
have problems and I had a client if
several years ago was a bank and they
had to send their people overseas for
business meetings and they had to carry
sensitive data on their machines so the
work of course encrypted now the problem
is that several countries that the went
to basically ask them to to decrypt
their laptops and if they wouldn't do
that they would be held in contempt
basically locked up until they gave up
their passwords now our current
situation is that in more and more
countries the rulings become that if you
don't decrypt you go to jail like in
Australia for example we're talking
about you can go to jail for up to ten
years in the UK I think it's five years
right now and the only way out of that
is if you can actually show that you
don't have to pass
that you forgot it or that the volume is
destroyed or whatever now this is where
the talk comes from originally now sadly
about a week ago I ran into a discussion
with our legal department which told me
you cannot actually talk about the
details of the project you did for a
client way back then so I had to
implement all the code again so bear
with me
it's not that nice anymore so what is
the issue with giving up your passwords
or proving that you don't have it
anymore we don't actually have the
ability to intentionally forget
something you know it's not like oh yeah
I learned my password and then across
the border I get asked and then I oh
sorry I forgot it right away you know
nobody believes that and it's actually
not psychologically possible without
harming yourself in some substantial way
and that actually means that you may
yourself never know the secret they're
asking for because you kind of forget it
you may not even know it and the other
thing is you shouldn't ever be in the
position that you have shared it with
anybody because there anybody then holds
your secret and can give it up now the
the lineman would probably approach the
problem like this you create a random
secret that you never learned you trade
it blindly you encrypt it to a third
party and then whenever you have to
decrypt your device again you ask the
third party for the decryption of your
secret and then you apply it and use it
now there's a problem with that and that
is you have shared your secret so
anybody could go to the third party take
the secret from them and you're forever
doomed now what you really have to do is
you have to work on Oracle's so an
Oracle is basically a device or a
software or entity that performs wisdom
for you that is where the term comes
from Greek Oracle's
you ask the things something and you get
an answer and what do you do there is
that the first step in creating a random
secret and give it to a third party to
decrypt it it's actually a decryption
Oracle is how we call it and if you hear
about trends the trusted third party
that is exactly it now
the problem is when you have done that
then anybody could after you know asking
you for the secret also go to the Oracle
and say hey I want the secret back from
you and the the real reason is that this
period of time that you have that you
can resist torture is actually
relatively short I'm not really sure how
many people here have torture experience
but it takes minutes for most people to
say you know what it you know
here's my password they're only like
these really hard ass looking people
like in the back row they're you know
they look like they can maybe stand up
for an hour you know but in reality
nobody of us is strong enough to really
protect so you have to do something that
we call time lock keys so time lock key
is a key that we can show will only work
for a certain period of time now what we
are doing now is we encrypt our random
secret that we don't know - a key that
we can show works only for a certain
time and then we use another key the
Oracle key to protect the message
against all of that and time lock keys
are something that is in a way we're
actually using that I mean most people
actually use that because time lock keys
are nothing else but Wretch's algorithms
like you find in signal for example for
perfect for security or secrecy in this
case it's an a symmetric ratchet
algorithm which means it creates a
symmetric key pairs which is contrary to
what signal does
and it basically works that you have a
start value and all of that start well
you create a sequence of key pairs you
publish the public part of those key
pairs and you assign a certain time to
them and then you go back in the ratchet
you take the original start welly and
then you go through the ratchet again
but now in real time you don't pre
generate but you follow the time and the
point with ratchets is that you can
actually throw away the state and you
cannot go back in time when the state
has been thrown away so that is what you
will have in symmetric and asymmetric
ratcheting algorithms now in practice
this looks like this you need a laptop
that you want to travel with it has a
networking partition basically an
operating system with networking on it
and you have the actual partition that
you want to be protect the secret
partition and then you need a tool that
serves as the Oracle for you now the
tool is software and hardware the
software that I'm actually releasing
today is cipher lock and cipher lock
implements all these protocols and you
can basically download it throw it on a
Raspberry Pi that you leave at home that
you put pour on and then you can use
that as an Oracle while you're traveling
now even if they force you to say hey I
want to go back I want to have this
stuff again because the ratchet keys
expire and the state is lost even you
giving up the raspberry after a while it
doesn't leak your secrets and then you
have a client program on your travelling
laptop that used to interact with your
home Raspberry Pi with cipher lock
daemon now when you're actually
travelling them then you cross the
border with your laptop it's protected
and if nobody bothers you you just go to
the hotel you unlock your device and
you're happy to go however if you're
under distress if they force you to
give up your secrets you only have to
wait and not very long it depends on
what you specifically configure but you
can configure it for like an hour or two
and after that hour and two that you
basically just have to stall the the
conversation your secrets will actually
become irrecoverable there's no way to
go back and discover your secrets again
but you can prove that your secrets were
valid once so you give up your
passphrase after an hour and the border
agent can verify that it's actually the
right path phrase but it doesn't work
anymore
now there are a few things when you use
the tool I'm going to talk about the
tool a little bit more in a second is
it's of course very stupid if you travel
you have your cipher lock device at home
and you have your SSH key to that cipher
lock device so don't put that on the
unprotected partition and the other
thing there's the tool was originally
developed to use tor as the transport
layer and you actually have to use
transport layer security or tor to
securely use it now lots of talk that is
relatively unimportant now how to use it
it's actually trivial because we re
implemented the tool to be used by
journalists which are not necessarily
unknown for being the most tech-savvy
persons on the planet so this is how you
set up a cipher lock server on your
Raspberry Pi you download the software
you just say create and it gives you an
ignitor key that you have to record and
then you switch it on by surf and that's
it everything else is automatic and then
on the client it's a little bit more
complicated
you have the cipher lock create command
which basically creates those Oracle
messages for the future and you can say
for which time frames you want to create
them you need a local passphrase that is
only for the Oracle messages that is the
passphrase that you would give up when
you're under pressure and you need a way
to deal with the secret you
a secret and you want to use the secret
now we're using shell scripting here you
can you know try it out yourself if you
want to pipe it into looks Crypt setup
whatever that is exercise for home so to
speak but it's relatively simple because
on UNIX systems you have file
descriptors that you can juggle around
and be happy with now of course there
are a few more options so we have the
create option already we had the unlock
option to unlock your secret then
there's the thing that's called extent
which basically means take a secret that
is still valid and extend its validity
for a longer time then you can say from
when to when your secret will actually
be valid and then there's like a help
which is useful you know actually don't
memorize everything and everything else
is like configuration where to store
stuff but these are actually all options
you ever need now you can actually
download all of that from the link down
there and it's written in gold which
actually allows you to run it on several
operating systems and there are pre
compiled versions if you trust them
otherwise you compile it yourself and
it's for Linux and specifically for
armed 64 which is what raspberry PI's
are using and if you're like an open BSD
guy like me that is pre compiled as well
now and that is actually the main part
of the talk everything else is practice
practice and questions so I would like
to thank you all for the attention that
you actually had and I have to do a few
shoutouts I'm legally bound to that so
I'd like to thank Frank Brown who is
actually a co-developer of cipher lock
I'd like to thank tatiana who's actually
trading the journalists and using that
and i think frank Rieger he is doing the
contacts and use cases thank you
[Applause]
any questions welcome
all right there thanks for your gonna
talk it first was very interesting I
don't have so much background in this
kind of operation so from my question
might be a little bit naive we have in
cryptography at least ways to hide
information like they're gonna graffiti
or if if you have a more applied sense
you have the TrueCrypt and hidden
volumes and here you are taking a
completely different approach in which
there's actually approved that person
maybe a journalist has had some
encrypted has a data on this device can
you reason about this oh I can say the
problem is that actually no policeman
believes you when you're a target that
you don't use encryption that's number
one so it is naive to think that as a
target banker journalist whatever you
can cross the border without them
expecting you to have protection
there's someone number two is when they
look at your systems today and that
happens on all majors Boris today is
they have devices that they plug into
your device that the forensic analysis
so that means they look for tools that
are installed they look for how your I
note are used on your computer they look
when you have an SSD for example they
look at the caching refresh rates of
certain cells and there is something
they do totally automatically there are
several companies that sell those tools
and that actually means that you cannot
hide from them that you're using
cryptography and you cannot hide from
them even that you're using hidden
volumes in reality it breaks down to
they will just claim that you're using a
hidden volume when you're using
veracrypt or to hit or whatever and they
hold you so long that sooner or later
you give it up that's it you know
there's the reality is actually
that you cannot hide and when it comes
to steganography
for example that simply only works for
very small messages and even there we
have statistical artifacts that can be
relatively easily detected with most
tools so if you're a target don't trust
it that's it it's really better to to
play open cards and to say yeah I am
protected but I cannot actually help you
anymore you know then the the playing
field is clear and you're easier to make
a legal case sexually because otherwise
they'll just claim hey you're hiding
stuff from us and before you don't give
it up you know you go to jail
keep i I have a question regarding this
time expiring keys so basically if we go
through the use case that you have set
up the Raspberry Pi set up at home you
have your laptop with an encrypted drive
and with this time expiring lock and so
let's say that the expiry period is one
hour does that mean that your laptop
needs to be in constant connection with
the Raspberry Pi box in order to help
say keep the adeno key from not expiring
course usually that exactly say
basically the the timing enforcement is
done on the Raspberry Pi its remote you
cannot touch it anymore you can only
talk to it with the protocol mm-hmm so
and what you have on your machine is
basically pre-configured and pre
encrypted messages to that device and
you decrypt those messages and sent them
to the device which serves as an oracle
and says that sends back the answer and
that only works while the keys have an
expired yet so it depends on what you
set as the update time so how long is a
single key ballot that's number one and
number two is what you configure so that
is basically your the granularity of the
system is the lifetime of the keys but
there's an infinite number of those keys
that are created by the selfie lock and
it is your client that where you can
configure okay I want a certain time
span in which I want to use that and
that can be much lower larger than the
key value but it can also be shorter
it's just not less secure when it's
shorter but you can set it a lot to
longer as well and that time frame is
the timeframe in which you have to
communicate back to the device hence you
need two partitions basically you need a
networking partition that allows you to
connect to the internet and you have the
secured partition which you decrypt
after you contacted the cipher lock
daemon yeah and so just to add up to
this question so for example if you're
being stopped at boarding crossing so
basically you need to disable your PC
before you actually got how to say
before we got questions because
otherwise it will continue sinking no no
it's not sinking automatically so before
you're going to the border you basically
run the command and say okay it probably
takes like two hours until I'm through
the border and I give it another two
hours security window you know if I lose
my way or whatever so you basically set
the cipher lock device to be able to be
enabled for the next four hours
oh okay and then you have four hours to
disable it again afterwards your secrets
will be oh okay okay I get it thanks hi
I was the one question you were talking
now about keeping the secret secret yeah
but the content or on your drive is
encrypted in some program and it's not
affected by this product actually now so
nobody stops customers - or police or
government to decrypt those files files
content Oh try em all right well the the
thing is really that you have two
different uses for cryptography here so
one thing is your full disk encryption
or partition encryption the other thing
is where does that encryption have the
key from and it's the first thing that
usually is like a password that you put
it in our case we replace that with the
cipher lock so it basically allows you
to say okay here my decrypt scripts you
know you can look at the device how its
setup you know and you cannot decrypt
the decryption key anymore that is your
proof so it's two levels of security we
don't we don't do this encryption we
just protect the disk encryption key
okay thank you
yoky it's me again listen I there are
not so many Christians here remember
that is actually why I rushed through
talk so there's one okay okay so at
first you're trying to prove that you're
unable to decrypt your data which brings
us my dears in my mind let's say how do
you prove that there are no other copies
of your data I mean if you have a
Raspberry Pi at home yeah and you can
contact it over tor then you're somewhat
reasonable to assume that you were able
to copy compromising pictures of
whatsoever on that Raspberry Pi okay let
me go through that slide again that is
that slide yeah but you have to prove it
no you know this is not proof that you
cannot access your Raspberry Pi using a
password no the the thing is this the
only thing that the border people have
at that moment is your device and you
have to create a reasonable explanation
why you cannot decrypt it anymore
to stay out of jail so on your device
you shouldn't have the key to be able to
connect to your Raspberry Pi
if that is on there you do because they
will find it yeah but the initial thing
what's that you're unable to forget a
password
so what's how many keys have you've
memorized oh it really depends on the
key size I mean one or two it's probably
fair if it's elliptic curve key yeah so
how can I prove that I don't have the
key in my mind well it's the maybe we
have to go to how law actually works and
how police actually works okay so police
doesn't come there with hypotheticals
like maybe you're super smart
maybe you memorize all your passwords
whatever but what they go by is what
they find on your device because then
evidence and they go by their experience
so if we have this case that hundreds of
people get stopped that have their full
SSH keys memorized then your argument
might become true because then it
becomes their experience but I'm pretty
sure that they have never encountered
anybody where they could show hey you
have memorized your SSH key so in
reality what you're doing is you're
making a case you know this tool helps
you to make a case in a secure manner
and it says okay this is this practice
that we use we have this certain best
practices and if we would do anything
else we wouldn't have to use the key and
Eddie tool in the first place and that
is how you stay out of jail and yeah two
other questions the first is has it
worked in practice yeah do we have
experience okay and the next one do a
plan to to audit yours is source code or
has it been audited already well as I
said in the beginning I have this little
issue that I was not allowed to release
the original source code because our
client from back then didn't want it and
they paid for it and they kind of had
control over it so I have to
re-implement it as again you can
actually look at this at the code
yourself and there is actually a
commercial version that is audited but
this is the open source version if you
want to audit it go have please okay
assuming you're stopped and detained and
have all your devices taken away and
you're stuck in a room where it's
impossible to tell the passage of time
how do you know when you can actually
give up the nonworking yet you shouldn't
take too long of a time span for that
use case we're relatively good in
counting hours we really suck in
counting days so don't make it too long
you know make a realistic time duration
that's number one number two is in most
cases you have your recourse - it
depends on the country of course but yet
recourse to legal counsel and one of the
questions you are allowed to ask is what
time is it allowed to about in practice
I'm not so sure about that but either
okay let's say you ask for their time
and they take this as a hint that you're
waiting for something or hiding
something they could hit you with an
obstruction charge for example yeah say
that is why I said the thing you have to
do is use realistic time friends don't
use days on it you know if you know it
takes whatever an hour or two to cross
the border then just make it four hours
until you have to decrypt you know and
you can do that in reality and that is
what most of our clients do they enable
that on the on the airplane so when they
land they open their laptops they
activate cipher lock because you don't
need a network connection for the
activation you only need it for for
unlocking it so you just you know when
you land you pull off your laptop you
say okay in the next hour I want to
decrypt otherwise destroy and we were
pretty good in counting hours and their
processes actually take along okay I
won't keep poking holes in this but they
could just grab you on the flight and
you'll never open your laptop of course
and the thing is if you fly the or when
you have the strap model or the the
threat hanging over you you have to have
threat modeling you know I mean that is
that is the practice so if your enemy is
the
let's take a random example the US
government for example and you fly there
with the US airline yeah they can
capture you as soon as the doors closed
in Serbia you know if you're flying with
a Swiss airline then they cannot capture
you before the doors open in the US so
you have to be conscious of your threat
model and that is true for for all
security tools if you're looking for a
silver bullet you're going to die thanks
well I was wondering we solve the same
problem in a more simple manner for
example what if I tell the police that I
don't have a key and my friend is going
to cross the border or send a key over
the secure Channel when I tell him that
I say if it was the border yeah there is
actually the thing where we tried it out
in reality it requires that you have
those best friend their travels it
requires you to actually have somebody
at home that you can call whatever so
this works for single people under their
own control
you don't need an organization whatever
so it's it's a practical means to do it
and it's a means that it's relatively
good against committing operation of
security errors so the the whole I call
home and please give me the passphrase
to decrypt my PGP key which holds
whatever and so on and so on it's
something that might maybe work for a
few tech people that have good friends
in reality in a company environment or
for journalists that is actually
problematic they're looking for the the
easiest use case possible with the least
offensive
so I've been asking questions because of
the backups talked yesterday as well and
Here I am I
I see a new hammer that can hammer my
nails I'm looking for a system that can
auto expire backups that shouldn't be
there anymore so you use a key to
basically encrypt the whole thing and
you expire things I just ran the tool it
seems to only support one active cipher
lock yeah you can have multiple that is
what the the server hard is for that is
four different directory service you can
have instead of just having one
Raspberry Pi at one location you can
have ten raspberry PI's in ten locations
and use them to protect the same secret
and they have this path thing which is
basically telling you where the data
goes and if you take a different path
you have a difference I feel perfect and
it also has source code so that already
means that this is a great hammer for my
nail great thank you you're welcome
actually I never thought about that
sorry so it was it just one we're super
they're a very realistic question what
happens if your raspberry pi is down
your ADSL at home is yeah that is
basically what I mentioned right there
is you can have multiple cypher locks
that protect the same secret so you have
one raspberry at home one at your
company and one at your girlfriend or
whatever and that's okay thank you does
anyone else have a question
[Applause]
[Music]