[Music]
[Applause]
so next up we have what any college with
writing the wife thank you very much so
hello everybody I like to see a lot of
people it's interesting
probably that people are still drinking
rocky up from last night
so I hope soon they will show up and as
soon as they are a can there will be fun
for them because in the end you will
have big beep which will make them for
sure so what are we going to discuss
today a lot of stuff
we are going to make this like
introduction to SDR software-defined
radio which we use a lot during the IOT
work so we are going to show you a
little bit of theory and a little bit of
practice and I hope in the end we don't
have enough time to do a little bit of
demo to demonstrate how it actually is
used in real life so a few words about
me I'm leading the IBM x-force led
European team our team exists under this
name for more than two years but a lot
longer than that
without the proper name so we were part
of IBM for 10 years doing a lot of stuff
my personal expertise is electronics
embedded IOT and SCADA stuff and I like
to hug vehicles and also we are doing
SCADA stuff which also use a lot of
radius so that is interesting when you
capture stuff on the long pipelines that
nobody expected that you can do so we'll
start with shortest history of radio
because it is fun and I believe that you
already saw those guys in the hallway
does that when you enter the premises on
the right side there is a radio Club
from the angle index showing all the old
equipment of radio and they were having
some demonstration last night
so who invented radio
so actually radio waves exist since the
Big Bang
so first Big Bang generated
electromagnetic waves but we as the
humans are unable to detect those waves
except in some small short range which
we called light other than that we are
not aware of existence of right there
waves because we don't have sense that
can detect it so first knowledge
actually first idea of radio waves came
in 1860 some years by the work of
Maxwell and his four equations of
electromagnetism actually predicted
possibility of electromagnetic waves and
German Heinrich Hertz is the first one
who actually demonstrated the
electromagnetic wave in a nature after
that was almost 20 years after the
Maxell predicted them after that we will
wait a few years before our beloved
Nikola Tesla actually created first use
for this radio waves by creating first
radio controlled device or receiver and
transmitter which were used to control
these boats here which he demonstrated
in u.s. in almost eighteen ninety eight
or nine so at the end of the century so
this was the actual first use of
electromagnetic waves to control and to
communicate Tesla had one
he was genius but he had one issue here
he didn't believe that electromagnetic
waves can be used for long-range
communication he believed that they are
limited just to line-of-sight
so he was born thinking about how he can
transfer power we are electromagnetic
waves but not communication so the guy
who came after him Marconi is the one
who actually saw this possibility and he
was the one who made the first
transmission of radio waves over the
ocean and later he had granted patents
but unfortunately in 43 his patents were
invalidated because they are proved
nothing new
everything was based on previous work of
Tesla and Maxwell and Hertz and other
scientists who were doing research on
the electromagnetic wave of that time so
we are now going into new century and as
a human species is unbelievable species
so our progress comes from our wish to
destroy as much suffer of rest of our
species as possible so the wars and
military are usually derived the
progress so and world world war was the
beginning and century so first use of
radio waves are there but problem is
radio waves they were not very useful
why
first thing radio devices of that time
were really big and unreliable so it was
not possible to use it on the front
lines they were breaking they were big
and heavy to transport and the problem
is cryptography at the time was not on
top so if it was easy to communicate
with guys you want to communicate but
everybody else was also able to capture
your communications so we needed to wait
a little bit more of cryptography
developments for radio to become really
really useful as we see it today so this
this it was used during the World War
one it was used mostly to as a remote
control for torpedoes and we have
demonstrated there was demonstration
about American ship which was
radio-controlled completely and who
could target other vehicles in other
ships actually so after 20 years we have
Second World War when we already have
radio in almost every every home and it
was used mostly in propaganda purposes
during the World War two but we already
see that the Germans actually did a lot
in development of right radio waves
technology because they wanted their
airplanes and missiles to be very
effective so they developed a lot of
radio technology that we are seeing even
today and during the 1941 I believe one
of the big discovery was made
in u.s. and then actually by one German
who was in u.s. at the time and who
enabled our use of Wi-Fi today anybody
have idea who invented what those yeah
but this is unfair okay
so Heather Lamar she was a actress in
Europe before the war and 1938 I believe
she ran from the war to Germany to from
to us and she wanted to make these
missiles more controllable and to make
it more resilient to tampering and
overheating so she she had an idea based
on all the piano which was doing
automatic stuff and she used the help
from a guy who actually made pianos to
create first frequency hoping the
technology in which receiver and
transmitter would simultaneously hopped
through different channels and to make
any Eva's dropping and more difficult
and this is technology that we are using
today in our wireless techniques so to
jump from channel to channel so it
enabled all of us here to be connected
to the same wireless spectrum and at the
same time after the world wars we saw a
miniaturization and appearance of solid
devices like tubes and the transistors
and integrated circuits and that made
use of radio waves in our everyday life
so I kept here few pictures taken from
these guys in the hallway and this is a
big receiver I don't know if you can see
that cubes are actually blowing so it is
receiving at this moment so it is very
interesting piece of equipment and this
is developed somewhere in 50s I believe
if I recall correctly but as we see
usage of radio is expanding and I
believe in this moment everybody if you
have at least three radios on you so you
have Bluetooth radio you have GSM radio
and you have virus
in your phone so three different radius
and what is the problem so if you want
to hack that stuff using these salt
technology it was really difficult to do
first because on high frequencies every
absolutely everything is antenna so even
your soldier joints can be antenna so it
is easy to calculation and to have a lot
of problems everywhere and to have low
quality of of receiving the emanations
and that would make it very difficult to
actually analyze the content of what is
transferred over the waves
so in order to help us with this we
needed a little bit of progress so hard
there was not enough first idea was ok
let us put all these different receivers
into one box and then to use a software
to decide which box is active so which
function is active so we have two
software controlled radios at this point
when you control amplitude modulation
frequency modulation software can choose
and activate harder for it but have
their head to exist to be able to use it
we can switch frequencies through
software Eakins switch gain we can
control filters but it is all
implemented in hardware and software is
just providing control and selection so
it is not still you need to develop
hardware so this is what caused the
first appearance of software-defined
radio during the 80s there was a lot of
research in this area again military was
leading this because it was not very
easy to have a lot of different
equipment on the front lines so it is
easier if you can go with the small
devices and the idea behind this is we
will have radio which all definition all
functions will be implemented and since
software and hardware will only be there
to transmit and receive this information
in 2010
we gained the first trip and usable as
they are so before that only military
had access to this technology because it
was really expensive
in 2010 kernel developer called Erik
Frey was trying to create a driver for
Linux for these small DVD sticks that he
had and he had a problem with them and
in order to analyze what is happening he
started the debugging them and when the
bugging on Windows machine he saw that
if you put this chip in the debugging
mode IQ parameters will be transferred
directly to your computer via USB and we
got first ship RTL dongles which are now
everywhere so how is this like what is
this IQ parameters that are sensible
first it is to every wave can be sampled
into two time more than frequency to
gain the amplitude and frequency of the
signal so that sanitarium for selecting
but if we do it a little bit differently
thanks to this small map here which is
simple we will say that every phase
modulated signal can be represented by
two components which are 90 degrees of
the phase which called quadrature so if
we sample the signal in 90 degrees with
two SEM two samples which are 90 degrees
in phase we will be able to reconstruct
this signal it is not exactly hundred
percent sure correct when you have
amplitude modulation in addition to in
addition to frequency phase modulation
but it is close enough for all practical
purpose so this is why we call it
narrowband signal so for what it is it
is okay for narrowband signals in which
modulated frequency is much lower than
actual carrier frequency so thank to
this map we have two components inq eyes
in phase component and Q's quadrature
component which is 90 degrees move and
this enable us to reconstruct every
possible signal in our software model in
algorithms so this is what actually make
they are possible this simple math so
thanks to this we now have a lot of
different devices which can which can
actually which can actually be used to
transmit and receive radios so we have I
believe for 10 dollars you can order
from your favorite Chinese supplier
delivered and problem with these devices
is they are listen-only so they can
receive signals but you will not be able
to inject signals back it is easy to
overcome if you have Raspberry Pi by a
distant of small wires to port GPO 18
which is PBM harder PBM you can make
Raspberry Pi to actually inject
electromagnetic waves back so by
combining this with the very very cheap
device which you can already you can
actually data space so this is very
common used for sniffing replay attacks
so you will saw later that if you have a
club for example for car some of them
are not implemented properly so if
you're just listening to write frequency
you can capture the signal to unlock the
car save it and then play it later so
you can capture additional play with
your Raspberry Pi with just additional
wire and if you'll unlock so receiving
only is fun but obviously we we want to
have ability to also inject signals
thanks to thanks to Mike who develop
hacker f1 we actually have a cheap
relatively cheap device I have one here
it is very cheap very small I have it
always with me because it is relief
non-intrusive and it's very useful
because it can also receive and transmit
but not at the same time so that is the
only limitation of this device it cannot
do it at the same time so it is helped
to put device but it has everything that
you need in it
and if you really need full-duplex and
we will saw why we need fooled objects
Duplessis devices later
there are blade f RF ettus or a lot of
new devices that are currently being
developed that you can actually use to
to to accomplish both receive and
transmit functions at the same time so I
do see these box is really small it fits
it on my bag and I never have problems
on customs I have problem if I try to
put this but no problem with this and
this I can never take the airplane
actually with this I can just drink it
or spit water on you whatever so this is
our perception of risk that's the
problem I have here a large picture of
hack RF because I really want to go
through how this actually works because
it is really important to understand how
it works in order to be able to use it
effectively as any tool you need to be
aware of its limitations in order to
understand what you actually are getting
if it is problem with the tool or it is
problem with the processor it is on
something else so now you are going to
see how antenna can be really really
useful even if it
we are not transmitting or receiving
anything because it can be extended
almost 1 meter and I can show or 2 BQ if
I need if I really need ok so here this
okay okay so you have to be really loud
let me try this fine
where is the laser but how can I beat
people with laser no I don't see lasers
so I will use liquid is this always or
not need batteries and I talked loud if
you cannot hear me just yell and I will
repeat so first we have antenna
connector from this village this is
connected there and it injects a switch
our new technology this is more fun
I cannot beat you with this so let me
see which button did is then thank you
don't forget to pick it up so you can
tell a connector
I need my okay so let me try to
synchronize I'm still thinking about my
antenna okay so yeah
can you hear me now yes excellent so we
have antenna and we have a few passive
devices here which are just use to
condition the signal that we are
receiving from antenna we know you know
that antenna must be matched to
impendence of the of the inputs
amplifiers in order to avoid problems
and then we have first step in our
process which is this piece of harder
here this is all actually RF module and
it process a radiofrequency one so
signal comes to this local oscillator
and this it is down mixed to two point
two to 2.7 gigahertz so whatever
frequency we are capturing here it will
be shifted to this range two point two
to 2.7 gigahertz and then after that it
will be processed by this bed bug in a
baseband transceiver which will actually
pick up the signal due amplification
filtering and whatever needs to be done
and move it from this intermediate
frequency to base but frequency based on
frequency is close to zero so it is
actually from zero to whatever number of
samples per second can this device get
up here give and this device is actually
quadrature ADC and DAC so when your
signal comes in it goes here here here
and then comes here in analog mode this
device here will convert your signal
into I and Q parameters very quickly and
provide it to the bus this device here
is a big
dialing selfie da which is actually
doing acquiring so it is really quick
and it is used to synchronize all
communication between computer which is
connected to USB port here and the radio
receiver here so this is main device use
it for control this is glue logic
between the analog world and digital
world and if you big arm core here which
controls the complete process and
provides USB communication to the
computer so we have radio frequency
signal here and it enters it enters
there and exits here as I had Q
parameter strands transferred over us
before so when we are doing sampling we
are pretty much limited by speed of USB
port so in this cases we have USB 2 that
is about 20 21 mega samples per second
and all although this device here can
provide a little bit more this is
practical limit so you will never be
able to do more than 21 mega samples per
second even in a ideal condition so we
are saying 20 mega samples per second is
what is expected so that gives us 20
megahertz of bandwidth that we can scan
and then we are going the other way so
when we are producing the signal we are
going to inject our NQ parts here it
will be processed transferred converted
to analog converted to to irate your
intermediate frequency and then this
chip will be putting it into the
expected frequency and send it to
antenna what is the problem so when we
are receiving stuff it's not really
problem V if our antenna is not matched
properly to our radio
parameters it will create bad reception
but that's it usually only problem is if
you have to strong signal here we might
make some damage in this part here but
when we are transmitting and if we turn
on gain we can actually do a lot of
damage because antenna must be better
matched to avoid having power reflecting
back into the RF circuit so we need to
be a little bit careful especially when
we are doing sniffing if you are too
close we can actually fry our circuit so
avoid setting
in the beginning if you don't have to so
keep the game to the lowest limit
possible and there is other problem a
bit game is that usually we are not
licensed to transmit on specific
frequencies later we will go through
some of the frequencies and you will see
that we are allowed to transmit only on
27 megahertz which is called citizen
band and everybody is allowed to
transmit without license all other are
usually really heavily regulated and
you're not allowed to transmit without
proper shielding and minimal to avoid
any interference with a real devices out
there okay is there any question about
this part so far you're sleeping okay no
nobody need to be bitten okay excellent
okay so now we have our harder developed
working and now we need a little bit of
software because our radio is all
defined in software at this point so in
order to make it work we need a piece of
software so the one most that is most
commonly used and most versatile is
actually the GNU radio companion which
is available I believe in on almost
every a little distribution that I have
seen so far and it is actually a very
great tool because it enables you to do
development like Lego so you will just
pick up your boxes and put the boxes on
the screen connect those boxes and you
will have resolved okay you need to know
which boxes and how do you they are
going to connect them but that's another
story so I have here shown the most the
simplest possible script which have just
one source which is my Rea SDR and one
sync which is this waterfall plot and
this is actually showing the most
interesting part of the spectrum this is
for three three megahertz where we have
a lot of IOT devices communicating and
we see in this waterfall plot we can see
that the higher the power the color is
upper so with green it is somewhere in
the middle if it is red we can
very strong strong transmitter so by if
we don't know where is our device we can
just scan the spectrum and discover it
by checking the power and we are devices
on and off and to make this process more
efficient
we need to called spectrum analyzer
spectrum analyzer is the tool that which
will scan the range of frequencies for
you and map the power of the receiving
signal in time so in this there is a
tool called your spectrum analyzer of
course it supports hack RF since the
recent reasons that took almost two
years actually and I Baqir scanning the
full range that is possible with this
device that is up to 6 gigahertz and we
can see few red stripes in a lot of blue
so I don't know if it is easy to see in
this area here we have tiny speckles of
red any idea what is here
Wi-Fi yes we have this large large piece
here in about five point one gigahertz
that we have something here in two point
point one what is that
dreary yeah we have mobile telephony in
a lot of places we have it in 850 to 290
we have it 2.1 gigahertz depending on in
which country you are so and you can
also see that lower frequencies are full
with different communications and there
is a lot of red so I pull up here this
is I think up to hundred yep
two hundred two hundred megahertz and
we'll see it over the end of that we
have a lot of transmitters which are
very strong and that would be FM
stations and this e-bill beyond that we
have a lot of stuff in a lot of
frequencies 37 megahertz that is a
bandwidth that you can use to transmit
freely you can find the radiometers in a
lot of the 20 meters 60 meters 10 mega
10 meters bands where radiometer ham
radio operators are using to transmit
and receive so we have a lot of spectrum
and sometimes if we don't know what our
device is working we need to do the scan
and to find where the device is actually
generating electromagnetic waves in
which spot in which band there are tools
which can help with decoding so if you
manage to capture your electromagnetic
waves you need to be able to analyze
them and to collect information which is
actually transmitted over those ways I
may here you can see this is different
FM stations and this tool is called huge
q g QR x and it can automatically do
some decoding for you amplitude
modulation frequency modulation
Telegraph so a lot of stuff can be
decoded by these two automatically so
you just put this position your filter
select frequency and you can hear you
can hear the D radius so we will can you
turn on the microphone so I have
I have stuff ready here so I know the
frequencies so we can see here that we
have right microphone is turned on and
it is receiving
test one two three okay now now I will
start the coding test testing one two
three
okay it's two two two two two quiets to
quiet my laptop is too quiet generating
what it's never mind okay
but you can see how when she is talking
we see a lot of shifting so this means
that it is some kind of frequency
modulation probably fm and now he is
silent and we are on base frequency so
it is relatively easy to analyze what
you are getting but unfortunately these
two laptop is too quiet to show you this
in real
you can well this can be a lot of stuff
so you sometimes have different
transmitters and receivers in the same
range so we can also capture that one
does position the cursor to frequency of
death device
why I'm not going to move
with me see I lost it when use it is
some side Bend of the microphone so when
she turned off the microphone she
disappeared so it was some reflection
summer so that is the problem with radio
waves they have a reflection they have
different channels everywhere so
something that was the SDR shot it's
windows tool because on this machine I
have only windows unfortunately and
these devices are not working really
great with virtual machines because you
need high-speed USB and if you are doing
anything serious don't use virtual
machines
it's useless okay so you can listen
actually to a lot of different stuff by
this aisle I have few guys in my near
mic home and they are really funny and
they talk to each other almost it today
and then I whenever I'm bored I just
tuned to their frequency and I laugh
because they are crazy on Dave I'm not
sure if they are aware that anybody else
is listening to them but they're crazy
there are a lot of different software so
when you capture your sometimes need to
do the codes of of your signals there
are some tools which will help you run
the tile like the best is in spectrum so
when you have this is some frequency
modulated signal we have two frequencies
and devices on then off and on so this
can be something like low key so on-off
keying
when you press the button you have one
frequency and then you only release
button there is not nothing or something
like I saw this device you can easily
analyze the spectrum and you can
actually decode by positioning the
cursor and providing some additional
information you can actually get the
signal reconstructed you can also do the
same with low soft radio so everything
with your signature can be done the use
of the radio but problem is in new
software radio you really need to know
what you are doing so but it is really
versatile and you can create decoders
for absolutely everything after you
become aware what
the holding there is a bold line which
is very good for analyzing the spectrum
so when you capture some spectrum and
you want to discern if it is specific
kind of specific kind of encoding so it
is project furniture or or be face key
shift or whatever this is a tool that
can help you grade and one of my
favorite it is ultimate radio hacker
let's tool will do everything for you
automatically for the for protocol that
it supports and it supports a lot of
protocols so we can and this tool you
can actually do a fuzzing of the radio
waves so it supports fuzzing so that
that's something that I find really
interesting in our normal work so now we
have hardware we have software and we
have an idea of device that we want to
access but where are we going to start
if you were here before we started
presentation you might overhear my
conversation with those guys when I was
asking them which frequency your
microphone is emitting and hit on the
Ossetian filter part because at this
moment I cannot retrieve this
information but usually if device has
FCC ID on it it is possible that FCC has
documentation on it FCC mandates that
every device it emits any kind of
electromagnetic waves must be certified
and in order to get this certification
you need to provide a lot of information
about your device including pictures of
the board's electromagnetic spectrum you
need to specify which protocols are used
how you are encoding information and you
can find a lot of information and the
best part is you can find this
information even before devices on the
market because device will get certified
before it enters the market so if you
plan to test any device you can discover
this information and be ready
so when device is on the market you can
be really quick to discover problems
which sometimes you will discover
problems even before you have device
they just reading documentation and
probably the FCC site it is really
difficult to navigate it is nightmare so
there is a guy
created FCC I outside which actually has
only search box that you can use for
searching and it will provide you is if
you go for you on the FCC side search
for information and provide you direct
direct links so you can just click on
link and get get your reading stuff but
there is a lot to read but it is
necessary because it will help you
tremendously to lower the time you need
for analyzes of off of the device okay
so when I said that my stuff first thing
that I like to do is actually to follow
the planes and my kids like because my
home is near to landing strip on the
boundary the airport actually it is an
approach so we have our planes on no
more than two kilometers above us and
dial s signal goes dust across our
building so it is very common for us to
hear airplanes and people what is this
plane what is this plane and sometimes
if I have time I just put my Hawk RF
from the window and I set up everything
I need to spot the planes why it is
possible first thing planes have a lot
of radius in them I already mentioned
ILS ILS is instrument landing system it
is used to help to help airplanes land
on the runway so it is guidance if he
has two radios go into the details too
much so it has ILS it has the word so
for there is possibility for airplanes
even before there was GPS they had to
navigate so there was a system of radio
transmitters over the planet Earth which
are known frequency and you can have
find them in wraps and maps and you can
use them to navigate so there is a radio
in airplane which receives this
navigational data and of course we have
GPS but this a DSP system is mandatory
on all new airplanes and it is giving
the position and callsign and a few bit
of details about the plane as it flights
and control towers using this
information as a secondary source of
information in addition to primary radar
there are some talks the
the some of the control aerial control
will change this and instead of using
your radar as a primary they might
switch to ideas be as a primary source
of information however dangerous it is
because it signal is that very easily
found that 10 and 90 megahertz
it is both position motive modulations
or just position of pulse you decide if
it is 0 or 1 it is not a cryptid and the
code is very fairly easily and there is
a lot of information I'm not aware I
know the guy created injector for this
but he is dipping this code private but
it is not too much too difficult to
develop and imagine that fun if you make
you start injecting ideas signals back
into their space how fun it would be
we spoke with error control and they
told us that it should not be possible
because they say so they never got into
details how they are preventing this but
they said it is impossible it is illegal
and why you are asking that are you
criminal or something so it is simple
thing I have here capture and you sir
have you if you see because this is
unlucky unlikely choice of colors but
this is you will see there is a big
yellow line and streaks as we have
pulses so it is really easy to spot and
to analyze this information I have here
as an example decoding block in GRC and
there is a standalone tool dump 1090 you
could see this tool running on the stand
there last night they were tracking some
planes and they have big antennas
somewhere on the roof and they have a
lot of planes I have here only few but I
didn't have much time to capture them so
you can see different of information we
here we have a velocity of the plane
altitude position call sign so we can
map it on the map and you know exact
position of the plane
and problem is that there are some other
radius in the in the airplane which are
using this information also there is a
so-called traffic collision avoidance
system in in every big airplane which is
using this data in order to verify a
current situation in a nearby vicinity
of the plane and to try to prevent
crashes so two planes to avoid crashing
so there is automated systems which will
trigger alarm and take action based on
this information so if you go back to
injecting this information if we add
that in this into the picture it might
be really dangerous to be able to inject
this information then we have a KERS
system which is all the version of a DSP
because not all planes are new planes so
we have a lot of especially amateur
planes like Tesla's like coutras here
which do not have this system they have
all the acres it is a simpler version of
a DSP and it is also easy to decode and
track it is amplitude modified signal
modulated signal and it uses one thirty
one point five megahertz for
communication
okay so those you still there yes euro
in my presentation yesterday yeah
so for a project that we were doing we
had a device to test the IOT device
which is used to transmit among other
stuff also location of device in order
to control the target so the idea is to
enforce geofencing like on dogs for
example so when you want to know where
is your dog and to know if your dog ran
out of your yard so you can put him on
collar small device and you can also set
in the application of perimeter when he
is allowed to go and as soon as device
leave this perimeter you will get alarm
that your dog run away or even in some
sadistic cases you can shot the animal
all of it is used for training of the
indigenous animals not on dogs I hope so
it was I needed to verify a lot of stuff
a lot of stuff was related to radio
devices and among one it was GPS we did
this summer in 2015 and 16 so we didn't
have a lot of information and
unfortunately the tool that we have now
was not mature actually we didn't know
even existed in at that time so we
needed to analyze GPS system and to
analyze and to understand it in order to
create tools that we needed at the time
to spoof the position so all these
pictures are generated in the last few
days they are not but the idea about GPS
system is that by knowing your position
of a few stationary locations and by
knowing your exact distance from these
stationary locations you can triangulate
your own position in this case we have
34 satellites which are currently
deployed although I believe 30 or 31 is
actually needed and wrested spares in
case of malfunctions or needed
do some maintenance on them you can just
move one other satellite in place of the
one that needs to be worked on and you
need actually to see only four of them
to get precise lock on your position but
as everything the more you have the
better precision you have and in order
to have the structural satellites are
not stationary they are going circling
around the planet and we are moving
around the planet so in order to know
exact location of the satellites when
our receivers need to have this data so
this is called Almanac and it is created
devices downloading them our phones can
use violence to download almanacs from
from providers so that is when you have
assisted GPS so you don't receive this
information directly from satellites but
receiving them from providers and you
need to have precise time measurements
so this this is what is needed so when
you have we will see later on section so
we need to have this information to be
able to locate every GPS satellite emits
two signals one is for public use so
this is the one that we are using and
there is another one which is for
military use only and it has protected
access so GPS signals are emitted on two
frequencies one five seven five point
four two megahertz and one to two 7.16
megahertz and we have CA code it is
course acquisition code it is the first
signal that your device will capture
from the satellite and it will provide
ability to locate other satellites so
during this code you will be receiving a
family's table for this specific
satellite a Domenic for all others so it
will give once at every satellites know
where are the others so they will
transmit this information to your device
and it takes about one point five two
minutes to transmit this information to
your GPS receiver so this is why when
you turn on GPS it will not locate
instantly but it will first need to
verify time on our multiple satellites
because we
not have atomic clocks in this otherwise
this would cost probably hundred
thousand euros not thousand euros so we
have only simple crystal clocks in this
and on satellites there are real atomic
very expensive clocks which are very
precise and by using some communication
tricks this device will synchronize to
that clock and have exact time and after
acquisition of satellite communication
it will download a family stable of that
and you know location of other
satellites if you quickly connect other
satellites take it family's tables which
are precise so Alban act is just rough
ephemeris tables for specific satellite
is very precise if you collect all this
information and after five minutes as we
saw yesterday you device will have full
lock and no it exact position so so by
spoofing this satellite signal we can
make device believe whatever we want as
all sold you yesterday it was easy to
spoof signal and to convince drone to
land because it thinks it is somewhere
very far away so we did something
similar but we were sitting in UK and we
convinced device that it is actually in
Egypt in Cairo so it was very funny
because when we did this I had my phone
turned off but my colleague who was
unlucky didn't do it because he had
iPhone and he couldn't disabled location
service and he was locked on the Egypt
and problem was it after this we needed
to go back about hundred kilometers to
have a meeting with the customer so idea
was ok we will sit in the car and go and
he started to navigate and his
navigation is still locked to Cairo
ok we have a problem ok he knows first
half of the of the way so we are ok let
us start unfortunately I didn't have
GPRS because I was in roaming and I
couldn't use my navigation so
we were in a bit of trouble but in about
half an hour his device recovered
managed to download proper ephemeris
tables and synchronize clocks and
everything and we managed to navigate
second part of the of the road without
problems
we did we did our meeting we heard
everything he came home and about 10:00
p.m. he called me why my why my rather
say it is 30 degrees and it is November
in Portsmouth it is minus 1 degree
outside sorry a lot happen
so it is really it can be really funny
and this is actual real log from device
after we came up so you see that it was
November it was minus 1 outside and
device device was handled per sensor it
is summer outside of Cairo so as a
consequence this is actually a picture
of weather that my friend had on his
phone at the time so you can see that we
have changed our position from I think
something to something else
yeah visors perfect this the position
what we also notice is that time is
little bit different than we expected it
to be so this is the picture I took
yesterday while helping those prepared
demo so it was 1705 but GPS time saying
it is three minutes after the midnight
and yesterday was 15
not 14th so for all practical purposes
if I allowed my device to synchronize
time to GPS time not to DSM cell I would
have completely wrong time on my phone
and imagine some financial institutions
are using actually NTP servers in their
infrastructure to synchronize the time
because there are regulations we say
that banks or all other financial
institutions must have precise time of
transaction up to hundred milliseconds
and they are using NTP servers which are
connected to GPS receivers very common
so GPS receiver provides authoritative
time for financial institution so if we
generate this signal near their antennas
it will be funneled so I didn't find
Bank which will allow me to test this
yet but I work on this and hope that I
will have a little bit more information
for a few years if when I when I'm out
of jail
[Applause]
there are some stuff that you can do to
prevent this kind of stuff by monitoring
your device and don't allowed and an
expected jumps so if your device is one
minute enforceable the next minute in
Cairo there is some error in the system
so you need to be a little bit more
resilient to this also this device has
other sensors which can help prevent
this so we will discuss them in the next
step so we learn not to trust GPS but we
usually don't think a lot about our
phone so our phones are trusted devices
if we put all our secrets on it our
financial financial stuff we could use
it for online intersection we have
payment information we have our health
related information we can route scans
of documents a lot of stuff we keep in
our phones but how it is secured so
problem here is not very good that's the
problem so we will not be talking about
half device applications are developed
that is for up web application guys so
we are going to speak about
communications so this device that I
mention has GPS and also have GPRS
communication so in order to provide
information that it collects it needs to
connect to some cloud-based
infrastructure and to provide this
information there and your mobile
application or web application will
solve information that is collected in
the cloud so you can see where is your
device what is the environment house how
quickly it moves everything and device
is communicating without wires and we
found that there is GSM SIM card
integrated on device and it was you it
was accessing some private access point
so there was custom SIM card which was
issued by some providers which offer
global GPRS service so in whichever
country you are it will be ve to work
except in Serbia for some reason in
survey doesn't work
so that was the problem with the testing
because I was brought back from UK and
tested in Serbia so what I can do so I
decided to spoof GPRS access point for
it so used in using blade RF and the
eight BTS we I created a specific cell
which I control and by analyzing filter
from device which we have successfully
dumped before we discovered what is the
APN and which credential device is using
by analyzing integrated SIM card we
discovered the mobile network and the
mobile country codes which we needed to
set up this fully so device thinks it is
in its native Network it sees its APN it
can authenticate to APN so it can
communicate freely but on the other exit
of that node is through my machines when
I suppose Steve the traffic I read
directly traffic I manipulate the
traffic and I did all the bad stuff to
this traffic thank to not properly
implemented certificate pinning said not
certificate verification they were
trusting the right hand is private and
nobody else can spoof it and probably
this river we were locked only to 2g
networks that was a problem at the time
there was not possibility to use and to
simulate any other network I believe now
they say they support LTE also I'm I
haven't verified but I will try soon
because they asked us to do this again
so we will probably be tracking if they
if it is possible to support this
so as a result of this sniffing of the
traffic we actually managed to collect
information which device is used to
connect to cloud infrastructure so we
managed to discover authentication
details authentication scheme
authorization scheme and we were able to
do what everyone we discovered the
algorithm they use to generate all of
these based device serial numbers so if
you know the my city library we created
some Python scripts that you just enter
serial number and you get everything you
need so you can just emulate this device
and tell to guy who is looking at his
phone where is his device the D his
devices summer completely else so we
didn't even need to spoof GPS we can
just intercept MQTT traffic and do
whatever we want with it so I guess we
are almost 10 so just one more slide
about this GSM sniffing so I showed you
how you can sniff when you can inject
yourself as a ruff node there is other
possibility which is much more difficult
because you need to know exact janna on
which device is communicating and using
grg CM and the Wireshark you can
actually sniff communication including
voice and SMS traffic that goes from the
phone to the devices you are using very
weak encryption a one or a five which
are all broken and there are decoders
for that publicly available so it should
not be a big issue of getting this thank
you if there are any questions
just - sorry just two quick comments if
you're cheap bastard like me and you
have Airtel SDR you can calibrate its
frequency using the GSM signals your
clock in there tell SDR won't be perfect
but there is a calibrate program which
will listen to the GSM clock and give
you the BPM of your local oscillator
which will make your Airtel as they are
even better and are you aware of FL 2k
or small FL 2k the VGA dock on us be
free which is probably the cheapest way
to generate signals very low-power
signals but you cannot beat one violin
on you cannot beat one violin
raspberrypi right price that's true but
this is the alternative thank you yeah
thank you
so you have here this tool I also am
showing it here used for calibration
okay
okay any other questions comments
yep thanks for the presentation just a
quick remark on the ignore radio
companion basically one thing that's I
would say it's also important to mention
is that you can also write modules in C
or in Python and you can quickly add
protocol decoders and this kind of stuff
you know - these little could say well
recording chained to the end of it
recording chain yeah thank you fix one
one comment on the single wire on the
Raspberry Pi it generates a rectangular
signal so even if you are transmitting
on a frequency where you are allowed to
transmit you will have enormous side
bands and frequencies where you should
not transmit so be careful with that
yeah it's using ppm so it is dangerous
but it works it doesn't have too much
signal strength to be dangerous
you need to be really close okay no more
questions okay thank you and we can
continue discussion later solving it
[Music]
[Applause]