we're going to talk about automating
binary analysis with gitra's b code
yes and my name is gerge or gary for
short
i do security research at siemens
and sometimes do tutorials on youtube
yep that's me
and about the talk
so first of all um
so in this presentation we are going to
talk about gydra and its intermediate
representation called p code
uh first a quick disclaimer i'm not a
guitar expert
i use it time to time um and then i had
a project on on backdoor detection which
kind of led me to the direction of gidra
because of because it's free and open
source and that also that also led me to
to work with p code and i was positively
surprised um by you know how well p code
worked and how well gitra worked for for
this stuff so that's why i thought that
it makes sense to uh to talk about it a
little more because i think it could be
really useful for anybody who wants to
automate stuff in in reversing
um so the first part i will very quickly
introduce kidra and then i will talk a
little bit more about gitra scripting
and then we'll spend spend most of the
time on talking about about p code and
um there will be a couple of examples as
well so that we not just look at slides
all right um so if you don't live under
a rock then you probably heard about
kidra that's the nsa's reversing
framework
that everybody was super suspicious
about when it came out but then i say
open source and now all is good um
ultimately it's very powerful um a tool
and it's a great competitor for ida pro
video ninja rotary 2 and all these tools
and it's free so which is a great plus
in my particular project i choose it
because i didn't know where my my tool
is going to be deployed so i didn't want
to be bound by you know the licensing uh
stuff with with the commercial tools so
i wanted to use something uh open source
um and you know kidro
seemed like a
great candidate um and it turned out to
be true so um you know i'm glad i went
with that
all right um if you haven't seen gitra
before
this is it it's it looks amazing it's
pretty similar to what you see when you
open ida pro um the only you know
difference at the beginning is that um
since the decompiler is built into gitra
then uh because of that the default view
is the the assembly and then the
decompiled
code
in sync
which is also very nice
and
we'll talk about the
rest of it later on i just wanted to you
know if you haven't seen guitar to just
to have a an understanding you know it's
a decompiler and this disassembler so
you can look at binaries and and see
what's happening in in the binary um you
know just a short segue um you can't
really see that that but but in this
screen i was reversing um a challenge
from the flareon challenges
if you don't know flareon um it's an
only reversing capture the flag from
from from fireeye and if you know
flareon then you know um you might
understand how difficult it was to work
on slides while i was deeply in in
solving fair challenges so um if you
like reversing it still runs for a
couple of weeks
so check it out it's it's pretty cool
just a fair warning um it's gonna uh
it's gonna suck you in chew you up and
and spit you out uh but it's gonna be
fun
so um yeah that was quickly about flare
and
now so this was all about gitra so
hopefully everybody now understands what
git ray is um a github script um
so kidra as all the other tools have
some kind of way of extending the the
tools functionality i know in ida you
have idc and either python
you can automate rather too as well
gitra has gitra scripts what they call
it and
and it has a similar tool um you
you can kind of define two
use cases
one is that if you want to automate some
kind of particle task in your manual
reversing like let's say
you have a malware and and it uses some
kind of encoding for the strings that
are in the malware or in the binary
and um you reverse how it's decoded and
you want to automate the the process of
decoding so that every time when you see
that that
an encoded string is used then you can
just quickly decode it and for that you
can create a gig script and whenever you
see such a such a an encoded string in
the in the ui then you can just run your
your script and it will decode it for
you um or the other way is to try to
write uh fully automated tools using
gitra script or git droid itself as kind
of like a reversing engine for your for
your tool or like a
levers in reversing library um that was
my use case so i wanted to create a
standalone tool uh without using the ui
um that can that can do you know
particular stuff automatically
um when you write githurscript you can
do it either in java or python but i
will talk about that later
and it has a huge sdk um
there is something called the flat api
which is like a set of set of methods
that are available directly um and there
is like a the rest of the sdk that's
basically everything that skidra is
but again i will talk about it a little
bit later on
what you see here now is the script
manager of gitra
this is basically where you can
where you can look at the scripts that
are or there
you can run your scripts and you can
also edit your scripts if you're not
looking for any kind of fancy editor you
can you can just edit the scripts uh in
giger itself
and
as you can see there are already a bunch
of scripts in gitra so if you're using
idra regularly
it makes sense to once go through all
the scripts look at them just to you
know have a rough idea what kind of
functionality is available for you as as
guitar script
[Music]
and the scripts also provide you
um as kind of a great resource to figure
out how to do stuff in gidras script so
when you're writing your own gitra
script uh many times you can look at
other scripts to see how you know a
particle class in the sdk is supposed to
be used or how a particular task
should be
implemented
all right
so quickly about python versus java
so gitra is written in java so the
native language of gidras script is is
also java
but i guess the guys at nsa realized
that that not everybody likes to suffer
so they they implemented a python
binding as well uh in jaitan which is
not that great so um it's somewhat
limited and it's python 2.
but there is another great open source
project called
github bridge that you can see there
which basically allows you to write your
code in python 3 and using the whole
python uh
like everything that python is so
basically get away from from jython
and it works pretty well so i i tried it
and and and and it works well so if
you're using i want to write something
in python then probably a gydra bridge
will be
something that's worth looking into
um but as much as i'm not particularly a
fan of java and the last time i actually
wrote java code was at my university
which wasn't really recently
so um i still you know after a while i i
had to come to terms with the
um with the fact that that the java
development environment for gidra is
actually great
so i changed to java and i don't really
regret it um you know there is a
learning curve there as well but but it
actually works very well
and um just to be a bit specific about
why i came away from python
is that um with all of these python
implementations the problem is that um
you know often you need to figure out
what class you you want to use or or
what method you want to use
um and then you need to convert between
or you know typecast cover between
different classes
and
this this class information this type
information is not impossible to recover
when you do this in python um but
obviously this is not a natural thing in
python
so you kind of can figure that out but
it's it's an additional overhead that
kind of
slows you down
so um
and also like i spend a lot of time
looking at the documentation and trying
to figure out how i should use those um
those classes and methods and um if you
use python then on the top of that you
you need to also figure out how this
java code is supposed to look like in
python
which is again also not impossible but
it's an additional step that that slows
you down so
um
and yeah just one one one other note um
so java is
that you have a job but development is
actually very well supported by by you
know kidro or basically nsa um there is
a there is an eclipse plug-in uh for for
github development um so you can
basically write your code in eclipse you
can start kidra from eclipse and you can
debug your own code in eclipse while
it's executing in in gidra so that's
that works really well and it helps a
lot uh with debugging that you can you
can see your code uh running inside
gidra from eclipse so so that's uh
that's pretty awesome
so shortly my recommendation is that if
you use if you want to do something
short something simple then you know
python is is cool and and going to work
great um if you want to like
use the whole sdk and do some kind of
more complex uh program then you know
probably it's worth to look into to uh
to java and see you know compare how
much uh
whether it will be easier to do that in
java and probably it will
all right um just you know one quick
word about headless mode
so headless mode is basically um
the way to run gidra without seeing the
ui so
this is what you what you will use if
you want to create like fully automated
tools uh you know without using the ui
um it's basically in that case uh gidra
is really just a just kind of a library
for your tool for you know whatever
reversing task you you want to do uh the
only drawback is um that you know
starting your program is you know it
looks pretty weird that kind of like
there's a comment uh comment line on the
top um
that's you know it just doesn't look
good so probably will want to do some
kind of uh rapper script but but you
know that's that's the only thing um
what it makes
a bit bit weird
all right um
now let's talk about the flat api or
officially it's called the
flat program api
um it's basically
like a set of um of methods and
attributes that are available for you
directly if you're writing a guitar
script so you don't have to instantiate
any kind of class you can just call
these methods and access these these uh
fields um it's around like 150 methods
and
just to understand why it's there um you
might be familiar with the feeling when
you
uh when you find an either either python
script or ida script on the internet and
you want to use it but it's for a
specific idle version and you can you
either have that version installed on
your machine or or you need to port that
that script to to the newest version or
the version you have
and you know it's just a lot of overhead
and and pain in the ass so um
so this is exactly why there is the the
threat program api
because they wanted to avoid this
problem and the the the rules for for
this uh for this
flat program api is that um methods are
not supposed to be removed and method
signatures are not supposed to be
changed so basically that means that the
the script if you write the script that
only uses the flat program api then then
probably it's going to run in five years
as well um so
that's pretty great um and uh and i mean
you see it's 150 methods so that's quite
a lot and it kind of covers all the
necessary stuff like looking at
functions looking at memory um you know
recovering data from um from the binary
like there's a there is a field called
current program and then from that you
can extract all like various information
about the binary that you are
running at that point
yeah
and then there is the program api which
is basically everything else that
everything that gidra is so
so you can access all the classes that
are used or used and implemented by
kidra um so you know it's it's huge and
it's powerful but it's also
also over overwhelming at times
but the documentation is pretty good
there is a javadoc on the internet and
you know i spend a lot of time um you
know looking at it you know sometimes on
a rainy afternoon i sit by the window
with the hot chocolate and and like just
looking at uh gidra documentation it's
it's it's a lot of fun
and um
just an example of you know complexities
like if you wanna if you wanna do like
if you wanna use an address like a
memory address in gitra it's not like
you can just use like a hex value and
then say okay let's use this as an
address
because there is a
address class in gitra so first you need
to instantiate an address object using
your hex value and then you can you know
do whatever you want to do with the
address it kind of makes sense but also
you know sometimes there is time to
figure out how these things um has to be
done
um
yeah two things yeah source code is also
available
uh which is again a great resource and
if you have like the you know eclipse
dev environment set up then basically
you can go to any class and then say you
know uh go to to definition and and then
it's going to open up the source code
and then you can look at stuff like how
this class is supposed to be used or
what exactly the functions are doing
um
so
with the whole program api
you kind of lose the stability that the
flat the the flat api provides um
because your program might you know
break with the new uh
gitra release uh but it's but it's a
huge resource and basically can do
anything that's that's that's done in
gidra so you you can you have access to
everything
um so
to summarize the the
program api is basically with great
power comes great responsibility and
some pain
uh first example
so um and this is how a gender script
looks like
um this is basically just to list the
imported functions of the um of the
binary
we're going to look at it in a second
just a few words about oh yeah i can't
show there anything so as you can see um
the base class is the grid gitra script
class this is what makes your program a
githurscript and then the only other
thing that you need to have is a is a
run method once you have these two
things then you practically have a
githurscript and what we do in this um
in this in this script is basically you
can see that from the current program
um
in line
we get the symbol table
and then from there we can get the
external symbols which are practically
the imported functions
and then
with the loop so we get an iterator and
with the loop we'll just
iterate through these functions and and
print them so it's that easy
now i will try to
yeah
all right
so
here we see it in eclipse um and
if i go here to
you know run or debug then i can run
a gidra
and it starts kidra
and
i will show it on this one
now we are basically opening a binary
it's gonna
analyze it
so here as you can see
here we have the assembly code and here
we would have the decompile called the
fully cutter function
but to run our script we go to the
script manager
and we choose our script
and say run
and hopefully it ran
and it did
so here in the console you see that all
the imported functions and the libraries
or the dealers are are listed
so this is just a very simple
example of what you can do
now let's get back to slides
oh yeah great
i never understood why is this this way
anyway
so so far we talked about gitra we
talked about what kidra scripts are and
now we are going to talk about
p code
so
p code is um it's a registered transfer
language which basically
it's an intermediate representation and
it translates um
assembly instructions to to set off or
sequence of of um
p called operations
here you can see on the screenshot
can i navigate oh yeah so here you can
see on the screenshot you can open this
you can open this
this bar here where you can enable or
disable different um data on this view
and if you if you go to p code
it looks like a button but it's not so
don't try to left click it and right
click it and enable because you know it
totally makes sense um
and once you do that you get like below
all right i will just give you them so
below each assembly instruction you will
have these sequence of uh gidra
operations and the really interesting
stuff with that and why it makes sense
is because
because
the the p code clearly states all the
side effect that in this instruction has
so
um like imagine a scenario that that
you're looking at a jump and you want to
figure out uh what's the condition for
that particular jump is and um
you know if it's if it's a jump if it's
a jump if zero instruction then the the
zero flag is going to be checked whether
it's set or not and depending on on that
the jump is going to be taken now you
know
most of the time the the the condition
is just above the jump like a compare or
a test instruction um
but you know that's that that's not
necessarily the case and who knows what
compilers uh can do in the name of of
optimization so it could be any kind of
other instruction that says the the uh
zero flag at some point so uh to find
out to find your condition in assembly
you have to know which instructions are
setting the zero flag and backtrack
until the first such instruction and
then see what's happening there
now with kidra the only the advantage
that you get is that you don't have to
like
know everything like this you have to
just go go up the the p code operations
and see when was the last time when the
zero flag was assigned here you can see
like here uh here it assigns the zero
fact so this is these are the the draw
opera the p code operation and this
operation says the zero flag and
basically this is going to be what
controls the the jump uh in the next
instruction um
so this is this is a this is a really
big advantage uh oh when
oh my god
this is a really big advantage when
um when using using p code and you know
intermediate representations are not
really a new thing so
compilers use that as well basically
when you when you have a source code
they're going to turn the source code
forward to an interme first to an
intermediate representation and then
separately they will they will turn that
intermediate representation to you know
assembly and and and machine code the
reason behind this is because the first
part is to get to the intermediate
representation is basically um
architecture independent and only for
the second part have to you have
you have to care what kind of
architecture processor architecture
you're going to be using
and this is the same for the compilers
so the compiler is first going to turn
the the assembly code to an intermediate
representation and from there they're
going to turn that to a c code or some
kind of code code
and just to make stuff more confusing
and there is actually two different
levels of p code the row p code and the
high p code and i didn't find like a
very clear documentation uh what these
are so what i'm saying is just my
understanding and you know correct me if
i'm wrong
um
basically um or first the
the multi-layer intermediate
representation is also not unheard of
for instance as far as i know binary
ninja also does this that that
to get from assembly to to c they have
like multiple levels of intermediate
representation where they with each
iteration they add more uh context to
the code
and basically this is the case here as
well when we talk about row p code
that's literally just a translation from
the of the instruction the assembly
instruction to uh these sequence of p
code operations and um
it's already great because because as i
explained there they're much more like
it has a structure and you have much
more information that from the
assembly
but at this point you don't have like
higher level concepts like um arguments
or parameters or variables or
any of these things you just have these
sequence of uh p code operations
and then
when we talk about high p code um
it's basically the output of the
decompiler so later you're gonna you're
gonna see in another example that to get
access to high p code we have to set up
the compiler and then we have to call
the uh high function method uh for the
the function want to analyze and then
we're gonna we get a high function
object back and then with that we can
access the high p code of that
particular function
and basically this is the closest you
can get to to dc
representation and um you know for
automated analysis it also doesn't make
sense to go further because here you get
the you get the structure or you get the
structured uh
p code and also you get the context
information that's available in the sip
zelda code so you know you can you can
have things like you know what is the
argument of this uh of this function
call or what kind of variable is this or
you know if you have a bar node which is
like the the generalized data
representation of of uh gidra then you
can ask like where is this where is this
war not defined and you don't have to
backtrack line by line on your p code or
on your assembly you can just navigate
to the place where this value is is is
basically set
so it offers it it offers much more
context to to your code
and
so why why usb code because it's cool um
but no so um ir is not a new thing so
intermediate representations are not a
new thing um obviously the fact that
compilers and decompilers also use them
means that you know they kind of help in
in understanding or analyzing um binary
code
so obviously it has advantage for you if
you are if you're creating an
analysis tool
and um
if that's not enough for you then then
then maybe the fact that with p code you
get the kind of architecture
independence because because you're
moving away from assembly to a level
where you're you're you don't care about
the processor architecture anymore
because you're just looking at the p
code and if you can stay on that level
that could mean that that your
application could deal with different
targeted architectures of of binaries
and you don't have to rewrite your tool
every time you want to use it with a
different architecture
yes
all right now everybody gets a demo
so the the next example
is gonna be
um we're extending our first script a
bit bit further um and uh for that a
little bit of background information so
um
there is this thing from microsoft
called the component object model um
it's kind of like
it's kind of like a standardized
interface for
whatever functionality so for instance
um you can you can get a com object for
for internet explorer and then you can
pragmatically um exec
or or control internet internet explorer
through through a com object um you know
like word uses these com objects or
office uses context all the time
so it's pretty popular in in microsoft
word
uh and the reason why it could be
interesting for reversing is because
malware uses it uh quite often and the
reason behind it is that like if a
malware wants to talk to some kind of c2
server then if you just you look at the
and it uses the windows api then if you
just look at the
the imported functions then you see the
all the networking functions it uses and
then you can just navigate to the call
sides and then see that okay then you
can really quickly reverse the c2
communication
of the malware on the other side if the
malware uses the for instance internet
explorer as like
a proxy for its c2 communication then
then it's it's much less obvious what's
happening just because how you use the
how you generally use com objects is is
not trivial and it's um you know not
easy to uh to understand just by looking
at the uh assembly code so you have to
invest much more time into uh reversing
that that binary like even the fact that
it's it's uh it's using the internet
explorer it's not gonna be obvious when
you just look at the uh the binary so
in this first script we just want to
um
we just want to
look at the binary and see whether it
uses com objects at all and if so then
we are going to you know print the p
code of the call side uh which which you
can use to uh
manual uh manual
analysis it's kind of like a
reconnaissance script to see whether
whether there is anything to do with com
objects and whether you should
focus their your reversing time
on that
all right i will try to
do this again
yeah and then we
oh
no that there is
then we go back here
so
this is the this is the second script
and basically
uh here you can see these are the
functions that are you know used to
to con like communicate with com object
the most important for us later will be
the co-create instance uh we'll see that
in the in the next
example
and at the beginning we do pretty much
the same so
we take the symbol table we look at the
external symbols which is which are the
imported function and then we we
iterate through the symbols
and then the only difference is that if
we
if we find um
if we find a com object and or
specifically the co-create instance then
we are investigating that further
and we are getting the cross references
to to to the to that function call
um and then we
we are gonna we are gonna
print out the basic block so here you
can see that i'm i'm getting a basic
basic block model for that program and
then i get the the basic block for that
particular address where that function
is called
and then at the end
here you see i have an instruction so i
iterate through the instruction of that
basic block
and
and print the p code of that instruction
so let's see we go to script manager
and
let's run this oh wait i will just
like empty this one here
so that it looks better
all right
run
and then we go back
and here's our output
so here you can see what happened so
the first com function found is the
initial initialize
that's supposed to be there and then we
found the co-create instance so we say
okay we're investigating co-create
instance further
and then checking cross refs and it find
that it finds a cross-reference at this
at this address
so
we go to we go to that address and then
we we um we take the the basic block of
that
the basic block of that address and
print the p code for that basic block
so uh for instance here you see this is
this is your address where the cross
reference was and here is the uh the the
call
operation that actually calls the
co-create instance function
um so again at this point you should you
still need to you know manually reverse
what's happening here
but
but in the next example we are going to
see
go a little bit further
i'm not sure i even have something
useful on that slide
yeah i do
so in the next example
what we are doing is
to find out what is that that's being
used as a com object we can you can look
up the
cls id and the iid so the cls id is
basic or these both both are uuid so
just a huge you know value um but the
cls id can be looked up in the registry
and there you would see what
what the program exactly is that's being
executed uh when this when this com
object with this cls id is used
the
the id is the interface identifier um
which is
it's a bit more trickier to use so we
probably have to google it what that
exactly is it identifies what kind of
interface that is exactly from that com
object and that's being used um i put
here
oh yeah you can see
yeah sorry
you can see here that the
um
this is where you find in the registry
which
which program the cll cls id refers to
obviously if this program is installed
on your machine so you know if it's
internet explorer it's going to be there
any case in any way if it's something
else like if it's it's something from
from office then you have to have office
installed to have this information in
your registry
and
and this is how the co-create instance
function uh looks like so we basically
need the the first and the and the
fourth
parameters of this
function call to be able to recover this
information so that's what we are going
to do
so again i go back to
to here
to eclipse and look at the third
code and
yes so here you can see that we're going
to start using the decompiler because we
want to do it with high p code so at the
beginning and
we have some some code to set up the
decompiler and it's mostly boilerplate
um
but but you know it kind of shows that
you're coming
away from simple script to you know more
complicated programs but again it's
mostly boilerplate so you can just
usually copy paste it from one one
script to to another
and then here is the here is the
decompile function
where we decompile a function but the
goal is that we just call the uh get
high function uh on on that
and
and with that we get a high function
object which will have all the the
compact
decompiled p code available available
for us
and
if i scroll down to
to the main to the run function the
beginning is the same so we basically
look up the
com related functions then we find the
co-create instance
and
and the
the
interesting part is here
so until here it's pretty much the same
as the previous script uh here we call
this
find cls id and iid
function
and then we can go to declaration
and this is basically
what
uh what it does this is what's going to
get the hype code for us so here we call
the decompile function
um
and then then we get the p codes of that
high function
as an iterator so that we can go through
the p code operations
and um
and later here um
this is what's important that this is
what is not possible
if you use ropey code because basically
you can say here okay here is a call
operation so give me the inputs
basically the arguments of this call
operation so you cannot do that in
assembly or you cannot do that in in row
p code because this is you know the the
um the context um what what all what is
only available in in hyp code and we are
requesting the first and the fourth
parameter because that's what that was
the cls id and the iid
and basically after that we are just
calling some helper scripts
helper functions to uh to turn that byte
array to
um to a human readable uuid
this script is limited to
to you know
uuids that are built like hard-coding in
a binary but obviously you can extend it
to to make it smarter
so i come back here to the
script manager and i will oh wait i will
just
empty the console again
and script manager
and let's run it
and here we have the output
and on the top it's exactly the same as
before
and here
here we have the looking for csid and
iid
and this is
we identified the call
of the concrete instance and as you can
see here this is this is what uh what
the high p code is is looks like that we
don't have just the call and then the
address where we what we want to call
but here we actually have the the
parameters to that function call uh
listed and now we have information
whether they are constant or like this
one is like a a register that is passed
to to that call and obviously the first
first parameter is the address of the
function that we are calling
and then here at the end we are printing
the
the cls id and the iid so these these
are the things that we wanted to
recover
at this point you can either start to
google these values or look them up in
the windows registry or if you are
running your your gitra script or on a
windows machine that you can actually
build in your gitra script that
to look these values up with windows
apis from the registry so you could
automate one step further if you are
if you are doing that on windows
um
and so again the advantage of
of this
on
with high p code was that we can we can
easily recover
the um the parameters of that function
call
and we didn't have to you know
manually look into uh you know where
these values are coming from
etc
oh yeah
so um that's pretty much it um i hope it
was understandable um
quickly recap so gitra is a really
powerful tool um i think it's worth
looking into it if if reversing is your
stuff
and p code can offer you
some some
great automation possibilities
and
you know it's relatively well documented
and um
and and you know
at the end you don't have to be a fanboy
uh if um you know you just choose the
tool for the task that you want to solve
maybe it's kidra maybe it's not uh but
it's definitely work to have worth to
have git dry np code in your
arsenal for uh reversing
and um just a few references um apart
from the document the official
documentation there is not so much stuff
on the internet about b code itself
um so that's why i wanted to post here
these two um these two posts so alexa
jeremy they they had a presentation on p
code some time ago uh and this is the
blog post to it and raw roll frost um
writes um sometimes about p code as well
so if you start on on p code you know
these are
um
it's not introductory but you know these
are good references to to look into and
i just wanted to mention carlos my
friend who helped me with his infinite
wisdom in creating this uh presentation
so thanks very much um i was gary um i
think we have time for questions
although probably you're already
hungry but
let me know if you have questions
if you don't have questions right now
you can reach me on any of these
platforms or you know generally here
today and tomorrow
so thanks very much
[Applause]
somebody questions there is a question i
think you get a microphone
it's the fastest way let's see
excuse me
yeah um you said that you started with
python and then switched to java
any tips on how to do that because i'm
not really a fan of java myself either
how did you how did you do it did you
learn it somewhere or just i mean i did
learn java at the university so we had
this great object-oriented programming
class which was in java but that was in
i think in 2000
um
like
maybe six so it was a long time ago well
it's just you know i say that i'm not
i'm a google programmer so i kind of
program using google so uh
whatever i want to do something i google
it so and it's not terrible uh to be
honest i i thought it's gonna it's gonna
be worse um but at the end of the day
once you set up this um this
uh development environment with eclipse
then basically by saying create new
gender script then eclipse is gonna
throw you like this template and from
there you just have to write your java
code to do stuff like you don't have to
care about um
how it's going to be executed because
because actually provided to you
um
but
but the java code itself yeah you will
have to google it like you know i also
googled how how to do a for loop in java
like things like that so um you know
obviously i think that's that that's how
and i'm i mean it wasn't bad so i still
google a lot of stuff but it wasn't
terrible all right thank you sure
somebody else yeah there isn't
yeah so
i just wanted to know uh when you write
scripts uh using p code is p code aware
of the calling convention or do you need
to ask specific well
you are um getting values of out of
specific parameters can you ask it to
give you parameter one two and three or
do you need to
ask me area x e x
uh so uh theoretically and and that's
what i tried to show you
in gidra
and uh we can go quickly back there
so this is this is the high p code you
can see here i'm not sure whether you
see it from zoom in to see here here you
already have the parameters so this
first value like normally in row p code
you only have the call and the address
that you're calling and then the
parameters are you know somewhere above
here with code you have the address and
then listed all the all the parameters
of that function call and this is what
like when you do get input so that's the
that's the method you call and you tell
which the number of the of the parameter
you want to have and that's how you get
the fourth or the fif
the the first parameter obviously this
isn't gonna work all the time so um you
know sometimes it's hard and
it has also limitations uh but this is
how it is supposed to work
okay thanks sure
any more question
thank you
no then i guess thanks for thanks for
being here and have a nice lunch and see
you later
[Applause]