so
good morning everybody welcome to it
troopers
2011 my name is an Orion I'm supposed to
give DF
opening remarks on combined for say
kind of keynote to get you going for
troopers
still people coming and
which is good
mean I'd like to learn to see as many
people in the room as possible
and its this ESPN and has been ever
I got back to this mckean later on %ah
what I'm going to tell your speed up in
three piece us
first one is so some simple
organizational announcements
a second I will discuss the concept of
troop us
why does seem in Texas what see purpose
of this event and
obviously a thought part will be to give
you an idea why do you think
troopers is important some as for the
organizational stuff
test two tracks attack and we such
Force One which is going to happen here
in this room in the auditorium
then there is some research and
management defense and management which
is going to happen without flaw
we will have a lunch break at 12
side 2 p.m. their wrists at batch
contest some of you might notice
these pieces have kind of their own
magic and that will be a a contests and
at whose and you can we know one of
these boxers
which is a brand new shiny iPad 2 so %ah
it might be an idea to a join that
contest all the details
as for the overall organization and to
you
and the contests can be found and a to
page flyer
hopefully everybody off guard if not to
show already I cessation desk and you
will get all you necessary information
we will have a sad in a tonight at 6:30
p.m.
we will provide in how to get there and
a detailed way
after she had dinner we will have
legendary traditional packet loss some
with a number of teams this year and
tomorrow in the morning again this is a
kind of a tradition
troopers said they were so close 10k run
I'll we'll have a
a run for one hour arm at the ballot
I mean its plan to a colored 10k efforts
8k it's OK as well
arm we are going on up D a so-called
final philosophers way one of the main
sightsee
places Heidi bach so if you feel
inclined to do so show up well at
died at 7 a.m. at the Marriott we'll
stop at the Q
to pick people up to get some fresh air
get our brains going in the morning for
those who don't know me my name is an
arrived I'm the
found up back in 2001 of Leon W I'm kind
of old school network a
and I still I'm still happy to get my
hands study in
until be in what in practical law it's
not just a
I'm a manager running a company I I
still try to
to be a two-year technical side of
things
and yes I'm a trooper solar system
and the kind of given its
and going W event and I'm lead off the
line W
I'm to some degree behind a cement
but it wouldn't have been possible
without number of people who have
heart and contributed to get this going
at this point on
a big thing service lauria okay please
stand up
and of coset this applies to all the
other members of the on w-2
on thanks fire getting this going and
hopefully we'll have a great another
free day some
young WSL highlight base our security
consultancy and assessment services some
love you already know
are young W some will have the
opportunity to get
an idea what we do in the next days arm
b-sides a I mean we have a what we think
we have a mission
this mission obviously a salute to have
our customers perform the business
and again obviously I'll
say we have to employ all employees and
feed them
but that's at we try to
arm be sites the paid walk follow our
customers
we try to contribute to the public
security knowledge in debates and
number waz and troopers is one of those
ways
Antti are even if this might sound a bit
say emotional we try to make the world a
better place
this cysts are the understanding of the
NWS walk
not just perform I'll day-to-day job
but to contribute to public security
debate and knowledge
and there was one same mindset
which is particularly important for
along the sending a long walk
that can be broken down to say the
slogan from
theory to add we hella T which goes back
to the and sometimes
when in the end of the nineties so
what's a famous some
US a couple close lofton they had the
their slogan was a making a theoretical
practical
and this is what what we try to do as
well I DR NW
not just discuss things under
theoretical side
but shell are things can be done both
are
and the protective side of things and on
the attack side of things are
it's not just see or hear bring it to
reality and
thereby contribute again to a better
understanding of how security walks and
all things
some can happen and this will keep this
in mind please
this will play a role for his opening
remarks talking about young w's walk i'd
like a
to highlight to the fact that we and
what a number of
we such projects a farce of them as cold
as more young
which the contributes so we such
India's space of telecommunication
networks there's another one
to get a whiff to entities from
Dartmouth College
called trusts every dance let me try to
understand
Howell on dusty organizational reality
house atrocities Press saw how does some
how do a I souls for example taken
decisions
what's a motive what's incentive some
YSL seemingly a gap
between different laws some why don't
they behave in a way like say
Accademia would expect this is what we
doing this project some
I'd like to ask some of you to
contribute to this one
on details a piece I get back to me if
you interests at
knowing what happens in the space in
contribute
this for two we such projects we on one
of them
does not activity obviously we try to
contribute to the greater good to the
greater public data sets will pass
this conference and we understand troop
us as our contribution
to death exact some space of Public
Security knowledge Public Security
debates on to our to do Sol
to be at say any event which contributes
to to security was in general we try to
bring
together different kinds of different
groups
which not necessarily speak to each
other a very often
that s people from industry people from
academia
and people from the what we call the a
community
we such as: which offers which are not
necessarily bound 22
say academic institutions but will
perform
things on their own will try to figure
out some
things walk cultural how to break things
dealers espero at
understand how things happen and
thereby progress on the personal level
decide if we group contributing dog to
troop us that as people from industry
people
from academia and I'll
as I said we saw just we want them to
interact
the main spirit of true persists bring
these people again a half them interact
have to communicate
a half damn educated necks are
generational thing for a sec
professionals
that's why we every year we invite a
number of Sir students
to be part of the event as we want them
to lon from the street or
you want everybody to launch from the
speaker us I mean it's because I
herewith tuolumne
expertise in with them hopefully
are we want them to educated and we want
everybody
a true plus to half ass a good time
to learn a lot and hopefully to
understand to each other Banda and some
contributes to a better understanding
our farm
how security walks how security in the
world some
walks and how to make it to a better
place
it's getting bigger every year every
time it's a
more people still the are it walks some
that people communicate its has not
become an even to me which is driven by
it a.m.
non mi TM people staying together on
mixing up some but thats
of it's getting bigger this year we have
about
150 people and rolled and
just saw that tom including the speaker
us
which just saw point %uh vietnam boss
that's not a point of view that is based
on perception
I after impression it's big arm its
I i have pizza giving the keynote last
year eg I gave in to the year before
at the time I haven't been signing in
front of so many people
as today so it is a bit like the
every year everything come its it's like
Christmas
sign you might recall a yet Christmas
it's all this year to talk is better
than it has ever be
on a Christmas we as a begun and the oil
law
more stuff on it than it has ever been
and I fear we mine that's of Christmas
to something we today asylum I mean I'm
I'm on the E 45 kind of I'm introducing
true plus
and it's going to start in this is like
a Halkett fields on the eve of Christmas
are like a looking up to great things to
happen
%ah yes I mean um are
obviously if a hopefully if true but as
the president himself but
that there might be a might be a about
various
mean so far getting your own presence on
feel mind after the sniper 2 which you
but you can collect from the kind of
Christmas tree
maybe we'll bring Christmas tree to
tomorrow and and you can take it down
if you win the contest army
again two passes abroad bringing people
to get on to give you some numbers
it's about 60 percent of people from
industry
we have 15 percent from academia yes
%ah 10 percent roughly a
from say that with such community and be
a fifty-percent
you dance this is what them hold a tour
bus
assembled is here and they are from
various parts of the world
so hopefully this will stimulator
discussion this will simulate
exchange whatever why trooper saw is so
important
from our perspective d interests eg
world is changing
there was constantly terrorists had the
architectural changes
I mean interesting world is changing all
the time and this is one of two
challengers and this is why I
particularly like
my discipline why I'm really glad to be
enlisted in for a sec farm
fun and yes now us it never gets boring
it's always some best new challenge us
you attacks
and you protection mechanisms some
and all this but a at the very moment
there was heavy I V architectural change
which might again having to change the
way Hall
we perform in for a sec and how it from
our perspective should be performed
at the same time are for most of the law
say the area of responsibility it gross
doesn't losses since you're responsible
for this different types of
system feel responsible for this yr hi a
variety of systems
a higher degree of heterogeneity Solon
again it's it won't get barring and
it won't get boring as a number of the
on NHL for Tex
changes as well it's not just said yes
and we have to protect
undergoes change its the frets
change as well and those two facts
together
me now one has to constantly on
constantly
progress constantly improve
to keep up with the pace and that's why
to process their
getting back to our discussion this type
of change
I mean um a keynote is meant to be a
say a hands to some degree a
simplification of things
and let's have a simplified look at
their way in that box while
look today I day recess of us
terrorists klein's
this lights as some all change in the
pariahs
what is going to happen yes silos will
move to
let's call it the cloud whatever bonus I
intelligence from that processing
largely most alert systems
that I call a smart phones here a
so what has been your network with your
systems at some point of time
and your network mediating access
between those
systems I'll will go to law
yeah will go to the Internet it's not a
law your systems normal on
unit block come will be somebody else
assist some saw
maybe a on the the front and processing
engines
not being under your management control
on
to it won't be your network wanna stuff
happens
and this is not only a technology change
but this brings
heavy architectural and conceptual
implications as well
are Toolman for some %uh view two main
say pilus of tea
a few interests in for a sec
architectures might go away
for us the concept of locality the
understanding like okay I know what
assistance are
and that sell why I can protect into
something we
maybe by physical physical access
controls all by
arm whatever type of things that Obama
wants a
to the location our system is some
can be found %uh all these types of
security controls will go away
and it's not only to concept of locality
is gone some what you might think okay
I'm we have had laptops in our
organization for ten years now
I'll what's this guy talking about
haliti still
having that tops in your organization
and most of
the places might have meant to Katie
said company provide at
entities a so you have some kind of
administrative fund management control
over them
and again and this one
the Society's our understanding BMW
we go away won't be easy you at some
point of time
la noche elements within the style one
my
just showed and I get back to this one
won't be under your control
but a I mean this is only one part of TF
things happening another part yes at the
same time
you get and even more systems that will
be connected to your network set
you will have to take care of on the
security side of things
them I P L what we call you in and other
things
on all types of entities can be
connected to net loss
and having to be secured embedded
systems all types that would be a number
of
there will be some talks on and that it
is some cell types of analysis is that
will pass
there might be controlled at wats which
Indian scan times
have been run completely separate
by a separate that group of people and
now de Sol you're seeing some March
on there was some conclusions drawl
out of these developments a
the first one as some a concert the
system management
looking at elements like cum seder the
cloud thing
the concept of system management like I
perform security
operations I perform security functions
by having administrative control of
things on this one will
goal weight to some degree and this one
will have to be replaced
what I call trust management
you are no more india summer view a
sisal might have noticed soul
five years ago large pile my walk come
worse doing some technical things are
leading technical documents and
evaluating things from detective point
of view and today
%uh 10 or 20 I am forty percent %uh
vidaa negotiating contracts
and understanding what's in the
contracts and dealing with legal
arm this is a have a change and
on this from our perspective meets
I you have to get some understanding
what means what means trusts what means
are to work together with a third party
and expect this third party to act India
in the sense of the own interests which
is not about control
some of you might still have the
understanding like I'll when we go to
the cloud when be
I love the handlebar on all things to a
third party is to perform for us
we must must been assaulted them me was
monitored on
are we have to have some instruments of
farm
the looking at an outside thing and
understanding what they do
and then the country's save if you have
those instruments
some dis Mon walk trust is not about
monitoring and controlling and of
solving
trust this to expect a third party to
happen the tool
act in my interests volat the ability
are to control it I mean if I trust you
and your turkey saws say my
my house here's a key for my house
a feel I get home %ah
and I I'm going to leave if I do sell
without cameras in my house and I trust
you if I have
a number of cameras in my house on I can
at every time a convo cable one what it
sees
you doing my house I don't trust you
obviously
and what you will needs is an approach
of trusts up
and not an approach of control I mean on
did you ever
at all at our say did you trust saddam
and maybe I'm potentially their fate
but you trust a damn and you did so for
whatever kinda Weezy
and what I want to we commend US try to
understand
who to trust and why to trust those
entities
and to understand some what
a trust is based on I mean I'm not
talking about faith
favors blind trust like all her God will
make things so
happen in a in a way that's good for
humanity which is a perfectly well it's
um
stance but understanding
why and how to trust entities will be
one major part of your
future walk I gave a keynote at some
one-on-one time with phone to hear
there I have outlined term what I think
a valid reasons for trust like asking
questions okay lemme
how did some third-party behave in the
past
on how much information to give me late
trust me
who date to dig deep and on de salsa
taught sorts of questions that can be
asked to give a
assay verified are a trust that the
space some reasons
and for some parts of the IT
infrastructure us you have to develop a
say in approach of trust
that s the fuss say
piece I want to deliver mckean second
ones
I mean some %uh him item might not be
the first time the European
keynote of mine and there was a
history will repeat some I'm I'm known
to be stocked a very simple security
will
its and this again
something I'd I'd like to to get your
to understand to hopefully
to get this message once again to troop
us terrorists
sake security fundamentals those
fundamentals
are there for a reason and looking at
this type of things
it turns out that I mean this one has to
be addressed by
some methodology so of trust but let's
have a look at dicks 1
let's have a look at the as much fun
side of things
it turns out Tom are
some elements moving this all or a
picture a Clyde in the immature
infant stage when it comes to security
just might apply to control networks to
something we just might
apply to smartphones and to illustrate
this
a give you a seat citation
from from a sudden paper on computer
security
which goes like another major problems
defects
there are growing pressure us growing
process from
say management VIP's hard to interlink
chaparral at
but we ate computer systems which are
at the time maybe not computer systems
and
and traditional sense of what but pieces
like this
into increasingly complex networks yes
this is what we commonly see
and there was on the line problems which
might be
operating systems do not provide
adequate support for computer security
which in itself might early to a number
of our
us a security problem saw security
implications
and if the you'll agree
that what's written hiya to some
degree applies for the count world of
these computing entities within your
networks
the interesting thing I saw when was
paper written
actually this is some of you might
notice one on
d the ahead
say economic side of people him might
notice one
that Anderson's paper on computer
security technology
at that computer security technology
planning study which
actually was written in nineteen seventy
tool
on the year well that one computer sir
computer games was like this Paul
this is th Gladys papon
are was written
and interestingly enough many things in
this paper
apply to certain types of systems
Yukon net wats which leads a
to another conclusion if the problem
statement
hasn't changed since for DES made
don't waste dress set haven't changed
since forty
yes I strongly recommends
to go back to from humanities once s at
fun test go back to the origins
to try to understand the wallet
and I think the and computer security
understanding the basic fundamental
principles laid out at
and see in time so laid out in things
they'll that we get beyond %uh because
the Seven Sisters
understanding these fundamentals and
understanding how these fundamentals may
help to secure computer networks
the should be a quite important piece of
you
if you walk this stuff was written for
wheezy
and as with cement and please some
followed as with some follow the simple
rules saw
to give you I'm say an application of a
simple
again aquino is meant to be transport
simple message S&S one
I'd like to to transport here looking at
this Sun
part of things
my a.m. there was a simple to conclude
from this on despot of things
most netbooks alias all will be
unmanaged mess you won't be able to
to seek you out to control dust off with
means
with technical means you have been
useful in other parts of your network
soul I allow myself to give a very
simple
say a recommendation here please please
please do not pros
us if you can somehow
avoid this i know i mean we aim for a
sec People v
we saw farm say corporate organizational
interests
that to keep this in mind
do not process sensitive information on
smartphones
we got less of luck to you non yesterday
maybe it'll michaelson when this
workshop
are full of for iPhones and maybe
there is so sucky places where stuff can
be controlled and managed
but you should expects maybe in and for
your six months
the same the APC organization
County asking for use of smartphones
they might ask for not getting his
which is android-based and latest at
that point
forget about security by
controllers are technical means a
whateva this is an unmanaged mass
and if say a fairy godmother turned up
and said to me OK and you one one wish
as for the security of such types of
devices it would be
do not process Austar sensitive
information
bills this will not walk in the
meet shot in a long time so far I've
covered a number of farm
what I think our architectural changes
in the info sekwalle
some unfortunately it's not only the S
and we have to protect
that change es Salaam the world outside
its
with Fritz frats changes as well and
if there was one lesson one could turn
to you live from the assay last 12
months since last four-plus
on maybe from the whole year 2010 then
it's this one
you frats
a new attacks new types of attacks bill
shall
up so we have to prepare be prepared
mentally at least some
for their some towers
%ah I'm going to to discuss
some of the stuff that has been
happening on to to try to draw some
conclusions and
of it when I had to turn 10 star tats
someone who might know that was
initially día
in in January 2002 in a min made an
announcement like okay
presumably some systems have been hacked
and we suspect
say chinese authorities to be behind it
a level washed behind nets
this could have been a say a makeup call
and as we know in the meantime it wasn't
just says a Google in Adobe
but it was a sever many thousands
of large US some organizations
were affected by this one and if this
one hasn't been a game-changer
like okay something happen Cindy the
outside world
suddenly just one awesome amino know if
a sector
keynote in in early 2011 fun mentioning
Stuxnet
arm stock net loss
of could have been on my maybe I'm
actually ASA
kind of game change on the interesting
question s
why might stocks that have been a
game-changer
what's so special about it yeah it was a
targeted
tech okay the set things happen
I'd use 40 days which
means some ugly was so serious about
getting some
some jumped on that SEO days being
around and being use our tax in itself
is not
is a new are probably is stocks and was
not develop say bye
arm Johannes front sitting in a garage
but some again this
in itself might not be a a
groundbreaking the main
point of stocks net from my perspective
s its media excess turns stocks net loss
day hour so it was a proof
from theory to reality imagine you
you would know Tess a non flying objects
the flying through the sky society block
maybe you would be interested in say
that the nature of the type of object
but it was some Hall change the way you
a seat or what and this is so from my
perspective the main
national one has to get from stocks net
this
a text like dais
level was the origin eight and 10 was a
target
attacks like these might happen it's not
just a
assay paranoid to in for a sec guys like
a
whole this might happen and to
following some lines of thought of a
conspiracy theory
bad things might on Oct Pat bad things
time and
up an effort say two months ago law
in your own organization you you would
have speculated
some about like a lot well what would
happen if somebody breaks in two hours a
day
on people would have looked at you Ilya
crazy on this well it's not going to
happen you're paranoid
so please take a lesson things
that have been theoretical at some point
of time
might have tea in reality and
icons refrain from this one talking
about Stuxnet
I'd like to point out some things haha
presumably stocks net I'll
was initially deployed and Sadie
I Netlog slide was a supposed to cause
harm
by contractors USB deweiss houses
southward kites on a simple s
yall I'll external USB devices
in to be protected networks anyway I i
understand especially in the in the
title in in control net loss
one has to have a means of transporting
data
but is can easily be done by say
the maybe you speedlights s that up
under some organizations control which I
know draw law
I of our some some desk for whateva
and whenever data has to be transported
take this peace dollars and use this
back to tune out let external USB
devices to connect to networks to be
protected
again if there was a fairy godmother
showing up like all you one wish
to secure control networks it would be
do not allow external USB devices to be
connected
and their small I'll stuff like this
analyzing stocks: net I mean sucks it
had a number of propagation methods
but amongst dole's was a say I'm
copping itself to unprotected network
Chace
and exploiting arm the exploit dead was
behind him
a Conficker dating back from to donate
on simple things could dash
in quite some net loss maybe half a
protected from
from Stuxnet like stuff and finally
Stuxnet had to months a variety of
further
technical things added a try to hide
itself by installing and rival
simple question again on Watson need to
install drive us
on production and on patrol Net but
machines once a on production
how often do you need is to install a
driver so lock it down
do not allow installation of drivers
some on
if you are in charge of securing
controlled what some
on on those systems simple rules might
have
I mean I'm not telling you that %uh
the say
one would have been able to a to a white
and infection
stocks net fully but in some that lots
this would have happened if simple
security rules
would have been filed
going on on the time line so we had to
in 2010 we had to
r RI and yet stocks not some let's get
09-02-2011 there isa stuff from
say naughty in for second text space
that might change the way how we
policy security there was the data and
that was and still is the %uh price
in non say the Arab lot
which might have shed that the
understanding of TV out in capabilities
of the Internet
and that was on I'll just recently it
Japan Aflac I'd like to take the
opportunity to think of the week Thames
for a second back to high
block and back to troop us test two
lessons
I'd like to draw from that a pain of
process
we are living in a globalized wats
things that happen in one part of the
wards
are catastrophes take happen in one part
of the world
might effects in for a sec
environments network environments in
other parts of the world and not just as
fine a male ability
you might have notice that Cisco who
have attached a two-time CEO
one in march in one in September de ti
phat
idea are Moche patch day
to September they should a statement
like
all we won't term we won't have found
the March the
patch day as we understand that some of
our customers at
to very time have for different problems
to cope with
then patching the Cisco Systems but
obviously there's some impacts
Asfaw say the net rights to be protected
at
from some of quake happening in some
part of the world
and there was a second lesson that is
some
talking about risk assessment
you might know that we at the on W we
have a strong stance as for risk
assessment and risk management
actually in the afternoon there will be
a panel discussing stuff like this and
Tom
I will be on the panel and I will I'll
hopefully
be able to argue from the position at
risk assessment sir
is a good thing and is needed at to act
on
in a in an efficient manner as fly in
for a sec
environments still risk assessment only
wats
living a variety year saying well you
its
far normal operation I'll
of art thing set can that can show up
and to our can be classified into
different risks
there might be Iran's that happen
but happened ray rally but which might
be a outside the scope of risk
assessment so not everything in the
world
can be addressed before success meant
best things that cannot be addressed
aren't I think a conclusions some I
difficulty in so you
but some being able %ah having deny if
understanding that one can control
everything
by me to risk assessment might be a as a
set
might be are
back to the in for a sec to the thinks
of
things happening on I discuss Oxnard I
discuss
Sadie Egypt Bryce just recently
nothing's happened towers study hours a
break-in
and our city comatose of
s 20 hours a break-in
I quite some %uh he'll are affected from
this one
to some degree they are so
a hot lots of lots of say speculation
going on
on what does this mean for us and two or
three alarm
how should we act I wrote a blog posts
about this and I i won't term
say a detailed discussion right here
still
I'd like to ask two questions and to
bring them on the table tool
support my my main message of peace
opening
marks process I'll one can ask a white
did
day keep custom seats at all
terrace in the same official app
explanation going i goal in case
a customer did not have a backup officer
of Darrell authentication systems and
del indication systems got school day
could approach on
I was a arm
and ask but as he fights again on there
was another explanation
from the conspirators conspiracy theory
space maybe
which goes like okay our same was
founded in the in the eighties in the
eighties some love you might know there
was a large debate
about seek skip check
the clipper chip and all the key escrow
debate so
are I will train from any country
conclusions here
but still a peaceful remember our
I'd try to convince your understanding
who to trust and why to trust her
entities might lead to interesting
questions and conclusions here and there
was a second thing
I'd like to point out to them quite some
people ask himself some
and I am amongst those people let's
assume
customers he fights have been
compromised and that SIA
the current demos say popular assumption
out study hours a case
like why when does some seat five person
will be on that success
systems why wasn't there nag
to to some degree and this might remind
us
that was simple security rules to follow
and maybe day didn't fall those simple
security rules
an ass did not another organization
Kamal
Commodore yes a I got this from the
Wikipedia article
article on them Commodores a privately
held group of companies
offering computer software an SSL
certificate products
let whoopi leaders for a sec privately
held group of companies offering
computer software
some anti-virus softer anti-virus I'll
like a well on what I understand
assess certificate products why to trust
an organization
cool of our security products
and say authentication
highly valuable authentication
and titties at the very same moment
from the very same company and I might
be conflicts at some time
if this part of business is not going
well are so maybe they have to push the
other part of the business
by lowering the standards so whatever
similar questions
as for the trust methodology I were far
too early a
which and and I didn't give details at
the moment but some
duck questions like what's the nature of
their business some
who'd a deep and on who are they related
leff
asking those questions might have led to
a conclusion
call might or might not be right partner
to get allies as certificates from
a and term what de public statements s
presumably some registration age and in
sao you are was compromised so
this sold at this is a mafia-style
I'll tell us how you are father this is
where the that the place so the part of
the wall outlet and let us honor sir
a sun is shining and aid ha IDO
corrupted anyway actually day only have
one registration agent in in Italy
so it's not too far-fetched them to say
it
maybe was Italy arm that's a story they
want to tell
interesting enough I have been a
registration agent flaw
for a major german on
CA sometime goal and at a time
up I had a dedicated smart cart just to
perform
SAT at the registration process
I and this one suddenly was not easy to
to compromise where
s assigning often all the stuff was on
the Colin was a car that had 'em
at a time eat something in the air Fife
certification
a soda story like goal that guy in italy
has been compromised
some I that I didn't have far good
security practice
which would mean a lot cessation agent
I should perform a texan not based on
this a simple pass what
are something out what's wrong with that
and term
I mean a smaller more on this there was
some potential there was actually a much
broader and issuing a farm
certificates for certain entities which
again
my proof de our side the intrinsic part
of the white
as well united with the other part of
the world as some having dollar-some
entities compromised might lead to say
life-threatening conditions
for some people in parts of the world
they spread the rumor loss
that Iran was behind the attacks and I
was even
sayin Iran in hecka on
confessing the whole thing in some
public forum like oh it was me who did
it
and I from Island I'm from Iran and I
act on my own
are maybe that's true maybe it's not
a point is: they played a card like a
old ass is soundly the FBI attacked by
governmental
entity and tell we could protect against
a sense of the virus a hours a man
mention this yr
ATT at once assistant rats
he threatening us in treating our
business I mean it's a business they
should be able to protect
and they should be able to explain your
holiday protect you should ask for this
to be a trusted that
I it sa the Act waiting for us online
from 10 maybe not so much trust and one
might have been able to find ol its
by asking them the right questions this
aside the part of the message I want to
deliver
are and they even had some yeah
pick up a common a hiccup roof you could
cook could get this certificate
obviously that Guyana pupil diameter
Italy didn't get our cell
but saddam ask yourselves if obviously
there are entities are capable
of breaking in 2 hours a day and
presumably steel seat fights and if
there were entities
live a little break into a
say well-established but maybe not by
Ron
CA entities
what would be way now go off to next Sun
such a type of attack yesterday
it's a you should keep in mind its those
guys who did this self
on might be on the next %ah gets
might be a are say cloud infrastructure
us this is at least what I would do
I if I wanted to get my hands on say
centralized for processing and highly
are potentially highly valuable data
arm it's not my intent to to spread far
did a very moment like a I'll just use
iCloud term
submit get my get make a compromise
my intended s to deliver free say
main lessons so we learn from what
happened in the past the process
theoretical mites get practica
so you'd you'd better be prepared for it
better be prepared for it mean size you
should have
a set of tools I me we believe in
risk assessment and in certain types of
risk assessment mission Amos you'll
to take decisions in a creek Mena
things might happen and things might
happen in a way you do not expect them
a cell you should be able to cope with
things you have
not followed up thought offered as of
today
again for weeks ago law nobody would
have I'll most people in a room one of
not have have expected a break-in at
hours a day
got a point there some noticia thing
happened
how do you love it can you deliver it
safe rapidly are I use
there was scratching your head okay
older sign I never thought of this some
I have to get sir
say people together and we have to
discuss sir how to go on
be prepared for things that's the first
lesson second s figure out who to trust
ask the right questions some some of
those are laid out in the in the iraqi
not a gay firm and I'm happy to discuss
all this some
a law all on-site some some point it
will pass in the past
relationship but some understand
who you hand over our badu
authentication
up some parts of your education system
are say your data processing
and to there was some simple security
Willis
which %uh damn because they have waged
try to all this we member to
a simple stuff this will help you in in
times of trouble
are we understand and I understand that
are say you might feel like him
her Alice in Wonderland wen Xia Inc
when she meets does to the Red Queen
which
one of T A multiple say
a bit strange personalities being an
in Wonderland and what happens yes some
al.'s
I'll in that and the cause of action of
the Red Queen
she starts running and she wants as fast
as she can
and a when she stops she'll realize a
ser
she didn't she did not even leave the
place work when she stopped
I she's wondering and assess the likely
like a
all in a country where I come from if
you run
are you on another play some after Iran
on to added that the Queen respond so
well in in this country
arm to keep up with the pace
States human must run twice as fast
and this is part say of the current
challenge
that yet we SAT for a sec professionals
change
face the one change s the number for
text
change s and a high of two maybe the
effort to run
foster sir double as fast as we did in
the past some
to keep up with the pace of things
happening but
are I mean we think there is help
I'm to one might turn twice we are in
for a sec professionals
should face a challenge sir
we had a true plus and join a conference
thank you
given this was a keynote it's not a
possible have
Q&A session are we gained 10 minutes
compared to the year
actual schedule you left the coffee
break now
feel free to approach me at any time for
discussions about to stuff
again enjoy conference and says he later
and the tracks