set for and his according to data center
using Cisco an excess thank you so
yet there's more details I don't think I
have to introduce myself
anyone that important to group group
which someone might know about and
working for a company called
I recall alright this is
Cisco nx-os for first has anybody here
her double heard of the annex OS systems
or the Nexus is
1234 well what you that's pretty cool
and do we have any any representations
from
from ciskei well in that case I was a
story about
that's fine so a.m.
I'm gonna talk about a short
introduction to annex or worse
from my perspective and
my a bit of history of what I've been
researching
and a review of the on delaying group
the budget on of in
of you
area all rights blah blah blah and I
have a few
through problems with the Cisco and
annex or system
animals we can talk about and some
africans those questions and also do a
short demo
all summations so what is
and excellence from my perspective
it is actually I E built-in
MontaVista Linux system based on the 26
and colonel which we all know is
fairly old by alright I mean
I suppose they called update these
always I'm so
span of a.m.
the loop look look somewhat somewhat
like this it's a big
the yes box with teleport's
for old
all you guys working with these the
the types also all systems are there in
in the square
the kind of systems that are actually
running this operating system
this as you can see is quite a few so
anyway
lost year
i'd may I a an accidental discovery of a
an attack that my friend FX
phone about nine years ago and
which then was classified as denial of
service attack
against world most Cisco Systems
this was patched and no one really sort
for a few years
and tomorrow and the
does a bit always be surprised votes
what about the whole thing
what happened so I try I I sold it to
you to the whole thing
and I was able to recover columns was
quite interesting
and later on my
I went back to to look look at the at
the Cisco firmware
oils and I was able to recover like 10 X
files from
from the binaries that Tuesday gives you
when you download it or
when yeah ways towards mused of
and some a number one abilities
when I haven't really looked into the
city
his DVD CD or F security stuff and
they're simply because
I don't really know Cisco I'm just a
hiker on this researcher
so if you have any Cisco specific
questions
I probably causes so
a.m. the Cisco 7000 which have been
focusing about
is the biggest badass thing you can
ever find out when it comes to
networking
you'll most likely find the scene lords
and why are men such as bank finance
poor environments you can pretty much
wrong
hold data center using one of these
machines the
the dorm by the fall with 512 tended
switchboards which is while wats when it
comes switching
and as you can imagine if you if you can
invest in new
your status and you may want to save
some money in buys
this G junk mail which is
from my perspective more no more than a
single male a.m.
the impact however if you if you own one
of these machines of course your mobile
ads
obviously you can probably stop
everything in
modify the traffic so
well yeah of course rootkits I haven't
looked into this
which is sunset on the researcher I
multi2 destroy the world all rights
a.m. this is a picture I stole from
from Cisco it describes the
the layout of the system the saudis
to the disease or virtual device
contexts
Cisco described them is with his
alright
anyway a.m. these are two virtual
switches
in in in in the picture and
in theory they should be separated by a
lady one
and all these protocols for letting go
between the switches as as any normal
switch
thank you in
a.m. group
in yeah he did you know
could
I am yeah good
as mine is one though anyway
so as you can see there's a little stuff
beneath all this witchy
and they forgot to include the Linux the
which is in there between
I am so I'd just one point where it is
sorry if you if you can imagine
if you own the next year on the whole
you hold your golfing which
is that so
my point of view 30
I'm I wanted to show you a bit of what
the underlying the next looks like
when you when you show its
to audience to understand this so
what we have here these for a
all US system look like I mean I this
system is just one kernel
with all the services everything built
into it and
as this is a Linux the they've to taking
all these particles movies
interpreters and made him into demons
did nice and everything and
as that will say you should never really
do through to the room
the report you can I mean none of these
not all these demands or either change
from
that were as any kind of other
protection so you can just imagine what
would happen if you
if anybody would find like a on ability
in any in any of these
particles that any modern switch today
has the capability of really
the impact would be enormous you would
only
little listener pretty much because
there's no other protection than
this whatever is so
II I started looking into
other things find
this was leary's up I was left field
so I started looking into
come on line interfaces as you all know
these
nifty Cisco for more money to face yet
when you SSH or Telnet
of bed to a Cisco Voice
you get this really cool
interface we can't add it helps you know
in every way possible
it's really see so I i find out that
these
the this this command line interface
actually drives from
a number of configuration files Baggins
is quite interesting because you know
know when as far as we know it was
really seeing what's
with my dick is all about so I started
looking into this and I phoned
interesting strings
such as him which I thought was quite
interesting
a.m. in a few places
in these corporations now
we all know that as a few
moans their I mean 681 hidden ones
you come on this is
this is what the conflagration place
looks like
at the top there you have the syntax
which is what's the interpreter would
expect from you
okay with type system you would type
GDP and there will be an important some
some pie
and as we can see it something to go to
between zero in sixty five thousand
Thursday's however
the key were hidden points out
that's GDP in this context
will not show up on any help or on any
Todd
or and unless
you can't do the exact why statements
they will just say well that's nice
no such thing and to demonstrate that
this is what it looks like from the
command line
is quite interesting isn't it
yes
obscurity reliable security so
a.m. world GDP as you might have noticed
is
am interesting from like your
perspective
so he ID the
I pulled wrong with it a bit and
found out that you could St command line
interface
using gdb first ball
this is a normal come on the neck
sources
people might know if you're on just
chill processes
you'll see the Linux processes
which is beneath the whole system and I
was
kinda surprised at first because I
didn't realize it was a Linux until I
started doing this alone would from
these processes looked so much like a
red
a.m. so this is what happens if you
typed the correct command with
yeah a process ID prisons
I did open porch: you can just connect
in
do whatever you like so what could
possibly go wrong
a.m. I had I not give them with this
because
you can own the whole thing so I'm just
gonna show you roughly what he can do
and as we all know using gdb you can
call
functions compiled in into the processes
and complete works sometimes dozens
sometimes does
so us we all know what all these
processes running
running on route context if we just call
arnal bash ID usual
you be there's endless possibilities of
destruction
so that's that's that's the first wave
actually escaping from the command line
interface into the
into the underlying obscurity
a.m. so what would happen if you if you
if you skate
everything on the
this shell is driven by pseudo
because what you have in your hands when
you log on to the Cisco switch
this is cool chill which invokes used
ones
in some cases or in many cases and
can anyone hear spot the problem
in this suit was filed
is here
he says all
no password so indicate in any case
if you are able to escape from this
packing crap
you can do whatever you like pretty much
I haven't really dug into these commands
because
I just don't wanna that interesting
you can read this in so many ways least
is dis
but you can you can just imagine me
for instance the when you're on the
system GDP
will start with the DB server and
context such
its it interesting
and also I've been up indeed compiling
the shell
to see what what it's actually doing in
some cases
and this is some scary call that I came
across
I mean you shouldn't really
launch the app uses
from binary system and this is not
is this is not one occasion medications
as a concise as you can probably imagine
those in those possibilities of
destruction
when it comes to when it comes to this
televise
so
I figured that everything is running his
routes
everyone X accused of
using pseudo were obvious reasons and
even binders new pseudo
so I mean is this even fixable from an
architectural
standpoint when the real I
solely on using pseudo and
roots of for everything and
I've been asking myself this question is
it possible to fix this
you know of space quick fix in some way
I don't know I personally I don't think
so
I think they have to rethink the whole
concept of
excellence in order to securities in any
perspective
of course I mean
you can have lucky lucky you can have
real nice user
you know us problem happen so
moving on what bout me too
a.m. CDP Cisco discovery protocol is
a slight said previously see
effects cross today denial of service
2001 a and we could
iPhone again and as we can see here
sipes no demon
message as everything else and is
running as root
what could possibly go wrong a.m.
yeah soul this is
this is the cool stuff mean I haven't
Crofton
unexplored for this yet simply because
I suck assembly but it's fine
because I don't wanna extra I don't
wanna destroy the world but
this is this is the this is one the core
dumps that I've been able to craft
and as we can see there is problems
and the
many have you for all we know that this
is
not good and
yeah interesting stuff this is what
actually happens
they've them they've made
their own mother function obviously
must be a good thing
are no you tell me
by mean I suppose if you're if you wanna
do stuff you don't wanna
I mean memory allocation really really
fast maybe you need to make a new one
a windfall for obvious reasons you
listed water and a few protections
maybe that so
I've been I've been
otherwise in this vulnerability and
my conclusions somewhat or
that the dealing better
is a 16-bit value which means it could
be
pretty big the
this is this is from the from the
from the actual X-ray thing
and as we can see that
they take the 16-bit value
making you byte value which is eight its
and they convert the lawn
from sixteen internet which concludes
truncation
and then the allocate memory using the
8-bit value and the
men called using the 16-bit value so
anyway
its gonna break however you do it and
that's just one of the problems I mean
are being a meanie studying the cold the
did
life found out that when I was the wrong
this II try to find out where is my
payload
I wanna see if can do something cool
here
which I couldn't from the payload
pictures
the in the cold there was a hard-coded
pointer
we saw didn't understand why because it
was members to and from
that hardcore pointer which is scary
enough
so I looked at that point remark or
dampen yeah there was Michael dans
so the using some kind of
or publication the I'll it's not really
my area
mean
kaya so that's pretty much what happens
when the
did you did you say I am 1400 bites
located 7 and then
system yeah
so
other other five funny stuff
a.m. in the Linux
system there's a pass the file I think
any other than a system
it contains the user's that can log on
to the machine
the
the uses has two
be there in order for
log on to you her he also has to be in
the
this is a configuration file for the
system rights with see that the user is
there
and iPhone these FTP user
which for all
all reasons as a password but
he also no shell so it's not possible to
use its
as far as I know I mean that might be
some otherwise some other attacks
factors we can use this user but you can
please log in using its
using message and I haven't really
looked into that
from I crack the password and
v1.2.3 and
body started to Google in
this is any way with the configuration
file looks like inside
and excellence miss you see you have the
up dude
but you don't have the FTP dude so
that's an interesting way of
actually back Tory the system the issue
in just one layer not the other ID to be
four
you 123 good Aires
is nothing interesting home
the most interesting I could find was
the it was an example on hold to
make your own snake all certificates and
the examples for the ad was an
123 for some odd reason so I don't
really know where it comes from
looks like
someone made her made me have written
example
doing something and and do you want to
three with your response word so
anyone know where this stands for in
if anybody has not played New Year
laid on the floor use god
iPhone God in the Cisco
not using it. cutie producing the shell
itself this is the shell that starts
when you long
as normal user to this is Google Voice
this is all the
parameters you can supply to its from
the command line
so in Example you're able to escape the
come online as they
Dom user you don't have really have been
permissions but you can still a typical
online sarin
inside the Linux but you you just have a
normal user but
you don't really care about the news
because you really one oldest
the router from the router perspective
how do you do that
a.m. for civil
you could jumpy
into any version please contact us large
or
you just skip all the rules and
that's a god I
I've been up in the a.m Corinne Google
about this
and this possibilities of destruction
even this and they say that this is a
feature that needs
so
I don't think they're gonna do
do away with it because they needed it's
a feature
the
for for those who knows annex OS
you do you know that you switch between
BBC's if you're not mean
I guess that they
what the actually doing the background
is launch another shell
with the ID of the context you wanna go
into
that's what I guess
so I guess the but
Mike my perspective issue should be on
in some other way so
a.m. I told you wanna show you some
Asian stuff when I found these
vulnerabilities I was looking around to
see if there was a DeLorean wrong
because
I felt like I am
back from the future or something group
ago and excellence
I actually have a minute an ex always
in my view where because
simply because there is a female version
an excellent
there is no real magic anybody can
download it from
from siskel Kong it's called the
one from we the one thousand comes with
the 60-day trial license
for anyone who wants to broken wrong
with the system
so back to the future
a.m. him y'all
sees
yeah will we're we're in the in the
linen the
in the Cisco system anyway
so wanna 11 one thing I
I tried 11 really early morning when I
was hungover and
been really know what I was doing I was
just pointing wrong with its and
I found out that can do
something like this
pop
back from the future good
I mean I tried to fall for these
presentations I tried to
to find references to when the Bhakti
vulnerability was first discovered and
the first reference iPhone was from 1991
I think
and
yelping up in buzzing around with
with with the stuff in life
phone maybe five or six different places
we can do this
and that's simply because the in the
configuration files
the the do some kind of input validation
but they have a kinda been put at ease
states like anything
and that's what the user
and us we all know shes
invoked from the next the newspaper
perspective so the just shove everything
into
into the backend and the
yeah glory good
a.m.
so for those have you are interested in
bug tracking there's a few bugs
you might be interested in in Truckee
the so those
is actually quite quite a few more
but these are the most interesting ones
when it comes to
from total annihilation compromise and
I'm also thanking one
Miguel Gonzalez from the PS or
right Ridge teen at Cisco because he's
been very helpful
he calls medications to see everything's
alright if I have released anything yet
and you once I threatened to resolve
anything because he didn't answer is the
his emails and then the day off to
recall
mean so yeah
it. questions as i said i
I i'm not a good siskel experts I don't
really know anything about the system
except that it's broken
in
check know best actually shell
yes I've actually had a question that
that
different conference and we had to take
it because I hadn't checked
the point so I had to go in and see but
there's nothing there
on a motion I didn't try the mean
I even tried to deploy my own chill
222 the to the
as the sages you can do you want them on
but that doesn't really work however
there are some really nifty stuff if
you're interested I can show you
in way
who group on this exit from this
craft this is the Linux
you'll
this is actually the shell which has
been executions when you log on
as a normal user it's a script day
and gets the
Journal complicated when you when you
start looking at is up in trying to
exploit this but my country dudes
the only thing over been able to do is
wrong
that's as a shell nothing else
you know its it looks really messed up
any stats on how many of these are out
there in the wild
a.m. workforce I know those
I'm from Sweden we have maybe six or
seven of them
in the country because there's some huge
I mean
you need to have like a review your
status and when these
and where I found this was actually a
customer of mine
is one of the bigger banks in Sweden
who was rebuilding the whole internet
banking environment so
site hasn't providers have something
like this
probably probably the I mean you buy
these
big is a model for about 250,000 euros
and yeah
you
couple yeah so what are you guys gonna
do about it
watches retention
you know that you can
last school for the source code tonight
you can
actually other you can do the same
because
salinas system what what's in the
criminal what they change their
they have to right right normally on
support page
its products email
source necks rights
come just you have to email right so
that could be
maybe your way K
probably do that either haven't really
thought about use I'm not really into
these
all licensing your was a good idea
any other questions yeah but there
decide see see bach
them are there any remotely exploitable
stuff because
for your text actual local user
you to write exactly exactly I haven't
really falls through all the
all the home all the demons
and that's just because I'm lazy and
because I don't destroy the world but I
mean that's BS
as I said before the whole lot yes good
I mean the whole architecture is broken
anyway what we gonna do bodies
I'm you gonna you gonna find hundreds of
problems in this
I'm literally used maybe twenty hours
too funny stuff
and only like
from the mornings really I N word like
poking around group there's not a bug
Press
its
you