the address will present some really
you stuff about I SAP we hiking
and this is one of the talks that will
be held very first time it's true press
conference
so expects quite you
stuff just up to you hi
thank you very much for inviting me I'm
for the troopers conference we have
designed this picture which is
our trip was about to forge just a few
words about me
and about the company I work for I'm
I followed what you forge inching
one victory for channel specializes on
SAP security and more specifically job
security
and this is practically the only company
does that
except of course SAP on I'm
an active SAP security researcher since
back then I fount the first the road
ASAP
was a buffer overflow in observing
ironically in
the password field arm since enough
given couple of talks
and rice conferences recent black cat on
a different topic though
I'm and a.m. also about mentioning me
wrote the first book
on sichuan programming there was no
yeah that's a comprehensive resource
before the book
no with it's out in was was released in
at a City Press and Sam what much a
forged us is
first will be based in heidelberg one
kilometer
away from this building am and our
specialty like I said it's our security
we have written and up security scanner
static code analysis tool forever
and be provide also very comprehensive
security guidelines if you try to write
your name
custom morning I'm missing something
which Mariano where mentioned before my
honest what was on
SEP standards what you can do were on
when you install the SAP standard
misconfiguration missing pages and stuff
like that what the focus on is not the
issue
the standard but what the customer just
the custom coding
this is our domain mistakes you can do
when you write your own custom code
and for that we have written guidelines
to provide training and consulting
to help customers to securely extend
their SAP Business
so I'm today
which Mariano the beginning also mention
most companies believe they're doing
enough
regarding their city security they have
a whole bunch of things
they're doing segregation of duties
authorizations picture management and
whatever
and the belief is OK we are now
safe everything said range but
unfortunately most companies do not
consider
Colt they don't consider if I write my
own called
I may introduce a back door to all the
security i
built customized patched and so forth so
this is a typical picture we see at most
companies today
if you're telling them they are risks an
out-of-court
the kind of go blank and reboot am
in their mind because they have never
heard about that cell
I'm what I'm going to talk about today
is I'm
program called subquery which is
basically the main
user interface you joost for recipe
today of course
like Mariano showed us we can use SAP
with Ben implications
web services but the old days and still
today in many many uses
use up to a cell and some who is closely
interconnected with up I'm
I found this risk to a couple of months
ago and the City of rain spoke so this
is authentic
about this million or language a.m.
if you look at at the park down there
and I even spotted the at character in
it kinda your
so I'm if you talk about
sup who we also need to talk about up
because sup
who is the primary rendering swoosh
about applications
and the visit about application for
college
controls so I'm first let's talk a
little bit about
up itself there as a couple of
information
list each year most importantly is a
proprietary language
addition Ishan up its not freely
available so if you're researching
about you really have to try and every
a lot of things Yukon cool to certain
resources and we told us the compiler
stuff like that it's all closed it pro
generates platform-independent code
someone else is important for talk today
yeah I'm there are some
its there so a lot about called
I come back there's a lot of other
according to 66
system 150 plus million lines of code
and on top of that customers create new
croat in the thousands of lines
partially millions of lines
without proper guidelines I'm
okay let's get that we don't have too
much time in this talk I want to go to
the exploits
or to the presentation of it were a
pretty fast so what is up with
who is a proprietary fat client provided
and maintained by ASAP
again it's closed source open source you
have to take it as it is
I'm is available as either a Windows
executed or a job application baby have
slightly different
most mostly the same I'm the
communication between sup who in the
back end is through the yet practical
its again a city specific
usually its not encrypt S&P also
openly communicates that but it can be
encrypt it since then it has just
compressed
which kind of real security but
its its usually okay so much what's up
lead acid
it renders about doing for programs
any standard user interface for me for
most companies if they want to inject
appears to be back at so I'm
also some we this is more interesting
provides
certain methods to interchange files
between the SAP applications
and the front
and it's also a scriptable so you can
basically do something with a few
you can record a session you can replace
session for automated testing
also possible from this phone
okay I'm when you're talking about sup
we hanging I
divided this into three distinct
sections sections 1s
you want to talk about attacks in South
we that
originate from an SAP server so here the
attackers a compromise sir
and the the user the client is actually
attacked
in order to do so we picked a couple of
functions that
available in up which I'm going to
demonstrate in a moment
first before me a.m. about has a
function module which is called WS
execute and this function module is you
write a book called
Chan execute alaska months on
the client for some who is installed for
the user thats
starting a program on the server the
program can
send arbitrary code to the client and
have a textured
a second function module using briskly
up note
which as the name might indicate upload
the file
from the client mess-up go isn't to be a
secure server
hence by seamer so there's a Guido not
function with just the opposite
notes a file from the server to the
client
we also have certain additional measures
methods
in CIA in a class called see a good
friend and services
and this provides functions like access
to the clipboard
getting directory listings on the client
and so forth a bunch more
so I'm if you look at all that they are
all
either based on the up command call
method of
which does oil oily communication with
Window System
an on-call calls in in the abstract
I don't want to discusses much bring
about this is basically
all drilling down to those methods
sonya just first demo
so what I do know I'm connected through
to our
SAP server and virtual forge
and I'm invoking and other program is a
specifically prepared which makes use of
the functional units I've just sold to
you
okay and when it starts up I'm going to
write
little file
guys I'm having a great time
group
your ex troopers
Sony store that in our data for like
with give it some random name
no
okay i mispelled it
an unknown up okay II it took a while
so what happened now I just created
distorted on my local drive by the
a program was stunning it took a minute
now 'em
might expect tells me that someone has
modified my file
in if I want you know it so
what happened here the content of my
phone was changed
from the server ends
so basically when this is over do it it
scans my local filesystem
for files actually a problem just sex
check for specific folder it reads all
the text files in the folder it looks
in the folder if if I misspelled the
garage troopers
it then changes to file and upload
against my client
without me getting any hint about what's
going on and certainly the finest there
what it also does it also started
notepads
with this file so this is done through
on operating system command
on my client as a proof-of-concept and
when it also did
about show you that one it created user
on my computer called troopers
all of this has been just done by the
up so when I executed to primp
it started Liz that check fights my
client
exchange my file is uploaded it again
it started not pitch runways come on
and it created a user on my system
what does that mean it means in this
constellation
if I'm sup weak lines and i connect with
the server actually owns my client and I
don't
you can see it so
but the ramifications of course in place
I'm I I'm using the old subquery
seven-point 10
and some we7 point 20 which is
release now can completely restrict this
kind of excess or if you're running a
subsequent 720 you can say I don't want
in your voice commands I don't want
file access and social so you control
that
there's also an additional information
you should read if you're still running
a subquery 710 order because
otherwise you have these kinds of
problems but of course if the problems
only if there's militia scored on a
server
but this is just a proof of concept to
show you what can happen if the service
militias so member one
for section was the service even now of
course
which is more common declined to Siebel
or more specifically the use in front of
the Chinese people
so you're not checking what can what can
I do
um if I'm
trying to manipulate sup away and a
couple of things i wanna show you first
of all
I'm the topic forcefully browsing
which is a well-known problem in better
locations
which means I can change parts of the
screen and
emulate buttons that are not they are
all make
on editable fields editable and so forth
and there's something I wanna show you
know
so I wanted to do that I need to first
log on again some recipes system with a
restricted user song
and I'm trying to go to them too much
infection issue 01
original Snitzel creations and
keeps what's
I'm not authorized
use transaction seems everyone across
the eulogy was
very restricted but I can go to
transaction
St 30 SE 30
am offers methods flava front analysis
to check
which programming time which programming
tricks
a faster than others to improve
performance
my coat so how does it work I can pick
some topic for example
access to internal tables and I've
bet called on the left side and it
caught on the right side in can say well
okay measurement and then it says okay
the left cordis
'em several microseconds on the right
Qantas optimal
0 from am which is probably not exactly
correct I'm
but this gives you the possibility
to test which faster however I'm
what happens behind the scenes this that
the program a problem in Sweden it reach
the contents of those disabled feel so
if I go in here
icon changer it's blocked but because
behind it if you look at the source
court and a purpose always available
source code you can see that you can
modify the code if you have certain
privileges however my user doesn't have
the privileges
from but I'm I come across
a nice little too which is called window
pic
and went to hike allows me to change
element so for example I can now check
what is the window ID of the specific
element
and reached and from here I can for
example say well
I 12 changed in read-only mode
so I can go piano and type something
but this just makes for a couple of
seconds and certainly someone notices
you something's going wrong and freezes
again
so of course one thing would now be too
enable it to be the leader in its
disabled enabled the legal
but this is a little bit cumbersome so
there's an alternative
your I can also say which is is your
sent texts
so now instead of activating just
type in some up for months
soul this month actually do what I try
to beginning
they are telling the system to start the
transaction issue 01 bitch
lost me to read get access to users
sonar send the texts
thank you very much link but now it's in
here and now again go to measure
runtime:
what's what happens there was no runtime
measurement the court was executed
when the system was trying to muzzle
runs an offer internal table excess but
actually it
now jumped to a transaction issue 01
and as you can see it now I am inside
the transaction although previously I
did not have the authority to start it
which means I can using this simple tool
went away
which is freely downloadable from the
internet manipulate subways trains
make this in a few enabled and do
betting small
this is of course really example there's
something really bad happens
because this is called which I can
execute usually
I'm this is not possible and to support
fixed I'm
for for a lot for a long time but them
problems like that gives users easy
access to
right called in if I have the authority
to write out of court
i en route because about record is not
restricted
buy anything because or privileges
except the code uses authorization
checks in the code that would restrict
the use of
but if I can control the court I don't
use any authorization checks
of course still in this transaction here
although I'm now
in the transaction if I want to for
example 2a to use or something
I can't do that because this problem has
additional
authorization checks apart from 8 to
start it or not
okay so this was an example that you can
really
them yeah forceful drones
sup Hui
but another thing which is a little bit
more curious is that you can
even I'm trigger cross-site scripting
vulnerabilities in subquery
on
let's go back to my city system
so I just type in a text and
as you can see the text us your insight
certainly
just writing checks test which is
nothing better
course let's try this again
individualism time restraints
I'm just trying to start in a large
which is the first thing you do you try
to testing
scripting and here it is
so even a subquery application can
consist
of rosa parks signed and that case I'm
this is actually exploravision
which contains as you look at it source
code HTML code
and if um custom application
few simple to this to this I'm custom
control
for HTML you can embed scripts
and run it of course the test is not as
as good as it sits on the bed because
there's more Dom you can't
me to keep your something that is not
inside I'm
with their national big information
regarding that
insights ugly but you can still execute
script unit/units the content
office certainly interface well
the more interesting part of that is I'm
b-sides
running JavaScript you can also I
mention that all your scripts up to you
itself
let's try this again but missed some
Visual Basic Script which can be used
to sort of script sup we
automatically without any into
intervention by the user
started
for a time
okay now I am back the script and it
tries to
start transaction which is called issue
38 original settlement programs
secure that
okay somebody a or so
in they did what you should do they
changed
the the flag that allows us to remotely
execute croat
total to execute scripting so we have
yet on except with them
okay don't see it now I do that at the
end of a talker first one to show you
something else which is more interesting
so what should have happened years that
court should have also executed like the
JavaScript instead it just me the script
and
it actually executes condoms going so
what when the lessons learned here
for developers do not transport
important data supply ground troops
which means if you
write something in a control which is to
say but don't read it again
hoping it nobody enable it I'm
issue using the HTML control I'm make
sure
did you do it securely and you don't see
any input sewage because otherwise you
may have
a cross-site scripting problem and she
is also an him how to disable subway
scripting rich mining
dear colleagues at the company currently
did and not knowing that I need is in
the presentation
um so I'm you can lock this down
okay number for pictures my opinion the
most interesting
attack against sup creates an attack
from the internet
I'm the Mariana also mentioned that
am most companies say well what can
happen
are locked in our internet we have no
direct
link to the outside world if you're
running on the subway you have known
better medications
when you're safe nothing can happen no
one can get into or excuses
but this is Brian we actually found a
way to a tech
from in Internet application a subquery
application
so how does that work
so we jump this cross application
request forgery
which is close to cross Chris cross-eyed
request forgery differences Justin in
cross-site request forgery
one back page a text another web page so
you have a broken hip
one more page on the right and one of
the left and one of those
something bad and high as a request into
the other through the brazen
however in this case the fire requests
from the internet through the browser
into up to you
so prerequisite is of course I have a
running suppli session which are
currently ash
and a.m. I also have a browser open
which is talking to the internet through
my corporate level
seemingly I'm I'm pretty safe but the
militias
about chance and specific Kaman's under
certain circumstances to simply
and trigger a common to support
ongoing demonstrate that on this of
course
some friends have disabled this as well
again
so they're pretty tight about security
in my brother okay
so I'm no going so again here's my
subcommittee session
just open here's my bros in I start the
browser
had no effect expects up to you I get
this prompt
which asked me do I really want to do
you need
the user to join us and this common came
from the internet
so by by downloading the specific page
I downloaded Akamai wanted jumped from
my bros
engines coolly and tried to delete this
user
of course this is just a proof of
concept and there's
risky because this specific SAP
transaction issues everyone has a
from 10 you try to tell you the user and
across like to request for prosecution
request forgery conned overcome
trent this of course and Oakley yes but
of course I don't do that but this is a
proof of concept that
when you're locked into sup we in your
secure
Internet Intranet and in the same time
use a browser on the Internet
and come across the militia side it's
possible more specifically
boss possible that command control verse
from the browser into you softly
and take your system no
I don't want to be she cell
however I'm we we discovered this one
rib in a team
via go recipe has pitched also
a while ago and but still
its it's important that you apply those
pages in order to be secure from this
kind of attack
so know if you have some minutes left
ninety minutes long so
first two things them I would like to
recommend to you if you interested in
this kind of problem
insecure about poor tourists from other
port I'm
bears some and organizational bizarre
.org the business security initiative
I'm which was cofounded by to forge my
company and on up sis
his company and it deals with top
threats in
SAP environments and your trying to
build this up to build a community here
so everybody interested in that is
invited to participate and contribute
content
and also if you're interested in
literature
regarding up development is horrible
unfortunately did
only available in German so if you want
to right secure a book called you have
to learn German
and should you be in the position to
find 20 days
here's the email address send them
securities issued
okay am basically I finished thank you
for your attention
if you have questions
okay any questions
know ASAP yes other
so to some question about the
across application request forgery was
that use the euro
endless boys no activates some bras
object
am basically I'm
the not telling too much about this it
it is downloading a specific file type:
which is dynamically executed by sup
we with a type of a specific extensions
Israel is transferred to your system
certainly takes over Open City
execute set/sets that's a basic word
course
see if I can get this worded and would
you
i'd
okay let's let's try this again
ni
I don't know it was a quick
shell melham
thank you
I'm midst Blitzcrank kind of lost it now
where was my ability the crisis gripping
okay should too long
again the input movie and
moms No
maybe I have to log in again that might
be the problem just a minute please
so when you when you change the setting
that allow scripting you have to login
again otherwise it's not effective
you check first okay no it's their books
called executed so VBScript code I just
inserted
makes up we open a different transaction
as the 38 like I mentioned before which
Colonel Sanders yeah I mean SE 38 now
and superstar that
so it's possible by if you have a
misconfigured certainly climb that
and you get import in and as such in
HTML control
element part of the application then
somebody conscripted
going to bed things without even
noticing so three days
basically different kinds of attacks
server against client
militias client against the sample
session and the third one
I'm locked in the Internet bingo
thank you very much attention thank you
very much impressed
a.m. other further questions