rob really needs no introduction except
if he ever shaved his beard in which
case nobody would ever recognize him at
all i see him sitting there and he's
already got the best prop room raider 10
of 10 a bottle of botanist gin to kick
off his conversation
awesome well thanks everybody and thanks
for having me uh this is such a fun
little format so i appreciate that
everybody to help put this together
and for those of you
that are in this talk look i appreciate
you don't get me wrong however in track
one uh is brandon and i believe it's
brandon's first cyber security
presentation that he's giving and so
it's getting recorded i'm gonna give the
talk anyways you're not gonna hurt my
feelings but you should totally go
support brandon uh other than that for
those of you that are sticking around
anyways or looking in the recording
we'll go ahead and jump in with the talk
this talk is around structuring
intelligence assessments and gen
cocktails and we'll spend roughly 15 to
20 minutes in the beginning
talking about cyber threat intelligence
and mostly around the intelligence
assessments themselves and then i'll
spend the next 15 20 minutes after that
making gym cocktails and then hours
after that
enjoying my cocktails while you all
continue on with your conference
and i put a blog link it's up on the
screen as well but i put it in the slack
in the track 2 slack
essentially this blog is going to be the
talk i wrote it last night
just make sure that people can and can
review it and be able to read it as
they'd like not a huge powerpoint fans
we're not going to do any slides a day
and then down at the end of the blog
there is my spreadsheet with the gen
cocktails that we're going to talk about
and some of them will make today so
anyways uh hello folks my name is rob
lee i'm the ceo and co-founder over at
dragos which all we really do is
industrial cybersecurity so like ics and
ot stuff today my presentations have
nothing to do with that except for the
fact that you need
control systems often in large scale gin
production so maybe there's a tie-in
anyways
but as mentioned today i wanted to talk
about intelligence assessment so let's
start off
i will highlight the sections of the
blog that we'll talk about i'll talk
about things beyond the blog so that
it's actually useful for you but that
way it'll um kind of center you in the
right locations before we care about the
blog at all though before you take a
look at it i want to start off with a
quick discussion of really what cyber
threat intelligence is in the first
place there's plenty of you that
probably deal with it in some form or
fashion but often times what i find is
that
people have
perceptions of cyber threat intelligence
largely generated by marketing and media
and
vendors talking about cti and so forth
really all intelligence is
is analyzed information about a
requirement
generally that satisfies the requirement
i should say generally it relates to
adversaries but that would be those that
have the intent opportunity and
capability to do you harm so that's
really all we're talking about you talk
about threat intelligence is i've
analyzed information to come up with
some insights and knowledge about the
adversary that helps meet somebody's
requirement that that first piece that
is really important to foot stomp is the
requirement you can do a lot of
intelligence stuff and skill sets that
are the same for intelligence analysts
but not actually doing intelligence in
other words there is no intel for intel
sake we usually call that the
self-licking ice cream cone if you are
not satisfying somebody else's
requirement you're probably not actually
really doing cyber threat intelligence
the whole
starting and ending place is somebody in
the world has a knowledge gap or pain
point about an adversary and they're
trying to address that and so that's
where we get involved now the first key
point this is where i'll
start highlighting the blog first key
point could really be summarized as
those three words there which is you do
you
i am pretty opinionated
and i'm opinionated about the world of
intel and how i would do things versus
how other people would do things and
i'll tell you it doesn't matter if you
are satisfying the requirement of your
consumer and you're doing it in an
honest way
then everybody else's opinion is just
that it's an opinion and the critique is
probably not all that valid i think
there are some things that you can do
really really poorly as an example
i think a lot of the ways that i see
security teams track threat groups as an
example
tends to be around malware they focus on
the malware itself the
some technical artifacts maybe the
exploit being leveraged maybe they focus
on
word usage keyword usage file names
folder paths install paths various
things about the malware and then
they'll start to cluster intrusions
based on that malware
that may be really useful to somebody
but have a little bit of problem with
the over focus we place on it because
oftentimes what you're tracking is not
necessarily the group doing the
operations but the group that developed
the malware and in some
parts of the world and in some circles
and some adversary groups if you will
they might be one in the same but
especially to talk about state
operations or larger criminal groups
usually the people that are developing
the malware are not the same people
acquiring and managing the
infrastructure that's being leveraged
are not the same people that are
actually on keyboard doing the operation
are not the same people actually doing
the analysis on what they get out of
those operations so sometimes our large
focus on clustering or grouping
intrusions or or adversary attempts to
get into your networks
by malware can be misleading but what we
actually want to track which might be
the tactics techniques and procedures of
the adversary which relates to more of
the keyboard operators and what they're
doing
during the operation so i can sit back
and go through that and say oh look i
think that's interesting i think that
might be wrong but at the end of the day
if you are generating intelligence and
generating insights that satisfy
someone's requirement
my sitting on the sidelines and being
like wow i would have done it this way
or would have done that way is largely
irrelevant now we can all try to push
each other to be better and hey i think
you can use these areas to be better i
think you can
consider these collection gaps or
knowledge gaps and we start throwing out
all those fun intel words we can be
collaborative as a community and
critique each other as long as we keep
it respectful um but at the end of the
day don't let analysts get in the way of
you and your consumer
and i joke around and highlight the
beginning that generally speaking the
only thing that analysts want and
analysts who can agree on is the analyst
theory is wrong you're not going to have
a whole lot of intelligence analysts
that agree about
most things let alone everything if we
did that's a problem means there's
probably a bunch of biases getting in
our way like groupthink and
it's unlikely we're all coming to the
same conclusion so i'm going to walk
through some of my suggestions as a real
estate intelligence assessments but they
really are just that okay you should go
through and actually
just make sure that you're satisfying
your requirements now i did highlight
that point about honesty and i'm going
to
talk about that real quick but we do
deal in a world of trust
when a consumer a business leader maybe
even the security operations analyst
that hasn't dealt with cti as much when
somebody looks into what we're doing and
asks us for our assessments and our
insights it's very common that it looks
weird
and and it's like how did you derive all
of that out of netflow and malware how
did you how did you come to that
conclusion
and and ultimately it can kind of fall
into one of two camps one camp is
it's such an obvious conclusion in
hindsight that hindsight bias being
another type of advice be careful of but
it's such an obvious conclusion in
hindsight there's questions to get
raised about why did it take you that
long to generate that assessment
and sometimes it falls in exact opposite
camp which is
uh it takes us a long time to get to an
answer we got to an answer and nobody
really knows how to repeat that like
from an external perspective not another
intel analyst but the consumer i might
be looking at what you came up with and
it just looks like you know dark magic
it's like what how did you get that
and and so because
who are consumers they may not have the
expertise we do on the field that we're
focusing just like every other security
field out there
it really relies on a lot of trust
and i often tell people that if you were
ever caught
misleading people or
um in any way um misguiding them based
on your own biases desires and personal
agendas or so forth you ought to pack up
go home pick some other field that stuff
gets out as it should
and because we deal so much in trust
eroding that trust will largely kill
somebody's career just as a quick
example if we look back and to
let's say the democratic national
convention compromise of 2016. for those
of you like i don't want to deal with
politics like it's the world of intel
man like wrong talk all right so if you
if you look at the democratic national
convention compromise of 2016
uh nsa cia and fbi all came out
and made assessments about uh who was
responsible for the dnc compromise and
why
and
they actually showed really good uh
maturity in their assessments where they
all came up with a high confidence that
russia was responsible
but they had a little bit of different
confidence levels as related to
the why it took place cia and fbi came
up with a high confidence assessment
that putin wanted trump to win the
election
nsa got there as well but they came with
a moderate confidence assessment so from
a consumer perspective other folks may
have looked into that and go oh nsa and
cia and fbi aren't fully aligned cia and
fbi have a high confidence nsa has a
moderate confidence as we'll talk about
later a moderate confidence assessment
is still a really good assessment um but
likely for the reason for the disconnect
is it even though it's not actually
disconnected
is the collection that a cia or fbi is
going to have largely relates to human
intelligence and the ability to talk to
individuals and be in the room where nsa
historically depends more on signals
intelligence telephone calls
cyber data of some sort and for that
type of assessment that gets into the
intent of an adversary really helpful to
have that human collection so because
nsa didn't have
all the collection that cia and fbi had
they weren't able to get to the same
confidence level right but let's roll
that back to the whole point of trust so
what was the what was the disconnect
well when fbi cia and nsa gave out that
assessment
a lot of news publications and i'm not
talking just fox just msnbc or cnn a lot
of news for locations a lot of the
majors came out and started having
guests from their shows and talking
about how we couldn't really trust the
assessment
and if you go back and set google to
just the time period and look around the
reasons given for not trusting the
assessment the number one reason cited
was the wmds in iraq
and people were saying look we trusted
the intelligence community back after 9
and they misled us and our politicians
and leaders misled us about what was
going on in iraq and there were not wmds
and that was the pretense for the iraq
invasion
this is misleading
what if they're doing it again
and from an from an insider view where i
had spent time at the agency that i said
agency nsa my caa colleagues always
remind me that they call it the agency
too but let's be honest it's lesser and
said with love uh when you look at uh
the nsa's point of view as an example
the nsa in 2016 was a different nsa that
existed in 2001 um different people
different mission areas people working
on incident response and intrusion data
related to hacking uh into the dnc are
not the same people working on photos
and insights into wnd movements in iraq
but to the public it's all intel it was
all the intelligence agencies and it was
you guys misled us
so long story short be very thoughtful
with your assessment it is better to be
mistaken than to be wrong it's an old
intel axiom
and the idea of course is it's okay to
be mistaken and then you correct
yourself maybe transparent in that but
don't be wrong and definitely don't be
misleading you you will lose the trust
of your consumers and they just won't be
able to rely on your assessments anymore
because again a lot of what we deal with
is in trust but part of that and part of
having that trust is being precise in
words i linked this article here words
of estimate probability if you go into
this article and it's free just to be
able to go and take a look at it
it is
essentially a manuscript written by
sherman kent sherman kent is one of the
kind of
godfathers of modern intelligence in
many ways and he'll go through and he
talks about what words to use what words
not to use kind of how they help a
consumer make it uh
take advantage of the information you
present but if you really boil it down
what kent is saying very accurately is
whatever you do
just be consistent and be precise
so if you're going to use words like
almost certain and probable as he has
over here in this graph
he actually has a mathematical kind of
consideration around it saying almost
certain
is a 93 percent or better insight give
or take about six percent
now you're not going through and
calculating each component of what
you're doing to come up with a
mathematical score you could you could
create a mental model or some sort of
structured analytic technique to try to
do that if you want it would be too time
consuming
but having it weighted with a number
helps keep us honest between analysts
because maybe i could be pretty
consistent in my own
word usage but as i get onto a team with
four five six seven different intel
members
the language between us can become a
barrier
and so to sit everybody down go this
word
has a representation of around 93
helps you understand the difference
between almost certain and probable well
this one has roughly 75 percent and and
it's not again to actually calculate up
anything it's just to put that there
going are you like 93
sure
then if you are you can use these types
of words and again it doesn't matter so
much what words you use but i would
create a scale on your team you can just
use the the ones that um sherman
put out but no matter what you do um
this is a good place for a style guide
but an intel team you'll usually create
a style guide not like a grammar style
guide that that can be in there but a
style guide would include what words we
use and which words we don't the meaning
behind them if we do use other
structured analytic techniques and
mental models um if we have sample
intelligence requirements that we've
already satisfied and how did that look
and what what kind of
outcomes do we usually address what are
our collection sources
if if there's none that aren't too
sensitive to put in a style guide i mean
you sort of have the playbook for the
intel team and this words of estimate
probability or a major portion of that
um so as an example i don't like the
word believe
and sergio would say belief is for
religion not intelligence i'm i can't
stand the idea of having belief well i
believe
that the adversary might have intended
to harm us you know they might have not
anyways like what like you know you
didn't feel confident with me giving you
those words it just seems sloppy and so
forth so not even just the might and the
probables and the so forth just
depending on how you deliver it it could
really distract your consumer but belief
what do you mean you believe do you
actually have data to support this or
not it's not an element of belief it's
an element of i assess this or i don't
am i just giving you a judgment call or
did i take the time to sit down and
actually come up with an assessment um
either way it's not belief now you may
not be so pedantic
but for me i don't like the word believe
so in a style guide we'd say don't use
the word belief instead here's some
other words to use in these different
situations
um and so again
it's okay whatever you do so long as
you're consistent because and this is
another key point here
the most one of the most important
things we as intel analysts can do is
reduce frictions and barriers for our
consumers
a consumer does not care how smart you
are they do not care to get into the
intel report as if it's a forensic
report to go down and go oh they did
this oh here's the hashes for that okay
all right i see the ida pro screenshots
like that's not necessary you can put
some candy in your reports if you want
um but but put it in an appendix or put
it kind of
down below the cut line if you will the
whole point of an intel report
assessment insight that we're going to
drive to them is as briefly as possible
as clearly and concisely as possible
delivering the intelligence that
supports the requirement not oh hey you
didn't ask about this but here's a bunch
of other interesting crap we found like
you can always have a conversation about
that but for the actual assessment for
the actual report for the actual product
that we're delivering them hey you asked
about x we're delivering you why if you
want to know any of the details or
anything else we're happy to expose
those to you but it's trying to be as
quick as possible because we want to
reduce those barriers to them consuming
it we don't want them to sit there and
go oh that's a nice picture of our brand
well if that wasn't useful to the
intelligence requirement then just move
beyond it right so
intelligence assessments are going to
have
different structures
we're going to talk about that in a
second
but the first thing i want to talk about
with intelligence assessments
is really again what exactly are we
doing in the language that we're using
so at the end of the day
and i see this a ton in commercial
reports
if you are
talking about something that is a fact
or an observation just call it that
there's no assessments required when i
open up an intelligence report i'm
looking for one or two assessments
because that relates to one or two
intelligence requirements or maybe i
have two assessments off of an
intelligence requirement i'm not looking
for every other paragraph has the word
iss or we assess because if it's not
mapping back to an intelligence
requirement
you don't need to put that in there and
if
you aren't dealing with 15 intelligence
requirements in the same report i don't
need to see 15 plus assessments in the
same report those are general rules of
thumb
but as an example i put in the blog here
if it's something that is a factual
statement that's all it is it has
nothing to do with assessments uh was
the malware on the system yes or no
we don't know because we don't have the
collection is a perfectly fine answer we
do know because we looked at the system
and there's not malware on it or yes we
looked at the system and there's malware
on it
none of that relates to intelligence
work
that's not an intelligence assessment
there's no need for an intelligence
assessment because ultimately an
intelligence assessment is going one
step beyond the actual data
it's going one step beyond the facts if
you will we're taking an analytical leap
based on the synthesis of information we
put together to say you know what
i see the malware on the system i see it
connecting out to command control
that malware and those command control
servers end up being used by these
threats these threats are focused on the
financial sector we are in the financial
sector based on all these things that
are factual statements
i assess with moderate confidence that
the adversary intended to target us not
just have us as a victim in other words
this isn't some random infection this
adversary is likely targeting us and we
are a target of their operation so i'm
speaking about an adversary's intent and
i don't have any collection or ability
to collect to go and be like hello mr
episode did you intend to harm us yeah
yeah you were my target like that's not
a normal interaction that takes place
and so we're going one step beyond the
facts and we're making an assessment
about the facts available that would be
essentially what we're talking about
that's essentially good intelligence
work
if there's a requirement for that if the
response is going to be the same the
company's not going to do anything with
the information of being a victim versus
being a target then there's no reason to
slow things down with the intelligence
work if it's just hey if we have now in
the system we're going to respond that
way great cti analysts can take a step
back don't complicate anything let
people go do their work no problem no
need for an intelligence requirement no
need for an assessment
but if being a target versus being a
victim in this case matters
then we will actually put that work
together or hey we saw
50 different intrusions across the
company this last quarter
of those 50 intrusions 20 of them were
successful and actually
got into some level with three of them
leading to an actual incident at the
company
are there any groups that are associated
with the three and are there any
patterns around tactics and techniques
and infrastructure they're leveraging
that we could group these intrusions
into
adversary groups where we would be able
to define
run books playbooks
scalable detections et cetera against
those intrusions that's great
intelligence work yep cool you have a
knowledge gap or pain point we're going
to synthesize intrusions and synthesize
adversary data and come up with
assessments about them perfectly
realistic
so you will probably be familiar with
low confidence moderate confidence high
confidence you've probably seen or heard
those words before
and what i'll note with them just like
the
estimate of
words of estimate of language we want to
be precise with what they mean now
there's a lot of things that can go into
it but the short and simple version for
me
would be a low confidence assessment is
a supported hypothesis it's not just a
guess
not just some information manifested now
i'm guessing if that were the case
i could just say that they say we don't
know we haven't put the time and effort
on this but based on my experience
i'm gonna give you a judgment
but i've told you where it's coming from
not synthesis of insights and
intelligence work but based on my
experience and intel animals especially
those that specialize in various fields
are perfectly capable members to make
analytical leaps to make analytical
judgments to talk about their experience
relative to a situation there's nothing
wrong with that but it's not an
assessment at that point it's an
analytic judgment
now let's say though a low confidence as
i was talking about earlier i've got a
hypothesis that is supported it's not a
guess
now there are
other hypotheses
that could be accurate right and maybe
i've identified some of them maybe
there's five or six
uh possible outcomes of this scenario or
hypotheses
and i've looked at them and we have
evidence or an insight and data to
support this one as the leading
hypothesis
but we haven't had a lot of time maybe a
factor or maybe we don't have a lot of
collection maybe a factor
or maybe
it's some element of a changing scenario
ukraine scenario right now going on with
russia that absolutely the changing
geopolitical nature
could mean that other hypotheses end up
getting more weighted or more
information relative to them over time
so i might say at this time
based on the available information
we assess with low confidence this this
answer right
and that is a perfectly supported
perfectly usable assessment but i know
on my team
that it's likely single sourced in other
words as i'm collecting information
maybe i'm only getting malware data at a
virus total maybe i'm getting netflow
information out of team camro
maybe i'm getting
open source information out there but
even though i might have multiple
sources
you know osen netflow malware database
it might not actually be multiple
sources because the open source
information might be reporting about
what's in those power databases the
malware database and the netflow may be
about the same infection and i'm still
looking at the same case so you'll be
really careful just because i'm getting
the information from multiple databases
doesn't mean it's multi-sourced so as
i'm looking at it and i go this is
single-sourced information so if that
information is wrong or that source is
wrong or that source isn't as
trustworthy as i would like or even if
it is trustworthy but i know i'm missing
a bunch of information from other
sources that's not something that i'm
really going to be able to rely on
so again it's it's a good assessment but
it's low confidence when i get to
moderate confidence i'm now supporting
it likely with multiple pieces of
information ideally we're getting to
multi-source but we still might be
single sourced but the big difference
between the low confidence the moderate
confidence as i've either had enough
time or resources
go analyze those collection gaps maybe i
don't have an incident response team
inside of the company to give me all the
insights that i want them only operating
about what's coming out of
that company through those databases
like virustotal or news sources
and so i know i've got collection gaps
but i can look at those collection gaps
and determine
one can we get around them can we go get
that collection oh and two
even if we had that collection is it
reasonable to suggest that that
collection could alter what we're
looking at could alter on the hypothesis
in other words if i've got
malware samples original phishing emails
i know it's come in through a specific
convection vector i know that company is
compromised
going and interviewing the cso is a type
of collection but probably not going to
get a different outcome than the one
that i've already come to so i'm not
going to highly rate or weight that
collection gap because it's just not as
important so moderate confidence
assessment as i'm identifying and trying
to
mitigate those collection gaps but i'm
at least aware of them and i've done
some level of insight on is this really
going to change the assessment anyways
but if i've got something that is
very well supported i'm now in that
above 50
right it's not the either or flip a coin
kind of feel it's
hey 60 70 75 percent i feel this is the
right answer but a moderate confidence
assessment is is the way to go when it
gets to high commons assessment
this is when a predominant amount of
available information and data supports
our hypothesis
we want to make sure that we're not
falling prey to other types of biases or
logical fallacies like becoming anchored
on one piece of information or
um having some level of congruence bias
where we're not considering other
hypotheses right
and so
i've got
pretty much all of the information or
close to it is supporting the hypothesis
it's not taking away from that
hypothesis
and it is definitely multi-source at
this point it's possible to have a
single source to high high confidence
but almost never
i'm definitely going to have multiple
sources that are getting to me this
and this is a all but certain like this
is a 95 percent above like
it would be insane for us to be wrong
about this
in this given scenario so a lot of
information supporting it multi-source
usually there's plenty of time to really
go through the assessments
and again we've identified and mitigated
those collection gaps so
if you think about these
what tends to happen i talk about this a
little bit later what tends to happen is
folks get
uh sort of
i would say biased towards wanting high
commas assessment so i put that down the
bottom where everyone kind of wants to
have high confidence assessments because
it feels like that's a better assessment
and it is i mean it's totally fair to
say hi comments assessment is a better
assessment than a lower moderate
competence assessment but low confidence
assessments are still the product of
good intelligence work and are
assessments that you can trust they are
good assessments
and if you find on your intel team that
you're constantly putting out 70 80 90
of your assessments are all high
confidence
the problem that you might be
experiencing is that your consumer is
over valuing high comments assessments
your analysts are trying to get to a
high compass assessment because that's
all they're willing to use
and hopefully the analysts aren't faking
any of that hopefully they're getting to
it the real way
but part of the cost is now it is
unlikely
that you are producing intel quick
enough right so there's those four
components of good threat intelligence
completeness accuracy relevancy and
timeliness cart c-a-r-t
and when it deals with that
focus what we want to make sure
is that we're getting intelligence out
fast enough to support those users and
those consumers so i should actually
have it where 40 or 50 of my assessments
are probably low confidence a little
less or moderate and a little less or
high um by bryson you've come on board
what's up man yep we got a question in
from slack how often do you or your team
use ach
yeah analysis and community hypothesis
is one type of structured analytical
technique if you're interested in
structure analytical techniques i would
highly encourage you to go check out
richard hure's work
and he's also there's a psychology of
intelligence analysis it's a free ebook
you can go download
and it'll walk you through that
my team doesn't use ach often ach is a
very intensive structured analytic
technique i find it very valuable but it
would only be used for some particularly
like important assessments where you
want to be very methodical and the most
important thing sometimes out of
structured assessment
structured analytic techniques is not
necessarily that your outcome changes
it's more that that you have
traceability now you actually have an
understanding of why you came to the
assessment you did across multiple
analysts and that can be very useful
um so good question last thing i'll do
and then we'll switch over to the second
part of the talk
when it comes to the structure of an
assessment what i would generally like
you all to follow and again pick
whatever you want but just have
something that's specific um i generally
like to find that there's a confidence
level the analysis itself evidence and
sources easy structure of a statement we
assess with moderate confidence that
electrum is targeting the ukrainian
electric sector based on intrusions
reserved to the kiev electric
transmission substation by our instant
response team as well as publicly
available data from the ukrainian ssu
but right there anybody looking into
that does not need to be an intel expert
they get hey we're assessing with
moderate confidence and if we have any
relationship with them they should know
what that means by our interactions
across time then we give our analysis
and then we talk about where is the data
coming from yeah this is from our own
instant response scene as well as public
information and right there it's
self-contained into a very very easy
sentence that any consumer could use
have confidence in by having that
consistency and understanding what when
when went into it um so anyways
hopefully that gives you a little bit of
view into intelligence assessments and
there's a bunch of different articles
and readings and
videos that i'll link down here which
would be useful for you but at the end
of the day if you're giving consistency
and language and consistency in your
analysis and it's something that's
transparent and generally repeatable and
you've established that relationship
with your consumer on the words you
choose and so forth you're going to do a
good job again don't freak out about
other people doing things differently
the world of intel is a very intimate
relationship between the producer or the
intel generation capacity and the intel
consumption based state all right uh
bryson i think there might be another
question then we can get in yeah i feel
like we should get the the threat until
one's out now um
so uh i don't know if you can see it but
they have the results of your current
take on the
um so we have seven percent provides
value for the stock 31 good to show
external visitors and 62 percent waste
of dollars should be banned yeah i was
glad that he threw up that poll um look
i'll i'll just
i i i am mr
everything is you know you do you at the
same time that's one of the areas that
draw a line and go you are wrong if
you're using pew pew maps and all the
but the management likes her it can get
budget or whatever all you're doing is
training your leadership to be stupid
and and if we deal in trust as intel
analysts then i can't have something on
a screen that's useless
that looks pretty and tries to get
people to go to an outcome because all
i'm telling them is i'm willing to
do tricks to get you to do what i want
you to do
and and that is is counter to everything
that it is to be an indulging
professional so it's just to me it's a
good example of one of one of the few
things you can actually be wrong on in
the world of intel
well that also goes into eroding trust
too right yes
absolutely
all right so i think we got about 10
minutes left for gin and tonic stuff um
so again as at the bottom of the
actually i'll go ahead and share my
screen again at the bottom of the blog
is uh this spreadsheet that i made this
morning for this talk uh and uh look
you're it's the same thing as intel this
is one of the reasons i love gen
cocktails and cocktails and cyber threat
intelligence have a lot in common in the
sense that like you do you there's
some bartenders out there and guides
they're like no it's going to be 1.5
ounces versus 2 ounces and like just do
it to taste yeah and i'm for that
purpose usually i have like a cocktail
set and i'll actually have like a 1.5
ounce and you know
shakers and everything else today i'm
going to keep it real simple i'm not
even getting precise on the measurements
but i put the ones that i like in the
excel spreadsheet for you but what i
wanted to do was show you how gin
cocktails don't have to be intimidating
like on the right side
of the screen like if you scroll over we
start getting into places where there's
you know chartreuse and brandy and and
you know creme de velez and and like you
know as a kid from alabama those are all
pretty big words and uh i'm like oh
that's intimidating and so if you start
over on the right hand side you're
probably not going to get antigen
cocktails but the classic one
so let's start with these um all of
these can be made with just very simple
ingredients right so if you've got your
lemon juice
and just get something nice easy right
real lemon is good got your lemon juice
you got your simple syrup you got some
greninden and you got some tonic you can
make four or five different drinks and
this isn't the world
of drinks here but as an example
we'll start with one of the gens i'll
use the botanist there's a bunch of
different types of gens out there of
course
what we generally like to see is
natural grains like something that's
very pure and i like to keep the
ingredient list pretty small there's
plenty different styles out there so
like roku jin out of the centauri
distillery in japan you'll notice that
it's um essentially uh grain neutral
spirits with juniper all your gens are
gonna have juniper in it and then they
pick like six local japanese botanicals
same thing we've got this one here bar
hill from maryland that's where i live
currently um support actually sorry i
bought it in maryland it's from vermont
but it's uh the local local place that
gives it out and this one is just
juniper and honey and the natural grain
spirits so everything's going to have a
different little flavor the botanist is
one of my go-to's
they've got a little over 20
different botanicals in here
and it's from scotland
one of the things that i like is if i
just take and i'll just take a
let's see nice cubicle over here
drop it in and i'll i'll give it a a
decent pour i'm again normally you'd
want to measure these things out so i
just give it a decent little pour
and if i do nothing more than get some
fever-tree tonic water which is um
kind of a go-to for me as well
right
if i just poured that in that would be
the gin and tonic right but if i if i
take the same ingredient list and just
add a little bit of greninja just
a nice little splash of that the same
gin and tonic that i had
with one extra ingredient i've got
another extra drink here pour that in
together i get a nice little
uh
pink flavor pink looking pomegranate gin
and tonic this i'm putting down is the
g2 and t technically it's called
pomegranate genatonic but i just love
that it's gen grenadine and tonic so g2
and t um or the gin and tonic but again
if i had this same drink and started
adding just a little bit different
things
i'd get a completely different drink in
this case if i take the gin and tonic
add the grenadine now i've got this one
and if i take the the um
same ingredient list
but take out the grenadine i can just
put a little lime juice and simple syrup
in there and i've got a completely
different drink
so all in all i'm very simple yeah
lickety
go ahead you had something
oh
yeah yeah maybe a little bit but
by and large it's uh it's linked in the
uh the blog there for you
um but
um actually let me see if i can see on
the youtube channel looks okay over
there um
let's get a little bit more complicated
so
those are stuff that you can easily make
um at home when we come over here
the next kind of class of ones to make
is when you can start adding some egg
whites
i find the egg whites really really take
a drink to the next level by having it
be a smooth
kind of frothy consistency all of these
you're going to come up with basically
the same ingredients to get to so again
i'm kind of clustering these and hey
pick one out of these five with these
same ingredients pick one of these
through these ingredients um in this
case i'll do a clover club so the trick
with egg whites
is sometimes you'll shake things over
ice but when it's an egg white you want
to do a dry shake so that you don't
break down the proteins in the egg yolk
or the egg white i'm in this case right
pour a little bit of gin in my shaker
here
i'm roughly three ounces but again i'm
pouring to sight um you can pour the
side if you want but probably better
uh to have your um to be able to
measure it out
but again for a computer desk in my home
office we're gonna do the best we can
so get the lemon juice here for one
ounce of lemon juice take a little bit
of that grenadine that i showed earlier
i can figure out where i put it right
here so take that nice little green
indian right that pomegranate flavor put
a little splash of it
and then
all we're going to do is take the egg
white
which hopefully this all works well in
my home office
crack the egg
and then i'm going to just collect
the egg yolk you can use the shell to do
that here
essentially if you can take a look all
i'm doing is having the shell kind of
balance out as i pour out the yolk but
pour out the egg white but keep the yolk
in there right you don't want to break
that yolk or anything like that i'm
going to take that just the egg white
that i've got here
throw it in to the shaker
that opposite side and like i said we're
going to just do a nice dry shake
there's no ice in here
um just simple
and that's gonna allow that um egg white
to be able to mix in get pretty fluffy
it's gonna make a nice drink at the end
if i want to then i can add some ice
either in there and do a wet shake
afterwards so shake it over ice or i can
just throw
an ice cube or so into a nice glass pour
it out and we get this kind of nice
little fluffy looking
like little pink monstrosity here
but all in all a nice little drink
yeah i know you guys can't taste it but
it's phenomenal it was funny when they
told me it was a pg-13
rated talks it turns out there's a lot
of cussing and
alcohol in pg-13 movies i don't know
what they're trying to tell me there but
it's all about the same
um beyond that another very simple drink
that i'm not gonna make here today now
but one i could with the same ingredient
list is if i just take gin some lemon
juice and some honey that is the bee's
knees and you can also just add a nice
little uh twig of lavender to it if you
want to do a nice lavender
bee's knees but this is the one that
we'll go to next
across the
earl grey martini and royal tea martini
or the royal tea cocktail
i love these because they have tea in it
i'm a big tea fan
um in the earl grey martini you would
actually just infuse the gin so as a
quick aside you can infuse gen with
almost anything just take your favorite
bottle of gem
like an aviation gen pour it into some
mason jars and muddle up some like
strawberries and throw it in there or
blueberries or rhubarb or something
flavorful in this case
the leaves of one of your favorite teas
and put in the fridge for five days
every day shake it up a little bit at
the end strain it out you have a nice
flavorful infused gin
so in like a martini as an example um
what you're doing in a martini is
generally gen and vermouth in this case
though you can do gen with some lemon
juice simple syrup uh egg white and uh
earl grey uh infused gin that's pretty
fun bryson you got something for me
uh yeah nope um it's time to toast you
off oh all right well for the the last
pour here what i would tell you is make
some um
breakfast tea
um breakfast tea with some lemon juice
uh throw that in with
some honey make the honey and the tea
before you chill it but you'll chill
that honey and tea with that lemon juice
pour in some gin
throw in an egg white in there and it'll
make the royalty cocktail which is one
of my favorites it's a nice little
breakfast or brunch i'm gin and cocktail
for you and as i said as you go across
the list there's some more complicated
ones for you but if you're able to
master the gin and tonic add some
grenadine if you want master the clover
club and master the royalty three nice
gin and tonics are jenning cocktail
drinks for you to be able to enjoy
over this nice pandemic so with that
thanks everybody for sticking around and
uh bryson back over to you all right
cheers those of you who are do dry
january the talks are recorded so you
will be able to make all those drinks
afterward um rob your spreadsheet is
that something that's going to be
publicly available yep on the blog that
i threw in the slack the one that i
threw up earlier it is the
very bottom of the blog
is the excel spreadsheet that has all
this information in for you
all right sounds good
all right