thank you so much for coming this
afternoon to our next session cyber
security for the defense of democracy we
have three speakers from the defending
democracy program today and before I do
their entry in intros a couple little
housekeeping things
just remember QA is at the end of the
session I know you guys are gonna have
exciting questions to ask don't like
burst out in the middle of the
presentation please but save them for
the end we have runners on both sides of
the rooms who will bring you a mic if
you're a social media user please you
know be considerate don't you know if
you have concerns or hard questions
before you drop them on Twitter please
take advantage of the Q&A time to ask
them because we're trying our best to be
very transparent and honest and open
about some of the programs going on at
Microsoft today and have that dialogue
with you
and so dialogue happens best in person
versus with the entire Internet but feel
free to feel free to tweet as well and
then please turn off or silence your
mobile devices I don't have a cute
little video like in the movie theaters
but you get the idea so getting started
with our next session we have yawn newts
Bobbi O'Brien and Ginny bed bidet bidet
ins the Don's I'm sorry I should have
checked that first here to speak with us
today
Bobbi is a senior cybersecurity
strategist and the program management
lead for the cyber security and
democracy team yon is the director of
cyber security policy at Microsoft and
leads the team and Ginny is the director
of special programs I mean special
strategic programs we're just gonna add
new things to her title Ginny's kind of
awesome so we're gonna let them get
started and thanks so much for your time
and attention
[Applause]
great thank you can everybody hear me
okay excellent well thank you so much to
our friends at nsrc for having us
my name is Janowitz I lead our defending
democracy program and it's our special
honor really do have a slot on this on
this agenda and be able to share with
all of you some of the things that we're
doing as part of part of this effort
which is a fairly new effort at
Microsoft let me just kind of before we
get into what specifically we're doing
as a team and as part of our program
back up for a second and and share
obviously some of the context for how we
got to where we got and I I would assume
that all of this is quite familiar to to
all of you but one of the main drivers
obviously for us to be concerned about
cyber enabled threats to democracy is
the fact that nation-state cybersecurity
attacks and and and and threats are
increasing and so we our team put
together just a very basic high-level
timeline on what some of these attacks
entail and I think part of it is to tell
the story that obviously these attacks
have increased in frequency they are
becoming to some degree more
sophisticated and one of the I think
things that are of most concern is the
targets that these actors are going
after are no longer some of the more
traditional targets and motivations
really for financial gain or maybe more
traditional military espionage it has
really become a tool in trying to
interfere with some of the most core
processes and institutions that underpin
our democratic societies that was
evidenced not only in the 2016 US
elections which I think we're all
familiar with but frankly it's been a
concern around the world for many
democratic countries when you look at
the French elections in 2017 the fact
that the German parliament got
compromised in the run-up to the German
elections and when you read some of the
reporting out there the Canadian
Intelligence Agency recently put out
port that estimated at about 40
countries in the last 10 years or so has
have had their electoral processes
targeted through cyber means by
nation-state actors so this is this is
certainly something that is on the rise
and and I think it is of concern to to
all of us as I mentioned we have some
prominent examples of this and in part
because of what we're what we're
witnessing it sort of occurred to us and
it seems to us that democracy itself
really needs a cyber security strategy
and part of of this context has then led
Microsoft to decide earlier this year
that we need to do more that that we
can't just rely on the fact that
governments or others in industry are
going to take steps in this regard and
we're all aware that many governments
are very concerned about this and are
taking important steps but we too from
Microsoft perspective need to think
about what we can do in this context
from a much more holistic perspective
there just for some context there's been
a lot of work going on at the company
for years working with political parties
working to some degree with some of the
main political committees both in this
country and also in other countries
around the world but what we wanted to
do by launching the defending democracy
program is to bring all of this together
in an insert of a more robust way and
and when we will not announce the
program on April 13 of this year and
there were four things that we said we
were going to do and so four core
pillars to to our program one is to
think about ways and and very actively
work with the campaign ecosystem to
protect campaigns from from hacking and
help campaigns better protect their
infrastructure and and the way that they
are able to secure themselves and so
campaign security is a huge component
off of this work
the second piece of course relates to
processes that are underpinning the
elections themselves so how
folks both at the state and local level
in this country sometimes the federal
level in other countries are leveraging
technology and securing that technology
to run the voting process and that's
everything from voter registration
databases to tallying of the vote
securing those pieces as well as then
reporting out and vote and both Bobby
and and and Ginny you in a moment will
talk about those two aspects in
particular but there's a second part to
this which is really closely connected
and I think we are in our minds at least
well advised to think about the threats
to democracy in a holistic manner it's
not just the underlying infrastructure
that we're concerned about it's also
very much on what you call the content
side and and the two things that really
stand out there are disinformation
campaigns computational propaganda that
we've seen several nation-state actors
employ there's one particular
nation-state that I think we're all most
concerned about in that regard and then
there is the issue which is closely
related and that's advertising political
advertising especially in the online
space and the transparency that that or
lack thereof that we that we all need to
need to take a hard look at and figure
out what we can do from an industry
perspective what some sound policies in
that space looked like and so on and so
that is my quick intro for you in terms
of what we're doing we're very much
looking forward to broadening out our
partnerships as a program as I said
we're a fairly new effort and if you
want to get engaged with us in our team
please do reach out both if you're
working on these problem sets from a
technical perspective if you're here
representing a government organization
we'd love to hear from you and learn
from you if there are initiatives going
on in this space and with that turn it
over to Jenny thank you
okay so campaign security there are a
few things to think about
yawns already alluded to them when we
talk about campaigns and why they need
special attention right now not just in
the US but abroad of course we know
about what happened in 2016 and as he
mentioned there are a lot of other
incidents in other
countries as well where information was
all of a sudden weaponized wasn't used
for traditional espionage like we've
seen it previously but it was used in
that in a new and kind of different way
but before we get into the details of
what we're doing now I think it's
helpful to talk a little bit about how
Microsoft's been engaged in the campaign
space previously there were teams who
have already been working with the
political campaigns and committees we
supported the Iowa caucuses in 2016
through technology solutions to help
them get the vote right and get the
results reported on time we also
supported the National nominating
conventions for the two parties in the
US and that was really an infrastructure
build we helped with both security as
well as just their operations as they
led up to the conventions so this is a
space that the company has been paying
attention to has been plugged into and
engaged in previously but when we think
about campaigns and the party committees
and the folks who are in that ecosystem
and we think about it from a security
standpoint there are a few things that
make them a little bit different
campaigns are traditionally not very
well funded and I'm speaking in the u.s.
context right now and that is somewhat
contrary sometimes to what you might
hear in the media where you hear about
millions of dollars especially because
the US has such a different system
sometimes people have this impression
that campaigns do have a lot of money
the money is all based on donor
contributions from donors and they are
often fighting for resources as to how
they want to spend that money and they
are motivated by victory right so
they're going to spend the money on ways
that they can see to getting out the
vote and it's often very difficult to
get them to you spend those hard-earned
funds on basic infrastructure and IT
setup the other thing to think about is
campaigns are often like startups in
that they start up really quickly
they've got an influx of some money and
they have to build out really quickly
the difference though is that they crash
and they're over soon after so there is
no longevity in what they're trying to
build they're built to be temporary and
that is not a great scenario when you
want to emphasize security and get them
to think about security they don't hire
IT teams occasionally they will some
well-funded campaigns will actually have
an outside IT firm that will do work for
them but often the person who's running
their IT is also the guy that they
depend on to do their digital ad buys so
they're not
thinking of this the same way that other
companies or traditional larger
companies will but when you combine that
with the vulnerability that they
experience right now especially and the
fact that we know that they are under
attack and the fact that we know that
their nation-states and others who want
to get into their emails who want to get
access to their documents that's really
kind of recipe for a disaster we had two
talked about the context limit on so
many of you probably heard about in fact
many of you were probably involved in an
announcement that the company made
earlier this last month referencing some
spoofed sites where Microsoft again
folks probably in this room identified
that there were sites that were being
spoofed for phishing attempts
particularly for the organization's IRI
which is International Republican
Institute and the Hudson Institute as
well as a generic Senate site and also a
Microsoft site and so when these sites
were identified one thing that we did
that was a little bit different and
stepped out of kind of a traditional
path is that Brad Smith authored a blog
that not only referenced the specific
sites that we found but also attributed
them to strontium also known as fancy
bear which is one of the connected
Russian organizations so in that
announcement one thing that you may have
heard about as well was the release of a
new program that our team is running
that we're calling account guard so just
want to talk a little bit about what
account guard is and who it's targeted
for because we have identified the need
that these campaigns have for some
additional protections one thing that we
as a team wanted to identify early was
how can we between now and the midterm
elections how can we come alongside our
customers so these are political
campaigns committees as well as think
tanks democracy advocacy organizations
and then also some of the vendors who
are these little small companies who do
work on the tech frontlines for these
organizations as well how can we come
alongside them and help them protect
themselves as they lead up to the
election and so a count guard is
fundamentally about offering three
things first and foremost it's about
education I guess we can go into this
slide first and foremost it's about
education
and the reason for that is we did a
little bit of sort of a listening tour
with some security professionals many of
them probably in this room where we
wanted to understand how we could come
and help these customers and these folks
and the first thing we heard was look
there's no voodoo that the that the
security community can do that's going
to be better than these guys turning on
multi-factor authentication there's
nothing that we can do to help track or
monitor attacks against them if they're
not showing that they can have good
passwords and we took that really
seriously because while we are enlisting
support of folks like you and and across
the company we do also want to make sure
that we are talking to these customers
about what they can do to protect
themselves with the equipment and the
features and the tools that are already
there and so with that in mind we lead
with education so when folks opt into
the program and enroll in it the first
thing that we do is send them
prescriptive guidance and we start
talking to them about hey we know you're
using office 365 here are some really
easy ways that you can protect yourself
with the program that already exists
here are some ways that you can turn on
multi-factor authentication at least for
your admins
okay now let's roll it out to the rest
of your users and then we also give them
guidance on things like best-case
scenario for for how you can teach your
your your employees to use better
password security and we use things that
are not just Microsoft focused but also
based on other products that are out
there because we're really trying to
educate them about how they can have
better security so education is the
first tool in account guard the second
is what we're calling cross account
notifications so what is kind of unique
here is there's a process already that
if a customer if our threat intelligence
team notify is aware that a customer has
been attacked or breached by a
nation-state actor that we go through a
process by which we notify them of that
but what's unique about account guard is
we're inviting them to include
individuals within their organization so
its employees maybe if we're talking
about a campaign maybe it's the spouse
of the candidate any individual who is
going to likely be targeted because of
their affiliation with the group that is
opted into the program if they have an
individual personal Microsoft account so
that's a hotmail comm or an outlook.com
account they can also opt
into account guard individually they'll
get access to the education components
that come with it already but what
they'll also get is they'll be granting
us permission that if they are attacked
or breached by one of these known
nation-state actors and we detect it we
can then notify their organization that
we see that happening on their
individual account so what this is doing
is trying to close an information gap
that exists in this election community
so the example here as we've already
referenced is the John Podesta situation
where his personal gmail account was
attacked and hacked because of his
affiliation with the Clinton campaign
however no one really knew that the two
were connected because of course they
were separate accounts and so with the
permission of the individuals we're now
able to notify the organization they're
affiliated with if we see that activity
it also provides a better mapping
situation for our threat intelligence
teams so they can tell that this random
hotmail comm account over here is
actually the campaign manager of this
really important Senate race and that
provides them with a better mapping of
what the threats are and then the third
aspect of the program is that we're
we're providing access to private
previews for folks in this in this
audience that's not all that interesting
or new but when you think about the pace
of a political campaign you think about
where their attention is and their focus
is they are not paying attention to our
latest and greatest office 365 security
private preview they don't know it
exists they don't know how to get to it
they don't really care so what we're
doing is reaching out to them and saying
hey there's a really cool program that
we think will really make your security
better and we sort of walk them through
the process of getting them enrolled or
at least at the very least making sure
that they're aware of it so that's a
count guard in a nutshell and then
Bobby's gonna come talk to you about our
work with election integrity great Thank
You Jenni so I wanna talk briefly today
about election integrity I wanna start
actually in the year 2000 which many of
you remember that election not for
security reasons but because of the
issue of hanging Chad and other issues
around ballot discrepancy so what did
that do in effect what it did is it
shown a lot of light on the American
election process it brought to light a
lot of significant issues with that
process and ultimately stimulated some
congressional action in terms of the
2002 help America votes act in 2016 we
had a little bit of a similar scenario
the difference was was initially
discrepancy in ballots resulting from
hanging chads but instead security
incidents that brought election
integrity into question so where did
that leave us
really what it led us to an
understanding of the fact that the u.s.
election process itself is really a
system of systems the questions around
election integrity shone a light again
on our election processes and showed
just how complex they are so I have a
few different visuals here from a report
that was recently put out called
securing the vote from the National
Academy of Sciences Josh Bonello who may
or may not be here but as in Microsoft
Research and as a senior cryptographer
was actually a part of that committee
really what these visuals are designed
to do is talk about all the different
elements of the election process or at
least some of them and how complex they
are so on the top left there you can see
a mapping at the county level of
different voting machines that are in
use and you can see that it's enormous
ly diverse you have the election process
itself which consists of multiple
different elements and then you have
systems that are tied into the election
process could be the DMV could be an
online VR system as well all in all
you're talking about 10,000 different
election administration jurisdictions
many of them have the ability to make
their own decisions about how an
election occurs from a security
perspective obviously this makes things
extremely challenging so what are some
of the early emerging election security
recommendations the first and you guys
will probably laugh a little bit these
because these are recommendations to
kind of come up in any security context
the first is let's put more money into
the into the game okay so there's
there's a legitimate reason for this
after the 2000 election the help America
Vote Act authorized somewhere between
three and four billion dollars to date
the only additional funding that's gone
out for the purpose of election security
since 2016 from the government has been
380 million dollars so that's quite is
quite a difference a second is
information sharing again this is
probably one that you guys security
practitioners hear quite a bit in this
context we see information sharing both
from being proposed both from a
perspective of private enterprise you
know sharing information with government
but more importantly with the federal
government sharing information with the
state government and vice versa
the secure elections Act which is a
bipartisan piece of legislation that was
or is co-sponsored by amongst others the
chair and vice chair of the Senate
Intelligence Committee who performed a
pretty authoritative investigation into
the 2016 election looked at information
sharing is a core piece of the puzzle in
terms of solving some the election
security issues so what does that look
like it looks like you know if a state
experiences a verified target of its
voter registration databases providing
that information to other states
providing that information to the
federal government if the federal
government from an intelligence
perspective is aware of verified threats
against us elections writ large
providing that information to States and
so information sharing has also been one
of the early election security
recommendations the final recommendation
to note is this idea of audits and
particularly post-election audits I
think this has gained a lot of traction
because generally the idea as well you
know if we know that some of these
systems may be targeted and in fact may
be tampered with we at the very least if
we can't protect that and we assume some
form of breach we need to be able to
determine afterwards that that breach
occurred and it that the results have
been affected in the audit space one of
the areas in particular that's been
discussed is this idea of risk limiting
audits risk limiting audits were
developed in the late 2000s what they do
is they provide statistically robust
assurance that an election outcome is in
line with the the votes cast at an
accepted level of risk but today my very
brief overview of some of the work on
election integrity really what I want to
get back to is this idea that we're
really at the early days of
understanding especially the US side let
alone the International side the
end-to-end vulnerabilities in the
election process and in fact when you
hear a lot of the dialogue that's
focusing on issues related to election
integrity really what it's focused on is
what we know was targeted in 2016 in
some cases more granularly what we know
to be vulnerabilities whether it relates
to you know voting systems voter
registration databases so on and so
forth one of the things that we've been
toying with as a team is the idea of not
only how can use cyber security
technology to help defend democracy but
how also how can you instill
cybersecurity methods into the process
of thinking about the defense of
democracy and so one that we've talked
about that will
the old news to many of you but is in
fact news to many of the stakeholders
that were working with is the idea of
basically threat modeling hey we need to
understand if we look across the
elections we understand there gonna be
many different vulnerabilities do we
actually understand where those
vulnerabilities are and what the impact
is if they're exploited is it the case
for instance that voter registration
databases which were targeted
overwhelmingly in 2016 or actually the
most critical vulnerability that we need
to go out and protect or should that
investment be spent someplace else
and so one of the questions that we're
really asking and I have a nice little
picture up here that part looks familiar
to many of you of the Microsoft threat
modeling tool is what does that threat
model for democracy look like at a broad
level well more specifically we got to
look good elections what does the threat
model look like how do we think through
the exercise from you know a technical
and a political perspective frankly in
an interdisciplinary way of thinking
about if you were an adversary and you
wanted to affect an election whether
it's u.s. presidential election or
election a particular jurisdiction what
would actually be the Avenue the threat
vector that you would use to have the
most impact and so with that I want to
pivot to our call to action
we'll start with young sure so first of
all thank you both I thought that was it
was terrific maybe what one thing I'd
like to do is actually ask we have we
have members of the team in the room so
could I ask members of the define
democracy program to stand up so you get
a sense of oh there we go
excellent if you want to connect with
the team these are the folks that you
should feel free to reach out to in
addition to whom you're seeing on stage
quick word about the team it's a diverse
group of highly talented people that I
get to work with we have some
technologists as well as public policy
experts and some legal expertise and so
we really are sort of a cross domain
team trying to focus on these issues the
reason I mentioned that is we are
recruiting and so if you're interested
in getting in touch with us please do
please do reach out but it's not just
about this being a great recruitment
ground this really also is about us
wanting to as I said earlier learn about
initiatives that
all of you might be engaged in our
programs you're running where we can
explore opportunities for for full
partnership so another call to action is
getting involved in the democratic
process and that can mean it's national
voter registration week so I have to
make the plug register to vote if you're
not already registered to vote democracy
starts with you but other than that
other ways that you can get involved
outside of the traditional volunteering
and knocking doors you all have a very
special set of skills and so those are
really desperately needed in this space
right now there are a lot of nonprofit
groups fairly small for the most part
but there are some nonprofit groups out
there that are looking for people with
security expertise who can volunteer
their time contributing to campaigns or
committees or others in this space who
really need some help we're happy to
connect you with them they tend to be
partisan but there are ones on both
sides so if you have a particular
interest please it really goes back to
the first point please feel free to
reach out to us and we're happy to
connect you with some of the
organizations that will connect you and
let you sort of bring your expertise and
help these campaigns because they
certainly could use some of your support
and the last thing is just a discussion
point I would encourage everybody to
think creatively about ways cyber
security technology and methods can
actually be put to work in defending
democratic institutions threat modeling
is just one example amongst many in
addition as you're going through your
own security exercises whether it's a
final security review or other security
reviews along the way to releasing a
product or a feature or service think
about the potential impact that that
service could have on some of these
democratic institutions I think it'll be
a fun exercise if you have any have any
good learnings please share them with us
and with that we were happy to take your
questions is there any
hello I
I've spoken with someone on a the Senate
IT team who been up balloons the
separation between the hard separation
between personal mail campaign mail and
government mail where it just becomes is
completely unmanageable for them do you
have any insight or or guidance that
you're working on with a federal level
to try and and deconflict some of this
or change policies so when i talked
about account guard i didn't mention
that we are looking at how we can expand
it we've had a lot of requests from
different industries and markets where
we can expand it one of the areas that
would really really like to go to that
we're just working up the legal aspect
of it is to Congress and Senate their
official offices if they're using office
365 but they have Microsoft personal
accounts essentially what account guard
is doing is trying to bridge that very
gap obviously it's really newsy with
what happened last week and the reports
that Senate staff were being targeted on
their personal accounts we can't of
course have much control over their
personal accounts if they're not related
to Microsoft products though we do talk
to our colleagues at other companies and
they know everyone's really thinking
about this right now but the way that we
as Microsoft can impact that is trying
to bring a count guard to other groups
like that and and try and bridge the gap
between those accounts the the other
issue there that we were on up against
and again this is a real-world issue
that many of you probably deal in many
areas but we run into for instance in
the account guard scenario or other
scenarios regarding security things like
campaign finance restrictions and Ginny
can speak a little bit to what we did in
that space but there are blockers from
an administrative and a legal
perspective oftentimes to actually
getting security best practices into
space and that's part of our remit as a
team is to figure out how we can you
know overcome some of those hurdles yeah
it was our goal to do it from the
beginning but we there's legal concerns
but to his point one thing that we did
we are offering this to political
campaigns right now well there are laws
about offering things for free to
political campaigns essentially you
can't do it
and the count guard is not something
that we were up charging for it's
considered and
additive feature for our existing
customers who are eligible so what we
did was we wrote a letter to the FEC
the Federal Election Commission
requesting not a waiver so much as
saying we think that this is our our
choice to add this feature to our
customers who are already paying we
think it fits well within federal
election laws do you agree and they held
a hearing the FEC this is something you
won't hear very often was really
wonderful and they voted on a they did
it they held the hearing as quickly as
was possible given their constraints and
rules so it was within ten days of us
submitting the letter and they voted
unanimously across partisan lines to
approve it which I don't know the last
time they did that on any matter they're
pretty much deadlocked on everything
these days so it's a good indication
that they think that this is important
and also that we were making a good
legal case we hope to make that same
case for the federal government
customers as well as for a particular
state customers we also hope to make
that case as we expand it to other
democracies because this isn't something
that we want to limit to US customers
we'd really like to spread it to others
as well but as you can imagine every
country has its own rules its own laws
gdpr like there are a lot of things to
consider and so we're working on next
and expending it expanding it as best we
can elsewhere yeah I may be able to pick
up on that last point so really
important we are trying to actually take
elements of this program both in terms
of what we're doing with a count guard
but also more broadly to other countries
around the world there's a lot of as you
all know there are many many elections
happening all the time there are some
some really from a geopolitical
perspective interesting countries coming
up - they're holding elections in
particular central Eastern Europe but
also we're seeing Latin America and and
so we've had a lot of had a lot of
interest both internally in the company
but also externally from from partners
and from from governments frankly to to
figure out ways for how we can partner
with them on some of these questions and
I think that's just maybe maybe do
highlights of the global nature of the
of the program and I think the other the
other piece really around the question
of account core what you were saying you
know we
we're grateful obviously that the FEC
move moved fast on this those those
rules clearly differ country by country
and so there are some places where we
able to move a little faster than then
than others but we're quite enthusiastic
really about the opportunity to work
with with these stakeholders in advance
of the midterm elections because clearly
they're coming up very fast and we were
thinking about ways that we could
actually offer something impactful in in
a very short order of time last last
piece on this is the other thing that
we've really noticed and feedback we've
been getting is is obviously great for
us as one company to try and help and
provide some of these solutions but we
also see a need for a lot most of cross
industry collaboration and I think you
know it's fair to acknowledge that some
of the other major players in the space
I've started to offer similar similar
services I obviously think account card
is very special but but series and first
but the serious point is just from sort
of a threat perspective it makes a lot
of sense from our perspective to
coordinate some of these things in a
more robust way but when it comes to for
example threat Intel sharing and so
we're thinking about ways we actively
and we're in conversations with with our
partners about how we how we can
accomplish that questions hi
so I've noticed some places around our
country are starting to dabble in
electronic voting as you have an opinion
on that do you want to collect a couple
of questions yeah there's there's one
state West Virginia who recently
announced that they are doing blockchain
voting online through an app and they're
they're doing it for military
professionals who are living abroad so
I'll start by saying that we commend
West Virginia for trying to think about
how they can solve this very big problem
of how they make sure that their
citizens and
you know remembers their state for
abroad especially those serving the
country abroad are able to cast their
vote and do it in a way that's timely
and will be counted so we recognize that
as far as the principle of voting in
that method we think that there are
probably some better ways that it can be
done I think that the general consensus
right now is moving away from anything
electronic for the mechanism of actually
voting so even in the polling places the
direction everything is going is really
towards paper ballots but it's worth
remembering that while you that is a
problem that needs to be solved and
addressed it is an end-to-end issue that
we're talking about you're not gonna get
voter registration back on paper right
that will take everyone back many steps
we need to be able to have solutions
where people are able to register to
vote
we need accessible solutions for folks
to actually cast their ballot and
sometimes paper is not the most
accessible way so there there's going to
be an electronic component in voting
somewhere in the process and we as a
community as well as others who are
thinking about that's really hard need
to find a way to make that as most and
most secure as possible and just a
double-click on that really briefly I
flashed the National Academy of Sciences
report up there I mentioned the secure
Elections Act again and again you see
recommendations coming out from this
election security community it's a there
at least needs to be an audible paper
trail that paper trail in particular is
actually a requirement for risk limiting
audits versus considered sort of state
of the art and so regardless of what we
feel individually on this matter you can
see that the consensus as a whole is
really moving in in that direction all
right great
yes so with a lot of the work that NIST
has been doing over the past decade with
the cybersecurity framework has helped
private enterprises and then most
recently the work that they've been
doing for small to medium businesses you
know producing a simplified version of
that it seems like all the work that
Microsoft is committing today along with
some parallel work being done by Google
and other tech companies it seems like
we're in a position where we might even
begin discussing with engagement nest to
produce another set of standards for
elections do you know from your vantage
point is of those engagements begun or
what's the state of discussion in that
area yeah it's an absolutely fantastic
point and in fact one of the things that
we didn't mention is that you know US
elections were actually classified as
critical infrastructure fall
in 2016 which actually technically
brings up within scope of the
cybersecurity framework you know to date
the savage security framework obviously
wasn't focused on Elections its
cybersecurity framework for critical
infrastructure now so I know that
there's work underway and that domain
that we're attempting to plug into
there's questions about exactly how it
will fit into the framework what that
will look like
in addition and again this is one where
Josh Bonello is very involved there's
the voluntary voter standards guidelines
the V VSG and other sort of standards
work that's been done across the federal
level that's engaged in this quite
closely yeah in terms of figuring out
you know in that case it's not just
security it's across the voting process
writ large but I think the long and
short of it is you're absolutely right I
think that NIST is a place that has a
lot of expertise in this space that
could be ported over to look at this
issue area and we're actively looking at
engaging them on that start in the back
good afternoon I wanted to ask to one of
the points that you made earlier about
how was in industry we have a lot of
companies wanting to work together on
this kind of topic I'm actually very
curious in terms of US government for
example is there are lots of interagency
--zz wanting to work together for these
things because kind of looking at
government it feels like there's a bit
of a hands-off like we're going to
handle it our way we're gonna handle it
our way so I'm very curious is there
that actual collaboration between
various government agencies for this
type of topic also been saying that the
government agencies have specifically
DHS has two task force task forces that
are really focused on this one is the
foreign influence task force there's a
little bit more in the disinformation
social media side then they also have an
election security task force that's
headed up by a gentleman named Matt
Masterson who actually was running the
EAC I notice is getting really wonky but
like the AC was the election assistance
Commission point is he's really
knowledgeable really understands the
challenges that are facing the states as
far as what they're trying to do from a
security standpoint I know that they are
reaching out to all of the tech
companies I know your question is more
about interagency but sugar starting by
saying how they're reaching out to us
and to our community they're doing a
very good job of trying to create a
dialogue going back to your slide about
information sharing in an informal way
there are already some formal mechanisms
of course for sharing information I know
that they work with FBI closely who has
parallel task forces that they've set up
for similar purposes I'm not like in
their business so I don't know how
they're all talking to each other but I
do know that these task forces are set
up for the very purpose of creating
dialogue not just with one another but
also with us and others who are invested
in the space like NGOs and nonprofits
who are doing a lot of work with
elections okay the other thing I'd add
on that is again this is an interagency
but it's that the federal state level
dynamic so you know by classifying
elections as critical infrastructure
that actually empowered DHS to put forth
tremendous resources to provide to
States States ultimately you know in
election jurisdictions are able to make
their own decisions but it opened up a
floodgate of new resources if you go
over the DHS website and you look at
things like the
election security task force you know
they're offering vulnerability scanning
services they're offering risk
management training they are setting up
Matt Masterson amongst others regular
setting up calls to coordinate there's
an information there's a nice AK and
other ways that really the federal
government is working directly with the
election administrators and the
secretaries of state who oftentimes
oversee elections to make sure that
they're able to maximize their their
security posture I think they have
Albert censors yeah in like almost every
state now the states are letting them in
to put in Albert censors so there's yeah
the that's a great point is the federal
state communication is better than you
might have expected it to be I've been
impressed with the work that they've
been able to do together quick question
so a lot of customers who aren't
political campaigns deep in
south-central kind of like energy
companies are kind of wondering how can
they benefit from this are the items
that you guys are doing or is it kind of
trickling down to our regular customers
or is there something they can do to
engage with you guys and say like hey
we're not a political campaign but we
are critical and for structure energy
company earrings like that or just
generally we just want to be as safe as
possible what what concussive other
customers do to help themselves in this
okay okay I just say you know our
program is part of a broader effort at
the company that is looking both into
cybersecurity policy from sort of
perspective off best practices
recommendations things like helping to
actually explain
the NIST cybersecurity framework which
which we certainly contributed to as
well as and there's a little bit more
specific to the efforts that you're
seeing here also connecting to different
security teams across the company and so
that's both on the proactive side when
it comes to security assessments but
also on the reactive side and so one of
the things we've been doing as for this
team is actually pull together what we
sort of called a broader virtual team
across the company that ties in these
these different these different pieces
of course there are many established
processes
is that Microsoft has not only nsrc we
got the C doc the cyber defense
Operations Center and and and and so on
that that that's of our part of our
broader security posture but we try
certainly whenever we come across things
that we think are applicable for other
stakeholders customers to make sure that
some of the not only the work that we're
doing with some of the lessons learned
and ultimately some of the some of the
sort of services that we're standing up
are going to be made available in to
broader audiences so like one example is
account guard right we're already seeing
that we saw so much interest from from
sort of the broader policy community and
sort of democratic institutions that we
decided to at launch go beyond just
political campaigns but also focus on
think tanks research institutions etc
we're actively thinking as Ginni said
about broadening that out further and as
we're developing for example best
practice and guidance be adhere at the
top ten ways you can secure your o365
account or your your your azure and
since many of those will be applicable
not just to campaigns but to many others
for example small and medium enterprises
and so we're working hand in glove with
those other teams that are focused on
those stakeholders here
thank you so so with regards to the
disinformation portion of the initiative
could you speak a little bit about how
Microsoft can contribute to this in a
way that's nonpartisan and also
respectful of freedom of speech sure
thank you for the question
so one of the things that we've really
been working on from a disinformation
perspective because obviously our you
know our services are quite different
from those who oftentimes have platforms
with disinformation manifests on the
platform itself it's actually working
predominant on research partnerships and
so some examples of research
partnerships are the Oxford internet
Institute in the UK who's created an
international election observatory which
is effectively taking sort of their
tried and tested methodology for
measuring the effect of particularly
computational propaganda but also some
other misinformation efforts and
applying it to specific election
scenario so they recently put out a
report on Sweden they're working on
Brazil obviously the u.s. election we're
also partnering with Princeton
University who's developing so what they
think are news sorry disinformation
detection tools I would also say that
there was a lot more work occurring
organically at the company in this space
then I had expected when we originally
came into it which is to say a lot of
very smart technologists and security
professionals some cases working on this
in hackathon context in some cases
within Microsoft Research working on
this from a technology research
perspective an economics research
perspective and so really the way that
we've been focusing on this is
predominantly through creating you know
new partnerships and trying to energize
the ecosystem who's focused on on this
issue area sure I can talk about that as
well so another another prominent
partnership that we announced was a
partnership with an organization called
News card news card technologies was
founded by Steven Brill and Gordon
Kravitz one of them was traditionally
associated with the left side of the
political spectrum one on the right side
there a long time experienced
journalists who hired a number of
different analysts typically individuals
who also have backgrounds in journalism
to effectively go look at
online news media in particular I think
it's like the top 98 percent of shared
online news media in the English
language in the United States and from a
journalistic perspective create a series
of nine transparent criteria go to the
source level which is like the site
itself the digital news media outlet not
at the article level and determine from
their perspective how that site lines up
against those criteria they then
manifest that what they call a nutrition
label which is something that's always
very easy for all of us to digest in
technical terms they have launched a
edge extension as well as a Chrome
extension that you can actually install
with one click when you do install it if
you go to Bing or to Google or even some
of the social media platforms you'll see
that next to an article if it's
associated with a new site that they
have rated you'll see either a green or
red shield or if it's the onion it's
actually a gesture in purple and if you
hover over that it'll tell you something
to the effect of either you know from
our perspective this site has been
complying with the basic practices of
journalistic integrity or you know
proceed with caution but still proceed
it also has more information from a
nutrition label perspective that you can
click on and get lots of extra data in
terms of their perspective on that site
Microsoft helped we're actually the
exclusive sponsor of the launch of the
browser plugin which came out on August
23rd and is available to consumers to
download for free really the way they
positioned themselves to your good point
about free speech is providing
additional context like a library would
on the background of the digital news
information that's being you know
consumed as opposed to telling you
whether or not to actually read it yeah
it's really important to understand
their approach is not and anyway about
censorship right which tracks very well
with our own approach to this this is
about additional providing additional
transparency and provenance about the
news source and so we think it's a
terrific effort they had a where they
have an ongoing partnerships with
libraries around the country where
they're trying to roll this out Los
Angeles Public Library
by many other public libraries as well
yeah and I think they're working on
blowing this out also by an API that
different mics very excited about the
news guy partnership I can tell what are
the biggest challenges you've faced
onboarding users and campaigns to de set
de faire like account guard yeah it's a
great question it's um it's getting
their attention and honestly it's it's
getting there you know what are we forty
days out or something from the midterms
right now and so getting a campaign to
have the person who's in charge of their
IT if they can find that person to go
online and request an invitation or if
we've invited them to get them to
respond to it it's it's a lot about
sharing the information so we've we've
tackled that in a couple ways first we
reach out to them directly as best as we
can identify our customers in that space
we also been working with the National
Party committees I'll say that every
eligible National Party committee has
enrolled in account guard and they
mentioned a few names so people get a
sense of okay oh wait it's a bipartisan
grouping will just say that but but
they've been working with us as well to
get the news out to their campaigns I
will say that it took a little while
because we had to get that FEC opinion
before they would really buy into it and
understandably they didn't want to put
themselves in a position where they
joined a program and then later turns
out it's illegal which was what we were
thinking when we went through the
process so we were really glad that it
worked out but yeah the campaign's the
committees have been helping encourage
the campaign's to find us and to enroll
and that's been really beneficial in
fact one of our colleagues Dave is going
to be doing a webinar with one of the
committees Dannette just next week where
they're going to have all of their
campaigns join and he's going to talk to
them about account guard and sort of
spouse the virtues of it and why they
should enroll so the biggest challenge
has been awareness and attention but
even if they're aware of it just getting
them to actually engage we probably have
time for one more question okay
do you have them do y'all tell me doctor
up there between nation state level
actors and financial constraints and
lack of awareness it seems like
compromises of especially if campaigns
is a question not of if but when yeah
and so I'm curious is there any thinking
around risk mitigation of yeah somebody
is going to get in can we make sure that
a candidate's entire email history
doesn't get dumped WikiLeaks well one
thing that we talk about when we talk
about education is essentially
essentially that like have a plan of
course no one wants to get hacked but if
you get breached do you know which
federal officials to call do you know
your local FBI person who you're
supposed to reach out to do you know you
have a comms plan that's something that
for example the Harvard group at the
Belfer Center in Harvard have been doing
a lot of work on reaching out to this
whole community there's a whole lot of
stuff that they're doing it's really
great you should check out their site
but one thing that they're doing now is
a coms plan to make sure that the that
they know how they're gonna respond to
the media in case this happens and that
they have thought about it beforehand so
there's certainly conversations
happening we're part of it others are as
well to think about what happens if and
when that breach occurs another thing we
didn't really talk about on account
guard I need to add it to my talking
points I don't know how I missed it
if that happens if we do and if we go
together with our colleagues and do a
notification of a breach to one of these
customers we are going to immediately
follow up with remediation
recommendations now because of a lot of
federal laws and whatnot we can't
actually go in and do remediation but we
can offer them some potential next steps
we can make recommendations for vendors
given their particular situation or what
we are aware has happened so we are
thinking about the worst-case scenario
though certainly we're leading with the
hey try not to let that happen but if it
does here are some things that you
should have planned ahead of time so
that's a great point because it's going
to happen all right thank you all so
much let's give them
[Applause]