I'd like to introduce you hi from Anna's
focus to talk about mitigation bypass
past present and future
yeah okay hello everyone thanks for
coming my name is a min Hye Jeong and
I'm a researcher or Fuu as a focus and I
was so win the occasion by past Ponte
for years you know law since the 2015 so
let's first review the posture of
communication bypass before 2002 just
good all the days of our ability exploit
because there's no medications at all so
exploiter is just travel forth take
apart all wrong it's just or right at
the return address in the stack and the
for hippo power over just or right at
the hip meditate just so simple so once
you find a vulnerability you can achieve
a little code execution that's very
simple so since I was changed there was
medications these are the medications of
force take a buffer or wrong and
medications are for HIPAA for more
important that there are general
medications that his the asar are and
the EP
this too is a DP and as they are
together can make exploited difficult
then you'll find the or ability you
counter simply or chew up the code
exclusion you need to do more work to
achieve that that's education bypass so
there are many ways to achieve this but
her most popular was first to get with
the right perm cues from the
vulnerability and then use this with the
writer capability to hijack a control
flow as a crafter the function point or
crafter with an address on the stack
post can lead to orbital called
extrusion that's the worry a classical
education bypass technical and it has
been used for many years but we are
Windows 10 was released since our
changed first hood there are new recent
strategic there will be two major
updates every year and new medications
in each update in the first or release
of Windows condenses the th1
Wakata safety and care to with carter
CLG and imager load the policy in our s1
Wakata
ECT and the child process policy and the
universe - regardless FG speaker mode
and sfg explorer expression and finally
in our s3 we got a nolo mandatory
boy image that's a extension of the
image loader policy so let's see these
new medications
first the most important medication is
CFG it's very very simple
just gather the interactive function
call or interact jump by validate to a
target in the compare time it will find
all possible interaction core target and
collected metadata of these functions in
the wrong time when the processors start
it will build a bitmap to mark or
derrida target and well new body over
our loader the bitmap safety presumable
we are being updated to mark the
functions inside module
finally we interact the core internal
function was a quote so we are be
inserted a small code to horrify that
the target was worried which he was
mocked from the bitmap
so with CFG we can't simply crop the
function pointer because the crop the
target we are not appear worried the
work so one way it was blocked so was
steel with an address program so the IPG
due to some reason FG was not a list now
because the current software based
implementation is not secure enough but
er we appeal how they are based
implementation so in but we don't know
many detail of that implementation now
so in this talk we don't cover this part
we just assume energy where without the
return address corruption program so
post way are blocked we can't simply
achieve a better code execution we need
a new medication bypass technique URLs
there was two category of this technical
one directly the watery safety to bypass
it and that the other chose alternative
way to achieve a little code exclusion
first first I'd like to see the water
technique house the first one is to use
the unprotected code there are many such
coder non-self G modules AIT generally
the code into a carriage Jam and sample
own job and writable I ate here what is
the kind of technical devices being
submitted to Microsoft
so there are which although one by one
dance FG module was blocked by CF
district mode JTA generated encoder was
broken up by Sergey or JIT into example
occupies safety or L chance
the satyr jump alone jump was blockaded
by longchenpa hardening finally rattle
all right here are removed so in the
long run we can you can consider it
shattered there will be no more
operational code so that away was
blocked the other Missouri técnico was
too
he was worried essentially with
functions such as we exist and he
continued or to a lock also protect hip
greater will feel each session that we
are be aware we were long list of such a
sensitive functions but I say I was
generic medication ways that is to use
the FG explicit operation that we are
explicitly superest sources essential
function and safety exporter suppression
we are make or exporter functions not
valid target in the long run you can
consider there we are being no more well
either sensitive functions but there
still will be wrapper functions here is
the for such a wrapper
there are what is the safety packet and
we are call so successful functions in
the implementation and the problem is
such kind of a function cannot be
generic found so they can only be
addressed the Kasbah case well why is
reported one can be resolved so in the
run say oh well well being such a
function
I think so this is the first program of
current medications okay let's see the
alternative bypass technical first is to
load a library
it's where we travel to call it the
library to load any library once you
pewter the reader right przemek used
here is a simple JavaScript code on
Saturday we can do this so with this
capability we can use UNC path to load
or remote library which to attacker can
fully control
so when since the library was load it we
are cattle exclusion to atrocities there
was no remote or immediate policy of the
material or the policy which we have
prevented a lot of round remote past
however the browser itself will catch
casual page state which you can be used
to deliver the library to local so we
can load the militia library from local
SOPA pastor no remotely migi policy to
address this there was this energy which
he parental loader on trustee the
library that is to say only Microsoft
resign the library can be loaded but a
crossover design in the total net and
native image is valid to be load and the
ether contains other blacks section
which you can modify user with the right
primitives and you can write the chakra
to that section and adjuster executed so
so the final medications ECG which we
are prevented the creation of a table
Code section if a city is enabled when
you will order such a total identity we
material field to create a second
section but if we but we when we cannot
allow such a library to create a table
section we still can load the older
version of an idea to call auntie
continue because the system core ID are
different from origin to version the ID
in the current system of NT continue is
the idea of an answer function in the
other version of an idea and the third
function can be a little safety target
so we can just load the other version
and cosine function it will actually do
what in the continue to so we can use in
the continue to issue of the code
execution so finally the no no mandatory
label image policy we are prevented
loader from catch fill because
Orfeo right by the browser we are being
mocked as low level so it can't be load
with all these medications what the
library technical RP blocked
so let's see the last type of mitigation
bypass technique out that his to abuses
the future I have a reporter for kind of
this technique oh the first thing is to
abuse unsafe calm object the second is
to abuse the JIT compile the soda is to
open use launch ie and the last one is
to abuse the Chinook SC one by one for
the common object the theory is very
simple the common objective is designed
to be used in different environment some
environment low unsafe calm objector
which you can do militia action such as
creating a new process and some
environment who is so low such as
browsers but how to do determine which
environment occur under the processor is
it's determined by some flags so we can
use the rewriter from table to modify
those flags and to remove the
restriction so we can in some in because
in the web browser to extension so safe
will come object and to create a new
process
this is a worry very interesting future
which can be abused and many people has
used this to gather the medication and
that past bounty this is for sure he
carted the first toe communication
Baba's upon him and his his tackle is
tested use a unsafe become object and
say yeah okay Tom keeper win the second
of medication Pappas Ponte I use the
similar tack like James for house and
there was a little window sort of funky
use just a similar technique cause what
the technical pewter in IE and
technicals cannot be used in the course
of the age because Microsoft HD do not
support her ActiveX however I will
wen-chi the to implemented they are
technical in because of the age just
just by changing some flags and bring
octavia causes back to age and let's say
use the same technical to achieve
arbiter code exclusion and I will talk
about that technical in the CSS covers
now let's see the second future can be
abused JIT compiler this technically I
have talked about two years just before
in blue-haired so I just simply
it was simply meaty to is to show it's a
very simple just find us someplace to
write on your shoulder and waiter the
Shattuck compiler to make a turtle
location excludable and you can run your
chakra from site a location
[Music]
many medications and further purpose in
this topic since I have talking about
hater so I under total detail this time
and one more thing
the OPA IT processes medication
technical condom equations this attack
you are fracture has talked about that
you can you can refer that talking
further detail so let's eat
so the future can be abused in Microsoft
age itself was a future called alar ie
that is where you browser web server
which is not all compatible with age
it'll we are shows this and you can
click the button to launch a ie to view
that page so in the internal is just a
simple transaction function call but we
you call this function in your web page
you are cattle and Iraq the permission
denied this is because the set of
functional we are check the URL which
causes the function so we can simply
just we writer the URL in the memory
and you can actually I to wheel anywhere
and since I is noticing every age there
was many you could see the way to
achieve the conclusion so you can
finally exclude any code so let us see
the last future can be abused that is
shima hook it seems that they are we are
hook particular functions by modifying
the IAT this is a very powerful future
because it will come modified with the
only date you can see this called
snipped it will check the protection of
the Takeda memory and make another
location variable modified and reverted
to the previous protection so if we can
abuse this future we can filter any code
because you can modify the modify an
encoder page to rattle your shellcode
how how the shim hook to the hook is so
it was guided by some meditators during
the SP pondan's structure so you can
just modify that structure to later the
assumes modify any data for you
including the riddling areas and they
achieve a vertical exclusion so we can
you can see for the future abusing
technique house there was not a general
communication way there can only be so
the Kasbah case so this is the second
program of the current medication okay
let us see the future of communications
first as I has talked up Saturday repeat
the Intel CT paster RF t this is a
hardware based alpha T since this
medication is not released yet we don't
know much detail so we are not talking
much about it yet and the others the
other thing is we are P fine grid safety
many problem of the current setting
plantation is the Chester because he is
only cross grid CFI so we enter fine
corridor FG many current technical
cannot be used however even zo was fine
credo safety control still can be reject
I think because nowadays long travel
applications are very complicated so -
we are always be internal cause that has
multiple worried attacking exists and
some copies are not actually not allowed
because of logical reason that cannot be
detected by the assembly logo so if we
you modify the function pointer to that
logical not a low target you can still
hijacker the control flow and do some
malicious scenes
and another another way of medication
purposes is to use existing FG bypass
technique as you can see it's in the
education by was the party page there
are so many out of school kind of
technique oh it's a long list
many of this is the technical steel can
be used in the future
UNC I was a fine career self G and that
the last important is current current a
medication has too many critical data
protected a pirate only such as the
cutter dispatch here I call a PTR the
art he'll the only use P function
pointer and the tableau tableau 64 APC
routines all this what's this important
things are only product the peridot only
which he could be modified to right
elbow under the cropped so
if we can build a summer future to
modify the only integer we can fully pay
past safety and they chew up the code
exclusion and in the end there was still
future abusing there's at least some
possible way such as the donator or
PowerShell to abuse the delay load the
library to abuse the auto food
processors technical and extension all
these are powerful future which can do
powerful scenes
so if which are abused they can
potentially be used to bypass
medications so in the end I think that
there was no servlet no easy way to
January educational order exploited
technicals the our defender needed to
occur hard to so all this case Bacchus
and keep working hard to resolve all the
new emerging purpose technicals so
that's all any questions
[Applause]