next up we've got mark and Mac PI or
Adam and Mac's by coming from the
Microsoft Intelligence Center they are
working tracking some of the nation
state organizations and threats against
Microsoft and our customers so with that
all right so yet we're in the threat
intelligence team within mystic so
mobile teams within mystic but we focus
exclusively on tracking the initial
state actors and this is kind of a
review of last twelve months and some of
the achievements we've had not all of
them some of them man
we're not going to talk about today even
though we called them dear in our hearts
but there's definitely been some that
I've met need the press coverage and and
the some that we just want to kind of
highlight in terms of the pieces that go
beyond that kind of like everyday
business as usual so Microsoft we track
the the groups as periodic elements of
the periodic table
we've got about 132 at last count I
think some of those are in kind of
development state some of them are fully
fledged and we've kind of progressed
over the years which were working in a
third iteration now of the of the kind
of mystic team where we're doing a lot
more work with cee-lo in terms of the
defending democracy initiative a lot
more in space of kind of disruption to
some of these actors that are affecting
our you know our clients across the
various products and services that we
have and we spend our kind of days
tracking at least 30 of those groups so
at full time and then others as and when
we had the receive Intel or there's
reason to kind of focus in on them a
little bit more we are now
Redmond Reston just outside of DC
Cheltenham and soon to be Israel as well
so we're expanding in terms of Geo and
that kind of brings new insights in
terms of the kind of threat as we see
when I'm talking with government and
industry partners yeah should have done
that as I was talking but anyway I've
hand over to Adam to talk about some
some recent work thank you so about this
time last year December of last year
there was
news articles that came out saying that
we working with Facebook and reality
another organization chose not to be
named we took some action against some
North Korean and adversaries so we have
a group we called zinc I tend to stay
away from the term Lazarus for those
that aren't ti people in here you might
roll your eyes but the reason I do that
is Lazarus sort of has been associated
with a bunch of different meanings some
people sort of use it to say anything
North Korea others use it to relate to
something from like the blockbuster
report from Nevada a few years back but
zinc is sort of a subset of that that we
track and their sister which might be
like those who are going after the the
swift making organization so we targeted
specifically zinc and some of the stuff
they were doing what was unique about
this so the reason we did this was you
know one across really the big the big
push so that affected a lot of our
customers affected a lot of people in
this world we thought it was a step way
over over the line and so we wanted to
figure out if we could do something
about it another thing that happened in
that time frame that is sort of out
there in the public was zinc also
started targeting youth utility
providers here in the US and we didn't
want to see that escalate to something
really bad and so we got together with
Facebook and a few other places and
tried to see what we could do about it
and so we sort of combined your unique
forces and took some actions so as
Microsoft we have a capability called M
SRT the malicious software removal tool
this has been talked about publicly so
it's sort of a way for us to if there's
like a really bad piece of malware think
like a worm like config or something
it's a way for us to go push a signature
to delete that globally on any Windows
install that's receiving windows update
essentially and so we pushed about it
was about eight families from zinc in to
M SRT in December and so one morning in
December these adversaries woke up and a
lot of their stuff was gone so a lot of
their access was deleted maybe even on
some of their own systems as well as
their servers etc and on top of that we
also went after their accounts so not
just you know hotmail Outlook accounts
etc Facebook accounts but also some of
their social
profile so if anyone read through the
hundred and thirty page indictment from
a few weeks ago from POC jin-hyuk that
the FBI released they sort of hinted to
there being some LinkedIn profiles so
their social media profiles and I'll
talk to those in a second so we went and
shut all those down I think it was well
over 200 accounts that we took down all
at once and but the thing with the
social media profiles is sometimes those
are things that take them a lot of time
to build up so they have to build a
repertoire they have to build friends
and connections and so deleting all
those is pretty painful for them overall
what was the impact of that we didn't
expect to get rid of them forever they
did sort of died down and do nothing for
about a month and we didn't see anything
from them for a month and when they came
back they came back sort of just solely
focused on cryptocurrency exchanges they
did change their tooling up a bit using
some of their older tools that weren't
directly it sort of affected by this and
since then we've only seen a few things
sort of cleaved back in so they're
they're still operating what do we do it
again I don't know but it's it's sort of
an option we exercise too so they I
talked briefly about social media stuff
so LinkedIn in particular you know
obviously we purchase LinkedIn a few
years ago we've been working with them
on this the document talked about the
profiles we didn't really go into much
detail about them so here were two they
had several you'll notice both of these
are people that claim to work for
defense industry companies that doesn't
mean they were targeting these companies
what they do is they are creating these
profiles to sort of exist in that
industry and then they try to connect
with people in the industry and so
obviously LinkedIn is a very powerful
platform for them because they can say
you know I'm really interested in a
certain person that works on a certain
technology and so they can easily come
to find that person and then what they
do is they try to connect to them and
once they connect they don't necessarily
send malware over LinkedIn once you're
connected you can view the person's
contact email so they'll take that
contact email and then they'll craft an
email using a recruiters name and it's
like routed they found on LinkedIn and
say hey I'm from such-and-such company
you can see me on LinkedIn I've got this
great job opportunity you should totally
open this document with macros enabled
because it's going
all about the awesome stuff you could
you know work for here and so I'm not
going to say they were super affected
with that but that's a technique they
continue to use as they go across
different industries the other thing
about these profiles is like real people
would go and endorse them and say like
oh yeah this person is great they leave
like a full testimony about how you know
how great they are to work with little
do they know they were endorsing a North
Korean hacker
right and so also like I've shown some
of these to some of our internal
security trainings and people sort of
get scared realizing that you know they
could have connected to a North Korean
hacker and like one of the obvious ways
to find these is you actually just sort
of look for like the best looking
pictures so like one thing we've joked
about is what if you could like pipe all
profile pictures through hot-or-not and
you just look for like the ones are the
very top those might be North Korean
hackers so another thing about this this
so those accounts are a little over a
year and a half two years old and at the
time they were the interests were all
like defense related but then about a
year and a half ago we saw them start
adding interest to like cryptocurrency
type exchanges or interest groups and so
we think some of the same people who
were involved with this defence
targeting started using these accounts
to then target some of these
cryptocurrency
exchanges that we've heard about in the
news another piece to zinc that hasn't
really been talked about but we have
some unique visibility on because of
azure so you know we're constantly
tracking this group in particular and
about a year and a half ago there was a
piece of Malory came across and the c2
server ended up one of the c2 servers
ended up being an agile instance and so
we worked directly with that customer to
get permission to conduct an
investigation there and the the insights
that gave us was pretty awesome and so
one of the things we learned Oh
so zinc like 99% of the infrastructure
at the time was all compromised
infrastructure stuff they go out and
compromise in use and so in this case we
found a vulnerability in or they were
using a vulnerability in managed engine
service desks which is like a IT Help
Desk tool they were just scamming the
internet for that finding it exporting
it to up a little
while they pop this web shell on their
very generic gave them a way to upload
files and run commands was anything
super fancy but this does run on top of
like this is running inside Tomcat so we
actually found cases where they've
actually developed like a full
server-side suite all built on like
using JSP that we've only seen them use
once so far but they do have it out
there and so once we get information
like this we turn around and we're gonna
scan the rest of adjure for it try to
find other instances that might have
been compromised maybe using the same
web shell using the same well exploit
vulnerabilities and then what they do
with all this infrastructure as well is
they also go and they set up like a big
proxy network that they'll sort of
bounce everything through there's a good
paper by a group IB there was released a
little over a year ago where they go
into this a bit more detail but one of
the tools we end up recovering was their
manager for some of this proxy
infrastructure so when I first got this
I was hoping to be much more exciting
but no it's pretty pretty dead simple
but this is essentially what they would
use on their and to manage all these
compromised nodes that they've acquired
so there's another group that we track
call them thallium they are not super
advanced at all
they are not you know they did not show
the best most awesome techniques out
there but they're still extremely
effective and so of course is it as a
CIA analyst I would love to track
someone super advanced like you know the
stuff we heard today from about Turlough
or equation group but this is still a
big problem for our customers and so
we're still gonna focus a lot of efforts
on this and so a large majority of their
of their attacks are all just standard
phishing emails hey you have unusual
signing activity review your activity
and when they do that they're going to
get to a login page a very generic 365
login page we also have seen cases where
they'll create you know if you're a
another suspect tenant and you have like
your you can set up a custom looking
login page they'll emulate that and make
it look like that this is actually led
us to do some interesting things on the
o 365 ATP side where we'll use like the
azure computer vision API to look at the
site there about the
like on and if it looks like one of our
login pages are one of the customers
login pages but it's not actually hosted
on the right domain we'll block that and
flag it most recently though they they
started doing something interesting over
the past two to three weeks so they were
sending out links and the links if you
click them from a non chrome user agent
it would just send you to this PDF that
look corrupted but if you clicked it
from a chrome user agent you would go to
this PDF that looked corrupted loaded
with an iframe but then it would pop up
this JavaScript alert saying oh you need
to install the improved font provider
Chrome extension and if you clicked okay
it would take you there and this one
magically was created just four or five
days ago but has thirty five star
reviews and has been used like things
like sixty eight people in total and you
know very first version everything this
is actually they have two versions of
this this is the most recent one a
different name and so interestingly to
some of the reviews were very specific
so this one was like hey if you're part
of the UN committee
you should definitely install this
because it's great and what this would
do is can't really see it that well in
there but if they install the Chrome
extension it would give them permissions
to all your tabs all your cookies etc so
anytime you would go to visit a specific
page and so they had not only like
organization specific pages in there but
also you know Yahoo AOL Gmail Microsoft
Excel hotmail it would steal your
username password and cookies for that
site and send it back off to them so you
know they'll do everything from the
basic cred fishing stuff to this this
sort of gives them some some persistence
on this front one of the things we do
see them do as soon as they get access
to an account is they go and set up SMTP
forwarding on the account and so we've
had a lot of people move from different
you know whether it be on pram or other
mail hosting solutions to o365 recently
and one of the things we're learning and
seeing is that sometimes when they bring
their forwarding URLs with them these
forwarding rules might've been in place
for two three four years where thallium
has had persistent access that mailbox
over time and the user had no idea and
so all
these have sort of led us into some
initiatives that matter we'll talk a
little bit more about but notifying our
users when they've been targeted or even
compromised by some of these
state-sponsored actors and Valium is
definitely sort of leading the charge
there so if you saw us talk yesterday
you'll see that when something happens
to one of our customers or indeed
affects our customers through maybe a
third party such as supply and shear in
the tax then a lot of areas across
Microsoft product groups I'm sorry
mystic indeed get involved and it's
about kind of assessing you know the
scale of it the damage what can we roll
out in terms of detections and then in
some cases we were even approached by
third parties who are affected to notify
on their behalf so the reason I've kind
of included this is to kind of talk
about some of the trends so this is
certainly something we've seen as a
growing trend whereas we've kind of seen
some of the discussions about these
third-party suppliers being compromised
I think in terms of kind of attribution
for us we see you know criminal gangs
kind of starting off a law highly
targeted in at least the two related
cases there with the Wonder schools
vendors where the targeting was specific
to IPS there we're not entirely sure how
they merge to tie to the organizations
that they were after but we also say you
know apt actors in particular and barium
which I'll touch upon a little bit more
in a second has been you know very busy
in this space so we heard the ccleaner
and the shadow pod stuff but also
potentially TeamViewer so from open
source reporting and if you mind
virustotal we can find some additional
evidence there to suggest that perhaps
TeamViewer themselves have suffered an
issue or at least in the case of
ccleaner Avast have suggested that that
was the route into their network so if
you've got the Jimba credentials you can
obviously log in you can get those
credentials in a number of ways fish
them from the user maybe even just brute
force if it's a weak password but this
seems to be something that we've
observed in IR cases and industry
partners where essentially a third party
remote solution provider has formed the
kind of initial incursion into the
network with
or necessary kind of evidence to suggest
credential harvesting upfront kind of
worrisome in some ways but in this case
I think barium seems to drop there then
sort of known payloads very quickly
after each intrusion so it was quite
easy to at least detect malicious
activity at that point obviously if
they'd wanted they could have remained
quite quite anonymous on their on the
networks so that's certainly something
we're seeing and it's prompted us to
take a little bit more of a step in
towards the kind of the I guess
takedowns obviously used in the headline
here but the action against the actors
to to use some of our success against
the strontium after for example in terms
of seizing the domains extending out the
barium and other actors as well in one
particular case we actually had been who
was down for presenting this topic and
sadly he couldn't make it this week he
actually went with our global instant
response team to a customer site and was
able to in kind of real time not only
advise them on maybe where they should
look having known this actor very well
but also examine logs find new things
pivot and basically build out that
picture to not just help with the
attribution piece but then also to find
onward victims and form the basis of a
lot of notifications manganese is
another group we track in around for a
long long time you know you've seen the
apt one kind of maybe come and go and
come again these guys have been around
for just as long very quiet for a long
time but well we don't see much from
them in terms of kind of malware being
deployed because we've managed to keep
track of them over the years
we can see when they do and a victim
network and even if we don't say have
something like you know a SC being
affected or Windows Defender deployed
across that network we can still kind of
see how they're abusing that compromised
and in this case one interesting piece
was they've taken a very very kind of
interest in proach of using that victim
as a as a way to register for any an
endpoint protection trials so our own
Windows Defender has been included I
don't think they're they've activated
yet but would be interesting if they do
but there's at least
sort of for other providers where
they've now got that in that software
probably installing it within a test
network hopefully not on their own
enterprise network but that would indeed
be interesting for whoever gets that
Kalama treats but you know we're not
seeing kind of like the new malware
development but this would suggest that
they're testing malware or at least
testing techniques so that they won't
necessarily caught out when they do hit
the kind of intended targets in the
future and strontium probably the one I
cited zinc where was kind of attribution
by association or outright calling out
the the country and there's incus the
normal policy is not to attribute to a
country organization hence why I didn't
go into in-depth with barium and
manganese there but strontium I guess
everyone's seen kind of the association
with fancy Bayer and if you 28 so it's
not surprise were being kind of active
against some of the attacks for a long
time now he around the elections and we
recently mentioned in the press again
this has kind of been an interesting
piece so we kind of took steps before
necessary or was I necessarily was on
the radar of a lot of other sort of TI
providers or response companies to again
use that kind of the ability to take the
demeanor away from the actor before harm
actually comes to the end target and
something else that we've done in this
space and particularly with the thallium
after as well is extend the
notifications based on compromise to
targeting as well so being able to say
you weren't actually necessarily
infected by this attack or perhaps we
blocked this attack but we'd still like
to tell you that this group has a
particular interest in you and that's
kind of something with it I think we
will continue to expand upon you know
trying to do this at cloud scale this
crosses over all of the places we have
visibility whether it's on the endpoint
in the cloud in the mailbox and the
initial feedback I think is pretty good
from those who've received those
notifications but I think it's important
to inform customs about what they didn't
see because it was blocked just as much
as when they have to take action to
resolve an incident obviously we've got
a lot of news coverage on the the recent
strontium piece I think a lot of it was
positive
which is great but then we also had some
some more scathing reports and I think
Artie in particular had three different
reports out in the sim dear essentially
citing that you know other companies
maybe didn't have any evidence that it
was happening
maybe that's based on visibility but
yeah to basically try and say that we
were trying to push a product etc and
this is kind of you know they can draw
parallels with some of the initiatives
we've started but really this is kind of
based on the work that we're doing and
with some of our trusted partners to
essentially stop an app and app they're
in their tracks and take their power
away from them immediately so we can
ignore all that and try to keep doing
the good work that we're doing there did
you battery down recently I as part of
the what was the digital Geneva
Convention now I believe digital piece
which has evolved quite a lot since that
initial blog post by Brad some years ago
two set of core principles now they're
really I think that as we develop this
and we've been working with them with
partners who essentially are you know
working this space in a more
humanitarian context it's something that
I think a lot of kind of you know
governments around the world will get on
board with and one of the kind of slides
I had from from that talk was talking
about the kind of evolution in the CNA
and so in this instance it's you know
very much kind of a shortened timeline
with a thermitic on sort of more visions
and intent year but it was kind of
really to illustrate that if we kind of
look at geographically where these are
from and not necessarily always the same
group but we kind of see very targeted
attacks where the the purpose was to
disable systems which is typically CNA
rather than CNE so attacker on an
espionage is to disable a system or to
wiped it very surgical you know very
kind of controlled we see kind of
retaliation for that with the Shamoon
attacks which you know in intent there
was kind of like to strike back but
don't in kind of a whatever the
technology at the time and that couldn't
rely them to do the Sony Pictures is a
bit of a strange one because I think
that was very much retaliatory but you
know that
put those actors on the map really for a
lot of people but if we look at kind of
as time goes on more frequent examples
of CNA or coming from the same region of
the world and although some of them tend
to be focused on one particular region
we can see that it's actually it is
definitely in a an increasing trend but
by the time we get down to the bottom so
Triton a group that we call dysprosium
we've been looking after to attribute
those guys but it's it's interesting
really that that's probably where we die
like we move on from just see any in
terms of the examples we're used to and
move into like the real world actual
harm so the potential here to actually
cause a safety system to fail cause the
plant to explore the the damage to human
life I think that's where we do start
moving into the you know that you need a
convention that would apply in that kind
of context whereas previous examples
have been essentially stuck in the cyber
realm so hopefully we won't really get
to that point but I think we're you know
it's only a matter of time before we see
loss of life because of a cyberattack
more directly so than say the the
efforts that have been used to kind of
disrupt during a more traditional kind
of military action
so we we don't hear as much anymore
maybe a few years ago you would have
heard of a lot of activity groups using
O'Day's we don't see it as much we still
do see it so one of the groups this year
that had a couple was a grouping called
dubnium so the first one was reported to
us by butchy who and when our nsrc
analyst first looked at it they said oh
this actually reminds me a lot of one I
worked last year which was 2017 Oh 149
and that's that was actually attributed
to a group called zinc so the time when
they report us we didn't know which
group was behind this when we know days
do come in our group is involved we try
to figure out who it is to sort of help
inform the decisions that should be made
and how we should approach it and so
what was interesting is that this ended
up being a group we called dubnium and
so on the left was that was the zinc
expert on the right was the the recent
dubnium exploit occupation is the same
right so don't know if this was
intentional don't know if they were just
sharing the same package
we don't believe zinc and dubnium are
related really at all but it was it was
interesting to make this note and so
there was also this this carrier dock
that would speak to auto sound checkers
and so we went and pivoted around on
that information from the O'Dea and
started looking around and ultimately
were able to find cases where it was
appearing the there is malware talking
to those domains on systems that had
dubnium our like as Rex and Skaar craft
signatures for example we also think we
pivoted into what appears to be maybe
development network or an adversary
network where a bunch of the Maur was
all coming from initially and that tied
into some other accounts we had and sort
of opened up the the graph for us on
what dubnium was doing today interesting
thing is I I really personally hadn't
tracked dubnium for maybe two or three
years but because they use node a now
we're gonna pay a lot of attention to
you and so this this sort of opened up
some old memories but fast-forward a
month or two and they were back at it
again kaspersky in in their blog posts
about the first o day they sort of
hypothesized that the way the bug worked
they could probably modify it and use it
again and they definitely did Trend
Micro reported that but again they're
using that same style of off eustachian
and it looked it looked very similar
overall between you know three
ago and now they've changed some things
but some of it still looks really
familiar to me sort of the way they
register domains and infrastructure
still seems to be the same they still do
this trick then you can go see some of
the pictures where like the next stage
payload is sort of using steganography
or hidden within an image and it can
throw some some analysts off but overall
haven't changed but still demonstrate a
big capability here they've had a lot of
flash show days in the past and in IE
and this would sort of fall in that
category as well and so we're gonna
continue to keep a close eye on them and
sort of watch for for mode more Oh days
coming out of them moving forward they
also have sort of had as we taught us
apart they've had some really like
interesting targets so they're very
specific on who they target they don't
sort of blast things out and that
obviously goes into the equation when
we're thinking about okay they've got a
node a how fast we can move on this
where how prevalent is it and so like in
this case we were able to recover a male
where they were emailing someone in Cuba
but they were expecting that person to
speak Korean and it was like super or
some sipping that god I can't ID who the
victim is I couldn't based off the email
address but seems to be very very
particular some of the other victims we
were able to sort of notice based on IP
address etc seems to also be very very
specific and sort of global not sort of
focused on large region of the world but
they seem to have very surgical
precision in that regard and so with
that let magpie cover a bit of the
trends yes so kind of covered some of
these points but I'm definitely going
for the kind of supply chain whether
that is through software updates or
whether it's you know providers of other
other items obviously we were used to
kind of like CSC has been hit and the
code signing so it's been stolen and
passed around see any efforts I
definitely think we want a watch and
it's boring that we probably need a
real-world incident to really get some
traction on that but we're pushing as
hard as we can to get efforts put in
place to try and avoid it really apt is
a service is probably a piece that we've
also seen but we haven't got any slides
on happy to take some questions or
discuss it later on but this is the
thing that I guess
we'll use the water quite a bit when it
comes to companies performing to their
intelligence and trying to attribute
when it's not just a zero-day that's
being purchased by mobile customers but
you're also getting the 0d the
weaponization of the documents produced
on the same horse for example the sim
malware family says the payloads but
there may be you're kind of the first
foothold on the on the victim network is
also being orchestrated by the third
party that's that's being paid before
handed off to a specific customers and
often we've seen a customer who's
purchased this kind of package but
they're on themselves at least in the
terms of geography also a target so not
another paying customer so it's
interesting to see that it can easily
look like it's a global effort but it's
probably six seven different paying
customers all funneled through one
provider and there's probably about four
or five providers that we've seen
illustrating this kind of thing in the
in the last twelve months
it also means that if you don't have a
huge development effort or the cash to
to build a multi-million dollar
framework then it's probably quite a
fallible service for you and it gives
you that country their ability to
perform CNE and also hiding the noise of
other customers sim for infrastructure
we see that in terms of third-party
providers or contracts where maybe one
or two different APD groups in the same
region tend to operate out the sim
infrastructure but very different
missions very different malware families
different tasking and it just caused
confusion and the worst bit I guess is
passwords bruh having been involved in a
number of different cases that have been
escalated up trying to track down the
the infrastructure and then onward to
back to the actor for password spray it
is a bit of a nightmare so the the guys
in the identity team here at Microsoft
there are they are working on some great
analytics to detect this but I must say
when it comes to trying to attribute to
a group we all find it difficult with
huge kind of skill of Ruta compromises
and that kind of thing so yeah I think
it's a one for I guess I'm gonna say
machine learning in the eye because then
it gets a gets off my shoulders
so with that I think we're out of time
but any questions yeah thank you very
much everybody I'm gonna give him nine
o'clock we're running very low on time
we can take one or two questions if does
anyone have a question if not we'll be
in the hallway afterwards perfect thank
you much thanks
[Applause]