I would like to introduce our next
speaker this is a Fabio Cellini from the
Kaspersky Labs group and he's going to
be talking to you about some amazing
work he's done please give him a big
hand this is andrew andrew is a big
friend of mine he's very passionate
about security but he's a regular icky
guy working in insurance company in
Brazil but he's very passionate about
phishing attacks actually andrew is one
of the top submitters of fishing on fish
tank comm probably you guys know and all
of us here use their feed their database
of phishing domains phishing URLs he's
one of the top guys every day
voluntarily sending new things to fish
tank and he do it because security is
his passion and he do it actually very
very well he's very well to report new
and fresh phishing attacks he's so good
to do that that he received a death
threat from Brazilian bad guys I don't
know why some Fisher's discovered his
Rio identity his email address his
personal data and sent to his death trap
it's written in Portuguese it's full of
bad words but basically it says you will
be killed tomorrow and this is all your
personal data following the message that
it's not on the print screen there were
his complete name his phone the name of
his relatives number of his documents
and so on could imagine that why he
received this death threat because he
was doing a good good job trying to
protect people and sometimes we as
defender defenders we face the situation
and talking with him about this crazy
story we started a Congress
that it was the inspiration of my
personal project that I'll present here
today he did a very honest question to
me why and ksham our products aren't
proactive to block something very simple
as a phishing attack and then my answer
was for sure sure we are we are practice
user istakes we use reputation we use
blacklist season bla bla bla then he
told me well most of the attacks most of
the phishing attacks I found and I
report on fish tank iron block it in the
beginning by nobody zero blocking zero
detection nothing my he told me my
impression is that nobody nobody cares
about this topic and then my answer to
where to hain was nothing I know he was
right he was right and then he asked me
why did why the secret industry are not
proactive doing us the minority report
movie as the precogs predicting the
crime why you were not practice and
these questions hurt me inside because I
have an announcer to him and the search
for such answers was the start of this
project I want to share with you today
the shoot first ask later proactive
strategies to defend the most efficient
country in the world thank you for this
opportunity to stay here and thank you
to stay here in this room and not on
another room to see my presentation I'll
share with you what we have about this
interesting project well we know
phishing attack is something very simple
but it's something that works and 91
percent of our all cyber attacks starts
with a simple phishing email we know
that
and see attack started so we started
with phishing messages sent to John
Podesta we know big attacks started
small with a very simple phishing email
huh
for example this case reported by Brian
Krebs of a bank in Virginia that last
2.4 million dollars and that taxes
starts small with phishing emails or the
great philosopher of the RT industry on
Twitter the crook once said give me a
zero day and you have access for life
teach a man to fish and he have access
for life and this is completely true
because big attacks sometime an apt
attack
start with a very simple phishing email
and when we talk about phishing
Brazil is the country number one on our
statistics more tacit by this kind of
attack it's in the top and this is there
are heat map from 2017 I'll show you
numbers Brazil is on the top with
Australia and China almost 30% of every
Brazilian are a target at least once per
year by a fishing by a phishing message
and now some more numbers about this
threat in Brazil as you can see here
this is from 2017 and 2017 we block it
36 million phishing attacks only in
Brazil it's an average of one hundred
and one thousand attacks per day per day
and this here is the Black Friday
expected now let's look for 2018 in the
seven first months of the year 2018 we
already registered the double of attacks
40 million phishing attacks blockade in
Brazil an average of 220 mm attacks
per day and this one here is the workup
this is the situation in the country and
it's something very interesting well we
know very well all the strategies the
cyber criminals are using to do this
their attacks they use email they use
SMS they use telephone calls they use
advertisement on Google and Bing as well
they use fake profile on social networks
they hack it websites and we know how
they do it we know it very well all of
us we know it but the attacks more
effective they are creating domains they
buy a domain with a name very similar to
the real one they put a digital
certificate there from let's encrypt and
then they start the attack who registry
this kind of domain with a name very
similar well domains craters fissures
regular users and of course of course
legit owners they register as well to
protect their brand that's what they do
and when I when I tell to everybody that
Brazil is the country of the fraud
people laugh like come on we have fraud
everywhere and then I'll I'll show some
examples that we have there and people
the conclusion is wow there's a lot of
fraud in Brazil and I'll show you some
cases we have fraud everywhere where
every layout program in Brazil they are
fishing for example gas stations in
Brazil they have a loyalty program so in
the end of one year you have some points
and you can earn free gas these loyal
programs are fishing as well because our
big criminals want free guests other
point every service of the Brazilian
government are fishing this is something
really incredible especially the health
services the public health services in
Brazil it's fishing as well
cybercriminals want to enter in the
system aiming to change the position of
some citizens and waiting lists for
example for a surgery they do that or
their interest in Scenario data brokers
invert the legit data brokers in brazil
they have credit scores for every
citizen the same as here in US and cyber
criminals want to broke and they did it
they broke their database aiming to
change the credit scores of someone else
so this guy will have a good credit to
buy things but the most interesting case
for me some telecoms as well they are
efficient because cyber criminals want
to do the same swap but the most
interesting case for me was fishing
against Obama Obama is the government
environment and nature Institute they
are responsible to control the Amazon
forest and how companies will attract
wood from the Amazon forest and some
time ago I started to see fishing
against Obama employees and and then I
started to wonder why why cyber
criminals are fishing this institution
from the Brazilian government and then
after three weeks I find out why they
broke into into Obama's system they
entered there and they unlock it 23
companies these companies they were
previously blocked to extract a root
from the Amazon forest they broke into
this system they unlock it these
companies and they were free to extract
wood from the Brazilian forests and they
did it they did it for a long time and
the result was 11 million dollars in
wood from the Amazon forest that was
instructed illegally and this would feel
100 1000
100 trucks with wood and everything
started with a fishing message can you
see that that's why we say Brazil is the
country of fraud fraud everywhere
everything that is online is fish it in
Brazil
well 58 percent of all these phishing
attacks are against financial
institutions bank credit cards credit
unions and so on it's natural because
cyber criminals want money fast so 58
percent of all these attacks are against
banks okay so most of the more effective
attacks they started with a domain as I
told you previously they resist
registering a domain using your name
very similar and look this is the window
of opportunity that we defenders we have
because between the registration of the
domain and the moment that the bad guy
will use it for attack we have a gold
window of opportunity that as far no
nobody are using on our industry and
when I decided to to start this project
some people told me come on
a PG a peach is more fancy is more cool
why do you why do you want to look for
phishing attacks it's something come on
that affects everybody for the masses
why
and actually my department on Kaspersky
we are like specialized it to deal with
apt attacks and I agree these attacks
are out of the box they are really cool
but we are still missing the basics I
mean we as defenders which you have
space to improve or phishing detection
and let me tell you in the name of our
industry because I checked the Texians
of the attacks I saw and oh it's really
bad
or phishing detection is that you really
really bad for the entire security
industry especially from the companies
that are providing protection for the
endpoint we have a lot to improve so
that's why ok apt school Maori school I
agree but we used to are missing a lot
of opportunities to increase our
detection on phishing attacks so as I
told you we have a golden opportunity
between the registration and death when
they attack really starts and looking
for the Whois data we can see who
registered a domain ok so with this idea
in mind with this identity in the
beginning of 2014 with we started this
experiment we decided to monitor all the
fresh domains registered on internet
using these names as 58% of all the
attacks we saw was against financial
institution ok let me track all the new
fresh domains register using these names
so these are financial financial
institution banks credit cards operating
in Brazil and in Latin America some of
them are very much national as Walmart
for example and we decided to to monitor
every day what the new and fresh domains
register using these names and you know
these is the same technique use it by
brand protection companies such as I
forget their name but I'll tell you
later it's the same technique so what
the owner of the brand what they do
someone registered a domain using my
name why so I'll go there I'll talk with
the on why you you're using my brand
this is my brand copyrighted and so on
so we have companies that offer this
kind of brand protection is the same
idea so we started to monitor
and we solve things like this someone
else registered a name using our domain
using a name of the Spanish bank or
someone else registered a domain using
the name of a very important bank in
Latin America but in the moment that we
visit the URL you see this future home
of something quite cool I mean there is
nothing there yet
because sooner or later I know and this
domain will be something bad normally a
fishing fish ok then we decided to
collect this lot of data and then we
started to use it the Whois database as
a repetition and classification to using
this this idea discrete criterias do we
did the correlation of the email of the
registrant so we have an email address
this guy registered a bunch of domains
and then we started to track everything
we decided to check for example if the
domain was registered using a free
webmail or temporary mail address
we also check it for invalid Whois data
especially typos and if the domain is
fresh or not and the reputation of the
hosting server where the domain was
registered we decided to create this
criteria and data of this this new and
fresh domains we started with daily
changes calm they offer you a list of
new or fresh domains you can find
registered every day and then we decided
to play a little bit with typos typos
squaring and so on and then we use it
these two Harry to do string similarity
it's the I don't know if my my German
pronunciation is okay leverage thing
left things distance we decided to use
the leviston distance and string
similarity to find typos squaring
domains and then to complete all the
sources of this project the certificate
transparency idea to find new SSL domain
specially on let's encrypt and putting
everything together we did the crazy
decision to block all these domains and
then the reaction was very interesting
the reaction especially from our guys or
our entry fishing team like the first
reaction was what the hell are you doing
why you block at this domain there is
nothing there I visit the domain there
is no why did you block it and then I
don't need to explain okay look these
are using a name of a bank but the
domain was not registered by a bank and
I block it because I know sooner or
later something bad will be there and
then they told me mmm ok but I think you
have legal problems and then the next
reaction or was of our legal department
hello Fabio why are you blocking domains
that there is nothing there ok in the
same explanation and then after some
time or guys started to see the good
results and the outstanding results we
get and then they realize that this was
good technique this is all something
good but the reaction was very very
interesting in the beginning and then we
decided to block everything no matter
who registered if you it's using a brand
brand trademark of a bank or credit card
company we block it so five years
shooting first in Fishers these are the
results these are the first results we
get
100,000 phishing domains bakit in
advance
well false positive of course we have
but very low rate less than 1% and
actually this was very effective not
only against phishing domains but also
against more domains and also some a
peachy campaigns that they use it the
same idea for example there is a lot of
bad domains registered using the name
Windows Update there is a lot and we
decided to block it as well and when we
realize wow this is blocking but who did
it Fabio Fabio why you block it
well I block it because it's using the
name Windows Update it do not belongs to
Microsoft simple so it was very
effective and I'll show you some results
for example this domain I block it in
March 13 and after 3 days the guys from
net craft that are dedicated to find and
block fishing they found it after three
days and it arrived and on our database
but the website was already there
because we block it in advance
another good interesting case 13 days in
advance I block it on February 25 and
all Robert from our key fishing guys
found it on March 11 after 13 days or
this case after 15 days I block it on
March 20 February 20 and our robot found
these domain use it in a phishing attack
on March 7 and of course there are cyber
the most common behavior from fishers
and cyber criminals they register a
barrage of domains and they started to
use one two three or four domains in
their face
first attacks they start to burn these
domains of the bunch they registered but
some of them are very lazy
for example this case here the guy
registered domain June and we block it
in June 12 but he decided to use the
domain after four months in October and
when he started the attack everything
was already blocked in advance you don't
need so much you don't need to do so
much things it is this simple very
simple but it's strong connected to the
language of the phishing attack for let
me give you one example
we are monitoring name of banks then in
Portuguese is banku but in Spanish is
banca and in fresh bunk if you use these
keywords you find a lot of badness in
your daily feed of new and fresh domains
registered you find a lot of things in
aspire no nobody on our industry are
using this data to perform proactive
protections and now we realize it we
were in the we were doing the good thing
when this case arriving in my hands and
I'll show you this stuff this case is
very very very interesting there is a
group of fishes in Brazil they were very
very organized they do fishing only
against big corporations only and they
do it over telephone they call the
company they presented himself as
employee of a bank or employee of
something important and they ask to call
with the financial director and then
talking with this financial director
they asked him to visit a specific
website
because they are from the bank and they
need to do something with the bank
account and they are very smart because
the fishing domain they they were using
it's on only in the moment of the call
if you try to access it before or after
the call it's not available and they are
very smart because they do a lot of
filtering so only a range of IP from
this company will see the content of the
domain and every other access from other
IPs will see nothing so they do IP
filtering and it's very very targeted
and against this attack it's quite hard
to protect because it's something very
very targeted and when this case arrived
it in my hands it was approved to me
that we were doing the good thing we
were doing a good approach to protect
our customers I'll share with you I have
the recording of the guy on the phone
yeah I have the recording and I'll show
you so let me detail the case this
fraudster he called a health insurance
company or customer in Brazil on
December 7 and in the recording he asked
the financial director to enter in a
specific website as I told you
previously and then these specific them
they the the fraudster presented himself
as an employee of the Santander bank
center there is a very important bank in
in Latin America they are from Spain
they have he also operations here in
u.s. he asked a financial director to
visit this domain Santander shinsa-dong
this domain was registered on December 2
the call was in December 7 we block it
this domain on December 3 by the morning
we block it and I'll show you right now
the recording of the frauds
terr calling with the financial director
trying to convince her to enter in the
website but the website was a red block
it the audio is in Portuguese in English
and you understand everything let's see
[Music]
they're supposed to call no as you can
see it the fraudster try everything use
Google Chrome use Mozilla but our
product block at their website actually
these fraudsters they registered more
than 30 phishing domains using the name
of banks in Latin America and all of
them block it in advance we can do that
it's simple we have the technology we
are smart we have the data we can do
that and that these are the outstanding
results we are having non phishing
attacks in Brazil that I'm sharing with
you today we as an industry we can use
the same idea and the same technique
were right to protect our customers
people that trust on our products trust
on our technologies we can do that but
we are not because when I check one of
the websites of these
of these gang of these fraudsters on
virustotal only Kaspersky are blocking
it
okay I know virus todo is not a tool to
check that I know I know it I know very
well but come on we can do it they are
using the name of banks big corporations
and of course this affect the regular
user and companies as well okay but what
was the reaction of the bad guys can you
think they saw it ok they are blocking
of course they reacted the first
reaction was new fishing domains Unicode
so we started to see domains like this
what's up con with very strange
characters very strange letters or this
one here this is a crypto currency
exchange with some crazy characters or
this one here as well and everything is
fishing but all in Unicode not only
using Unicode strings but also digital
certificates and the fishing domain this
one was very clever very very clever
against a Brazilian bank when you check
the digital certificate you see they
correct the URL it was there their
strategy to continuing attack users and
that's what they are doing right now
because if you monitor the if you use
the keyword of the name of the bank and
they changed some character you know the
result you not see this fishing domain
and another very interesting reaction
from that guys was this case looked at
this URL it's very very rare very
strange looked at Israel when you put
your eyes there you think oh this is
ipv6 but a girl in ipv6 no it's not
exactly ipv6 it's a hybrid model that
browsers except nowadays it's a hybrid
between
vv6 and ipv4 if you want to know more
RFC 4:03 eight there and we started to
see fishing and more attacking such this
one with this crazy role but of course
it's not very very effective because
when a regular user would they when they
saw this rural they look no this is
strange it's not so effective as i using
a domain okay everything was cool we
were blocking everything and then a big
tragedy gdpr happened a big tragic or
project then we started to see who is
data such this one knock-knock who is
not there or this one GDP our musket
everything musket so oh my goodness
it's our end what can I do right now
okay now or challenge is to do it
without the who is of course the who is
this GDP our project was a big impact on
the Whois database we are you waiting
the guys for an I can to do something
but nothing so far it was a big impact
we don't have more emails to do the
correlation no mori moose but we it's
you possible to block basing the name
guessing it's it's risky I know it's
very risky but it is to possible and we
are doing that I think I can tell you in
the end of the year our our false
positive rate will increase a little bit
and also it is you possible because
there is a field and the Whois data
called registrant organization and these
data can review who is the owner the
domain I'll show you late one example we
and we are looking for alternatives and
good ideas are welcome okay we think to
ask the owner
the brand but it takes a lot of time to
contact the correct people asking hey
did you register this domain or we try
it to create a database of legit domains
but this is something very huge to do
and time-consuming as well what we are
using right now passive DNS okay we have
here new domain where is it register
where is it's hosted so we are using
passive DNS in a way so this is the
registrant organization for example
these dot a PP domains they belong to
Google and a lot of features are putting
their domains there like we have there
Yahoo is a big bank in Latin America and
everything is redacted for privacy
redacted for privacy reducted for
privacy but we have in there in the
middle the registrant organization that
is someone else it's a girl it's not the
bank so block it okay to conclude my
presentation my presentation in nutshell
Brazil top the rankings of phishing
attacks worldwide on our statistics and
I believe the reason is doing this
picnic we are blocking a lot of bad
things and while we are with this
project Brazil remains in the top some
attacks are very local I mean do you
remember I told you they are very link
it to the language so for example for me
to be a little hard to do the same with
China because I don't speak Chinese but
it's very connected to the language so
you need some locals or people that
speak the language that you want to
monitor this brand monetary think it's
good to find this new and fresh domains
using some some name of a brand the GDP
are can be a problem but we are still
blocking and we are looking for
for alternatives to continue it this
good good project and I personally think
our industry we can do the same we can
do the same to protect our users we can
do to you the same to boost our fishing
detection not only fishing but morale as
well and everything that used the same
idea of bad domains using good names you
can some guys on our industry already
realize it this is something good to do
and I want to call everybody here to do
the same in your products with your
technology we can increase and get very
good results as I'll show you today ok
thank you very much for your attention
and I think thank you very much thank
you and I think we have time for
questions Nate good
it's a great talk I think thank you so
isn't the real solution though to block
this using the same techniques you're
talking about at the registration time
rather than after the fact is only your
customers are protected right I agree
well we try to do it as soon as the
domain is registered I mean we receive a
feed of new and fresh domains we receive
it twice per day we do a filtering this
it's a huge database of new afresh
domains every day we do a few three with
the keywords we are monitoring and then
we program our robot to block it
automatically why does why does the
registrar let these get registered in
the first place isn't that what's really
broken here okay
it's Verizon in the country but I'll
tell you what's going on in Brazil I
talked with the guys from the register
OPR and they told me they according to
local law they can't forbidden people to
register a new domain like yeah they
have the right to register it and they
can do something after someone some
company some security company sent then
a booze report like they are using this
name this name is mine but they can't
avoid or forbidden people to register a
new domain and in the first moment it's
I think this is connected to some local
legislation and it it depending the
country it can ver I more questions
awesome presentation and kudos to you
for pushing through legal to make this
happen I know that can be a big
challenge that's a great success I just
have a couple of questions about how it
was implemented did you block these
domains for all Kaspersky customers or
did you limit the blocks to those that
you knew and were in Brazil because you
knew that was the most vulnerable
population okay good question initially
we started small like
nobody trusted me like what are you
doing are you sure you want to plot this
domain there is nothing there and then
we started small and according we saw
the results we right now we are
automated I mean we do this
automatically blocking the domain and
it's distributed to all our customers of
all products mobile endpoint servers and
so on because we achieve it some very
good results and the guys decided to do
it or to block this domains were right
so we don't have like a separate
database for Brazilians and like
detection databases for Brazilians and
for Argentina and so on we have only one
and we are doing it worldwide right now
and do you have the similar analysis for
other countries or is it just Brazil
right now okay right no right now we are
we are we are using these techniques
with four languages and why languages
because as I told you this is something
very linked to language we are using
with brands in Portuguese Spanish French
and Italian our plan is to is to expand
for more languages with English as well
with we did some tests but right now we
are in this languages or our idea is to
expand thank you thank you
more questions appreciate the the slides
here so a question are you doing
anything with hashing the images of
those you know those sites that say new
and exciting website coming that way you
can start looking for that as a pattern
or even shoving the data that you're
finding into something like you are else
can do and then hunting those image
hashes looking for those new domains and
then setting your block on that ok good
idea we are not using it but what we are
doing is when we found some some attack
very fresh I mean against a new brand or
a very first time that we saw this
in attack we save we save the page a
copy of the page and we sent war guys on
and she fishing to improve or realistic
detection that we are using as well but
not using the service that you told but
it's a good idea we I can check it later
awesome I'll send an email okay hello hi
thanks for though yeah okay alright
thanks for the wonderful talk I was
wondering what was your false positive
rate at the beginning when you started
blocking those domains and how did you
deal with your legal team at the
beginning when you didn't have those
promising results to validate your sorry
say again but slowly I'm sorry
a new problem so I was thinking what was
your false positive rate at the
beginning when you started blocking
those domains and the second question is
how did you deal with your legal team in
the beginning when you did not have you
know these promising results to validate
your thought process okay
well initially the false positives rates
was a bit high quit was like in the
first look it was seven percent it was
high so we we tried to improve things
and we did it and the cases were of the
false positives we I saw they were like
very very specific and the impact was
not big initially but then we were
improving your technique and right now
is less than 1% about the legal thing it
was like a friend questions and then
like are you sure what are you doing I
mean it was more in the position like
are you sure nobody will soon us because
you are blocking this domain there is
nothing there then like I gave then I
explained it then I explained it to them
the the data we had like I think for
this this and this reason this will be
something malicious and after sometimes
we saw the results
that like they were satisfied with the
answer but it can be a problem in the
beginning of some companies as well of
course depend in legislations and so on
but in our case the good results was the
best answer more questions
thanks for the the presentation from
Brazil so I know exactly what you're
talking yeah I just had a few questions
about like so are you guys using solely
like your data the data that you guys
are captured because you mentioned that
like in the beginning fishtank I used to
be at Open DNS and they had a very
similar approach to blog like bad
domains so do you guys use like other
sources too like aggregate the data or
is mostly the data you guys are
harvesting as well
we had a plenty of fishing sources not
only a fish tank we have a lot but this
technique was good because we realize it
we were checking the effectiveness of
all the sources we had this one was the
most effective in the case of Brazilian
fishing so like we measured one of them
each we measure each each source of
fishing that we receive fish tank is one
of them and then we realize that these
source of the brand monitoring thing was
the the most effective I mean the first
one to detect fresh fishing domain
bracket so or right now we are applying
such idea to all the sources that we
receive and this is interesting because
you need to tweak the technique because
it's seasonal I mean during the work up
you see more fishing attack related to
the work up or during the Olympics it's
the same so you need to tweak the
keywords that you are filtering during
the year for example right now I'm
monitoring special the Black Friday
keyword
tax related to the Black Friday that in
in to happen in in some mouths so you
need to tweak but in in all the
resources that we are receiving fishing
fish tank is one of them these are were
the most proactive and in just a
follow-up question and you guys you guys
are not blocking through DNS right you
guys are blocking no we are no we are
walking on or call protection actually
we are blocking on a true way the the
first one are on our cloud detection
because it's faster than others and for
customers that are not using your cloud
protection we are blocking in in our
database
okay locally on each is because some
customers decide to not use the cloud
protection mm-hmm cool thank you thank
you yeah
more questions hi thank you so much for
your talk over here
I'm sorry and I guess it's saying over
here doesn't how much but I was just
just curious how do you actually go
about detecting false positives does the
domain owner have to contest' it and let
you know that you blocked their site or
how do you actually know when you've
blocked a valid site okay about false
positives the false positive sometimes
happens with a very specific keyword
I'll give you one example try to try to
explain to you we have a big government
bank in Brazil called Caixa
in cash in Portuguese also means box so
you need to take care with all the new
domains register with the keyword Caixa
because sometimes you will block a
website of companies selling boxes so
for some very specific keywords you need
sometimes a human approval like okay all
these are all the domains with the name
Caixa
okay this is related with the bank this
is not for example kasia update calm
okay update update the bank account so
fishing or
new boxes for sale calm this is related
to the boxes so for some very specific
keywords you need to tweak your
technique but it it works very well with
another brands especially when the brand
are very unique I mean you have this
brand this is something very very unique
that worldwide you will not see it
nothing more for example bradesco
another big Brazilian bank you will not
see it it's always related to the bank
or something something there is a
keyword with problem as well because we
have series with the name Santander so
in the beginning or false positives was
related with the websites of the the
mayors of the city of Santander and so
on so you need to do a special tweak and
for some cases you need human approval
it can be you need to tweak the
technique but in its G works ok we
welcome more questions
yep one - thanks for the talk thank you
all of my friends and relatives they
basically trust the website if they see
this like a green lock which tells it's
secure right yeah and the futures just
started to issue a lesson great free
certificates
yes for the website to get more trust
from the users yes so just a suggestion
even though you don't have the access in
some cases to Whois database and you
don't really see who actually register
the domain how about checking so since
this information is public how about
checking the new certificates that was
issued by let's encrypt yes
certification Authority and correlated
with the keywords like okay thanks or I
don't know if you're already doing that
or not yes we are we are doing that
because we have some sources fresh
domains and the certificate transparency
they have feeds of especially let's
encrypt that is most popular today to
show new digital certificates so
do the same like these are all the new
domains that requested SSL certificate
with flats and creep okay lets me filter
all this big list with the keywords I'm
monitoring and Brockett so the same idea
we are using and we need it because as
you told a lot of fishing domains with
digital certificates in this can be a
problem because the user the regular
user are mixing things think oh this
website have a green lock so it's okay
but in fact it's not thank you
if a be a great great presentation thank
you very much actually brings good
memories because a few years ago I was
doing doing the same research for
Australia postal service efficient run
somewhere attacks and it worked really
great a couple of questions for you the
first one is do you find challenging
that for some TLDs you cannot easily get
the new domain registration feeds like
calm is easy but some geographies will
not actually tell you which the mains
have been registered uh-huh and the
second question is did you find an S
record correlation like name server IP
for those domains to be the useful
signal to make decisions okay first
question yes for some registrant
companies it's quite hard to obtain the
list but oh I can tell you later some
companies that provide us the list of
new refresh domains we have two or three
of them in the market that they are very
good you cannot be tame this list freely
on daily changes com it's not very
complete but it can be I start like to
to establish the project but we have
like two or three companies that are
providing us this list every day and
their visibility are really good and the
other question sorry oh yes the name
server this is something very
interesting because Fisher's put all
their bad websites all together at the
same server so ok I find one
[Music]
from this one you'll find all of them
together at the same server and this is
something amazing because you can block
everything and you can do it
automatically but right now we are
facing this problem because I think this
is the GDP are your eye we're facing
some problems to see all the websites
hosted at the same server sometimes this
is information are not available easily
but it's a good way to improve detection
okay hey fab you straight hey hey this
is Kunal from Intel Corporation so I was
wondering if you are extending your
research for things like fake news and
I'm also interested to know how do you
go about blocking a domain who is just
serving you know some kind of
steganographic stuff which happened
during Korea Games and so what are all
the factors that you consider and can
you extend that for fake news as well
mm-hmm
no we we are not looking for fake news
or so on
the project is started and till this
moment we are focusing on financial
institutions right now so I don't know
maybe in the future we can expand to
look in other areas which we started
with government organizations and
financial institutions brands the names
may be in the future I don't know let's
see but it's a possibility as well
actually interesting we are right now in
in election time in Brazil and I started
like two weeks ago to look for new
domains using the name of the
politicians there and I found very
interesting things there I can I can
talk right now what exactly we are
investigating okay more questions well
actually I think we are running out of
time
we gotta get everybody out and in who
wants to switch rooms thank you again
please give a big hand to Fabio very
much thank you
[Applause]