good afternoon everyone welcome to the
cloud track track two here in the kodiak
room my name is jr. keno I lead security
incident response for the cloud and AI
division and here joining us today is
Ross from the mystic team for doing
threat intelligence and we have a very
special treat because this is one of the
talks where Microsoft is gonna be
talking about Linux security topics and
so with that I'd love to be able to give
you guys a warm welcome for Ross and his
talk on Linux hello
I'm sure everyone here has seen this
slide probably to death but did you know
that 40% of the VMS on as your our Linux
did you know that 80% of the world's
largest banks run Linux did you know
that you know LinkedIn and Skype
Brandon X and Microsoft runs loads of
Linux kind of VMS and has a massive
Linux estate and so do our customers and
the problem is that every minute we see
thousands of attacks destined to these
Linux machines and for us for our
customers so we need to protect
ourselves we need to protect our
customers and one of the ways we do that
for our customers is where there's your
security center and so that's a little
bit one be talking about today and how
we use deception to do them so before I
begin some caveats this talk is about
Linux but most of the kind of concepts
so I'm going to suggest are you know
applicable to any of us it's also worth
saying that some of the slides may look
like attributes of attacks to kind of
some individuals now there is no
attribution in this talk if you see
pictures or things like that don't take
it that Microsoft is going to attribute
this circle of certain individuals a lot
of this is kind of raw threat Intel and
you know some people could have been
polling themselves also now there's real
URLs real IP addresses here and they
don't get excited and tied them into
your search engine of choice so linux
attacks there on a bit of a spectrum
cannot on the right hand side there's
kind of nation-state there's your
advanced activist groups and on the left
hand side is you know your automated
bots and kind of in the middle as your
script kiddies this talk is about the
left hand side not about the right we do
lots and lots of stuff on the right that
you know we're focused mostly in this
talk along kind of the automated bots
were actually a bit boring but more
interestingly is the kind of script
kiddies and they mount the kind of
attacks against our customers that you
know run up loads of his your credit
blaring customers with a mess bill you
know there's still data and you know
attack of the customers so you know
really annoying things and i don't
there's a name for this so i call this e
apt so extremely annoying persistent
threats actually see thousands of
thousands of them per second to
represent this in a lovely graph because
i like graphs this is just a small
snapshot of all the commands that are
entered into my sensor network over the
course of a couple of days and you can
kind of see on the left you've got the
kind of the real massive massive botnets
the mariah sck ones and you know they're
typing in the same commands over and
over again and so each bar represents
you know a series of commands typed in
and pretty much everything on this
screen is some kind of bots because
they're just so prevalent but if you
look at that tiny tiny tiny red speck at
the end there those are real people and
by kind of minor data and having a look
i can tell you that kind of in the
course of about a month 77 real people
had hands on the keyboard and we're
trying to attack people I mean these are
77 real people that you know make
mistakes mistakes that we perhaps can
use to protect customers so what kind of
attacks do we see well there's generally
kind of three no an attacker gets an
exploit and uses that exploit and then
immediately does some kind of action
then there's brute forcing you know
plagues everything every protocol can
brute force brute force they get a
credential then stall something and that
something is at the moment pretty much a
coin miner and then there's a third type
which is a little bit more interesting
which is brute force brute force brute
force they get credential and there is
no attack and then you know days maybe
weeks can pass by and then someone else
on some other infrastructure comes in
and kind of attacks that machine is
still some software so for us to kind of
use deception technology you know
correctly we need to understand this a
bit more all right why does this third
case differ from war rest and it comes
down to kind of the dark web and this is
a shot from dream market probably the
most popular kind of site at the moment
where you can buy kind of lots of
different things and if you type SSH up
there in the corner and hit enter you
couldn't buy kind of SSH creds two
machines on the Internet
and we're just there you can also buy
tools to kind of find your own creds as
well you know lots of other things for
sale on here but you know I'm
concentrating on those kind of SSH
credits cuz that's really prevalent to
our customers and they're doing a bit of
a translation now it's about five
dollars for a fast machine so you can
use someone else's infrastructure to get
your Netflix or or whatever
you can also buy things like billing
databases so this is a VoIP providers
billing database and that's about thirty
eight dollars so in it these are real
really happening today these are kind of
real screenshots from about a month the
game so the ultimate question here is
now we know a bit more about the attacks
how can we use deception to help prevent
it well the first thing it is kind of
what is deception
well it's an emerging area of InfoSec
that's been emerging for the last twenty
years most people have heard about it
from honey pots but there's loads of
different techniques in there as well
now Microsoft we've got a bit of a
history on this so two years ago Daniel
Edwards was presenting about the results
he found from putting up honey pots and
then last year Toma teller put some
things out and with honey tokens or
canary tokens you might know the mouse
which kind of shows how Microsoft use
this kind of technology and I've taken
this and kind of take you into a little
bit of another level so really really
briefly what are we talking about here
it's honey pots but not just any kind of
honey pot but first there real briefly
bit of a refresher the three basic type
of honey pots you've got low interaction
which is effectively just Wireshark you
put Wireshark in a box you get the
results you make pretty graphs you might
be able to kind of determine trends that
kind of stuff a medium which is you know
medium a interaction is a bit rubbish
it's you know you write a bit of code to
do just enough to do perhaps the
authentication collect a little bit more
information and then where most of the
industry is at the moment is with high
interaction honey pots and this is you
know a Linux VM it's you know on the
network it gets a attacked as soon as it
gets attacked and they brute force those
creds they tear it down put and you want
and you know take that information call
it threat intelligence and find
something to buy it but the big problem
is that you know pretty much all honey
pops are broken but fundamentally a
honeypot kind of tells you about the
attack and not the attacker and they're
really easy to spot so if you port scan
a honeypot there chances are it's got
about 200 ports open they're trying to
get as much data as possible you know
you can go on showdown there you can't
open the IP address of a machine and see
if it's a honeypot or not and you know
attackers do things like they land on a
box
they'll send some packets out and
they'll check to see if kind of like
what's my IP from a machine is the same
as the IP they've come in on and you
know loads of the big providers are
caught out by this this stuff so the
information you currently get from these
high interaction honey pots isn't all
that good anyway so we know we're being
attacked so can we use this deception
technology rather than kind of alert us
to an attack that we know we're going to
get but actually get it to tell us more
information about the attacker rather
than attack right I put it to you that
a tax change all the time but attackers
probably don't and at mystic we try and
take a lot of these these processes and
apply them to a kind of apt groups can
we take some of the things we've learned
by tracking kind of you know
state-sponsored groups and their ilk and
apply it to kind of the script Kitty
range put this another way when you're a
defender defending a network and you
receive and kind of use this honeypot
threat Intel what you're given is pretty
much kind of this if you can imagine
like an attack is like almost like a
playbook or a flow diagram of what an
attacker we're doing right login write
this command do a decision based on it
do another command if that work do this
command and at that point when you're
looking at kind of traditional high
interaction honeypot data
you only get success states and kind of
this is really annoying because the
understanding kind of the the other kind
of states an attacker could get into
understanding what's hidden underneath a
fog of war is the key to understanding
what kind of attackers are doing in the
first place and if we don't understand
what attackers are doing in the first
place then it's kind of game over for us
kind of what I want to do is kind of
force attackers to make difficult
choices and and those difficult choices
might get them to reveal different
infrastructure and if we got different
infrastructure then you know potentially
we can make they'd kind of what they're
doing more expensive or reveal kind of
infrastructure in a predictive
infrastructure they might use in the
future so how do we lift this fog of war
well I'm going to present to you kind of
a something a bit different and that is
a hybrid honeypot and what the hybrid
honeypot is trying to do is kind of lift
this fog of war and show all the
different states that you can get an
attacker into we can get off only
success state from our traditional
honeypot data but imagine if every
command that
attacker entered failed well that would
give us kind of these failure states and
what we want is something in between
both of those so rather than doing what
everyone else is doing which is creating
a nice machine for the attacker you know
that always works
I want to track them in a maze I want to
monitor their progress I'm gonna track
them almost like a rat and that's why I
liken this to a maze and if you kind of
know or understand graph theory you
could think maybe this flow diagram is
kind of connected weighted graph so what
is this hybrid approach well it's trying
to combine the best of each kind of
honeypot kind of interaction level low
medium and high along with specific
technology to deceive attackers and by
deceive them this is you know at the
human level trying to get them to do
some other behavior that we want them to
do we're trying to enumerate an
attackers behavior and we're doing this
by fault injection so what does that
mean
so what happens if you type double you
get your URL and it doesn't work well
chances are you might use another URL if
you're presented with the right
information what happens if you landed
in a box and you try to compile your
exploit and then you ran out and it
crashed
what happens if you landed on an old OS
that'd be really difficult to emulate or
really new OS you know this is what this
hybrid approach is trying to do and then
we're going to use this in addition to
you know current high interaction honey
pots to catch all the different rafter
behavior and attacker would use and do
this to kind of predict new
infrastructure potentially you'd think
that coming up with the faults that
would cause a attacker to make different
choices in this flow diagram would be
really really difficult one of the
things I'm saying today is it's not we
can get inspiration from loads of other
domains and pick up the rules that other
people are using kind of these are
domains like sales so salesmen do this
day in day out they have
on a training course and they'll tell
you need to know your audience create
problems and sold them agitate and solve
you know when you're injecting a fault
include a reason why and they have that
kind of a concept of scarcity and
reminding people that the choices are
making they're making of heirs to kind
of build confidence now there's other
places to look like magicians now they
say never reveal the secret to the trick
practice to perfection and don't repeat
the trick in front of the same audience
now Frank Abagnale said that you know
smarter people are more gullible and
this is kind of good for us and the
former head of international hostage
negotiation of the FBI Chris boss said
and the idea is to really listen to what
the other side okay the attacker is
saying and feed it back to them and
social engineering the art the human
hack of the book says you know listening
is a major part of being a social
engineer so that's what we need to do
and implement that in our honeypot and
if you're interested in what people are
doing in real life like just go on
YouTube and have a look at people who
are scamming the Microsoft technical
support scammers and they put great
videos up on there and you know I've
been very inspired by them but also you
know casinos you know they are experts
in the art of influence
they've got tricks to keep you in the
casino tricks to the school your body
clock tricks to make you think you're
richer than you are how do they do this
well they placed services strategically
they've got near wins that keep you
spinning for the jackpot everyone sees
the big prize in the casino but also
they try and give you a sense of control
and then finally game theory this is an
emerging area and I talk about magic
mapping behavior on to kind of this
interconnected graph and game theory is
all about kind of taking this graph you
know treating kind of these things
information warfare is game and a can we
model good and evil and you know the
limited work that is out there at the
moment says you know you can map kind of
this behavior onto game theory and what
they found is you know optimal their
optimal strategy wasn't kind of purely
random it was
to kind of make machines that don't look
like the most obvious targets but not
the least they're something in the
middle so crucially can we take all of
this and implement it in the language of
our choice so I've come up with a kind
of a few rules which I can of don't
create the most or least vulnerable
asset create a variety think carefully
replace these strategically listen
carefully this is the crucial one that
means high instrumentation of whatever
you're doing don't reveal the secret to
the trick helps you demonstrate these
things to different groups and let
attackers see these big wins but keep
providing them small ones so they keep
playing the game as I could work knowing
the audience which is no threat modeling
including reasons why when we inject
faults and where we can kind of create
problems and solve them this kind of
agitate and solve approach so these are
the techniques that we'll be
implementing lies persuasion mimicry
distraction traps and decoys laws and
breadcrumbs you know this is everything
society tells you not to do and I want
to take these techniques and implement
them in c-sharp and use them to get
attackers to make different choices move
them around my maze change the weights
in my graph and so I can get more
interesting threat intelligence first
off we need to start with our threat
model and this is in a pretty simple
that I'm not after BOTS now I can create
a simulation and the bots won't care
they'll just type all of their commands
in and that's all they know so I'm not
really after those no I'll get them for
free I'm not after state then they'll
never find the you know the simulations
I'm putting on the internet and they're
not really after them either and put too
much time and effort behind you know the
prep work and if they even got into them
they've despotic pretty quickly I'm
after this middle ground you know real
people b77 real people who are kind of
creating these attacks see script
kiddies what do I want to do well
I want to take time and resources away
from the attacker and divert them to my
honeypot infrastructure that way they're
not attacking real systems now I want to
make it so expensive for them to attack
people that they stop doing it and it I
hope that the accidental result of this
is you know the creds on the dark web
cost more or attacks go down yeah this
is what I'm after but before you go out
and kind of build all these things it's
worth saying that yeah I talk a lot to
kind of our lawyers and when we're
putting these things on the Internet we
need to be really mindful that we're not
creating victims that we're doing this
to protect customers we don't want to be
involved in an attack and that's quite
quite crucial and if we can we want to
protect everyone not just our paying
customers everyone can benefit from this
but crucially we don't want to be
involved or be used to carry out an
attack so what did I do
so I implemented an SSH server in
c-sharp and then on top of that built an
abashed / linux emulation 100% c-sharp
you can putty into this you can SFTP
files and winscp files you know you can
start docker images you can connect to
the database
I also log every tcp syn packet so I can
get the best from those live interaction
stuff and you would think that
implementing a decent Linux emulation
that would fall attackers would be
really really hard maybe it was a bit
but you can use district the techniques
I've talked about you know lies and
mimicry and distraction in you
implementation at first of all only
implement commands attack is going to
use and then you know the commands
they're going to use don't have to even
work like most commands that successful
on Linux don't print a response so you
know we get a lot of commands for free
but not doing even anything the most
complicated ones we can show canned
responses and they're even more
complicated ones we can write a bit of
code to do it you know the testing for
this is quite easy you can point
our simulation and a Linux machine and
make sure you get the same data
crucially there's no VM at play here
nothing is ever executed so how does it
work well everyone gets to log in the
first you get three attempts and you
will always get it and you'll always log
in and whatever user name will come
their password combination you try and
give you three attempts I'm not
interested in collecting user name and
password combos we've got other things
to do that I want to let you in I need
to provide a little bit of a barrier I
randomized the OS in the kernel so you
know I could be Ubuntu for one person I
could be Red Hat for the next and I
don't know if you've heard of kind of
cost of goods sold or cogs but this has
got really good cogs because in a high
interaction honeypot you have to spin up
a VM and you know there's lots of
maintenance surrounding that whereas I
can spin up thousands and thousands and
thousands of machines it's kind of on
demand these kind of fictitious machines
and then you know commands are typed in
and you know you get results now they
are at the Kandor programmed so we've
hosted these VMs which which have this
software on on loads of different data
centers and as your because we need to
protect ourselves and connect us a bit
of a no-brainer
also we host on other providers as well
because we know that attacks affect kind
of other people will probably affect us
tomorrow and this is all for security
Center and that product you know it
doesn't matter what infrastructure
you've got you might have some boxes
that are on Prem 1 some boxes that on
kind of other cloud providers and we
want to protect everybody so we want
we're kind of agnostic to providers
remember what I said about game theory
and casinos we want to strategically
place these assets so that's what we've
done in lots of different data centers
all over the world the problem is I log
so much data that I don't want to be
responsible for managing that and
way shape or form so I use log analytics
I take all this data push it into log
analytics which is great and then I can
query things really really fast off the
back of that the data we get and we
process this with you know a few
internal tools but also if we see URLs
or files we'll check that into
virustotal because there's no point just
us benefiting you know everyone can
benefit from that if we see a tax that
we can take action on because they're
viet customer VMS hosted on our
infrastructure on a jewel then we can
send reports to nsrc and get things
taken down there so getting a little bit
into kind of the data side if you
haven't seen christo there's a cousteau
query there and christos absolutely
great in query things really fast I can
query kind of many many gigabytes of
data you know in real time pretty much
and that's just a query that will give
you the top five use name password
combinations you can take queries like
this and you make wonderful dashboards
so this is my honeypot dashboard that
gives me kind of trends over time so I
talked about my SSH implementation and I
talked about listening carefully but
what does this actually mean so if we
apply this to an attacker it means we've
got to re-implement things from the
ground up to really get the maximum
value at what we're doing and this you
don't get this with high interaction
honey pots at all you're running
somebody else's code that probably
doesn't have the instrumentation so a
little bit about SSH you know it is
horrendously complex I won't recommend
anyone else implement it you know it's
remote access one moment it's a proxy
the next it has file transfer
capabilities kind of baked in it starts
a little bit like SSL or TLS we're kind
of both sides exchange the cipher suites
that they want to kind of use and they
agree on that and then messages are you
know produced by the client handled by
the service are pretty simple after that
and then it's got lots and lots and lots
of kind of client specific extensions
that crept in over time mostly kind of
putty ones so what do we get what's the
point of doing all this reimplementation
well
we get loads of information that we
wouldn't otherwise get that may or may
not be interesting so kind of cipher
Suites kind of that are in use on the
attackers real machine kind of the agent
string of their you know ssh climb which
can be really interesting kind of
terminal modes kind of real specific
linux things that you know the terminal
they're using actually supports and you
know things like the terminal size and
there's no smoking guns on this
information but you know it's it's
interesting to know know we can even in
some cases get the user's locale which
is can be quite useful for there may be
kind of geo-locating kind of an attacker
line get other things from that you know
what about your uptime because i record
the first packet that comes from the
attacker this packet is really special
because it's come from the attackers
machine and you know the tcp standard
says you know certain values need to be
present and they need to and it be
generated on the attackers machine so
magic field like the time to live the
window size and the tcp time-stamped
kind of give us interesting information
now we can work out uptime
can work out kind of the attackers real
OS even if they change their agent
string and the TTL give us a kind of
good approximation about how deep they
are into a network because it's kind of
decremented every kind of hop they do
yeah so this is great and what is the
point of all of this well now we have
our ssh implementation we can use these
tiny sources of entropy in the protocol
you know the ciphers that we found named
mote terminal modes all those kind of
things can collect it together and we
can use it to build a fingerprint a
fingerprint of the infrastructure there
as hacker is using this is great because
if we see an attacker over there you
know the maximum we get out of it was
you know an IP address before and now we
can use this fingerprint so we know it's
the same software being used over here
as over here so that's good i've said
you know we can work out the real OS and
how deep they are
and all these kind of things and we can
do things like compare them to the
agents during their sending so if I see
an attack that comes from an agent
string that says it's putty and the
underlying OS is lilyc so I know some
weird things are going on and that's a
telltale sign a something Bad's
happening but what if I told you I could
get someone's public keys if you have an
authorized key in your keyring on kind
of Windows or authorised key file on
Linux every time you connect to a remote
host the remote host can take those keys
and check to see if you can log in with
them and that's exactly what I do in my
implementation attacker provides in
their keyring and I say nope that's not
the key that can log in nor that one nor
that one and what people like Bangkok's
have done is built kind of databases of
these public keys and then you know
there's a link there to a service where
you can log in it'll tell you what your
ID and the great thing here is that if
we had a database of everyone's public
keys we could then start finding out who
is really doing these attacks or maybe
attribution aside and there is one such
database github allows you to pretty
much download everyone's public key as a
matter of course in order to make the
service work and so that's exactly what
I did I've got a fairly large database
of everyone's public keys and every time
someone logs into my honeypot I
enumerate all the keys on their system
and then compare it to what I've got and
I'll show you some results of that later
but back into kind of deception
technologies we need to start when an
attacker logs into a honeypot they
already decided that now this machine
could be a honeypot so we need to reduce
their fears over the environment in a
con they call this the put on and
interception technology we need to kind
of do the same thing we need to kind of
tell the attacker kind of not in words
but you know in actions that you know
this is a real machine
attack has already do this like some
phishing sites have gdpr warnings on the
top taking them make people think this
is legit so how can we do this in our
fake Linux simulated honeypot
environment well I found the best way
there's a legal disclaimer so you know
that's that's a good thing now you see
that and attack a good thing or you
wouldn't put this on your honeypot by
default would you so that's one way of
doing it how could we make this even
better well the answer is making it
extremely long because the longer you
put it on it the more likely it is to
come from an organization us have
mandated policy for this so that's what
we want to look like what other things
we can do well inject faults but will
cause us to get more URLs so the idea is
if you try and double you get something
with one URL and that fails that the
attack will probably use other
infrastructure and we want as many URLs
as we can but we can't get too greedy so
we use the rule of three you get two
kind of faults and then the third one
appears to work another thing you do is
try and reach the data we're getting
from these attackers and a good example
of this is from the zip files loads and
loads of malware Linux malware will be
delivered in a zip file because the
Tekkit finds it easy the problem with
that is there's not a lot of metadata
that I can go that was it filed to be
able to do you know further processing
on it what we want is tar files tar
files have loads of metadata and here's
an example of two kind of real attacks
and the tar files that were delivered
and you can see we get a little bit more
information and this is the you know
potentially the username of the person
who created that archive so how can we
make someone use tar it was it well this
is incredibly simple and we just say
that you know zip doesn't work instead
you have to use tar and there can be
loads of different messages we put into
that so you know that we're not using
the same trick every time another thing
we do is
try and track stolen data so we seed our
environment with files to make it more
valid and when attackers break in no
chances are they nose around because why
wouldn't you we want to track this
information we want to know where it
goes and crucially kind of these kind of
honey or canary tokens before they've
been used to kind of warn you in it of
an attack but we're in a different
standpoint that we know we're being
attacked so can we use this kind of for
tracking instead and the answer is yes
you know here's an example of you know
some of the files we put up and someone
will download you know link text and
I'll type the link into their browser
and hopefully it'll be on different
infrastructure and then I'll get a
warning in my inbox saying this things
happened and then we can use that to
kind of get more information on how an
attack is being it kind of run but it's
just not enough to put files up there
and expect people to click on them we
need to do this kind of we have to
practice our lures so if you do that if
you create a directory with important
files and put in voiced or text in it
first of all no one's going to download
it and second all their blacklist your
IP address because it just looks so
weird we want to do things like like
this we want to get an attacker to find
that file themselves because if they
find it themselves they will believe
that they found something the perhaps no
one else would have seen and we used
every trick in the book to try and make
this the most attractive file to
download so I've ringed a few things
there the most colorful icon largest
file name the file sizes are kind of
tricking the eye into making it so it's
kind of a bit arrow like the time stamp
really stands out so does the group and
the directory it's in as well and we do
all of these things to kind of draw the
eye so that being an interesting file
and one other technique we use is
scarcity and salesmen use this really
really well I know we've only got one
car left at this price so you better
make this choice now how can we map this
onto a you know some think that we can
take and put into a honey pot well there
are a few ways of doing this but the
best one I found is this your machine is
going down for reboot you've got to do
something quickly otherwise you're going
to lose access to this this combined
with other techniques to you know make
it a high value proposition for them it
really works crucially we're doing
things like we got scarcity but we're
officers giving a reason why you shed
you'll reboot this this machine will
come up again and you might not have
access to it so I've implemented this
I've been running this I think since
about May and the good news is that show
Dan doesn't think I'm a honeypot so
that's really good so it's all about the
results it's not enough nowadays to
collect all this threat intelligence and
have a massive database you've got to do
things with it and I want to show you
kind of here kind of two real attacks
they've kind of slam together into a bit
of slide where this is kind of what you
get from a real high interaction
honeypot I know this is an attack this
is what you would see this is what you
would write you're in a detection logic
against and it's not very much then
there's a lure in there and you know
there's disclaimer but you know I want
more stuff so this is what you will see
if you kind of put deception technology
onto it yeah
things don't work I mean some commands
work some commands don't you know we
can't use unzip because you know that's
not there we're you know changing
targets but attackers behavior we're you
know injecting faults and we're
introducing a scarcity so we're building
confidence we have a lure you know we've
got the you're on the billing server and
that's the big win we're including
reasons why faults occur you know you
can't fault we can't find libs it but we
found you know lib G's ed and live B's
it I see maybe you should use those as
well
you know we're using the rule of three
and with small wins to keep them playing
for this big prize
we're enriching our data where we
possibly can and we're using distraction
and scarcity to make them make mistakes
we've already done our really good
listening so in addition to all of this
here we get there real OS we get public
keys
I like metrics
I'm exercise everything are we doing a
good job with this well let's have a
look at unique URLs into just by real
people first of all there's got a trend
line that goes up that's good and
statistically there's look like a
constant error in this graph because
some attackers always use kind of some
randomness in their URL but now things
are getting better we are collecting
more URLs from people who are logging in
from real attackers and we put these in
our internal threat database and we send
them to virustotal so kind of everyone
can benefit let's have a look at time
spent by attackers in our environment
and that's going up as well so this is
over about a month and a half as we're
deploying different deception technology
into our sensor network it's a 12-hour
graph and what you can see is that now
there is a gradual trend up and it's
worth noting that a lot of these kind of
attacks at this end of the spectrum you
know these are smash and install
operations you know you get your creds
you get in there you you put your mouth
a down you get out so the fact that
they're spending more and more time you
know that's really great for us we've
gone up from about one minute to a
little bit over to you and in some cases
there's some really high outliers in
there which is good one of the ways that
I prove that can I'm doing a good job
with this if we compare the IP addresses
that we've got to get from this
technology and then query our own
internal threat databases and then what
do we get well I sampled a hundred IPS
that I've seen through this
infrastructure and compared them to our
other databases and about twenty to
thirty percent were already known by
other sources so we're definitely adding
value by doing this
well about some real attacks well we
felt there was an attack came in from
digitalocean and attack and tried to
install a coin miner you know not that
interesting to be honest now I get to
see the attack the commands they're
typed in you know the Monaro wallet
they're mining against but ordinarily
from our kind of data sources that would
be all we see but this attacker also
downloaded linked or text and they took
link text and they used different
infrastructure to kind of visit that URL
so a clean IP address and that IP
address linked them back to Romania so
that's really good we've we've got
additional information that we would
never not otherwise have got there's
some kind of other cases of attackers
you know testing their infrastructure
and I didn't even think when I did this
kind of query that I'd get anything back
but I got two different attackers
testing their infrastructure and then
you can go onto your search engine of
choice and google those and find the
actual script that was used in the
attack and then you can find the author
and you can track that author back to
you know github and then you can track
that back to maybe WordPress dumps
they've done in the past you know
databases they've compromised
maybe you track them back to Instagram
maybe you're talking about to their
steam profile so at that point we've
linked you know someone testing out
their script maybe attribution is hard
attribution is really hard people but we
maybe found the author of of that attack
now I really love public keys and I've
been collecting public keys for about
two months and I'll say attribution is
really really hard and then when we're
using these keys and kind of comparing
them to our database you know the person
themselves might not be an attacker they
could have had their infrastructure
compromised this all could be fake you
know put up by attackers for our benefit
but let's see we're kind of it it goes
anyway so the first hit I got got mean
it back to someone's get our page and I
got there
and their username which I've kind of
blanked out there which is real
information that I would another
otherwise you know not been able to get
and then I got someone else and I got
their picture and their full name and
you know lots of other things and its
really common I'm sure you do it as well
as I know we use usernames between
different services and I'm quite bad
because I will take usernames that I
find and then type them in to search
engines and find people's Instagram
pages and then I'll go through their
Instagram pages and I'd find the photos
and geolocate their photos and in this
case I think have found the actual
keyboard that was used in the attack
maybe attribution is hard now is this a
bad person I don't know and I'm not here
to say this person is bad or good but
infrastructure related to kind of these
accounts was used in this attack know
what else do I see lots and lots of
proxying I see Android kind of user
agent headers and kind of Android
traffic I see kind of your eBay searches
that's yours IDs attackers and I see
kind of Amazon things as well and you
know why do I get all of this
well it comes back to the dark web and
that people are using some of these
services to kind of proxy traffic
they're literally breaking in and
deciding to proxy all their traffic
through there which quite frankly I
think is madness but hey what else do I
get well I'd say probably by and large
it's C to traffic and this is a quick
example of an attacker communicating to
their WordPress backdoor because you
certainly don't want to talk to your
exploit server by you know your home IP
address you want to use someone else's
infrastructure and I see you know this
is by far and large what I see the most
of but it's not all good bad things
happen and you know I talked a lot about
creating laws and making them really
attractive well if you repeat the same
trick to the same person twice they
might find out and this is exactly what
this person did
and they left me a message and you know
that wasn't good and this for me is a
bit of a failed state you know there was
a glitch in the matrix we did something
wrong
so at this point I'm going find kind of
the related sessions I'll understand
what happened to our AB commands change
output excetera to put this attacker
back on the kind of right path but
sometimes you get into weird states
you know this attacker and was you know
looking to see if this was a honeypot
machine and they ran this command and
they decided there was something that
they didn't like about the output of
this you know the file I put there was
wrong or something what did they proceed
to do they tried to nuke the box you
know they're catting dev random into the
raid array they're deleting the default
route to the internet and I'm rebooting
the machine so you may think this is
also a failed state but it's not because
the attacker thought it was real
remember this is all 100% c-sharp this
is all you know fiction is a hundred
percent simulation so the fact that
attackers think they're gonna have these
effects kind of shows that I'm going
down the right lines hopefully and also
makes me think that you know person got
quite angry which no it's wasting their
time so they're not attacking our
customers so that's good in these kind
of cases what I'll do is I'll take all
the infrastructure down recycle the IP
addresses so you know they don't put us
on a blacklist or something another good
example is when someone spent ten
minutes trying to fix the DNS resolver
and you know looking through the
commands it's like you can feel the
sense of terror and dread and this is
great because I know these this person's
only got one set of infrastructure and
it's kind of desperate for it to work in
the end they just got disconnected
because you know you've only got a few
that we only give attackers you know ten
minutes or so to do this so we get all
this data and what do we do with it well
we use it to inform and develop
detections for as your security center
and this is your security center here
and we use this to kind of train machine
learning models we give analysts a fee
real attack data so they understand the
merging attacks and they can write
detection for it we test our detection
z' against this data and you know we've
improved our detection by about 75% in
it it gives analysts more time to spend
on you know the areal emerging attacks
and when you opt into a SC you get these
alerts here and a lot of these are based
off this data if you're interested in
more deception stuff this is cliff Stoll
and this is his book and I really
recommend that you read it and cliff was
doing this kind of deception stuff you
know years and years and years before it
was popular so it's a really interesting
book to read so I'll leave you with this
to say that Microsoft is using deception
technology to protect customers
crucially we want to understand the
attack and the attacker because we can
write detection for the attacker well
that gives us loads of attacks if you
want to start using this you should be
using AZ set pack or as your security
center and if you've got big data and
you don't want to don't care too much
about how how to process it and you just
want to run queries you should be
pushing it into log analytics because
it's great okay that's the end and I can
get all of those things
[Applause]