this is a important from seung-hyun
University in South Korea
my team came here for a third hackathon
project I to NSF I to NSF central
interface to the security functions for
the cloud-based network of city services
my team are seven students and one Korea
telecom operator and also the researcher
are involved dissertation project we
have proved our data driven security
management operations overseas the I to
NSF is to make interfaces and framework
for heterogeneous that took curative
solutions how to integrate the using
standard interface this time hackathon
we proved a data-driven a young model to
manage a security policy and enforcement
or the skills policy into the 3d
function learning on top of the culture
religion environment we implemented two
things the first one is why were based
on the port information the second one
is a repeater or based on the content
such as debatable YouTube the content
over HTTP a web a protocol can filter
out we demonstrate our framework and the
center of the interfaces based on iso
MSA a protocol we implemented the idea
based on IETF sort function training
establishes so we combine the talk on
fire and web filter together based on
SFPD framework next time we announce our
model especially focus on consumer page
interface also we worked for the ledger
agent interface and then we fully
implement our I to NSF standard
interfaces and that we can approve also
our from there our young model will be
are synchronized with another or
whatever supa supa means simplify the
use of
use your policy so we can work for
on-air work together