my name is Howie Peterson and I'm from
the free university in Berlin and I'm
also one of the riot team team core
developers so this is actually my first
time too I tff never been here and also
my first time to the ITF hackathon then
of course and we came here with quite a
large group about like 10 people from
the riot team and so what we are hoping
for is to connect riot which is an
operating system for very small
constraint IOT devices to connect that
of course to other projects and
protocols that are going on at ITF and
so we have picked different topics which
we try to prepare it IDF and the one
topic I'm involved in currently is to
try to port the home net protocol Saudi
NCP and agency p4 very constrained tiny
devices so we talked to the guys from
home Ned who are actually also here and
that's one of the nice things about the
hackathon that you just can connect to
all the people that basically made those
protocols you're trying to implement and
talked a little bit with them and they
said it's maybe not their their core
concern for the protocol to to have it
on those kind of devices we will we will
try it anyway and see how far we get and
then kind of have a working version on
those systems we can evaluate for the
future and see if there might be room
for improvement or other kind of
profiles we would need for those kind of
devices and kind if ever life they're
more feasibility study in the end so
yeah and if you want to learn more about
riot just go to ride West org and there
you find of course all the high-level
information what riot what it's about
and but more importantly you find the
links to get her where you find all of
our code it's all open source also you
find the links to our mailing list where
you have a very very good starting point
to get in touch with the community to
get in touch with the people actually
who made the ideas who started
everything and so from there basically
you get all the information you need and
it's also a very active community and
that's what we're focusing on very much
on these not only the technical aspect
but also the community aspect and then
the open-source idea behind it because
in an hour would be strongly believe in
is that if we have all these embedded
tiny devices all around the world and
everywhere with like millions of things
or billions of things even in the
Internet of Things and we only really
can trust those devices if we have free
software which we can trust which we can
and look into and also of course free
called an open protocol it's not free of
it and and so that is the main idea and
that's why we're also pushing this idea
put community so much because only an
open nice community can actually create
something that's open and a nice ears