I have my name's Keith burns I'm with
open daylight and work on group based
policy and service function chaining
here is my ETA for the first time we're
here at the hackathon just held before
the official idea start I guess on
Saturday and Sunday and just working
with the group of folks on extending the
group based policy and service function
training functionality there's a service
function training working group here at
the ITF and recently I opendaylight we
integrated both the projects and has
been implementation so we thought we'd
come here and just extend the work and
find out how we can work better with the
ITF and the service function training
working group yes so one of the real
benefits of the hackathon has been asked
is getting outside of the typical
opendaylight community and seeing people
who haven't necessarily understood the
controller where we work and having to
explain to them how things work together
getting different perspectives that's
been really helpful and we've got a lot
of great ideas for our next release as
well as a hopefully a bunch of new
contributors and you know how to be more
involved in the ITF moving forward out
of this so the hackathon has been really
good really valuable it's been nice many
bunch of folks here to cause a huge
benefit