hi I'm Rick to Aniak and I lead Cisco's
devnet program which is a program we
started back in two thousand January
2015 and it's Cisco's developer program
and what we're trying to do with Dev net
is in the networking world is being
bring traditional software developers
and traditional networking experts
together in form a new community around
networking we're here at the I ATF we
just had a successful hackathon where we
had 135 people learning and developing
on top of our networking platforms these
events are very important to us and
they're synergistic with the IETF we
want you all to get involved because we
want to build that developer community
as large as possible thanks