yes hack my talk but supporting
kubernetes um that's what we are now
talking about and I'm also very
surprised that most of the people still
sitting here because we're talking about
kubernetes and I always see people like
running away from it and that's why I
give this talk to give you like an not
like a real overview but uh introduce
you to some yeah weaknesses kubernetes
have and we will look at the logic of
kubernetes itself
so
to start I will give you a brief
introduction to who I am my name is
Benjamin kolterman I'm from Germany I'm
the former CEO of avalanche we are doing
kubernetes auditing and kubernetes
security for larger companies
I'm also in kubernetes or Cloud security
engineer as you want to call it um CTF
player at fluxfingers and so my Twitter
handle is paquito or packet zero
so um before I start actually thanks to
Google Cloud for sponsoring the
environment
um I want to keep it short uh I created
the whole kubernetes environment and
some it's a bit pricey so I just want to
thank uh to say thank you to Google the
whole talk is not about gke it's about
vanilla kubernetes it's very important
and some yeah just let you know
so what's on the agenda for today we are
going to start with can you eat it I
will give you a brief introduction about
what kubernetes is I think Matthias did
a really good job on it so we will keep
it short the next thing we are going to
look at is the demo environment because
actually this talk is running in
kubernetes the slides are in kubernetes
it's not PowerPoint and stuff like this
it runs inside of kubernetes
um at third we are going to have like a
little 101 of kubernetes security just
that you learn some yeah some yeah some
security issues that exist in kubernetes
uh the fourth topic is we'll go and have
a look at the advanced scenarios and at
last one I we will do like a little
security evaluation of the kubernetes
application itself you're currently
seeing here
so let's start uh can you eat it no you
cannot eat kubernetes kubernetes
um is like more it's it's a uh it's a
word some some people don't have hit so
just to starting like with little joke
um what is kubernetes actually it's in
container orchestrator and I also wanted
to keep it short it consists of worker
and masternodes so the Masters like the
controlling component that does the
scheduling of your workloads and some of
the the worker nodes actually running
all of the workloads so there's yeah
kind of you differentiate between master
and worker nodes
kubernetes also has these uh yeah
concept of everything as an API object
so actually every port you run in your
kubernetes is an API object you can for
example also curl it if you like
authorized to the kubernetes API
so everything is an API object and we
will see that one later
also the most here at kubernetes let's
say words or objects you will find are
nodes which are like the VMS the
workloads are running on namespaces
which are like logical separation of
your for logical separation of your
workloads there are deployments
deployments consist of PODS and yeah
deployments consist of PODS so they like
kind of Define where and how your
workload or your Port is going to be run
then there are Services services are
there to let's say exposing pots to
other pods or to the internet and
there's Ingress which does like Ingress
control as you might have guessed
um also this is also something I want to
keep really short because Matthias did
the introduction to it
um
I just want to say that the cube API
server is like an https or an HTTP API
where users actually talk to the cluster
so I copied
um the for me or for the security forks
and most important sentence from the
kubernetes documentation just that you
if you read it um everyone here should
yeah should think about and should think
oh I have really to secure this one and
yeah the cube API server let is like the
primary let's say
um yeah API where you talk to where you
can like control all of your components
and all of your API objects
the next one is hcd hcd is like database
where the whole where your whole cluster
configuration is stored also something
um where you have a look at and where
you where security strategy should apply
the next stuff is the cubelet um the
cubelet is like the primary node agent
runs on every node exposes an HTTP an
https port and so with the cubelets you
can like control the pods that are
running on the Node where the cubelet is
running and that's also why you should
definitely have a look at it and also
get that one into your security strategy
and the last one is the container
runtime the container runtime itself is
just responsible for running your
container workloads but also that one
belongs should be long in your container
should belong to your kubernetes
security strategy so that's it for the
brief introduction into kubernetes
nothing more
um let's start with kind of
the fun things
so let's have a look at the demo
environment I created
um I taught about doing this talk and I
needed kind of a demo application so
after thinking for like two minutes I
was like hey let's do my presentation in
kubernetes and actually it looks like
this so it's a little application we
have one masternode we have two worker
nodes
um we actually have one namespace that
works like in content delivery Network
delivers like the JavaScript and the
pictures you're currently seeing and
there's another namespace that works uh
yeah kind of as the static HTML that are
it's currently serving my slides so
there are two deployments and two
different namespaces and yeah those are
running the presentation you currently
see
what we also have to do for this talk is
we need to do some assumptions so the
first one is I don't attack the
kubernetes source code itself it will be
just on the kubernetes logic so you
won't see me doing like oh here's like
one bits in the source code is said
wrong
um you can do buffer overflow there it
is more like those are real kubernetes
features and we are like abusing real
kubernetes features we are attacking the
logic of kubernetes
um also this talk has no interaction
with any third-party product it's only
vanilla kubernetes you will find
anything you see here you can do
anything without third party products
and the search the first third step is
after a successful exploitation of
application in some scenarios yeah the
hacker gains access to different
um kubernetes resources
this is something I had to put in
because if you configure kubernetes like
right
um it's extremely hard nearly too
impossible with only attacking the logic
of kubernetes like to gain code
execution in the cluster and stuff like
this so
um some scenarios some or some Advanced
scenarios you will see are building on
that we have hacked for example the
application the web front end and gains
let's say access to the node or stuff
like this
so let's do some math the 101 of
kubernetes security it's also I will
keep this one short um and I have
prepared lots of demos so looking
forward to those one
first of all a malicious container image
I think that's
um you all know what's what's going to
happen if you like have a malicious
container image there are like two
scenarios we either pull it directly
into the cluster or some developer
builds like a Docker image a new one and
the first line is basically you choose
your base image and if your base image
is the malicious image then also you
have malicious code in your cluster so
take away from this one is scan your
container images please do it mostly
malicious container images are like the
first entry point when malicious code
comes into the cluster
next one is the cube API server what we
can do there
um Cube API server actually gets
restricted using arbark so please use
role-based access if you are creating
for example service accounts and stuff
like this and also every pod in your
cluster has a service account attached
so if one pod is compromised
the attacker in the pot has valid
kubernetes credentials and he can talk
to the API and then it's up to you what
your role-based access looks like to get
the configuration right also please
Harden your TLS configuration because if
your TLS is like kind of up
um everyone could read what your traffic
is and maybe don't do public exposure it
depends uh how if you need it or not but
if you don't expose the cube API you're
reducing the attack service massively
so let's go on with the cubelet and um
yeah the cubelet is as I said the
primary node agent and per default
that's also in the kubernetes
documentation it allows unauthenticated
access to their https endpoint which
grants control over the node and
containers so normally per default it is
getting better with time so what we are
currently seeing is if you deploy now a
vanilla kubernetes it has this
configurations set so in the
documentation it still says it's
unauthenticated access but if you're
actually going to create your vanilla
kubernetes cluster you will see that
those argumentations for the cubelet are
set so
if you have maybe like an older version
go look at at the cubelet flags if
Anonymous authorization is is false or
off
um because otherwise
yeah you can just curl your cubelet on
slash pots and see every pot that's on
your node
um so please make sure that those
configurations are set and also for the
API server
ensure that uh yeah you have the
authorization on and that you're using
role-based access and node authorization
we will come to that one later
um where this one extremely helps but
just to make sure those are the like
arguments you definitely should be
setting for the cubelet and for the AP
Cube API server
so let's head into container runtime
security a bit
um
yeah let's start with like a container
breakout if you don't Harden your
container runtime
um what we're doing here is we like run
a pot
um in this case it's named name breakout
we over we do we do override of the yaml
we deployed for example we are setting
the host PID to true so our pod can
actually use the host process IDs
um yeah our pod actually sees the host
process IDs thus we can then later do an
NS enter which is like we're entering
namespace of the first process we are
entering the mount name space so we like
have the yeah the root file system of
the node literally like Mount or we are
entering the same namespace as
um yeah as the root file system of the
host has and we have full code execution
there and let me see if I just can pull
that one over yes
I hope you
all can see oh that's like I should have
mirrored it's um and if I'm going to
copy this one
and I hope the internet is good enough
and I execute it
just need to wait a little bit
yeah and there it is
um we now literally did a container
breakout it's like a very very very
basic thing
um
and we could only do it because we could
use the host pids and we could also
start the privileged pod that's very
important and to show you that we like
have the container breakout I will just
do show you that I can list all
containers running on the Node
um those are all the containers running
on the Node I'm using CTR which is like
um yeah Docker just for container d
um so we are now on the Node and we are
root on the Node so we could like do
everything there
um so the main takeaway of this is
please please don't allow privileged
pods it's very important because
otherwise this happens to you and
everyone who could run a port
um literally can get root on the Node
so let's head into some more advanced
scenarios and those scenarios are
yeah as I said um advanced
so who uses kubernetes here like who
uses kubernetes maybe in in their
company okay okay some of you and who
does kubernetes security from you here
okay okay also some some some folks nice
nice to hear
um
so the first Advanced scenario is like
we can create every resource in the
cluster or we just need one specific
resource but let's say we can create
resources in a cluster and we aim to
read every newly created secret even
though we are not currently access or
actively accessing the cluster so what
we like wanted to do is we will do we
want to do data exploration on
kubernetes with only the kubernetes
logic without even like touching
um yeah vulnerable code in kubernetes
so what we are going to need is like we
need an admission controller uh we need
to validate an admission web hook in
this case an admission controller
Matthias also did an introduction uh
there the validating admission
controller like validates every API
requests and we then can send we can
then send those API requests that are
validated to our server uh actually this
looks a bit like this one so as user you
kind of yeah you want to deploy your
yaml to the API server but in between
their mission controller and says is it
valid or is it not valid so
yeah in both Direction either it's valid
and it's got a sec accepted and then
it's stored in hcd or if it's not then
it's like thrown away or yeah or you get
a warning and stuff like this
um so I will do the demo at the end of
this scenario so let's head into what
does our admission controller looks like
um what we can create is uh we yeah we
create the validating admission webhook
configuration and we need uh yeah some
operations where it should like get our
secrets and we are looking for the
create and update operation in no matter
what API Group and no matter what API
version but we wanted to have the
resource Secrets here
and also important is notice that it's
like sent to my URL
so and let's demo this one I think
um
so I hope everyone can
read it
um yeah so actually here's like my
admission
weapon configuration looks exactly this
is the same like you see it on the
slides
um and also I will show you
um just to make sure
there is that you can see that or that
you can see that what what's running
inside the cluster this is currently
running inside the cluster so
uh just to let you know so let's apply
this one
no there it is
so now we
get it and see if it's there
okay there's our secret checker
um to actually like receive the secrets
uh I will just open another shell and
SSH onto my command and control server
where the secret is going to be sent
so
um and the command control server
there's an nginx running so I think you
all know what nginx is and and what it
does
and I'm just logging
the kubernetes requests that are coming
or are sent to the API so to This nginx
Server I actually think I have to
restart it
um
start engine X
and now let's have a look at the log
and on the left side if you are now
going to let's say create
a secret
what
as you can see it we are now creating a
secret a generic secret I call it demo
and we are using the key is password and
the thing that is like concealed is
super secure
and if I'm sending that one
you see I'm getting stuff here
and if we like searching for the right
field uh here it's password it's our key
you will see something base64 encoded
um yeah so let's no
let's Echo that one
into a base64 and decoded and you see
actually super secure so what you can do
is we can do data exfiltration in every
namespace this is not regulated or
dedicated to one namespace we can create
the submission controller and let it
like get our all of our secrets or any
resource we Define where we Define the
scope of the admission controller we can
send it to our server and then we can do
whatever we want with it and um yeah
it's like native kubernetes logic and
kind of let's say built in
so this is for the first one
yeah so let's head into the next
scenario
um the next one is a little bit
I would say not that much complex but it
is something you you sometimes see at
companies that are that didn't like
shift in their heads to the new
infrastructure model we see today so
what you have like in in the good old
days let's say like this um developers
are allowed maybe to debug their codes
on like Dev VMS and stuff like this and
it is possible and I've seen it a lot um
that companies for example allow their
developers to get a dedicated note just
for them and where they can do for
example their stuff they can debug
special Network purposes there and all
of those things so the scenario is like
we are like an developer
who somehow gets access to the node and
um yeah what we now can do is we can get
ourselves every deployment that is
deployed into the cluster like
everything
um and we can do it or we can just do it
let's say when the deployment uses
something special which I will show you
so we're like in the scenario of
stealing deployments from maybe other
Dev teams
we can do it changing note labels so the
way kubernetes
like schedules workloads is using node
labels and node selectors so what you
actually can do is you you label your
node for example you have a kubernetes
node there is let's say GPU
um or it has a GPU in it and then you
label GPU through your node let you know
okay this node has a GPU and you can
then tell your deployment
um that requires a GPU to run only on
that node using a node selector but we
could also abuse this one if we like can
set node labels so I can label my def
node GPU true and with some let's say
also luck or if I remove the label from
another node I can get this deployment
scheduled on my node and then I have
like if I have access to to the node I
can have also access to the Pod and then
I can access the Pod and maybe have a
look inside
um yeah the deployment the other team
actually builds
so what we can do
is we can label or I will do the demo at
the end again we can do label our node
with like Cube CTL label
um yeah label the node with the node
name key value pair
and in the deployment it will look like
this I talked about the node selectors
and the node selector we are using now
is like we are
looking at the node selector I am
currently using for my talk so the node
selector I'm using is app slides to
deploy slides on the I think it was the
worker 2 node I didn't currently have
its um but we'll look at the node
selector app slides and we will abuse
this one to like get the deployment
scheduled on on the right node
okay this is this complainer so
let's head into that one
I don't need the command controls over
here
so let me first show you
the current labels that are set
um
there it is
so we can see that the worker one has a
label called app CDN for Content
delivery Network and we can see that
worker 2 has
a label called app slides
if I now has have access to let's say
Node 1 and I'm simulating all to that
one
sshing on worker one
so I now have access to that one giving
me pseudo rights just that everything
works out as planned
what I normally find on the Node is
credentials for the cubelet so everyone
who has access to node has also access
to the kubernetes API and what I then
can do under
Etc kubernetes on every node you will
find cubelet cubelet conf and this Cupid
conf you can use to talk to the API
server so what I do is I do an export of
my cubeconfig
and set it to wait let me show you let
me show you like this and set it to the
cubelet conf so now that I have a valid
um kubernetes config I can do like Cube
CTL we get ports for example
and
or like this and I see every pods or I
see every pods running in the cluster
um now what we want to do uh also show
the nodes oh chipctl Cube CDL get notes
and show the labels
oop typo there
so I can also get the notes and I can
now also label my notes so I do Cube CTL
label oh
I don't have the LDS here set Cube CTL
CTL label nodes
um worker one
worker one with app
slides
so
like this one and what I have to do
because I can only set one yeah one
label with the key app I have to
overwrite my current label
so let's do this dish overwrite
and my notice labeled so now I can if I
now do the cube CTL
get notes show labels you will see both
of the nodes now have the label slides
and you guess where it's going
um
if I now for example let's simulate
that the slide deployment is restarted
oops okay get parts
yeah I'm in the right namespace so
currently we will see there's a white
you currently see that it's scheduled on
worker 2.
I can either now let's say restart uh
this the slide port or
um
I will just scale this one for
uh yeah just that that it works on the
first time because I now have like a 50
50 chance that the deployment is
scheduled on the Node I control and if
I'm not going to try it um yeah I just
scale it uh that makes it a bit easier
scale slides reply cars let's say five
oh
so and if I now do a get pods
you see that there are also pods
scheduled on work one these two and
those two parts because I control the
node I have literally full control over
it so if I do here CTR Dash and
kubernetes I O container list
oh that's quite that's quite big
let's do it a bit like this one
um you can see for example over here
that there are slides scheduled so yeah
I can could now debug uh the containers
that are scheduled on my note and I
could have look at it and um yeah those
attacks are
normally like seen when you like have
larger Dev teams that are developing not
only one application for on one
kubernetes but like developing together
those steps if they have access to the
node those could take over the
deployment of the other team and that's
something to consider if you're like
yeah
um developing
some some application with the larger
security
so let's head into the next
one or more how you can fix those
we have an admission controller in
kubernetes uh it's named node
restriction and the node restriction
Mission controller uses or lets you use
specific labels of the form node
restriction.kubernetes.io and no
cubelets can modify this label
um let's do a spontaneous demo I didn't
plan to demo this one but uh
let's do this
no
oh no didn't mention
didn't mean to inspect
um
so if when I do a cube CTL label worker
one
using this label
um app CDN
CDN
uh oh labeled up this label note
if I'm going to label this one and let's
have a look over here
if I now do a cube CTL we get nodes they
still show labels
um you we should see that here is like
the that the labels should be set over
here I don't know ah here is a note
restriction yeah kubernetes I O fcdn
this admission controller is also
enabled by default now if you deploy
vanilla kubernetes so you don't have to
like edit your Cube API and stuff like
this so if I'm not going to do Cube CTL
uh
Cube CTL like label node worker one
um I copy this
label
and let's hope it works because it's
really spontaneous demo
um slides yeah you see I cannot edit the
label so the admission controller
restricts the label editing thus I can
yeah I can now safely deploy my
application if I use the node
restriction labels in my deployment
um so you have kind of to adapt your
deployment using the node restriction
labels and that's like the key takeaway
here
it's forbidden it's not allowed to
modify labels but uh
good try
um yeah you see it's forbidden so um
yeah I cannot overwrite the label in
this form
um so it's not quite complex to use
those labels but that can give you like
good security if you use them
yeah and now let's head into the last
one and the last one is kind of a post
application exploitation technique where
we if we like successfully exploited
code that runs in kubernetes like this
talk and we have really deep access on
the Node root access wouldn't it be a
great thing to create like our Auto
scaling malware within kubernetes out of
scope for every application
um out of scope for every
yeah kubernetes security product out
there I think it is so let's do it
who here uh that also does kubernetes
security is aware of pause containers
oh you you know name that's great
so let's build our Auto scaling malware
in kubernetes
and we are going to abuse post
containers
um what is the post container for those
of you who have never heard it the pause
container is like
yeah it's it's
a container that start is in every pot
running in every pot under the radar of
the kubernetes API
um it for example holds the network
namespace open in case the container
restarts that if your container restarts
it gets assigned the same IP address
that's because the post container is
there and it's also responsible for
reaping zombie processes so yeah that
there are no zombies running inside of
your kubernetes cluster so let's abuse
this one
um this is like kind of little step to
step guide how you can do it if you like
it and the post exploitation phase and
successfully exploit the kubernetes
application and have a deep access on
the Node
so first of all oops determine uh which
containers which container runtime is
used
so
um yeah we just need to make sure that
we know which runtime is used in our
case it's a container D running you can
have a look at it for example
if you
new seconds if we do like Cube CTL get
notes Dash or white oh that
yeah they there you see uh that we are
currently using container DS container
runtime
um or you just can go and have a look on
the Node itself and um
yeah you see from the tools or from the
directories created which can or from
the processes which container runtime is
used
second step is find out how this
container runtime is the sandbox or
pause containers it's a little bit
different from runtime to runtime for
container D it's like we are just
setting
um one parameter for a cryo as an
example you have to set not only one I
think there are three parameters to set
but you can read about it in the
documentation of the container runtime
um the third step is you know let's
build our own post container we have to
fulfill some requirements
um but we also could use like the
official pause.c file and then put our
little put a little like shell command
on front of it you will see it later
because I actually built my own post
container
and we what we should also do is either
place the pulse container image on the
nodes or put it in like a publicly
accessed registry with that doesn't
require Authentication
and the fifth thing is reload the
container runtime to use the newly
created pulse container
so let's demo also this one
um so I have here root access on the
worker node
and I said we have the containerdy
runtime so in ETC container D you will
find config files
I can do it a bit better I hope you can
you can all see it
and let's have a look at the current
config tunnel this is a config I set
normally there is no config terminal but
this is also the default pause image for
kubernetes is called it's kfs GCR i o
and if we do like the CTR listing we can
also see that there are pulse containers
running and they're running several of
them so it's running in like every pod
and now I built my own pulse container
yeah it's uh this image so I just copy
it over
it's almost back to conflict tomorrow
let's have a short look at it there's
running my post container
um what does my pause container do I
also show you that one
so it is I will give you I will give you
the docker file
um it's just like a standard Ubuntu
image I copy the officialpost.c from the
kubernetes repo over in this container
and my command is I just curl my demo
server here to like show you that it
works and that you can create your own
like malicious requests out of scope for
kubernetes and then I run the pause
binary so it's like just to show you or
just to give you like a little demo
um
yeah so let's we have copied the
contract over we just restart
the Run container runtime
and now if we create a new port
um I call let's call this deployment law
um yeah
it's just a demo so I think it's fine
let's create a new deployment
oh wait before I actually create a
deployment
um let me head over to my command and
control server
um
because actually we can see those
requests
so also nginx is like logging those
um well log nginx
nah
so and let's do tail
Dash F on the axis lock oh no not till
tail please
so
we are now seeing the access log
and if I'm going to create a deployment
the deployment must be or in order to
get it worked the deployment must be
scheduled on the right node yeah so if
I'm not going to create a deployment
maybe we have luck no we don't
if we like to get parts
oh not a white only get pods
we see that the load container is
created
um but let's scale those deployment and
get some containers scheduled on our on
our node like scale
deploy
and let's do like 25 replicas
and we'll bet a bit and there's coming
the requests so what we are now seeing
is that the pause container actually
curls my server reaches out to it and if
we have a look at the normal kubernetes
environments
foreign
everything is running everything is up
everything works as expected
um you won't even notice it if you like
scanning it with your like commercial
container scanning tool because it's a
runtime
feature so it doesn't even or or not not
the kubernetes API itself like gives the
request to pull the image it's the
container runtime so it's out of scope
for the commercial scanner you deploy it
in your kubernetes cluster and I can run
like literally a malicious image that
isn't scanned in every port and outer
scales
uh it's a great thing I guess for me as
an attacker
so yeah the call requests
and let's see what the best things about
those are
yeah in every new instance or pod
created depends on if I could for
example set my config.tominal on like a
scaling template for kubernetes for a VM
scaling template every new created node
has my pulse container on it so I can
infect more and more and more nodes
every new instance or every new pod
created on the Node is yeah I can abuse
to do my malicious uh malicious code
execution it is out of scope for every
common kubernetes security tooling
included as I said your commercial or
paid tooling you're using the kubernetes
cluster behaves normal you won't see any
any difference you won't even like
notice that think things changes are
changing there and it persists over
reboot and over update in your whole
kubernetes cluster so it's a very evil
thing to identify it's very actually
very very horrible to do this
yeah and um what I can do from this for
example if we come back to like
attacking the torque infrastructure
itself if I should have done it or if if
I if I had done it before I actually
deployed my yeah my real talk
environment I would have an in container
in every pot and in every like let's say
also namespace yeah
um not the namespacing kubernetes but
the namespace that container D uses so
Linux namespaces I had the pods in every
Linux namespace where I can like reach
out to the official workload pod and do
stuff there so it's very great that you
can actually do stuff with this
yeah the next one is um over the years I
stumbled over several different security
uh kubernetes security related topics
and we always for example when I worked
at the customer and or somewhere else we
always had like some issues to do like
thread based analysis for kubernetes at
a larger scale for like really big
clusters with hundreds and thousands of
notes and stuff like this
[Music]
um
so over the time I like collected all of
those threats in kubernetes I've seen
and I kind of Built My Own my tree
attack metrics for it
um and this is also the stuff that is
going to be released with the talk
um together with an open source
kubernetes security blog hosted on
kubernetes security de and kubernetes
security i o those are both domains um
yeah we will be using to get you folks
informed about kubernetes security and
what's going on
so this is what it looks like
um it's a big metrics and I'm extremely
sure that there's
still stuff missing so if you actually
have some more attack vectors that you
would like to see or would like to share
with me I would like to put it in there
because
also from my perspective kubernetes is
such a big it's such a big ecosystem and
getting the overview about every
potential yeah let's say vulnerability
we have in there is
it's totally crazy so please reach out
to me if you like have other newer
different attack vectors or think that
there's something missing please reach
out to me I will definitely put it in
and it's it's the metric is also to be
submitted to to the micro team
um yeah because
um I think what we should do more is
like threat based kubernetes analysis
analysis to not only get the application
security layer right like securing your
web front end and stuff like this but
with kubernetes we also we're also
introducing platform security so if your
application is hacked then your platform
is going to be under attack but if your
kubernetes platform is attacked then
your application is going to be under
attack so we kind of have to rethink
what we are doing we need to like secure
both layers not only the application but
also please the platform itself
yeah that was hack my talk um the whole
talk is going to be open sourced you
will find so everything on GitHub in
this repo currently I didn't
um yeah like finished it in time to like
publish everything there so it's still
an empty repo but I will do upload
everything there once I've get the
materials together
and also if you want to like to like
re-watch the talk you can actually do it
the talk is running in kubernetes and
what's the whole time publicly available
you can have a look at it at yeah the
domain you're currently seeing there it
is exposed in the internet and you can
like look at it all the time for the
whole Troopers conference it will be up
so
that being said please stay safe not
only in your kubernetes and application
environments but also in terms of like
Corona thank you
[Applause]