[Music]
so I saw that I was like wow yeah that
would be awesome something that you can
get together on a team and you go after
hackers and so that was one of the
inspirations for some of the stuff for
me to go through this talk so I hope you
guys enjoy it it's a lot of stuff here
put all the time into it and stay for
the end a lot of good stuff in here and
I'll let you guys know at the end how to
get the slides if you want them so
anyway Who am I
started out in this journey my name is
Ralph calm I work for a company in
Columbia South Carolina named training
concepts basically I started out as a
server admin got went through and did
the mcse track and way back in server
2000 and Server 2003 and then since then
I've been a consultant and or a trainer
instructor for training concepts since
then so that's kind of what I do I focus
mostly on security I am a cool organizer
of wasps Columbia a group in town that
in Columbia that does application
security awareness and our more security
adverse key we have a meet-up coming up
in December if you guys are interested
so you go to all US Columbia find out
more should be good also a member of
Colo sec local security meetup group and
Columbia South Carolina so both of those
really fun to do
as well as my passion is kind of just
kind of spreading the word when it comes
to information security
kind of a kid of the 80s so everything
80s I am huge fan of stranger things and
the new season today just came out with
so that's have a little bit about me I
guess where we're gonna get started and
kind of go through this long journey to
get you guys into information security
or even if you're in information
security kind of tailor what you should
be doing maybe some of the things that
have enhanced my journey as far as an
information security and then we'll kind
of talk about the general state of
things as well as we go through
this project so to speak here so what is
computer security in today's world well
as Frank my other Corgan eyes were
Colossus had said this morning we're
kind of in a stuck in a mess and we've
been there for a little while but
ideally a lot of what's referenced in
information security originally kind of
just to protect our assets and that's
really what the goal should be but now
it's kind of been immortal sighs to buy
things like our media and or cool shows
like mr. robot and or you know
everything on from 60 minutes to you
know everything that's covered today so
a lot of cool things there that kind of
give it a lot of press coverage as well
as some of these sites are amazing it
kind of giving you an idea kind of a
foothold of where our current climate is
from a regards to information security
and so we we need to kind of raise up
cyber army so to speak and that's kind
of what prompted me to kind of bring to
light this particular talk today my
quote of course a lot of people use the
Sun South a lot in their presentations
Mike what's a little bit different who
controls the information wins the war
and that's really where at today and
information security and you see it with
a lot of the nation-state actors that
are out there China and all the Bears
and as well as Russia and North Korea so
ideally it's a scary climate to be on
but it's also an exciting time to be in
information security as well so I'd like
to kind of go over that a little bit now
you don't have to go far to see some of
the big issues that are out there from
everything from Equifax to ebay to
Target and everybody else and so here
ideally it's not a matter of when we've
probably heard this before but just is
it happening right now is it happening
tomorrow eventually everything will be
going down the road to everything
needing to be protected today and so
that's kind of what you see a lot in the
news and of course that's been
publicized pretty well this year were
things like not Pecha and want to cry
and all the various other types of mess
out there and
that's the complexity of things
internet-connected stuffed animals
and/or webcams that you know are nanny
cams and stuff like that that are being
hacked so we put a lot on the internet
and IOT and or network of things is
becoming more and more popular and so
that's kind of the next evolution and
security of trying to kind of protect
some of these devices when our fridges
start to get ransomware and our TVs it's
a pretty serious business right so those
are some of the things that are my
highlights at least from the last couple
years on where information security is
in its current climate as well as if you
look at what's the definition for
information security and so ideally I
said in the beginning for me information
security is about protecting assets and
those assets are digital assets those
assets are of physical and/or non
tangible assets and the concept of
things like intellectual property we're
losing a lot of that there's some great
books out there like glass houses that
you can read that kind of talk about how
our intellectual property is being
mishandled and so when we say protecting
assets that's any item of value and we
look at that that's what infra SEC is
really is trying to protect those assets
and preventing things like data theft
and/or identity theft
those types of things are really where
we're looking in the future even things
like securing big data is super
important to information security all
right so why emphasize right ultimately
why pick this as a role I get that
question a lot being a trainer Inc or
instructor at the place I work and see
lots of students come through and ask
well why should I focus on information
security well it's very popular today to
say that these are some of the reasons
one is the big biggest discussion point
for a lot of people is that well ideally
information security is a place that has
a very high demand however is very much
craftsman oriented which means basically
you can't know everything in information
security if you think you do then you're
probably in the wrong spot so ideally
the cool thing about it is like when
they come to me and say I want to
information security that's like saying
you want to be a doctor you have to
choose a specialty tour something that
you're interested in are you interested
in reverse engineering or you're
interested in pen testing are you
interested in security analysis or
whatever the case may be there's many
many different roles in information
security today and or as you probably
have seen through several different news
articles on the internet but very short
supplied to be a hacker you got to think
like one so oftentimes when I do classes
on ethical hacking or hacking or
whatever you want to call it a lot of it
becomes that what can we learn from an
attacker we can learn their
methodologies that we can learn their
tactics we can learn and get an
understanding of what they're after now
you could say that the defense is where
a lot of your money is made and that's
absolutely true but you'll find a lot of
red teamers out there as well so it's
both of those we want to think like a
hacker or an attacker we want to learn
from how they attack so that we can
better our systems and better our
networks so offense informs the defense
you oftentimes hear that as well we also
sometimes see a heavy placing on things
like compliance today gdpr is being
implemented right now and will be in
effect next year and there's a big it's
fine
stiff fine and penalty for organizations
that are doing business with European
nations that aren't up to par in
compliance and so that will be a big
initiative for companies next year
you'll see is making sure that they're
in GDP our GDP our C compliant privacy
compliant so maybe it's compliance and
wanting to just be compliant today so
those are among many other reasons to
want to be an information security today
although then it's a lot of fun if
you're a tinkerer or if you're a person
that likes to take stuff apart break it
build it that's definitely the place to
be if you're just inquisitive about
different things information security is
definitely for you all right so what's
the current threat landscape the threat
actors a lot of these we talk about in
some of the classes I teach we talk
about the gray hats we talk about the
black hats white hats state-sponsored
espionage we talk about you know you're
anonymous or you're hacktivists crowd so
looking at the current threat landscape
as far as what is out there there's a
lot of different types of attacks that
that we're going under and then usually
it kind of falls into three camps is it
that the cybercrime is an organized you
know state agency that has a lot of
backing it has a lot of resources that
they can put behind themselves to go
after an organization that's maybe
us-based to get more Intel about US
relations or US military intelligence or
is it somebody as a simple ass someone
wants to basically go after an
organization for some of the thoughts
and views and their political side of
the religious side of things so we've
got those as well as in our activist and
then of course we're starting to see an
increase in people that are trying to do
espionage and people that are trying to
do internal attacks as well so the
threat itself can be internal it can be
external and also can be somewhere under
these hats that are described commonly
with a threat actors today the threat
motives that we see in most cases what
would be the biggest threat motive what
do you guys think why do bad guys do
what they do money a lot of times it's
that right it could be some other things
it could be for fame and notoriety it
could be some kind of revenge plot right
I've seen several of those in the past
it could be blackmail ransomware has hit
a tipping point and will continue to go
further and further in advance things
like I was saying earlier into your
fridge into your TV and so that's a
non-stop market for a lot of organized
crime syndicates as well as maybe the
desire for power as another option here
we see a lot of that and smaller nations
maybe like North Korea that are trying
to get more one up upon the u.s. and so
a lot of motives behind attackers today
and why they do what they do
now as you talked or had a talk in the
beginning this morning Frank was talking
about the deeper inner ization of
security today so exactly what does that
mean well the current threat climate is
growing it's no longer that we can set
things up at the front in the fence and
make sure that everything is good at at
the edge so to speak so we've got cloud
we've got IOT
we've got mobilization and everybody
bring in their cell phones and their
tablets into the organization and that's
changing the actual landscape for
security
look at the clap right as a good example
as well so our ability to outsource to
the cloud now a lot of people and I'm
one of those too there's many many
benefits to using cloud services today
or managed services one of the biggest
things that sticks out in most people's
minds though is the loss of control of
that data and then how thinly that the
cloud provider themselves have to spread
themselves they're thin with handing out
other resources to other potential
service providers and things that they
can't provide themselves so maybe in
this case our ability to control a chain
of distribution is becoming harder and
harder today so a lot of that is where
the current threats are and you know all
threats are new like Jack was mentioning
in the earlier presentation
I mean dde a very popular a thing back
in the early 90s or maybe even mid 90s
now becoming something else that we have
to deal with right now
so DD and DD e injection attacks inside
of office is the new range and so we
start to see things that were all become
new again and so that's a that's kind of
interesting as well as the botnets that
are taking off of course with things
like Mirai botnets one of my favorite
botnets of course is the what was it
called the get the go spot botnet was
the one that basically went around and
basically started stealing um you know
balances off of your gift cards and
stuff like that so you start to see
those types of attacks becoming more and
more popular and more and more in the
media today now when you look at threats
and how they think and how they act
these are kind of some of the different
categories I just picked a couple of the
things I like to do when I'm going over
and trying to evaluate an organization
today so one of the big ones is
reconnaissance oftentimes
we skip this phase a bit much because of
the time constraints maybe possibly but
you should because there's a lot of
information that can be had today with
assent and the ability to evaluate an
organization and how you can Mack
relationships between employees within
an organization some of my favorite
tools will course talk about some of
that and
but where you see a lot of this being a
problem is in things like hard-coded
credentials hard-coded a key API keys or
things that are pushed out on the
internet that should have been sanitized
before they are out there on the
Internet and so in general that's
another large cost for concern today for
business
of course the malicious software will
never get any easier it's just going to
be something that continues to grow and
grow and grow and so with things that
are now starting to put together a
series of events that take place to hack
an organization chaining or malware or
chaining malicious code together there's
a very popular type of attack technique
that a lot of organizations are looking
at so malicious software and ransomware
will continue to grow will not get rid
of denial service I mean again it's
protocol manipulation so unless you're
gonna get rid of the protocols or build
new protocols that don't have some of
those same things that's gonna be a big
cars for concern and of course as it
goes to the mobile marketplace and our
cloud as we continue stretch ourself in
we'll continue to have that more and
more to be a concern and then of course
we can't get rid of users right so they
are also one of our big threat targets
so we look at threat modeling now I'm
not the person to be an expert in threat
modeling but it just makes sense to me
if you would want to understand better
your organization and what some of the
insecurities your organization are you
might want to come up with a way a bad
guy would attack those assets in that
environment that's kind of in essence
what threat modeling offers us so if you
implement threat modeling in an
organization today it'll give you faster
detection it'll make you more self-aware
of what's around you and in your
environment it will help to reduce the
overall effect that if an attacker does
compromise on organization what effect
that has on the overall organization
itself and there are lots of different
types of methodologies that you can
follow lockheed-martin course the one
that a lot of people throw out there for
threat modeling in the use of the kill
chain but then there's also the use of
things like threat intelligence feeds
with some people you know called snake
oil or something else there but you
should definitely look at and evaluate
threat intelligence and threat modeling
in your environment to make sure that
you're covering your basics
so risk management we can't also look
not look at this so ideally a lot of
times when we look at risk in the
organization it's all a measuring stick
so as Frank mentioned this morning we
talked about metrics and that's really
the prime principle behind what can we
do to lower the threat if you're gonna
lower the threat you've got to
understand your vulnerabilities in your
environment you've got to have be able
to map the threat to the vulnerabilities
in the environment you've got to
understand better your risk so and those
risks themselves they're not something
that we can put in a package put a
dollar number on it's more than that we
have to understand what's the ideal
threat so I could say you have a huge
vulnerability in your environment well
what's the likelihood and then of course
look at the impact as another part of
that and so when you're looking at risk
management in general it's not just
buying insurance it's not being able to
say all we'll just deal with that later
it has to be method methodology that
you're applying in your environment to
make sure you're dealing with risk in an
appropriate manner all right so then
what do you got so you've got several
frameworks to follow one of the things
that I'm a believer in is methodologies
now I don't say you can't run off of a
hundred percent one of these
methodologies that are out there but
there is some great resources out there
that you can go in and grab so you can
look at for example with with regards to
risk you can look at some of the NIST
800 series there's a lot of good stuff
in there some of it's out of date
obviously but you can look to apply some
type of methodology and make it work for
your business and that's definitely a
road to go we looked at the CIS controls
earlier I mean there's the NIST 853
which deals with security controls for
your environment so that's definitely
something to look at as well as there's
a lot of cool things in the NIST
standards that you can evaluate for for
your business and see if there's
anything that they can stick now as we
move the corner here kind of look at
some of the stuff that I personally like
a lot of times it comes to the
discussion of is it that I want to be a
red teamer or do I want to be a blue
Timur or somewhere in the middle maybe
purple team or something like that for
me you know it started out as a red
teamer I want it to be nothing but being
able to break
and bang on stuff but now as I get a
little older and I start wanting to
understand things more I'm in the middle
right so I like to be able to understand
both the red side and the blue side you
don't have to pick a side most cases
unless that's your design job and even
if it is your design job you can still
learn from both sides of the puzzle and
so I think it's an extremely important
and extremely important thing to not
have these things that Diana was talking
about this morning and the use of things
like silos or maybe it was Frank I can't
remember that's an extremely important
and valuable solution for us in
information security today I start
breaking down some of those silos so
what does ethical hacking or hacking a
lot of people put that term out there a
lot of times that the term hacking
itself gets a very or people think of it
as a very a very derogatory term it
doesn't have to be an ethical doesn't
have to be the word you use with it and
in general hacking is being able to take
something apart to the point that you
understand what what is doing and
understand more product of what you can
do to to manipulate it and modify it and
so if you haven't and if you're starting
in information security you know I tell
a lot of people start from a background
of understanding some of these protocols
so look at RFC 793 look at RFC 791 look
at some of these protocols that define
tcp and UDP and ICMP because that's
really when you look at hacking that's
what we're doing we're taking those
protocols that are already in green and
very well used today and we're
manipulating them so that's really what
hacking is it's the ability to kind of
take something that's already in
existence and modify it right now when
you look at the types of attacks that
are out there today I just pick some of
the very fine few that are out there
denial of service distributed in our
service and so again it could be
protocol manipulation maybe we're
looking at the app server and doing some
type of slow loris variant type of
service or whatever or maybe we're doing
some type of brute force where we're
doing like user side denial services
we've got lots of different types of
denial of service attacks that are out
there a lot of attacks today are in
regards to being able to implement
social engineering will do spoofing or
masquerading as an attack another
of attack very popular today's
man-in-the-middle so in order to do a
man-in-the-middle attack the first step
of it is ARP spoofing so we go through
the process here of manipulation and
each from one of these and then we've
got great tools like from Black Hills
Information Security the male sniper
right being able to do you know password
guessing basically is what it's doing so
you can feed it a password list and a
bunch of users or a password and a bunch
of users and you can go through and you
know access outlook or exchange whatever
it is so lots of cool attacks and that's
one cool thing you'll see in information
security you never get tired of
researching or looking at the various
different attacks that are out there so
we look at the attacks we learn about
the attacks we learn about how the
attacks are being implemented and then
we start looking for controls what kind
of controls can we put in that resource
environment to mitigate some of these
types of techniques alright so I picked
another particular type of attack that's
very useful today social engineering
social engineering works 100% of the
time most of the time so ideally this
particular attack is just a human
manipulation so you're going in to a
targeted environment you're looking at
some of their social media maybe
LinkedIn because we don't put anything
fake on LinkedIn and then you're trying
to manipulate that person into doing
something that they're not understanding
how sensitive that is and it might be
disclosing password to just giving off a
handful of attributes about the company
that helped that social engineer to be
able to access that company a lot easier
today some of the tactics we like to use
at least that I've done in the past very
popular to use some of these so you'll
go in and you'll send an email and it'll
have something like well here I'll show
you some of the fishing stuff I was
gonna show you in a second it'll have
something like this where it'll say in
order to access this particular document
you've got to enable content right or
you know oh I sure need to read this
document this presentation or whatever
it is because it was sent to me by this
person that I trust within the
organization or at least they it looks
like someone I trust so I click a link
and then by clicking that link against
me access to that particular user in
that environment and that's all an
attacker is looking for is a pivot point
so you get the first be Chet into the
environment and then from
be chat you start the pivot and pivot
all throughout the organization using a
variety of different types of tools and
so you know maybe simple as something
you know sending a phishing email right
could be a good example social
engineering today of course as we talked
about ransomware is on the rise it
becomes more and more of a huge problem
for a lot of organizations today and
there's really not a lot to to get to
the point of fixing it now Windows 10
does have protected containers which is
a new feature that they enabled in the
creator's update that they just released
here so that's something in the right
direction and some of the other options
that they're doing even though they're
terrible privacy are in the right
direction with micro virtualization and
some microkernel rose realization that
they're doing in Windows but we're also
still getting the simple self right like
I said just getting something you click
on it and then BOOM compromise that for
organization through that click link
yeah so attacking ICS is another big
problem for us today so as we start to
look at things like black energy I'll
let you guys read that for a second so
black energy from the Ukraine and some
of the issues that they've been having
here recently it they're kind of all
fathered around the Stuxnet worm and
it's getting worse and worse and so
we're at the point now of critical
infrastructure and or I do ot that we're
starting to see it more and more attacks
using that particular platform of choice
so until we understand better how to
protect around these systems and add
controls around these systems sort of
things like patching that's going to
continue to be a big problem for us and
so and zero days are there too so you
look at Stuxnet as a classic example of
using multiple zero days to compromise
organizations so what are some of the
other issues that a lot of organizations
have so big ones policy weakness so
you'll go into an organization I'll just
give you an example here if I'm on an
engagement I'll go in there and I'll ask
them oh you want us to look at and
review your policies for any things that
are you know standout that are things
that you should be looking at and
implementing that you're not so it all
starts here right person is not
implementing a acceptable use policy
with email and then they wonder why
their employees are signing up for
Dick's Sporting Goods
with their company no and they're
wondering why they have a massive
problem with spam and other things and
so the issue here that I see a lot today
is there's no policy around something
nothing that governs resource access
nothing that enforces what are the
consequences if you violate policies
today and so you'll even see you know
the change management and some of the
turnover be a part of this as well so or
people leave organizations and they
still have access to email
six months later down the line and so
that's a big disconnect for a lot of
organizations today is making sure that
they apply a policy that is enforceable
and understandable throughout the
organization access controls are being a
problem too so will implement some fancy
system but until it's after its
provisioning phase whatever you wanna
call it it's disabled even though we've
spent a lot of money and of course one
day the service technician will come in
and he'll turn it on and we'll get
trained on it and then that's another
year later that after we've had this
device that was supposed to be helping
us in the first place with security so
those types of things are real-world
scenarios that are out there for sure
enough and then things like not properly
planned segmentation so one thing
that'll happen a lot it's a really cool
attack Kerberos ting so you'll have an
organization that creates a service
account and it's managing sequel
managing SharePoint or whatever it is
and they're using one standard password
that's got the main access in the
environment and then you go off in
Kerberos that environment and the
problem here is now you have no
segmentation years and crappy passwords
and so it's easy to crack those
passwords and now I've got access as a
system or access as a service account
that has higher privilege in the
organization so there needs to be more
policies I know that's some problem
nobody wants to hear that are not only
concise not only understandable but also
enforceable in organizations today and
then also other stuff too so you can see
here a non-existent incident response
plan or nonexistence disaster recovery
plan what's the number one way you're
probably think in your head to fight
this thing called ransomware well maybe
have a good backup or have a strategy
for disaster if something happens I'm
just thinking out of the box you know so
we still have human error and there's no
way to get around this
it's a huge step right for an
organization to change the behavior of
the employees for the organization
becomes a huge hurdle for any
organization that has to look at this so
we have to get management on board like
they were talking about here earlier
upper level management and having
incentives as another big process to
this and maybe it's not that we have
security awareness training once a year
maybe it's an ongoing effort that
continually tries to make adjustments
and tries to make incentives and changes
to the organizational employees to to
move the needle a little bit in that
direction and we have to have metrics we
have to have ways to measure the
effectiveness of it so what do you do
well you assess right so you've gone
through all this security awareness
training how do you know what's working
you assess right some of those to see if
that actually is working are you
changing the attitudes are you changing
behavior of the employees and then the
configuration weaknesses this one's
aggravating a little bit so obviously I
understand every service that we use
pass configuration every technology that
we use has a some kind of said default I
understand it but the problem here
becomes more and more you see that those
defaults are getting us into trouble so
here we might not have applied a patch
that turned off something that we should
have turned on or turned off scuse me Oh
or maybe it's a something that is being
turned off that actually helps us right
and as a layer of separation between
maybe standardly run processes and
elevated run processes and so those
types of things are huge and what you
see is a lot of this right so we move
things to the cloud and you know there's
tools out there on the cloud but we move
the same crap from on-prem to off prem
and in this case we'll call it today we
just expected it'll be more secure
because hopefully that vendor has their
stuff you know up to date and their
stuff in this case lockdown which is not
always the case so you're still seeing
lots of verbose error messages lots of
defaults lots of issues within
organizations today and it all boils
down to defense-in-depth now I
understand as we said the perimeter is
changing but that doesn't mean you still
can't have this methodology of
defense-in-depth so take those see is on
top critical xx controls that we can
apply in an order is a
start with number one right number ones
pretty simple right maybe not I don't
know
no what you got right you can't protect
what you don't know you got right so
you've got to go through and evaluate
what's out there in your environment and
then focus on authentication are we
doing multi-factor authentication or are
we doing things or everything that we
can to evaluate the privilege for
resources and users in the environment
so is there a standard you know group on
it right or user behavior monitoring in
the environment these are all great
things that you can apply takes a lot of
work but these are the things that we
have to do to get better as an industry
and of course I like this part this is
my fart so penetration testing one of
the things about pen testing that's kind
of unique and kind of interesting all
the same is it never gets old there's
always new ways to manipulate different
types of protocols right or always neat
tools that you can learn about or build
yourself your own tools and so why do a
pen test well one it prevents or it kind
of reduces hopefully the chances of a
breach having a very very large impact
in organization so it does help a little
bit there but think about it like this a
pen test if you're given a week if
you're given two weeks it's a very small
format so you're only gonna get a little
taste of what the resource really is in
that environment and so it's not a
replacement full full system security
and your environment should be the last
series of controls you have sometimes
you'll do it to meet compliance so
that's also another very big reason that
a lot of organizations get pen tests at
least on a yearly basis it should be a
part of your standard software
development life cycle so as a part of
that you should be looking at the
threats that that adds as you add new
features into your software systems and
again the cool thing about this is it is
not an exact science so you can feel
free to reach out and go outside of the
box so to speak and so when we look at
methodologies and information security
we should think of it like a framework
right or skeleton we add all these cool
parts on that make it much much better
and so when you look at hacking yeah its
recon yet scanning gets exploitation
post exploitation
and then writing the report but it's
much more than that that really is just
this the skeleton of what kind of comes
all around it and so you know when I
look at pentesting today and and and
hacker methodology these are some of the
types of tools I like so might be hard
to see from that list but of course
recon ng probably one of my favorite and
as well as spider foot at recon tools
now you can use a ton more right shodhan
is a great place to go Josh mentioned
the o cent framework earlier that's
another really great place to go Mike
Roselle's web site and some of the tools
he has to offer a great place to go to
learn about OSINT all right and being
able to do effective recon in addition
to that after you get through your recon
you find email addresses you find phone
numbers you find all that good stuff
that can be used to to link and
attribute relationships of employees
within the organization they get
scanning so scanning is kind of fun you
can use various tools for scanning you
can use in map you can use unicorn scan
you can use HP you can use any kind of
packet crafter you want you can use
scape e so these various tools help you
to poke and prod and and as well as some
enumeration of your service domains so
understanding better what version of
this or that they're using within the
environment and then it comes to
exploitation so the cool thing is go to
exploit VB look around right after
you've discovered what's there you might
find an exploit on exploit dB that you
can craft to be your exploit that you
use to go after an organization now you
can use a ton of other tools as well you
can use Cobalts try it you can use a
Metasploit you can use a variety of
different other tools for exploitation
the idea there is we want to take
advantage of the vulnerability we want
to plant a payload in the resource
environment and then we want to utilize
that as we go through and pivot and
pillage so just a taste of that these
are some great sites I did a talk last
year here of hiding from the internet
was a real good experience if you ever
get a chance go to Justin Carroll's a
web site he has a 30 day security
checkup
it's a kind of a challenge that he has
there that kind of walks through how can
you be less internet visible and so it's
kind of neat to do stuff like that and
there are lots of good resources out
there but you know going through this
list here Spokeo or pipl
or you know some other ones that are
listed here what am I gonna find well
I'm gonna find out a lot of information
about employees within the organization
what's their job role I'm gonna find out
the things like their email address I'm
gonna find out relatives and what
happens a lot of times is you connect
the dots with a lot of this information
you can use something like DNS map for
finding some other information through
reconnaissance there's lots of domain
crawlers out there like DNS dumpster
that are really good at mapping out an
organization and some of the things like
subdomains
in trying to link some of those and then
going through simple stuff so some of
this is what I like to do is Google
hacking right it's amazing go to the
google hacking database literally twice
a week at least and kind of look at some
of the different new ones that are
listed and published out there so this
one right here basically goes through
and looks for SharePoint sites within
organizations now I don't know about you
guys but I hate SharePoint it's a great
target I'll say that much but a lot of
organizations put a lot of money and
time and effort into using SharePoint
today there's a lot of open stuff out
there by using SharePoint target that
one a lot LinkedIn try to search for
employees within organizations a lot of
the stuff that you put on LinkedIn is
real stuff so that's why I like LinkedIn
so much because you're not gonna fake
stuff there as much and then you could
always build your own self a social
profile that's less connected to you you
can use things like the pseudo app it'll
give you a phone number that's
anonymized it'll give you an email
address that you can use and some of
those things you could use something as
well there's lots of options there
privacy comm might be a good place to go
and then Oh sent some of the information
there I get a lot of times is going to
sites like Intel techniques comm and
looking at some of the links they have
alright so here is the grand finale
we've finally reached the climax so to
speak so how do I get into emphasis
right ultimately all the other stuff was
just talking about all the cool things
you get to do in emphasize right so what
makes InfoSec so cool like I said you
don't think of it as a job right so any
type of job you have
all right gosh I really have to go to
work today right or you think of it as a
job gosh I got off work then that's
really not something you want to be an
InfoSec will burn you out in those cases
so you want to be definitely passionate
you want to be excited about the career
one of the cool things about emphasized
like I said is it never gets old there's
always something new around the corner
that you can poke at and product new
tools new techniques all these fun
things information security someone said
this in their talk a couple at Derby con
they share that that was extremely
useful information security is thought
of as a journey not a destination
so you'll ultimately like I said you'll
do say I want to be in InfoSec but
that's like saying I want to be a doctor
you can't be that all in one person you
have to kind of focus on something
you're interested in really and dig deep
one of the most important things you can
see and like I already mentioned you can
go to those RFC 791 793 some of those
ones that are the core networking
protocols that are out there today dig
into those because what you're going to
do as an attacker you're going to start
manipulating some of those different
protocols they're out there I don't have
any usually show up I usually drink a
lot of rock star not a lot but once a
day at least
so you got to have a lot of caffeine so
that's one of the cool things in
information security that keeps you
going
kind of a lifeblood of information
security today you also have to be
technically adept and so one of the cool
things you know I wasn't really always a
windows person I started kind of doing
Windows server and server administration
and I kind of moved into the security
side so anybody that is interested in
security it's hard to say that you can
kind of just start out and maybe you can
just going into information security
understanding protocols understanding
how the network works troubleshooting
system administration those types of
things really build on top of each other
when you get into information security
today but you have to love the tinkerer
that's one of the important things about
information security today so these are
some of the skills what questions I
would ask right I would say what moves
you right what are you passionate about
what Wow's you those are the things that
you know you get explore as an
information security professional you
read a lot right I'm always constantly
looking at new blogs or I'm constantly
looking for on Amazon books to find new
books that I'm interested in and I want
to learn about everything as much as I
can get my hands on so you'll read a lot
watch a lot so iron geek makes a lot of
his videos available from all these
conferences his web site will be your
best friend as well as YouTube right
there's a lot of good be
sides on YouTube there's a lot of good
conferences on YouTube you know even if
you're a Microsoft person you try to get
in Microsoft a lot of their ignite stuff
they put on YouTube so there's lots of
stuff there that you can watch and then
participate so practice a lot come to
these events go to see TFS try to find a
local meetup you know those types of
things and then once you get to that
point you start teaching a lot and
trying to be kind of presenting this
information out there for everybody to
consume trying to become a mentor those
are also very key things to you know
pushing this emphasize information
security for love to solve puzzles write
persistent passionate those are all
keywords that a lot of people in
influence X say you need has to be
successful in information security
podcast right so on the podcast junkie
right I'll be honest with you guys
there's lots of good ones out there this
there's some in my notes I didn't even
miss and I mentioned you guys a chris
sanders source code podcast course I
already mentioned iron geeks YouTube
channel the complete privacy and
security podcast from Ike Brasil is
another really good one if you're a more
privacy prone or you want to learn more
about Osen so maybe you've got that you
know long commute in the morning or in
the afternoon you could use something
like that as a place to kind of learn
something or you know catch up with
things or if you're cutting the grass or
whatever the case may cleaning the house
those are types of things that you can
use these podcasts for to fill the gap
right so I think podcasting really helps
a lot especially you know I like to get
reading and/or listening and or
participating do your research right I
already mentioned the RFC's right you
can go to a whole bunch of other sites
out there on the internet and find out
information about particular
vulnerabilities here recently I was just
doing some research on eternal blue and
internal romance and some of the
vulnerabilities that came out this year
so learning more about how those
particular vulnerabilities are grossed
and building your own exploits right
after that point and so it I would I
would definitely say that in information
security you'll find yourself research
and a lot of things so using some of
that you know maybe using some of these
like the Verizon data reach port as a
good litmus test to find out you know
what is the current market of where's
everybody being at
from so some of that is definitely a
part of it being able to look at blocks
like literally at least once or twice a
week I'm opening up like I don't know 50
or more tabs and Firefox or Chrome and
just reading through all the various
different types of security articles and
blogs are out there there are a ton of
really good ones out there information
secured in physics and lers a daily blog
so you can go to that one that's another
one I've been I didn't put in a list but
it's in my notes a lot of the subreddits
I love those man they got good hacking
ones they've got good anti forensics
ones computer forensics ones there's
lots of good subreddits out there but
find some some easy to digest type of
tool that you can go through these
different blogs and learn information
through different security books I
already mentioned security books there's
so many of these I'd say buy a Kindle
because I used to have a look case fool
but it just got too full so what's the
next step right just kind of getting it
in more of a digital format so you
paperwhite is the one I'd like to use
but you can find another one Palo Alto
Networks has their cyber Canon
definitely go check that out it
basically is a list of cool books to
read and they even kind of do a little
award ceremony of some of the different
books that are out there so find some
good books there are tons of ones out
there or write your own book it's easy
to sell published today training so you
can go to training at conferences you
can come to a local group Meetup
training at Cole ASEC um I did a class
on wire just Wireshark so one day class
on Wireshark or whatever it is so go to
the meetups find out if there's anything
offered there maybe go to pay training
so there is some of that I know at the
place I work at we do lunch and learns
now they're not recorded online or
anything like that but that'd be
something that you could use as another
option and this this week actually I'm
doing one on building an information
Siddhant response program so those types
of things go to those free learning
events find free learning online so
there's lots of options there go to
check out webinars
I know blackulas Information Security
does some find a meetups look at the
certifications now I don't see
certifications everything even though I
do teach certifications on some of the
guys but it's a great opportunity to
disclose lots of information and be able
to kind of get a little on how well you
think you're doing as far as some of the
information that's out there
lots of options online as well cyber EIT
another really good resource there for
online free training of course you could
go the route of certifications like I
said in the beginning I I don't really
use certifications as a crutch I like to
use certifications now as a way to
understand how to better help my
students that go through some of my sort
of my certification classes so that's
really the only use of certifications to
me today
but it demonstrates a working knowledge
of your information that you have that's
probably the most important part of it
you know it could be a career
differentiate err for you and that's a
reason that a lot of people go to
certification classes they're gonna try
to get a job somewhere certifications
are a must for some of that stuff
established best practice is etc
etcetera go to conferences well if you
can't go to a conference I mean we have
besides Charleston we have besides now
it'd be Greenville coming out in
December we have besides Augusta
besides Charlotte besides Asheville so
there's lots of East Side's around but
then there's also conferences that are
held that are larger conference as well
so go to some of those different
conferences that are out there
Carolina con and Raleigh is a really
good conference so those types of
conferences try to get out and meet new
people and networking and stuff like
that another big part of it I'm not
gonna sugarcoat it for you guys you got
to build a lab so every student that
comes to my class I ask them what their
lab looks like it's great as an
interview question if you're
interviewing someone you should ask them
plainly what is your home lab look like
right because you're trying to
understand how passionate are they about
learning things and applying new things
in their information security career so
I definitely think it's huge there's
lots of good resources there you can
participate even if you can't afford
right now a lab you can participate on
online CTF some you know some of the
government's ring 0 I find myself every
Saturday night going kind of looking at
ring 0 and working on some of the
challenges there so there's some really
good resources out there go to a meet-up
CTF we did one at Cole the second those
types of things you learn a lot of
things through those resources it's easy
to get images a lot of people don't know
I don't know why but Microsoft
developers have a site called modern ie
you can download Windows 7 Windows 8 and
I think Windows 10 and basically they're
viens so if you're trying to get
windows VM download it and you can pick
VirtualBox or VMware VirtualBox is free
and you can have that for a certain
period of time now you can use it for
testing and then of course you know move
on from there but there's also lots of
great Linux distros out there so one of
my favorite sites is von Hub right I go
there at least once a week and kind of
see what some of the new vulnerability
app images are out there that I can
download and paint on and bang on excuse
me so that's a really good one
of course oh wasps has a lot of broken
web app projects we just did here a
class on recon search-and-destroy for OS
columbia and august and we were using
one of the OWASP a vulnerable web app so
lots of good resources out there and of
course even with the use of things like
you know Kali mint Linux it makes it a
lot easier there are other solutions out
there for hacking distros though I you
know try try black Arch Linux is another
options got even more tools than Kali
Linux does or parrot pen test or some of
those other solutions out there and
again Callie's kind of the gold standard
so to speak but there are other options
out there you play well with and then
lastly here kind of learn to code so
notice I didn't put this first you know
I'm kind of biased towards things like a
PowerShell and Python and I didn't want
to feel like you know putting this up
front especially if you're getting new
into information security you got to
learn right away coding I definitely
think it's a part of your path on being
a better information security
professional but it's not the first
thing you have to do is learn how to
code so the two primary languages
probably want to focus on or Python and
PowerShell every PowerShell class I
teach I tell everybody go to the
PowerShell survive a guy just google it
it's a bunch of good resources that are
put up there from Microsoft that provide
you videos and and tutorials and a lot
of things if you're trying to learn
PowerShell and get in going with
PowerShell and of course learn Python
the hard way or some other different
resources out there to learning Python
and helping you on that Python journey
as well alright that's it guys uh
appreciate your time any questions I
think I did pretty good at their
questions please
I will tweet them out I guess I don't
know how they do slide management here
but um I'll probably tweet it out um or
here there you go
how about that one you can email me
right there and if you want it I will
send it to you guys thank you for your
time I appreciate it guys if there's
some more questions or you want to stick
around chit chat please feel free I
teach in Columbia South Carolina and
place called training concepts we do a
wide variety of different types of a
train not fly school yeah yeah I mean
I'm up for anything I there's nothing I
mean I can't do it through training
concepts but I'll do anything outside
sure alright thanks guys