thank you very much appreciate everybody
coming for you know what in hindsight is
probably the least exciting topic title
ever so we'll try to make that up with
some material why I want to be here
today is you know I've been doing
security for quite a while and I have
the fortune of going to a lot of
conferences and seeing a lot of really
great talks and for me the greatest
talks are not the ones where they always
just drop the tool and they do the demo
I like learning the story about how how
someone got there you know because I
think there's often the tendency to
think wow that person's just naturally
genius and you know there are natural
geniuses and there are people like me
who just Google for everything
constantly and try to make something
work so I think I hope that there's a
value in there in in the storytelling
you know and I want to share a couple
key points about you know what I
consider you know to be good usability
good security we're gonna talk a lot
about you know some tools
there's tons of live demos so you know
that always goes very well never has a
problem so I think we'll it would be the
same here and you'll see QR codes up if
you want to scan the QR codes it's fine
they're not connected to anything there
are demo codes you could play around
with the quest defender soft token or
you could play around with Google
Authenticator if if you like so how is
it that I come to be here today
principally because of a piece of
software that is just absolutely I would
say unusable especially for non security
people it's called the Dale formally del
now quest one Identity defender product
it's a one-time password system you know
that has obviously a GUI a way to
present you know one-time password for
multi-factor authentication and it has a
you know a series of back-end hooks so
you can easily add OTP a multi-factor
off to let's say VPN or let's say system
login and it has you know some nice
Enterprise II type features they support
a whole bunch of tokens so they support
their own bizarro token
has a grid on and you have to select
stuff they support SMS token messages
they support Yubikey and you know what
it looks to be vasco rebranded tokens i
mean so they have a whole range of token
support and they also support software
based tokens right these are tokens that
work on android that work on iOS they
work in Windows Java even blackberry and
Windows Mobile so and that is really
this the scope of the talk today that I
want to share with you not really
interested in the background
infrastructure today not really
interested in hardware tokens or custom
tokens I'm only focusing on software
based token the principle reason why I'm
focusing on the software based token is
because this has caused me the most pain
right so if you can imagine you're an
organization and you release you know
you get a new employee you give them a
laptop and maybe you pay for their phone
and you say that's great
go ahead and VPN into the network we're
just gonna need you to sign up for
multi-factor authentication and you
might have worked somewhere where they
did that well and that seemed okay to
you until you receive this email that
said download the app and enter
approximately a hundred and ten
characters on your phone with no error
correction or indication that you have
it right until you press the activate
button and then it either tells you your
token code is invalid or not it's if you
remember playing mastermind where you
had like six digits and you had to
figure out which is the digit well now
you have a hundred and ten so horrible
horrible horrible and I said I'm a new
here but I think I can help you right so
we went to make you our codes because
the Android version of del quest
defender soft token actually supports
the ability to scan QR codes so that's
great so let's scan the QR code if we
select scan QR code
unfortunately the token app does not
actually build the barcode scanner into
it they tell you go to the Google Play
Store and download barcode scanner and
install that yourself
great usability and then when you do so
you realize that in order to activate
multi-factor authentication you are now
giving a fourth party access to all of
your contacts all of your Wi-Fi
connection information because that's a
critical component of you know barcodes
apparently so that doesn't seem right
here you know and so that on its surface
would warrant further inspection further
modification so if we switch to iOS
unfortunately the story is even worse
because in iOS you're presented with the
same crippling usability you know you've
got enter in these characters you've got
to hit done and they don't tell you that
you have an option to scan right so you
know the world's flagship phone
ecosystem you know with a 12 megapixel
camera is not able to help you import
your multi-factor authentication token
you must use a third-party QR reader
that you find by yourself if you have to
create a QR code you have to then scan
it you have to extract the activation
code by using copy and paste which is
universally so easy on mobility devices
and then paste it into the software
token you know which strikes me circa
2001 right it's just not acceptable
nowadays too we can't treat people this
way from a security perspective it's
it's not right and you know it it gives
security I think a bad name when you're
just trying to protect accountants and
people in marketing and people in sales
and you're making them go through these
hoops I mean if the hoops are bad enough
that people who are in the information
security field who understand the value
of multi-factor authentication who know
what a one-time password is know the
value that it protects and then still
choose to like hate the system like this
that's a bad sign so what I wanted to
look at is hey there already exists a
very usable one-time password token
keeper it's called Google Authenticator
let's look at the token that is
generated by the software token app and
let's figure out if there is there an
opportunity here is there a
compatibility between the data the
essence of these third part of these
proprietary software tokens and being
used in Google Authenticator so I'm
gonna say we're going to perform you
know what I call you know a little bit
of deductive reasoning in airplane mode
which means if I turn on airplane mode
and the phones have no network
connectivity whatsoever I'm still able
to import the token and I'm still able
to generate valid one-time passwords
valid six digit tokens so that tells me
that these strings of all lowercase
characters through a through Z they must
contain the token serial number because
you can see the serial number in both
instances right and that's not made up
somewhere else and it must contain the
data to generate the one-time password
we would generally have to stop there
but they were also nice enough to tell
you that the token type is o'the
compliant sha-1 when I say something
like and of course we know or I say
something that sounds obvious what I'm
omitting in parentheses is I googled for
this okay so of course both complied
sha-1 tokens are an RFC for two to six
standard related to kind of h mac
one-time passwords right which is the
easy thing to google for so i've got a
lot of hope you know when i'm starting
this adventure i know that whatever the
activation code is has enough
information to generate a one-time
password and I believe that the one-time
password is going to be compatible and
compliant with an industry standard
which Google Authenticator also agrees
to adhere by so I think I have a
syllogism here right I equals B B equals
C equals C so I think I'm good and my
goal for the rest of this talk is to
turn that phrase of text characters into
a QR code so that it can be loaded in
Google Authenticator and I can throw
away the old code
so and now we're going to do that I'm
gonna want to reverse engineer the
application well it's an Android
application so what you're looking at is
a screen shot of a console accessing a
rooted android device right that is like
a big google search there how do i root
my device how do I get access to log
data
where does system store information I
mean each one of these is as valuable
google searching so I run this command
adb logcat it dumps the log and i grep
for the word token because if i'm really
really lucky they really really
instrumented a lot of logging and that
would be ideal right from a researcher
perspective if they said hey this is
your activation code this is what we
think it is in blah blah blah so
unfortunately they don't do any of that
so that's not a value to me so my next
step is to look at an android decompiler
so if i'm on if i copy the APK file
right which is the what is it is the
java archive data file so it's a jar
file it came from the end device and I
know that and remember I know that means
what I googled that apk files and jar
files are zip file so I'm going to unzip
it and now I've got a Dex file okay what
is a Dex file well a Dex file is dalvik
Dex file right ok very good very good so
now I say I do some more googling I'm
saying I'm going to dump this
so I'm going to convert this because if
I try to edit this file it's binary it's
it's not really usable for me so I'm
going to look at that I'm gonna I'll
call it output that jar then I'm gonna
unzip output that jar and great it gave
me you know a bunch of text files that
should be the decompiled codes that's
you know this is a very exciting day and
I'm thrilled to be doing this and let's
just look at dump text but unfortunately
and I you know didn't go to a programmer
school by trade this is not the
easiest piece of code to digest right a
lot of labels that are just you know
random letters and numbers for variable
definition you know it's not really goto
statements I don't see my common you
know I don't see a lot of parentheses
this is not code that I not a smart but
very lazy man I'm interested in working
with so I'm like I'm out okay so then
the next thing I do is I say well hey
you know I could use Ollie debug because
dal quest they make available the
Windows version of the java token that's
fantastic a ladybug I hear is this great
disassembler let you look at all the
code that proves even a worse idea for
the lazy and unmarked okay so we looked
at it I looked at it
there was threads involved there was not
common naming constructions and I was
like yeah I'm not gonna do that so I
just move on right that's a that's a
process for me is to try something when
it's too hard move on to something else
and when that's too hard go back to the
first thing and say hey can now can I
make this thing work and so they also
make a generic Java app so I say okay
there's a generic Java app and that is a
jar file which we know is zipa below we
unzip it and it puts it in the same kind
of space so I'm gonna go to crest token
DT alright and these are class files and
I know that if I look at class files my
eyes go cross-eyed because they're not
readable so I remember a long time ago I
used this thing called java decompiler
so I'm gonna run it I'm gonna run it on
the same file so we can kind of compare
apples to apples and it makes this dot
Java all right well okay hey this is
pretty usable right so I've got function
names that I can understand right so
debug probably makes something go out
you know hex dump that probably
dumps hex code so I'm like oh I'm gonna
fixate though I'm gonna fixate on this
code for the rest of the of the exercise
okay
so I so now I'm here what I want to do
is figure out where in the code is the
activation code being processed right
I could read all of the code find the
main right where is the code initialized
see that it's probably multi-threaded
because it's gui-based and look for the
handler that has the activate button and
look for the callback that initiates you
know the processing of your text but
that looks kind of complicated so I you
know googled and found a better way and
that better way is to use a program
called Java snoop Java snoop is a
wonderful wonderful tool and it's a Java
based tool that essentially hooks in to
the Java Virtual Machine and is able to
interact with other Java processes
within the JVM all right so I'm gonna
start a new process I find the jar file
that is you know the Java executable and
I start the process up process waits for
a second to instantiate and then loads
the GUI that mill lets me manage it and
say ok so I have this screen here that
is the screen that manages Java snoop
and I have the application under test
here the defender soft token so let's
just try it and see what happens just to
make sure it's working
so I enter the token and I click
activate ok activation code is invalid
for this platform oh by the way quest
defender decided to restrict the
activation codes to only certain
platforms but I I can worry about that
later so I'm okay what I want to do
remember is find out where in the code
my activation code is being processed
cuz that's the code I want to I want to
modify so they make a great thing called
canary mode canary mode is a system that
you input what you're looking for I'm
for the letter e occurring four times
and everywhere that that string a string
that contains four letter e's is
processed the Java snoop is going to
dump what function that is okay so see
how that works go demo and eee and if
you could see that there these are the
functions you know first the system
calls activate token then it calls check
token then it calls DT check platform
that's probably checking for word the
platform right so Java versus Android
versus iOS D serialized blob and from
printable strength so my guess is that
the code that actually decodes that
activation code is probably this from
printable string all right reasonable
guess turned out to be right which is
probably why I'm now claiming it was
reasonable and and I didn't have to like
I didn't have to read and follow the
code right I used a tool to tell me
where to look so that was very enjoyable
so we do that so now we're back and we
are and this is where we came to right
so we know that from printable string to
serialize blob DT check platform check
token etc etc now we're going to work
our way up back up the stack so to speak
so to do that I'm going to use another
tool that I searched for because I
wanted to write I wanted to convert so I
went in to to the code from my jad file
and I copied out the section of code and
I'm trying my best to understand how
does it work how does it take these
lower case alphabetical not alphabetical
but alphabet characters and turn it into
something that that means something to
the the token I wanted to write a
utility that would convert these for
everybody to use and I wanted to write
it in JavaScript
mostly because JavaScript and HTML could
make a reasonable GUI without much
effort on my part and it could be
self-contained right I don't want a
release code that like uses a web
service to receive your activation code
and give you the QR code right that
might be a poor security architecture
decision so I'm going to use a piece of
software called plunker if I'm
pronouncing it right I hope so
and what plunker is is it's kind of like
a little mini rapid prototyping engine
alright so for making code that executes
in in JavaScript right so it has an
index file it's going to execute the
code in this script and this script I've
copied all of the code from the jad file
and I've added a little you know hello
just to make sure that this works and
I'll just click run and of course I
learn that these things are not
generally compatible right if I if I
remove the comments from my java code
this will not compile all right but
what's great is for someone who maybe is
not a programmer it's highlighting all
the errors for me right and so I'm
saying well ok you're defining a private
static string I'm gonna Google for how
do you define strings and I'm gonna
learn the JavaScript just use of the
word var and I'm generally correct
because the GUI made that red x go away
right this is natural compliance
engineering you get rid of the red X
right so I'm private int ok it's
actually a function so I learned that
that is the word function still has
problems because I learned that
JavaScript doesn't cast very very czar
doesn't apply casts to values so you
have to get rid of things like string
because it's going to figure out the
type itself and that goes away so I go
through the code and then I'm probably
gonna do some stuff like this console
dot log J right I mean I'm not a
complicated individual I use printf as
my debug right you could use gdb or you
could just use printf so I
go through the code and I just keep
running in till I get something that
works and eventually I'll come to the
realization of something like this
I'll just output everything and you can
see up at the top of the slide is the
activation code so you can follow along
on the right-hand of the slide I could
see for the first loop the character was
the letter e the index of whatever that
is it's the number for the second
character is the letter n the index of
is number 13 and then the value whatever
that is a byte 0 is Oh X 14 that appears
to me to be made up of the first value 4
and the second value 13 simply
represented in hex so I follow this
along a little bit and I'm able to
discern the pattern what is the
algorithm here right it's the algorithm
turns out to be relatively simple you
have letters A through Z that are
numbered 0 through 25 that looks like a
common like Caesar cipher right you just
have a letter it's going to become a
number and then in and kind of two
blocks at a time each value is it
becomes you know the high and low order
bits of a byte of a character right so 0
for D is made up of 4 which is the
letter E and 13 which is the letter M
and then the tricky tricky part of those
folks at Dell or Quest is every other
pair they add 10 to it so all I have to
do is subtract 10 so if I look at the
letter Q Q is 16 subtract 10 is 6 that
becomes 6 W is 22 subtract 10 is 12 that
becomes C and then it repeats you know a
is 0 becomes 0 and 50 etc so I'm able to
now you know write some code that is a
little more intelligible than just
copying and pasting from Java into the
system and I have looking going up the
stack so we did this code we did from
printable string and we were able to
decode it so we check we decoded the
activation code what is left to get at
the contents of the system well there is
on 4
fortunately some encryption right said
encryption key get encrypt soft digest I
look at the code there and look at the
jad files and it's 400 lines of code
there's a lot of math there's bit
shifting I mean these are things you
know that I try to avoid okay and
especially trying to go from Java to
JavaScript with a bit shifting and a lot
of XOR and stuff it wasn't a good recipe
for me so I'm like there has to be a
better way
so we'll just Park that and then there
appears to be a couple loops so there's
one loop that has an install key and a
DES decrypt okay then there's something
that is a loop that XOR is a value okay
XOR is a common cryptography hiding
thingy and then it does it again and
makes a loop again and then it makes a
different XOR with a different value so
what I want to do is use Java snoop and
another tool that I'll showcase called
cyber chef and I'm gonna learn that a
couple things one without even you know
really having to learn what do we think
the encryption algorithm is it's des
right because they named it des decrypt
right and I don't think I meant that des
encrypt the data for you right so it's
definitely des and it's it's interesting
it's eight bytes at a time because you
can see in the for loop it's plus eight
you know it's it's I equals I plus eight
right and that tells me you're going
eight bytes at a time and how am I gonna
figure out the key I'm going to figure
out the key using Java snoop so in order
to do that I have to use another
capability in Java soup called
adding hooks so I'm gonna browse for the
functions okay and I'm browsing for the
des function no there we go
hold on here there we go and I see that
there's install key so I'm gonna add a
hook for install key I'm gonna add
another hook yes and the other co hook
was des decrypt write for DES decrypt
okay
hooks our capabilities in Java snoop
that let you tamper with the parameters
or tamper with the return value there's
no return value so it's not letting me
tamper with it I don't really care to
tamper with the value but I want to
learn what those values are because I
know you know from you know I think this
is now common knowledge right to encrypt
and decrypt something you need
ciphertext the part that's encrypted you
need a key and you need an algorithm so
I think install key might be the key
just a wild guess and the decrypt
function is gonna have to have that
information in it so let's go ahead and
enter an activation code and see what
happens all right so we'll go demo nine
activate great so I'm at my first
install key so what do I do
I edit it and I copy this value I am
just you know essentially opening a
notebook where is it there we go
essentially opening a notebook and sang
install key is this value okay and I've
gone ahead and kind of done a lot of
this you know it's like Betty Crocker
right you you never see her make the
whole cake she puts it in the oven and
just magically comes out so I copy the
install key all right and I go back to
go back to Java snoop oh great
okay now I'm on des decrypt and I see
some more values okay okay so I copy
those values over to TextWrangler and I
could see those are my values what's
interesting is already I can see some
commonalities this is my decoded key and
this is the text this is the these are
the bytes that are being sent to the
decrypt so it's clearly what's happening
is des decrypt is going to decrypt the
ciphertext that I decoded it's also a
nice win because it validates that we
were doing the decode function properly
okay so I accept the changes I go
through can I look at the next install
key I copy that I paste it down here
don't know that there's is there
anything interesting here the kind of is
hey look some bytes of the install key
are now the first set of bytes of my
decoded key that is very interesting so
I'll copy the DES decrypt function value
and then I'll do that like one or two
more times I'm always trying to just
figure out you know I'd say higher-order
function what is the system doing how is
it doing it well in order to figure that
out I've got some data now I have
install key values I have ciphertext
values and look at this the second time
I call des decrypt the first eight bytes
are no longer the eight bytes of my
decoded value this suggests to me that
this might be the decrypted value so if
I can get some kind of program to take
the key to take the ciphertext and
produce this output I think I'll be well
on my way to figuring out how this works
so in order to do that I'm going to use
cyber chef cyber chef is a fantastic
fantastic product it's free and what's
really great about it is it lets you I
say rapidly prototype modifications of
data right so I could do this I could
say I want to go I want to take
something to base64 and then I want to
make a hex dump to hex dump and then
what if I type this in you know it gives
me the hex dump right and it's they call
it recipes because you're a cyber chef
worlds I mean this tool is just awesome
it's open source and published okay
and they have which is great because I
did not care to write an encryption and
decryption functions they have des
decrypt so they have the decryption
function for me I don't I need Python I
don't need you know and if I code
something up myself
I'm almost always confident that I made
a mistake so if it doesn't work I don't
know if it didn't work because I'm a
horrible horrible programmer which is a
truism or you know if I'm
misunderstanding something so as much as
possible I try to rely on other people's
code to validate sometimes they're wrong
though which we did which I did learn so
let's go back to round zero install key
is this value okay so the key goes here
and it's in hex format I mean that's
super easy I don't have to do much you
know which is stuff something in there
and the input is the ciphertext right
and what I'm going to do is I'm going to
say look I'm only going to input the
first eight bytes because only the eight
bytes changed right why make more work
for myself it's um you know I just want
to be simply so I'm gonna take the first
eight bytes a ciphertext and one two
three four five six seven eight yep so
now there's a lot of variables and
configurations for des decryption as
simple as it is so I might play with
some of these values and say hey okay if
it's CBC mode it's definitely not that
padding that's not getting me a result
oh that's okay so that didn't go very
well
also I want the output to be X okay so I
did get some value there and remember
the value I'm looking for is for 107 so
if you see for 107 let's let's stop okay
so I'm going to say okay let's find you
know cipher block chaining I think
that's cipher feedback mode I'm not
getting my code counter mode not getting
a code output feedback block cipher
maybe not working
ECB none of these things are working
okay that's that would normally be bad
for the demo
but I've expected and anticipated this
all right so what what could some of the
issues be well if I look at Mikey Mikey
is actually 16 bytes Dez quick Google
search is how many bits of strength 56
but they technically use 64-bit keys and
it's just sloppiness that drops it to 56
so I only need 8 bytes so the question
is is what 8 bytes make up the key well
I know if I go to the end of the file
and I remove data my output doesn't
change it doesn't change because only
the first eight bytes of being used so I
know that the information is not in the
first eight bytes or would have already
given me an answer so what I'm gonna do
is just delete two bytes at a time
you'll see my output change okay
but I'm not getting the code I want so I
just keep holy right so that's good
because now that was a good positives
for dramatic effect right because now I
have with the key and what turns us to
be the last eight bytes of the install
key variable I now have this input that
generates f10 7 9 f8 3 DAC 6 so I have
successfully recreated in other code the
decryption algorithm that's really cool
all right that's really it was a good
day when that happened so we can repeat
those steps but in the interest of time
I won't but we could XOR right so the
other thing is we could use we could
make sure is this really working or not
so they have an XOR function right and
the XOR function goes what's the value a
a right ok and of course the output is
hex so I have to go from hex which makes
binary data i XOR the function and then
I go to hex
and now this would be the first eight
bytes through the install key des
decrypt loop and the and the next XOR
and then I repeat this for the next
install key loop and it turns out they
use a different algorithm not a
different algorithm but they get the
first eight bytes a little differently
but it doesn't matter because my
approach still works and now what I'm
left with is the decoded activation code
the cipher text we know of what it is
because we decoded it the key is very
simple the key is that blob that first
eight byte blob plus the rest of my
activation code so they're using the
activation code the kind of decrypt
itself just slid over eight bytes right
which you know if you think about it
maybe that wasn't the only option they
had because they had no network
connectivity they couldn't exchange keys
etc and it the code has to work on every
platform so that is what they have and
that this is the DES decrypted plaintext
if I repeat these steps I now have in
that long text those long hexadecimal
values that is the completely decoded
activation code that's fantastic but it
doesn't really help me enough and yet
what I'm looking for is remember I said
the token serial number is probably in
there and there has to be data to
generate the H Mac one-time password
where is the token serial number well I
know that the token serial number is
three oh five three whatever but my
activation code when decoded went
decrypted it's not in decimal so I just
used Google to say what is this number
in hex and I get this value Baker six
zero two three David zero four do you
see that value anywhere in here yes and
no you see it but it is Indian I just
say it's Indian because I always get my
bigger little mixed up so I just
abstract it to say there's an Indian
Asst about the data which is the case
and I can see the second to last 4 bytes
appear to be where
the serial number is okay so it's great
cuz all throughout this exercise I'm
getting like a positive feedback loop
from the research telling me I'm
probably on the right path because the
serial number was there the last byte 82
is probably just an integrity check or
checksum that just seems something that
programmers can't help themselves from
doing okay so I want to take this now
and figure out where is the secret data
that generates the sha-1 H Mac one-time
password so to do that let's just take
one little sidestep to do a little
further google research into h OTP right
i mentioned it was this RFC standard it
has components that are shared secret
that generates that and it's counter
based right the other common one-time
password compliance system is totp
time-based time-based is technically the
same as HT OTP except the counter
instead of being like 1 then 2 then 3
the counter is like the number of
seconds since the epoch you know divided
by 30 or 60 all right so the counter
it's still the same function it's just
how they calculate the counter and then
we want to make this work in google
authenticator so we have to do a little
more to say you know the base 32 the key
has to be based 32 encoded alright
that's good to know
and the C is the increment encounter
that's just a number and truncate google
authenticator while completely compliant
with the standard actually only supports
the six-digit version of these codes so
that's just stuff I need to be aware of
so now I want to say how can i generate
these these tokens right so my goal is
to figure out I've got this amount of
data these are the bytes somewhere in
here must obviously be my token right
the data that generates the one-time
password I don't know where it is so I
grab a very quick Python script I
actually made the Python script minus
the imports and I basically say I'm
gonna go through you know starting at
byte
zero and for one bite all the way
through the end you know through all the
bites I'm just gonna calculate one-time
passwords over and over and over again
make five make the first 500 TP
calculations and save them to a file and
then when I grab for my token and I find
the x and y values I'll know positively
the start and stop of the secret
fantastic it would have been better if
it had worked okay so that didn't work
all right which happens you know from
time to time all right and so that we
have to throw away I also tried nd in
this right so I tried just you know the
serial number was ND and decoded right
so it would make sense you know that
they might do that too so there's a
script in there where you might say I
calculated the endianness but literally
I just wrote that wrote the hex bytes
backwards it had the same effect right
and that didn't work either so now
remember I can go up the stack and I
could figure out actually what is the
secret right I'm using Java snoop so why
the heck don't I snoop it and figure out
what the actual bytes are and compare it
to my decoded value all right so let's
go ahead and do that so I'm back in the
Java snoop land and accept all the
changes all right so I'm at a problem I
threw my google searching and finding
freely available activation codes for
research did not find an activation code
that worked for the Java client so I
don't get the ability to generate the
one-time password but I have complete
control over the application so I might
have an end right so what I'll do is if
I go up the stack if you remember here
right so we do this there's this you
know what does it do
activate token calls check token check
token is a boolean I didn't even have to
google what boolean metz okay it's true
or false so my guess is if it's false it
didn't check out so I'm gonna modify
that and see if I get some joy all right
so I'm gonna add a new hook
I'm gonna look for oops I'm gonna browse
the SDK this is where it is oops and I'm
looking for
it was check token right I miss it
[Music]
check platform no I don't think that's
the same one hmm well yeah it wasn't in
DES so that's good one I'll tell you
what we'll just do bill just oh actually
you know if I was smart I would just go
here look at the code go one over and
they got play get the nice visual effect
okay all right I get there later all
right so here
yeah it's in quest doc token right so I
had the wrong class all right so easy
mistake anybody could have made it I
swear
all right so we add a new hook and I'm
looking for
I already Fred ja token right and it was
[Music]
no I wouldn't forgot it again quest
quest star token dot Java dot token now
see I see see I went too fast
everybody quest token dot Java dot token
all right cuesta token that Java but
took a quest token okay yeah so that's
it all right
and I've got it's a boolean I'm looking
for boolean check token name nice try
but that's not it boolean check token
okay
so add the hook
and there's at this time I want to only
tamper with the return value so okay
very good so I will do that enter my
activation code demo Shazam
click activate and the value is false
I am gonna change this to be true now in
the interest of time I'll save the 30
minutes it took me to figure this out if
I click true and click accept change it
won't work because the GUI wants you to
like exit the cell that was not a good
day for me when that happened okay
because I thought I knew how programming
worked you know even a little bit and
that didn't work so but now Shazam
there's my token nine one seven six two
two I know since I've generated a token
I've clearly generated a one-time
passcode so let's make another hook add
another hook let's go for word one time
password algorithm and generate OTP
fantastic and look it even has a series
of bytes and you know some numbers so
I'm like it's gonna be a good day I
think all right so go here we're going
to tamper with the parameters I'm just
gonna refresh my token and there are my
values 6 2 2 D 7 4 etcetera etcetera
etcetera which turn out to be right here
alright so I know exactly for this token
what value was used to generate the OTP
and I'm able to lay that out and now I'm
able to figure it out right so I have
for whatever reason they dropped 3 bytes
out of the stream all right and then the
rest of the bytes so it looks like I
think maybe 20 or 40 bytes long there
looks to be some unused space the night
at least didn't figure out there's a
platform type so seven is Android we
know where the serial number is etcetera
so all I have to do is take this binary
data and if you trust me that I that
this works
there's a base 32 encoder and I just put
that in there and then I generate this
one-time password right that is the
secret URL that if I make a QR code will
generate otps that are compliant and
synonymous with the defender tokens so
let's see how that works in practice
we'll go to a demo i used plunker to
build this
assist right so and I learned a lot
about CSS and divs and blah blah blah
okay cuz previously my HTML is limited
to geo cities versions right which was
just h1 h2 maybe B for bold alright so
we've we've stepped my game up
considerably and so I've got I put in
this Android code I've got some fancy
debug output and I know that my token
value is nine one seven six two two and
I generate the Google Authenticator
compliant token that's awesome okay
that's really really good I went ahead
and made some other enhancements because
as ah-ha as a counter based token this
functionality is great when you get the
token when you get the activation code
and you say I don't want to use del
defender one-time blah blah blah when he
was Google off because I use it for AWS
and LastPass and I don't know World of
Warcraft I use it for everything so I
don't want another pieces crappy
software so you got to figure out where
is the token value and every
incrementing value you can see the token
value changes and the QR code changes so
if you know the token number right which
is available in the view token
information you can get that but you
could also be really smart and say if I
know what a token is if I enter that
I'll know that that is counter value 537
so I provide in this utility a way for
you to enter your current token on the
defender app enter the activation code
and I'll generate for you the QR the QR
code that Google auth will map to to an
activation code that you can use inside
Google auth and you can throw away the
poor usable defender token which is
fantastic a couple of gotchas about that
right is that you have to be careful you
can't use start using two tokens at the
same time right why is that anybody
right exactly the counter will go bad on
you right and you'll see this in my
lessons learned I had the pleasure of
doing that to myself because I was
refreshing too many times and I became
out of sync with the server and I had to
ask for another activation token and
maybe there were some questions around
what I was doing so you know generally
generally you want to avoid that okay so
that was the demo and it worked so now a
couple takeaways you're looking at
because I think of not enough I was
serious when I think oh not enough
people you know showcase thank you
showcase the steps they took to get
where they are this is a word cloud of
all of my Google searches that led me
through the exercise today I put on
Twitter this morning like a short video
of the actual searches I looked right
and I would say it's humbling right to
see a grown man claim that he had to
Google for what is 13 and hex all right
but this is how we make improvement all
right so you know how do you write a for
loop in Python every time I write a for
loop in Python I have to Google how to
do it so whatever all right good
security requires good usability I would
say it as information security
professionals we have got to stop making
people go through the nine gates of Hell
to authenticate to VPN all right it's
it's not right and you know security has
to be easy to use to be secure all right
get out of this you know we need you to
hop and dance in some ways to take away
was this was easier than it should be
there was no code obfuscation all right
there were plenty of sample tokens to
play with right a Google image search
for vendor activation code and I got
enough tokens to play with I didn't
actually code a whole lot of this stuff
up the des function the OTP function the
QR code generating function even the CSS
file came from the World Wide Web
right so it's very easy for me to make
this work and in some ways and honestly
in honesty I made this harder for myself
right so I
used old tool sets that I was familiar
with at the time dad is like your
father's decompiler okay because there's
Gen X now and it has a GUI it let you
see all the code at once it does a much
better job I talked about the token
drift even cyber chef is being
constantly maintained so you know you
know organized plan upfront would be
good there's always a security trade-off
right a lot of people use the time based
tokens because your phone is NTP aware
because the telephone network requires
it the backend server is correctly timed
because they require it so it's very
easy to use time based tokens and you
say well only a fool would use a
hardware counter well maybe but you got
to understand is if you steal a
time-based token the victim never has
the opportunity to learn that if you
steal a counter based token they may
cause the drift so there is a plus and
minus two different token types I think
the last takeaway is activation codes or
secrets and they must be treated as such
just because quest defender says it's
only good in Android and it's only good
in our app and it can't be used anywhere
you might have a researcher who's upset
a bunch of poor usability and discovers
that's not the case so maybe you
shouldn't email activation codes all
your employees because then a breach of
the email system now breaches the
multi-factor off last note I want to
make is about reverse engineering
because we did kind of peel away and
look inside of something and I highly
recommend you know I'm a big time
supporter of the Electronic Frontier
Foundation and they have a great website
and a great article about reverse
engineering and they also can make
available legal advice and I had a great
experience with them in this regard so I
encourage everybody before you go taking
something apart you may want to
understand what your risks and
liabilities are and that's it and this
is on github so it's my first github
public repo where they wasn't trying to
fix somebody else and it's called open
fender which was probably a better
cooler sounding name
the topic and any questions no I'm sorry
I should have looked yes that's a great
question so the question was just for
the camera was when I was doing the demo
there wasn't actually any reference to
the initialization vector I believe that
there is actually no initialization
vector it's just in cyber and cyber chef
if that value does not exist you get a
different result than if you then any
value so I could have put the letter Q
in and I would have got the right toko
so don't really know you know why but my
get my belief is there's not an IV in
the decrypt function it was an artifact
I had to inject into a nuance of cyber
chef to make it work great question and
good pickup yes great
any other questions will you all oh yes
I have no idea they're entirely welcome
to run a Google Alert for their own
company name find out
hence the conversation with other people
but but great not also a good question I
don't know what their response would be
we'll find out yep very good
alrighty you all were a kind and
gracious audience to host me thank you
so much hope it comes across that I love
this stuff and you know if anybody
wanted to work on stuff together you
know I would be more than happy to do so
and thank you all for your support
[Applause]