this is a little bit different type of
talk
it seems the rooms pretty thin so maybe
I didn't do a good job describing this
is definitely a talk about breaches but
not just breaches to talk about what is
going on you know there's a lot of us
out there who a little bit fed up with
you know some of the stuff that's going
on especially with with breaches
nowadays and if you use Equifax and
that's a company with plenty of capital
plenty of money plenty of expertise on
hands and how they let certain things
slip away from them it is a little bit
frustrating you know there's plenty of
us who've been kind of preaching the
same thing for years and you know we're
sick we're sick of listening to
ourselves so when you see people get on
the offensive and you see people say
things that are derogatory just know
that breaches can happen to everybody
and we realize that but when certain
places breach not just your personal
data that you didn't consent to them
having but it's also a breach of trust
right breach you know breach in itself
is not just losing your data that's been
lost thirty times it's the level of
trust that in an organization and it
forms that relationship with you as a
consumer and you know some good has
happened with some of the breaches right
so there's one thing I can think of is
that target target right now has one of
the best blue and right teams in the
country I believe I know the gentleman
who run each of those teams at target
and they're a phenomenal group now it
sucks they they had to have a wake-up
call like they did but it happened so as
I get started here again title the talk
is what up breaches I don't see a lot of
children in the odd
which is good because I'm gonna get a
little colorful here and there but I
want this talk to be interactive right
this is a small enough group if anyone
here has ever been to shmoocon before
feel free to throw something at me they
won't injure me if you want to call
I would love to discuss it if
you have any questions speak up some
familiar faces in here and there's gonna
be some good examples so I had some
ideas for this talk again I had some
teenage daughters so you know indicative
of that so the talk was almost titled
dropped database breaches or drop your
breaches unfortunately I did see a
Splunk t-shirt like that years ago I was
gonna do breeches are crazy but then I
started to think about any implication
so that and with that we'll get started
quick intro I know I was introduced
earlier Ralph is here he also runs the o
Oz chapter with me in Columbia I'm
primarily an application security guy
nowadays I've done a lot of things
previous lives obviously started and
helpdesk went to sysadmin network
engineer some pen testing and bug bounty
and I was a CIO so at some point in my
life that was in the past
personal life in case you care I am a
husband a father I do have a farm
believe it or not I like to break things
I like to build things and most
importantly I end up fixing a lot of
stuff and again one of the motivations
for this talk was just being one of
those guys who's tired of being ignored
for for years and years and years and
I'm tired of getting the emails I'm
tired of getting the free identity
protection I'm pretty sick of it I'm
sick and tired of it and and that really
leads me on to my next slide so I feel
like you know we lose control
of we lose control of some basics and by
basics I don't mean I don't mean basics
as far as things that Jack mentioned
right Jack Jack had some really good
foundation points I'm talking about
basics of our modern-day info second
application security departments those
kind of basics basics that we function
at on a daily basis that should be baked
into the processes that we hold and
they're not and I want to bring some of
those points up I've seen what works
I've seen what doesn't I've seen too
many mistakes again I'm nobody is breach
proof we all can be breached but I think
that we can do better again again you
know sophisticated attacks do exist and
if a nation-state or no days is
targeting you from from China or Russia
you probably don't have a good shot at
being successful they're probably going
to win but our nation states attacking
you know most of the breaches that
you're getting notified for I mean aside
from you know OPM or or Blue Cross I
guess anthem aside from those are most
of the notifications that you're getting
from people who've been targeted know
you know is everyone in here facing
power system types of breaches on mass
scale with Israeli governments probably
not so those are the ones that I'm gonna
really focus on here there's a lot of
simple solutions out there there's a lot
of tactics there's a lot of questions
that can be asked and answered that
aren't being asked and answered and I
and I I just want to kind of play on
those now so without further ado let's
take a quick look at this
I know that the slides a bit small and
text I got this information from breach
level index it's just one source of
breaches but these were the top-scoring
David reaches like it was a great
achievement for them to be a top story
or something they're like hey we got
tens yes right but what I want to focus
on here is the source of the breach
right malicious outsider do we have the
insider yeah we have an insider we have
one insider there and that was a Korea
credit bureau right so every time that
someone says the insider threat is real
it is it's a hundred percent real but
most of these breaches that pissed me
off are not because someone's in there
stealing USB drives full of company
secrets it's malicious Outsiders right
let's go back to my state sponsors sure
we have an anthem here right
state-sponsored
you're not gonna win if someone's
targeting you that you know you have the
entire government of a country focusing
on you the chances are you're gonna get
popped
sooner or later with some tactic that's
just the guile it goes but that's one
right that's one the rest of these here
are malicious outsiders the industries
are obviously berries we have financial
or retail being the top ones but but you
know the fact matter is delicious
outsider is using things to get in they
are fairly common most of the time and
I'll pick on some in a little bit
statistics some scary stuff that's count
decimal places we're talking trillions
these are trillions of records but even
worse every day we're talking five
million records you break this out an
hour and by minute by
it's ridiculous okay so let's look at
this right breeches that were deemed
useless because proper encryption was
done 4% 4% of the data was encrypted
that was stolen the other 96% was plain
text that's that sucks we can do better
than that the unfortunate part and you
know hey I'm a dad so there's a lot of
dad humor in here so you know if you
don't like a lot of the memes and stuff
then you can just ignore it you can
throw something
but sometimes breaches happen sometimes
they have there's there's no there's no
question about that and the main
question I have is why there's a lot of
reasons we went over these but there's
some here that I haven't touched on yet
and these are the ones that I'm going to
focus on so determine sophisticated
that's your nation-state your insider
yeah okay they do exist it's real
addressing now as we go forward
complexity and difficulty of
environments no matter what this is
usually has something to do with the
breach our environments have become so
muddled and disorganized that very very
basic hygiene procedures are not being
practiced you know how many environments
out there that you say oh well just
apply the patch and then there's the
whole other campus says we can't just
apply a patch do you know how difficult
that is well yeah I do and the
difficulty in complexity and
environments really needs to be wrangled
and that brings us the patches yes/no
ones that I see things all the time
where there are not patches being
applied carelessness and laziness that
does happen again unfortunate and it
sucks negligence that's interesting
you
Katie how negligence feels I think that
they're paying one of the largest fines
for breeches ever been levied fines are
coming and you know a lot of the
organization's also on the smaller side
I guess smaller a medium resort to
something like this and I've seen this
we couldn't hire saying too many scary
things about our computers yeah the
chances are that there are a lot of
scary things that are they need to be
said about your environment so we can't
fix everything let's start with the ones
that we can we can do better
I feel like again part of the motivation
here is we are focusing on too many
vendor centric next-gen artificial
intelligence machine learning blockchain
magic blinky light boxes that are just
pieces of that could do anything
most people could do with decent amount
of scripting there are good commercial
solutions out there but there are way
too many solutions to problems that may
or may not exist we need to take a step
back we need to breathe and we need to
answer some questions the next few
slides are real questions from real
clients I have a former colleague in the
room sitting over here as named Jason
Kent all of these questions have been
fielded by us these are real questions
and answers and these are the questions
we need to start to ask quick things how
many web applications do you have in
your environment
about we think I don't know well guess
what the one you have sitting behind the
Imperva that you're spending a million
dollars on that's great you're securing
that one what about the other ones the
ones that you don't know about you don't
care right there
do you have an accurate asset inventory
do you know what you should be
protecting
right Am I am i dropping Oh days on you
know I'm asking you simple questions do
you know what should be security mostly
mostly do you skin constantly
are you constantly checking your
environment for vulnerabilities all the
time now we can because something could
break if we constantly are testing these
things you know we only have maintenance
windows where we can test I understand
that's great
yeah so what you need to do is you need
to put something out there that says
that hey hackers you can only look at
our systems during these maintenance
hours during these hours where you're
allowed to take a look at our systems
and if your falls over because I
run an nmap scan on it you have other
issues if I cannot scan your enterprise
database in a financial institution
because it will fall over and I'm using
nmap you have a bigger problem
real things and that currently exists at
a very large place today
what is your patching cycle what's your
what is your tolerance for critical
severity vulnerabilities if I find out
that there's a critical severity
vulnerability how long do you have to
patch that how long is acceptable in
your production environment is it more
than 24 hours is it 48 hours how long
does it take for a piece of POC code to
pop up on github is that what you're
racing maybe not usually a good answer
there this is all real data none of this
is okay none of this is fine we need to
do better on the basic questions and
answers alright more fun I can't get
away from these because this is one of
my favorite questions do you know what
your real parameter is and what is open
on it and you wouldn't have a good
answer for what your real parameter is
excellent so there used to be a
perimeter it used to be a nice you know
fortress that you can build a big wall
and put barbed wire up and that's your
perimeter and you're good well guess
what every web browser every mobile
device every piece of connectivity every
line of code that you have running
that's externally accessible is your
perimeter what's open
no idea no idea ports that are open we
you know walking into a fortunate pain
customer I can show you ports that are
open on your externally facing
environment you probably did not know
that we're there it's pretty scary
um training training training training
no one wants to pay for training we have
all these fancy tools well guess what if
no if you don't have the right trained
individuals to use these fancy tools
that you're just spending millions of
dollars on you're gonna have really
fancy tools and a whole lot of data that
you can't use or you don't know how to
use to be basically you're throwing away
money encryption usually everyone is
quick to answer this question no matter
where I am D is your sensitive data
encrypted every single time with 90% 95%
of the time yes absolutely
well guess what if 4% of the breaches
never had any encryption on them I don't
know 90% of people are lying let's go
back to network security Jack touched on
this they was the basis for a lot of
what exists out there in pen testing
teams it exists the basis of what exists
today for a lot of info SEC teams to
begin with is network security there's a
gentleman whose name is Paul cog and I
don't know if anyone knows and he's from
Alabama if anyone has ever seen him talk
he works for Wells Fargo
he is a Cisco guy Oh old Cisco guy who
is now a network security guy he focuses
on very advanced
pentesting using only network layer
vulnerabilities if you ever get a chance
to launches any of his talks you'll
understand and where I'm going with this
is it's even scarier because this is
turning to application so
software-defined networks as the ends
your old your cisco guys right your your
network guys who are down on your net
ops team how many of those guys write
java well guess what that's where it's
going so all of your automation all of
your fallback all of your networks that
are all going to code it'll all be
software-defined and that will bring
this a whole new level
so basics I can sit up here and preach
basics but I'm not making this stuff up
I didn't write this stuff these are your
CIS 20 controls right basic controls are
basic for a reason you don't need a
shiny vendor product for many of these
again what's important for your
environment may differ from what's
important in someone else's environment
sometimes it's the little things like
inventory and I think Jack did mention
stress and egress filtering so let's
talk about egress filtering for a second
why does your point-of-sale terminal
that you swipe your credit card on to
pay for something why does that Terminal
need to be able to talk to any IP in any
country on any for why does that
point-of-sale terminal need to be able
to talk to Russian hackers doing Chinese
anime at midnight on a Friday like why
Sidhu you think I'm crazy but the the
exfiltration of the data from memory
happens on these point-of-sale terminals
and then that those point-of-sale
terminals actually filter exfiltrate the
data out yes a lot of the newer ones are
using 443 and it might go out HTTP
it needs to talk there but why do they
need to talk your point-of-sale
terminals only need to talk to one or
two IPS that's it
you should have egress filtering setup
you should not have these terminals
being will talk to everything target was
a perfect example of that their
point-of-sale terminals had egress to
zero zero zero zero zero zero zero zero
so they could talk to anything anywhere
at any time
simple things if we don't need these
point-of-sale terminals to be locked -
they need to talk to a couple of IPS or
maybe your basic control falls here now
I can all I can argue that 18 is not a
basic control but maybe some things
about it are right maybe it's AB SEC
maybe it is application security an
application security can't be tough I'm
a little bit I'm an app set guy here so
I'm gonna dive into this for a second
not so basic but a quick fact this quick
fact is brought to you by a friend of
mine who was formerly a horizons new
sponsor he actually published this Dvir
this is his chart web app attacks we all
know number one source data breaches why
anyone know who this guy is anyone is
Alan Jackson Aria we got one person in
the room anyone know why well app said
he's hard yes it is I thought I thought
people are saying I thought this talk
was going back to basics good catch and
if I say application security is hard we
do go back to basics but hear me out
Alan Jackson reference top of the slide
if you don't get it it's fine it slain
them it's me remember when I talked
about inventory now say we're talking
about a normal inventory of IT assets
and computer systems what about your web
app inventory it's also in inventory
well I remember when I talked about
perimeter and understanding what your
perimeter is understanding what web
servers are out there with what open
that's all your perimeter yeah that
so counts I talked about scanning and
patching scanning and patching not just
operating systems and network devices
but patching vulnerable what if you're
using a vulnerable library and whatever
your applications that patch counts just
as much as a stupid Microsoft Office
patch counts why should that pack take
any less precedence on your external
facing system than an office patch or a
Microsoft server patch an unfortunate
reality is that those patches are
getting pushed way down the line
compared to your OS patches and
understanding that and applying those
basic concepts to application security
can help you remember when I talk about
encryption yeah that's an important one
for web apps maybe we should think about
that too
you know there's a big push for HTTPS
and your little green shiny lock oh
that's wonderful but what about the data
that sits behind it maybe we should ask
those questions too firewalls everyone
in this room I guarantee has a network
with a firewall right why why do you
have it because it's important right you
need a firewall there well now what
about your perimeter applications why
why should they be treated any
differently you have a firewall sitting
in front of your you have a firewall
sitting in front of your desktop at your
desk that's sitting behind some switches
and routers and things why shouldn't
there be a firewall or something
protecting those web applications that's
also has critical data like your
workstation versus a web app like there
needs to be protections they're
addressing the majority of the OAuth pop
thing to me those basic functions need
to happen and their application security
just as your 20 critical controls need
to take place multi-factor
authentication to me that needs to be
basic how many of these things can be
protected with multi-factor
authentication we are in the state of
South Carolina everybody who lives in
South Carolina please raise your hand
who has lived here from one state
13 to today okay all of you are victim
to a breach that happened because there
was no MFA there was no multi-factor
authentication on the system that was
able to get the data the person had
legitimate credentials the half occurred
with legitimate credentials so there
wasn't a patch not applied they were
credentials that were compromised so if
I log into a state computer system
remotely and I it's it's been fixed but
if I let's hypothetically hear me out
back when this happened I log into this
computer system remotely
I have legitimate credentials I'm using
an IP address now okay let's pretend
that I decided to use the local proxy so
the the local proxy doesn't look out of
place I'm not accessing it from some
server in China or something like that
and I log in and now I connect I take
all the data I want I compress it I
encrypted I FTP it out whatever we talk
about egress but that's a whole other
thing
simple multi-factor authentication for
systems that contain critical data that
breach which costs our state millions
whoever has SC ID protection comm
everybody in here that raised their hand
could have been avoided with one simple
multi-factor authentication that was
that one particular instance I won't say
it's good for everything but it happens
now the other side we're all smart
intelligent people it can't be this easy
I'm making it sound like people are
simply choosing not to do these things
if these were indeed basics and the
basics could protect us
why couldn't these large technically
savvy companies with really capable
individuals and budgets not solve these
problems already why wouldn't the
breaches just stop
am i oversimplifying things let's go
back to those questions real quick right
do you think I'm oversimplifying things
do you think anything I'm saying has
been oversimplified no one's talked
alright so the first thing we need to
know as we dive into this and in those
questions on the other side of it and
this is important to understand both
sides right you can't just be on the
offensive you have to put yourself in
the shoes of making things better so
making things better all it comes back
down to we're all human we make human
mistakes we screw up I screwed up
earlier this week said something I
shouldn't have said to someone I
shouldn't have said it to it ended up in
a slight breach of trust and it was a
pain in the ass I screwed up
we're spend too much time checking boxes
I've been on way too many engagements
where someone says will this cover me
for X and X is checking the box and the
answers like yes but and they don't want
to hear it I think that a lot of the
mentality of checking boxes really needs
to change and that can't change with
that top-down security support top-down
support starts at your sea level
you know the unfortunate reality is if
you don't have that support from the sea
level you're going to be checking boxes
and you're not going to be successful
another thing that might have to do with
this is that you know with all the
security breaches in the news there are
budgets and with budgets people like to
spend the money and they spend the money
so they can get another budget the next
year because if you don't spend it
you're not going to get it renewed
so with that they buy a lot of stuff
they buy stuff and with that stuff what
do you think they forget to buy they
forget to buy training they forget to
equal budget their products with their
implementations consultants their
implementations professional
implementations they buy stuff and
they're not focusing on that a lack of
training again I can say this very
firmly training Trump's tools be smart
use bow
but your training will always trump the
tools now let's dive a little deeper
we're gonna do a little scuba and a lack
of understanding in the complex
environment is key to understand why
sometimes these basics get lost and I
think that's kind of a given but the
next one's huge right so why do these
basics not always work - because we're
spending money on these tools and we're
trying to show something that's almost
impossible your ROI on security if I
never get breached and I spent ten
billion dollars on it can i I mean is
there something that says ROI on
security stuff is there something to say
that if I didn't do it I would have been
fine with only seven million maybe I
think security also looked at as not a
business problem but more of an IT
problem when it's really not it focuses
on your business everything about your
business has now is now related to IT if
you take the IT department out can your
can your business function without IT at
all if the answer is yes great throw
this slide away if your answer's no then
obviously security is not just an IT
problem it's a complete business problem
and there's impacts yeah scan patch
basics all things not just important
things not just your main website what
about your interfaces your middleware
secure all of them all the weakest links
and the unfortunate part again is
something to avoid here this is a quote
by Darren boozers the CEO of NCC data
and then the unfortunate part is apathy
enterprise companies today right they
have the bribe procedures and teams to
prevent attacks but the perception that
your business is safe leads to empathy
but no empathy for them
apathy cyber criminals remember I
mentioned earlier about the your
maintenance windows cyber criminals are
constantly looking for vulnerabilities
to stay ahead of this you're trained IT
teams need to be looking 24/7 and
upgrade packages of software and you
know this quote is great I just hope you
know I really hope that people can take
it into better consideration a little
bit of what the future will hold here's
what I think I want to spend a few
minutes on this slide in particular
cyber insurance and guarantees with the
amount of breaches and things that are
happening out there
there's our companies out there who are
really leveraging to put insurance
policies or sell insurance policies to
corporations and those corporate and
that cyber insurance would essentially
limit their liability from any breaches
or knock down their liability right if
not totally nullified but liability now
that leads us to an interesting question
what if I owned a company and I want
really want feedback on this one please
if I owned a company and I can buy a
cyber insurance policy that would cover
me for five million dollars a year but
my security spend would have been ten
million dollars for the year to cover me
what how do you justify to your
stakeholders that you should be spending
the money on security and not just
saying screw it and buying your breach
insurance for half the money
I will come do an assessment of what
you've done and I'll tell them they did
nothing and they won't they'll give you
your premium back perfect
I mean they used companies like bit
sites we found out like a FICO score
okay where there were bridges and
preexisting condition right so they're
gonna deny you for pre-existing
condition essentially right they're
going to show a pattern there may be
negligence yep excellent point so that
brings us to guarantees there are
companies out there who are guaranteeing
with high amounts of money that you
won't get breached if you use their
services there's two things there one
it's putting your money where your mouth
is and two it's using the expertise that
they can offer and I you know I'm album
gonna anyone have any feedback on the
cyber guarantees of guaranteeing a
customer won't get breached if they use
us for X up to a million dollars
twenty years so when we point at it we
say listening do what we say and I
promise you won't get breached in fact
back it up with a million bucks this is
a sales pitch I won't tell anyone here
who I work for you go google it but the
fact that we can offer this service it's
a lot of people to go well that's
interesting and then they go back to not
having inventory not patching right they
don't come to us in probes like these
sort of but they would simply because no
one cares about this insurance it's not
doing it at all there's no accident
there's no accident these two things are
up there if anyone here follows Jeremiah
Grossman or other people they know that
these these things are real right the
push for cyber insurance which i think
is a terrible idea
it's that agenda is still being pushed
whether whether it's going to work or
not it's still being pushed guarantees
more and more coming out there now we
talk about liability and fines now I I
think that the liability for companies
who can't do the basics now I'm talking
about
Equifax again because they pissed me off
a little bit here so if if you have a
portal open with admin admin is that
neglect and externally facing is that
neglect like for a company like after
Equifax not for Joe who owns the coffee
shop on the corner maybe but for a
company like Equifax that houses all of
your sensitive data question
we're violating regulations when they
got breach there are states that require
notification of an average there I know
for a fact that that they have not yet
notified residents of the estates
they're breaking existing regulations
and that where does it coming the only
thing that's going to hurt them is the
wallet right when the CEO decides to
leave but takes a seven or eight figure
check with them they don't give a
they're like hey this is great I'm gonna
go on the beach have a nice day exactly
for a company like that you know let and
another thing bug bounties they work
they're going to increase not everyone's
a good candidate for them there are but
bug bounties work and I think that's
something that needs to keep going
forward now free pen tests for everyone
this comes back to my earlier
inclination of tests I promise you that
whether you like it or not your company
is getting a free pen test right now
they are getting a free pen test right
this second everybody that's sitting in
this room that has a presence publicly
facing presence is getting a pen test
right now for free now the difference is
these guys want to be paid for it but
they'll tell you about it and the other
difference is the other people they
might want to be paid for too but
they're gonna just go sell it undone
ioan somewhere and have a
I stay in the dark web or who knows
maybe just for kids but yeah exactly
yeah this is what I found so bug
bounties I'm a big advocate for always
happen I more than willing to talk to
anybody on that but I think they work
very well I don't think that they
replace pen testing I think it's a good
supplement and I think that you're as
long as your maturity level is an
organization to understand the where are
those and how to fix those
vulnerabilities and address them are up
to par then they can be super beneficial
for you consultancies use them there are
a lot of really good consultancies there
are a lot of shitty ones there are a lot
of companies who will tell you who the
good ones are and if anyone here works
for Deloitte I'm sorry they're number
one yes Gartner has put them in that
Magic Quadrant in the top right they are
the number one cybersecurity consultancy
in the country according to Gartner so
sea levels automatically are going to
hire those right I mean they're part of
the big three where is that 2017 is June
published but they're still plugging it
so if they're still publishing the
article it was published in June so
timing wise it's interesting but the
fact that Deloitte is using that
information to advertise today is kind
of still you know I don't know it's kind
of ballsy in my opinion right but its
marketing they need to make business and
there are a lot of good people there I
have some friends that are there so you
know but pick your consultancies wisely
a big push here that I like to see too
and there's a really good talk later at
3:00 p.m. in this room about what to do
when someone wants to disclose
vulnerability to you I'm just going to
touch on this real quick but adding the
security about txt to all of your
external facing that
nations that simply has hey our security
dresses this are put that in there I
mean there's a lot of times that and I'm
Jason's gonna go into it in depth but
there are a lot of times where there's
just way too many vulnerabilities and we
as hackers find these things and
sometimes I find them by accident when
I'm online shopping but anyway so being
able to disclose these is not always
easy so if you're trying to secure have
a way for someone to report have someone
have a way for someone to report
something to you and I know that this is
also part of a problem probably not so
much lose it I don't care how many
followers on Twitter you have I really
don't know if you need help ask for it
there are a lot of good people in this
room who have been doing a lot of things
in different niche areas for a long time
I'm looking around the room and I
recognize definitely some really amazing
talent so ask questions I would be sidon
over there I see yeah so there's a lot
of feel free ask for help network
remember we're dentists with that I'm
running out of time but before I run out
of time you know besides is an amazing
place I'm not up on a stage in front of
a hundred people I'm not talking about
Python bastes security systems like my
last talk here we're not in the weeds
with this talk on you know but what I
like to do is network and I think that
the feedback and the amount of
communication we can have is extremely
beneficial so as a group we'll take the
last couple minutes here I think we have
the last four minutes or so and let's
interact with each other let's ask some
questions concerns let's get some things
going if we could
yep come to my dog come to James
anaconda 3d it's all about his name of a
stock is are you ready and that's all
how to respond because if you don't
respond anybody else yeah
[Music]
that's an excellent question I think so
the leadership that takes security
seriously and I believe I mentioned that
one of my slides one of the key
indicators there that I find a
commonality with is people's support for
training having people come to these
events or come to black out or coming to
training events getting hands-on
training taking classes whether it's
sans whether it's specific other
training that injures people but keeping
training up is usually a good indicator
now I don't say it's a one-for-one but I
will say that it's usually a good
indicator of leadership dedication to
the to usually people or places that are
better off holistically on the security
threat than others other things too are
you know having having red teams and
blue teams on both sides and keeping
those exercises to work and feed off of
each other it sounds kind of old and
stale but I'm seeing a lot of that do
more good lately and you know morphing
into these purple type of teams and
things where you have exercises where
you have attacks and defenses going on
simultaneously and then sharing that
information and knowledge with each
other and usually anyone who gives that
kind of flexibility to hiring you know
the right kind of people and bringing
those people in are you
in a better spot anyone else
yeah so one thing that I left off here
and it's my bad so I made a mistake
these metrics it's part of that top 20
but I think metrics is a huge huge part
of being able to show effectiveness
being able to self report being able to
report on what you've done and obviously
what you're saying is even going beyond
that right it's showing actionable
metrics that you what you actually
stopped and I think that metrics is a
huge part and what you have to do is
assess and reassess and constantly
update leadership on those metrics so
it's not just you know it's not just
running the metrics but its presenting
it in executive format presenting it in
a readable easily readable format and
then doing it on a regular basis to show
progress to show the curve show exactly
what you're doing and how things are
getting better what did you do to fix
the problems that they found you know so
metrics is good but as you mentioned
definitely keep that in I think if any
one more all right
but the scientific method repeatable
reproducible make so mean time to
failure do you see that happening in the
industry like science I'm going to
separate that myth though is that I'm
going to use a lot of like so I'm seeing
a lot more analytics and data science
and that's it's related but the
analytics related to large organizations
that have data scientists that work
together to be able to to increase
efficiencies and show those values
really have more advanced analytics
platforms but if I am seeing that but
it's really only the big people that are
doing anything like that as you probably
know data scientists are not cheap so
advanced analytics and data science is
definitely an area of growth and I see a
lot more large initiating especially
your Amazons and things like that we're
using those two for for efficiency and
pertwee to
going once going twice almost sold yeah
I I see no I don't see any immediate I
see nothing moving in the direction of
standardization for metrics across the
industry as of right now if you could
come up with something that'd be great
but I don't I just I personally don't
see it yeah all right
I'm told amount of time thank you
everybody here's my contact information
pretty easy to find if you see me around
I'll be around today if you have
anything follow up thanks
[Applause]