we're in cover several judges we're
going to define cyber security which is
probably been defined already today at
least once i'm going to use something a
little bit different on these foreigners
versus are screwed
the flying situation awareness combined
bulb then I'm going to go scenario-based
the Kennedy 10 speaks Latin there's a
lot of majors in here who knows when the
credit Luna means trust no one pretty
much when you're on the Internet trust
notebook dr. first guy I'm not going to
charge the guy says trust me and then
we'll go into a hack scenario what's
your bottom arm hole how about hard
perfect then I'm in that's right for the
country or Arkansas cybersecurity the
body of technologies across the system
practices designed to protect networks
computers programs and data from attack
damage or unauthorized access the
computer context the term security file
Cyrus according to a December 2010
analysis of us spending plans the
government it's 2010 you plan on
spending 13 billion annually over the
next five years so 13/5 that's the plan
was
I've got aggressive stuff very much
quick video on a hobby
the cake
our little kick
look
as a Russian
probably like
found
what
bear with me
but this
there you go
really
at me the phone
good situation
sorry guys
would you be comfortable living in a
house that soils have a key to what if
an underground tunnel led me to it from
a public park where it's windows would
never quite close all the way would you
trust it with your safety and your
privacy the internet is that house this
is not to say never go into the house
but rather you should know the hazards
before you store all of your valuables
there and do what you can to protect the
whole so why is it as secure and why
can't we just fortify it until it's safe
well first of all the internet was not
originally built to be what it is today
it's like someone decided to expand a
shoebox into a skyscraper the internet
originally developed on computers were
huge and so expensive to Elm that only
universities big businesses and a few
governments have them the point is
originally will select these massive
supercomputers to talk to each other and
as students to computers were send
information back and forth we had a
network then they were gradually
improved to a personal computers
emergent 1980s and then explode soon
we're not just talking to each other but
also exchanging money playing game
creating dues shopping and doing
everything the associated with the
Internet today other devices started
talking to network to Tom's the karmic
refrigerators and elevators and power
plants and much much more but the ease
of all those devices talking to each
other came at press security one
computer could send in other
instructions to delete everything on it
or take it over we call these viruses
and malware or one person that steal
another's identity by guessing cracking
or extracting a password what offer
abilities such as thieves will never
completely go away because they're built
into the Internet's very architecture
penalties than the steal billions of
dollars governments use them for
surveillance antagonists use them to
further their political goals between
2004 2013 over 1 billion records and
personal information were stolen were
leaked through data breaches of make
your organization as a thought
experiment let's imagine when perfectly
secure Internet users would not be
allowed to download or install any on
their computers all internet traffic
would be monitored and regulated by box
and humans massively limiting the number
and websites you can visit in order to
log onto a website you have to tag in a
100 character password committed genetic
sample and whistle a tune the disturbers
that hold data would be kept in heavily
armed fortresses on
and even with all these safeguards in
place some clever hacker well most
certainly still find a way in here how
the good news is even are flawed
internet there are simple things you can
do to protect yourself and there are a
lot of people committed to making the
internet or circle you know the
cybersecurity lab you'll play as one of
these needle protecting a company that's
the target of increasingly sophisticated
cyber attacks you must continuously
strengthen your defenses to deport these
attackers you'll do this by completing
challenges that will give you basic
coding dirties help you spot scams
designed to trick you into giving up
your secrets empty bottom line the area
that was not designed to be witness to
the social media companies universities
they've all added into the mix of
gradient turning what it is now compare
that to 13 billion over five years to
just the 2015 budget 38.2 billion is
going to be invested
one of the first times the budget is to
churn increase because of tax workers
times going to be increased by competing
industries organizations activists
foreign country or foreign countries are
especially dangerous because they have
the resources not only to fun long-term
attacks but to recruit commit
individuals or a capable of developing
the codes needed for these sustained
attacks just like iris book about before
Korea Russia how the resources to commit
to individuals right now China is
educating kids recruiting kids as young
as four years old and teaching them how
to hack and create code it's imagine a
kid that starts at four my time is 10
what kind codes be created or new ones
15 11 he's 15 years old the stall kicks
keeps growing
situation awareness and the security
world is the ability to identify process
in Capri onda the critical elements of
information about what is happening
whereas the mission or simply smelling
what's going on around here in a sudden
as the fuck that's defined by us by the
US Coast Guard cyber situational
awareness the media knowledge of
friendly adversary and other relevant
information gardening activities in and
through cyberspace and the EMS
specifically EMS you guys know what
happened last year May of last year
somebody hacked into the EMS emergency
management system and sent a code out
from Atlanta to New York asking people
to call a specific number the threat was
that it started off in Atlanta caprice
ignored what if they had sent that code
out to have somebody go to a specific
location and then engage at that
location that's why that threat King so
dangerous and prevalent for the APR
something as simple as a thumb drive
some kid picks up a thumb drive from
school or strategically placed thumb
drive somewhere within a classroom
they're going to go home plug them into
the computer and there's a virus on it
the virus has now infected that computer
all their dad remember the family uses
that computer to interface their their
business now that businesses have it
were infected with whatever virus was on
some of the top 10 path 2014 this is
just this year compact call themselves
halt publish the xbox one sdk virus acts
the information allows them to protect
home to develop their own home brew xbox
apps to run under any constants it's not
a huge threat to anyone outside of the
game community on a second anniversary
of orange sports is dead and internet
practiced and talent computer over would
help fountain reddit in phlebotomy and
the organization created continents
happy to face 15 sites of Massachusetts
Institute of Technology the US military
man was officials who oversee operation
the least are happy a twig american
airlines group attacked him on Jerry
2012 thanks Jerry 17 hackers breaking to
pay I be calm virtual marketplace online
but reversed several banks financial
institutions report abusive installer
tens of millions of end of enemy
corporation are out how they are Danity
stove so on and so on this happens every
single day it's a constant barrage of
pack attacks the trading on the trust
mental except for those guys to devour
each other
oh good internet better radicalization
Isis is constantly looking for ways to
recruit individuals they do it at
universities they do an ad on social
websites they do it with individuals who
aren't getting satisfaction or the
recognition from the peers so they are
now looking to get famous be Royal
Canadian Mounted Police the finest
radicalization has the process by which
individuals are introduced to end
poverty ideological message and belief
system that encourages movement from
moderate mainstream beliefs towards
extreme views while rather than thinking
invite is by no means problematic in
itself it becomes a threat to national
security when citizens or residents
support or engage in violence or direct
action as a means promoting clinical
ideological or religious extremism
sometimes referred to as homegrown
terrorism this process of radicalization
is more correctly referred to as
domestic radicalization leading to tip
terrorist violence there's going to be a
bunch of handouts here from resources
and the rand report that came out in
2013 is a great read on about causations
of individuals through the internet the
one of the things problems the FBI faces
right now the group called the sovereign
citizens making love her dishonest
few people there's a really interesting
video on the internet style of pulling
sovereign citizen choose cop in the face
I didn't know what the crowd was going
to be so I didn't add it in but routine
traffic stop put they pull over a
sovereign citizen or pull over an
individual with his son pull them out of
the vehicle an officer comes in as
backup and as they pull the individual
the driver off to the side the 14 okay
look kid pulls out a p-47 shoots a pound
of the face seven times he then proceeds
to shoot what's that nothing on you then
receives to shoot the other officer as
he's running to ditch kills them both
and ends up in a shootout at a Walmart
we talked a little bit off valve al
qaeda al qaeda literally means the base
al Qaeda in nanna in the Arabic
Peninsula is actively recruiting college
students kids drop out of school their
forward they take these classes they
think they owe it's not for them well
neither got not only do they have a
radicalized I ideology right now but
they also own over thirty thousand
dollars in debt well guess what they
will pay that off for you you'll pay
that off for you but you come up with
that they won after that
and there have been several we see where
he really was all the time Americans
found in Iraq that's 50 Afghanistan
individuals that are radicalized the
Boston bomber the ass attacks on the
officers in the subway system in New
York the patch attack in Louie Armstrong
airport the individual who was 16 years
old was who was bound and determined to
kill his family and then go into school
all those individuals had something in
common they had a copy or access to the
mujahid handbook ISIL Isis publishes an
a an online publication called inspire
magazine inspire magazine started in
2010 they took the culmination of what
they put into those magazines inspired
and put it into handbook moves I need
handbook in the mujahid handbook it
specifically speaks about crop top box
so that's how the guys in bought the
Boston bombers learn how to kind of
create those those hot hotbox they also
talked about a thing called the human
lawnmower it tells people to well blades
onto their pickup truck and go to fairs
and mobile start driving back and forth
back and forth that I mean the industry
to see how many they could take out and
then to make sure they had nothing
ammunition to step out because when I
first responders come because eventually
the body's going to stuck underneath
your truck the first responders come the
tip started shooting at first responders
this is on the internet it's mushahid
handbook I don't suggest you download it
for those of you in the security field
how many of you have heard that we've
got even a blur don't downloading get a
copy from your local fusion center or
from your local police department all
right it's a good thing to have on hand
in that book specifically talked about
hack attacks or patch of tax or
individual tax sports law enforcement
specifically law enforcement
the dark web how many people know about
the dark web there you go how many
people have every actress that's me
which you guys by trustee I don't know
it's good like a perfect yeah I didn't
know what the heck is that is perfect he
knocked on the door really we're not to
do it a couple weeks that's anonymous
right there boys right yeah there's a
gentleman without of itself don't put
herself and if you guys are better than
amateurs all right so dark web in 2012
the FBI got into a design their own
website on the dark web where you could
actually go in and buy information now
they were trading information using that
information to gather more information
on individuals that were coming into the
web by the time they were done they had
to finally shut it down because their
codes kept getting half consistently a
progressive hack attacks when i rose
talking about
the equation group they had their
version of the equation group that would
kill his whole thing up and eventually
that's how the eight track down and
individual that scar the anonymous and
they were August doing was he had a
couple computers his a kid living in
Brooklyn and all announced our lower
west side and all he was doing was trade
information about it for somebody had
information here heaters traded but you
have to have an access to encode the
only way to asks the dark web as if you
know somebody gives your code to get
into the into the dark web for you have
to have a specific program is designed
to get into the web it takes time it's
not something that you're going to
overnight I'm you guys coming out you
guys can't like overnight pretty much
just go into a dark web unless nobody
what's up has a hub DQ on account like
the initial sites there's possible that
they need to shit on you just even tore
up in browser right right you know
minutes of work well use tor server
snowing don't all bottles of stuff
research
back which goes back to what I was
talking about careful will you
engagement because some of these people
on the vet on the web are absolutely
ruthless like your chest when you trust
you guys what's the whole point of that
you need Nexus can't search her
enthusiasm
exactly and I understand that but
there's some people that are just
absolutely i mean there are people that
just because you know how to access
those little those locations where you
have accidentally out that will track
you down and your dad needs to dr. you
to look to you though that is a dog dog
pound cake UK out your go on there you
go and any one of those everybody's
pretty much covered fishing fishing is
just a it's a rudimentary way to get in
from gather information through email
internet public the social websites and
now we get social network
when you put out there and people will
continue to do whatever they want to do
that social networking is one of the
most hacked websites out any one of
those social networks linkedin facebook
anyone tag no mess around but if you're
putting it out there if you're accessing
those websites pretty much hoping them
Dorf the to get half depending on what
information you click on there are
people that that's all they do they have
sustained patience there's another video
how many people have seen the Jeep get
hacked ok
useless
we're not going through this whole video
i just wanna get your look in more
addictions there is no word for what we
do it's not
it's not fun to have your to time suvs
breaks just as perfect front
okay all the time hold on oh that's what
I've learned from Charlie Miller and
Chris valasek pair of hackers who have
spent the last year developing the piece
of software that can wirelessly sabotage
this 20-14 jeep cherokee hasn't been
altered in any way there no devices
attached to it but like many thousands
of jeeps around the world it can be
remotely hacked over the internet
through a cellular connection to its
entertainment system they were allow
them to take over its steering its
transmission any of its brakes to
demonstrate that I'm going to access to
these crash-test dummy and driving on
the highway here in st. Louis well
charlie crist hijackings digital systems
from Charlie's house miles away you want
to tell me what they had plans but they
assured me that would be anything
life-threatening remembering andy no
matter what happens don't panic it's not
the first time in driven a car model is
being attacked by these two packers but
in 2013 anyone back seats in the laptops
were wired is the vehicle to afford
years back give me another sending the
same sort of attacks remotely and I have
no idea what they might do he's going as
fast as I am so so first we're going to
turn the fan on yeah those aren't van
ons and even notices
RL it something just turned on all the
fans and AC is the I didn't do that the
trick started small oh my god that was a
fixture of Charlie and Chris in
tracksuits that just appeared on the
backboard but that's they drove down the
interstate things started getting on
pleasant and very loud
if an ally
monkey
I'm gonna do it do it Kalenjin so we can
imagine right now I stomped on the gas
but the Jeep slowed to a crawl I turned
on the hazard lights but I was still
stuck in the right lane with no children
escape onto these panting he's head of
yours everything so loud this is better
I do beautiful work again
it won't work you guys good
alright so
when they hacked that car use the same
technology the u.s. use basically the
same kind of coats too hyper accelerate
the centrifuges at the new plan and
create some kind of air bubble system
they accessed a 2,000 pound vehicle and
this technology has been around probably
within the past three or five years
Korea has developed that seeing kind of
technology to remotely access control
systems in production facilities so
let's say you've got a facility that
Jenna that creates anhydrous ammonia you
have an individual has those codes I
wanted on a plan water on the dark web
who knows so they hacked so that
individual from a remote location
accesses the anhydrite ammonia process
thereby setting up a cloud or an event
which would include evacuation and our
death any on the amount of movies the
only way to stop in hives ammonia
anybody now mix it with water that's it
air is a factor you could take out a
good portion and Davenport before before
anything is actually fun if there was if
we had any higher learning facility
hearing same thing with protein
manufacture solar LNG and cheese awesome
love LNG
these guys leave there's several
facilities here in the United States who
have been packed broken into and they
still don't do anything about it either
several corporations your united states
that have been hacked the process is
hacked into same as this and still have
not done anything about it why budgetary
concerns budgetary issues they don't see
the value in investing in a bunch of
technology that would bring them to a
safe safer place
Plus few slides he's be aware that any
time you asks the internet you're open
yourself to up to an intrusion cognizant
of your environment make sure that there
is not someone over your shoulders
reviewing every single thing that you do
while you're sitting down having cup of
coffee at Starbucks people have done it
it's sit behind you they can hack your
system from police guys probably doing
it right now I'm in a minute about doing
that you oughta I did a thing for Fox
News Chicago about six years status
really you that was you doing my boss
that's awesome see and that was about
six six years ago six years yeah perfect
example right there what was the
scenario deduce you just SAT there just
look over while somebody's buying
something early we used a little bit we
set up a fake access point that arsenate
starbucks access point just basically
internal agency
onto the system's a while see exactly
what every single episode on condoms
yeah while we call far where you how far
away we were going with I mean we have
they were the corner and we have full
access to come all that laptops and wow
there you go right there hacktivist
security researcher that's awesome no
that's that's absolutely awesome
be vigilant moderator online counts
frequently take advantage of security
opportunities offered by your account
managers like secondary verification
were multiple to your verification like
IRA talked about a senior you're getting
a text message or an email to your
locate two separate email a verification
code use that all the time make sure you
monitor your house control yourselves
stop putting up so please stop putting
up what every other single can you do
regardless of whether or not you think
you're not in a pattern you are there's
some sort of pattern algorithm that
something to figure out that you are
doing by posting your pictures at
specific times at specific locations
you're setting yourself up for failure
great you want to share the news you
know what write a write a memo Freehan
diary back in back in when I was young
back in the old days we had Diaries we
didn't post everything on facebook
journals thank you very much journals
for more little of the speckle blog for
maven but yes absolutely stop posting
stop posted everywhere very singing
winky moment stay informed keep coming
keep coming to things like this keep
coming to to every single opportunity
that you have to go to a cyber
conference or every single opportunity
to have to go to a security conference
that you have access to every single
opportunity you have to go to just a
general forum meetings lepc so how many
people here with government la pcs a law
enforcement of the local emergency
planning committee thank you local
emergency planning committee if you work
with an industry or add an industry give
me about 10