I mutual friends we sure def con he
spoke at black hat he has a unique
experience and he's trying to spread
knowledge and awareness I guess as to
some of the policies and things that
have actually happened to him he is
joined us all the way from Atlanta
Georgia so without further ado we'll go
with my going through your mind thank
you very much I am when I speak to
technology medical people like to keep
the slides fast and snappy so we
actually like a hundred slides but I'll
go through them and and I don't you know
this is a if I could title is the way i
wanted to i call this is how they do it
and one thing i've learned there i've
been in medicine for 30 years I'm from
Detroit Michigan yes Troy Golu this
channel on I'm sorry we're playing very
Marilyn now that's how much I
Johnson such an awesome guys I'm just
misurkin and anyway I want to kind of
tear through my story to get to what the
bigger picture is because that's the
most important thing we have especially
with time in the morning we've seen such
tragedies my tragedy is a kind of a
small tried to be compared to what
really is going on the world but it's
more important to the shock that I found
about how the government operates in the
final analysis how is the solving any
problems and in my opinion clearly it's
not it's actually enabling and creating
more and so I learned what I wanted to
be effective to get people to message
letting yourself on fire saying I'm the
victim is pretty none effective it so to
be 15 minutes of roadkill and I don't
want to be 15 minutes of rovco so I
learned through the UCLA people the
neuroscience Department about storing
and the most important thing about story
is that it really neutralizes the
Opposition in the brain so when you
speak in story versus just add Union and
at you gives us 17 minutes of your
attention it tends to put you in the
shoes of the communicator and you go
along that journey together and as
Americans that's what happened so my
book is written like a novel and I will
get into the specifics that later
through the story of exactly how they do
and we know states will leave through
this and you'll see how the bigger
picture
Jonah has happened so this is about you
know my group vision of the Federal
Trade Commission and how they overthrow
ground thanks and in the fact is I just
got back from Sydney Australia by the
way this slides are really trying to
tell everyone that this is a world
problem interesting thing about this
internet and is that all our barriers
are really disappearing and when I spoke
in Sydney was two days after the Ashley
Madison breach and so I just said of the
crowd is you know what are you gonna do
is to the server in Toronto putting to
do and of course known in the room of
course I envision Madison now how many
people here are in a corporate setting
academia students in academia government
okay great so you'll see now what just
even this morning is you notice this
kind of ties everything this is this
this is like this is porous and all
these cyber security shoes just impact
all of us and it's like nothing we've
seen before and we've had so many
benefits of it the past 15 20 years and
now what we're seeing is the river here
holy cow we forgot about security and so
we're putting the mad ketchup so in like
we said earlier that the the biggest
weakness is the human in that your
weakest link and I just saw certificate
71 percent of all these breaches are in
small organizations and one thing I've
noticed about being a small businessman
d with 40 employees that are highly
intelligent confident because we
diagnose cancer is that we're very much
dismissed by the privacy community the
cybersecurity academia and government
because Burnett think wearing a
multinational or I'm going to over the
place and it's ironic because they're
going to echo chamber of their own
solving us and they're disregarding the
main source of where it is small it's
not me weaker insignificant until the
people that have power to do this
understand that you're still going to
have leaks going on they're going to be
spinning and spinning so and one of the
big things the government has done that
I've learned is that they're building
Wears many masks none more dangerous
than the masker virtue and everything
fell trade commission's job is to
protect consumers EPA's is to keep our
water clean the eris make sure we peered
at some time and isn't it wonderful on
that just put the bag of what's going on
and what I want to focus on is
accountability instead of marketing
labels on these agencies so we hope to
share your stumps with a knowledge of
those who are driving the ship but
that's scary when he was here this
morning we kept playing that sorry it'll
be time for luncheon and so obviously
myself I always joke i'm on the Titanic
saying iceberg iceberg everybody wants
me to shut up so until they get back to
just dancing and so it's important to
communicate to not go to and to
conspiracy because you have to give
people and I was one of them I only
became aware when the tree fell down on
me
I was buried in medicine making great
money doing wonderful work having the
best time of my life the tree fell down
on me and before the tree fell down on
me i would also kind of go like hey
don't ruin my buzz life is good here I
don't want to know about this and so we
have two more gentle when you wake
people up you can so hopefully I'm gonna
more gentle alright so now it's time for
Oaks we're going to go back to this I'm
gonna play this video just to pick you
guys up on real quick I'm on what who my
company as was and what happened to get
over the hump of my story get to the two
bigger macro picture
glad you're about 20 employees who
diagnosed yeah I'll do it right
we're about 20 employees we diagnosed
cancer figure ologist all around the
country tissue comes in you process it
physicians on staff diagnose it things
are going in quite well now the blue
thumb ring stand by how many tech guys
that somebody get my own browser gives
me the bar thoughts that have been
minimized
windows soonish Michael you although
after
we're about 20 employees we diagnose
cancer for urologist all around the
country tissue comes in process it
physicians on staff diagnose that things
are going to quite well the blue of the
phone rings it's a gentleman from
Pennsylvania cult I versa we had no idea
that that was his name was Robert Bob if
he said it was a CEO and that he had
found one of our files on a peer-to-peer
network we wanted to know how he got it
and I didn't trust this at all so I want
to make sure that he only community with
us in writing so we could have some sort
of a paper trail he emailed the file and
he was a-goin file from our billing
department nine thousand patients in
there with their patient name date of
birth social security number insurance
information everything we needed to know
to file insurance we ran up the building
department and we found the workstation
because it was a report that was clearly
off the managers workstation and we
found software there limewire that was
terrifying she used to t listen to music
the employee had no idea she was making
any type of patient information
vulnerable she was violating policy by
listening to music and in that folder
were eight hundred and some-odd music
files and this report and about 37 38
patient files but they were all redacted
out except for this one with nine
thousand and one another with one
patient we were just amazed how this
could happen and it was something seemed
to miss so we started asking questions
the first logical question is where did
you get and then how to get it and then
what's the IP address and as soon as we
got to the IP address there was a little
bit of a shakiness in the response and
they said well we're going to have to I
them via services agreement he we have
to get us a bit and see if it's possible
this is a red flag we called our lawyers
and immediately wanted to make sure the
patients were fine the first thing was
let's close them any vulnerabilities
that are there if they're there and look
to see if we can find the file anywhere
it's even spread anywhere we are a gas
of what's going on one of who has got
this it's not outside in cyberspace we
don't find it anywhere we turn our
attention back to mr. Bobak in his email
communications he's seductively trunk
act like the nice guy and warning us
that the spread could continue the
longer we waited to hire them to look
for it in the meantime we see no
evidence of its out there we don't know
who he is he won't tell us anything
unless we pay him so we told him to go
away and only call our lawyers which he
did in late two thousand and his lawyer
contacted our lawyers and said we're
going to turn this over the Federal
Trade Commission we found that
interesting and said fine go ahead turn
over the government a year and a half
later we got a call from the FTC
it was just as creepy feeling like we're
being watched
be sure to subscribe to my social media
outlets at LinkedIn Twitter Facebook and
YouTube also follow my blog at the del
inside the beltway com okay so that I
want people to actually see the medical
facility know what we're doing
diagnosing cancer and get that inside
all right now 2009 comes and all we're
doing is trying to get back to normal
and we just keep looking we can't find
it and every time we starts to fade away
we're looking fight us out there you try
and prove something you don't think that
happened there's no guidelines in Aspen
you know what it was to tell patients if
he notified while we didn't have any
legal application at a time and most of
our patients are elderly so high a guy
called he says he has it he's got it we
don't know how I won't tell us huevos so
in 2010 we get a letter from the FTC and
we have no right after that they put out
a press release it says widespread data
breaches uncovered by FTC probe fgc
wants are properly so sensitive consumer
data fear of your files economics here's
the key thing they've notified almost
100 asians about personal information
all this is is limewire peer-to-peer
everyone knows one more is probably
let's skip over that with this crap now
I'm trying to figure out what the heck's
going on because the FTC's calling me
and and they are enforcing this on the
FTC section 5 Act which I'll talk about
a sucker and what I'm learning is I'm I
learned that my lawyers say that that
there's been any proven problem there is
a fake any proven breach there's there
to be anything they can make up the
rules about what you've done wrong as
they go along and I don't I have to you
know what while I'm an extroverted sort
of you know
contran or ultimately I'm a science guy
and I want to like clip together the
pieces as to why and it's not fitting no
matter what I did so I have to figure
out how this happened and so what I tell
audiences look we're taught in school
then we have the executive branch
additional branch and we have the
legislative branch which founding
fathers splitting two because it will be
very difficult to regulate and to bring
in legislature so they snap the
legislate button to just make that
mountain steeper which is also why it's
so hard to solve mistakes in but 100
years ago Congress created what we
consider fourth branch of government
which is the government agency an
administrative process and all our
freedoms and separation of powers are
here so that they can oppress us and
they can't do things now I think the
Congress of 100 years ago didn't
understand what they were creating
what's morphed into so even today as I
spent so much time in Congress now even
congressmen and their staff don't
understand this there is so little
communication between the government you
really learn from 911 and don't think
they fixed that since not and what
happens is wooden teeth this
administrative process here is where
they have their own policing they have
they sell police they have their own
courts they have they're in this trailer
process and Congress has said you can't
fight to the judicial system until
you're through it and that turns into a
fist so the separation of powers happens
and this is why you see things like the
FCC making rules and refusing to tell
Congress what's in them until they pass
and the tail starts wagging the dog now
this creates a petri dish for corruption
because these are not Democrats or
Republicans
bureaucrats and they come typically now
which is different than a years ago they
come straight out of law school and
they're regulating medicine and
technology without knowledge so the bull
in the china shop they don't know what
they're smashing but they have a load of
power and bureaucrats have scant
experience world they regulate and they
have TC lawyers with us or more
concerned with cooperation and truth so
right off the bat we have higher the
lawyers and spent a ton of mine the
second you call the lawyers dick dick
dick dick and so and so let's go through
what the FTC is I'm trying to wrap my
head around them so the FTC's official
agenda is to protect the consumer from
in fairness and deception an act or
practice is unfair and let me tell you
something this next three points or what
billions of dollars are spent because of
this causes or is likely to cause
substantial injury to consumers it
cannot be reasonably avoided by
consumers and is not outweighed by
countervailing benefits to consumers
border competition now because the way
Congress has create the agencies who
makes a decision on what is likely to
cause what is substantial what is
reasonably avoided what is a
countervailing benefit they decide so
you have judge jury prosecutor deciding
and you've got this perfect setup where
the only way to get through it is crawl
through millions of dollars in several
years a typical target is corporations
so you've got law firm departments that
just sign a check and go and this all
used to be fine until we starting the
cybersecurity and medicine now that the
government has reached into those levels
you just got these people that don't
know what they're doing that you have
corporations that just roll leave
because they bet
sign away and so the noose tightens and
we're this tipping point where their
effectiveness in fixing the problems of
Technology and submarine warfare and
medicine are obviously not working now
one of the commissioners who just
resigned a month ago was only in there
for two years what he said was he put
this talk out this article and there's a
promise section time when they sue you
these are foaming soap so far okay no
flesh and blood sugar so when they go
after you and they investigate you and
most people roll over and they decided
ticket administrative process you're in
the record so I'm an administrative
court and the judge is at FTC gov and if
they lose the judge rules against the
FTC the last 30 years 20 years number
seven time they were a little staff
which means if the judge says staff
you're wrong the commissioners can
overturn just by boat and every single
time they have and half the time when
they go to appeal the FTC loses so there
is this gigantic bias that makes every
law firm tell their client the con is on
the system's rigged right to check move
on the problem is when you do that to a
medical facility that's diagnosing
cancer you're just ruining the
reputation and right now it's not as
visible as four years ago human this is
2008-2010 tried remember me nine
thousand patients now that's like you
mean not 99 in 2015 alone we've had 90
1.3 million healthcare records briefs
United States and we have nine thousand
that we later proved never got out and
they're freaking out and so this is the
type of behavior is so incredible the
power so centralized that you have to
everyone just rolls and so then you have
the gas lighting because then they're
still hitting
they have become a sort of PhD and all
this stuff now because it so happened to
me but think hit Congress they hit the
media they hit every law school and they
say we're doing this wonderful things
we're saving all the stuff we've got a
broad power Congress has given us for
our power went on the inside they want
to be afraid I was in a unique situation
I'm not judging all these lawyers from
these other companies that just rolled
and stuff but the problem was that I was
in a lose-lose because I ran a medical
facility so Jessica just acknowledging
that we had this potential maybe make
every physician frigga all you have to
do is doubt and you've got a system of
people that are moving a hundred miles
an hour in medicine they don't just they
don't need any of more scoops on their
ice cream phone so they also what the
what the government wants you to do and
they act like this is nothing is they
want to sign a consent decree it's a
really key negotiated peace understand
and this isn't just the FTC against
consent decrees anymore the contract and
a contract agreement can be with solar
cell encourage you at a government this
is just a fancy name for you sign an
agreement that says will admit no
wrongdoing and will allow you to in by
annual audit us at our expense with an
outside consulting firm for 20 years
what they don't tell you is that then
they're going to put out a press release
that makes everyone think you're too
cold fight busted come on folks if it
doesn't fit a tweet we don't pay
attention so everyone's going to thank
my company 11d has beds data security
practice and I have a really small
company that keeps the tail of multi
billion dollars labs and so they're
going to run around putting fear
uncertainty and doubt and if and so we
were in this unique situation that we
were dead no matter what we want to lose
lose if I sign the consent decree was a
bad
if I didn't so I really have nothing to
lose so I'm not a big I mean I have a
big principal guy but I didn't have I
had a very unique decision to make and
so I knew that sign the consent decree
would not be okay because everyone's
going to use that against now I will
tell you that as background from Detroit
both my parents were police officers
when they met in Detroit and so my whole
life was has been judges and police
officers and the lawyers so i think i
had an advanced jaded opinion of the
federal investigators my dad so this is
nothing more than shakedown this is
nothing more than just go along to get
along it's going to be terrible that's
what your own what you're going to say
forget justice for good due process come
on grow up but this is all secret law
because what they were telling us what I
was aghast at is they don't have to have
roles or standards or regulations
section 5 can be that broad they in
medicine this is unbelievable because in
medicine we work collaboratively we're
regulated like crazy we were inspected
top to bottom every man you everything
I'm every machine every every test is
documented back into hard drives and
applications and we are we're just
amazed that that they're acting so
punitive Lee Nick as they go along
because they're big excuse in the
government is that well cybersecurity is
happening so fast if you write a
standard rule
we'll never be able to get the bad guys
and you guys want us to get the bad guys
don't you and for my experience in
medicine that's a big crunk because
there's nothing more that changes faster
than medicine and we do not regulate
peanut early but I decision to do if I
should fight or flight so the common
burden is what I talked about earlier
these regulators aiming in the wrong
direction and their collaborative vs.
punitive regulatory practices and the
fact they just wanted to go on get
longer and if you don't they're going to
bury you in procedures in day time and
they're nuns with guns and they're doing
the Lord's work and if floor doesn't
work that good other means but they try
to keep friendly and the whole thing you
go get through your lawyers which
surprised me nuts because don't get him
in don't get it man I was always like
why why not get I've had this is the
most absurd thing i've seen my other
what I'm going to do that they're
already planning on doing because when
they go knock on your door folks they
think you're busted already they don't
show up unless they've done a ton of
homework already then the beginning of
the process with the government is not
high but we got you that's int so I
start doing my own home because this
just stinks to my own lawyers are like
conspiracy theorists I'm like oh no no
not but so and I find out that Homeland
Security has written a 24 and a half
million dollar grant to Dartmouth to
research cyber security breaches and
links within the government setting and
health care and Dartmouth hires remember
babak up there in the video you know
where he was doing that was his
congressional testimony babak is working
with Dartmouth and bombings put out a
press release that they're working with
Dartmouth and through this grant they
have their monitoring for a half million
work stations worldwide and they just
for this study alone they have
downloaded 14 million files none of them
music military thought
tax returns medical financial and I'm
thinking I have cracked the code they're
all in this together and I see all this
congressional testimony from 2007 and
2009 from the house oversight in the
Commerce Department I mean that the
Commerce Committee and there's babak
sitting there with who's an advisory
board General Wesley Clark Howard
shouldn't we've got the FTC sitting
there I'm like well there's no
conspiracy here I got it right here in
black right under hope this is great
I've cracked the case and they're like
and these people are in bed together and
they I want anyone to know and I call my
lawyers know life doesn't matter all
that matters is you had an employee but
why we're in a workstation for
authorization and even if nothing got
out they can say what they want because
they can make it up as I go along so I
can't get an answer what we do wrong or
what we do right from the government
that's coming at me side swiping the
company by the way and so I called then
right at sands he's the only I could
find it that actually criticized the
Federal Trade Commission of them in the
way they're dealing with cybersecurity
regulation and I paid they have him come
in he's a technology lawyer out of Texas
he went to Georgetown Law he lives to
everything basically saying you know
your effective of a crime and there's no
breach here and the reason there's no
breach here is because it never got out
it got out to a government agency it's
fully under control the legal to the
definition of reach is that it's out of
control this now in control there's no
bridge and sure enough we start looking
at the FTC's communications and then
first nor the press release a hundred
companies all those bridges said that
would breach just disappear
but the thing is the public knows enough
just be dangerous and so even when you
don't say breach that's the layman's
term and we're small business and I said
it earlier 71 percent of these things
are coming from small business doesn't
we're totally being ignored and the
issue isn't that we're small dishes okay
by yourself probably not include where
tech and then the FTC loves to let you
know for the discussions that there's
these little flash bulb moments that
they say things like they're having a
good time and they say you know we can
reopen our investigation anytime we can
always come back to it and you have the
sense of Gillian watch forever and I'm
just I'm not afraid of these people
which really pissed them off but I knew
if I was going to take them on that they
have the long slog of justice mountain
and the long slog of justice mountain is
the number one negoti to all of our
agency it's like yeah yeah yeah you're
innocent this isn't in Criminal
Investigations you don't have the right
you think you have and will just drain
your driving and that's what your
lawyers were telling you on your side so
we weed so they sue us I'm sorry they
insist they start threatening us and I
what I put up here in words I like to
use the courts words because I figure if
I say it's doubted but the judge says
it's true and we they said they were
going to be wouldn't sign a consent
decree which was a humorous story in
itself because I'm telling these people
never heard the word no and they were so
enamored that this feisty little boy
from
lands a small company would have the
nerve to take a son I mean they were
they were hammered by it and that they
said we're going to sue tomorrow or in
this way they happen they didn't do it
next thing you know we're in court
because they're they're filing
investigate demands of me and my vice
president we start fighting it we at the
Eleventh Circuit saying do they have the
right to come in and the judge starts
saying right off the bat no one's
litigated your authority this air do so
but you've done a lot of it that's
because all these movies are rolling
over and the noose is tightening around
everyone's neck because an ox playing my
later so and the FTC thinks that their
law of notification due process is
speaking on panels and workshops and
publishing diamonds on her website they
think that's long but the judge happy as
much as he beat them up in court he says
he can't he has to enforce us to sit
down and be interviewed again now keep
in mind this is after two years of being
investigated over and over non-coloured
thousand dollars we've installed
websense which didn't exist for
companies under 250 they had to
customize a package we had spent all
this money not knowing what to do so he
went as far up as we could because what
are you doing they want a what to do you
just over shoot as much as you can
overshoot and sure enough the judge
Huff's and puffs but says I can do any
kind why can't I do anything because
Congress makes the rules and this is
Congress's rules and what this means
folks is that that government can come
in and use in any way anyhow so I
decided I've got to tell you so and I
and I want to actually kind of probe
those it is and so I read about any and
I can't take how it works of other might
have ever imagined because I message is
that this is persecution through process
and it's such a tipping point they were
paying the price unlike maybe twenty
years ago that these are such severe
attacks on our liberty and our commerce
because that's what they cyber security
lasers are so China is doing arrested
they're sucking in our military guess
and commerce and yet you have these
bureaucrats are just enough power play
so they can rule the internet so
litigation strategy they have to see
when they do persecution due process is
they can choose to just go option one
straight to federal court which is I'm
going over the wyndham case that's been
out of you but there's two major cyber
security cases in the United States
right now my case lab md versus FTC and
Windham Williams this huge company they
had a load of patients lost bad media
they have 10 million out of damages they
go straight to federal court when they
don't have such a strong case where they
just want to drain you dry they go here
and the thing is they get to make their
own rules it's not like federal court
Congress says you have your importance
you get to make criminals and then
Congress has to approve them and let me
tell about Congress approving oh yeah i
mean i've been there now to know that's
not what our some shins are they're too
busy they're spread to them there's too
much noise so they drank you'd are
financially they make down rules they
allow here saying the attorneys are
privileged to all their investigators
are attorneys so when you ask what you
did wrong or would have an investigation
like you would when a trial
happen they don't have to tell you it's
so bizarre even though lawyers and have
experience in this court in this type of
a litigation just scratch or headland
can't believe it they want two numbers
on the time as you saw they assassinate
your reputation because they say they
don't participate in media commentary
but they do when they file case and
that's why they're so stinging when they
follow psychological warfare because I
own the company I'm gonna go down the
ship if you work for me and you see this
is going on when I say I didn't do it
who believes that the press is
cooperative because we have to save the
world of the government's not saving the
world will goods government and we have
a press right now it I don't to check
the press directly except to say there's
no money in newspapers anymore for
Investigative Journalism there just
isn't there are no investigative
journalism is a good local newspaper
very rare so they're they're aggregators
what comes out of the Sienna bottling
and those people are either afraid to
tick off people with power or they're in
bed so it's very hard and so that this
all damages operations so that's a long
version of minus my employees are going
to fund and what I learned then what you
have to see really doing here because
congress hasn't made law and the MTC
doesn't want to go to Congress they
don't want to pay the process that these
are these agencies are now on by hundred
years old and they are their own
governments on their own and they know
they get the concurrent consent agree
you go precedent by having a glossary of
them you avoid the courts because I'm in
rolls over you miss leaves John Wall
Congress and then you play hero to the
press and the common law becomes the law
yet the 50 biggest state of recent
health care now one resulting at UC
action wise advocate
Lancer easy to slaughter big companies
around so we're tiny and we don't really
matter we are necessary unfortunate
what's that word on carnage collateral
damage so then they sue us now what
happens is type versus oozes for
defamation because of the book came out
32 f I got sick I know it's going to get
sued that's in those continents so we go
see it by the FTC now it is juicy the
word breach alleges exposure and
vulnerability because you know there's
not a computer in the country or the
world that doesn't have a vulnerability
or a risk of exposure what you get down
to is the biggest orgy of wordsmithing
you've ever seen in your life we're
upside down is right side up and these
people say stuff with a straight face
use that there in shaker and then there
are PR machine hits again and this is
bullying and I mean it's just
entertaining how cocky they are I mean
these people really think they're saving
the world but I'm like based on what
they are just in that Bell weather echo
chamber of DC the stereo hospital road
right to the right to the agency that
there for 20 years once and they use
every penny here they justify us
behavior because they're utterly
convinced or saving the world they know
and there's no shortage of people think
you're guilty because the government
uses you and so I was knowing this and I
was spending about eight months was
write the book in DC and there's a
couple rules when your call on Congress
the number one rule is never act like
you're
or ask them for help or to save you
because that's the fastest way to get
injuries as they run the other way they
just don't so I didn't ask I want you to
let you know how the agency's gonna
start a conversation I didn't put any
one spot I didn't make anyone
uncomfortable I didn't like I was in a
panic you know it wasn't a panic and my
house on fire and everyone but you get
the sound working one to work well cause
of action I met through that experience
is a non-profit law firm that does pro
bono work on government Malfi and so so
when they filed the lawsuit put the
press release out I mean I was in
Orlando speaking I got a phone call from
The Associated Press thing give me
comments but you're gonna suit that's
what I finally going to sue they put
this huge press release up first it's
just they want to show I mean if you
dare challenge them they want everyone
else to see what they do who dares
challenge this is not about my case this
is about a message to everybody else
like heads on a spike from the earlier
professor that's what this is this is
cybersecurity head on spikes and so in
the fall of two thousand thirteen now we
have shocked and all day 40 subpoenas
they went after physicians vendors
nurses are text my assistant people that
love the IT department six years before
they're just saying this huge message
and they're getting nothing nothing and
when we interviewed when we had our
first deposition it was a babak and he
said he said well there's there's for IP
addresses out there I just get my slides
and hold on i go back so when when I'm
the court the FTC says to the judge so
this is our now they've sued us we're
actually in court it's a scheduling
conference which is when you leave just
discussed on the judge assam have you
let people know and the FTC says there's
nothing out there for going to look to
and so you there nothing there's nothing
to know what to do but they're closed i
busted and then we
pose ty versa and they said they found
for additional IP addresses now this is
important because then the winner goes
on in lab md closes in a sudden that we
had my vp took off my lawyer it's just
it's a mess I mean a lot of things
happened where I just if Bobby people
got really terrified because it was
terrifying I mean when you work in
medicine you diagnose cancer and we had
everything we had we wit web since we
had firewalls weekend her found anything
out there it wasn't out there who they
couldn't find a bridge they couldn't
find the victim they would have told us
they spent years going after it's disco
so meant but suddenly April 14 I'm
having dinner and the Cummings been
closed for three months now and I got a
call from Rick Wallace who I don't know
who he is is and he was nervous and a
broken soul and he was a whistleblower
he worked for typer so he worked
directly for babak he's the one who
would go into work stations he told me I
go into work stations I take files at
the border of my boss and I changed the
metadata and I lie to everybody about
where they find it there your stuffs
never been outside your work station
it's never been anywhere oh and by the
way remember when Barack Obama was first
inaugurated and they found his marine
one bless marine one plans and arraigned
workstations and remember that story is
all over there's that's a line we found
that in a consultants workstation in
Virginia and then babak said change IP
address so what is Baba doing he is
creating a fog crisis finding every one
thing that peered appears is huge thing
and he's a sick
come do how many charges you so he's
Fanning a false crisis so he can be the
profit-making solution and who's he
duping the House of Representatives the
Federal Trade Commission NBC is this
believable it's unbelievable what the
hell's going on so I to thank goodness i
had no congress by this point because
that got generalizes attention then they
went crazy and then as i was just
supposed to start book tour what am i
doing i'm in congressional
investigations they can't tell anyone
what's going on which is actually kind
of fun and we bring everyone or just
uncovering so much stuff that i still
can't talk about but it's possible be a
great moving one day and so you have
tiresome bostik so this is the scary
thing about about the front of trade
commission or any regulator that doesn't
have intellectual training academic
training and what they're trying to
manage this is what you're up against
folks and this is why people go crazy
with regulators diverse is up there
saying we have 300 to 1.8 billion
searches a day we do we we minor 4.5
workstations just this one study we
download 30 million files and then the
FTC says we want that we want every file
that has over a hundred people and
consumers and every human beings
consider consumer because we are going
to go after what company is not got the
best time security practices to protect
these consumers their opinion is if you
get breached is your fault you are not
tight enough in your cyber security and
you're going to go down so how many
files do you think ty versa but these
kind of numbers turned over the FTC
that's a good one 86 now you think
there's something wrong with this this
is a matter that they're upset with me
they just kept on trucking and then ty
vs said well we don't want to give to
you because our clients going to think
that would work and we're awful and they
said okay well why don't you create a
false company so the photo trade
commission assists the at the tiber set
by creating company called the privacy
Institute and they move the file some
privacy Institute they subpoena the
privacy so no one knows it's what I
versa and they get the files that way
and that's the almost a hundred
companies over that in the beginning do
they verify the evidence ooh gonna take
their word for it absolutely did they
know guru ball says so they're
gaslighting in talking about her that's
going on and so now we go back to court
because we are screaming that they've
destroyed the company and that is the
one little tiny crack where you can go
in and have a core telling to stop but
the court basically says well you're a
dead so too late but these are the
comments there and I'm going to for the
type of time I just get a couple of main
ones here the agency's acting mean
spirit do you see how hard it is to get
an outside court netword you're like
this is five years after the first call
from Ty versa over three years after the
FTC started and we see are just
scratching barely at the federal justice
system mean-spirited the FTC is going to
business a minor investigating they've
said it within their authority but
there's no amendment to section five
asbestos asbestos specifically allow it
which means agencies do what they want
regards what Congress says in the
apologize later and again the dupe
holidays takes years and millions so
there's now
apologies there's very few challenges
this all great if they are effective you
have no information how those ducks were
obtained that's correct I don't how I
got to say that count in your agency to
wait until months before hearing you're
not taking any interview in effort to
interview the people who claim heavy
underlying documents that strikes me is
unconscionable I mean you sure heard the
judge he was just smacking them all over
the place here at people never see one
for you with every see stand-up who are
you clear hey just it's all drama just
being the heck out of them you don't
know where they came from holy cow no
morning can't get herself you know this
coming willing to lay along pretty close
we're investing we were regulator rear
we have been cleared it's it's it's
insane spike it we're in kangaroo court
still and the judge can't it came to
court you love with circuit rules after
all that temper tantrum is rolling as
can intervene yet not right to intervene
because Congress says the Administrative
Procedure has over which I say is as
soon as we're done with your funeral
would be to the hospital and the first
questions when the sure that the court
started the administrative court started
now was where's the money where's the
money where's the money does the end is
typers to make any money no he run it if
she says no they don't and that turned
out to be nothing that's not true so now
we're the trial now I'm on trial Mayo
2014 in the FTC sprout and he says hang
on a second
you don't center whose evidence of harm
that's correct yet we're still guilty
excessiveness is true do planners
evidence of penetration what happen
under sentence then we we are fighting
to at demand what standards they use to
halt ascent and the court has to rule on
the FTC rules and the FTC is allowed to
make their rules because Congress says
they can and the FTC's rulers are that
respondent that's the defendant may not
discover legal standards FCC is used and
I quote this because who's going to
believe me when I say that I have to
give you the porter is so unbelievable
and so then we bring in the
whistleblower now they rested their
cases is beautiful they had rested their
kids had no idea what was coming out we
had Richard on the witness list before
we knew he was so we had the result of
witnesses pretty heavy stuff he comes in
he pleads the fifth and then they come
in in and his lawyer comes in with a
with a note from Congress but I versa is
under congressional investigation now
this is when I start really learning how
things really work Suzanne saxman
grounds lawyer she was working for Lois
Lerner she would over house oversight
Jay Rockefeller Democrat best friend of
fabric motion Elijah Cummings now I will
tell you this is the moment this got
politicized red eye blue eye I did not
want to get stuck in back and forth
Republican Democrat but and I voted for
both parties but the facts are that we
had read coming into Congress with hard
drives and forensic evidence and because
of the animosity between the Republicans
perhaps Democrats would not need him
would not look at the hard drives as a
matter of fact no they would not look at
it they try to smear Suzanne saxman
grooms is Ryan a show she is a master of
sitting on stuff Annette letting it out
Rockefeller sticks his nose and sends a
letter to the press the data from
supposed to testify before Congress
saying Congress is intervening they
shouldn't be doing any of this this is
in the press buys it because you got
these second third tier young kids that
don't have time to research anything
they're there in overdrive and Elijah
Cummings is going along to get along
because anything that harms the carpets
all wonderful and great brand is got to
be covered up which is why my next book
is called the politics of crime this
shocked the heck out me it's a shocking
I couldn't believe it that they would do
this and they threw out the reading
order to the press releases and they
work on they don't look so you won't
find now what they didn't know was that
that they didn't know the judge had
stayed the case until Congress could get
a shot to do this and all we wanted to
do was get ribbed criminal immunity and
we needed criminal meeting from
oversight with two-thirds of the vote
that's for Democrats we couldn't even
get a vote to come on but what we didn't
know was that the Justice Department was
waiting and if Congress failed by
October the just runs most of it this is
the difference between how they usually
contain everything in the IRS Joseph we
had a backdoor they'd know about and so
anti versa is being hauled into Congress
by the Oversight Committee and he's like
I don't know what's going on and yet
when he goes at FTC's like oh no oh Rick
Wallace he's a terrible guy drinks like
crazy he's been arrested for domestic
abuse he's terrible oh by the way we'd
those for to be made up but we found
three more we found three more it was
out there and and so they say they say
close to crime dog because FTC's in big
trouble if they are really sitting they
have no choice but to double down
because they relied on a petty thief of
heading cyber p to go after 86 companies
so we filed Freedom of Information Act
information we find out that the head of
the FTC different mirrors and Senator
Rockefeller we have been chatting
through their staff member so it's not
direct about the hearing and how to
screw that up that's why suddenly a
senator gets involved in House of
Representatives that's kind of new and
unusual gosh what is such a big deal
that they go to such efforts to close
out the stuff and they're caught
red-handed so all they do is whistle has
the greater because you remember earlier
I talked about the silence so we're
using silence and corruption is the use
of position of trust for dishonest gain
and then the Justice Department comes in
and there's Rick the county that has an
alcohol problem getting his FB i-- award
we found out tears before from the head
of a peon so there's a problem kind of
discrediting him
and then the congressional report comes
out and so so this is what is the
highlights of what Darrell eyes was
reporting him by the way this report was
finished and because of I'll skip over
the slow bills of Justice distant him
until may of this year Rick couldn't
testify till May of this year and so
aissa while still no longer the head of
the committee had held as a portal it
was done and because everyone's afraid
of no matter how much when they smear
you in politics everyone's afraid of
mine including Iceland everyone was
holding on it until he testified in a
great way and he did testifying a great
way because he's brilliant so when you
just get out of the emotional and got
the fear get in fact he is completely
pro so tibor recession I'm often
ethically and sometimes unlawfully 100
Direction volvic provided intensely
falsin with the government probably
provided false testimony about
fabricated documents the US government
Nets changing IP addresses according the
whistleblower divers have fabricated
rampy address of the marine one did so
to receive press attention for the
company found that tibor sustains could
not be substantiated because now
someone's actually trying to
substantiate when is it none scary three
congressional hearings and seven and
nine all those people think watch those
hearings here just shake your head like
wow this is the most horrific story
which I can't go to into but basically I
can't talk about all the stuff that's
gone on that I found out through the
whistleblower but I did not find this
out from there was
I found this out coincidentally my
insurance carrier also defended an AIDS
clinic in Chicago and this guy came in
and testified next to me right here and
hey tibor's had called up the open door
clinic in Chicago and said you know
we've got your patients we found a
peer-to-peer it's out there would you
like to hire is force in five an hour
yayaya exactly like us and they said no
because they don't have peered her
somewhere anywhere soon enough to
possibly happen and so what he did is
there is a a lawyer work with the
company filed a class-action lawsuit
that eventually settled for substantial
amount of mine he be so heat the AIDS
patients are given to a law firm and
that's the first time they found out
their permission was that one lawyer
calling them informing them and asking
them to participate in a class section 1
C so then the clinic is always terrible
press and how low will you go I thought
for sure that would light up the media I
thought for sure that would have the
Democrats on oversight going nuts and
that's what flipping out it didn't he
flew up he testified right after me
about all this stuff the private
Institute which we talked about earlier
they knew because they were in bed with
the FTC they knew about enforcement
actions wife walks one of them and so
when you're a pussy do you're trying to
figure out how to get the bag off your
head you kiss the butt of those the
government life so they hire tempers
them because they thought the government
like to episode and yet there's no
evidence from any of this stuff and the
FTC now does this because that's all
they've got but they have a lot of
friends because this is a culture of
fear because I'm not the head of a team
so I am the ultimate pain in their tail
now the screaming silence of this
we're close to time up here each other
so not everybody but what I've learned
through this experience at cronies
academia privacy experts media big law
firms any of those in that world in it
for the money don't want this out
because we have been your aesthetic
feeding off a false trauma so it's fair
and certainty in depth and people that
make a fortune office you know just kind
of why this is not 0 this is not a
one-off this is law that impacts
everybody and this is my bigger picture
is that that this is exactly that this
isn't gonna be effective I'm gonna let
me get back to the order my son so the
FTC secretary real agenda is to be the
number one self-appointed regulator they
span their jurisdiction into medicine
technology financed by building a
portfolio of consent decree so they
bully you down you don't get the court
that turns into common law they avoid
the courts they nail you persecuting new
process usually corporations role
because the smart thing signage jack
forget reality forget truth and justice
move on and get smart with decision they
expect chicken littles at Congress in
the media the sky is falling we're all
good dies there's years terrible the
problem right now is how it helped on
anything target 91 my health patients
just this year you know there are
confidence that start to show the
evidence of their results so my basic
point is bureaucrats are not going to
solve this problems people that are in
this room there no songs problem like
the people that created all the software
at RS day we had 165 cybersecurity
startups on the floor 45 from Israel
that's what's going to stop this problem
the garbage is going to punish it away
in the meantime so they can keep their
jobs and yet we have to figure out the
meantime what we're supposed to do and
they intentionally don't want specified
which is inflating the market as we all
shoot
place so the keys not the regulators and
so I that's really the key shoes in this
room but I just want everyone to
understand this isn't just how the FTC
works is how the FCC works the SCC works
and they're just split in the government
the FBI the NSA CIA hate this because
they know they need to work within
citizens to get to the bigger picture
and yet they're more law enforcement
training the lawyer train crowd what
some people sarcastically say the people
that couldn't cut it and go to the
Justice Department just want to focus on
their power and so you also see right
now the fight between DHS FTC and FCC
for cybersecurity authority so that's
enough for now I'm going all time the
book is being sold half off for the
super ten bucks and I look forward to
talking as their honest questions there
to thank you