I'm looking your laptop like it's my
slides welcome so welcome to navik 57
here in Orlando we are in our very first
Monday to wednesday program meeting I'm
Dave Temkin I'm the chair of the program
committee the rest of the program
committee a decent amount of them are
represented in this room today are on
this I chart on the screen right now
these guys put together the massive
amounts of content that we're going to
throw at you over the next three days we
have we had 41 program submissions of
those 41-26 were accepted I'll borrow a
term from Dave Meyer which is that this
meeting is has a very short runway we
tend to lose weeks around the Christmas
and New Year's holidays where people
just don't submit things for review and
then they either submit them at the last
second or we or we have to go chase
after them and so it's a testament to
the quality of the content that we still
got that many submissions and we're able
to fill with with more content than we
had more content than we could accept so
just a few reminders there's a break
area where some of you had lunch outside
earlier that is where the brakes will be
for the rest of the meeting for coffee
and such the survey I just wanted to
call that out as we always do one thing
I just wanted to make sure we say is
that if you really like something please
tell us about that also don't just
complain we're happy to hear your
complaints and everyone in the room is
certainly as good as I am at complaining
when necessary but if if you guys could
tell us when you really like something
that helps us figure out how to improve
the program going forward instead of
just assuming that everything is neutral
and you guys are just trudging through
it
reminder the Aaron helpdesk is out front
I used them earlier today incredibly
efficient and oh he's very helpful the
other thing we wanted to call out is
that tomorrow during the tracks lot
which is really for 30 p.m. after the
afternoon break there is an errand
public policy consultation and this is a
track we're going to include going
forward here at nana as Aaron and nanog
both evolved Aaron really wants to hear
from the operator community you are
relevant to them in many different ways
everyone in this room one way or another
has influence on Aaron whether you're a
voter whether you remember well you know
whatever that may be this is a way to be
heard by Aaron and there will be people
in that track who may not normally be at
nanog who represent Aaron and so we hope
that those who feel strongly about their
relationship with Aaron will attend
wanted to call out real quick the monday
to wednesday program i know a lot of you
had travel issues with it we're sticking
with this we want to see how this works
out for this meeting will likely make
some changes based on feedback and that
goes back to the surveys just to find
efficiencies for those of you who are
asking about YP rooms on wednesday
afternoon there's a good reason for it
that allows peering related content to
follow that we've regularly had an issue
with for example the GPF meetings
colliding with nana sponsored socials
and in order to avoid that happening
going forward we thought best to to put
that by itself to allow the GPF the
people who run gpf to have their own
time after nanog we will attempt to
publish the skeleton for the agenda as
early as we possibly hem we will
probably do it a little bit late after
this meeting just as we we debrief and
regroup and figure out what did work and
what didn't work for this monday
wednesday program but once we've done
that
will will certainly update the schedule
discussion guidelines they're posted on
all of the microphones basically speak
to our speakers like you would want to
be spoken to if you were up here you
know yield the floor if someone else is
waiting in line to ask a question you've
already asked yours general rules
they're on I believe they're on the
website as well and they're on each
microphone summarized not lab sorry keep
throwing things at you but now glad
we've transitioned the nog lab from
being a responsibility of the
development committee to a
responsibility of the program committee
our goal here is to demonstrate new
technologies and ways of using existing
technologies and new ways in an
excellent manner right so what you'll
see in nob lab today and you'll see in a
demo here shortly or a discussion about
the demo shortly is we're showing you
what's new in the world of
software-defined networking and the NOC
lab is right around the corner from from
where the break area is if any of you
attended the tutorials in the morning
over on the side it's directly across
the hall we invite you over there to
check it out and get your hands a little
bit dirty with it and with that I'd like
to hand it over to our executive
director Betty Burke good afternoon
everyone
it's new i'm saying good afternoon
generally I have to say good morning so
this is new having our opening in the
afternoon I hope everyone enjoyed the
tutorials this morning we had overflow
it was great attendance on behalf of the
Board of Directors see what I'm supposed
to say i do want to welcome all of you
to me on our 57 here in Orlando it's
nice it's warm back home for me in
Michigan it's 18 degrees I'm really
happy and we couldn't do this we the
board of directors on behalf of all of
you could not do nanog without the
support of our committees and our
volunteers we can call them out by name
but their names are on the webpage and
they have these little ribbons so that
you can find them and know which part of
nanog they represent being the
communications committee the development
committee as dave has eluded the program
committee they really are important to
giving you a great experience and we
hope you make the most of that we have
this evening at the close of our program
a community meeting it's an opportunity
for the board of directors to just share
with everyone in our whole community our
large community a little background and
update about what's going on with nana
what are we here for what are we doing
on your behalf and sort of where we're
going into the future a little bit and
give you all an opportunity to speak
with us about in 45 minutes 30 minutes
this afternoon and we welcome you all to
come back for the community meeting or
stay for it tomorrow morning those of
you who are here who are also members of
nanog are welcome to join the board
tomorrow a reminder that we're having
breakfast with you again just an
opportunity for those who are really
interested in being on board with voting
in being part of owning nanog and
setting direction we're having a
breakfast just to get your input as well
and later this afternoon you'll get some
update about the social activities that
are being planned for you here while
you're in orlando i welcome you again to
thank the sponsor
that are going out of their way to
provide the funding for the social that
doesn't come from our nan our budget
your registration fees those socials are
a really important part of why you are
all here why we're here and I hope you
take advantage of them again we always
say thank you to our sponsors you'll see
a lot of thank yous and some logo
splashed around not too much because one
of the things that we stay true to at
nanog is to not create a trade show at
nanog that said we all know that doing a
meeting of this kind or running an
activity of this kind owned by the
community takes money and we could not
do it without the very very thoughtful
and grateful contribution from the folks
listed on this screen those that step
forward and we're willing to be our
hosts and work with me for three four
five months in putting this meeting
together and our connectivity provider
who are actually willing to provide at
their expense great bandwidth for this
meeting our premium sponsors and our
infrastructure sponsors just we couldn't
do it without them and please as you see
those here attending the meeting
representing those companies extend your
appreciation as well and with that said
that's my brief introduction my
challenge to you is to enjoy this great
content and socialize in the hallway and
I am going to introduce and say thank
you so much to the gentleman setting to
my right Josh no harm
thanks guys I've had the honor of
hosting nanog now five times my previous
company is my first time was Cyrus one
usually I would do the obligatory
network diagram but I'm not in the
network host anymore I would do the the
wiring craziness and all the hard
problems we had but I didn't have to do
that that was his problem so and all the
times i've hosted nanog I've never taken
the opportunity to do a marketing slide
deck which is my first time so you guys
are you have to bear with me because I
can do it you're gonna have to eat it so
so Cyrus one Cyrus one is a very large
data center provider that just recently
spun out on the Nasdaq couple weeks ago
which was awesome got to ring the bell
which is a cool experience we have over
a million square feet of raised floor
space several million square feet of
data center space around the country
really giant facilities lots of power
lots of cooling and primarily focused
Texas Phoenix and Ohio with lots of
expansions coming this is our Phoenix
site it's a million-square-foot site so
i get to pitch this is really fun kind
of cool big boxes bigger than nota which
is my last big box I get to build this
is our Dallas site this side is 700,000
square feet so this is the kind of scale
you're going to start seeing in the data
center world and something in Cyprus
ones are bringing along what I came into
Cyrus want to do is build a new IX and
that's kind of a cool thing I think
everybody here appreciates what we're
doing is actually making it free and
this one in particular is in the state
of Texas it's in Dallas Austin San
Antonio and Houston including free
metroix reports and all that kind of
good stuff and if you notice that the
bottom says seismic traffic anybody know
what seismic peering is this is cool I
can teach you guys something new so most
of our customers or oil and gas
companies and what they do is go around
do seismic research dragging sonar
arrays thumper machines and this kind of
compute data is exabyte and yottabyte
level data sets it's so big that they
actually need exchange type technology
but they didn't have it these guys are
still making tape so instead of tape now
we're bringing the same IX of army you
guys normally use big brocade switches
and infinity gear and these guys will
start exchanging seismic processing data
across metros and starts opening the
door for other peering and you know
bring into new markets oh it's kind of
neat kind of a little diagram of the
state of Texas and the MPLS Network and
layer 1 connectivity we're doing my very
of animated slide so I want you guys to
appreciate these I spent a lot of money
on these and there's tons of them in
that in that cool so so broke aids
running multi chassis trunking ml x 32
ease with seven or 68 ports on them and
in fin eras and multiple fiber rings
this is the Dallas ring Houston which is
a completely new ring and a lot of
people are looking to pier in Houston
that's kind of neat and exciting again
just a lot of resiliency and just to
make it clear this is an x 10 gig at
free capacity across multiple facilities
so giant peering lands across city sets
that really nobody ever got to peer in
before geeks going to seaworld so we
have a little problem and I want you
guys to be aware of this I proved the
slides and and this flyer and all that
stuff and apparently I didn't really
read the contract that I signed and
we're going to sea world tomorrow not
tonight so everybody be clear it is not
tonight I just found that I little while
ago so instead of starting at 7pm it's
actually started 8 p.m. tomorrow so when
you get really drunk at beer in gear
you're going to go to SeaWorld hang out
with the dolphins get more drunk and
then go on a roller coaster if you
notice there we actually booked up the
entire Manta roller coaster this is
going to include dinner Italian food and
free open bar all top shelf so I hope
you guys enjoy yep yeah yep you gotta
switch your I'm not gonna say what
patrick said he has to switch but he has
to switch that day oh yeah and I'm sorry
very important your families can come a
lot of people have their their wives and
kids here or husbands or what have you
everybody's welcome there's no
restriction on that again open bar food
and and I just don't want to think about
what's gonna happen on the roller
coaster wrapped everybody's drunk but it
should be interesting so again it
includes dauphin petting it includes
penguins there'll be tons of food and
music and the roller coaster the Manta
ride is a 60 mile an hour ride girls if
you're wearing dresses don't if you're
wearing flip-flops you might lose them
it's one of those ones you hang from and
dangle and it does loop-de-loops and
twirls and all that stuff so it's going
to be interesting so this is actually a
description of it but again ignore the
7pm it's going to
8 p.m. tomorrow right after beer in gear
we're going to go over and it's going to
go to 11pm so the Flyers are wrong but
it is tomorrow not tonight everybody got
that so nobody's gonna walk to sea world
on my dollar tonight make sure we're
good all right okay guys thank you I
appreciate you letting me host again I'm
I actually signed up to host in 2015 in
San Antonio because I'm nuts and
continue to do this for many years I
really love nanog it's been a big part
of my life and my career and you guys
are all my friends and it's really
enjoyable to be a part of it again
thanks other days this is Tony man from
TW telecom there the wonderful host for
our network that I didn't have to deal
with this time well thank you everyone
it's great to be here this afternoon
this is the first time TWM is actually
participated in an eggnog event so we're
really honored to be here before I
really get into my my quick presentation
here I do want to thank on Betty Berg
for helping us with all logistics
without her there would be no internet
connectivity or bgp sessions going on
today i also want to thank our local
vice president and general manager soo
designer who's up there in front she
took care of all the coordination the
operations to make that connectivity
happen and especially thanks to Jason
Brown the network application engineer
from the land o market yeah precious
Jason Jason spent the last couple of
weeks working with the people of nag nag
and several people with the hotel
facility here to make sure that they
ipv6 and be for connection was active so
thank you again Jason we really
appreciate it excuse me sorry about that
so let's talk a little bit about the
network that we provided here today it
is a 100 Meg internet service first book
to a full 300 merrick it is actually I'm
traversing a 100 gigabit I'm skivvy a 1
gigabit ethernet connection going back
to a duel diverse route 10 gig bring
back to our orlando central office from
the Orlando central office it actually
takes one of four routes depending on
the destination of the traffic or
EP metrics to the rest of world you guys
notice to our if you want to test out
our asn number is four three two three
so I don't want to go into the details
of the network but doesn't especially a
component stay with the Juniper insist
goes but that's what you guys are using
today to get out to the rest of world
since this is the first time TW telecom
is beyond participate in an egg nog
event we want to give you a little bit
about who we are now this is not going
to be any commercial I'm just going to
give you some basics of what we got here
Peter telecom has been around for at
least 20 years we're in 75 marks across
the nation each one knows 75 markets is
actually an access point to the Internet
backbone so from there you can get to
domestic or global peering points in
transit and transit connections we're in
char we're in 17,000 buildings across
the united states that are 17,000
buildings that actually connect to our
fiber optic network and we have 28,000
five miles around local and regional
networks we also connect over 400 data
centers across the nation and these data
centers are people like Cyrus one here
and also additional cloud providers and
application software provides as well as
you can see there's a 10 gig IP backbone
that's 10 gig to each of those access
points it doesn't mean that the whole
infrastructure is 10 gig so I talked
about our deliveries on the gigabit
transport Gigabit Ethernet transport co
telecom has been doing ethernet service
for quite a while now we are one of the
industry leaders we meet the DF
certification in mefs certification and
standards and we prefer ethernet hand
off over the tradition of tedium because
of its ditional scalability and flexible
you get with ethernet the ipv6 that's
being provided by Tito a telecom it it's
not we've been doing for a couple of
years now we started on being dual stack
from 2008 of course we follow all Aaron
rules and regulations as far as
registration and allocation blocks and
of course we do multiple BGP sessions
across the world this slide here justly
talks a little bit about the additional
subset of what we provide here today
as I mentioned it's a 100 megabit
connection that's posted to 300 and it's
only thern a transport that ethernet
transport is a subset of what we call
intelligent networking the intelligent
networking actually encompasses Semak by
segment monitoring management of the
network it provides what we call real
time on demand bandwidth deny ramp
solutions direct access to all of our
cloud providers I like serious one
amazon and a couple of our providers out
there and then of course we have
application of where where you can
actually get allocations of bandwidth by
the application or the api of the
software that traverse the network well
thank you that's all the time I have for
today like I said ta telecom is proud
and honored to be here in a sponsor for
your access on for today we would like
an opportunity in the future to one day
talk about additional stuff and do some
some network on Brownback sessions and
breakout sessions and tutorials thank
you for your time
thank you so real quick we wanted to
give you guys a glimpse into what we're
doing over in the nog lab as I mentioned
there's been some significant changes
and how we look at using it in what we
think it can provide as far as insight
into the future network so I'd like to
invite at ballast from Indiana
University who's more or less leading up
the effort in there to give us a run
through what's going on sure sure yeah
so I work in the global knock and I have
the pleasure of managing a team that
develops network monitoring and
management and in general network
control software and so what I want to
do today is oh I just got up I did the
reflexive click that's right here okay
so what I want to do today real quick is
just talk about sort of how he came to
have some open flows software that we're
demonstrating here today so going back
in time basically way it works is the
global knock collaborates with an
organization called Internet to who
whose mission is to service the research
education networking community with a
nationwide backbone so in collaboration
we built out a hundred gig nation wide
open flow network and my team has
developed software that runs on that
network providing customer controlled or
customer provisioned vlans we expect to
have other applications in the future
but thus far today the main application
is this is this sort of portal based
provisioning system so we ask you to
come to the nog lab and check it out we
have a multi-vendor demo of that and I
am nothing
do I point this thing it should just
there we go brief history so this might
be a little bit more than in brief if I
can't get the seam to go faster alright
so in the beginning quote unquote in
late two thousand nine the openflow 10
spec was was published the key concept
here that was an enabling technology was
his a notion of separating the data
plane from the control plane really what
this gave us as developers was a
vendor-neutral programmatic access later
in july of 2010 internet2 was awarded 60
62 million dollar grant from the
government to build out a hundred gig
capable network and so using that they
embarked on in deploying a brand new
optical system as well as a hundred
capable layer two layer three system
fast-forward to April 2011 people's
minds got going and they they realize
they were on to something here the
combination of those two those two
precursors so what they what we create
was this thing called ndd I the network
design development initiative whose
objective was to develop a
software-defined wide area network our
objectives were to support
simultaneously domain science so people
doing physics research etc etc as well
as those doing fundamental network
research in some ways those things seem
diametrically opposed some people want
the network to be stable others want to
figure out how to break it but the
upshot is really want to figure out a
way of just doing a better job with
network engineering and how to design
these things so a month later we decided
based on all the risks that we really
wanted to pick an established use case
which this customer controlled vlans was
one that we had already had in place for
several years and we really put our
focus in the down stack risks the
software itself the requirements are
that the open-source we had we provide a
VLAN translation backup past sub-second
provisioning and failover integrated
measurement management as well as high
availability we bake that into the
software design we decided that we were
going to roll out a 10 gig network as a
baby step what you see in the lab is
essentially that network just in sort of
in localized form and from there we
embarked on evaluating the switches and
controllers to figure out the good bad
and vapor in September time frame we
decided upon the NEC 5820 as a switch
the Knox controller and we decided that
we're pretty much
going to have to bake in the h a and the
application layer not rely on the
controller stack looks like this I'm
running throughout time so if you want
more details on this come talk to me
application looks like this point and
click geographic frame of reference easy
to use and users can use it in their
bathroom right or whatever this is what
the network looks like five nodes
geographically distributed so a month
later we had a working demo from there
we went and looked at a package called
Jenkins which provides a sort of
continuous integration automation that
kind of thing we also use mini net to
allow us to do testing before we
actually had Hardware in hand we had one
switch the time and we faked it with
many net from there by December that
year we had five nodes deployed
geographically and the network is
operational 24 by 7 monitoring we did a
void mission critical application
procedures so from there it took us by
another 10 months to get 100 gig Network
deployed that was a brocade system and
then this month we're actually looking
at throwing junipers into the mix later
this month and also something called
flow visor so we could do Network
multi-tenancy which I can go into when
I'm there so in the lab itself we've got
two different networks that are
basically the same thing they're
multi-vendor we're using OSS to
contribute configure them so you guys
can come by and play with them and you
basically just check out what it's all
about so we're going to be there today
and tomorrow from 10 to noon and four to
six and then Wednesday from 10 30 to
noon as well so if you're interested
OpenFlow come by if it curious about our
experiences or I want to participate
come on by or if you just been sitting
too long and you're going numb so for
more information you can go here there's
my email address the google the google
code page for our software as well as
our website for my organization
you