no I'm time just have to find out what
it looking
oh my lord our projector has an IP
address probably means it's got now
we're in it okay so we're going to start
with this I can figure out slideshow
from the beginning Lord so very briefly
there are probably two people in the
room who don't know exactly why IP
address spoofing is a problem so for you
I'm going to sort of set the backdrop of
what rrl is designed to solve so the
essence of all of the attacks you've
been reading about other than the lower
low orbit ion cannon and some of the
other get requests floods that some of
the banks have seen all of the packet
flooding attacks you have been reading
about on the nanog list or in the
newspapers in the last six months use
this mechanism whereby an attacker who
is able to use someone else's source IP
in other words the victims source IP
address on a request sends that request
and the reflecting amplifying orbital
death ray projector which is your dns
server most likely or perhaps it would
be mad Larson's dns sensor dns server /
calm will answer it because it has no
idea by the time it has been through the
great internet cloud in the sky that
that IP address makes no sense for
coming where from all that noses gia
came out of the Hat of the cloud I
better answer it when I first started
talking about this bc p38 was about a
year old and I wrote a companion
document meant for pointy-haired bosses
I'll have a reference to it at the end
of this where I said gee we really need
to be stopping this at the edge because
when a packet first enters the great
internet cloud in the sky that guy knows
that
source address would make no sense and
so I've been working very hard to get
that done but what it looks like at that
time is that the attacker would the
abided PC and it was running you know
what ever said about where it had picked
up recently it's behind a NAT and that
means a lot of these food source IP
addresses would die right there at the
NAP box because we're here in 192 168 1
dot 7 or would it if you've got an IP
address that's inside RFC 1918 chances
are you cannot use someone else's source
IP address on a packet that leaves your
network so it's only map that has saved
us from an even worse set of problems
related to source IP spoofing now the
other thing that was great back then is
that these boxes were generally megabit
speed connected dsl was the order of the
day and so even though these boxes had
terrible sis's men they didn't have a
whole lot of computing horsepower you
had to really gang 10,000 of them
together to get enough packets to really
hurt somebody not that 10,000 was a hard
problem but things have changed now we
have the cloud we have all of these
virtual hosting clouds and I don't mean
to pick on anybody so I won't name any
of them but you can now order a Linux VM
from anybody and they will push a button
and clone that vm for you tell you its
root password and then you have you know
some VirtualBox running in somebody's
cloud somewhere and it tends to be
gigabit connected unfortunately these
are as poorly system and as the old
botted pcs are and once that button has
been pressed and you got your clone you
would stop getting any kind of updates
in particular to something called Joomla
or PHP BB or anything else that would
allow bad people to come and use your
computer for their purposes instead of
just for yours and these tend to be
gigabit connected there are millions of
them don't downplay this problem you can
now get enough horsepower from enough
different clouds that you don't strictly
even need to reflect off of anybody you
can
and bury someone in traffic that they
did not solicit and cannot stop just by
spoofing some other address and fire
bombing them directly apologize for all
these pop-ups so in other words the
problem has recently gotten much much
worse and of course the cloud owners
will tell you yeah we gave that guy the
root password we cannot now reach past
him and update his software for him and
we understand that he's not smart enough
to do it but you know will pass your
complaint to him but you won't
understand that's that's the direction
we're moving so in the future this
projector will since it has an IP
address will no doubt have malware
running in it because you've all heard
about SCADA industrial control systems
getting default passwords running telnet
or whatever the idea behind these boxes
is volume and at scale security gets
lost in the noise let's plain a little
bit about that and again this tends to
be your dns server i'm going to explain
what you can do about it in the other
half of this talk right I don't know
what we were thinking UDP in the white
area is crazy it works fine for NFS or
anything else that's in your land or on
your campus but I don't know what the
heck we were thinking creating a
protocol like DNS and expecting the
whole world to run it and not have this
problem I really don't know about DNS
SEC because some complete moron wrote an
RFC number 26 71 that allowed for the
response to a pack that would be a lot
larger than the old 512 byte limit in
order to accommodate the gigantic
signatures that come with DNS SEC
especially negative responses so we were
crazy we're hurting from it we could
have seen this coming now to add to that
you know sales of smartphones and
whatnot go up if it has flashing moving
things on it that you can press and so
forth and that means apps that means
pulling data over the network
promoting it code and executing it in
some form like Java flash activex
whatever I don't know what we're
thinking because every one of these has
had all kinds of problems where the
executable data gets corrupted or is
deliberately corrupted by its creator
and then collapse your box soon it will
co-op to your refrigerator and lastly
you can't expect somebody to be assisted
in I understand that the iOS devices
iPhones and whatnot get this better but
thinking that PC Mac cloud server
smartphones any of these are going to
that your mom is going to sit at home
and stay it's time for me to update my
software because there is a java flaw
that's not realistic so we really could
have seen this coming if you have a
recursive name server and you're open to
the world and you're not google or
opendns or some other entity that is
really dedicating a lot of time to
filtering abusive flows you probably
need to close that and figure out how to
answer queries only for people that are
you treat as your users your customers
you can do that with access control list
you need rate limiting I'm going to
explain what that is if you run a
network that's at the edge and you have
some customer that you're feeding
connectivity to in a data center over a
t3 or whatever it is you could filter
any packets they send you that doesn't
have an IP address that you've allocated
to them and if they say but wait I'm
multi-home then you make an exception
for them I'm not saying you should never
do what I'm saying the default should be
don't do that you know keep people from
doing this and this business of giving
somebody cloud servers without any kind
of hope of ever having any system and
again after day one is is a bad idea so
there needs to be some kind of a premium
service where you pay an extra dollar a
month and get updates applied for you
promised you some references dancy knee
and paul ferguson wrote pcp 38 i noted
that it was too long and too complicated
for pointy-haired bosses so IRA of Sacco
for i recommend printing both of them
and then
distributing them up among your
workplace to the point of here in a non
point to here at bosses okay it's to let
you know why we're here now to tell you
what I'm here to tell you there's a fix
for this on the dns server side and like
all fixes it's not perfect and and yet
it is working pretty darn well so i
talked about this this is an actual demo
on my actual recursive server what
you've seen is a burst of 25 requests
and I'm telling The Dig command don't
fall back to a TCP session and a bunch
of other things don't retry and so forth
because if you let dig work normally
then it will timeout and retry and if it
gets a truncated response it will retry
with TCP and so forth so without all
these fancy options you just get 25
decent answers even from my server so i
had to in order to demonstrate that i'm
dropping some of these of this burst i
had to turn on these extra options and
all this is really saying is out of 25
times we ended up with three truncated
responses to if you set the TC bit that
tells the questioner yeah i didn't have
room in the packet for everything i
wanted to say to you so if you didn't
get enough which they want from us
because it's a zero-length response then
you should try again with tcp this is
dangerous because tcp is three round
trips and seven packets and a lot of
state on both sides and it will not
scale so you can't be doing this all the
time but you can do it statistically so
we have a mixture in rrl response rate
limiting we have a mixture of setting
the TC bit on some things and dropping
some things and the result is that you
get no actual loss you get a little bit
of extra delay if that particular person
is under attack and a particular name is
under attack now is what it looks like
in the config file I'm simply stating
hear that
remember five seconds of history for
anybody who has exceeded the when the
maximum of five responses per second now
to be a response means not just that you
your IP address asked me something it's
an IP address similar to yours bucket
eyes down to the flash 24 if it's ipv4
usually that's the default an IP address
similar to yours has asked me a question
that had an answer similar to the one
that I'm thinking about giving you
because otherwise somebody could just
randomly pick you know random string
calm oh and another random string calm
and so forth every one of them would be
a unique reply and you would not
necessarily be able to detect that as a
flow but from our point of view a
negative response is actually a response
from the apex so if I ask random string
calm and I get a negative answer we
treat that as a negative answer from
calm we ignore that the random strength
so we haven't seen negative impact on
real flows now Andrew Sullivan pointed
out recently last day or so on one of
the mailing lists I'm on that for a CDN
provider with really low ttls this is
bad this is bad juju because if your TTL
is lower than the average time of the
retry then you're going to end up not
giving good response to these CDN names
I'm not a big fan of CDM DNS but I still
recognize we should fix this I just
don't know how yet other than that no
negative impact when we threw these
patches out there a number four people
were being attacked at that time in that
moment and publicly stated both had a
filius and nominate for CEO WK that they
threw our patches in without nearly the
testing they would have preferred to
have but their house was on fire and
they had to do something and it worked
so if in an authority server I just
recommend that you turn this on in a
recursive server it doesn't help because
repeated flows on a recursive server are
probably coming from some post pics or
send mail or Apache or some server on
your network and they really
legitimately do ask the same question
is because they have no cash so this
won't help the recursive site that's why
i started my other talk by saying on the
recursive side which you need is an ACL
make sure that you're not answering
questions that didn't come from your
customers and you probably won't need
rate-limiting on the recursive servers
of not buying specific number of people
think that everything I do has to be
bind related that's not true this is a
DNS thing and to that end I want to note
that NSD has just implemented this in
three dot-to-dot 15 which was released
day and a half ago and they used the
same logic but of course completely
independent source code and that means
you don't have to run bind to get rate
limiting anymore other server operator
or implementers are certainly encouraged
to also implement this at into something
it's a public health hazard to operate a
name server that can be an orbiting
death ray projector for anybody is a
public health hazard don't do it if you
don't currently run by under NSD then
consider switching to one of those and
telling your current dns server provider
why you did that and point them to the
internet draft looking document that i
wrote that describes this it's not
patented it's in no way protected I want
people to turn this on now that it's
been implemented across two servers I
will be submitting an internet draft and
letting the IETF take a swing at it
obviously if I started this with an ietf
document then it would be 16 years
before we had the ability to run code
anywhere so I didn't want to do it that
way there's a mailing list if you don't
join it but you think this is a good
idea and you just sort of turn on
rate-limiting anyway that's fine because
this rate limits mailing list tends to
be people arguing about how it should
work rather than people trying to find
out how it does work this is safe
technology don't worry about it any
questions people warns walking up to the
mic is there any thought on deploying
the similar technology for other
applications or is a generic rate
limited technology for
colonel so you could look at other wide
area UDP protocols in here and looking
at MTP and say every one of these needs
some kind of rate limiting that's not
exactly true there are some MTP family
protocols that have a larger response
than the request and that was the
administrative window where you could
ask some clock what are your peers and
get that list that was a problem that's
amplification but everything else MTP
does has a response that is equal in
size to the query and that means there's
no benefit to bouncing your attack off
of somebody if you're able to spoof the
source IP of packet and you're able to
send a certain number of packets having
a certain number of octets in them you
may as well just send them straight to
the victim as to bounce off somebody who
won't amplify now very few people are
crazy enough to put an NFS sir or out on
the open Internet but that would be a
great amplifier if they did most people
have learned the lesson about not doing
it with the Samba program so really
although i think the IETF should adopt
the the attitude that responses shall
never be larger than requests for all
new protocols there aren't any other
loeb there's no other low-hanging fruit
is nothing else that needs to be fixed
as desperately as dns needs to be fixed
warren warren kamari google so more of
an observation the non of network does
not do bc p-38 i love that i noted the
same thing when i was at a ripe recently
and you'd like to think that we should
at least be able to do this for
ourselves but I'm betting that if we
found the poor son of a bitch who had to
build this network he would say my
equipment won't handle that or it does
software switching if I enable that
option or there's some vendor reason why
I can't do what I should have done and
in that sense we need to go after the
vendors and let them
that this is a public health hazard and
we're going to stop buying their stuff
until they fix it yes sir david by rocky
TNT are you starting to see some of the
DNS appliance vendors expressing
interest in our in implementing rrl yes
I am cloud shield in particular which I
didn't really realize this until after
they got bought by saic they are an
astoundingly smart company and the way
they built hardware and so forth there's
a language called packet see I recommend
you all google and read up on was
co-designed by them they've got a
hardware device that they can front end
that whatever your front-end speed is
that they are now adding rrl to
specifically because they haven't been
able to solve this problem by Counting
requests right so if anybody tells you
they're going to solve this problem in
their firewall by looking at client IP
and then or maybe they're even going to
look at the query but they're not going
to look at the response send them to me
and I'll explain why this has to be done
as a response rate limiter not as a
request or client IP flow limit but so
far they are the only ones who have
picked up on this but I know that once
one of them cells that the others are
all going to start losing rfps and then
they're going to implement it also thank
you hi Jim shank from to come ur e have
you given thought to the possibility of
this being used as a denial of service
attack to keep domains down and not
propagating by spoofing a address in a /
24 as a source and not allowing the
answers back yes we wanted to make sure
that in no case would we ever make the
situation worse and Andrew Sullivan has
taken the time to point out that there
is one case where it gets worse and
that's where the TTL is so low that the
total transaction time that we can
induce if there's a retrying a timeout
retry or have you retry with TCP is
larger than the TTL that's that's the
problem but in the normal case where the
TTL is an hour or a day or whatever we
normally use for ttls the answer is no
because the real client is going to be
getting some of our answers
and our answers are a mixture of the
real answer a timeout which of course
the client will see is a timeout and a
TC equal one response if they get the
real answer they're satisfied if they
get a timeout they're going to retry
usually two more times they get a
truncation they're going to retry with
TCP and if the channel is so congested
that their queries are being lost and
they can't successfully retry that's a
problem that we came here to solve and I
would have to say some in some cases we
don't solve it but in the other two
cases we didn't make it worse if
somebody is spoofing your IP address
asking his server for a certain name and
he's running rrl he will eventually stop
answering that question if you ask it
but you'll be very happy that he didn't
congest your upstream link with all of
the responses that you would otherwise
have gotten because that dramatically
increases the chances of you hearing one
of his TC equal one responses or hearing
a real response that he will send you
and because you have a cache once you
have it you'll keep it sorry answer is
yes we thought a lot about that but
using the bit masking for matching on
the source if I choose an address that's
one above or in the same / 24 but not
the DNS resolver that I'm wanting to
block a domain from being resolvable
from then wouldn't it be possible for me
to keep a particular domain from being
resolvable from a particular resolver by
spoofing an address that's in the same /
24 and keep asking a question that that
server would then not cash because it's
not receiving it so it wouldn't matter
if you picked one off IP address or pick
the actual address either way we will
suppress responses and we're trying to
do is transform an amplifier into an
attenuator that means we're going to
drop some responses all together and
we're going to turn others into TC equal
1 responses you have with the normal 3
retries you have an eighty seven and a
half percent chance of hearing a real
answer from us if you through the normal
retry logic of a normal recursive name
server
and that frankly is good enough for me
okay thanks yeah the one of the thing to
keep in mind here is the scaling of this
that doing this processing to do the
rate-limiting you're taking time out for
your CPU I don't want to I'm not
debating what this is useful that's very
useful but the consideration areas it's
taking time out of your runtime
resources to do this it's kind of
shifting the attack now from yeah but do
you have any thoughts about what do you
think are the scaling bottlenecks what
do you think is going to be a thing that
goes at some point you're going to have
so much traffic or what what do you
think would make what could blow this
out of water basically is what do you
think I'm asking out of genuine
curiosity not sure if i'ma so the
additional resources that you will use
if you're running a rate-limiting are
the other guy retrying and more often so
certain network load that you're
incurring you using more cpu time to
make this decision and you using more
memory to keep track of what the IP
block has asked for what thing recently
we limited all of that to the extent
possible and it turns out to be perfect
we can on a server that was receiving
like 50,000 queries a second each from a
unique IP each asking for a unique name
the total amount of additional heat
space that we will require is a couple
of megabytes and as you know servers
that get a hundred thousand per second
are not getting from unique queries or
unique IPS to unique names so that
really is the worst case and for the CPU
we don't actually marshal at least in
the bind implementation of our RL we
don't marshal the response right once
we've known what the response would be
that's when we check to see if there's a
bucket open for this and if we've
exceeded its quota and that means that
in any case where we are suppressing a
response we are also avoiding the cost
of marshalling that response and that
marshalling cost is much higher than our
dropping cost so it does it does mean we
have an additional fixed cost on the
responses that we don't drop but I'm not
worried about
in terms of actual server Headroom you
can't see this if your server was
running a ten percent cpu utilization
ninety percent headroom you might be
able to see a third of a percent of
difference if you turn on orl but it's
just we we wanted to make sure that we
weren't creating a resource vector to
trade out for the old vector Michael
Michael Sinatra yes then you'll be the
last by the way I'm Way over the time
okay just two I'll be very quick then
just to address briefly Ed's comment in
experience running this while under
attack the biggest problem with cpu and
with server utilization is actually when
you're trying to do query logging while
you're under one of these attacks or
while you're being used as one of these
reflectors if you're trying to query log
a syslog that's going to take up a lot
more resource than running rrl and the
other point to make is as someone who's
experienced being a reflector this is
the best way to handle it right now that
i know of with no with very little
collateral damage and everyone i think
is going to want to be looking at this
stuff because you either have had this
happen to you you're going to have it
happen to you or it is happening to you
right now there aren't that many other
categories unless you simply don't run
an authoritative name server so you
didn't ask a question but i'll add on
which is a question mark on the end of
that if you want thank you so a number
of people have turned this on not
because they thought they were under
attack but because somebody told them
this was a public health thing that they
should just do and they discovered they
had been under attack they just hadn't
noticed it before but you know I've seen
people I've seen traffic graphs that say
yeah this is when I used to have to send
five megabits of constant response
traffic five megabits is not very much
by the standards of the people in this
room it was a lot to that guy he thought
it was necessary and it turned out that
actually about a half a megabit was all
that was necessary and the rest was okay
to drop so I think you'll find that
there's a lot more of this going on than
anybody knew so thank you all I'm sorry
for these overtime that's great
alright I'm going to present something
that is on behalf of somebody else real
quick and Larry and David o has both you
to come up shortly Daniel Clemens and I
had a discussion about some work that he
had forwarded to me just sort of on a
whim I think and I took a look at it I
thought it was quite interesting and I
said why don't you come to nana I can
talk about this and he he wanted to but
he could make it so he said why don't
you go ahead and do this one day half so
basically the system some work that him
and his colleague exact date and had
done about a year maybe a year and a
half ago taking a look at who
anonymous's what are they all about how
to monitor them and the tools that they
use in analyzing those tools so I'm just
going to kind of summarize for you this
white paper that he wrote and I don't
have permission to distribute this white
paper if it's I even going under the
oppression that any of you want I could
get it you just have to ask him so if
this seems interesting to you either ask
me later or write down this email dress
small have people have we put in touch
with him I'm gonna go through this kind
of quickly in the name of time but if
those of you who I hope are very few are
familiar with anonymous I mean they're
their modus operandi is pretty
straightforward most people consider
them at disa that our heck to this
operation who really took prominence a
few years ago when Tom Cruise was in
this video on YouTube that just kind of
went viral and when YouTube took it down
at the request of church of scientology
group of folks can when nuts about that
and thought it was you know some sort of
violation of their writer freedom to the
post this material and so they started
watching all sorts of interesting and
very often malicious protests and
attacks against that group and then from
from there they just their popularity
continued to rise as more people sort of
join the group and they took on
so-called operations and there's a
number of them undoubtedly
many of you have heard of some of these
attacks and so this is just sort of a
brief snapshot of a couple of those that
I just wanted to list for you here
Daniels work what I found most
interesting about it is he essentially
him as colleague since she went through
almost 40 pieces of software and
examined them mostly from the point of
standpoint of source code and try to
identify ways to fingerprint the attacks
that they would generate and so I found
this really interesting because I think
that's really potentially useful
information for anyone who's
particularly on the receiving end of
that attack and so they built signatures
for all sorts of stuff mainly the tools
that they were looking at we're focused
on this low orbit ion cannon stuff but
some of you may have seen started as a
simple Windows application that which
essentially blast packets and had a few
parameters on what to actually stand for
traffic they built snorts the signatures
because they felt that that was either
who they were writing this for or
perhaps based on their experience that
was most convenient for them as I was
reading this stuff however that may not
be entirely applicable to many people in
this group because I imagine some of you
who have very large networks don't enter
runs snort in line and some of your 10
giggling so it's just not going to work
so in essence many of these signatures
just aren't going to work for many of
you in these would be pushed perhaps
towards the edge and I took it look at a
one tool to see if there were things
that you could implement it like a
simple ACL and the one I looked at for
examples slow loris and I didn't see
anything really obvious to me like that
you could do like I'm layer three
earlier for that would but it would do
this summer sorts of things that they
had done the thing that also stood out
was that the attacks generated from
these tools that they were doing
signatures on was largely based on a
default use case of these tools so
basically you download this tool and you
run it and then the signatures based on
the default parameters of that tool
which are actually pretty dumb there's
all sorts of you know you've been hacked
kind of strings in the in the attack
payload itself and those sorts of things
that are easy to filter on if if you
have that deep package
Shin capability and if the attacker
isn't actually changing anything about
the configure the tools so there's some
limitations to the signatures that
they've created but presumably in
practice that doesn't happen all that
often here's just a quick screenshot of
one of the JavaScript based on Kanin
stuff and below that is a sample
signature and I don't intend if you to
actually read that but that's just going
to say so that's essentially if they
didn't they didn't find any back doors
and they did they weren't able to do
complete attribution to who wrote some
of this stuff but they were to find a
few breadcrumbs for some interesting
parts and so that's all I wanted to
share with you if you are interested in
more of this sort of thing you can
certainly talk to me about it but i
might just refer you back to them so
that's that if anyone has any questions
about it feel free to get up to the mic
I have one more a brief thing and then
I'll maybe I'll start with David because
I know you've tested your so one of the
things that I've been slowly working on
it to be quite frank Damon had a whole
lot of interest in is this success in
quite yet is these so-called DNS any
attacks and this is related very much to
the things that Paul was just talking
about what this is is the it's a type of
amplification reflection attack that's
going on in the wild practically all the
time at least every day I see some
evidence that these are happening in my
view of the world is relatively limited
and some of you have much bigger views
of the world and so you presumably you
would see even more than I would the
idea is that you send in some type of
any query to a server and you'll get a
response when you send in any query you
get basically anything that that server
can tell you about that query name
whether it's an MX record types record a
record a quad aid all the Guinness SEC
record types and usually or often that
response would be quite large and so
that's the amplification so you couple
that with the with the smoothing
capability that some networks still
provide for and then you have that
reflection piece
these have been going out for at least a
couple years now specifically in any
attacks and I've asked a couple of times
you know there's anyone figured out you
know who's doing this what's the code
that's actually being run to enable
these and no it's seems far as i can
tell knows the answer to that question
so I'm just getting sick of not knowing
so well I'm not personally indirectly
being harmed necessarily by these
attacks directly I'm just interesting
and figuring that out so I'm trying to
figure that out and at the end you'll
note that i'm asking for any assistance
that some of you I know could help
provide so I essentially said all the
match well let me back up and say what
we do see often is the in any queries
tend to use a handful of q names career
names often it's is Sea Org they provide
a large response for an inquiry right
that's another popular one but we've
seen a few others but those are the two
most well-known ones are the most common
ones as I've been looking at this last
few weeks I've in the so that the
evidence that I've gotten quite a few of
these attacks while they've been widely
reported in the operator community the
operators being the DNS operators
servers are errors I'm also seeing
evidence that a lot of these attached
are actually geared towards gaming
servers and at least one of the or a
couple of the attacks seem to be
particular types of gaming server which
counter strike for example seems to be
one that's getting hit with these so
that's some clue perhaps to you know
who's involved in some of this stuff the
other thing i see that i don't know if
it's actually related or not yet but
it's awfully suspicious is we also see
query names for simply rude so now is
the org or any and I don't know that
this is a tack backscatter or not I see
these queries essentially being spread
all over the net so I'm getting queries
all the address space that I have
visibility into and I don't know if this
is someone simply scanning for name
servers that will respond to in any
queries and if they get a response or if
it literally is backscatter traffic
attack so this may be a completely
separate thing to investigate but if
they're related investigating that a
long thing at the same time that in the
hopes that this will lead me someone
okay so how do you mitigate this stuff
well obviously Paul talked about RL
which is very popular anyway any
networks who do aunty spoofing is a
problem I in fact talk to people here
this week who have admitted that you
know you can't always doing exploiting
filters for various reasons that some of
you I'm sure aware one of the things
it's not an assay mitigation technique
but it's a perhaps of a reactive
approach is to figure out where this
stuff is coming from based on what I've
seen so far I'm led to believe although
I can't prove inclusively is that many
of this text don't appear to be that
well distributed they may be coming just
from a handful of networks that of
course allow spoofing and therefore
there may be a small handful of networks
who are the ones that we want to look at
and beat down with the hammer or get
attention of so that they can help us
fix this how do we do that will some of
the networks that may be involved in
again I don't have evidence but i'm
getting the c key sneaky suspicion that
their networks who have operators
they're not necessary that friendly to
people in this room that is that they're
not actually unfriendly but they're not
usually going to go out of the river to
play nice in the security community or
spend a lot of time helping us out so
how do we get their attention if we if
we wanted to get their attention do we
do peer them do we start announcing
their prefixes with their asn or opera
fixes with their asn in it and since
they can't get to our networks that will
maybe get their attention I don't know
but maybe it's time to get a little more
aggressive with them so I I suggest that
and lastly I'm looking possibly for help
for many of you who have visibility
particularly background operation people
have maybe access to so-called
interesting customers and I'm not
suggesting that any of these specific
hosting providers are bad actors
but this isn't some example of some some
in any related traffic either victim or
Target or sources that may be occurring
that I haven't been able to get to a
good contact into you I've been told at
least a couple of these I'm not going to
get that contact for these networks and
they're just not type of people we're
going to play nice with people in this
room but so maybe some of the up streams
might be able to help us in that
situation so if you can help or if
you're interested in helping or if
you're at least until I come asking that
would be good to know so come find
uniform so any questions about this
stuff come up to the mic and I'll let
David if you want to come up and start
getting ready go ahead don't you delete
the slides up probably good idea can't
get back to the medications I had
submitted a lightning talk which I
haven't heard back on where when the
mitigations that we had been looking at
is trying to actually kind of change the
protocol that's in a way by just dying
access to any queries under UDP night
I'm going to save you the entire detail
abide light and talk but that's another
way to say we're just not going to
answer anything that comes over UDP for
any and we can argue about good or bad
but there's a lot of fall behind it but
I data to a mitigation but it doesn't it
the problem is it could business I have
to be in any query that just happens to
be the one that's actively being abused
yeah I mean I we can go into the
rationale but the other thing I was
going to add was when preparing my
slides I went and asked some folks about
the background so we were looking at one
particular attack that was talked about
the last nanog that the one one of the
any query attacks we talked up there was
the ball the security track whatever
last time and i was told that since then
we have seen the any query attacks just
proliferate in not an unrelated ways
they're just a lot more use of any and
main different ways to attack servers so
it's become more Republic Ross the board
not just one particular use one
particular case one pickle incident it
just seems like more more bad actors are
using it in different ways to do
different things well the same thing and
that's where we were part of our
rationale behind looking at has the any
query become a tool
only before not many people used it it
was low now it's a big part of our
traffic it's all bad traffic so maybe
it's time to say we should really
different gate put it away so that
that's for a longer discussion Michael
Sandra yes that the bad guys have
already started using other queries even
in mid attack we saw them switch from
any to our our sake for a particular
domain that had our our sigs in it now
obviously our sigs an easy one to go
after because it's big but they'll find
something else to do and and related to
that too is I a couple of cases I've
seen a couple networks who given me
packet captures there have been and it
still been in any but they have been for
number large number of zones that that
server has been authoritative for and
clearly someone who's targeting because
they have to know that they have their
authority of any zones the attackers are
currently very aware of how to aim these
attacks and how to do them while we're
changing pcs here Darren we we had an
idea that we wanted to do like some
security personnel's like the peering
track would do and I know some people
are interested in sort of meeting people
in the security community sort of help
get in the secret handshake clubs so one
approach to do that is have people sort
of come up and introduce themselves say
a little bit who they are who they
represent what they need help with on
occasional what they can help with so
Darren was one of the ones that I've
talked to you about this he was going to
do be the guinea pigs of stand up and do
this sure I'll do it so I'm Darren
grabowski I'm the otj at the other than
Jared at ntt so I manages security team
so I'm actually won the operational side
of it where jared is the development guy
does a lot of things in as his hands and
everything so Darren grabowski thankee
yes 2914 if you have any problems feel
free to Kentucky me
I'm Brian sniffing I'm from off my
mostly I've been a cryptographer and a
web app security person higher up the
stack and we've started finding cases
where it doesn't matter how much we get
some of those issues right so I'm here
looking for interactions and advice on
getting things right at other levels of
the stack
hello my name is Eric rose and I'm of
red hat and I'm on our info SEC team and
I just came here to meet new people and
start networking hi my name is Liam
Heinzman operations at a dynamic network
services so I want to talk about DNS and
the attacks I'm here I'm David Barack
with AT&T consulting and I wanted to say
a little bit about some of the sensor
networking concerns we've we've run
across in some of the in some of the
edge network deployments so some of you
have some of you are involved in
deploying sensor networks and some of
you or not so just a quick overview of
what sensor networks are basically these
are these are the these are the things
when they talk about over the network of
the future the Internet of Things and
things like that that's that okay but
the real examples of this are your smart
warehouse where every toothbrush has an
origin ship in it or where every palate
of toothbrushes has has our kids in more
or every or the smart meters on every
power grid that weird thing on the power
grid or things like that they these
often are multicast multicast users or
should say multicast sources and
receivers often the entire communication
path is largely multicast this cause
this can cause some very specific issues
one of the in one of the reasons for
using multicast in that context because
you have so many possible sources you
know if you think about every every
tooth brush in a walmart right or more
to the point in the Walmart warehouse
every toothbrush that's a lot of
toothbrushes so if you can if you can
send if you can track them all with you
know send one multicast and then they
all get it right then that's that's a
lot better than having to individually
send the packet that every single one
saying are you still there
so the the in general the sensor
networks do tend to be machine
communication to other machines and not
directly for people the process there
will be processing and then it goes to
people and the also anybody I'm certain
there other public transit users in in
the room by the many of the public
transit next bus utilities are enabled
with sort of a almost a degenerate case
of sensor networking I mean you could
that could that could be effectively an
iPhone on a bus right I mean it could be
something that simple but it but it more
elaborate case can involve sensors that
are put around and put around the city
and it tracks where it is based on
proximity things like that so smart
smart power grids are the interesting
are an interesting case and and to look
at at an example I wanted to use the one
at use orlando and just as i have not
been involved in the deployment of the
smart power grid in orlando so it's it
but this is just as a case study to give
you to give you the the number and scale
of what you're looking at and where the
possible security threats are and these
are representative of what we've seen in
other contexts so there are 238 k people
in orlando and there are approximately
121 k homes that does include
multi-family multi-family homes if you
take out if you take out the
multi-family homes you're talking about
it approximately 500 sorry about 57 k in
individual structures so so the
something that you something you need to
be something you need to be aware of in
this is that your control servers of
your of your sensors need to be need to
be able to deal with the fact that
sensors are constantly coming and going
sensors tend to be small and they tend
to be cheap and they tend to break they
tend to be extremely low power and they
tend to and they will come and they will
go and you have to be able to deal with
that and then we'll burn out the and if
you're being concerned about security
you have to recognize that there will be
sensors that will become compromised or
and so therefore you or will become
flaky or dangerous in it will become
a problematic in some way and you need
to have a way to cut them off from the
network so you're the equivalent of a
remote trigger black hole effectively
but you need to figure out how to cut
how to cut them off at the closest point
so they can't do anything else to you
and generally have a knack knack system
in place the about why these would be
used while you use multicast to monitor
them okay they your threat model
obviously your biggest threat in any
context is always insiders and this is
this is that's always the largest threat
in any environment ever in any in any in
any room in any organization there is a
certain percentage of that organization
that can be it can be assumed to be
working counter productively shall we
say and and it's not specific to sensor
networking so I'm going to consider it
out of scope for this but that is the
that is a single largest problem the
denial of service threat that you have
to deal with include the rampant copper
theft which in the sensor networks we've
seen deploy is a huge problem because
the because these tend to be low
bandwidth they tend to be provisioned
over cheap copper and that cheap copper
unless you've done something like code
equipped are so that nobody realizes
it's copper tends to be an extreme
target of theft if you're using zigbee
you're using one some other wireless
technology you get RF camming you can
get you can get GPS GMA you can get all
kinds of jamming of anything that's
that's wireless and if you're you can
also get obviously the resource
exhaustion the the amplification attacks
and and the other data type in the
nettle service you get is of course a
self denial of service when you
implement something and then you knock
yourself off line and Nava general
that's security gone wrong now the
bigger problem in your power grid is not
denial of service it's going to be data
compromised because you're under
regulatory authority Lori concerns about
not letting your data leak because you
have personally identify
data about your customers that you're
not allowed to share so they're the you
know and and cabelas you know rev
injection hi check is a humongous
problem as is any kind of the tapping
attacks or or wireless sniffing attacks
additionally if somebody can inject
false data into your network it's very
difficult to recover from that that's
the destruction that attack effectively
once you can attack and once you can
inject false data how do you ever know
how do you how do you ever recover from
that so it's extremely difficult it's
easier to prevent these entities to
recover from them and denial of service
and data and data compromise do fight
with each other because the the the more
you do to prevent to prevent your data
your data compromise attacks in terms of
an theory play the like but more likely
you are to cause yourself that denial is
easier it is to knock your knock you off
the air so that is a that's an
omnipresent danger so on on looking at
looking at at the example topology
you'll have some some degree of home
aggregation that will have access points
they'll connect to your cloud of some
kind it'll go to your data center the
some number of homes are aggregated for
every access point they given that
Europe got 120 121 thousand homes you're
probably looking at between one and ten
thousand one thousand ApS that is a
non-trivial number of ApS so whether or
not your sensors are your argument ecat
sources or your aps or your multicast
sources is a significant scale and
concern which will tell you which will
tell you about your the amount of
headroom you'll have in terms of
resource congestion attack you know do
you really want 121,000 asses in your
Eskimo Chi on your switch routers can do
it but that switches tend to be pretty
unhappy with that and if you do that on
your in
you want to do that on your router's
watch out for hash table collisions
because that gets pretty unpleasant so
so the the types of the types of attacks
that you see general so your denial of
service attacks take place in different
in in different places and can be and
can be mitigated you're jamming and
copper and what you can't really
mitigate copper theft officer then we
can mitigate copper theft by using
wireless backhaul or using some non
copper backhaul but that gets kind of
expensive non if you use non wireline
backhaul then you get more gaming so
from secret are they using non internet
back backhaul can mitigate some of the
some of the some of the capacity to some
of the capacity flooding attacks that
could come from the internet the the
data compromise can be mitigated via
encryption but you can also give
yourself a self to not let service when
you do that and so that's the that's
where that will take place the and this
is the trouble with your malicious data
injection is actually capturing and is
capturing it and knowing when it's when
it begins because once you capture it
that's when you need to cut it off
basically at the moment you see it if
you once you've let it get in to get in
and you say oh we had a malicious data
source three months ago how long has it
been spitting in data and how long is it
how long is it you been able to corrupt
the other the other sensors and the data
from the other sensors so the way you do
the sorry the way you do encryption you
can either do it you can either encrypt
from the 80 back and then across your
network or you can encrypt end in and
end and it's cleaner but but it also
means that your multicast scale it gets
harder because because you don't want it
you don't want to try to unless your
encryption is at the application layer
because then
taking taking your non IP data and then
figuring out how to IP encrypt it gets
it gets down its kind of difficult and
it may be worth it may be worth it to
have a dual layer of encryption to
encrypt it at the IP layer and at the IP
and RF layers as well as at the
application layer now and there is no
actual amount of protection you can give
them prevent the sufficiently determined
attacker however the goal is to prevent
is to make it difficult so but it will
not prevent the it will not prevent
someone who's sufficiently determined as
we've seen from networks that are
disconnected from the internet entirely
and still get hacked so and still get
hacked to the point that their
controllers spin out of control and
explode so they these are just these are
some of the some of the concerns with
some of the concerns we've seen and
basic mitigation that we've been looking
at recommending any are there any
questions i don't think that mike's
working so i presume that the copper
techs do happen i've heard of that
happening particularly rural developing
areas of the world for the other types
of attack particularly okay so for the
other types of attacks more than network
based attacks is these are these threats
or what are you seeing these actually
occurring and if so what are the
motivations for them I don't know the
motive it's catching the attackers is
hard and generally that involves that
involve catching the attackers on on
attacking for instance of power grid
involves men with guns right as opposed
to involving mode like is not most of
the people in this room right so it's
mostly a matter for law enforcement in
terms of catching them and then
identifying their true motivation the
yes these are all attacks that we've
seen these are all attacks that are live
in the field we have a we routinely see
copper theft it's a huge problem and I
presume about other anybody else running
wire line stuff sees this on especially
in any in any area that is not you know
megalopolis is seeing this and the the
jamming attacks that you've seen I mean
there have been cases recently at people
jamming GPS and hijacking the hijacking
groans I mean it's the there's this kind
of stuff is absolutely coming and it's
getting more and more and more the
built-in security of things like of you
know the ltd + GSM style encryption is
simply not good enough let alone the
stuff that's built into is a be or they
need the other or wine axe or any of the
other levels so any kind of sensor
technology needs an additional layer if
you want to prevent it from being used
as an amplifier and if you if you if you
want to see if you want to see a real
amplifier compromise your sensor network
and have the and have the you know the
three million toothbrushes start sending
DNS queries to somebody so you know as
far as the scar they were saying about
it paula saying about the bottom fridge
don't worry about fridges worry about
toothbrushes so any questions thanks
there are you want anyone want to jump
up and introduce themselves I'll pick on
somebody Charlie come on get to thank
you
Charlie Renton t encumbering I'm in
operations with James shanks as well you
need anything just a note Anthony
Williams also go by the name of Albie
and I'm with verizon security Heather
Schiller I used to be verizon security
with Alvey but now i'm at Google Fiber I
would like to know one thing about
Heather that I would trust her to watch
Patrick's kid ok ok my name is Larry
Blanc I'm with merit network and I'm
going to talk a little bit about RBI and
I are our integration Oh most of you are
familiar with these two terms here I'm
assuming most of you are familiar with
IRS they've been around for quite a
while and our peak I is we're going on
in the ITF it's also been going on for
quite a while now so let's just get
started I'm not going to really do a
deep dive into rpi there's too much to
cover really but the basic idea is to
use public key cryptography with x509
search which have extensions to cover IP
addresses and a s numbers both before be
six addresses and so these are specific
extensions that have been documented in
RFC 377 I think or something like that
and and then those are in turn used to
sign where to call drought origin
authorizations it this is just one use
of the
resource certificates that can be used
for other things but right now a lot of
work has been put into the these rows so
basically they're just they're signed
statements I guess they're called CMS
signed blobs so you take one of these
certificates and then you have a CMS
flap that has origin and IP address
range and you can actually have multiple
ranges within one of these rows so you
can have multiple of e 4 blocks or v6
blocks and there's 1a s number and you
can actually have multiple roles for a
black so if you want to originate a
block from more than one a su would
actually create multiple roles for that
prefix so again I mentioned this it's a
it it also contains an expiration date
and you can also specify a maximum
prefix length so if you have a prefix
and you want to if you have a / 16 and
you want it will allow anything up to
like a / 18 you can say max length of 18
and it's a more compact way of doing
that than having a separate roll out for
each prefix so obviously that would get
out of hand quickly if you have a / 16
and you want to allow it to a / 24 it's
a lot more efficient to do this and they
have 256 different rows so these rows
are they're being published in the same
repositories as the resource
certificates and and so basically it our
sink is the current mechanism being used
to to download these from as a
distribution protocol so right now
there's a number that our IRS are
operating repositories that contain
these certificates in these rows and
once you download them you follow
certificate chain to actually validate
the rows so when you download them you
have to verify them and you know do the
crypto to make sure that they're
actually valid so that you can trust
them
as far as I'm integration work with IRS
there has been some work done in the ITF
under the site or working group and
there's a graft rps l dash sig and
that's been around for about four years
i believe i think it went to last call
back in May but it didn't actually
forgot progress beyond the last call and
is sandy Murphy I'm not quite sure if
anybody knows why what happened at so so
so the idea is add a signature to
existing our psl objects using these
resource certificates and it's actually
kind of generalized so you can use it
with several different object types
route route 6 at num guess block I net
na man inet6 no objects so here's here's
an example of this signature attribute
and you can see it contains a number of
fields here the first field is a version
number version equals 1 the sea is the
certificate URL reference so this we
don't have the full URL listed here but
so it's our sink URL as i mentioned m is
the signature algorithm t is a unix
timestamp a specifies which fields in
the object are being signed so you have
to actually have to specify which fields
are the signatures covering and then b
is the actual signature itself and coded
in base 64 so so this has some issues if
you want to use the signature with
existing I our tools you have to do all
this thing that your validation and you
know that that that can be
time-consuming to have to update your
tools to do that it's
not real trivial work to do that it also
creates additional work for users if
they're already doing raw as if they
want to maintain both rows and these
signatures they have to there's you know
few separate steps involved so you have
to remember to do both of them so it's
just you know users don't like to do
things twice i don't i don't think so
another issue that has come up recently
as many of the IRS are using what are
known as a hosted model for their
certificate authority so rather than
delegating certificates to users the
rars are actually hosting certificates
for users and the users don't actually
have a certificate that can sign other
the rbs.l objects with so right now the
IRS are concentrating on the rows and in
order to support these rps all
signatures you have to the RSO will have
to support this because the users don't
actually have this if they don't hold
the certificates actually help being
held by the I Robert so our idea is to
to look at the marks something
specifically involving the roles
themselves the roles are very similar to
the existing route in route six objects
in our psl and so the idea is to
actually use the rose to validate
existing route in route six objects and
so it's instead of using the
certificates themselves we go down a
level and user rolla's instead and it's
not quite as generalized we don't it's
only going to cover the route and route
six objects we're not dealing with the
autonomic I projects
so there right now there's an individual
draft on this row a status attribute is
what we're calling it right now so this
is there's a concept of generated
attributes in our psl we're instead of a
user supplying the attribute the server
actually generates an attribute and
returns it with the object so Rose can
have one of three possible states when
you're doing validations so it can
either return a valid response invalid
if if the row has if there's a covering
roll up but the origin house does not
match what's in the route object that
would be in an invalid route advocate
and then finally unknown if there's no
covering Roiz for an object so in
addition to the status we include a time
stamp to indicate the last time the
object was checked against the rpi so
it's kind of a freshness indicator and
then a URI link to our sink you are I
linked to the the row itself if it's a
valid or invalid status and then finally
the max length from the Aurora I
mentioned that you can have a max length
field and that actually provides some
additional value add to our psl and I'll
show you example here so in this case
you have the royal status and like the
signature attribute there's value pairs
so there's a version field so s is a
stout the status field which I mentioned
can be valid invalid or unknown so in
this case there's a valid covering row
off for this route object for 198 108 00
double sigh 14 the EM field is the max
length field so in this case the rolla
actually has the max length specified of
16 so it means that you can announce
anything under that this / 14 up to a /
16 would be considered valid and and we
get a lot of questions from people who
want to actually specify a max length in
the rod object in our psl when it was
specified in providing a mechanism for
actually doing that so by adding this
extra attribute where you can by using
the Royal you can actually add a max
length to your existing Road object
right now we see people off and we'll
just register every possible more
specific route object credit so you get
a lot of these you know dupla you know
pollution in the IRS from people
registering all these more specifics
because while they may not be announcing
them all they might want to announce
them for traffic engineering or you know
to respond to a prefix hijack or
something like that so they just
register every you know possible more
specific and then finally since this is
valid the you field specifies the URI
for the arcing for the row so if you
actually want to do the validation you
can fetch the row itself and perform a
validation as you can see they're kind
of lengthy so in the in the internet
draft they made that kind of optional
field so our ideas you could maybe have
a flag you specify to who is query if
you actually want that field since it's
so long you may want to just you're
probably only interested in in the
status field whether it's valid or
invalid so you may not really care about
the the URI if you're not going to
actually do the validation yourself
there's no real point in looking at that
so there are some issues with with this
attribute you have to trust the IRS X
since it's doing the validation for you
you're not doing the validation yourself
so somebody acts into the I our server
and messes with the objects you know
there can be an issue there so if you're
concerned about that you know you can do
your own validation on arola there's
another issue with the Aaron repository
they actually have a license agreement
to in order to get their trust anchor to
do validation
you have to decide sign this relying
party agreement which says that you
won't redistribute validated royal
information and I've spoken to Aaron
about this and they have indicated this
would likely violate that agreement so
their concern is liability since we're
publishing this the status information
publicly they're concerned that somebody
again may hack into the server and do
something bad or corrupt the data so
that's an issue we're talking with Aaron
about right now so right now we're
looking at modifying some of the
existing I are tools such as I our tool
sets to use this information so another
alternative which would not violate the
Aaron agreement would be to use to
modify the tools to actually look at a
local row of cash so in that case you
would have to actually create you own
validated your own validated world local
royal cash and you would be signing an
agreement with Aaron directly to get
their trust anchor and do your own
validation is it any feedback i'll start
off Larry since I'm so close so 22
comments or questions first it won't be
specific maybe perhaps the IR piece
which is maybe your focus the the work
itself i wonder if you see similarities
or are you encouraged by the DNS SEC
deployment with the work that is going
on in a Sider group and the BGP sex
stuff in general or will it take someone
like Dan Kaminsky to get people to
deploy the sort of thing the second
thing is once this starts getting
deployed what does it do to the
flexibility to perhaps do things like
Rob poisoning or the things that will we
lose something that we may wish not to
lose because of
I think there's been quite a few
concerns expressed on the mailing list
specifically about the ability to
respond to attacks quickly and do
traffic engineering and since they're
our propagation delays with these rows
and you typically only refresh them like
once a day or something so if you want
to do something quickly you know I've
heard feedback on that issue there is
work actually with using DNS SEC to do
something similar to the rolla with
using the inner part button ip6 darpa to
create these objects in the DNS that are
similar to a row as but you know using
the reverse screens did and the ideas
it's somewhat simpler and the DNS SEC
stuff is pretty pretty widely deployed
at this point so some people feel that
that's a better approach simpler
approach than the Rose rpki I'll do an
intro and ask my question at the same
time my name is Brian I was actually a
contractor Aaron I'm a software
developer so I've worked on our pki in
their irr and the reverse DNS so one of
the problems or challenges with rpki and
bgp sec is that you need to have the
entire set of rows right in order to
determine this and it's actually in most
rirs every eight hours not every 24
hours so this needs to be turning
constantly you need to return the or you
need to to pull right via our sank the
entire repository all the time and to
continuously be doing this and while
that helps for generating your filters
if you have a process in place is
generating your bgp filters from an irr
today if you're not doing that at some
point I think that this becomes more
work and less secure than just using
rpki and in future bgp sec and with
regards to rover wrote
bgp information reverse dns it solves a
problem right you can get just the rose
that you care about not all of the rows
but the challenge there is that while it
works for origin validation there's some
issues I think with path validation and
other things that need to be done to
secure bgp fully origin validation right
presents misconfigurations and hijacking
but not leaves so and if anyone wants to
come talk to me i'm total geek for this
time so i think by me later I mean I see
this sort of maybe as a transition
mechanism since there are people who are
using tools right now I are tools right
now and you know it's going to take a
while for them to deploy new router code
to support the rows in the router you
know the protocol to download the rose
into the yeah I agree and I actually
think it's a great idea I think that to
ease transition right it's easy for
anyone to go sign there there get the
resource certain sign there rose today
you can do that right now just fill out
a web form no big deal but to actually
start using the data once it's published
it becomes a lot more complicated so
anything that uses that I think is a
good idea Warren kamari google so with
regards to the cider rpki which was a
cider or psl sig draft I think there are
only two sets of comments submitted
during the working group last call when
they had a bunch of useful stuff in them
and the working group asked the authors
to incorporate the comments but hey I
guess got sidetracked
Thanks thanks Larry if anyone wants the
last opportunity to come up and just
introduce themselves real quick now's
your chance or if you just want to come
up and talk about any other securities
you have about 15 minutes otherwise we'd
all rush to beer and gear for some
reason you want to meet some people in
community you can always come up to me
and i'll either introduce you to other
people i see her now help kind of get
you introduce the community as well I
good evening my name is used I'm Yusuf
from telekom malaysia telecom benicia is
a incumbent player malaysia for telco
data and voice services we have 8 part
in the US so I'm basically management
managing those pop right here in the US
thank you
Jake mcclare director of operations at
nine so you're probably familiar with
Thein from two different products but we
have security dash team at dime comdy
mcom and that is for anything you want
to talk about whether it's any kick at
the any attack or we also have obviously
we are free product which a lot of the
botnets use so we are definitely
interested if you see activity please
let us know we may not be able to shut
it down right away because we don't want
to let us know that we're onto them but
we do want to know the information thank
you did you see my bit when i did the
any stuff do you have yes okay if maybe
you can't say it the mic but if you have
any additional information I don't have
yeah I mean we talked about it at the
last nanog and a lot of those slides I
totally agree with i will say that we
did try blocking any for a while and we
had negative repercussions that some for
some reason there are certain parts of
they were certain companies that were
calling us and saying hey because of
something that we do with any we are now
not trusting you and so we had to
re-enable it and so what we ended up
doing is we put a filter in place that
just watches it because as far as we're
concerned any is shouldn't be happening
very much or at all so we just basically
did an RL equivalent with our own
scripting and just shut it off after a
couple of tries so we had you were
paying attention there but yeah no word
out we're definitely keeping an eye on
it I mean I wish I had a better answer
but I also agree with the sentiment that
if we if we block it they're just going
to move on to the next thing so you know
things like vcp 30 30 a very very very
important she an update to that everyone
keeps same tcp 30th or 16 you were doing
so well whatever that draft is we need
to make sure everybody knows about it
because it's very important hi everyone
James Ashton from wide open west just
wanted to say hi we have a couple
million homes etc and you know if
anybody has any problems with anything
in our network feel free to say hi I'm
always around and listening
i'm joe perez with a wide open west data
center i actually run security there at
the data center and i was hoping you
could put your email address up again
how does not give you a business card if
you'd like yeah that'd be great alright
thanks ladies and gentlemen hopefully
I'll talk to some of you who I even met
yet maybe three or gear if you come at
me with a couple beers you hand that
helps